Shit!
If you pair of deuces
lookin for work
I suggest you get your
scrawny asses in here, pronto
Now, up on Brokeback...
the Forest Service has
got designated campsites...
on the allotments
Them camps can be 3 or 4 miles
from where we pasture the woollies
Bad predator loss, if there's
nobody lookin after em at night
Now, what I want...
is... a camp tender
to stay at the main camp
where the Forest Service says
But the herder... hes gonna pitch
a pup tent on the Q.T. with the sheep
and hes gonna sleep there
You eat your supper
and breakfast at camp...
but you sleep with the sheep
A hundred percent
No fire... Dont leave no sign...
You roll up that tent every morning
in case Forest Service snoops around
Yeah?
No
No!
Not on your fuckin life!
You got your dogs, your
30-30. You sleep there
Last summer I had a goddam near
25% loss. I dont want that again
You...
fridays at noon, be
down at the bridge...
with a grocery list and mules...
and somebody with supplies...
will be there at the pick-up
Tomorrow morning well
truck you up to the jump off
Jack Twist
Ennis
Your folks just stop at Ennis?
Del Mar
Nice to know you, Ennis Del Mar
My second year up here
Last year, one storm, the
lightning killed 42 sheep
Thought Id asphyxiate
from the smell
Aguirre got all over my ass, like I
was supposed to control the weather
But... beats working for my old man
Cant please my old man, no way...
Thats why I took the rodeo
You ever rodeo?
You know... well...
I mean once in a while
When I got the entry
fee in my pocket
Yeah
Are you from ranch people?
Yeah, I was...
Your folks run you off?
No, they run themselves off
There was, uh, one curve
in the road in 43 miles...
and they missed it
So, uh...
the bank took the ranch...
...and my brother and sister,
they raised me mostly
Shit!
Thats hard...
Can I?
Thank you
Only thing...
dont ever order soup
Them soup boxes are hard to pack
I dont eat soup
Well, watch it there
That horse has a low startle point
Doubt there's a filly
that could throw me
Let's git, unless you wanna
sit around tyin' knots all day
Oh, shit...
Cant wait till I get my own spread
and I wont have to put up
with Joe Aguirres crap no more
Im savin for a place myself
Alma and me, we're gonna get married
when I come down off this mountain
Shit... That stay with the sheep...
no fire bullshit...
Aguirre got no right makin us
do somethin' against the rules
No more beans
Damm... Shit!
I don't know...
Something wrong?
Yeah, so what...
Why didnt we get the
powdered milk and the spuds?
Its all we got
Well, heres next weeks
Thought you didnt eat soup
Yeah, well, Im sick of beans
Too early in the summer
to be sick of beans
Come on
Come on... Come on...
Whoa there, whoa, whoa!
Shit!
Whoa! Come back, here!
Whoa there, whoa
All right. Fuck it!
Okay, you bastard...
Where the hell you been?
Been up with the sheep all day
I get down here hungry as
hell... and all I find is beans
What in the hell happened, Ennis?
I come on a bear,
is what happened...
Goddam horse spooked
and the mules took off and
scattered food everywhere
Beans is about all we got left
Got whisky or somethin'?
Dumb-ass mule!
I can't believe that. God-damn!
Let me see
Shit
Well, we gotta do something
about this food situation
Maybe Ill shoot one of the sheep
Yeah, what if Aguirre
finds out, huh?
Supposed to guard
the sheep, not eat em
Whats the matter with you?
There are thousands of em
I'll stick with beans
Well, I wont
Whoo-wee! Yeah!
Was getting tired of
your dumb-ass missin
Let's get a move on
Don't want the Game and
Fish to catch us with no elk
Come on. Shit!
Yeah, Im commutin
four hours a day...
I come in for breakfast...
I go back to the sheep...
Evenin' get em bedded down...
Come in for supper...
go back to the sheep...
Spend half the night
checkin' for damn coyotes
Aguirre got no right
making me do this
You wanna switch? I wouldnt
mind sleepin out there
That aint the point...
Point is, we both
oughta be in this camp
Goddam pup tent smells
like cat piss or worse
I wouldnt mind bein out there
Well, Im happy to
switch with you, but...
I warn you, I cant
cook worth a damn
I am pretty good with
a can opener, though
You cant be no worse than me, then
Here you go
You won't get much
sleep, I tell you that
Yeah. Come on
Shot a coyote up there
A big son of a bitch
Balls on him the size of apples
Looked like he could
eat himself a camel
You want some of this hot water?
Its all yours
I dont rodeo much myself...
Whats the point of ridin' some
piece of stock for 8 seconds?
- Moneys a good point
- Uh-huh
True enough
If you dont get
stomped winnin it, eh?
Yeah
Well, my old man...
...hes a bull rider
Thank you
Pretty well-known in his day...
Though he kept his
secrets to himself
Never taught me a thing...
never once come to see me ride
Your brother and
sister do right by you?
They did the best they
could after my folks was gone
Considerin they didnt
leave us nothin but
$24 and in a coffee can
I got me a year of high school...
That was before the
transmission went on the pickup
Then my sis left... Met a
roughneck, moved to Casper...
And me and my brother, we...
we went and got ourselves some
work on a ranch up near Worland...
Till I was 19
Then he got married, and uh...
no more room for me
Thats how come...
...me end up here
What?
Man, thats more words than
you spoke in the past 2 weeks
Hell, thats the most
I've spoke in a year
But my dad, he was a fine roper...
Didnt rodeo much, though
He thought rodeo
cowboys was all fuck-ups
The hell they are...
Well...
- Yeehaw
- There you go
I'm spurrin' his guts out!
Wavin to the girls in the stands!
Hes kickin me to high heaven...
but he don't jackboard me! No!
I think my dad was right...
Tent dont look right
It aint goin nowhere... Let it be!
That harmonica dont
sound quite right either
That's 'cause it
got kind of flattened
when that mare threw me
Oh, yeah?
I thought you said that
mare couldnt throw you
Uh... she got lucky
Yeah, well, if I got lucky, that
harmonica would've broke in two
# I know I shall meet you #
# on that final day #
# Water-walking Jesus #
# take me away #
Very good
Oh, yeah...
My mama, she believes
in the Pentecost
Oh, yeah?
What exactly is the
Pentecost? I mean...
...my folks, they was Methodist
Pentecost... I don't know...
I don't know Pentecost is...
Mom never explained it to me. I
guess it's when the world ends and...
fellas like you and
me, we march off to hell
Speak for yourself...
You may be a sinner
but I ain't yet had the opportunity
Thank you
Shit...
Im gonna go up to the sheep now
Give 'em hell...
No, I'm...
You can hardly stand. Its
too late to go to them sheep
Well, you got an extra blanket?
I'll just roll up out here...
grab 40 winks...
and I'll ride out at first light
Youll freeze your ass of
when that fire dies down
Oh, that's good
You're better off
sleepin' in the tent
Yeah...
All right
Ennis!
What?
Just quit your yammerin'
and get in here!
Whatre you doin?
See you for supper
Come on
This is a one-shot thing
we got goin on here
Its nobodys business but ours
You know I aint queer
Me neither
It's all right
Lie back. Come on
Twist...
Your Uncle Harolds in
the hospital with pneumonia
Docs dont expect hell make it
Your ma sent me to tell
you, so... here I am
Bad news
There aint nothing I can
do about it up here, I guess
Theres not much you can do
about it down there, neither
Unless you can cure pneumonia
Jesus...
Them sheepll drift if I
dont get back up there tonight
You'll get pitched off your
mount in a storm like this
You'll wish you hadn't tried it!
It's too cold! Close it up!
Well, what are we
supposed to do now, huh?
Get on in there and untangle' em
Chilean sheep out of ours, I guess
Oh, where is it? Shit!
God, half the goddamn
paint brands have wore off!
Weve gotta try. The least we can do
is get the count right for Aguirre
- Fuck Aguirre!
- Oh yeah, fuck Aguirre...
What if we need to work for
him again? You think of that?
We gotta stick this out, Jack
Youll run them sheep off
again, if you dont quiet down
What are you doin?
Aguirre came by again
Says my uncle didnt die after all
Says bring em down
Bring em down, why?
Its the middle of August
Says theres a storm comin
movin' in from the
Pacific. Worse than this one
That snow barely stuck an hour. Huh?
Besides, that
son-of-a-bitch,
hes cuttin us out
of a whole months pay
It ain't right
Well, I can spare you a loan,
bud, if you're short on cash
Give it to you when we get to Signal
I don't need your money, huh?
You know, I ain't
in the poorhouse...
Shit!
All right
Time to get goin, cowboy
Come here!
- This aint no rodeo, cowboy
- Oh, shit!
Ennis... Ennis
Come here. You okay?
- You okay?
- Yeah
Some of these never
went up there with you...
Count aint what Id
hoped for, neither...
You ranch stiffs...
you aint ever no good
Wanna give it some gas?
I cant believe I left
my damn shirt up there
Yeah...
You gonna do this again next summer?
Well, maybe not... Like I said, me
and Almas gettin married in November.
So... Ill try to get
something on a ranch, I guess
And you?
Might go up to my daddys place...
and give him a hand
through the winter
I might be back... If
the army dont get me
Well, I guess Ill
see you around, huh?
Right
What the fuck are
you lookin at? Huh?
...and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us
Lead us not into temptation,but
deliver us from evil
For Thine is the kingdom,
the power and the glory...
for ever and ever. Amen
Under the powers vested in me...
I now pronounce you man and wife
You may kiss the bride
And if you dont, I will
You all right?
Stop!... No please, stop!
My old ladys tryin to
get me to quit this job
She says I'm gettin' too old to be
breakin' my back shovelin' asphalt
I told her strong backs
and weak minds runs in the family
She didn't think that was too funny
I told her it keeps me fit
Mornin'... Mornin'!
Pulled in last night...
Didn't want to wake you up
Oh, no, I was just...
I thought I'd tell you
before the Sergeant showed up
Parking this trailer
on the beach is illegal
Yeah!
Well, look what the wind blew in...
Hi, Mr. Aguirre
I was wonderin if you was
needin any help this summer
You're wastin your time here
What, you aint got nothin?
Nothin up on Brokeback?
I aint got no work for you
Ennis Del Mar aint
been around, has he?
You boys sure found a way to
make the time pass up there
Twist... you guys wasn't
gettin paid to leave the dogs
to babysit the sheep
while you stemmed the rose
Now get the hell out of my trailer
How my girls doin?
All right. Jennys
still got a runny nose
Ennis, could you
wipe Alma Jrs nose?
If I had three hands I could!
Come here. Come here. Oh!
- Girls all right?
- Yeah
Jenny stopped her coughin'
I think you should take the
girls into town this weekend
and get em an
ice-cream... or somethin...
Cant we move to town?
Im tired of these
lonesome old ranches
No one for Alma Jr. to play with...
Besides, Im scared for Jenny...
...scared she has another
one of 'em bad asthma spells
No, rent in towns too high
There's a cheap place in
Riverton, over the Laundromat
I bet I could fix it up real nice
Oh, I bet you could fix this
place up real nice if you wanted to
- Ennis...
- Hmm?
I know youd like it, too
Real home... Other kids for
the girls to play with...
Not so lonely like
you were raised...
You dont want it to
be so lonely, do you?
Yeah
Come here
I aint so lonely now, is it?
You sure the girls are asleep?
Yeah
Come here
Ennis...
Let 'er rip and snort, boys!
Jack Twist, hangin'
on for dear life!
And down he goes!
Watch out there, fella!
He's comin' for you.
Send in the clowns!
Okay, a fine ride by Mr. Twist
Shit!
Four seconds for him
Give 'em a hand, folks,
our very own rodeo clowns!
Give us a beer, Doug
I'd like to buy Jimbo here a beer
Best damn rodeo clown
I've ever worked with
No thanks, cowboy
If I was to let every rodeo
hand I pulled a bull off of...
buy me liquor, I'd have
been a alcoholic long ago
Pullin' bulls off of you
buckaroos is just my job
So save your money
for your next entry fee, cowboy
You ever try calf ropin?
Do I look like I can afford
a fuckin ropin horse?
Shouldn't we move a little closer?
No. Come on, let's
don't. Jenny'll get scared
Woo-wee! Look at this crowd!
Bound to be a lot of pussy on
the hoof in a crowd like this
All swelled up with
patriotic feeling...
and ready to be humped like a frog
So, where do you figure
the most pussy is at?
Las Vegas or California?
Hell, I don't know...
but if you make it between Montana
and Wyoming, I'd take Wyoming
Hey! You might want to keep it
down, I got two little girls here
Fuck you. Asshole...
Probably quit givin' it to his
wife after his kids was born
- You know what that's like
- Yeah
Ennis... Ennis... Ennis!...
Ennis, let's move.
Let's just move, okay?
Now, I don't want
any trouble from you
You need to shut your
slop-bucket mouths, you hear me?
You ought to listen
to your old lady, then
- Is that right?
- Yeah. Move somewhere else
What about it? You wanna lose
about half your fuckin teeth, huh?
Not tonight, bud.
I'd sure rather not
It's ok... It's ok...
Here she comes, ladies and
gentlemen! Oh boy, look at her fly!
Its Lureen Milton from
right here in Childress, Texas
Come on folks, shes one of
yours... Lets give her a big hand
Shes turnin' on two...
Shes around three!
Come on folks! Help her home!
Come on! Come on!
And the time is... 16 and 9!
Here's Cheyenne Hodson
from Cody, Wyoming!
Come on, girl!
She's headed around two!
Maam...
Come on, Cheyenne!
And her time is 17 and 2!
Here comes Scotty Griffiths,
out of Lubbock, Texas
Come on, Scotty!
Damn it! Let's give Scotty
Griffiths a big hand, folks
Better luck next time, cowboy
Boy, I tell you, folks, what a
heck of a way to make a living!
Next up is a
up-and-comer!
Jack Twist, all the way up
from Lightning Flat, Wyoming
He's onboard Sleepy
today! Let's hope he's not
Okay!...
There they go, folks! And
look at Sleepy go, boy!
He's broke free today, folks!
Come on, spin and spin and spin!
Oh, boy! Good ride, cowboy!
Lets see what the judges say...
I tell you, folks, that sure
looked like the winnin ride to me
You know that girl?
I sure do. Thats Lureen Newsome
Dad sells farm equipment.
I mean, big farm equipment
$100,000 tractors... shit like that
What you waitin for
cowboy? A matin' call?
# No one's gonna love you like me #
# No one else, can't you see? #
# No one, no one #
# No one's gonna love you like me #
# I know sometimes you felt #
# so lonely #
# I know #
# you felt so sad and blue #
Wait, hold on...
You don't think I'm
too fast, do you?
Maybe we should put the brakes on?
Fast or slow, I just like
the direction you're goin'
- You are in a hurry
- My daddy's the hurry...
He expects me home
with the car by midnight
- Hey, Monroe
- Hey, En
Is Alma here?
Yeah, she's in the condiments aisle
- The what?
- Ketchup
Thanks
Your boy gonna play again this year?
Hey honey! Hoeny, what
are yall doin here?
Big hurry. My boss called and, well,
he wants me to go up to the ranch
I guess all the heifers must've
decided to calve at the same time
I figured I could drop
the girls off with you
Ennis... well...
I got a million things I gotta
do here before I can leave
I dont get off for
another three hours
- Mama, I need crayons
- Not now, Alma
Ennis, please, you promised
youd take them tonight
Alma, I can't afford not to
be there when the heifers calve
Right, it'd be my job
if I lose any of 'em
What about my job?
OK, all right. I'll call my
sister. I'll see if she can take em
All right. All right
You be a good girl for
your mama, all right?
I'll be half the night
Bring home some ground
steaks if you think of it
Come here. Oh, Alma, please!
Oh boy!
- Ok
- Monroe, I am so sorry!
It's okay. It's okay, Alma
I'll clean this up just
as soon as I call my sister
to come get the girls
Really, Alma, it's okay. I'll get it
- Alma, come with me
- Watch your feet
Alma!
Honey, got a surprise for you
Hey!...
I got two whole boxes
of formula for you
You did?
- 120 cans
- 120?
L.D., where did you put 'em?
Oh, hell, back seat of
the car, where I left 'em
Rodeo can get em
L.D... I can already see
who little Bobby looks like
Good job, little girl
He's the spittin' image of his grandpa
Isnt he just the spitting
image of his grandpa?
Yeah...
Look at those eyes...
LAUNDROMAT
Hey
Hey, honey...
Hey Ennis, you
somebody name of Jack?
Maybe... why?
Cause you got a postcard.
It come general delivery
Friend, this letter is long over due
Coming through on the 24th. Drop
me a line say if your there. Jack
Is it somebody you
cowboyed with, or what?
No, Jack, he rodeos, mostly
We was fishin buddies
I'll color the beach
Maybe we could get a babysitter
Huh?
Take your friend to
the Knife and Fork...
No... Jack aint the restaurant type
We'll more likely just
go out and get drunk
If he shows...
Ok, we take one more bite and
then we finish with dinner?
There, thats a good bite.
All right, youre excused
Jack fuckin Twist!
You
son-of-a-bitch
Come here
Alma... this is Jack Twist
- Jack, this is my wife, Alma
- Howdy...
Hellow
- Oh, you got a kid
- Yeah, I got two little girls
- Alma Junior and Jenny
- I got a boy
- Yeah?
- 8 months old. Smiles a lot
I married the prettiest
little gal in Childress, Texas
- Yeah?
- Lureen
Yeah...
So me and Jack, were gonna head
out, and get ourselves a drink
Yeah?
- Sure enough
- Pleased to meet you, maam
We might not get back tonight... We
get to drinkin and talkin and all
Ennis?
Could you get me a pack of smokes?
If you need smokes, Alma, they're
in the top pocket of my blue shirt
There in the bedroom
- 4 years, damn!
- Yeah, 4 years
Didnt think Id hear from you again
I figured you were
sore from that punch
Right next summer I drove
back up to Brokeback...
talked to Aguirre about a job and...
he told me you hadn't
been back, so I left
Went down to Texas for
rodeoin... Thats how I met Lureen
Made $2,000 that year
bullridin. Nearly starved...
Lureens old man
makes serious money...
farm machine business... of course
He hates my guts... though
- The army didnt get you?
- Nope, too busted up
And rodeoin' ain't what
it was in my daddy's day
Got out while I could still walk
Swear to God, I didn't know we
was goin' to get into this again
Oh yes, I did. I
red-lined it all the way
I couldnt get here fast enough...
What about you?
Me?
I dont know...
Old Brokeback got us good, dont it?
What are we gonna do now?
My God, theres nothin we can do...
Cause Im stuck
with what I got here
Makin a livins about
all I got time for, now
Hey...
Well, me and Jacks headin out for
the mountains for a day or two...
Do ourselves a little fishin
You know, your friend could come
inside, have a cup of coffee...
Oh, hes from Texas...
Texans dont drink coffee?
You sure that forman wont
fire you for takin off?
You know, that foreman he owes me...
I worked through a blizzard last
Christmas. You remember that?
Besides, Ill only
be a couple of days
Bring fish, daddy. A big, big one
Come here...
See you Sunday at the latest
Im starvin. Wanna
get something to eat?
Yep
Last one in
Is there anything interesting
up there in Heaven?
Well, I was just sending
up a prayer of thanks
For what?
For you forgettin to
bring that harmonica!
Im enjoyin the peace and quiet
You know, it could be like
this, just like this, always
Yeah? Howd you figure that?
What about if you and me had a
little ranch, somewhere... little...
...cow and calf operation?
It'd be a sweet life...
Hell, Lureens old man...
you bet hed give me a
down payment to get lost
I mean, he... more or
less already said it
No, I
I told you... it
aint gonna be that way
You know... you...
...you got your wife
and baby in Texas, and...
...you know, I got
my life in Riverton
That so?
You and Alma, thats a life?
Now you shut up about Alma...
This aint her fault...
The bottom line is
were around each other and...
this thing grabs hold of us again
...in the wrong place...
...in the wrong time...
...were dead
I tell you
there were these two old guys
ranched up together, down home...
Earl and Ritch
...and they was the joke of town
even though they were
pretty tough old birds...
Anyway, they found Earl
dead... in an irrigation ditch
They took a tire iron to him...
Spurred him up, drug him around
by his dick till it pulled off
You seen this?
Yeah, I was what? Nine years old?
My daddy... he made sure
me and my brother seen it
Hell, for all I
know, he done the job
Two guys livin together? No way
Now, we can get together
once in a while...
way the hell out in the
middle of nowhere, but...
"Once in a while"...
Every 4 fuckin years?
Well, If you cant fix it,
Jack, you gotta stand it
For how long?
As long as we can ride it
There aint no reins on this one
Its nearly supper time. Where in
the hell do you think youre goin?
To work!
- I thought you had the day off!
- Well, you thought wrong!
The girls need to be fed
Well, you take care of it!
Alma!...
Alma!
Supper is on the stove!
No-ones eatin unless
youre servin it!
I already promised Id
take the extra shift!
Fuckin tell em you
made a mistake, then!
Goddamit, Alma!
Alma!
You girls need a push or somethin?
- No
Listen to her purr, gentlemen. Youre
not gonna get that with your Caddy
I told you what she could do
it, now Im gonna show you.
Say, didnt that pissant
used to ride the bulls?
He used to try!
Ennis, see you in a couple weeks
fish should be jumpin. Jack
Honey...
have you seen my blue parka?
Um, last time I seen
it you was in it...
Day we had that big ice storm...
Well, could have
sworn I seen it here
You know...
you've been goin up to
Wyoming all these years
Why cant your buddy come
down here to Texas and fish?
Because the Big Horn
Mountains aint in Texas
And I dont think that his pick-up
could make it down here anyway
New model comin in
this week, remember?
You the best combine salesman we got
Youre the only combine
salesman, in fact...
Yeah, well, Ill be back in a week.
That is unless I freeze to death...
And Ill freeze if I
dont find that Parka!
Well, I dont have the goddam Parka!
You know, youre worse than Bobby
when it comes to losin stuff
Oh, speakin of Bobby, did you call
his school about gettin him a tutor?
- I thought you were gonna call
- I complain too much
- The teacher dont like me...
- Right
- Now its your turn
- Okay, fine, so I'll call later
All right, fine...
Bye
I got 14 hours of
drivin ahead of me
See now, it dont seem fair
You goin up there two
or three times a year...
him never comin down here
Ennis, they got an openin over at
the power company. Might be good pay
Well, as clumsy as I am,
I'd probably get electrocuted
Daddy, the church
picnic's next weekend
Will you be back from
fishin' by next weekend?
Please, daddy, please!
All right, as long as
I dont have to sing
Daddy... Thank you
You forgettin somethin?
Youre late!
Look what I brought...
Here we go. No hands!
It's all yours,
buddy! It's all yours
Come on... Come on...
Come on in, Alvin...
I've been trying to
call you for hours
Its Saturday night. You
know, we could still smarten up
and head on over
to the church social
That fire and brimstone crowd?
I think itd be nice
Ennis... as far behind
as we are in the bills...
it makes me nervous not
to take no precaution
If you dont want
no more of my kids...
Id be happy to leave you alone
Id have em, if
youd support em...
Custody of the two minor children...
Alma Del Mar Jr. and Jennifer
Del Mar is awarded to plaintiff
Defendant is ordered to pay
child support to plaintiff...
in the sum of $125 per month
for each of the minor children
until they reach the age of 18 years
Del Mar divorce granted,
this 6th day of November, 1975
ENTERING WYOMING
King of the road!
In you go...
What are you doin here, huh?
Got your message about the divorce
Come here...
This heres Jack. Jack
these are my little girls...
This heres Alma Jr. and Jenny
Hey
- Say hi, girls
- Hi
I got your card that
the divorce came through
Yeah
So, here I am
I had to ask about 10
different people in Riverton
where you had moved to
I guess... I thought
that this means you...
No... Jack...
I don't know what to say...
See, I got the girls
this weekend, and...
Jeez, I...
Im sure as hell sorry...
You know I am
See, I only get em once and
month and... I missed last month...
So I just because
of the round up...
- So, uh well...
- Yeah, all right
Jack
Well, Ill see you next month, then
Comin' up...
Here we go
Here we are!
Whoa there, Rodeo. Stud duck
do the carvin around here
You bet, LD, I was just
savin you the trouble
Bobby? I you dont eat your dinner
Im gonna have to turn
off that television
Why mama? Im gonna be eating
this food for the next two weeks
Hey, you heard your mama
You can finish your meal, and
then you can watch the game
Daddy...
Daddy!
Hell, we dont eat with our eyes!
You want the boy to grow up to
be a man, dont you, daughter?
Boys should watch football
Like Hell. Not until he
finishes eating the meal...
that his mama took
three hours fixin
You sit down, you
old son-of-a-bitch!
This is my house, this is my
child and you are my guest
Now you sit down before I knock
your ignorant ass into next week
Daddy... tell about when
you rode broncs in the rodeo
Well... thats a short story honey
I t was only about 3
seconds I was on that bronc
Next thing I knew, I was
flyin through the air
Only I was no angel
like you and Jenny, here
I didnt have no wings
And thats the story of...
my saddle bronc career
There you go
You oughta get married again, Ennis
Me and the girls worry
about you bein alone so much
Hm Well, once burned
You still go fishin
with Jack Twist?
Not often
You know, I used to wonder how come
you never brought any trouts home
You always said you caught plenty
and you know how me
and the girls like fish
So one night I got
your creell case open...
night before you went on
one of your little trips
Price tag still on
it after five years...
And I tied a note to
the end of the line
It said, Hello Ennis. Bring
some fish home. Love Alma. "
And then you come back...
lookin all perky...
and said you caught a bunch of
brown ones and you ate em all up
Dyou remember?
I looked in that case
first chance I got
and theres my note still tied there...
That line hadnt touched
water in its life!...
That dont mean nothin, Alma
Dont try and fool me no more,
Ennis. I know what it means...
- Jack Twist...
- Alma...
Jack "Nasty". You didnt
go up there to fish, you
Now you listen to me. You
dont know nothin about it...
Ah! Im gonna yell for Monroe
You do it... Ill make
you eat the fuckin floor
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Get out of my house!
Daddy!
Alma!
Bye, Daddy!
Bye!
Hey, asshole, watch
where youre goin!
You stupid fucker!
Goddam
All I'm sayin' is...
...what's the point of making it?
If the tax dont get you, the
inflation will eat it all up
You should see Lureen, punchin
numbers in her addin machine
Hunting for extra zeros... her
eyes gettin' smaller and smaller
It's like watchin a rabbit...
tryin to squeeze into a snake hole
with a coyote on its tail
Thats some high-class
entertainment if you ask me
For what its worth...
You and Lureen
its... normal an all?
Sure
She dont ever suspect?
You ever get the feelin...
...I dont know...
when youre in town and
someone looks at you...
suspicious... like he knows
Then you go out on the pavement
and everyones lookin at you
like they all know, too?
Maybe you oughta get
out of there, you know?
Find yourself some place
different, maybe Texas
Texas?
Sure, and maybe you
can convince Alma
to let you and Lureen
adopt the girls
Then we could just live
together, herdin' sheep
And itll rain money
from LD Newsome...
and whisky will flow in the
stream... Jack, thats real smart...
Go to hell, Ennis Del Mar...
You wanna live your miserable
fuckin life? Then go right ahead
- Fine
- I was just thinkin out loud...
Yup, youre a real thinker, there
Goddam...
Jack fuckin Twist.
Got it all figured out, aint ya?
All right, hon...
Just finished my shift...
Wanna dance?
Well, I was on my way to
- Im Cassie, Cassie Farrah
Ennis... Del Mar
No more dancin for me, I hope
Youre safe. My feet hurt...
Its hard work, is it?
Yeah!
Drunks like you, demanding
beer after beer...
smokin'... Gets tiresome
What do you do, Ennis Del Mar?
Well... earlier today
I was castrating calves
What are you doin?
Tryin to get a foot rub, dummy
All right...
- That good?
- Mm-uhm
And then I pledged
Tri-Delt at SMU...
And I sure never thought
Id end up in a poky
little place like Childress
Then I met old Randall
here at an Aggie game...
He was an animal husbandry major
So we've been here for a month
and he got the foreman job
over at Roy Taylor's ranch
Like it or not, here I am!...
Was you Tri-Delt?
I was Kappa Phi myself...
Well, even though we aint
quite sorority sisters
we just may have to dance
with ourselves, Lureen!
Our husbands aint the least
bit interested in dancin!
They aint got a smidgen
of rhythm between em
Its funny, isnt it!
Husbands dont never seem to
want dance with their wives
Why do you think that is, Jack?
I don't know, I never
give it any thought
Wanna dance?
Yes! Thank you!
- Do you mind?
- No, it's all right. Go ahead...
Pardon us...
Thank you for asking
me to dance with you
I really appreciate that.
Randall never does
Its a good thing you and Lureen
happened along when you did...
or else wed still be stuck
on the side of the road
in that darn pick-up...
I told Randall we
oughta take the car
Of course, hed never listen to me!
He wouldn't listen to me if
he was goin' deaf tomorrow
I told him it'd take
more than chewing gum...
and baling wire to fix that pickup
Well... hes never been
very mechanical, though
- Come over here and ask...
- All right...
You ever notice how a
woman will powder her nose
before she goes to a party?
And then shell powder it
again once the partys over?
Why powder your nose just
to go home and go to bed?
I dont know...
Even if I wanted to know
I couldnt get a word in with
Lashawn long enough to ask!
- That woman talks a blue streak
- A lively little gal...
Youll like workin
for Roy Taylor...
- Hes solid, Roy
- Oh yeah, Roy, hes a good old boy
Hes got a little...
cabin, down on Lake Kemp
Got a crop house, a little boat...
Said I could use it whenever I want
We oughta go down
there some weekend
Drink a little whisky...
fish some...
Get away... you know?
That was right out of SMU
I could've had my pick of pretty
much any job in North Dallas
So my pick was Neiman
Marcus, which was a disaster
cause honey, where clothes is
concerned, I got no resistence
I was spendin more than I made.
More than Randall ever will make!
We come out here thinking that ranchin
was still big hats and Marlboros
Boy, were we behind the times!
Hey there, Junior? You ready?
What do you think?
Your daddy ever gonna see
fit to settle down again?
I dont know...
Maybe hes not the marryin kind...
You dont think so? Or you
dont think Im the one for him?
Youre good enough
You dont say much but
you get your point across
Sorry, didnt mean to be rude
Hi
Ah! Youre stayin
on your feet, cowboy
Excuse me darlin
So Ill pick you and Jenny
up next weekend, after church
Fine
You all right?
Yes
Are you sure?
Daddy, I was thinkin...
what with a new baby and all...
Ma and Monroe have
been awful strict on me
More on me than Jenny, even
I was thinkin... maybe I could...
maybe I could come
and stay with you
Id be an awful good
help, I know I would...
Well, I... You know
I aint set up for that
With the round-up comin...
I wont ever be home
Its all right, daddy
- Im not sayin I wouldnt...
- Its all right, I understand
All right, well,
Ill see you on Sunday, then
Bye
Bye, sweetheart
Going to snow tonight for sure
Yep
All this time, you aint
found nobody else to marry?
I've been puttin the blocks
to a good lookin little
gal over in Riverton
She's a waitress... wants to
go to nursin school or somethin...
I dont know...
What about you and Lureen?
Lureens good at making hard
deals in the machinery business
but as far as our marriage goes
...we could do it over the phone
I kind of got this thing with...
the ranch foremans
wife over in Childress
Im scared Ill get shot
by Lureen or her husband...
each time I slip off to see her
You probably deserve it
Tell you what...
the truth is...
sometimes I miss you so
much I can hardly stand it
I guess Ill head up
on to Lightning Flat...
see the folks for a day or two
There is somethin I been
meanin to tell you, bud
Well, its likely November
before I can come out here again
After we shift stock and...
before winter feedin starts again
November...
Well, what in the hell
ever happened to August?
Christ, Ennis...
You know, you had a fuckin week
to say some little word about this
Why is it were always
in the friggin cold?
We oughta go south, where its warm
You know, we oughta go to Mexico!
Mexico?
Hell Jack, you know me. About
the only travellin I ever done
is around a coffee pot
lookin for the handle
Come on Jack, lighten up on me
We can hunt in November...
Kill us a nice elk...
Ill try if I can get
Don Wroes cabin again
We had a good time
that year, didnt we?
There's never enough
time, never enough
You know, friend...
this is a Goddam bitch of
an unsatisfactory situation
You used to come away easy.
Now its like seein the Pope
Jack, I got to work...
Huh?
I mean, in them earlier
days Id just quit the job
You
you forget what its like
bein broke all the time
You ever hear of child support?
I tell you this, I cant quit this
one... and I cant get the time off
Its hard enough gettin this
time. The trade-off is August
You got a better idea?
I did, once
You did, once
Have you been in Mexico, Jack Twist?
Cause I hear what they got
in Mexico for boys like you
Hell yes, Ive been in Mexico.
Is that a fuckin problem?
Im gonna tell you this
one time, Jack fuckin Twist
And I aint foolin...
What I dont know, all them
things that I dont know...
...I could get you killed
if I come to know them
I aint jokin
Well try this one...
and Ill say it just once...
Go ahead...
I tell you what...
we could had a good life
together, fuckin real good life
Had us a place of our own...
But you didnt want it, Ennis!...
So what we got now
is Brokeback Mountain!
Everythings built on that!
Thats all we got, boy...
Fuckin all! So I hope you know that,
if you don't never know the rest!
- God damn it...
- You count the damn few times...
that we have been together
in nearly 20 years
and you measure the short
fuckin leash you keep me on...
and then you ask me about Mexico
And then you tell me you
kill me for needin something
that I dont hardly never get
You have no idea how bad it gets...
And Im not you. I cant...
...make it on a couple
of high-altitude fucks
once or twice a year...
You are too much for me, Ennis...
Son of a horsin bitch...
I wish I knew how to quit you...
Well, why dont you?
Why dont you just let me be, huh?
Its because of you,
Jack, that Im like this...
Im nothin... Im nowhere...
Get the fuck off me!
Its all right, its all right...
Damn you, Ennis...
I just cant stand
this any more, Jack
And now youre sleepin
on your feet like a horse...
My mom used to say that
to me when I was little
And sing to me...
I gotta go
See you in the mornin...
Excuse me...
Hey! Ennis Del Mar...
Where you been?
Here and there...
I left word for you, with
Steve, at the ranch...
But you must've got those
notes I left at your place...
Looks like I got the
message in any case
Carl?
Yeah, Carls nice...
He even talks...
Good for you...
Yeah...
Good for me...
I dont get you, Ennis Del Mar...
Im sorry...
I was probably no
fun anyways, was I?
Ennis, girls dont
fall in love with fun...
Jack, how about November 7 for
you? I can meet you at pine creek
DECEASED
Hello...
Hello, this is... Ennis Del Mar...
Eh...
Who?
- Who is this?
- Ennis Del Mar
An old buddy of Jacks
Jack used to mention you...
Youre the fishin buddy
or the huntin buddy, I know that
Would have let you know
what happened but...
I wasnt sure about
your name or address
Jack kept his friends
addresses in his head
Thats what Im callin...
to see what happened
Oh, yeah...
Jack was pumpin up a flat on
the truck out on the back road
when the tyre blew up
The rim of the tyre slammed into
his face... broke his nose and jaw..
...and knocked him
unconscious on his back
By the time somebody come along
he had drowned in his own blood
He was only 39 years old...
Hello?
Hello!
Was he buried down there?
We put a stone up
He was cremated, like he wanted.
Half his ashes was interred here
...the rest was sent
up with his folks
He used to say he wanted his ashes
scattered on Brokeback Mountain
But I wasnt sure where that was
Thought Brokeback Mountain
might be around where he grew up
Knowin Jack...
it might be some pretend place
where bluebirds sing, and
theres a whisky spring
No, maam, we was... herdin
sheep on Brokeback one summer.
Back in 1963...
Well... he said it was
his favourite place
I thought he meant to
get drunk. He drank a lot
Is his folks still...
up in Lightning Flat?
Theyll be there
till the day they die...
Thank you for your time
I sure am sorry...
We was good friends.
Get in touch with his folks.
I suppose theyd appreciate it
if his wishes was carried out...
About the ashes, I mean...
Want a cup of coffee, dont
you? Piece of cherry cake?
Yes, ma'am, I'll have
a cup of coffee but...
but I can't eat no cake just now
I feel awful bad about Jack
Thank you
I cant begin to tell
you how bad I feel
I knew him a long time
I come by to say...
if you want me to take his
ashes up there on Brokeback...
...like his wife said he wanted to
...then Id be happy to
Tell you what...
I know where
Brokeback Mountain is...
Thought he was too goddam special
to be buried in the family plot
Jack used to say
"Ennis Del Mar"... he used to say...
"Im gonna bring him up
here one of these days... "
"... and well lick this
damn ranch into shape"
He had some half-baked notion the
two of you was gonna move up here
...build a cabin...
...help run the place
Then this spring...
he got another fella gonna
come up here with him...
...build the place...
help run the ranch
Some ranch neighbour of
his from down in Texas...
Gonna split up with his
wife and come back here...
so he says...
But, like most of Jacks ideas...
never come to pass...
I kept his room... like
it was when he was a boy
I think he appreciated that
You are welcome to go up
to his room, if you want...
Yeah, Id like that, thank you...
Tell you what...
we got a family
plot. Hes goin in it
Yes, sir...
Youll come back and see us again...
Thank you... ma'am
- Hey there, Junior
- Hey, daddy
Come here
- Like the car?
- Yeah, is it yours?
Its Kurts
I thought you were seein Troy?
Troy? Daddy that was 2 years ago
- Troy still playin baseball?
- I dont know what hes doin
Im seein Kurt, now...
- Well, what does Kurt do?
- Works out on the oil fields
- So hes a roughneck, huh?
- Yeah
I guess youre 19
you can do whatever you
want. Isn't that right?
Sure...
Daddy, you need more furniture...
Yeah, well... if you got
nothin', you dont need nothin
So, whats the occasion?
Me and Kurt...
were gettin married
Well...
How long you
known this guy for?
About a year...
The weddingll be June 5th
at the Methodist church
Jenny will be singing and...
Monroes gonna cater the reception
Now this Kurt fella...
...he loves you?
Yeah, daddy...
he loves me
Was hopin youd be there
Yeah...
I think Im supposed to be... on
a round-up down near the Tetons
You know what?...
I reckon they can find
themselves a new cowboy...
My little girl... is getting married...
To Alma and Kurt!
Jack, I swear...