Hey! Come on.
Let's move!
No!
- Let me see.
- No!
Come on. I made you
a special breakfast.
You can't cook.
Hey, Mary, open up!
You look beautiful.
I look like a Disney character.
Where's the "special"?
The what?
You said you made me
a special breakfast.
Please don't make me go.
You can keep homeschooling me.
I've taught you
everything I know.
But I don't wanna go.
Well, I don't wanna go
to work, but I do.
You don't go to work.
You fix the boats on a dock.
Okay. It's a poor example,
but you're still going.
But what about Fred?
What about him?
You won't
take care of him.
You don't like cats.
I don't like two-eyed cats.
Fred, as you know,
is monocular.
Who's gonna throw him
his ping pong ball?
Fred's gonna be fine.
No more argument, okay?
We've discussed this
ad nauseam.
What's ad nauseam?
Oh, you don't know?
Well, looks like
someone needs school.
This is gonna be fun.
You're gonna meet kids today
you can borrow money from
the rest of your life.
Come on.
You're gonna be great.
You know, just...
I don't know. Try bein' a kid.
Mmm-mmm.
Frank!
Frank, I know you hear me.
There's still time
for you to undo this nonsense.
Go get in your car
and go get that child.
Are you technically allowed to
use those keys
whenever you want?
How can you stand there...
acting all calm
and everything, Frank,
and make light of this?
Now go get her back
before it's too late.
She gotta get out
in the world.
She has no friends her age.
No social skills.
She doesn't know
how to be a kid.
Two nights ago,
she told me
that even if Germany
bails out the euro...
there could still be
a worldwide depression.
I was staring at the ceiling
for three hours.
I'm so worried.
Come on, Roberta.
If you start crying,
I'm gonna have to
pretend to start crying.
Hey.
You know, there's something
you could be overlookin'.
This could work out.
Maybe.
But if anybody takes
that baby away...
I'll smother you
in your sleep.
Morning, Fred.
One plus one is two.
That is fact number one
of today.
Who can tell me
what two plus two is?
Who's got it?
- Mmm-hmm?
- Four.
Excellent, Donna.
It is. Two plus two is,
indeed, four.
Okay, who wants to try
three plus three?
Three plus three? Really?
I beg your pardon?
What kinda school
is this anyway?
It's the kind of school
where students don't speak
without permission.
All right.
But everyone knows it's six.
Nobody in this classroom
speaks...
unless they are called upon.
Okay? Is everybody clear
on that?
Yes, ma'am.
Good. Mary, can you
stand up please?
Stand on up. Stand up, babe.
These questions are for you
because you're so advanced.
What is nine plus eight?
17.
Yeah. Yes, it is.
That's good.
What is...
15 plus 17?
32.
Yeah. That is right.
All right, then.
Well, what is 57 plus 135?
192.
Yeah.
Can you tell me...
what 57 multiplied by 135 is?
Okay.
Who can tell me what four...
7,695.
I don't think
anyone can do that.
The square root is 87.7.
And change.
Now what does ad nauseam mean?
I have a very strange kid.
I have 27 strange kids.
Good morning.
Good morning, good morning,
good morning.
That's great, guys,
but take your seats, okay?
Oh, God. See ya.
Good morning, Ms. Stevenson.
Good morning.
Mind if I sit in?
Not at all!
Okay, class.
I have a treat for you.
I would like to introduce you
to our principal, Mrs. Davis.
Good morning, first graders.
Good morning, Mrs. Davis.
Are you ready
for a great year?
Yes!
Uh... Yes, Mary?
She's the boss?
Mrs. Davis is our principal.
Mm-kay...
Okay. Now I want you
to get on your phone
and call Frank...
and tell him to
get me out of here!
Wait a minute.
That's the dad? I know him.
I see him at Ferg's
almost every Friday night.
He's the quiet,
damaged hot guy.
What are you doing at Ferg's
every Friday night?
Trying to get picked up
by him.
Excuse me? Hi.
Oh. Look, it's my teacher.
Probably wants to remind me
what one plus one is.
Go to the car, okay?
- Hi.
Sorry to yell at you
and then chase you down.
It's okay. Mary's teacher?
Yes. I'm Bonnie Stevenson.
Frank. How are you?
Sorry about today.
I know she got
a little overexcited.
I think
it's just first day jitters.
Sure. Yeah.
We're running a little late
actually. We gotta get going.
Okay. I don't even wanna
talk about that.
- I'll keep you just a minute.
- Okay.
I think your daughter...
I think Mary might be gifted.
What?
Yeah. Today in Math,
she answered some really...
- Oh, no, no, no. That's...
- No, please.
- It's not gifted.
- Really difficult questions.
All right.
Just that
a seven-year-old would...
It's Trachtenberg.
- Jakow Trachtenberg.
- I'm sorry?
Spent seven years
in a Nazi concentration camp.
Developed a system
to rapidly solve problems.
It's the Trachtenberg method.
But she's...
I mean, she's seven though.
I learned it when I was eight.
Do I look gifted to you?
It's kind of gone out of vogue
since the invention
of the calculator...
but, uh, I can still win
a drink at a bar using it.
Sorry for today.
- Won't happen again.
- Okay.
Nice to meet you. Bonnie.
Frank.
Hmm.
For the record,
I didn't wanna go
to the stupid school
in the first place.
And the boy in the next row
acts inappropriately
for someone who's a child.
I'm sorry. I'm still passive
aggressively ignoring you.
Other kids answer questions.
They don't get into trouble.
You didn't get in trouble
for answering questions.
You yelled at the principal.
You know what? You're gonna
find this interesting.
So, I googled "first graders
who yell at the principal..."
and statistically,
you're never gonna
believe how many kids do it.
How many?
None.
Frank, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, right.
You can't show off
like that at school.
I know.
You promised you wouldn't,
then the first day...
I know, I know. I screwed up.
Do you think maybe
this boat needs a test ride?
Go get Fred.
Don't run.
I listen to the wind
To the wind of my soul
Where I'll end up
Well, I think
Only God really knows
I've sat upon the setting sun
But never, never, never, never
I never wanted water once
No, never, never, never
Fred loves to watch
the sandpipers.
He thinks he'd like to
catch one...
but he'd regret it.
Fred's not a killer.
He's a lover.
Would my mom have wanted me
to go to this school?
I can only guess.
But I'll tell you what,
she would have wanted you
to have friends.
Idiot friends?
And she'd want you to have
compassion for others.
Like a cat can have
for a sandpiper.
But what if
they don't like me?
Then they're idiots.
Good morning, class.
Good morning, Ms. Stevenson.
Good morning, Mary.
Okay, good morning.
Get a hold of yourself.
For my Show and Tell,
I have...
the most awesome cat
in the history of time.
Not only
is his name Fred, but...
He has just one eye.
Uno. Go ahead and count...
but I promise you,
it's always one.
How did he lose his eye?
I don't know. I wasn't there.
Just found him
inside of a trash can
next to a bottle of alcohol
or something.
He is a smart, smart cat,
but no one realizes that.
No one understands him.
No one.
Put your name
on the top of the paper...
so that I know
who did such good work.
I left my pen with you.
Pass those around, guys.
Okay? I wanna see your work.
Turn around, face the desk.
Think about
how you get to the answer.
It's not just about,
you know, guessing.
Don't be messy.
Done.
Let's see.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. I thought
you might finish quickly,
so a little something extra.
Done.
Oh...
Do you know who I am?
Hey! Mary's teacher...
Bonnie.
You lied to me.
Okay.
- Can you narrow it down?
- Mmm-hmm.
I'd like to know the truth
about Mary, my student...
your niece.
I was running
ridiculously late for a date...
and my sister showed up
with Mary.
And she never just
showed up unannounced.
She never showed up
with the baby.
She said she wanted to talk.
She said she needed to talk.
I told her I would talk to her
when I got back.
I think I figured showing up
that late to my date...
would hurt my chances
of gettin' laid.
Came home that night
and Mary was on the couch...
and found Diane
on the bathroom floor.
I mean, there's no way
I coulda known...
but I shoulda known.
Six and a half years later,
me and Mary
are still hangin' out.
And what about the father?
Diane was
so socially awkward...
she didn't date enough to know
a good guy from a bad guy.
This particular guy
didn't last a month.
And no grandparents?
- Dad died when I was eight.
- My mom...
Short version is
she turned her back on Diane
when she got pregnant.
Why?
Didn't fit into her plan.
She's an exacting woman,
my mother.
Uncompromising.
Very British.
Do you mean,
British in demeanor or...
- No. Like she's...
- She's from England.
From England. Yeah.
So, Mary is a genius?
Oh!
Look out. Look out.
Your little animals
are escaping, dumbass.
Hey! You should not
be laughing!
You did a mean thing
to a little kid!
What are you gonna do
about it?
Hey. Hey, you okay?
You good? All right.
How do we resolve this?
You know,
she could be expelled.
God. I hope not.
But if every other first-time
offender was expelled,
I guess fair is fair.
Are you gonna
take this seriously?
Sure. You don't bluff me,
I don't bluff you.
Ms. Stevenson believes
that your child
is exceptional...
and has talents
that our curriculum
can't begin to challenge.
It just so happens
that I am good friends
with the headmaster
of the Oaks Academy
for Gifted Education.
He has always said
that if I find
that one in a million...
And the one in a million
has a $30,000 tuition.
Mr. Adler, I can get
your daughter a scholarship.
Full ride.
I wouldn't say it
if I couldn't do it.
I realize, putting that girl
in that setting,
you know, 99 times out of
a 100, that's what you do.
It's the Oaks.
It's a great school.
I looked into it.
But this family has a history
with those schools.
And I think the last thing
that little girl needs
is reinforcement
that she's different.
Trust me, she knows. So...
I think Mary,
I think she's gotta be here.
Today's a bad ending.
You can't hit people.
But a 12-year-old
bullies a seven-year-old
and she stands up?
Do you know how important
it is to me that she did that?
You know how proud I am
of her? Aren't you?
Mr. Adler, your daughter
shattered a young boy's...
I know. You can't hit people.
That will be made very clear.
I get that.
But Mrs. Davis,
if we separate our leaders,
if we segregate them
from people like you and me,
you get congressmen.
So, I'm sorry.
I wish I could take
your offer, but Mary stays.
Unless you kick her out.
This is a mistake. We'll never
be able to raise this child
to the level of scholarship
she deserves.
Well, just dumb her down
into a decent human being.
Everybody wins.
You know what?
Can you excuse me one minute?
Bring me
every piece of paperwork
we have on this girl.
Hey.
Are you sure
you know what you're doing?
No.
Okay. Mary, I think
you have something you'd like
to say to the class.
You wanna hop up and say it?
Okay. I'm supposed to
say something.
Hitting people is wrong
even if they're bad.
I won't do it again,
so don't be afraid of me.
Okay. Thank you.
Now can I say something
I wanna say?
Sure.
Before they ruined it,
Justin's zoo
was the best art project.
By far. It was awesome.
Come on. A little harder.
Okay.
Thank you. Thank you.
There's a lady standing
in front of our door.
Who is it?
How should I know? I'm seven.
That would be
your grandmother.
Holy shit!
An Apple? Whoa.
It's a MacBook, darling.
Top of the line
with the Retina Display.
Hey, you know who else
has a Retina Display?
Fred!
Mary, I understand
you like mathematics.
So, on there,
you'll find a great
out-of-print book
by Charles Zimmer
called Transitions
in Advanced Algebra.
Yeah. Love that book.
You're saying you've read it?
Yeah. I've kind of moved on
to differential equations now.
Don't forget your manners.
Thank your grandma.
Thank you, Grandma.
Grandmother or Evelyn
will do just fine.
There's so much more on there.
Things I know you'll find
really challenging.
Yes. But sadly,
it's a school night
and there's homework to do.
What a surprise though, right?
Say good night
to Grandmother or Evelyn.
Good night.
I'd kill a priest
for a Benadryl.
Still with the allergies?
Why in God's name
have you got a cat?
You don't even like cats.
It's not my cat.
It's Mary's cat.
I'm just along for the ride.
So let me guess.
Our lovely principal,
Ms. Davis.
Never get on the bad side
of small-minded people
who have a little authority.
I thought I taught you that.
What are you doin' here?
You don't think
I have the right
to see my granddaughter?
I do. I'm thrilled your
seven-year exhaustive search
has finally come
to a fruitful conclusion.
I don't think this is
an appropriate time to talk.
Certainly not the setting.
While I was waiting,
a cockroach this big
tried to steal my shoe.
Yeah. They'll take a shoe.
Honestly, this?
This godforsaken mosquito
ranch was a conscious choice?
I could drop you back off
at the airport.
This thing is loaded
with cool problems.
So, are you teaching?
I repair boats.
- Please.
- I'm not bad at it either.
Well, then,
that explains this.
They don't sell
sunscreen here?
I wear sunscreen.
Not enough.
And you need a hat.
A big hat that shades
your face and neck.
You're playing Russian
roulette with your skin.
You look like a porn producer.
Okay. I appreciate the advice.
I do.
But we're not here to talk
about sunscreen, are we?
Oh, so no more small talk?
That's a shame.
Okay. The environment you have
created for that child
where she lives,
the school she attends,
it's substandard,
every bit of it.
I disagree.
We're getting nowhere
if we're not gonna be honest
with each other.
I am being honest.
I see. Fine. Well, I'm not
leaving without her.
Well, welcome to Florida.
Frank, please listen
to reason.
At some point, either you're
gonna come to the conclusion,
or someone in authority
is going to spell it out
for you
that the child's best interest
is all that matters.
You're gonna make me
pull rank, I will.
Diane didn't want you
to have her.
Diane...
Diane didn't always
think things through.
Arguably one of the brightest
minds on the planet.
Good luck
going down that road.
And what do you think
she'd say
if she saw
how her child is living now?
Do you honestly think
she'd be pleased?
That she's living a somewhat
normal life? Yes. I do.
She's not normal.
And treating her as such...
is negligence
on a grand scale.
I know your heart's
in the right place on this.
But you are denying the girl
her potential. You are.
I can provide for her,
I can enrich her life.
Oh, come on, Evelyn.
You're gonna take that girl,
you're gonna bury her
in tutors...
then you're gonna loan her
out to some think tank...
where she can talk
non-trivial zeros...
with a bunch of old Russian
guys for the rest of her life.
And you'd bury her
under a rock.
Look, I don't expect you
to understand
the price you have to pay
for greatness.
Oh, I do. That's why I have
Mary in the first place.
That's uncalled for.
Your sister had
a laundry list of problems.
She could have solved
Navier-Stokes
and gone down in history...
as one of the greatest
mathematicians of all time.
But she didn't because
she couldn't finish.
She was weak.
Weak like her father
and weak like...
Well...
Now, if it's who I think
it is...
Kinda puts a black cloud
over our luncheon.
You're still stubborn
and vindictive.
Careful, Mother.
There's an apple and tree
analogy lurking.
You guys ready to order?
Here's an idea.
Stop thinking about me
and you...
and start thinking about
what's best for the child.
For any reasonable person,
a clear picture will emerge.
If it doesn't, I suggest
you call your attorney.
He'll have the bucket of beer.
Hey, let's go outside.
No.
Come on. It's nice out.
I don't care.
Hey, no more math today.
Is there a God?
I don't know.
Just tell me.
I would if I could.
But I don't know.
And neither does anybody else.
Roberta knows.
No.
Roberta has faith
and that's a great thing
to have.
But faith's about
what you think, feel.
Not what you know.
What about Jesus?
Love that guy.
Do what he says.
But is he God?
I don't know.
I have an opinion.
But that's my opinion.
I could be wrong.
So why would I screw up yours?
Use your head.
But don't be afraid
to believe in things either.
Huh.
There was a guy on TV
who said there was no God.
The only difference
between the atheists on TV
and Roberta...
is that Roberta loves you.
She's trying to help.
Tell you what though.
One way or another,
we all end up back together
in the end.
That's what
you're asking, right?
Yep.
Okay.
Find something else
to worry about, will you?
All right.
Okay. Adler,
grandmother and uncle.
Really?
You sure you folks
don't wanna go out
in the hallway
and settle this?
No? Well, that's a shame.
Mr. Cullen, you are here
for the uncle.
Yes, sir, Your Honor.
Start charging you room
and board.
Mr. Highsmith,
you're on the wrong side
of the bay, aren't you?
I'm very happy
to be here, Your Honor.
For the record,
Mrs. Dibbons
is representing
the State of Florida
Child Welfare Department.
Proceed.
Your Honor,
my client, Mrs. Adler
is the maternal grandmother
of the child.
Her daughter,
the girl's mother,
was a troubled woman...
who seven years ago,
sadly, took her own life.
It was at this time
that Mr. Adler
preemptively and illegally...
took custody of the girl
and spirited her
across state lines...
for the purpose
of denying my client custody.
Now, there is evidence that
the child currently lives...
in unclean
and unwholesome conditions.
We petition the court
to grant my client
full custody of the child...
so that she may be returned
to the state
of Massachusetts...
and given the care
to which she is entitled.
My client took an infant under
his wing for one reason only.
It was his sister's desire
that he do so.
My client has been
her constant caregiver.
And, Your Honor, as far as
the living conditions...
I've been in this home.
It's fine.
I mean, if we adopt standards
based on...
our northern friend's
aversion to palmetto bugs...
we won't have a child left
south of Tallahassee.
All right. Last chance
before this starts
costing a lot more money.
Your Honor,
my client would need
reasonable access
to the child.
So ordered.
Ms. Dibbons,
you'll go over there
and check out
the living conditions?
On the books, Your Honor.
All right, folks.
Drive carefully.
Her lawyer has a nice suit.
Relax, Frank. More weight's
put on the talent competition.
Go have a cocktail, hmm?
Roberta, would you
like to have Mary tonight?
Why wouldn't I like
to have Mary tonight?
I told you something like this
would happen.
Now look where we are.
And I'm supposed to believe
you know what you're doing.
You couldn't even find
a white lawyer.
Wow. Look, just...
- Don't worry, okay?
- Don't tell me that.
There's nothing you can say
that's gonna make me
feel good...
because I have no say
in any of this, Frank.
I'm not a blood relative,
I'm not a legal guardian.
I'm nothing!
Just the lady
who lives next door,
whose opinion means nothing...
whose feelings mean nothing.
Would I like to have
Mary tonight?
I'd like to have Mary
every night.
Can't stop me now
Hear what I say
My feets gotta move, so...
Get out of my way
I'm gonna have my say
I'm going to every discotheque
I'm gonna dance, dance, dance
Whoo!
Till the break of day
Oh, shame, shame, shame, shame
Oh!
Shame on you
If you can't dance too
And I said shame, shame,
shame, shame
Shame, shame, shame
Shame on you
Hi.
Um, I heard Davis bragging
about a custody case
and then I found out whose...
I feel terrible.
But I also wanted you to know
that after we talked...
I didn't say anything
to anyone.
I swear.
And it's, um, important to me
that you know that.
I know.
Okay.
My lawyer told me
to get drunk.
And you're trying to do it
with that?
Okay. My turn.
Who was your first
celebrity crush?
Um, I'll go with...
Mona from Who's the Boss?
Oh, wow!
You know
who I'm talking about?
- The sexy grandmother.
- Yeah!
I always felt like
she had a secret.
Yeah, which is that
she loved sexual intercourse.
That was it.
And she wasn't secret
about it.
That's why I liked her.
You know what?
I liked her, too.
See?
All right. Um...
Least favorite student.
And why.
Oh, no!
I love all my students.
I don't believe you.
At all! Not for a second.
No, they're all great.
They're all so great.
I'm gonna go ahead and drink.
Let's keep this honest.
He? She?
Uh, he is Ronnie Middleton.
Sounds like a dick.
- He's a little child, okay?
- I'm sorry.
The point is that he's evil
in his core.
And there's nothing I can do.
Wow.
What's your greatest fear?
Wow!
That's a change of tone.
Yup, I'm a really
serious person.
Okay.
Look, if it's too much, you
can just drink your drink...
and live with the fact
that you're afraid.
No, I can handle this. Um...
That I'll ruin Mary's life.
You're very, um...
surprising, Mary's teacher.
Very much so.
- Okay. Hold on. I'm sorry.
- What?
Just so that...
I feel like
I need to say this...
just so that
there's no misconception.
Oh, God. No, I didn't...
No, hold on!
That this can't,
isn't happening.
I get it. I know.
I'm with you.
- Yeah? Okay.
- 100%. We're on the same page.
Good!
No, that's great. I'm sorry.
That's embarrassing.
It's okay. I get it.
Oh!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Okay. Good.
Can you promise
that there's no way?
Yes. Roberta has Mary
every Saturday till noon,
I promise.
- Yeah?
- Mmm-hmm.
Mmm. Mmm-mmm. Sorry.
I can't do this.
Okay.
I understand.
I'll take you home.
Yeah.
Sorry, just... One more time.
I can't find my DVD.
It's right there, baby.
No, it isn't.
You come and find it.
I'm doing lady business.
Now, you were the last person
to watch it.
What did you do with it?
Oh...
Oh! Oh, my God!
Good morning, Miss Stevenson.
Hi.
Look, I am...
Oh, you know what?
I'm actually incapable...
of having
this conversation right now.
Good. 'Cause I have no idea
what I was gonna say.
Great! Perfect!
Sir, if you please.
Take me to jail.
Awkward.
Mary...
Stop! Stop!
Stop with the Legos! Listen.
Do we have a rule
about Saturday morning?
What?
Are you allowed
in this apartment this early
on Saturday morning?
Yes or no?
- No.
- No!
Are you allowed to... Hey!
Stop! Enough with the Legos.
Are you allowed to
use Roberta's keys?
- No.
- No!
Hey! Look at me.
Then why are you here, huh?
Can you answer me that?
You broke every rule!
You just embarrassed me.
We have these rules.
We've gone over them
a hundred times! Ahh!
God!
Damn it!
Can I just get five minutes
of my own life?
Nothing that happened today
was your fault.
I got mad at you...
I was really mad at me.
And the manufacturers
of Legos,
they should all be in prison.
I'm sorry.
Do you forgive me?
Sure. Whatever.
Hey, close the laptop.
Come on.
Please. Doesn't count
if it's not eye to eye.
Come on, please.
Do you really have no life
because of me?
That's not what I said.
Hmm.
Did you mean it?
Last month you said I was
the worst uncle
in the world...
and you wished death upon me
'cause I didn't buy you
a piano.
Did you mean that?
No.
Not entirely.
There you go.
We say things all the time
we don't mean. So...
Let's forget it, okay?
Okay.
Frank?
Yeah?
Can I have a piano?
No.
Was that really Mary's teacher
this morning?
You know, I got a book called
Fundamentals of
Decision Making.
You can borrow it.
What is it?
It's nothing.
Looks like Mary gets to go
to Boston for a couple days.
It's just two days.
Relax.
So, what do you think?
Cool.
Wow! You and my mom...
were always together.
Always.
Oh, no, you don't want
to look at that one.
Is that you?
Yes.
How old were you?
29.
Where is this?
That's Cambridge University.
In England.
Who are those people?
My research colleagues.
For what?
Mathematics, of course.
Really?
Cool!
So, then you came to work...
at a college in America?
No.
I married your grandfather...
and I came back
to America with him.
And I had children.
Oh.
So, no more math?
It's late.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
Come on. Up, up, up.
Can I play the piano?
No, you can't.
- Now stop dragging those feet.
- But, it's fun!
Come on!
I have had
a series of nightmares...
where I'm fired...
because of what happened.
You get it?
And then I try
to rationalize...
that everything that happened
was just all alcohol.
I have an addiction
to fixer guys.
Dr. Shankland,
this problem is...
I know. Just copy it exactly
as you see it written.
But it's...
Exactly as written. Thank you.
So, what's this problem
I'm supposed to look at?
I don't know.
Is it like the problems
Mom worked on?
Your mother didn't work
on problems.
She worked on
just one problem.
Just one?
Her entire life?
Most of it.
Look.
These are
the Millennium Problems.
Seven great
and meaningful problems.
Some mathematicians
have worked
their entire lives
to prove them.
Who's the dude with the beard?
That's not a dude.
That's Grigori Perelman.
He proved
the Poincaré conjecture.
The only one
of the seven proved.
This...
This is your mother's problem.
Na... vi...
Navier-Stokes.
No picture.
- She didn't solve it?
- No.
She was close.
She would have won
the Fields Medal...
and probably shared a Nobel...
considering what it would have
meant for physics.
Maybe I'll have my picture
up here someday.
If you really desire it...
you can have
your picture there, darling.
I can help you.
It takes focus and hard work,
but if you succeed...
your name will live forever.
Don't be smug, Seymore.
Well, she's had plenty
of time.
She traveled yesterday.
She slept in a strange bed.
Give her a chance.
At six years old,
she read Zimmer.
Outstanding.
How much did she comprehend?
So, Mary...
I see you're looking
at our little problem.
Little? It's big.
Yeah.
Why are you so mad
all of a sudden?
I'm not mad. I'm annoyed.
Not with you, dear.
With that pompous ass,
Shankland.
I knew that guy was gonna
have a beard
before we even went in there.
Math teachers
like to grow beards.
I should never have agreed
to this in the first place.
Did he really expect you
to just walk in
and be able to dissect...
some random, massive problem?
Not much to dissect,
if you ask me.
Why do you say that?
It was wrong.
What?
Well, for starters,
he forgot the negative sign
on the exponent.
It went downhill from there.
The problem was unsolvable.
Maybe this school isn't
as great as you think it is.
Mary, you knew
the problem was incorrect.
Why didn't you say anything?
Frank says I'm not supposed to
correct older people.
Nobody likes a smart-ass.
I'm loaded with swag!
Wanna come inside?
Cat.
Frank,
I think this is stupid.
Why don't we just call Evelyn
and tell her
I don't wanna do this?
Because like I told you,
Evelyn didn't order this.
The court did.
So again,
what are we gonna do?
Tell the truth.
Exactly.
Sooner we answer
these questions,
sooner we get to go home.
So, no attitude, okay?
Okay.
Frank?
Mary.
I like Evelyn.
She looks like my mom.
And she has a piano.
But I don't wanna live
with her.
She's bossy.
I've heard that.
Hey.
Don't worry.
You're not going anywhere.
Promise?
I promise.
Hi, Mary. I'm Pat Golding,
but you can call me Pat
if you like.
Got it.
Do you know why you're here?
I mean has anyone told you
what this is about?
My grandmother wants me
to live with her
and I wanna stay with Frank.
That's correct.
I'm sure this can all be
very scary stuff.
Does any of it worry you?
Nope. Frank says
I'm not goin' anywhere.
Your uncle told you
you're not going anywhere?
Just 15 minutes ago.
So, we done here?
Not quite yet.
My best friend other than
Frank and Fred is Roberta...
who lives
a couple houses away.
Really? What's she like?
She's nice and funny.
And I love her.
That's nice.
Is Roberta your only friend
your age?
Roberta's not my age.
She's like 40, 50...
30-something.
Roberta's a grown woman?
People my age are boring.
Roberta's cool.
Okay.
I don't watch TV.
But I got hooked on SpongeBob.
Mostly because
Roberta loves it.
Oh. And on Saturday nights,
we watch the UFC.
The UFC? Is that...
Is that Ultimate Fighting?
Every Saturday.
You and your uncle watch
Ultimate Fighting?
Well, you don't just watch it.
Frank turns the sound down
and we do the grunting
and voices.
Hmm.
Sometimes I attack Frank
for real.
Which is really fun for me.
I think if you guys
knew Frank,
you'd leave us alone.
He can be pretty annoying...
but he's a good person.
I think.
Why do you say that?
He wanted me
before I was smart.
Mr. Pollard, are you...
the natural father
of Mary Adler?
Yes, I am.
And how can you be
certain of this?
Well, I always knew,
but then you had me...
take a DNA test.
I would offer the test results
as presumptive evidence
that Mr. Pollard...
is the father and natural
guardian of the minor.
As well as an affidavit...
from Mr. Pollard nominating...
Mrs. Adler,
the maternal grandmother,
as the legal guardian
of the minor.
No objections.
Mr. Pollard...
has Mrs. Adler offered you
any monetary reward...
or employment
for coming forward today?
No, sir.
I have a job of my own.
Thank you.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Mr. Pollard...
when was the last time
you saw Mary?
Uh... I've never seen her.
Oh, why not?
By the time
I heard about Diane...
passing...
the baby was gone already.
Well, did you try
and find her?
Best I could.
I couldn't just go
and search the entire country.
Do you use
a computer at work?
Sure.
You know what? Help me out.
Here, let's google
"Mary Adler"
and, uh, see what we find.
You know what?
Uh, you better add
her middle name.
It'll narrow it down.
Eileen.
Yeah. Hit Enter.
Page 2.
Second hit.
Would you please tell
the court what you see there?
It's a newspaper article
called
"Not So Terrible Twos."
And one of them
is Mary Eileen Adler.
Same name as your daughter.
Born on the same day
as your daughter.
With a photograph.
Um, in your defense,
you'd never recognize it...
- Your Honor, this is...
- Your Honor...
if there's one thing here
that's sadly obvious...
it's that Mr. Pollard
has never been
a genuine guardian
of the minor...
and his nomination
of Mrs. Adler
is no less disingenuous.
While the State of Florida
gives deference
to nomination
by a natural parent...
I'm inclined to side
with Mr. Cullen's laptop...
at this time.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Don't gloat.
Wouldn't dream of it.
Walk you to your car?
We've been so preoccupied,
I'm almost ashamed to ask.
How's Walter?
You wouldn't believe it
if I told you.
Why?
Well, your stepfather
is in Montana.
He bought a ranch.
Bullshit.
Exactly. A man whose idea
of roughing it...
is being too far from the ice
machine at the Ritz-Carlton...
now owns a 1,000 acres
of grass and dung.
Walter Price is a cowboy.
Walter Price puts on
a Brooks Brothers suit
to take out the garbage.
He has a cowboy hat
and cowboy boots...
and a horse
that doesn't know dressage.
Is there some
logical reason for this?
Midlife crisis, apparently.
He's 70.
I know.
Must have been on time delay
or something.
I guess I should be happy
it wasn't a 25-year-old
cocktail waitress.
But then again,
an affair you can explain
to friends in a minute.
For this, you put on
a pot of coffee.
And he's out there right now?
Yessiree!
Ridin' the range.
Punchin' doggies.
He had a six gun on his hip...
and a saddlebag
full of Lipitor.
The fastest asset management
in the West.
The man who shot
Liberty Mutual.
That's what I've been
calling him.
That's really, really funny.
Take her to the airport.
Go home, Evelyn.
Or Montana.
Rustle some cattle.
You know...
I have no desire to hurt you.
I hate it that we're at odds.
We're always at odds.
Yes.
Hotel.
Mary, baby,
come on now.
Stop this now.
No.
- Come on out, honey.
- No.
Why did you have to tell her
that deadbeat was testifying?
Because it's the truth.
And if I didn't,
Evelyn would've.
If I was the dad
of a little girl
and I never saw her...
and I was in the same town...
I would visit her.
Well, I hope you're happy.
He didn't even
need directions.
He could've followed you here.
Speaking of men
who aren't worth a damn.
Doesn't even wanna see
what I look like.
All right.
Hey, put your shoes on.
We're going for a ride.
You too.
A ride?
What are we doing here?
Waiting.
We can see that.
Why?
Because I said so.
How long do we have to
stay here?
As long as it takes.
And keep your voice down.
It's a hospital.
- Food's here.
- Yeah, food's here.
It's a boy.
Way to go!
That's exactly how it was
when you were born.
This happy?
This happy.
Who came out
and told everybody?
I did.
Can we stay for another?
Mrs. Adler, in your earlier
testimony, here today...
you've painted a pretty dim
picture of your own son.
Don't you think?
I'm under oath.
I take no pleasure in it.
So, your son's
a failure in life,
your daughter took her life.
You know, you're oh for two.
- Objection!
- Withdrawn.
If I go one for three,
I'm in the Hall of Fame.
You know baseball.
Fenway Park.
You know, I'd like to go there
some time.
How often in a year
did you take Diane
to a baseball game?
Diane wasn't interested
in sports.
She never wanted to go
to a game? Ever?
I don't recall her
ever asking.
Just out of curiosity, Fenway,
that's a tough ticket.
Where do you get yours?
My husband has
season tickets.
And how long has he had them?
30 years.
But I've only been
married to him for 20.
And Diane never went
to one game?
What color was the dress
Diane wore to prom?
Diane didn't attend a prom
because she didn't go
to a high school.
No prom.
What sports did she play?
As I told you earlier,
she wasn't interested
in sports.
Did she go to camp
during the summer?
No.
- Community swimming pool?
- We had our own pool.
- Girl Scouts?
- No.
Then what did she do
with all that time?
She loved mathematics.
It was her passion.
She preferred it
to all other things.
All other?
Mrs. Adler, who's Paul Riva?
He was a boy
from the neighborhood.
Oh, come on.
He was much more than...
just a boy
from the neighborhood.
Paul was Diane's first love...
wasn't he?
I wouldn't characterize it
that way. No.
And how would Diane
characterize it?
Diane was 17 years old
at the time.
She didn't know anything
about love.
Mrs. Adler...
in January of 1998...
didn't Diane and young
Mr. Riva run away together?
He coerced her.
- And where did they go?
- Vermont.
And you called the police,
didn't you?
- Because he kidnapped her?
- Yes. Yes.
And where did the police
find young Mr. Riva and Diane?
I told you. Vermont.
Stowe, Vermont. Wasn't it?
A resort town.
Stowe Mountain.
He took her skiing.
You see,
kidnappers don't usually
take their victims skiing.
But this is what Paul did...
because he and Diane
were in love.
No.
And when they returned,
you pressed
kidnapping charges.
You filed a lawsuit
against his parents...
until Paul stopped
calling Diane.
- Didn't you?
- Yes.
And Diane never heard from
or saw Paul Riva again.
Did she?
Not to my knowledge.
And how did she take it?
She was upset for a while.
She lost focus.
Mrs. Adler,
in March of 1999...
didn't Diane Adler attempt
to take her own life?
This episode was minor.
It was nothing.
I have the hospital report
in my hand.
It was nothing.
Diane was not like
regular people.
She was extraordinary.
And extraordinary people
come with singular issues
and needs.
You have no idea
the capability she possessed.
One in a billion.
And you would say, "Fine,
let's throw that away...
"so the boy who cuts our yard
can make a sexual conquest."
Maybe before you make
that decision,
you stand in my shoes.
I had responsibilities
which went beyond
the mother-daughter
relationship.
The greatest discoveries
which have improved life
on this planet...
have come from minds
rarer than radium.
Without them,
we'd still be crawling in mud.
And for your information,
counselor...
a year after this incident
with this boy...
Diane thanked me
for my intervention.
She realized she'd made
a mistake and she thanked me.
You see, Diane understood
she was accountable
for the gift she'd been given.
And she didn't shy from it.
And I think, if she were
here today, Mr. Attorney...
she would refute
your baseless insinuations...
that she would give up
her brilliant future
and take her own life...
just because Mommy didn't
get her a little red wagon.
No more questions.
Mr. Adler...
where are you
currently employed?
I repair boats.
Oh, really? At which marina?
I don't work at a marina.
I freelance.
So, safe to say,
no health insurance.
No.
About a week before
your sister took her life...
what were you doing
for a living then?
I was a teacher.
You're being
modest, aren't you?
You were a professor
at Boston University...
isn't that right?
Yes, well,
Assistant Professor.
And what'd you teach?
Philosophy.
Truth and logic.
That sort of thing.
Your attorney said
that the primary reason...
that you took Mary is because
it was what your sister...
would have wanted you to do.
Is that the truth?
Yes.
So Diane had visited
Pinellas County before?
No.
Indicated she wanted
her daughter
uprooted and moved here?
- No.
So, you decided to bring
Mary here, didn't you?
Did Diane have a problem
with your health plan
at Boston University?
Not to my knowledge.
Do you think she would want
her daughter
to have access to healthcare?
Of course.
So what do you do,
when little Mary gets sick?
You repair a doctor's boat?
- Objection.
- Sustained.
Mary has been identified...
as a math prodigy.
But her formal math education
under your care...
she's learning at the
first grade level, isn't she?
Yes.
And you turned down
a scholarship at the Oaks...
a school specializing in the
education of gifted children?
Yes.
And Diane,
she'd be fine with that?
I couldn't say.
Prior to Mrs. Adler
giving her one,
did Mary have a computer?
She used mine.
Mr. Adler, does Diane's
daughter have her own bedroom?
No.
Does she sleep
in a bed that you bought...
- in a secondhand shop?
- Yes.
So, the truth is, Mr. Adler,
that you didn't come down here
because your sister
wanted you to...
and you certainly
didn't come here
because it was good for Mary.
No, it was personal.
Diane was a star.
You weren't.
Diane got the attention.
You didn't.
And over the years,
you got angry.
And here comes Mary.
What a great way to get even.
You've uprooted
that little girl
and brought her here
for one reason only.
To do harm to your mother.
You blamed her
for your sister.
No, I don't.
And Mary to you is just a pawn
in all this. Isn't she?
Diane wanted Mary...
to be a kid.
She wanted her to have a life.
She wanted her
to have friends...
and to play...
and to be happy.
Do you realize
the consequences
of boredom for a gifted child,
Mr. Adler?
They become resentful
and sullen.
Mary's not an angry kid.
Really?
Did she not attack a child
on the school bus?
A 12-year-old tripped
a 7-year-old
and she came to his defense.
- Did she break the boy's nose?
- Yes.
On October 16th of last year
were you arrested for assault?
Oh, my God.
You have to answer
the question, Mr. Adler.
A drunk idiot attacked me
and I defended myself.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Did you spend the night
in jail?
Yeah.
You are in way
over your head here.
You're depriving that girl.
You're gambling
with her future...
and now you're being presented
with an opportunity...
to do right by her.
Jump at it.
Does counsel
have a question for my client?
Take the high road,
Mr. Adler...
before she is
irreparably damaged.
Does counsel
have a question...
- for my client or not?
- Yes, sir.
I do have the question.
Tell us, is your
continued guardianship...
really in the best interest
of this little girl?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
I have
no further questions.
Research
and Development...
has come up
with a brand new Fred cheer.
Fred personally asked me
if I would tell you it.
Let's hear it.
S-O-C-K I-T
Sock it to me, Freddy...
Sock it.
Tell R and D,
they got a winner.
That's exactly what I said.
S-O-C-K I-T
Sock it to me, Freddy
They wanna cut a deal.
Highsmith called me
first thing this morning.
Why would he do that?
I don't understand.
In the middle of...
Just listen.
Listen to me, man.
Mary would be put
in a fostering situation.
No.
- Come on, Frank.
- Cullen, I told you no.
It wouldn't be
a court-appointed
foster family, Frank.
- Hey! Drop it!
- We could cherry-pick...
from the cream of the crop.
Mutually approved.
Just hear me out.
Tampa.
I insisted, and they agreed.
No more than a half an hour
from your front door.
Now, she would attend
the Oaks.
It's a great school.
And visiting rights
for the grandmother...
but she was gonna
get that anyway.
Right? And on her
12th birthday, Frank,
she can go back into court...
- No.
- and decide then...
where she wants to live
and with who.
I don't understand this.
I thought you were supposed
to be on my team.
Why are you bringing me
this deal?
Other than
I'm required to by law?
You like this deal?
I love this deal.
They think they're gonna lose.
Yeah.
They do.
You think we're gonna lose.
Yes.
I do, Frank.
I gotta go put my kids to bed.
I'll do whatever
you want me to do.
But if we leave this
up to that judge, Nichols...
he's old school, Frank.
Does he like your mother? No.
Does he like her income?
Does he like her health plan?
Does he like her home?
You better believe it.
I've been in his courtroom.
A hundred times.
And if it's a coin toss...
Look at me.
If it's a coin toss...
that old boy is going to
side with the money.
So, do me a favor, Frank.
Just meet the family.
See how it feels.
It's all I ask.
Fly away, little pretty bird
Fly, fly away...
Pool. Florida.
That dock
is on the Intercoastal.
Which I guess is obvious...
since we're on
the Intercoastal.
Added this desk,
so she could do her homework.
Yeah.
And this would be her room.
I see in your eyes a promise
So, while I'm trying to
sell you on the house...
and us...
I just don't want you to think
that we're
completely insensitive...
to what you're feeling.
You guys gonna be okay
with a cat?
Absolutely.
Love's own tender flames
Warm this meeting
And love's tender song
you will sing
But fly away...
I've been thinking a lot
about the word "compromise."
On one hand,
good challenging school...
on the other...
foster people.
They can watch sitcoms
with her.
Take her to Olive Garden.
Teach her
to say "irregardless."
The only saving grace,
I suppose,
is she's better off
than she was.
Well...
Goodbye, Frank.
Hey...
come on.
I'm only 25 minutes away.
Please don't leave me here.
- Please.
- No.
Look, you're going to
a brand new school,
a better school.
I don't want to.
I want my crummy school.
- And you got Fred.
- Please.
And once a month
you can come back.
You can stay with me
and Roberta.
I want you and Roberta now!
And in a few years,
if you want...
you can come back.
You can live with me.
I wanna stay with you.
Frank, you promised me.
- Come on. Don't do this.
- You promised me.
I know.
Please, Frank.
Why are you leaving me?
Because the court said
I had to. You know this.
We've discussed this
ad naus...
We've discussed this. Come on.
- Come on, please.
- No!
- Hey, Mary.
Hey, Mary.
No! No!
Sweetheart, you know what?
No!
There's no easy way
to do this.
Not gonna be as long
as you think, honey.
- Frank!
- You're gonna see.
Frank!
Don't leave me!
- I know this is hard.
- Please!
No! Get your hands off of me!
- Frank! Please!
- I know it's hard.
- Come back!
- Mary! I know.
No!
Frank!
Don't go!
I need you!
Fred needs you!
You promised me!
No!
Huh.
Hey, down there.
I don't know
which mistake is worse.
Designing a water pump
that leaks...
or putting it somewhere
no human being can reach.
How do you design something
you know is gonna fail?
Gotta be devious
or clueless, right?
After the first few weeks,
I knew...
I had to find
a real family for her.
I was in way over my head.
And every day, I'd say,
"Today's the day...
"I'm takin' her
to child services."
And every day,
she'd do something just...
so unbelievably cool.
Her little personality
was exploding.
She was funny.
And she was angry, and
she was happy, and she was...
sad.
And was cute.
Just so damn entertaining.
And so I kept her.
Not that
that's in her best interest.
Not that I'm capable
of raising a child.
A child that might still
have a mother...
if I had taken the time to
notice that she needed me.
And now,
six and a half years later...
I finally got her
to the foster family,
and you know what?
It was great. She loved it.
I thought
it would be a nightmare...
of abandonment and betrayal.
But, turns out
it was a huge success.
I'm a fucking hero.
- Frank...
- No, Bonnie.
I appreciate
everything you've done.
Just...
- Hey.
- Hi, Frank.
We're having a little bit
of a problem in there.
What?
Uh, Mary's fine...
but she's having
a little bit of a meltdown.
Right. Let me talk to her.
No, hang on.
That's not a good idea.
Your visit here is the reason
for the meltdown.
What?
She don't wanna see you.
I'm sorry, man.
This is predictable.
You know, she needs time.
Just give me five minutes
with her.
I let you inside...
then we're gonna
betray her trust
and we have
an even bigger problem.
Oh...
- Hi.
- Hi! Can we help you?
Yeah. Do you have a one-eyed
orange cat named Fred?
We have a one-eyed cat,
but I don't know
what his name is.
Where?
I don't know.
Today was his last day.
Hey, you can't go back there.
Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what are you doing back here?
I told him he couldn't.
Hey, Fred.
Who brought this cat in?
Some guy. He said
it was an allergy issue.
Evelyn.
- Frank!
- Where's Evelyn?
Evelyn? You mean your mother?
- Yes.
- Kevin.
Evelyn is in the guest house.
Yeah, listen. I'm sorry, man.
Frank, let me tell you,
she was so helpful
with the tutors.
- Mary was so distant.
- Hey!
Look, we know
what you're up against.
Do you want your life back?
Go back inside.
What are you doing here?
Come on, Mary.
We're goin' home.
- No.
- You're trespassing!
You need to look at this.
Let's go, Mary.
- Let's move. Come on.
- No!
- Hey! Mary.
- Mary!
Mary!
- It's okay. I got her.
- Uh-uh!
Think again, lady.
Mary!
Mary! Hey, stop it.
No! Let me go!
No!
- No! No!
- Stop, Mary!
- Stop. Stop.
- No!
- Come here.
- You lied to me!
I know!
- No! No!
- Stop! Stop, stop!
I'm sorry.
I made a mistake.
I'm so sorry.
You promised me.
I know.
You promised.
I know. I'm sorry.
You said
you wouldn't leave me.
I made a mistake.
I'm sorry.
I was so sad!
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
They took Fred.
No. It's okay.
- I got him. He's home.
- What?
He's at the apartment
right now. I got him.
For real?
Yeah. He's home kicking around
his ping pong ball.
Why did you leave me there?
Because I thought
I was bad for you.
And then it dawned on me.
If Mary is this amazing...
smart, sweet human being...
then I must be
doing something right.
You're smiling.
Roberta!
Oh, baby.
Of all the stunts
you could pull.
- Where are they going?
- Nowhere.
Not yet.
You two, out!
- What is this?
- Do you want to know...
how Diane told me
she finished?
What is this
unconscionable lie?
I walked into her apartment
and she was sitting
on the floor...
with that baby in her arms
and you know
what she said to me?
Admit it. You made this up.
- She said, "What do I do now?"
- No.
It is not a completed proof...
- It is.
- No! It isn't! It can't be.
Evelyn, stop!
I'm taking Mary
and I'm raising her
how I believe Diane
would've wanted.
- We'll see about that later.
- I realize...
she's not normal.
But if Einstein can
ride a bike, so can she.
Let's just say Diane didn't
tell me, which is nonsense...
it's a Millennium Problem.
She would have shared it
with the world.
That's where
your charade falls apart.
If she had
completed the proof,
she would have published it.
Diane instructed me
very clearly.
That I was only to publish it
postmortem.
She died six years ago.
It wasn't her death
she was talking about.
I tried to talk her out of it.
But you know
how Diane could be
when she made her mind up
about something.
I called MIT.
Shankland's out of his mind
about the possibility
of publishing it with you.
He's waiting for your call.
You're gonna be spending the
next few years of your life...
defending it.
You won't have time for her.
What if I say no?
Back to Plan A.
Wait for me to die?
I know Diane was hard.
I know she was angry.
But something really good
came out of this, Evelyn.
She needs you now.
You're the best woman
for the job.
Take it.
It doesn't seem as though
Diane wanted me to have it.
Diane didn't always
think things through.
I'll be outside.
Let me know what you wanna do.
You've reached
the Department
of Mathematics at MIT.
If you know
your party's extension,
you may dial it at any time.
If you wish to speak
to an operator...
please stay on the line
and someone will be with you
as soon as possible.
Good
afternoon, MIT Mathematics,
how may I direct your call?
Hello? I'm sorry.
I can't hear you very well.
No! No.
Yeah. There you are.
Yeah, can I help you?
Uh, yes.
Doctor Shankland.
I'm really sorry.
I can't hear you.
Could you speak up, please?
Hello?
Evelyn Adler...
for Seymore Shankland, please.
And what I want you to notice,
is that when you
compute P of N...
for N congruent
to four mod five...
the answer
is a multiple of five.
So, the first person
to notice this
was Srinivasa Ramanujan.
In the beginning
of the 20th century...
he proved that
it was the case for all...
numbers congruent
to four mod five.
So, he proved
that P of five N plus four...
is congruent
to zero mod seven...
and that P of eleven N
plus six
is congruent
to zero mod eleven.
Good?
You drive
like an old lady.
It's Florida.
I'm blending in.
How was school?
Hmm, fun.
Not like regular school fun...
but interesting.
What is this book?
Discourse on Method.
René Descartes.
What's it about?
Existence.
Existence?
Yup. "I think,
therefore I am."
Well, of course you are.
That's obvious.
I think about Fred,
therefore, I am.
Cogito ergo Fred?
He's a dude and he's a guy.
And he only has one eye.
Fred, Fred, Fred!
Freddy, Fred, Fred!
All right, here we are.
Hey! Wait till
I come to a stop.
Then come
to a stop already!
A new wind is
blowing through these streets
Those cold days
are history to us
I'm not sayin'
times they won't get tough
We still got each other
That's enough
I know life
ain't simple for you, dear
But I'm here,
and I'm not going anywhere
I'm not sayin'
I know how you feel
I just know
that I can help you deal
Don't lose your mind
Don't lose your good heart
Just know this time
That you'll be waking up
in all these better days
This is how you walk on
This is where you belong
I'm not sayin'
this isn't where you 'll stay
But this is how you walk on
This is how you walk on
The warm light of the evening
sings so sweet
Cold grass
underneath your dancin' feet
These simple things
mean more than I can say
These moments make up
for our past dark days
Don't lose your mind
Don't lose your good heart
Just know this time
That you'll be waking up
in all these better days
This how you walk on
This is where you belong
I'm not sayin'
this isn't where you'll stay
But this is how you walk on
This is how you walk on
This is where you belong
I'm not saying
this isn't where you'll stay
But this is how you walk on
This is how you walk on
This is where you belong
I'm not saying
this isn't where you'll stay
But this is how you walk on
This is how you walk on