TOKYO STORY
Screenplay by
KOGO NODA and YASUJI RO OZU
Executive Producer
TAKESHI YAMAMOTO
Photography by
YUHARU ATSUTA
Art Direction by
TATSUO HAMADA
With
SETSUKO HARA
CHISHU RYU
CHI EKO HIGASHIYAMA
HARUKO SUGI MURA
SO YAMAMURA
KUNI KO MIYAKE
KYOKO KAGAWA
EIJI RO TONO
NOBUO NAKAMURA
SHI RO OSAKA
HISAO TOAKE
TERUKO NAGAOKA
Directed by
YASUJI RO OZU
We'll pass Osaka
at about 6:00 tonight.
Keizo should be off work by then.
If he got our telegram,
he'll be at Osaka Station.
Here are your lunches.
I'm leaving now.
You don't have to see us off
if you're busy at school.
I think I'll have time.
It's during a break.
We'll see you later, then.
I've put tea in the thermos, Mother.
I'll be going, then.
- See you then.
Do you have the air cushion?
Didn't I give it to you?
It's not here.
I'm sure I gave it to you.
Really?
Good morning.
Leaving today?
Yes, this afternoon.
Really?
This is our chance
to see all our children.
That's nice.
They must be looking forward
to your arrival.
Well, I hope so.
Keep an eye on our house
while we're gone, will you?
Of course.
Your children have all
turned out so well.
You're vey lucky.
I suppose so.
And what beautiful weather.
Yes, indeed.
You'll have a lovely trip.
I still can't fiind it.
No? It must be there.
Oh, here it is.
You found it?
Yes, I did.
DR. HI RAYAMA - I NTERNAL MEDICI NE
AND CHI LDREN'S DISEASES
Don't mess up the room.
I'm back.
Welcome home.
Have Grandpa and Grandma come yet?
They'll be here soon.
Mama!
- What do you want?
- Why did you move my desk?
To make room for your grandparents.
I want my desk here!
It can't be helped.
We need the space.
What about my exams?
I need a place to study.
Study anywhere you like!
Tell me: Where am I
supposed to study?
Mama! Tell me where.
Keep quiet.
You never study anyway.
I do too.
You do not.
So I don't have to study, right?
No more studying, right?
What are you saying?
They're here.
Oh, you're back.
Please come on in.
Please come in.
Yes, please come in.
Sleep well on the train?
You must be tired.
Vey well.
Come here.
Welcome.
It's good to see you again.
I just hope
we're not inconveniencing you.
It's been a long time, Mother.
It really has.
It's wonderful to see you.
How's our sister Kyoko?
Just fiine, thank you.
She stayed behind
to look after the house.
Fumiko...
I've brought a little something.
Some crackers.
Got them in the neighborhood.
Mama likes them.
Something to put them on?
A tray will do.
How about this?
Fine.
Did Noriko come to the station?
No, but I phoned her.
Wonder what happened.
Come along.
What are you doing?
Come here.
These are your grandparents.
My, aren't they getting big.
Minoru is a junior high school student.
He is?
How old are you, Isamu?
Tell her.
The bath is ready anytime.
How about a bath, Father?
Want to change your clothes, Mama?
Please don't bother.
Let's go.
Let me cary these.
Did Keizo meet you at Osaka?
Yes, he was there.
We had sent him a telegram.
Was he all right?
He sent you something.
Later's all right.
You have a towel, Father?
Yes.
Take your time.
What shall we feed them?
What about some meat?
Maybe sukiyaki.
That sounds good.
And some sashimi.
We don't need that too.
Oh, meat's enough.
We'll just have sukiyaki.
That's Noriko.
It's good to see you.
- I got to the station late.
- You went?
They had already left,
so I missed them.
They're upstairs.
I'll just go up and say hello.
Welcome to Tokyo.
- What a long time it's been.
- Yes, hasn't it.
You must have been vey busy.
Not really.
But when I fiinished, it was too late.
You didn't have to come today.
We'll be here for some time.
Are you still working
for the same company?
It must be hard
to be on your own.
Your bath is ready.
Coming.
Let me help you.
Oh, that's all right.
It's like a dream being in Tokyo.
And it didn't seem so far.
Yesterday we were in Onomichi,
and today here we are with you.
I'm glad I lived to this day.
The world has changed so.
But you haven't changed at all.
Of course we have.
We're old folks now.
Mama.
Let's go downstairs.
Mama, you've grown taller.
Don't be silly.
How could I have grown?
But you have.
And you're even fatter.
She was so big
when I was little
that I used to feel ashamed
in front of my friends.
Once in school,
a chair broke under her.
Oh, that chair was already broken.
She still thinks that.
Well, it was.
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
I'll put this away.
- What about this?
- Leave it there.
It's cooler now.
It must be vey hot in Onomichi.
Yes, it is.
Mother, how is Mrs. Ko?
She really must have been born
under an unlucky star.
She's had bad luck this year again.
After her husband died,
she married a man in Kurashiki.
Took her child with her.
But I hear she's not so happy.
Poor woman.
Papa, what was the name of that man?
The one who worked for the city.
Mr. Mihashi? He died.
Some time ago.
Yes, that's right.
Remember Mr. Hattori?
Of the Militay Affairs Section?
I remember him.
He's living in Tokyo now.
Really?
I plan to visit him.
Where does he live?
He lives in the Taito Ward.
His address is in my notebook.
Finished?
Have one - from Keizo.
He's sound asleep.
Don't bother. Let him sleep.
They'll go sightseeing tomorrow?
I'll take them around.
Good. Shall we leave, Noriko?
I suppose so.
It was good of you to come.
I'll see you soon, Papa.
Don't bother.
Sory to stay so long.
You must be tired, Father.
Mama, how about going to bed?
Shall we go to bed, then?
Good night.
I'll bring some water.
Aren't you tired?
Not really.
I'm glad they're all well.
We're here at last.
Yes.
What part ofTokyo is this, I wonder?
A suburb, I think.
It must be.
It was a long ride from the station.
I thought it would be
in some livelier part of the city.
Here?
Koichi wanted to move
to a livelier place,
but I'm afraid it wasn't easy.
OOH LA LA BEAUTY PARLOR
How long will they stay in Tokyo?
A few more days.
Shouldn't I go see them?
Don't bother.
They'll come here anyway.
I'll take them to a show
or something.
You needn't bother.
These beans are good.
What are they doing today?
Don't eat them all up.
Today my brother's
taking them somewhere.
Really? Then I'm free.
Breakfast time, Kiyo-chan.
Behave yourselves.
Grandma and Grandma will be with us.
Do you understand?
I understand.
- We're late. Aren't we going?
- Yes, soon.
Go upstairs and ask them
if they're ready.
Are you ready?
We've kept you waiting.
He says we can go now.
- Let's go.
- All right.
Where will you eat?
At the department store.
The children will like that.
Good. Isamu likes
the children's lunch there.
How is he?
Any appetite?
No. He'll only drink something cold.
- Did his fever go down?
- His temperature is still 102.
I'd better go see him.
Thank you.
I'm sory to spoil your Sunday.
Are the hypodermics disinfected?
I must see a patient.
Father, I've got to go see a sick child.
He's not doing well.
I'm sory.
- We'll wait.
It may take quite a while.
That's all right.
I'm sory, Mother.
Aren't we going yet?
I may be late.
What will we do about them?
Shall I take them?
You can't leave the house
without someone here.
We'll just go next Sunday.
All right.
- Where's he going?
- To a patient's.
I'm awfully sory.
No, no.
A good doctor is a busy doctor.
He works vey hard.
Mama, aren't we going?
It can't be helped.
A patient needs him.
It's not fair.
There'll be another time.
Minoru, behave yourself.
Just leave the room.
- You liar!
- You heard me!
- Come here.
- Don't want to.
Bad boys!
Well, boys should be lively.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
It's no fair!
But we'll go next time.
Always next time!
We never go!
It can't be helped.
You always say that.
Don't be so diffiicult.
It's not fair!
Behave yourself
or I'll tell your father.
Go ahead.
Vey well.
Remember those words.
I'm not afraid.
What's the matter?
I just don't know.
Come on, Isamu.
Let's take a walk.
Minoru too.
Let's go.
Go with Grandma, all right?
Why don't you come too?
We're going.
I'm sory.
Minoru, go with her.
Don't want to!
As you like.
What's the matter?
He's so stubborn.
So was Koichi.
Never listened to anyone.
Always had to have his own way.
You must be disappointed, Father.
No, not at all.
We'll go next Sunday.
That would be fiine.
After a few days here,
I think we'll go to Shige's.
Look. There they are.
What are you going to be
when you grow up?
A doctor like your father?
By the time you become a doctor,
I wonder if I'll still be here.
There was a phone call
from Mr. Enomoto about the job.
Then it's all arranged.
Where are they?
Upstairs.
I bought some cakes for them.
Have one. They're good.
They don't need such expensive cakes.
Good, eh?
Good, but too expensive.
Crackers would have been
good enough for them.
But they had crackers yesterday.
They like them.
Will you take them
out somewhere tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
I'm afraid I'll have
to collect some bills.
I see.
Koichi should do something.
How about the Kinsha-tei tonight?
What's on?
Some naniwabushi recital.
That's good.
They'd like that.
They haven't gone anywhere
since they got here.
Too bad they have
to stay upstairs all day.
It is, but there's nobody
to take them out.
She's got you working.
Well, hello.
What a job.
Where's Father?
Up on the laundy platform.
Don't you want to go to the baths?
Father.
Let's go to the baths.
Oh, hello.
Let's go out to a public bath.
And get ice cream on the way back.
Why, thank you.
We're going off to the baths.
Use my wooden sandals, Mother.
The old ones.
Really?
Hello.
Is this the Yoneyama Firm?
May I speak to Noriko Hirayama?
Thank you.
Noriko? It's me.
Oh, no. Don't mention it.
Look, I need a favor.
Do you have any time
to spare tomorrow?
Father and Mother
haven't been anywhere yet.
That's right.
I wonder if you could take them out
somewhere tomorrow.
I really should take them myself,
but I'm just too busy.
Sory to trouble you.
No problem at all.
Will you wait a second?
Excuse me.
May I have the day off tomorrow?
Thank you.
- How about Asahi Aluminum?
I'll fiinish it today.
Hello? Sory to keep you waiting.
I'll be at your place
at 9:00 tomorrow.
No, don't wory.
Give them my best regards.
See you tomorrow.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Tokyo.
Let's trace the history
of the great city of Tokyo.
The Imperial Palace,
formerly called the Chiyoda Castle,
was built some 500 years ago
by Lord Dokan Ota.
Its quiet setting
with its green pine trees and moat
is quite a contrast
to the bustle of Tokyo.
Koichi's house is that way.
And Shige's?
Probably over there.
And yours?
My place is -
Someplace over there, I think.
It's really a mess,
but I hope you'll drop in later.
Who is it?
Me.
You're back early.
- Is Miko-chan asleep?
- She just went to bed.
Do you have any sake?
My parents-in-law are visiting.
I have a little.
Is this enough?
Where did he have this photo taken?
Kamakura. A friend of his took it.
When was it?
Ayear before he was drafted.
So like him.
With his head to one side.
He always stood like that.
What is it?
Do you have some cups?
Just washed them.
Take these stewed green peppers.
Thank you.
I keep bothering you.
Don't go to any trouble, Noriko.
It's no trouble at all.
Thank you so much for today.
Not at all.
But I'm afraid you're tired.
Oh, no.
We saw so many places,
thanks to you.
I'm sory you had to spend
the whole day with us.
Was it really all right?
Certainly, Father.
Please don't wory.
We used to work even on Sunday.
Now, we're not so busy,
so I can take a day off.
Really? Then it's all right.
I don't have much here.
It's vey good.
Do you like drinking, Father?
Indeed he does.
In the old days he used to get angy
when the sake ran out.
Even at midnight
he'd go out for more.
Evey time a boy was born,
I prayed he wouldn't
become a drinker.
Did Shoji like to drink?
Yes, he did.
Really?
He'd go drinking after work,
and sometimes when it would get late,
he'd bring his drinking buddies
home with him.
Really?
Then you had
as much trouble as I did.
Yes.
But now I miss it.
Poor Shoji.
He lived so far from us.
I feel as if he were still alive
somewhere.
Father often scolds me
for my foolishness.
He must be dead.
It's eight years since...
I know, but...
He was such a willful boy.
I'm afraid he gave you trouble.
It seems he really caused you
some problems.
I hope it's good.
Please, Mother.
Help yourself.
They're late.
They'll be back soon.
How long will they stay in Tokyo?
Didn't they tell you?
Listen...
would you put up some money?
What for?
I'm putting some in too.
Two thousand yen or so,
maybe three.
Why?
What do you say to sending them
to the Atami Hot Springs?
You're busy, and I can't change
my work schedule either.
We can't always ask Noriko.
Not a bad idea.
I know a nice hotel.
Inexpensive, with a good view.
Good.
Let's do it, then.
I'm sure they'll like it.
Frankly, I was worried.
It costs money wherever we take them.
This is less expensive.
And there's the hot springs too.
What are you talking about?
We're planning to send
Father and Mother to Atami.
Good idea.
I've been worried about them too,
but I'm really busy.
What do you think?
Good.
I agree.
Let's do it.
We can't do anything for them here.
Right. Atami's the place.
They can enjoy the baths and rest.
An old couple would like that better
than walking around Tokyo.
That's right.
My, they're late.
Maybe they're at Noriko's.
Probably.
I've never been able to come to a spa.
We've cost them more money.
Doesn't it feel nice here?
Let's get up early in the morning
and take a walk along the beach.
Good.
There must be many good views.
A maid here told me so.
Really?
The sea is so quiet.
- Thank you for waiting.
- The noodles are ready.
- Oh, so you had that piece.
- Ouch, that hurt.
Discard.
There it is.
- I'll take that one.
- Ready.
- Ready?
- You discarded this one, right?
- Yeah, I did.
How do you like that, idiot?
That makes 1632.
He beat us.
It's awfully lively.
What time is it now?
What's the matter?
It's because
you didn't sleep well last night.
No, but you did.
I couldn't sleep a wink.
You did. You snored.
Really?
Anyway, this place is meant
for the younger generation.
That's true.
Those newlyweds last night.
Do you believe
they're really newlyweds?
This morning she was smoking in bed
after he got up.
He's an idiot.
He said, "You belong to me.
Your ears, eyes, mouth -
All of you is mine."
Who knew what belongs to who?
I wonder what Kyoko
is doing at home now.
Let's go back home.
You must be homesick already.
You're the one
who really wants to go home.
We've seen Tokyo.
We've seen Atami.
Let's go home.
Yes.
What's the matter?
I felt a bit dizzy.
I'm all right now.
You didn't sleep well.
That's why.
Shall we ty the upsweep?
I'm sure it would become you.
You have a good neckline.
Make the left side tight
and add a fluffy wave on this side.
Maybe next time I'll ty that.
It would be vey stylish.
Get me another magazine
and matches.
Welcome back.
Why, you're back so soon.
You should've stayed longer!
We're home.
Who are they?
Oh, just friends from the county.
Here, do these pin curls.
Why didn't you stay longer?
How was Atami?
Vey nice.
We liked the baths.
We had a nice view
from the hotel window.
That was a nice modern hotel.
Was it crowded?
A bit crowded, I'd say.
How was the food?
Vey good fiish -
Of course.
It's right on the sea.
And they served big omelets, too.
Why didn't you stay
for a few days longer?
We wanted you to relax.
We think it's about time we went home.
It's too soon.
You don't come up to Tokyo vey often.
But we'd better be going.
Kyoko may be lonesome at home, too.
Mother, she isn't a baby anymore.
Here I was, planning
to take you to see the Kabuki.
We don't want to put you
to so much expense.
Never mind that.
However, I've a meeting here tonight
with the other beauticians.
Are many coming?
It's my turn to provide the place.
We came back at the wrong time.
That's why we wanted you
to stay at Atami.
I should have told you so.
We've done the pin curls.
Just a minute.
What'll we do?
I don't know.
We can't go back to Koichi's again
and trouble them anymore.
That's true.
Shall we go to Noriko's?
She can't have both of us.
You go there alone.
What about you?
I think I'll visit the Hattoris.
I'll stay overnight if I can.
In any case, we should leave.
We're really homeless now.
Noriko may be home by now.
It may be a bit early.
But if you want to visit the Hattoris,
you'd better go now.
Yes, we'd better go.
You're so forgetful.
Look how big Tokyo is.
Yes, isn't it?
If we got lost,
we'd never fiind each other again.
HATTORI - PROFESSIONAL SCRI BE
I can't believe it's been so long.
It's already 17 or 18 years.
You've sent me
a New Year's card evey year.
And so have you.
I suppose Onomichi
has changed a great deal.
Fortunately the city
wasn't bombed in the war.
The place where you lived
is still as it used to be.
Is that so?
It was a nice place.
We used to like
the view from the temple.
After the chery season,
the price of fiish would always drop.
All these years, we've missed
the taste of that wonderful fiish.
Later.
Tell my friends
I'll be playing pinball, will you?
We rent the upstairs room to that man.
A real playboy.
He's a law student,
but he never studies.
He spends his time
at pinball and mahjong.
I'm sory for his father back home.
Let's go out for a drink somewhere.
I just don't seem to have
anything in the house.
No, I didn't tell you I was coming.
Do you remember our old police chief?
- Numata?
- He lives nearby.
Is that so?
How's he doing now?
He's retired.
His son is a big man
at a big printing company.
Well, I'm glad to hear that.
Let's go see him.
By all means.
That would be fiine.
- Have some more sake.
- I've had plenty.
Drink up, for old time's sake.
I haven't drunk for a long time.
You used to be a real drinker.
Remember the governor's visit
to Onomichi?
At Takemuraya?
You got drunk.
That young geisha who served -
Umeko?
You liked her, didn't you?
And the governor happened
to like her too, remember?
You liked her too, eh?
Oh, the fool I've always
made of myself by drinking.
Oh, no. Sake is good for the health.
You're lucky your children
are all settled.
Oh, I don't know about that.
I often wish at least
one of my sons were alive.
Must have been hard
to lose both of them.
Didn't you lose one?
Yes, my second son.
I've had enough of war.
Yes, indeed.
To lose your children is hard,
but living with them
isn't always easy, either.
A real dilemma.
Drink.
Let's change the subject.
And cheer up.
If I had an extra bedroom for you,
we'd drink till morning.
Miss, more sake!
Anyway, I'm vey glad you came.
I never dreamed
I'd see you here in Tokyo.
OKAYA ODEN
Here's a warm one.
Pour it for me.
You're so drunk.
Look, Hirayama.
She resembles someone, doesn't she?
There he goes again.
Don't you think so?
Well, who?
Yes, she does.
That young geisha?
Oh, no! She was fatter.
This one resembles my wife.
Yes, you're right.
See, especially here -
Why don't you leave?
You've had enough.
And both are bad-tempered.
You're a real nuisance.
My wife says so too.
Come here and pour for me.
Have some more.
No, thanks.
I think you're
the luckiest one of all.
How come?
With good sons and daughters
to be proud of.
You can be proud of yours too.
No, my son's no good.
He's henpecked
and treats me like I'm in the way.
He's nothing.
But being department head
is a good position.
Department head, nothing!
He's only an assistant section chief.
I get to feeling so low
that I lie to people.
He's a failure.
I don't think so.
He's my only son, so I spared the rod -
and spoiled him.
You brought your son up proper.
He has a degree.
But all doctors have to have degrees.
I'm afraid we expect
too much of our children.
They lack spirit.
They lack ambition.
I've told that to my son.
He said that there are
too many people in Tokyo.
That it's hard to get ahead.
What do you think?
Young people today have no backbone.
Where is their spirit?
That's not how I raised him!
But Numata -
You don't agree with me?
You're satisfiied?
Of course not, but -
You see?
Even you're not satisfiied.
I feel so sad.
No more to drink.
However, until I came up to Tokyo,
I was under the impression
that my son was doing better.
But I've found that he is
only a small neighborhood doctor.
I know how you feel.
I'm as dissatisfiied as you are.
But we can't expect too much
from our children.
Times have changed.
We have to face it.
That's what I think.
It is?
I see.
You, too!
My son has really changed,
but I can't help it.
After all, there are
too many people in Tokyo.
Do you think so?
I suppose I should be happy.
Maybe you're right.
Nowadays some young men
kill their parents without a thought.
Mine at least wouldn't do that.
Look, it's midnight.
So what?
It's closing time.
You get more and more like my wife.
I like you, you know?
Do something with him.
Leave him alone.
Let's drink up tonight.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Yes, a wonderful night.
Thank you.
That's quite enough.
It's been a long day today.
Back from Atami,
then to Shige's house,
then to Ueno Park.
You must be tired.
No, not so much,
and here I am, troubling you.
I'm vey sory.
But I really appreciate your coming.
I'm so happy.
I'm a burden to eveyone.
There now.
That's enough, really.
You must go to bed now.
You have your work tomorrow morning.
You need sleep, too.
Let's both go to bed.
Thank you. I think I will.
What a treat
to sleep in my dead son's bed.
Noriko.
Forgive me if I'm rude,
but it's been eight years
since my son's death,
yet you still keep
his photo here like that.
I feel sory for you.
Why?
Because you're young and -
I'm not that young anymore.
Yes, you are.
I feel we're doing wrong.
I've often talked to Father about this.
Should you have the chance,
please get married,
anytime you want.
I mean it.
It pains us that you won't remary.
All right. If I have the chance -
You certainly will.
Why wouldn't you?
You think so?
You had more trouble
than happiness after marying him.
I know we should have
done something for you.
Please. I'm quite happy.
But you should have had
a better life.
I'm happy.
I like it this way.
You may be happy
while you're still young.
But as you become older,
you'll fiind it lonely.
I won't get that old,
so don't wory.
You're so nice.
Good night, then.
Good night.
Excuse me.
Mr. And Mrs. Kaneko?
Who is it?
Who could it be?
- Who is it?
- The police. Offiicer Takashi.
I've brought you your friends.
They're quite drunk.
Why, Father!
Good night.
Who's he, Father?
Father, what is all this?
Father!
What's happened?
He's not alone.
- Who is it?
- Some stranger.
What's all this, Father?
Father! Answer me!
You've started drinking again,
haven't you?
You too.
You're impossible.
What happened?
Where did he drink so much?
How should I know?
He used to drink all the time.
Used to come home dead drunk,
upsetting Mama.
We hated it.
But he stopped drinking
after Kyoko was born.
He was like a new man,
and I thought that was great.
Now he's started again.
What shall we do?
I didn't expect him back here tonight,
let alone with company!
We can't leave them there.
It can't be helped.
Let's have Kiyo come down
and we'll put them upstairs.
They're too drunk to make it.
What will we do, then?
What a mess.
You sleep upstairs.
I'll put them here.
What a bother.
Why didn't he tell me
he was coming back?
So late and so drunk!
I hate drunkards.
With a stranger, too.
Oh, this is disturbing.
Thank you for putting me up.
I'm sory this place is such a mess.
Won't you be late for work?
No, I have quite enough time.
- Mother?
- What is it?
I want you to accept this.
Though it's not much.
What is it?
A little spending money.
Oh, no.
Please, Mother!
Come, Mother!
You can't do this.
It's I who should give you something.
Please take it, Mother.
Please.
Must I?
Then thank you vey much, dear.
You must need money for yourself,
but still you do this.
I don't know how to say it...
but thank you so much.
Thank you.
Let's be going.
If you come up
to Tokyo again, Mother,
please come visit again.
But I'm afraid
I won't be coming back.
I know you're busy,
but do ty to come to Onomichi.
I'd really like to,
if it were a bit nearer.
You're right.
It's so far away.
Mother, are these yours?
Thank you.
I've gotten so forgetful.
Let's go.
Will they get seats?
Yes, we're in a good position here.
The train should be in Nagoya
or Gifu around morning.
And arrive in Onomichi?
1:35 tomorrow afternoon.
Have you wired Kyoko?
I have.
Keizo will meet you at Osaka, too.
I hope Mother will have
a good sleep on the train.
She always sleeps well anywhere.
Even if I don't,
I'll be home tomorrow afternoon.
Don't drink too much, Father.
Last night was an exception.
A reunion, you know.
Has the headache gone?
Completely.
Let this be a warning.
I'm sure it was a good lesson.
You've been vey kind to us - all of you.
We enjoyed our trip.
You were so nice to us, children.
Now that we've seen you all,
you need not come down,
even if anything should happen
to either one of us.
Don't talk like that.
This isn't a farewell.
I mean it.
We live too far away.
I'm sory about yesterday.
- I heard your parents came.
- Yes. What a mess.
They weren't supposed to get
off the train, but Mother became ill.
What was the trouble?
She says she feels sick around here.
Is it her heart?
Travel sickness. She hadn't
taken the train for a long time.
What a bother.
Had to borrow blankets
and send for the doctor twice.
What a mess.
How is she now?
Feeling fiine this morning.
How old is she?
Let me see.
She's way over 60.
Sixty-seven or 68, maybe.
Vey old.
Take good care of her.
"Be a good son
while your parents are alive."
That's right.
"None can serve his parents
beyond the grave."
It must have been because
the train was so crowded.
Feel better?
Thanks. I feel fiine.
I'll be able to leave tonight.
We could stay here one more night
and take a less crowded train.
Kyoko must be worried about us.
But we're here in Osaka, seeing Keizo.
In ten days
we've seen all our children.
Grown-up grandchildren, too.
Some grandparents seem to like their
grandchildren more than their children.
What do you think?
What about you?
I like my children better.
But I'm surprised
how children change.
Shige used to be much nicer before.
A married daughter
is like a stranger.
Koichi has changed too.
He used to be such a nice boy.
Children don't live up
to their parents' expectations.
Let's just be happy
that they're better than most.
They're certainly
better than average.
We're fortunate.
I think so.
We should consider ourselves lucky.
Yes, we are vey lucky.
Papa and Mama
had to get off at Osaka.
Is that so?
She became sick on the train,
and they got home on the 10th.
Is she all right?
I think so.
They wrote many thanks.
She was tired.
Yes, the trip was too much for her.
Was she satisfiied?
Why wouldn't she be?
She saw lots of places.
Atami, too.
She'll talk about Tokyo
for a long while.
Speaking.
A telegram?
No, not yet.
From Onomichi.
It's so odd.
It says Mama is dying.
How strange.
I just got Father's letter.
It says they stopped off at Osaka
because Mother felt sick.
They got home on the 10th.
Telegram.
Just hold the line.
- From Onomichi.
- Read it.
"Mother critically ill - Kyoko."
The telegram just arrived.
You just got one too?
I'll come over.
See you soon.
I'll be waiting.
How did it happen so suddenly?
Is it serious?
Should I tell Noriko?
Yes, please do.
Yoneyama Trading Company.
Hold the line, please.
It's for you.
For me?
Hello?
Oh, hi.
Mother?
Is that right?
What does it mean?
I could see Father falling ill,
but it's Mother.
Vey bad?
I think so,
because it says "critically ill."
I guess we have to go then.
I felt strange at the station.
She said, "If anything should happen -"
She must have had a bad feeling,
somehow or other.
We've got to go, anyway.
Since she is critically ill.
If we're going, we better hury.
We'll take the express.
Yes, but I have to make all kinds
of arrangements before I leave.
Me, too.
At this busy time, too.
Come in.
Can you bring a bandage?
Let's leave tonight.
Might as well, if we have to go.
See you later.
What about mourning clothes?
We might need them.
Let's take them,
but I hope we don't need to use them.
I'll meet you at the station.
I'm going to meet them.
That's vey good of you.
What's the matter?
Is it too hot?
The children are coming to see you.
Kyoko's gone to meet them.
They'll be here any moment.
You'll get well.
I'm sure you will.
Her blood pressure went down.
She's still in a coma.
Really?
Her reaction's weak.
I'll come again.
Where's Keizo? He's so late.
Did he answer the telegram?
Not a word.
But he lives the closest of all.
Father.
You too.
Father, I don't like her condition.
What do you mean?
I mean it's dangerous.
It's not a good sign
that she's still in a coma.
Did the trip to Tokyo cause this?
I don't think so.
She was so lively in Tokyo.
Wasn't she?
- It might have been one of the causes.
- What is it, then?
She may not live till tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Probably happen around daybreak.
So.
She's not going to live.
Mother's around 68, isn't she?
So.
She's not going to live.
I don't think so.
So.
This is the end.
That's all.
Then Keizo won't be in time, will he?
Isn't life too short, though?
She was so lively.
She must've had a feeling
this would happen soon.
Yes, perhaps.
Still, I'm glad she came to Tokyo.
We were able to see her alive.
We talked about many things.
Did you bring mourning clothes?
You should have brought some.
And you, Kyoko?
I don't have any either.
You'll have to borrow some.
Borrow some for Noriko too.
She died peacefully,
without suffering, and full of years.
Isn't that Keizo?
How is she?
I wasn't in time.
I was afraid of that.
I was out of town
on offiicial business.
I'm sory I'm late.
The telegram came while I was away.
This is a terrible thing.
When was it?
This morning at 3:15.
If I had taken the 8:40 train,
I would've been in time.
Keizo, look at her.
See how peaceful she is.
Forgive my delay.
Where is Father?
Where, I wonder.
Keizo has just come, Father.
It was such a beautiful dawn.
I'm afraid we'll have
another hot day today.
What's the matter?
I can't stand that sound.
What do you mean?
As I hear it, I feel as if Mother
were becoming smaller, bit by bit.
I wasn't a vey good son.
It's time we started offering incense.
I can't lose her now.
No one can serve his parents
beyond the grave.
We once saw fiireworks from here,
didn't we?
Oh, did we?
On the night of the town festival.
Remember?
No, I don't.
You were so excited,
but after sundown you fell asleep.
With your head on Mother's lap.
I don't remember.
What were you doing in those days?
Head of the city's
board of education, I believe.
A long time ago, wasn't it?
Once we went to Omishima
during the spring holidays.
That I remember.
Mama got seasick.
Yes, I remember that too.
She was so full of life then.
How old was she then?
Forty-two or 43, I believe.
Take good care of yourself, Father,
and live long.
Thank you.
It may sound heartless to say so,
but I rather wish he had died fiirst.
If Kyoko marries,
he'll be left all alone.
I guess so.
We could have looked
after Mother in Tokyo.
Kyoko, did Mother
still have her gray summer sash?
I'd like it for a keepsake.
Is that all right with you?
And that linen kimono
she used to wear in summer?
I want that too.
You know where it is?
Can you get it out?
It's all over now.
You've been kind to come
and give your time
so we could mourn her.
Thank you.
She would have been pleased
to know Koichi looked after her.
I didn't do anything.
I remember when we had gone
to Atami from Tokyo.
She had felt dizzy once.
It didn't seem that serious.
Why didn't you tell us?
Or at least Koichi?
I guess I should have.
But that wasn't the cause.
She was overweight,
so the illness came on suddenly.
It's just like a dream.
When are you leaving?
I can't stay long.
Me neither.
How about the night express?
What about you, Keizo?
I can stay.
- So we'll leave tonight?
- Yes.
Noriko, you'll stay with Father
a bit longer, won't you?
You could leave with them.
I might as well go.
I have to make a report.
And there's that baseball match, too.
That busy?
Well, thanks for coming.
You'll be lonely now.
I'll get used to it.
A bit more rice.
Get the train tickets for us, will you?
Rice for me, too.
Can we get seats?
Papa, don't drink too much, please.
Don't you wory.
So, you'll all be going home.
Here's your lunch.
Thank you for eveything.
Come up to Tokyo on your vacation.
Must you go home today?
Yes, I must.
I'm sory I can't see you off
at the station.
That's all right.
Be sure to come to Tokyo.
I'm so glad you stayed.
I think they should have stayed
a bit longer.
But they're busy.
They're selfiish.
Demanding things
and leaving like this.
They have their own affairs.
You have yours too.
They're selfiish.
But Kyoko...
Wanting her clothes
right after her death.
I felt so sory for poor Mother.
Even strangers would have been
more considerate.
But look, Kyoko.
At your age I thought so too.
But children do drift away
from their parents.
A woman has her own life,
apart from her parents,
when she becomes Shige's age.
So she meant no harm, I'm sure.
They have to look after
their own lives.
I wonder.
I won't ever be like that.
Then what's the point
of being family?
It is.
But children become like that
gradually.
Then -you, too?
I may become like that,
in spite of myself.
Isn't life disappointing?
Yes, it is.
I must get going.
Good-bye, then.
Father, I'm leaving now.
Take care of yourself.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Please come to Tokyo
on your vacation.
Good-bye.
Has she gone?
Father, I'm leaving
on the afternoon train.
You are?
Thank you for eveything.
Please, I didn't do anything.
You've been a great help.
Mother told me
how kind you were to her
when she stayed at your place.
I didn't have much to offer.
She meant it.
She told me it was
her happiest time in Tokyo.
I want to thank you too.
She was so worried
about your future.
You can't go on like this.
Don't wory about me.
I want to see you married
as soon as possible.
Forget about Shoji.
He's dead.
It hurts me to see you
go on living like this.
No, it's not like that.
I mean it.
She said she'd never seen
a nicer woman than you.
She overestimated me.
You're wrong, Noriko.
She did. I'm not the nice woman
she thought I was.
If you see me like that,
it embarrasses me.
No, it shouldn't.
Really, I'm quite selfiish.
I'm not always thinking of your son,
though you think I am.
I'll be happy if you forget him.
Often I don't think of him for days.
Sometimes I feel
I can't go on like this forever.
Often I wonder,
when I can't sleep,
what will become of me
if I stay this way.
Day passes and night comes,
yet nothing happens,
and I feel a kind of loneliness.
My heart seems to be waiting
for something.
I'm selfiish.
You are not.
Yes, I am.
But I couldn't say this to Mother.
That's all right.
You are truly a good woman.
An honest woman.
Not at all.
This watch belonged to her.
It's old-fashioned, I believe,
but she used it
since she was your age.
Take it for her sake.
Please take it.
I'm sure she'd be happy
if you'd use it.
For her sake, please.
Thank you.
Please believe me,
I want you to be happy.
Sincerely.
I mean it.
It's strange.
We have children of our own,
yet you've done the most for us,
and you're not even a blood relative.
Thank you.
You're going to be lonely
with them all gone.
It was really so sudden.
She was a headstrong woman,
but if I had known things
would come to this,
I'd have been kinder to her
while she was alive.
Living alone, I feel
the days will get vey long.
Lonely.
You will be lonely.