(Man Screaming)
Open it.
Don't.
- We've got to see if -
- I know.
But not just yet.
Let's stay this way for a minute.
Phillip, we don't have too much time.
It's the darkness that's got you down.
Nobody feels really safe in the dark.
Nobody who's ever a child, that is.
I'll open these, alright?
There. That's much better.
What a lovely evening.
Pity we couldn't have done it with
the curtains open in the bright sunlight.
Well...
We can't have everything, can we?
We did do it in daytime.
Alright now, Phillip?
- Yes.
- Good.
You better put those away in my
chequebook drawer behind the box.
Now...
It's a museum piece now.
We really should preserve it for posterity,
except, it's such good crystal
and I'd hate to break up the set.
Out of this,
David Kentley had his last drink.
It should have been ginger ale,
or even beer.
It was out of character for David
to drink anything as corrupt as whiskey.
Out of character
for him to be murdered, too.
Yes, wasn't it? Good Americans
usually die young on the battlefield.
Well, the Davids of this world
merely occupy space,
which is why he was
the perfect victim for the perfect murder.
'Course,
he was a Harvard undergraduate.
That might make it justifiable homicide.
He's dead and we've killed him.
But he's still here.
In less than eight hours
he'll be resting at the bottom of a lake.
Meanwhile, he's here.
- What are you doing?
- It's not locked.
All the better. It's more dangerous.
And the lock's too old. It won't work.
I wish it would.
I wish we had him out of here.
I wish it were somebody else.
It's a trifle late for that, don't you think?
Whom would you have preferred,
Kenneth?
I don't know,
I suppose anyone was as good...
or as bad as any other.
You, perhaps. You frighten me.
You always have,
from that very first day in prep school.
Part of your charm, I suppose.
I'm only kidding, Brandon.
I obviously can't take it as well as you,
so I'm turning on you a little.
- That's rather foolish, isn't it?
- Yes, very.
May I have a drink now?
By all means. This is an occasion.
It calls for champagne.
- Champagne?
- I put some in the icebox.
- When did you put it there?
- Just before David arrived.
- You knew it would work.
- Of course.
You know I never did anything
unless I did it perfectly.
I've always wished
for more artistic talent.
Well, murder can be an art too.
The power to kill can be just
as satisfying as the power to create.
Phillip, do you realise we've actually
done it, exactly as we planned?
And not a single thing has gone wrong.
It was perfect.
- Yes.
- An immaculate murder!
We've killed for the sake of danger
and for the sake of killing.
We're alive, truly and wonderfully alive.
Champagne can't equal us,
or the occasion.
I'll take it, though.
You aren't frightened any more, are you?
Neither of us can have fear.
That's the difference
between us and them.
They talk about committing
the perfect crime but don't do it.
Nobody commits a murder just for...
the experiment of committing it.
Nobody except us.
- You're not frightened still, are you?
- No.
Not even of me?
- That's good.
You just astound me, as always.
That's even better.
To David, of course.
- Brandon, how did you feel?
- When?
During it.
I don't know, really.
I don't remember
feeling very much of anything,
until his body went limp
and I knew it was over.
- And then?
- Then I felt tremendously exhilarated.
H-How did you feel?
Oh, l... I...
- You don't think the party's a mistake?
- No, it's the finishing touch to our work.
It's more.
It's the signature of the artists.
Not having it would be like, uh...
Painting the picture and not hanging it?
That's not a good choice of words.
It may end up too choice,
thanks to the party.
Oh, rot. This party will be
the most exciting ever given.
- With these people?
- Oh, they're a dull crew.
The Kentleys couldn't be duller if
they tried, but we did have to have them.
After all,
they are David's mother and father.
That doesn't make them
any easier to talk to.
Don't worry.
Janet'll be buttering them up, poor girl.
She's banked everything
on hooking David.
Somehow, I don't think
she's going to succeed.
- Do you?
- No, somehow I don't.
Well, she can switch back
to Kenneth tonight.
You must admit, it was most considerate
of me in view of recent events to...
- Phillip?
- What?
- Take the other one.
- What for?
Never mind. Come with me.
- What's this all about?
- You'll see. It's brilliant.
What the devil are you doing?
Making our work of art a masterpiece.
- Brandon, you're going too far.
- Why? What do you mean?
I just thought it'd be nice
to have supper in here...
on this.
Isn't it a good idea?
Well, at least this way
no one will try to open it.
I don't think you appreciate me, Phillip.
I'm beginning to, Brandon.
Come on, we don't have much time.
Mrs Wilson will be back soon.
Did you forget to borrow her key?
I might've known -
I didn't forget. I have her key.
- Oh, good.
- How are you going to explain this?
- I'm not.
- We've got to have some excuse.
- We can't leave our guest alone.
- We must have an excuse for the others.
Let me think.
Really, you get much too upset
much too easily, Phillip.
We have a very simple excuse
right here.
What are you worrying about, Phillip?
Mr Kentley's coming
mainly to look at books.
What could be better than having them
on the dining room table
where the poor old man
can easily get at them.
Considerate, aren't we? (Phone Ringing)
Hello? Oh, of course.
- You start on the books -
- Who is it?
Mrs Wilson.
Brandon?
Brandon!
What the devil?
Don't you have any more sense than to...
What is it?
- Well, go on, yank it out.
- I can't.
If Mrs Wilson were here,
she'd yank it out for you.
A stupid display like that in front of
others will be as good as a confession.
Take these and get ahold of yourself.
If you'd let me keep the light on,
I would have seen it.
Alright! You're perfect.
We have to be, Phillip.
We agreed there was only one crime we
could commit, that of making a mistake.
- Being weak is a mistake.
- Because it's being human?
Because it's being ordinary.
I won't let either of us do -
(Door Buzzer)
You owe me $2.40 for taxis,
including the tip.
If it weren't for the traffic,
I'd have been here a half hour ago.
It's just as well.
We didn't expect you back until now.
I went to five stores
for the special pt we like.
But the prices! I couldn't see any
reason for throwing away good money.
So, I went downtown to that little
delicatessen where Mr Cadell goes.
But I tell ya, the next time
we give a party, I'm only going to -
Good evening, Mrs Wilson.
What, may I ask,
is happening to my table?
We're just moving the things in here.
Well...
I personally
thought my table was quite lovely.
Oh, it was quite lovely.
But Mr Kentley is coming to look
at these old books I had in the chest.
You wouldn't want the poor old man
to have to get on his knees to see them?
Well, I think it looks downright peculiar.
- Peculiar?
- Very.
Particularly those candlesticks.
They don't belong there at all.
On the contrary, I think they suggest a...
a ceremonial altar,
which you can heap with the foods
for our sacrificial feast.
Hmph, heap is right.
Isn't enough room for me to set
things out properly, is there, Mr Phillip?
Oh, you can make it do.
You two'll be the death of me.
What's to be done with the books?
We'll lay them out
on the dining room table.
A crazy idea, if you ask me.
Well, I have too much to do
to discuss this thoroughly, dear.
I still think it's peculiar.
- What on earth is the matter?
- I was sure she'd notice.
- Notice what?
- The rope, of course.
Brandon, we've got to hide it.
- Why?
Yes, why? It's only a piece of rope,
an ordinary household article.
Why hide it?
It belongs in the kitchen drawer.
- Mrs Wilson?
- Yes?
There's champagne in the icebox.
- We're not giving them champagne?
- We are.
Oh, it's going to be that kind of party.
I'd better doll up a little.
We only serve champagne
at Mr Cadell's on very high occasions.
Matter of fact, he and I once had
a glass together on my birthday.
Tonight, Mrs Wilson, you'll have
an opportunity to renew that romance.
May l? Mr Cadell's coming.
Oh, my. Oh, Mr Cadell is terribly nice.
- Rupert's coming?
- Yes, I thought I told you.
No, you didn't.
Some people say he's a little peculiar,
but I always thi...
Well, you might let me finish.
I thought you liked Rupert.
- I do.
- Well, then?
Of all the people on this Earth, Rupert
Cadell is the one man likely to suspect.
He's the one man who might appreciate
this from our angle, the artistic one.
- That's what's exciting.
- I'm glad it excites you. It frightens me.
I suggest you keep your voice down.
It would have been too easy
with the others, Phillip, and too dull.
As for Rupert,
I once thought of inviting him to join us.
- Why didn't you? The more the merrier.
- He hasn't the nerve.
Oh, intellectually,
he could've come along. He's brilliant.
But he's a little too fastidious.
He could've invented and admired
but he never could have acted.
That's where we're superior.
We have courage. Rupert doesn't.
Mr Cadell got a bad leg in the war for his
courage. You've got your sleeve in the celery.
(Door Buzzer)
They're here. Are we ready?
As ready as we'll ever be.
Don't you be so busy
at that piano that you don't eat.
You're getting too thin.
And don't you let them gobble up
that pt before you have any.
Let's hope it's a success. Oh, my tray.
Take it in the kitchen.
I'll answer the door.
There wouldn't be this last minute
hustle bustle if you'd kept my table...
Now the fun begins.
- Hello, come in.
(Kenneth) - How are you, Brandon?
- Fine. Just put your hat there.
- Thank you.
It's been quite a while.
Yes, that's why I sounded so stupid
on the phone. Surprised, I guess.
- Hello, Kenneth. Good to see you.
- You too.
- Been up to much lately?
- Oh, nothing to speak of. You?
Trying to get ready for exams. I have
to start cramming before everyone else.
- Am I the first?
- You are.
Why is it I'm always too early
at parties?
Probably because you're always on time.
Mrs Wilson, champagne.
Oh.
It... It isn't someone's birthday, is it?
Don't look so worried, Kenneth.
It's really almost the opposite.
The opposite?
Phillip's bidding the world a temporary
farewell. I'm driving him to Connecticut.
Oh. Where are you going?
To Brandon's mother's place
for a few weeks.
- I'm to be locked up.
- What?
To make sure he practices
six hours a day.
- I've finally wrangled a debut for him.
- Town Hall, at that.
That's wonderful.
I hope you knock 'em dead.
Thank you.
Mmm. Most decorative.
Think so?
- Hey.
- What is it?
- I feel pretty honoured.
- Oh, why?
Well, it looks like
a pretty small farewell party.
Well, we're really killing two birds
with one stone.
The party's also for Mr Kentley.
- David's father?
- Yes.
Oh. Is... David going to be here?
- Of course.
- Who else is coming?
No one you don't know,
if that's what's bothering you.
- The Kentleys, Janet Walker -
- Janet?
Yes. I thought you'd be glad to see her.
Won't you be?
Brandon, Janet and I are all washed up.
- Didn't you know?
- I'm sorry, I didn't.
Well, you knew, Phillip?
Oh, I'd heard vague rumours, but I never
pay attention to that sort of thing.
I wish you had. (Door Buzzer)
- Why?
- Well, Janet and David are -
(Janet) Hello, Mrs Wilson.
- May l?
- Help yourself.
Cheer up. I have a feeling your chances
with the lady are better than you think.
- What do you mean?
(Brandon) - Janet.
Hello, ducks. Angel!
Be careful of my hair. It took hours.
- You smell dreamy. What is it?
- That swill you gave me last Christmas.
- I knew I had good taste.
- You do. You look lovely.
I won't by the time it's all paid for.
Was that funny?
I never know when I'm being funny.
Whenever I try to be,
I lay the bomb of all time.
- Phillip, sweet.
- Hello.
What's this rumour
I hear about you and Town Hall?
I bet you're going to play a foul trick
on all of us and become...
horribly famous.
I believe you've met.
- Hello, Ken.
- Hello, Jan.
That was fascinating, wasn't it?
I seem to have run down.
What would you say
to some champagne?
'Hello, champagne.'
You see what I mean
about trying to be funny?
- How've you been, Ken?
- Fine, thanks.
- How's the new job?
- What are you doing?
Writing that same dreary column
on how to keep the body beautiful.
- For whom this time?
- An untidy little magazine called Allure.
Thanks, chum.
- Oh, isn't that painting new?
(Brandon) - Yes it is. Do you like it?
- Well, what is it?
- New Young American Primitive.
I have a new young American sister.
She's three
and her stuff is really primitive.
(Laughing)
(Janet quietly) - You dirty dog.
(Brandon quietly) - Why?
- Didn't I notice another one in the foyer?
I don't think so. Which?
This.
- I could really strangle you, Brandon.
- What have I done now?
At times, your sense of humour
is a little too malicious, chum.
What are you chattering about?
- Why did you invite Kenneth?
- Well, why not?
You know perfectly well why not.
We called it quits ages ago and I'm
practically engaged to his best friend.
- David?
- Yes, David.
Which makes everything
just ginger-peachy.
I'm terribly sorry, but it is difficult
trying to keep up with your romances.
After me came Kenneth,
and now it's David.
Why the switch
from Kenneth to David, anyway?
- Obviously, I think he's nicer.
- Well, he's certainly richer.
That's a new low even for you, chum.
(Kenneth) - Gave me a 'D' in conduct.
(Phillip) - How's your drink doing?
How many years has it been since I said,
'Oh, it tickles'? And don't you tell me.
- I hear Rupert's coming.
- He was invited, but you never know.
- I hope he does. How is he?
- Who is he?
Rupert Cadell
was our housemaster in prep school.
Housemaster for you three little dears?
Four little dears.
He tried valiantly to teach David, too.
Rupert's a publisher now, isn't he?
Successful? Maybe he can give me a job.
Rupert only publishes books he likes,
usually philosophy.
Oh. Small print, big words, no sales.
- Right.
- Rupert's extremely radical.
Do you know that he selects
his books on the assumption that
people not only can read
but actually can think.
- Curious fellow, but I like him.
- You always did.
Golly, those bull sessions you
and Rupert used to have in school.
Brandon would sit up till all hours
at the master's feet.
Brandon at someone's feet!
Who is this Rupert?
- He used to tell you the weirdest things.
- Really? What sort of things?
I suppose Kenneth means Rupert's
impatience with social conventions.
For example, he thinks murder
is a crime for most men, but -
- A privilege for the few.
- Yes.
It's alright, Mrs Wilson,
I'll answer the door.
- Mr Kentley. So glad you could come.
- Thank you, Brandon.
Mrs Kentley isn't well, so I took
the liberty of bringing my sister-in-law,
Mrs Atwater, who's staying with us.
- Delighted to have you.
- Delighted to come, dear boy.
I've been in New York two weeks.
Alice has been ill almost the whole time.
Henry is forever cataloging his library.
Oh, no, Anita. Occasionally,
I even read one of my books.
But I'm on a visit.
This is just my second party.
- I suppose it's only fair -
- Let me take your things.
- I'm sorry to hear Mrs Kentley's so ill.
- Oh, it's just a cold.
Colds can be very dangerous
this time of the year.
I hope Mrs Kentley's staying
in bed with lots of fruit juice.
- She is, thank you.
- Well, that'll do the trick.
Colds dangerous, in this heat?
I don't understand that at all.
Exactly two years ago
this summer I had one myself.
I was down for three weeks.
The doctors -
Excuse me. This way, Mrs Atwater.
(Janet) ...particularly at parties.
(Kenneth) This is over my head.
David! (Glass Crunching)
(Brandon)
Uh, no, you've made a mistake.
This is Kenneth Lawrence.
(Mrs Atwater) Oh, I'm so sorry.
(Henry) That's alright, Anita.
Kenneth is often mistaken for David
even by people who aren't nearsighted.
We haven't had much opportunity to
observe the resemblance lately, my boy.
- Haven't been studying, have you?
- I've been trying to, sir.
Oh, dear.
The resemblance is only physical.
I believe you both know Miss Walker.
Janet, my dear.
I finished working out your horoscope
just before we came.
- Oh, tell.
- The stars are very kind.
They indicate a marriage very soon.
to a tall, fair-haired young man
with a very lovely father.
- Oh, Anita, I told you that a week ago.
- Oh, well, I suppose you did.
- But the stars confirm it.
- Wonderful.
(Brandon) Mrs Atwater,
may I present Mr Phillip Morgan?
- How do you do?
- Oh, you've hurt your hand.
- Oh, it's nothing, just a little cut.
- What happened?
Nothing. The glass was cracked
and it broke. That's all.
- May I get you some champagne?
- Oh, I should adore some.
Daddy used to have a glass
every morning at eleven.
But of course, Henry doesn't like it.
Mr Kentley, may I get you some?
I'd prefer a little Scotch
with a lot of water, if you don't mind.
Is David here?
I expected him to come with you.
He called and said
that he'd meet us here.
- Where did he call from?
- Our maid spoke to him.
He was at the club,
studying for his examinations...
In tennis.
The trouble with David is, he doesn't
have to study. He's too bright.
- David does alright, very much so.
- Thank you.
- How's Mrs Kentley?
- As usual. It's a cold this time.
I hope David arrives soon.
She wants him to call her.
David's her only child, Mr Kentley.
He's my only child too,
but I'm willing to let him grow up.
Why don't I call
and tell her he's been detained.
- No, you mustn't pamper her.
- David might have stopped to see her.
- Mr Kentley?
- May I use the phone?
- Of course. It's in the bedroom.
- How cosy.
- Aren't you ready for another?
- I will be.
I am, thank you.
(Henry) What a charming young man.
I wish David saw more of him.
(Janet) Yes. I'll go and call.
Kenneth,
there's too much air in your glass.
- Mine's fine, thanks.
- Would you mind taking this in to Janet?
Sure. Why?
No particular reason. I thought you'd like
to take it to her. She's in the bedroom.
- Then you'd like David to walk in.
- No, that'd be too much of a shock.
(Atwater) - When were you born?
(Phillip) - July 14.
- Can you really tell my future from that?
- I'm only an amateur astrologer.
- I'm sure you're very good.
- I do my best.
I suppose you want to know
if your concert will be a success.
- Yes, I do.
- Let me see now.
You were born on the 14th of July.
You're Cancer, the crab.
You're a moon child.
You're very much influenced
by the moon. May I see your hand?
You don't remember the hour
of your birth, by any chance?
No.
Good fingers, strong, artistic.
What about the concert?
These hands will bring you great fame.
(Henry) Well, I consider myself
a very fortunate man today.
- I'm on hand for the grand opening.
(Brandon) - Of what?
- Of your collection, so to speak.
- Oh yes, of course.
(Atwater)
Are you going to play? How lovely.
(Janet) - Your wife sends her love.
(Henry) - David wasn't there ?
No. He'll probably be here
in a minute, though.
- Your touch has improved, Phillip.
- Rupert!
I... I was beginning to think
you weren't going to show.
You know me better than that.
Mrs Atwater,
may I present Mr Rupert Cadell.
- Delighted.
- Thank you.
- Mr Kentley.
- How do you do, Mr Kentley?
Rupert Cadell,
the housemaster at Somerville?
- I used to be.
- You must have taught my son, David.
- You flatter me. How do you do?
- Hello, chum.
- Oh, Miss Walker.
- How'd you know?
- Brandon spoke of you.
- Did he do me justice?
Do you deserve justice? Well!
Well, little Kenneth Lawrence,
how you've grown.
- Hello, er...
- Kenneth, school's out. You can say it.
Rupert, you're the same as ever.
It's awfully good to see you again.
- Why?
- Uh, well...
Don't mind me.
Very pleased to see you again.
And that bears a curious
resemblance to champagne.
- It is.
- Very good champagne.
- What's the occasion?
- I told you on the phone.
It began as a little party for Mr Kentley
so he could look over the first editions.
Then it turned out Phillip
and I were going to the country -
Yes, you told me that too, Brandon.
- Did l?
- Yeah.
Well, I thought I'd make it
sort of a farewell for Phillip.
- Therefore, champagne.
- Yes.
- I see.
- Well, it's true.
You always did stutter
when you were excited.
Well, l-l guess I'm always excited
when I give a party.
- Really?
- Mr Cadell.
Oh, Mrs Wilson.
Well, what have we here?
(Whispering)
I got that special pt you like.
(Whispering) - I don't like it anymore.
- Oh, no!
No, I'm just teasing, just teasing.
- You're awful.
- Thank you. Thank you.
You'd better get along with the carving.
The rest of the things'll be here
in two shakes.
Oh, Mr Brandon, I found it.
I haven't the least notion
what it was she lost.
Wonderful Mrs Wilson.
I may marry her.
It looks heavenly.
I hope David gets here soon.
- Yes, where is David?
- I haven't the faintest idea.
But he's so late,
Mr Kentley's getting annoyed.
- And you?
- Me? I'm hungry?
Brandon, exactly what is this?
- A cassone I got in ltaly.
- No, I mean why are we eating off it?
Oh, I've turned
the dining room into a library.
Trust you to find a new use
for a chest.
One was always turning up in the
bedtime stories he told in prep school.
"The Mistletoe Bough,"
that was your favourite tale, wasn't it?
- What was that one about?
- I don't quite remember how it started.
- It was about a lovely, young girl -
- She was a bride-to-be.
On her wedding day,
she playfully hid herself in a chest.
- Yes, that's right.
- Unfortunately, it had a spring lock.
Fifty years later,
they found her skeleton.
- I don't think I'll get that playful.
- Would you all please help yourselves?
Talking of skeletons, have you seen
that new thing at the Strand?
- Yes, I adored it.
- Did you? Good.
I didn't like the new girl much.
Definitely Scorpio.
No, I didn't like her either,
but her clothes were fabulous.
- Simply divine!
- Absolute heaven!
- I must see it.
- I have a passion for James Mason.
- Is he good?
- Absolutely terrific.
So attractively sinister!
Taurus, the bull, you know.
- Very obstinate.
- Really?
But I have a confession to make.
Do you know, I think I like Mason
as much as Errol Flynn?
- I'll take Cary Grant, myself.
- Oh, so will l.
Capricorn, the goat. He leaps, divine!
- So much "oomph."
- Yes.
- Absolutely.
- He was thrilling with Bergman.
What was it called?
"Something of the something."
No, that's the other one.
This was just plain "Something."
You know, it was sort of, you know.
It was right on the tip of my tongue.
Mine too. It was just plain
"Something" I'm sure. I adored it.
- And Bergman!
- She's the Virgo type!
- Like all these, you know.
- Oh, I think she's lovely.
I once went to the movies.
I saw Mary Pickford.
I was mad about her!
Didn't you love her?
Well, the Virgo type, like all of these.
- What did you see her in?
- I don't quite recall.
"The Something Something."
Or was it just plain "Something"?
Something rather like that.
I don't believe you ever went.
If I were you, I'd go easy
on the pt, dear - calories.
Phillip,
would you mind helping Mrs Atwater?
I'd be glad to. Sit down, Mrs Atwater.
I'll bring it to you.
Thank you so much, dear boy.
I must apologise for David.
I can't think what's keeping him.
He's only in town for the weekend
and David is very popular.
- Here, let me help. White or dark?
- A little of both on this for Mrs Atwater.
- What about you?
- I don't eat it.
How queer! I never heard of anyone
who didn't eat chicken.
Did you, Brandon? Oh, you probably did.
- Why don't you eat it, Phillip?
- I just don't.
There must be a reason.
Freud says there's a reason
for everything, even me.
There's no reason, Janet.
As I remember,
you have a very funny reason.
- Doesn't he, Brandon?
- Yes.
- I knew there had to be one. What is it?
- It's nothing too much.
(Rupert) - It's fascinating.
(Janet) - Come on, Brandon, please.
Well, it happened about
three years ago in Connecticut.
Mother has a place there, you know.
We were going to have chicken
so we walked over to the farm.
It was a lovely
Sunday morning in late Spring.
Across the valley,
the church bells were ringing.
In the yard, Phillip was doing likewise
to the necks of two or three chickens.
Oh, dear!
It was a task he usually
performed very competently.
But on this particular morning, his touch
was, perhaps, a trifle too delicate.
because one of the subjects
for our dinner table suddenly rebelled.
- Like Lazarus, he rose -
- That's a lie!
(Phillip) That's not true.
I never strangled a chicken in my life!
(Brandon) - Now look here, Phillip -
(Phillip) I never strangled a chicken,
and you know it.
(Janet Laughing) Forgive me,
but it just seemed very funny,
you two being so intense
about an old, dead chicken.
(Brandon) Sorry.
We were ridiculous and very rude.
I apologise for both of us and the story.
Well!
- Is it all over?
- I'm afraid so, Rupert.
Oh, what a pity.
In a moment, you might have strangled
each other instead of a chicken.
(Atwater) - Mr Cadell, really.
- But a man's honour was at stake.
And personally, I think a chicken
is as good a reason for murder
as a blonde, a mattress full of dollar bills,
or any of the customary,
unimaginative reasons.
Now, you don't really approve
of murder, Rupert, if I may.
You may, and I do.
Think of the problems it would solve -
unemployment, poverty,
standing in line for theatre tickets.
I must say,
I've had a perfectly dreadful time
getting tickets for that new musical,
what's it called?
- You know.
- "Something" with what's-her-name?
My dear Mrs Atwater,
careful application of the trigger finger
and a pair of seats in the first row
is yours for the shooting.
And have you had any difficulty getting
into our velvet rope restaurants?
- Frightful!
- A very simple matter.
A flick of the knife, madam,
and if you'll kindly step this way -
Oh, no, step over the head waiter's body.
Thank you, and here's your table.
(Janet laughing)
Rupert, you're the end.
(Kenneth) There's a hotel clerk
I could cheerfully flick a knife at.
Oh, no, sorry. Knives may not
be used on hotel employees.
They are in the
"death by slow torture" category,
along with bird lovers,
small children and tap-dancers.
Landlords, of course, are another matter.
You seeking an apartment?
Call on our Miss Sash Weight
of the blunt instrument department.
What a divine idea!
If it suits your purpose, merely...
- But we'd all be murdering each other.
- Oh no. Oh no.
After all, murder is, or should be, an art.
Not one of the seven lively, perhaps,
but an art, nevertheless.
As such, the privilege of
committing it should be reserved
for those few who
are really superior individuals.
And the victims - inferior beings
whose lives are unimportant anyway.
(Rupert) Obviously.
Now mind you,
I don't hold with the extremists
who feel there should be open season
for murder all year round.
No, personally, I would prefer to have...
"Cut a Throat Week."
Or "Strangulation Day."
Probably a symptom
of approaching senility,
but I must confess I really don't
appreciate this morbid humour.
- The humour was unintentional.
- You're not serious about these theories.
(Brandon) - Of course he is.
- You're both pulling my leg.
No. Why do you think that?
The notion that murder is an art
which superior beings should practice -
(Rupert) ln season!
- Now I know you're not serious.
(Rupert) - I'm a very serious fellow.
Then may I ask who is to decide
if a human being is inferior,
and is therefore
a suitable victim for murder?
- The privileged few who commit it.
- And just who might they be?
Oh, myself, Phillip...
possibly Rupert.
(Rupert) I'm sorry, Kenneth, you're out.
- Gentlemen, I'm serious.
- And so are we, Mr Kentley.
The few are those men of such
intellectual and cultural superiority
that they're above
the traditional moral concepts.
Good and evil, right and wrong were
invented for the ordinary average man,
the inferior man, because he needs them.
So you agree with Nietzsche
and his theory of the superman.
- Yes, I do.
- So did Hitler.
Hitler was a paranoid savage.
His supermen, all fascist supermen
were brainless murderers.
I'd hang any who were left.
But then, you see,
I'd hang them first for being stupid.
I'd hang all incompetents and fools.
There are far too many in the world.
Then hang me. I must be stupid, because
I don't know if you're serious or not.
In any case,
I'd rather not hear any more of your,
forgive me, contempt, for humanity,
and for the standards of a world
that I believe is civilised.
- Civilised?
- Yes.
Perhaps what is called
"Civilisation" is hypocrisy.
Well, I'm sure Rupert, fortunately,
has the intelligence and imagination -
(Kentley) Please, Brandon,
we've had had just about enough.
Phillip, where did you put those books
you set out for Mr Kentley?
- I'd like to see them myself, if I may.
(Phillip) - They're in the dining room.
Mr Kentley, wouldn't you
like to see the books now?
I apologise, sir.
Again, I'm afraid
I let myself get carried away.
Oh, that's quite alright, my boy.
I think it's a good collection,
the first editions, I mean.
Yes, I'd like to see them.
May I use the telephone first?
I'd like to talk to my wife.
She may have some word of David.
(Phillip) - Of course, it's this way.
(Atwater) - Oh, dear, oh, dear -
- Uh, Brandon?
- Yes.
You were pushing your point rather hard.
You aren't planning to do away with
a few inferiors, by any chance?
- I'm a creature of whim. Who knows?
- I see.
(Janet)
I think he's definitely Scorpio.
Uh, Mrs Atwater,
wouldn't you like to see the books?
Oh, I'd love it.
Do you know, when I was a girl,
I used to read quite a bit.
Oh, we all do strange things
in our childhood.
Kenneth, why don't you switch on
the radio or play some records.
Atmospheric music goes a long way.
He is such a sly, little devil, isn't he?
(Record) Bringing us back together
with sweet music.
Don't let it get you.
He's always doing something like this.
- I'm going in the other room.
- To see the books?
No, to let Brandon see me.
- Do you care what he thinks?
- I know what he thinks.
He thinks I threw you over because
David has a bigger bank account.
Then, why do you go?
Because...
Because I'm embarrassed
at being here with you.
Oh, Janet!
Never thought I could be, did you?
Honestly?
No.
Well, I am and I don't like it one bit.
I should think you'd have the decency
to be embarrassed yourself.
- Why?
- Well...
You threw me over, chum, remember?
My, wouldn't friend Brandon
love to know that?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. I'm just thinking.
- What about?
- Female vanity.
Well, I'm also embarrassed because...
Go on.
Well, you and David
used to be such good friends.
You're not now and it's my fault.
- I'm such an idiot girl.
- No, you're not.
Then I'm certainly giving
a good imitation of one.
Why must I try and be so smart
with everyone but David?
Don't you kid with David too?
I relax with David, thanks to you.
- To me?
- Yes.
That... That grim Sunday at Harvard,
when you called it quits,
David took me for a walk.
My chin was about an inch
from the ground.
I just couldn't be the gay girl.
I just relaxed and let everything pour out.
The real, real me stuff.
Did you hear that phrase?
I hear myself saying things like that...
Oh, where's David?
You know, I'm not very smart.
Why?
I never realised you were...
(Sighs)
Brandon and his atmospheric music.
You are in love with David, aren't you?
Yes.
- I don't get it.
- Get what?
Brandon made a crack when I got here.
He implied I'd have a chance with you
again because David's out of the running.
Wait. You mean, before I got here
Brandon knew we had broken up?
- He even knew about you and David.
- What?
Kenneth, he pretended to be completely
ignorant when I told him. He said -
What's going on here?
I don't know,
but I'm going to find out once and for all!
- Brandon?
- Yes?
- May I see you for a moment?
- Certainly.
Why can't he keep his hands off people?
Well?
Just exactly what are you up to?
- Up to getting you a coffee, if you like.
- Let's dispense with the charm!
I'd like to know why you had gall
to tell Kenneth he wouldn't have to
worry much longer about David and me.
I don't think that's precisely what I said.
It's what you implied
and I want to know why.
Some women are quite charming
when they're angry, Janet.
Unfortunately, you're not.
- Cut that out, Brandon.
- Well, chivalry rears its ugly head!
- I don't believe David's coming.
- Wait and see.
I don't have to. He's never this late.
He's never late at all.
If something had come up,
he'd have phoned.
I think you deliberately arranged it
so that he wouldn't come.
How clever of me.
I might have known you couldn't
just give a party for Mr Kentley.
You'd have to add something
that appealed
to your warped sense of humour.
I hope you've enjoyed
yourself, Brandon. I haven't.
(Janet) He's really impossible.
(Kenneth)
You shouldn't let him upset you.
Something gone wrong, Brandon?
No, Janet has a talent
for being bothersome at times.
However, I suppose I'd better...
Uh, what did you mean,
'something gone wrong'?
You always plan your parties so well,
it's odd to have anything go wrong.
She seems to be missing David.
(Rupert) As a matter of fact,
I'm beginning to miss him myself.
Aren't we all?
- Two desserts, Mr Cadell?
- One for you and one for me, my love.
The others don't seem to be
in the mood for ice cream.
No, well, they could
all do with a little cooling off.
My, it's a peculiar party,
not that that surprises me.
- Why not?
- I could have predicted it this morning.
Both of them must have got up
out of the wrong side of the bed.
They've been in a state all day!
Mr Brandon says he's always
in a state when he gives a party.
First time I've seen it.
Usually, he lets me prepare
everything my own way.
But, look at this,
the chicken's hardly been touched.
- What was so different today?
- What wasn't?
Mr Brandon was in the maddest rush
for me to clean up and get the table set.
And, oh, it looked so lovely!
(Mrs Wilson) But when
I was whisking out to do shopping,
he suddenly told me to take
the whole afternoon for it.
The whole afternoon,
after that mad rush in the morning.
- Did he say why?
- No, just a whim, I suppose.
But when I came back, he and Mr Phillip
were going at it hammer and tongs.
Oh. What about?
Now, Mr Cadell, even if I did know,
do you think I'd tell?
- Well, I hope so.
- Not me. I'm like the grave.
Look at this mess!
Just makes double the work.
After I have this cleaned off,
I have to clear all those books off
the dining room table,
bring them here,
put them back in the chest,
which is where
they were in the first place.
- Why did you serve from here, anyway?
- It wasn't my idea.
I had everything laid out in the
dining room and it was just beautiful.
(Whispering) On this thing,
it doesn't have... (Fade Out)
(Undiscernable)
Is she still harping on her table and
how awkward it is to serve from this?
It's much more convenient, you know.
Because this way, people don't have
to go all the way into the dining room
to get food and come
all the way back to eat it.
Seems to me they've gone in there
now for their dessert and coffee.
Mrs Wilson, please serve the guests.
Don't lecture them.
We did get up on the wrong side
of the bed, didn't we?
(Piano)
- I'm in quite an embarrassing position.
- How do you mean?
I seem to be the only one
having a good time.
You and Mrs Atwater.
What's going on, Phillip?
Would you mind turning that off?
- Sorry.
- I don't like the light in my eyes.
You know, Phillip,
I get quite intrigued when people don't
answer questions and quite curious.
- Did you ask me a question?
- Yes, Phillip, I asked you a question.
(Sirens)
Well, what was it?
I asked you what is going on here.
- A party.
- Yes, but a rather peculiar party.
What's it all about, Phillip?
What's what all about? Stop playing
"Crime and Punishment", Rupert.
If you want to know something
come out with it! Otherwise -
Now, now, temper, temper.
- Don't stop.
- I'd like a drink.
Wait, I'll get it for you. Keep playing.
What would you like, Scotch?
(Phillip) No, brandy.
(Piano Continues)
You're very fond
of that little tune, aren't you?
You know, I wish I could come
straight out with what I want to know.
Unfortunately, I don't know anything.
I merely suspect.
- I said that -
(Phillip) - I heard you.
- This alright?
(Phillip) - Thank you.
(Guests Laughing)
- Do you use this?
- Sometimes.
I thought only beginners did.
- I must say -
- Alright, Rupert, I'll ask you.
What do you suspect?
Oh, I'd forgotten. Where's David, Phillip?
I don't know. Why?
- Brandon knows.
- Does he?
- Doesn't he?
- Not that I know of.
- Oh, come now.
- I don't. Why don't you ask Brandon?
I have,
but he's too busy manoeuvring
the other two points of the triangle.
What for, Phillip?
Just what is Brandon trying to do
with Janet and Kenneth?
(Laughs)
- What are you laughing at?
- Nothing.
What is it?
What, am I so far off the track?
There's nothing going on at all, Rupert.
You're, uh...
more than usually allergic
to the truth tonight, Phillip.
That's the second time
you haven't told it.
Thanks. When was the first?
When you said that you'd
never strangled a chicken.
You're confused.
Brandon dreamt that up
for the sake of a very unfunny joke.
No, he didn't. No, he didn't, Phillip.
And if you'll think back carefully,
you'll realise that I know he didn't.
About a year ago,
I was up at the farm. Remember?
One morning
I saw you display your handiwork.
You're quite a good chicken strangler,
as I recall.
Well, l... I just meant
that Brandon's story wasn't true.
- I didn't mean I hadn't killed chickens.
- That's what you said.
Well, I didn't think it was a suitable topic
of conversation while we were eating.
- You could have said that.
- Alright, I didn't.
We're not eating now, Phillip.
What did you lie to me for?
- Because I don't like to talk about -
- About what? Strangling -
- I can't play with that thing!
(Brandon) - I want you to have them.
(Kentley) - It's extremely generous
of you, Brandon. I don't -
(Brandon) Please, I know you appreciate
first editions more than l, Mr Kentley.
(Kentley) - It's very nice of you.
- What's wrong?
(Kentley) - You must come to dinner...
- What's wrong now, Phillip?
Don't you want
Mr Kentley to have the books?
- No. I don't care if he has them, I just -
- What? What?
I think it's a clumsy way
of tying them up, that's all.
(Brandon) David's never had
trouble taking care of himself.
(Mr Kentley)
I know but I cannot understand this.
Whenever he's been detained before,
he's telephoned us. Isn't that so, Janet?
(Janet) Oh yes. He's always
been after me to be more punctual.
(Kenneth) And well he might.
You wouldn't know me these days.
I'm a new woman, punctual as a clock.
(Atwater)
That's very unfeminine, my dear.
(Kentley) Perhaps,
but I prefer manners to femininity.
(Atwater)
Oh Henry, you sound just like Daddy.
I remember once, when David
was still at home...(Fades Out)
Take it easy, Phillip.
- Rupert's onto something.
- He isn't. Now, let up.
- I've got to have a drink.
- Enough.
Take your hand off my arm!
Don't you ever again tell me
what to do and what not to do.
- I don't like it, and I'm not going -
- Keep your voice down.
I, uh, hope I didn't upset Phillip.
Uh, no, he's more likely mixing his drinks.
- You seem rather upset yourself.
- Do l?
Yes, there's something upsetting
both of you a great deal.
- Something that -
(Wilson) - Excuse me, sir.
There's a lady phoning
for either Mr Kentley or Mrs Atwater.
- It must be Alice. I'll talk to her, Henry.
- (Kentley) Alright.
Down the hall to your left, dear.
- Thank you.
- The first bedroom.
(Janet) Mr Kentley,
do you suppose David could be home?
(Kentley) I don't know. I hope so.
(Rupert) I hate to throw a damper,
but if David was home, I think he'd
be calling instead of Mrs Kentley.
- Wouldn't you say so, Brandon?
(Brandon) - I wouldn't know.
(Rupert) The David I remember
was polite as well as punctual.
(Janet) He hasn't changed.
(Rupert) Of course,
if he's not home, where could he be?
(Kenneth) Don't ask me. I don't know.
(Brandon)
He might be at any number of places.
(Rupert) - Such as?
(Brandon) - The club, or Bradley's party.
- Maybe he went down to Janet's.
(Rupert) - Why?
(Brandon) Perhaps he decided
to pick her up, after all.
(Janet) I phoned my place
after I spoke to Mrs Kentley.
(Kentley) - He wasn't there ?
(Janet) - No. I left a message in case.
(Rupert) We might have a better chance
of finding out where he is now
if we knew where he was this
afternoon. What do you think, Brandon?
(Brandon) I haven't the least idea
where he was this afternoon.
(Rupert) Don't you think It would help
if we found out where he was?
(Brandon) I suppose so.
(Kentley) I know he went to the club
this afternoon to play tennis.
- I know he got there.
(Rupert) - Why?
(Kentley) Someone phoned with a
message that David would meet us here.
(Rupert) - Do you know who?
(Kentley) - No.
(Rupert) Obviously, David ran into
someone at the club and changed plans.
You weren't there this afternoon,
were you, Kenneth?
(Kenneth) No. I wish I had been.
(Rupert) I don't suppose
you or Brandon were, Phillip ?
(Phillip) No.
(Brandon) Hardly, we had our hands
full getting ready for the party.
(Rupert) Oh, there was a lot
to be done this afternoon?
(Brandon) - You know.
(Rupert) - Yes, I see.
You didn't speak to David at all today?
(Brandon) No. Why do you ask?
(Rupert) I thought he might have have
called to say he'd be late or something.
(Brandon) He didn't.
Neither Phillip nor I have talked to
David since we invited him to the party.
(Kentley) - That's odd.
(Rupert) - What do you mean?
(Kentley) I thought I heard David on the
phone to Phillip yesterday morning.
(Phillip) Yes, you did. I'd forgotten.
(Brandon) Oh? What were you talking
about? Did he call about the party?
(Phillip) Yes, he wanted to make sure
about the time. That was all.
Here, I'll help you with that.
Oh, thank you, Mr Cadell.
That's alright, Mrs Wilson.
You can put the books back
when you come to clean in the morning.
I didn't have any idea
of coming in in the morning.
I'm afraid you'll have to.
Just let the books go for now.
Well, alright.
Henry, Alice hasn't had a word
from David. She's frantic.
- I better talk to her.
- She hung up.
She began to cry so badly.
Oh, Henry, I'm worried.
What did she say?
She's called every place he might be,
not once, but several times.
And now, Henry, she thinks
he may have had an accident.
- She wants you to call the police.
(Janet) - The police?
(Kentley) Oh, no, Anita,
I don't think that's necessary.
David's no longer a child.
I'm quite sure he's alright. I -
Brandon, I think I'd better go home.
My wife needs me.
- This isn't like David. He -
- No, of course, I understand.
- May I go with you, Mr Kentley?
- Thank you, Janet.
- I'll get your things.
- Thank you.
- Oh, Mr Kentley, your books.
- Oh! Oh, yes.
I can't tell you how sorry I am.
Would you call me as soon
as you hear from David?
(Atwater) I'm sure the dear
boy will turn up somehow.
- Janet?
- Yes?
This is hardly the time,
but I'm very glad we had that talk.
So am l, and David will be too.
Good.
- Well -
- Kenneth, why don't you come with us?
- Oh, I don't -
- Please.
- Thanks.
- This yours, Janet?
Yes, I'll just carry it. Oh, thanks.
- I'll get my hat.
- Oh, going with Janet?
- Yes, we're all going together.
- What did I predict?
(Brandon) Good night, Mr Kentley.
I hope Mrs Kentley feels better soon.
(Kentley) Thank you.
(Brandon) You will call me
the moment you hear from David?
(Kentley)
I will. Say good night to Phillip for us.
(Brandon) Mrs Atwater,
thank you so much for coming.
(Atwater)
Thank you for letting me come.
I'm so sorry we have to leave. Bye.
(Brandon) Good night.
(Laughs) - Oh, that's not yours.
- Oh. Oh.
(Kentley)
I'm very sorry we had to spoil it.
(Brandon) You couldn't possibly
spoil it, Mr Kentley.
(Kentley) I meant by leaving so early.
Good night.
Be careful of those stairs, Anita.
- Thank you, Mrs Wilson.
- Good night, Mr Cadell.
- Oh, you going too?
- Yes, I must. Good night.
Good night.
(Rupert) May I help you
with those books, Mr Kentley?
Thank you for a lovely evening.
Good night. It's been charming.
(Laughing)
Oh, Phillip, this party really
deserves to go down in history.
Well, come on, it's over, and it
couldn't have gone more beautifully.
Yes, it could, without Rupert.
But he was brilliant. He helped me
say all I wanted to say to those idiots.
He gave the party
the very touch I predicted.
The touch of what?
Prying, snooping, or just plain pumping?
Do you know how busy
he was questioning me?
- About what?
- Oh, what difference.
You were busy in there arranging
that other little touch of yours.
- What touch?
- Tying up the books that way.
Oh, I thought that was wonderful.
Didn't you like it?
No, Brandon, I didn't like it one bit.
You'll ruin everything
with your neat little touches.
Be quiet. Mrs Wilson's still here.
- Determined to get drunk, aren't you?
- I am drunk.
And just as childish as you were before
when you called me a liar.
- You had no business telling that story.
- Why did you lie, anyway?
I had to.
Have you ever bothered for one minute
to understand how
someone else might feel?
I'm not sentimental,
if that's what you mean.
That's not what I mean,
but it doesn't matter.
Nothing matters,
except that Mr Brandon liked the party.
Mr Brandon gave the party.
Mr Brandon had a delightful evening.
Well, I had a rotten evening.
Keep drinking
and you'll have a worse morning.
At least if I have a hangover,
it will be all mine.
Y-You know, Phillip, I've been thinking.
We deserve a real holiday
after it's all over.
Where would you like to go?
Of course, we should come back here
for a few days, first.
Otherwise, it might look -
I've been praying I'd wake up
and find we hadn't done it yet.
But why?
I'm scared to death, Brandon.
I think we're going to get caught.
Oh, there's not a chance.
Well, there was, but not any more.
Why, we're pra - (Door Opening)
Uh. Is that you, Mrs Wilson?
Yes. I'll need a key to get in
and clean up in the morning.
That is if you're still
driving up to the farm tonight.
- Oh, we're driving up, alright.
- Oh, that's good.
You don't look too well,
either one of you. Oh, thanks.
Of course, I could do with a rest myself,
but I want both of you
to come back in tip-top shape.
- We will.
- Well, I'm off. Enjoy yourselves.
Don't forget to write.
And mind your P's and Q's.
Who are you calling?
Only the garage.
Hello? This is Mr Brandon Shaw.
Would you send my car around, please?
Yes, right away. Thank you.
We'd... better draw the curtains.
(Phone Ringing) Who's that?
- Brandon, who's that?
- Probably the garage man. Answer it.
There hasn't been time
for him to get here.
Then maybe Mrs Wilson
forgot something. Answer it.
Brandon... Brandon,
couldn't we pretend we're not home?
With all these lights on?
Answer it, Phillip.
(Phone Ringing)
(Ringing Continues)
Who is it?
- Brandon. Brandon, it's Rupert.
- What?
He wants to come up.
He says he left his cigarette case here.
- Well, let him come.
- You know he's lying! He's caught on.
- Shut up and get back to that phone.
- I won't.
- Get back to that phone.
- Brandon, I can't.
- You've got to.
- No! He knows -
Shut up!
Rupert? Come on up.
No, uh, course not.
He's just a little tight.
No, but we'll find it in no time.
Right.
Phillip... Phillip, listen to me.
Rupert's on his way up now,
and you've got to pull yourself together.
Phillip, did you hear me?
Come on, have another drink if you must,
but get hold of yourself
and keep your mouth shut.
It'll be over in five minutes.
I don't know how much,
if anything, Rupert knows,
but I promise you he'll be out of here
in five minutes, one way or the other.
Phillip, for those five minutes,
you've got to pull yourself together.
- Brandon, Brandon -
- Now look.
I'm not going to get caught
because of you or anyone else.
No one is going to get in my way now.
(Door Buzzer)
Brandon, it's not loaded, is it?
(Rupert) - Sorry to bother you, Brandon.
(Brandon) - It's no bother. Come in.
I knew you were leaving tonight.
I didn't want to be left without my case.
- Hello, Phillip.
- Hello.
I didn't mean to alarm you before.
You didn't alarm him. I'm afraid
Phillip's a little antisocial tonight.
- Oh? I thought perhaps -
- Any idea where you left the case?
No. No, not at all.
Completely unlike me to forget it, isn't it?
I suppose a psychoanalyst would say
that I didn't really forget it at all.
I unconsciously left it
because I wanted to come back.
But, uh...
- Why should I want to come back?
- Yes, why?
For the pleasure of our company
or another drink.
That's a good idea.
May I have one for the road?
Of course. A short one?
No, I'd prefer a long one,
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
Phillip, will you fix Rupert a drink?
Now let me see,
the last I remember having the case
was when I was there.
I was just going to open the chest
for Mrs Wilson, when you came over.
And then what?
I think l, uh -
Wonder where it could be.
Oh, well, here it is, right where I left it.
Gentlemen, I beg your pardon.
I'm very sorry.
I, uh -
Well, may I have that drink anyway?
Of course.
- You really don't mind?
- No. Why should we?
- Well, you might be -
- What?
- Tired. You're sure it's alright?
- He said you could have it!
- Thank you.
- Don't mind Phillip.
- I'm afraid he's had a few too many.
- Well, why not? Why not?
After all, it was a party.
Well, it's very pleasant to sit here
with a good drink and good company.
I'm glad.
- Please don't let me be in the way.
- Of what?
- I know you have things to do.
- What do you mean?
Packing, last-minute odds and ends.
You are driving
to Connecticut tonight, aren't you?
- Yes, but we're all packed.
- Oh, I see. All ready.
All except one guest,
who must be gotten rid of.
Well, I'll be off as... uh...
as soon as I finish my drink.
There's no need to hurry, Rupert.
Thank you.
I, uh... would like to stay a bit.
Perhaps even see you off.
I always hate to leave a party,
especially when the evening
has been unusually stimulating,
or strange, like this evening.
What do you mean, 'strange'?
Did I say 'strange,' Brandon?
You often pick words for sound
rather than meaning.
I don't exactly know what I meant,
unless I was thinking about David.
- What was strange about David?
- His not showing up.
You don't think anything
really did happen to him, do you?
- What could have?
- He could have been run over or held up.
- In broad daylight?
- That's right, I'd forgotten.
Yes, it must have been broad
daylight when it happened.
When, uh... what happened?
When whatever did happen to David.
Nothing, probably.
Still... where is he?
- What's your theory?
- Mine?
I was considering
Janet's for the moment.
- Oh? I didn't know she had one.
- Yes, you do.
I couldn't help overhearing Janet.
She thinks you kidnapped David, or did
something to prevent him from coming.
I'm not interested in Janet's prattle,
but you always interest me, Rupert.
Do you think l, uh... 'kidnapped' David?
It's the sort of mischief that would
have appealed to you in school,
for the experience,
the excitement, the danger.
But it would be slightly more difficult
to pull off now, though, don't you think?
- Ah, you'd find a way.
- How?
I mean, suppose you were l.
How would you
get David out of the way?
You're much better
at this sort of thing than I am.
What would you do if you were l?
Well... if I wanted to get rid of David,
I'd invite him for a drink
at the club or some quiet bar.
or better still, I'd invite him here.
- Then no one would see us together.
- That's good. And no witnesses?
- Yes, that's right.
- Then what?
Well...
Well, let me see.
(Rupert)
At the right time, David would arrive.
I'd walk slowly
out of the room, into the hall.
I'd greet him, tell him how fine
he's looking and so forth,
and, uh... take his hat.
Then I'd bring him in here,
make some small talk
to put him at his ease,
probably offer him a drink,
- and then he'd sit down.
(Brandon) - Yes?
(Rupert) I'd try to make it all
very pleasant, you understand?
Phillip would probably play the piano.
Now, as I recall, David was quite strong.
He'd have to be knocked out.
So I'd move quietly behind the chair
and hit him on the head with something.
His body would fall forward on the floor.
(Brandon)
Then where would you put him?
(Rupert) Well, uh...
Well, let me see.
Well, I think I'd get Phillip
to help me carry him out of the room,
down the back stairs, and the
two of us would put him in the car.
- You'd be seen.
(Rupert) - What?
Well, you said yourself
that if anything did happen,
it must have happened in broad daylight.
Oh, that's right. I'd forgotten.
I'd have to find someplace
to hide the body until dark.
Yes, you would, but where, Rupert?
Yes.
Yes, where?
- Cat and mouse! Cat and mouse!
- Phillip!
- Which is the cat and which the mouse?
- That's enough of that.
- Mind your own business.
- That's enough, Phillip!
I told you before,
mind your own business!
It really isn't any of my business.
I'm not his keeper.
With him in this condition, though
there doesn't seem to be
much point in your staying, Rupert.
That is...
unless you came back to find something
besides your cigarette case.
You mean, for example,
to find if you really got rid of David?
- Yes, that's what I mean.
- Oh, you're as romantic as Janet.
I don't think for a moment
that you kidnapped David.
I'll admit Janet put the notion in my head,
but I never would have mentioned it,
if it weren't that you seem to be carrying
fear of discovery in your pocket.
- What?
- That's a gun, isn't it?
(Laughing)
That teased my suspicions
more than anything else.
And to tell you the truth,
it really scares me a little.
I'm terribly sorry, Rupert.
I don't blame you, but... well, here.
You can relax.
I have to take it up to the country.
There have been several burglaries,
and mother's a bit on edge.
- Uh, finished, Phillip?
(Phillip) - Alright.
(Brandon) Did you hear
what Rupert said about the gun?
He thought... (Laughing)
It's odd the way one can pyramid
simple facts into wild fantasies, isn't it?
(Brandon) - We all do, don't we, Phillip ?
(Phillip) - Yeah.
(Brandon) Particularly after a few
drinks. How is yours, Rupert?
(Rupert) I think I'll be running along.
(Brandon) Phillip, you'll feel much
better once you get out in the open air.
I don't think there'll be much traffic
and we ought to make good time.
(Rupert) It's a lovely night
and you'll be driving up in good weather.
I almost wish I were going with you.
It might be rather exciting.
Driving at night always is,
but driving with you and Phillip now...
might have an additional
element of, uh... suspense.
You were right, Phillip.
Those books were tied clumsily.
- He's got it. He's got it!
- Phillip.
He knows. He knows. He knows.
- Alright, easy. I'll take care of it.
- No, you won't.
I'd just as soon kill you
as kill him - Sooner.
This is what you wanted,
somebody else to know.
Somebody else to see how brilliant
you are, just like in school.
I told you he'd find out,
but you had to have him here.
- Now we're done for!
- Shut up!
You made me do it
and I hate both of you. I was -
(Gunshot)
- Stupid babbling drunk. I'm sorry, Rupert.
- It's alright.
It's alright. If you really want to kill,
you don't miss, not at that range.
Of course he didn't want to kill you.
He didn't know what he was doing, any
more than he knew what he was saying.
I didn't want anyone to know this but
he's becoming an alcoholic, Rupert -
Brandon,
will you step over there, please?
Phillip's drunk, Rupert.
Surely you don't take those
nightmare ideas of his seriously?
Brandon. Brandon, I'm tired.
And in a way, I'm frightened, too.
- But I don't want to fence anymore.
- What are you going to do?
I don't want to,
but I'm gonna look inside that chest.
- Are you crazy?
- I hope so.
- With all my heart I hope I'm crazy.
- This has nothing to do with you.
- I've got to.
- Don't.
- I have to look inside that chest.
- Alright!
Go ahead and look.
I hope you like what you see.
Oh, no. No!
(Brandon) - Rupert -
- I couldn't believe it was true.
- Rupert, please -
- Please what?
Listen to me. Let me explain.
Explain?
Do you think you can explain that?
- Yes, to you, because you'll understand.
- Understand?
Rupert, remember the discussion
we had before with Mr Kentley?
Remember we said, 'the lives
of inferior beings are unimportant'?
Remember we said,
we've always said, you and l,
that moral concepts of good and evil
and right and wrong
don't hold for the intellectually superior.
- Remember, Rupert?
- Yes, I remember.
(Brandon) That's all we've done.
That's all Phillip and I have done.
He and I have lived
what you and I have talked.
I knew you'd understand, because,
don't you see, you have to.
Brandon -
Brandon, till this very moment,
this world and the people in it
have always been dark
and incomprehensible to me.
I've tried to clear my way with logic
and superior intellect.
And you've thrown my own words
right back in my face, Brandon.
You were right, too. If nothing else,
a man should stand by his words.
But you've given my words
a meaning that I never dreamed of!
And you've tried to twist them
into a cold, logical excuse
for your ugly murder!
Well, they never were that, Brandon,
and you can't make them that.
There must have been something
deep inside you from the very start
that let you do this thing,
but there's always been
something deep inside me
that would never let me do it,
- and would never let me be a party to it.
- What do you mean?
I mean that tonight you've made me
ashamed of every concept I ever had
of superior or inferior beings.
But I thank you for that shame,
because now I know that we are each
of us a separate human being, Brandon,
with the right to live and work
and think as individuals,
but with an obligation
to the society we live in.
By what right do you dare say
that there's a superior few
to which you belong?
By what right did you dare decide
that that boy in there was inferior
and therefore could be killed?
Did you think you were God, Brandon?
Is that what you thought
when you choked the life out of him?
when you served food from his grave?
I don't know what you thought,
but I know what you've done.
You've murdered!
You've strangled a fellow human being
who could live and love
as you never could.
- And never will again.
- What are you doing?
It's what society's going to do. I don't
know what that will be. I can guess.
And I can help. You're going to die,
Brandon, both of you!
You're going to die.
(Someone Running)
(Woman 3) There were shots fired!
(Man 2) I think that
somebody better call the police.
(Man 3)
Did any of you hear any shots fired?
(Man 2) Somebody better call
a squad car. Can I use your phone?
(Man 2) I'm not going up to look.
There might be a mad man up there!
(lndistinct Conversation
From Street Continues)
(Sirens Wailing)
(Man On Street)
Here comes a squad car now.
They're coming.
(Sirens Blaring)
(Piano)
Alfred Hitchcock - Rope (1948) DVDRip (SiRiUs sHaRe)