THE BICYCLE THIEF
Ricci?
Is Ricci there?
Are you deaf?
Come on! Get a move on.
And because I'm a brickIayer
I shouId die of hunger?
What do you want from me?
Just be patient.
We'II see what we can do.
We'II try to find something.
- Ricci, you'II hang posters.
- Posters?
Go to the empIoyment office.
They'II give you a work permit.
My God, a job!
Hey, what about us?
I've got two jobs,
but they're not for you.
Because it's not for me
I must continue to rot?
There's just no work
for you peopIe!
Ricci, don't forget
to take your bicycIe.
You need one.
It's written on the sIip.
A bicycIe?
I have one, onIy it's broken.
I can get it in a coupIe of days.
WeII, they won't take you then.
Why not?
I'II waIk for a whiIe.
Do you have it or not?
If not, somebody eIse'II get the job.
I have a bicycIe!
You're not the onIy one!
I do too.
You're a brickIayer.
That's a different category.
- Then change it!
- I can't.
Ricci, either you have
a bicycIe or not.
I have it.
I'II pick it up now.
Remember: If you don't have
a bicycIe, nothing doing.
I'm not going to wait around
another year.
Don't worry.
I'II have the bicycIe.
Maria!
What is it?
My rotten Iuck, that's what.
I found a job
and I can't take it.
What are you taIking about?
Stop, Antonio. TeII me.
And a good city job too.
AII right.
We'II take care of that, Antonio.
Take care of what?
I need my bicycIe.
I must be there this morning...
or I Iose the job.
What can I do?
Did you have to hock your bicycIe?
What wouId you have eaten?
I've been cursed
since the day I was born!
I feeI Iike a man in chains.
Get up!
- What are you doing?
- You can sIeep without sheets, no?
They're aII sheets, six of them.
They're Iinen and cotton.
ReaI good stuff.
BeIonged to my dowry.
They're used.
Not aII of them.
Two are new.
- How many pieces?
- Six.
Three doubIes, three singIes.
- 7,000.
CouIdn't you make it a bit more?
They're used. They're used.
AII right, take them away.
7,500.
Name?
Maria Ricci.
VaImeIaina.
It's for a bicycIe.
- 6,500.
- Why?
Interest. It's the 31st.
A Fides. Next to the red one.
I know, I know.
Wait a second.
Where's the man in charge?
Over there.
Put it down.
What's the matter? Are you afraid?
Put that bicycIe down.
My name is Ricci.
The empIoyment office
at VaImeIaina sent me.
You'II start tomorrow morning.
Go to the storeroom.
They'II give you what you need.
Tomorrow at 6:45.
- How did it go?
- Good.
You had to wait,
but everything is okay.
There's some work for you.
It's the beIt of my cap.
It's Ioose.
You have to take it in.
Come over here and have a Iook.
Everyone has his own Iocker.
See how big it is?
They used to give shoes aIso,
but the pay is stiII good.
6,000 pIus an aIIowance
for the famiIy.
And there's the overtime!
CouId you stop
at Via deIIa PagIia?
- What for?
- I have to pay someone a visit.
It's up there.
Who Iives here?
I toId you. I'II onIy be a minute.
Hurry up!
- It's mine!
- No, it's mine!
HeIIo! Is anybody here?
Excuse me.
Does the Santona Iive here?
Santona?
Yes, the one that sees.
I don't know.
Let's try the first fIoor.
- Is the Santona here?
- Yes, Iast door.
CouId you watch it
for a whiIe?
How is he?
He's been sick over a year.
Last door.
How Iong has he been in bed?
AImost a year.
You couId have brought him to me!
This one yes and this one no.
Dear God, bIess me with Iight.
Your son wiII be out of bed
before the first Ieaf faIIs.
What do you mean
''before the first Ieaf faIIs''?
Your son wiII be up by autumn.
Maria, Iet's go.
- What are you doing here?
- I owe her 50 Iire.
Come on, don't be stupid.
She predicted you wouId get a job.
You did.
- I want to do my duty.
- I'II teII her what I think!
How can a woman with two chiIdren
and a head on her shouIders...
think about such nonsense,
such stupidity?
What are you doing now?
You must have money to throw away.
I don't know what got into your head.
Some woman!
CouIdn't you spend it better?
Better? I'm gratefuI.
Because she's the one
that got me the job?
Let's go.
Let's go home, dumb-dumb.
Hurry up, Bruno. It's aImost 6:30.
I can't cIean it good
because it's stiII dark.
Daddy, did you see what they've done?
It's dented.
Maybe it was there.
No, it wasn't.
This is where it got hit.
Who knows how they take care of them.
They don't pay for the repairs!
- Shut up.
- I'II shut up, but I...
wouId have toId them.
Is my cap ready?
- Something good?
- OmeIet.
- Handsome?
- Boy, you Iook Iike a cop!
Stop it! You're hurting me!
WiII you behave? Stop it.
You'II wake the baby.
Here's the omeIet.
Let's go.
Bye, Bruno.
See you tonight at 7:00.
Wait for me here.
Good day.
First, you give it a coat of gIue...
Iike this.
Then you put the poster
over it Iike this.
Then you attach the poster
Iike this...
to fIatten the poster
and to smooth out the Iumps.
Got it? Shut up, kid!
Because if you Ieave any Iumps...
the inspector wiII see them
and he'II fine you. Got it?
See, Ricci...
to do this job,
you've got to be very inteIIigent.
You must have a good eye
and work fast.
Here, it's done.
Let's go.
I'II see you, Ricci.
So Iong.
- Thief! Thief!
- What happened?
Get in! Get in!
Go after him! Quick!
Go into the tunneI! I saw him!
Faster!
What is it?
I was mistaken.
I was so sure he went this way.
It turned out
to be another feIIow.
Yes, there were peopIe around.
Then I started to run.
Come over to the meeting.
But Capece's going.
Everything's changed.
Capece stays, and you're going.
Sign this.
Quadrone!
We have to go to the meeting.
You'II Iook for it?
Look for it yourseIf.
I can't Iook aII over Rome.
You're the onIy one
who knows it.
I gave you the description
and the Iicense pIate.
Sure. It'II take me the whoIe
mobiIe unit to Iook for it.
What's the use of my compIaint, then?
Suppose you find it tomorrow
in a pawn shop.
You can caII a poIiceman,
you're on fiIe.
Anything, Captain?
Nothing. Just a bicycIe.
- Then it's up to me?
- I've aIready toId you.
You've fiIed a compIaint.
There's nothing more I can say.
Daddy, it's 7:30.
I came by bus. Let's go.
And the bicycIe?
Is it broken?
Yes, it's broken.
You go inside.
I'II be back Iater.
It's not a question of not working.
The point is that peopIe
are not pIaced.
We have taIked about it
to the Department of Labor.
Nothing is resoIved with the subsidy.
The weIfare check
humiIiates the worker...
and doesn't heIp things
get any better.
We need
a socioIogicaIIy-oriented program.
At the meeting, they said the
same thing: ''We can't do miracIes.''
WiII you keep quiet?
''You can be sure...
that we'II do our best
to get you jobs...''
I've got to speak with you.
They stoIe my bicycIe.
ReaIIy? Where did they steaI it?
At the FIorida
as I was starting work.
- How couId you...
- You've got to heIp me, Baiocco.
I have to find that bicycIe.
I'II heIp you.
Excuse me, Baiocco, Iisten.
We'II be here aII night.
I'm Iistening.
SiIence, everyone!
Keep rehearsing! I'm coming.
They'II seII it
at Piazza Vittorio.
They unIoad their stuff there
as soon as it's stoIen.
They won't waste any time.
We'II go first thing tomorrow.
Is it true?
I avoided going home,
so don't start crying here.
I'm not crying.
But when you hear such news...
Did you do something?
Did you Iook for it?
Don't cry.
You Iook Iike a baby.
We'II find it.
It'II turn up in the market.
We'II examine
every bicycIe in sight.
We'II bring it back.
Right, Antonio?
Tonight you
may not sIeep too weII...
but tomorrow the bike'II be back.
Don't worry.
Ah, no! You can't meet here!
Go back or I take my group out.
- Tomorrow, then.
- Good night.
And pIease... don't worry.
Give her a IittIe gas.
We'II never Ieave this pIace.
Get that pushcart out of the way!
Meniconi and Bagonghi,
come over here.
What make was it?
A Fides. Frame number: 12033.
He knows it better than I do.
Good... so we can divide up the work.
StoIen bikes are aIways taken apart.
Bagonghi, Iet's go this way.
No, Iet's go this way.
It's better here.
You two Iook onIy for the tires.
You, the frames.
Bruno, the pump and the beII.
Let's go.
A Fides frame.
We'II Iook for it piece by piece,
then we'II put it together.
There's onIy vegetabIes here.
We're not Iooking for that.
Remember: Don't Iet on
why we're here.
Look how many there are!
Isn't this something?
The pIace is Ioaded with bicycIes.
Remember, Bruno, pump and beII.
That's aII.
And if you see something, whistIe.
Bruno, if we find it,
we'II ceIebrate.
Wake up, Bagonghi!
A Fides.
Hey, you want to buy or touch?
Let me work, and get off my back!
You reaIIy got it cozy!
Leave me aIone.
I'm poison this morning!
Just stop it and get Iost!
It's useIess to stick together.
Antonio, you Iook for the tires.
Bagonghi for the frame,
the kid for the pump.
I'm going on my own.
Take a Iook at this frame.
WeII?
- What make is it?
- You're buying?
Don't touch. It's just painted.
What's the seriaI number?
Why? You're coIIecting seriaI numbers?
No, he's not.
Just show him the frame number.
- What if I don't?
- Then I'II caII a cop.
Go ahead! CaII one!
You think it's stoIen stuff?
Who says it is?
You must show the number
when you're asked to.
Do I ask for the size
of your shoes? No!
So I won't show you my number!
- You pIay the Iottery?
- No, I don't.
Don't you want a beII?
You've been here haIf an hour
just Iooking.
How much does this beII cost?
150 Iire.
He has to show you
the number.
Show him that frame.
Go ahead, Iook!
A man can't even work in peace!
Don't you trust me either?
12024.
Is it yours?
Here. You got paint on you.
Listen, a man who's been robbed
has the right to Iook.
You see it's my bicycIe.
We aII make mistakes.
Hey, friend!
Here we're aII honest.
Come on.
Remember, a Fides.
- Where is my son?
- Must be near the carts.
There's nothing more here.
It's difficuIt. DifficuIt.
Want something eIse?
I toId you to stay cIose to me.
Come on, Iet's go.
Antonio, he'II go with you.
We'II stay here. You never know.
I say it's better here.
It's too Iate for the other market.
Come on.
Take him to the Porta Portese.
Can't win.
Every Sunday it rains!
Sundays I'm through at 1:00.
And where can you go?
Movies bore me.
I'm stuck at home.
Look at him!
You stupid jerk!
I ought to run him over.
They get under your car,
you don't even know it.
Look at how it's pouring.
It's hopeIess.
Every Sunday, it rains.
- What happened?
- I feII down!
Here, use this.
100 Iire? That's aII I get?
That's your spIit.
You're Iucky to get that much.
It's the thief!
Stop him! Thief! Thief!
We have to find
that oId man!
There, Daddy! There he is!
Damn it! Where did he go?
Come back, Bruno!
I found him! Come on!
Excuse me.
I want to ask you something.
That young feIIow--
where can I find him?
- What feIIow?
- The one on the bicycIe.
He did something wrong?
No, nothing.
It's a personaI matter.
It's nothing urgent.
What can I do?
I don't know him.
You were together under the arch!
Lots of peopIe stand together.
Wait a second!
I must taIk to him, understand?
Where did he go?
PIease! I'm an oId man.
Leave me aIone!
I mind my own business.
I bother nobody.
And what do I get?
TroubIe.
Again? You're supposed
to be here before 10:00.
Isn't the mission aIways open?
Come, you must get ready.
- And the soup?
- I see you have no mess kit.
AII you newcomers must bring
your mess kits out into the yard.
AII right. Come, come now,
Iet's Iine up quickIy.
Let's try
to keep some order here.
Need a barber?
Then go inside.
AImost finished, counseIor?
AImost. Just these two...
No, not me.
We can begin, then.
Don't shave the chin.
Just the sides. I'm growing a beard.
PIease hurry, counseIor!
Everyone's waiting.
Some job for a Iawyer!
WiII you Iet me in?
Listen, I must find that young man.
I must taIk to him.
WiII you teII me
where I can find him?
Listen, I don't even know
the boy you're taIking about.
Why don't you
Ieave me aIone.
Page six.
''O my Lord, we your poor souIs
yearn for sanctity.
We embrace the triaIs
of our Iives...
- and tread the path of sorrow...''
- He'II profit by it.
It invoIves some money.
Where is he?
I'm not obIiged to teII you.
TaIk, or I'II get the poIice.
What have I done to you?
Leave me aIone.
Don't bother me.
''Send us, O Lord,
guidance from within...''
I'm sure he'II be gratefuI.
Just teII me.
What can you Iose?
I don't expect this for nothing.
I'II pay you.
- What do we get to eat today?
- Pasta and potatoes.
So... wiII you teII me?
JaiI is worse.
You'II rot there.
- Where is he?
- AII right. Via deIIa CampaneIIa.
What number?
I think it's 15.
- You're coming with me.
- Me? I won't go.
Either you come with me...
or I take you to the poIice!
SiIence! SiIence! TaIking
is disgracefuI during services.
Are you coming? Yes or no?
Leave me aIone.
I'm nothing but an oId man.
What can you Iose?
- I'm Iosing my patience!
- Lose whatever you Iike.
For the Iast time, wiII you go?
What do you want?
I'm not Ieaving this pIace!
You're going with me,
you hear!
I'm not mixed up with anybody.
Leave me aIone.
I've got nothing to do with him.
Come on, Iet's go!
Let me have the soup first,
at Ieast.
I'II go with you.
I sat through the service,
I'm entitIed to the soup.
- Where are you going?
- To get the soup.
Ladies, did you see an oId man?
PIease attend the service.
It's too earIy.
Wait! What do you want?
- I want to get out!
- The door's cIosed.
You can't get out.
The Iawyer has the key.
Stop making so much noise!
You're in a church!
You're disturbing the service.
It's better if you just Ieave.
I have to find him!
Did you come for Mass
or to make troubIe?
I'm Iooking for an oId man
who was here!
I've got to find him!
You'II find him after Mass!
See, he was here!
Who knows where he's gone.
He didn't just fIy away.
Why did you Iet him
go for the soup?
Shut up!
Where are you going?
Come on, Bruno.
Come back here.
Let's go! Some kid I have.
Come on, Bruno!
Why did you hit me?
Because you got on my nerves.
Let's go.
Why'd you hit me Iike that?
WiII you come on!
You act Iike
a father-in-Iaw.
Big mouth!
I'm going to teII Mama.
In a second you'II have
more to teII her.
Wait for me by the bridge.
Just stay there.
I'II Iook for the oId man.
HeIp! A boy's drowning!
Bruno, put on your jacket.
Tired?
Sit for a minute.
There isn't much we can do now.
We'II go home.
''Hurray For Modena.''
Think Modena wiII win today?
Are you hungry?
WouId you Iike a pizza?
Let's go.
Why shouId I kiII myseIf worrying
when I'II end up just as dead?
Come on.
Let's get something to eat.
Let's forget everything.
We'II get drunk!
HaIf a bottIe?
- A whoIe bottIe and a pizza.
- No pizzas in this restaurant.
This is not a pizzeria.
Give us something eIse.
You want mozzareIIa on bread?
Two mozzareIIas
and a fuII bottIe.
We'II drink wine with our meaI,
but Ieave room for dessert, okay?
What's the matter? Drink.
If Mama couId see us!
We can do anything we want,
because we're both men.
We'II eat
and be happy for now.
There's a cure for everything...
except death.
To eat Iike them, you have to...
earn at Ieast a miIIion a month.
Eat, eat. Don't worry.
You Iike it?
To think,
if I had my bicycIe...
how much I'd earn.
We couId Iive again.
I figured...
I'II show you.
12,000 a month to start.
Write it aII down.
12,000...
2,000 overtime...
pIus the famiIy aIIowance...
which is 800 a day.
30 times 800 makes...
Add it aII up.
Who couId want more?
Am I to Iose it,
Iose it after one day?
I don't want to Iose it.
See why we must find it?
Otherwise, we don't eat.
What can we do?
We'II find it.
We'II go every day
to the Porta Portese.
They've aIready sIipped away.
Your mother and her prayers
can't heIp us.
Nobody can but the saints.
...and the foIIowing soccer games
wiII take pIace as scheduIed.
Last door.
She knows everything.
Put your faith in her power.
I onIy hope you're right.
Easy, easy.
This one yes
and this one no.
You must pIant your seeds
in another fieId.
Do you understand what I mean?
I don't understand.
It's simpIe, my boy.
What good is pIanting seeds...
if the soiI rejects them?
You pIant and don't gather.
Understand?
I haven't understood a word.
She doesn't Iove you!
Forget her!
Dear boy, you're very ugIy.
Yes, ugIy.
There are so many other women.
Go and pIow a new fieId.
Mama, the tea's getting coId.
- Good day.
Daddy, here! Look, come on!
Excuse me, we've aII been
waiting here for hours.
Wait your turn.
- PIease, it's very important.
- I'm in a hurry too, and I came first.
PIease understand,
I beg of you.
It's good.
Look here, the Iady is first,
and then me.
I shed my Iight on aII.
This one yes... this one no.
Dear God, send me your Iight.
What's wrong, my son?
They stoIe what?
- My bicycIe.
- Your bicycIe?
What can I teII you, my son?
The BIessed Lord
sends his Iight from above.
Now Iisten carefuIIy:
UnIess you find it this morning,
you won't see it at aII.
Either you find it now
or you never wiII.
So, Iook.
Now? But where?
There's no more to say.
Try to understand me.
Find it now or not at aII.
It's that simpIe.
What happened today, AdeIe?
My husband's stiII drunk.
It's your cross to bear.
Stop giving him money.
What can I do?
He takes it.
We're cIosed!
The Iadies are having breakfast!
Where are you going?
And with a kid too!
You can't go upstairs.
It's cIosed!
You can't go upstairs!
It's not time!
When it's cIosed,
it's cIosed for everybody!
No one is aIIowed
in the dining room!
I must taIk to him.
Me? Go ahead.
That's the dining room.
You can't stay! Get out!
Maria, stop shouting.
I've got a headache.
Throw him out.
Give me my bicycIe back!
Come out in the street with me!
This is the first house of Rome.
If the Captain finds out...
Give me back what you stoIe from me.
What did I steaI?
The bicycIe!
What bicycIe? I'm no thief.
Leave me aIone
or you'II have troubIe!
I'II kiII you
if you don't give it back!
Give it back! You hear me?
Look at him! He's crazy!
Leave me aIone.
Get your hands off me!
I didn't do anything to you.
I won't move from here
untiI you give it back.
You stoIe it at the FIorida!
I wasn't even there!
You were there yesterday
wearing that German hat!
Get a pair of gIasses.
You can't accuse peopIe Iike that!
You're not getting away with it,
understand?
AIfredo! What is it?
Lay off!
Yesterday I was at the fruit market.
Excuse me.
This man here stoIe your bicycIe?
Yes, and I want it back.
You're sure it was this man?
I'm absoIuteIy sure!
Where was it stoIen?
- At the FIorida.
- If you're so sure, get the poIice.
No, you're not Ieaving!
Don't touch me!
Get him away from me!
You've been accusing a man
and you're not sure.
Why don't you go?
AIfredo! He's trying to kiII him!
Put his head down!
I think you better go!
And next time, be sure!
You know you couId be sued
for IibeI?
Get him out! He's a murderer!
My God, Iook at my son!
AIfredo, my son!
BIessed souI of your mother!
You aIready Iost your bike, stupid!
Want to Iose your waIIet too?
Stay back!
You're aII aIike!
You're thieves!
- Are you crazy?
- No, just trying to cooI him off!
Where is the bicycIe feIIow?
There he is, putting on a show.
Look how scared he is.
He's more dead than aIive.
I said I've nothing to hide.
You can't accuse my son!
He has a cIean record!
Everybody knows it!
Just because he wears a German cap.
I shouId be arrested then, too.
- Come on, get up.
- He can't be moved!
Let him rest awhiIe.
He's very sick, Officer.
WeII, show me your house.
We're honest peopIe.
You can Iook.
I'd sue you for sIander.
Don't pick on him.
He wouIdn't hurt a fIy.
One room we Iive in.
Look for your bicycIe.
Here's his bed. You see there's
pIenty of room to hide a bicycIe.
My daughter, another kid and I
sIeep here.
Instead of insuIts,
you shouId give my poor boy a job.
BIess his souI.
They're my brother-in-Iaw's
car tires.
He used to have a car.
Look! Look everywhere.
Are there any witnesses?
I'II testify myseIf.
CouId you wait outside?
Take as Iong as you want.
What do I care?
Are you sure it's him?
You're not mistaken?
He's the man.
Come here. Look at them.
AII those peopIe
wiII testify for him.
You're sure you saw his face?
Yes, as he was
making off with it.
- You saw the back of his head?
- No. His face I remember. ReaIIy.
- Were there peopIe who saw it?
- Yes.
Did you get the names
of any witnesses?
I couIdn't stop to take their names.
Then you're out of Iuck.
You hardIy saw his face,
and you have no witnesses.
You may be right,
but you have no proof.
And suppose he's innocent.
Then you're in troubIe.
With these characters, you have to
find the stoIen goods right on them.
If I don't get it back,
I'II break his head.
Then I'd have to arrest you.
If you onIy knew
what this means to me.
I have nothing to hide.
Satisfied?
What did he find? Nothing!
I've got a cIean record.
What's your name?
Want to press charges?
He's got a cIean record.
Remember to send us a postcard!
Don't forget:
Stay out of the Via Panico!
Don't ever come
around here again!
Here, take the streetcar.
Wait at Monte Sacro.
You heard me. Go on!
HeIp! He's got my bicycIe!
Thief! Stop him!
Catch him!
Here! I'II teach you
to steaI bicycIes!
CriminaI! ScoundreI!
- Where to?
- To the poIice station.
Wait, Iet him go.
You're not fiIing
a compIaint?
I don't want the bother.
The man has enough troubIe.
A fine exampIe
you set for your son.
You're Iucky you got off easy.
If it had been me, you'd be in jaiI.
Be thankfuI the man
didn't have you arrested.
And you can thank God.
Video SubtitIes By
Captions, Inc. Los AngeIes