And they're off and running!
Seattle breaking on top.
Purple shadow is second.
At exactly 3:45
on that Saturday afternoon...
In the last week of September...
Marvin Unger was perhaps the only one
among the 100,000 people at the track...
Who felt no thrill
at the running of the sixth race.
He was totally disinterested
in horse racing...
And held a lifelong contempt
for gambling.
Nevertheless, he had a five-dollar win
bet on every horse in the fifth race.
He knew, of course, that this
rather unique system of betting...
Would more than likely result
in a loss, but he didn't care.
For after all, he thought, what would
the loss of $20 or $30 mean...
In comparison to the vast sum
of money ultimately at stake?
- A bottle of ginger ale, please.
- Yes, sir. Comin' right up.
Favorite broke bad.
Could be anybody's race.
Could be.
A five-dollar win
next to the five-dollar place.
- Quite a crowd you got.
- Yeah.
Passing the quarter pole,
it is lucky arrow and purple shadow...
With stopwatch
on the outside to third.
At the head of the stretch,
it is purple shadow leading by a length.
Lucky arrow is second,
behind by a quarter.
Stopwatch moving up on the outside
by a length and a quarter.
Then comes southern star,
baynard brit, Stanley eight...
Third row and lovely dilemma.
It is lucky arrow leading by a head.
Purple shadow by a header and
stopwatch moving fast on the outside.
It's lucky arrow, purple shadow,
stopwatch neck and neck.
It's lucky arrow, purple shadow
and stopwatch.
It's stopwatch taking the lead.
It's stopwatch by a head.
Purple shadow second by a head,
lucky arrow third by a length...
And southern star finished fourth.
Waiting for the race
to become official...
He began to feel
as if he had as much effect...
On the final outcome
of the operation...
As a single piece
a jumbo Jigsaw puzzle has...
To its predetermined final design.
Only the addition of
the missing fragments of the puzzle...
Would reveal whether the picture was
as he guessed it would be.
The result of the sixth race
is now declared to open.
Twenty-five dollars.
About an hour earlier that same
Saturday afternoon in September...
In another part of the city...
Patrolman first class Randy Kennon...
Had some personal business
to attend to.
Hiya, Tony. What's the good word?
Same as always... havin' a ball.
See you later.
Good evening, Randy.
How have things been?
What's the use of kickin', Leo?
You wouldn't believe it, anyway.
I suppose that we're very well.
After all, a man drives a new car,
lives in a fine apartment.
So I like to live good.
You got any objections?
None at all...
As long as you don't overlook
your obligation to me.
I trust it was purely an oversight.
I'm sure a man in your position
wouldn't deliberately antagonize...
His creditors.
I ain't got it.
I know I should have it.
I'm as anxious to pay you off as you
are to have me, but I ain't got it.
Well, we all get a little cramped
now and then.
Suppose we make it a thousand.
I'll rewrite the balance as a new loan.
Give you a fresh start.
Listen. I'm broke. Get me?
Flat broke.
I couldn't give you 1,000 cents,
but if you can wait a couple of weeks...
Might be arranged,
with the proper collateral, of course.
You mean, where's the dough
comin' from? I can't tell you.
All I can tell you is, it's a sweet deal
and I'll be able to pay off.
- In two weeks? No longer?
- Maybe even less than that.
You know I wouldn't pull a thing
like this on you. I couldn't afford to.
I'm glad you said that.
I was going to point out as much...
But since you relieved me
of the unpleasant necessity...
It's a deal then? I pay you the 2,600
within the next two weeks.
Plus $400, a total of 3,000.
The extra interest, of course.
I trust that'll be satisfactory.
I couldn't say no.
Thank you.
I was sure you'd see it my way.
Take good care of yourself.
I'll take care of myself, mister.
That's my specialty.
At 7:00 p.M. That same day...
Johnny Clay, perhaps the most important
thread in the unfinished fabric...
Furthered its design.
None of these men are criminals
in the usual sense.
They've all got jobs.
They all live seemingly normal,
decent lives, but...
They got their problems, and they've
all got a little larceny in 'em.
You take my pal Unger, for instance,
the guy who owns this apartment...
He's putting up the money to operate
with him and he's letting me stay here.
He's a bookkeeper.
Been with the same company
for ten years.
You know, fay, the biggest mistake
I made before was shooting for peanuts.
Five years have taught me one thing,
if nothing else:
Anytime you take a chance, you better be
sure the rewards are worth the risk.
They can put you away just as fast for
a $10 heist as for a million-dollar job.
You don't have to sell it
to me, Johnny.
You know I'll go along
with anything you say.
I always have, you know,
ever since we were kids.
I've always believed you,
everything you've ever told me.
Those five years you been away...
I know they must've been
terrible for you.
I mean, being locked up
must be a terrible thing.
You know something?
This may sound funny, but...
Waiting for you all those years
and staying by myself...
It was like...
Not that you were locked in,
but I was locked out.
Well, look at me.
First time we've been together
in five years, and I'm making speeches.
Now, now. Everything is gonna be
all right, I promise you.
Make sure you're right about it.
I'm no good for anybody else.
I'm not pretty and not very smart,
so please don't leave me alone any more.
Now, nothing is going to happen,
not this time.
I guess I better leave you be now.
I know you've got a lot of work to do.
- When will I see you again?
- Saturday night.
We'll be on the plane together.
Until it's over, I want you
to stay out of the way.
- If there's anything I can do to help.
- No. Just make the plane reservations.
Remember, tell them at the office
that you're leaving.
Tell them you're getting married.
I don't want to say good-bye.
- We were just talking about you.
- Hi, Johnny. Hi, miss fay.
- Hello.
- I hope it was something nice.
Yes. Johnny was telling me
about what a wonderful friend you were.
- Fay was just leaving.
- Don't rush off on my account.
- She's late for an appointment.
- That's right.
- You be sure to call me.
- I'll do just what I told you I would.
It was nice to see you again, Mr. Unger.
Take care of Johnny.
There's nothing
I wouldn't do for Johnny.
I'll see you.
A half an hour earlier
at approximately 6:30...
Mike O'Reilly,
the track bartender, came home.
Ruthie, I'm home.
At 7:15 that same night...
George peatty, the track cashier,
arrived at his apartment.
- Feeling okay?
- Fine.
I've been kind of sick today.
I keep getting pains in my stomach.
Maybe you got a hole in it, George.
Do you suppose you have?
How would I get a hole
in my stomach?
How would you get one in your head?
Fix me a drink.
I think I'm developing
some pains myself.
Sherry, can't I ever say anything at all
without you joking me about it?
Hurry up with that drink.
The pains are gettin' worse.
I saw somethin' kind of nice
comin' home on the train tonight.
Somethin', well, kind of sweet.
A candy bar, George?
No, not a candy bar, darn it.
It was people.
This couple sittin'
just in front of me.
They weren't young exactly.
I guess the woman was about your age.
A little senile, you mean, with
one foot and a big toe in the grave?
You want to hear this or not?
I can't wait.
Go ahead and thrill me.
Anyway, they were sittin' in front of me
and I could hear what they were sayin'.
Well, part of it.
- They weren't young exactly...
- She was about my age, you said.
Not any more. Maybe she was when you
started telling this story, but not now.
Anyway, she was calling him papa,
and he was calling her mama.
The climax to this exciting story?
The moral, the punch line?
Forget it. I just thought I'd tell you
about it, but I might've known.
I know. You want to bet I know?
I'll give you seven to five.
Cut it out, will you?
I'm tired.
I don't feel so good.
You want me to call you papa,
and you want to call me mama?
- You know all the answers.
- Go right ahead.
It may be the last word you ever say,
but I'll try to kill you as painlessly...
I gotta go out tonight. I don't suppose
there's anything for dinner.
Of course there is.
There are all sorts of things.
- We have steak, asparagus and potatoes.
- I don't smell nothin'.
That figures, 'cause you're
too far away from it.
- Too far away?
- You don't think I had it all cooked.
It's all down in the shopping center.
Tell me somethin',
would you, Sherry?
Just tell me one thing.
Why did you ever marry me, anyway?
When a man has to ask his wife that,
well, he just hadn't better.
Why talk about it? Maybe it's
all to the good in the long run.
After all, if people
didn't have headaches...
What would happen
to the aspirin industry?
You used to love me.
You said you did, anyway.
I seem to recall you made
a memorable statement too...
Something about hitting it rich and
having an apartment on park avenue...
And a different car
for every day of the week.
Not that I really care
about such things...
As long as I have a big, handsome,
intelligent brute like you.
It would make a difference, wouldn't it?
If I had money, I mean.
How would you define "money"?
If you're thinking of giving me
your collection of Roosevelt dimes...
I mean, big money...
Hundreds of thousands of dollars.
You really don't feel well. Are you
sure that pain's in your stomach?
I'm gonna have it...
Hundreds of thousands.
Maybe a half a million.
Of course you are. Did you put
the right address on the envelope...
When you sent it to the north pole?
Go ahead and laugh. Wait and see.
Maybe you won't be laughing so hard
in a few days.
You're serious. You really think
you're gonna have a lot of money.
I don't think nothin'. I know it.
You've never been a liar. You don't
have enough imagination to lie.
What makes you think you're gonna have
several hundred thousand dollars?
- 'Cause I do. I can't talk about it.
- Not even to me, your little Sherry?
I shouldn't even have mentioned
I was going to have it.
It's not that I mind. I know I can
trust you, but if these other guys...
"These other guys"?
I can't talk about it, Sherry.
Is that why you're going out tonight?
To meet with them?
They got nothin' to do with that.
I just got to go uptown for a while.
I see.
Well, you go right ahead.
If you want to act that way,
I certainly won't try to stop you.
Now, Sherry, honey,
don't be sore at me.
When a woman's been married five years
and her husband doesn't trust her...
You think more of them
than you do of me.
What right have you got
to say a thing like that?
You know I'm crazy about you.
I'd do anything in the world for you.
You're the one I'm doing it for.
If I didn't love you so much...
I don't want you to do
anything for me.
Go up and see your fellow...
Whatever you want to do.
Don't you be surprised
if I'm not here when you get home.
You better be here.
You hear me? You will be, won't you?
You wouldn't do anything foolish,
would you?
I certainly wouldn't want to,
but as long as you don't trust me...
Or have the slightest bit
of faith in me...
- If I ever found you with another man...
- You have no use for me.
You say you do, but when it comes
to a showdown, or proving it...
You say one thing
and then you do the opposite.
Well, I could tell you a little bit
about it, I guess...
Or most of it.
- But you got to promise to keep quiet.
- Why, of course, Darling.
Just a second.
- Well!
- Hello.
- How'd you get away from George tonight?
- He had to go somewhere.
That's a break.
I'm glad you called me.
Somethin' wrong, baby?
No, nothing's wrong.
- Can I get you a drink?
- No, I don't think so.
Come on, now.
That's not my baby.
- Val, I called you last night.
- Yeah?
- There was no answer.
- I guess I stepped out.
- I called you four times.
- I guess I was out somewhere.
Oh? What'd you do?
I guess I was goofin' off
at a movie or somethin'.
Why are you doing this to me?
- I don't know what you mean.
- I think you do.
Oh, look, Mrs. peatty...
What I do is my own business.
I never tried to pin you down.
I never asked you how you
got your kicks before you met me.
That hurt. You didn't used
to talk to me like that.
I'm sorry, baby. But don't bug me.
I gotta live my life a certain way.
I can't stand it
when the walls start closin' in.
- But you know how crazy I am about you.
- And I'm crazy about you too.
I've given you
sufficient proof of that.
It's just that lately
every time I call...
So I step out once in a while.
You got yourself a husband.
The guy'ii spend
every last nickel on you.
He won't ask you any questions when you
come home from an afternoon movie...
At 9:00 at night.
- Don't be greedy.
- I'm not greedy. I'm in love with you.
If that's being greedy,
then I'm the biggest glutton on earth.
Don't make it sound so ominous. You
sound like you're gonna eat me alive.
I might just do that.
Darling, what are the two things in life
you're most interested in?
- What?
- Money and women?
That's a nice way to put me down.
- That about sums it up, doesn't it?
- We'll let it stand.
But I imagine what you really meant
to say was "money and woman."
We're gonna have money, more money than
you've dreamed of... maybe even millions.
- Yeah? How?
- George, that's how.
He's stumbled onto somethin' big.
- That meatball?
- Meatball with gravy, val.
You know he works at the track.
Somehow... and don't ask me how...
He's got connected with the mob.
They're gonna rob the track offices
for the day's receipts.
He seriously told you he and some mob
are gonna knock over the racetrack?
You can believe him, 'cause George
may be a fool, but he's not a liar.
The guy's crazy.
That's never been done before.
I told him that, but he says the job's
all set up and it's gonna be done.
And if I just sit tight, I'd be
up to my curls in cash just like that.
Let's suppose this is all true.
How do I fit in?
Well, you know I'm gonna leave George.
I guess you know why too.
You've been sayin' that
for a long, long time.
Everything's changed now.
I was gonna tell him tonight.
George may be very rich very soon.
That's all he needs, isn't it?
He'd still be George.
So you think... let's say,
George and his boys...
Pull this job
and George gets his cut...
Maybe I could take it
away from him, huh?
I think you could.
What about the others?
Any idea who they are?
Only this. I went through his clothes
while he was showering.
I'm quite sure
George went there tonight.
Kiddo, I think we got somethin' here.
If this is true, this is
a lot bigger than you think.
You're interested in takin'
Georgie's cut? I got news for you.
Georgie's cut's gonna be peanuts
compared to this whole thing.
We gotta find out more
about the overall plan.
- You think he'll tell you any more?
- Not a chance.
I could see he was scared
'cause he talked as much as he did.
I don't get it, Johnny,
about these two other guys.
There's gonna be two other guys,
and we ain't gonna know who they are?
That's right. You don't know who they
are, and they don't know who you are.
- That makes sense, doesn't it?
- I guess so, but...
Makes sense to me, all right.
What are they gonna do?
One of them's for
the job with the rifle.
None of you boys can handle that,
even if you were willing to.
The other one starts the fight
in the bar.
These other fellows, how much they
cuttin' in for. Not that I mind?
These men are not gonna be in
on the basic scheme.
They're getting paid to perform
certain definite duties...
At a certain definite time,
and they're not cutting in on the take.
They'll be paid a flat price
to do a straight job.
If they don't know anything about
the basic plan, why are they doin' it?
Simple. These boys are straight hoods.
They get paid in advance...
Five grand for the one with the rifle,
2,500 for the other.
- Where's this money comin' from?
- That's where Marvin comes in.
He's getting the 7,500 for us,
and he gets it back off the top.
I wish I could do more.
It's almost not right for me
to get as much as everybody else.
- After all, all I do is...
- Your money counts for plenty.
- You don't hear any of them complaining.
- You're okay in our book, marv.
But if these two hoods
get paid in advance...
How do you know
they're gonna do their jobs?
I'll vouch for 'em.
These guys are pros.
They can't afford to weasel out.
If they did, they'd be washed up.
Any other questions?
Let's take a look at this, then.
This is a rough drawing of the track
as I remember it.
Randy, you'll have to get me
an a-1 street map of the whole district.
George, Mike, I want you to go over
this thing with me inch by inch.
Bring it completely up to date.
Add or subtract the slightest change...
Even if it's somethin' as small
as the placing of a hot dog stand.
Now, give or take a few thousand...
I figure the loot on this deal
at two million.
There should be that much
in the track offices.
That includes profits
on the pari-mutuel betting...
The breakage money,
taxes from the mutuel machines...
Receipts from the concessions
and the money from ticket sales.
None of this money
is allowed to accumulate...
At any one point around the track.
Except for money to make change with
and the mutuel clerks' payoff money...
It all goes into the office.
Out of the entire take,
only a few thousand dollars...
Is put in the office safe
to cover emergencies.
The rest is out in the open,
held for pickup by armored car.
That car arrives about 5:00...
And parks directly in front
of the entrance to the clubhouse.
Two men stay in it... one at the wheel,
the other at a machine gun.
Two others enter the office
to collect the dough.
They're armed, and so are
the track detectives who cover them...
From the car to the office and back.
Once the armored car arrives,
a stickup is...
Is out of the question.
What in the name of Pete would a babe
be doin' outside the door?
What do you think?
Any of you
ever see this woman before?
It's Sherry, my wife.
Why, you, you been talkin'.
You spilled to her.
I did not.
What, do you think I'm crazy?
You jerk. You clown!
Come on, clown.
Sing us a chorus from "pagliacci."
You better talk. Come clean.
Talk, or we'll get it out of her.
You wouldn't do anything
to hurt her, Johnny, please.
I don't want to, but if you
won't tell us what you told her...
I didn't tell her nothin'.
Why would I do a thing like that?
Sure, she wouldn't.
She's just the building inspector.
She just stopped outside that door
to measure the keyhole.
Let's have it, George.
We're gonna get it outta one of you.
If you didn't tell her,
then why was she around here snoopin'?
She must've found the address
in my pocket. That's what it was.
Thought I was two-timin' her,
runnin' around with another...
Of course.
She's just checkin' up on me.
I didn't tell her nothin', honest.
You'll let her go, won't you?
- You won't hurt her?
- Randy, Mike.
Take him to his apartment.
Stick with him until I phone you.
- I'm not leavin' Sherry here.
- You're leavin', all right.
- How are you goin'? Slidin' or walkin'?
- Come on. Let's go.
What are you gonna do now?
I don't think
I'll have to kill her...
Just slap that face
into hamburger meat.
Why don't you take a walk
for an hour or so.
Yeah.
I'll be back in a couple of hours.
All right, sister. That's a mighty
pretty head you got on your shoulders.
You want to keep it there, or do you
want to carry it around in your hands?
Maybe we could compromise
and put it on your shoulder.
I think that'd be nice.
- What were you doing outside that door?
- Doing? I was listening, naturally.
Trying to, I should say.
You admit you were out there snooping?
Wasn't that naughty of me?
But I'm afraid I was.
I found an address
in George's pocket.
I thought he might be playin' around
with another woman, so I came here.
You'd care if he was playin'
another dame? That would bother you?
You don't understand me, Johnny.
You don't know me very well.
I know you like a book.
You're a no-good, nosy little tramp.
You'd sell out your own mother for
a piece of Fudge, but you're smart...
Smart enough to know when to sell
and when to sit tight.
- You know to sit tight in this case.
- I do.
You heard me. You like money.
You got a great big dollar sign there
where most women have a heart.
So play it smart... stay in character,
and you'll have plenty of money.
George'll have it,
then he'll blow it all on you.
Probably buy himself
a five-cent cigar.
You don't know me very well, Johnny.
I wouldn't think of letting George
throw his money away on cigars.
Isn't there a big "if"
in there somewhere?
There's a couple of them.
If you're smart, if you keep your trap
shut and don't nose around any more...
You'll have money,
you'll be loaded.
But if you don't, we'll forget
the whole thing. You won't have a penny.
I wouldn't like that.
Frail as I am,
I'd much prefer to be loaded.
I think we understand each other.
Now, beat it.
Those guys... fine friends
they turned out to be...
Slappin' me around,
callin' me dirty names.
I thought Randy'd cave
the side of my head in.
Poor George.
You're all right now, aren't you?
You shouldn't have come
over there tonight.
It's a wonder
we both didn't get killed.
I don't think there was
much danger of that.
If they'd killed you,
there couldn't be a robbery.
If they'd done anything to harm me
or offend you...
They have offended me.
They've offended me plenty.
Oh, don't be such an old bear.
They have,
and I'm not gonna forget it.
What else could they have done?
I thought they acted quite reasonably.
Well, anyway...
What... what did Johnny do to you?
Do? I already told you.
Just asked me some questions and made
sure it was all right for me to leave.
Sherry, did Johnny try anything...
What a terrible thing
for you to ask.
I don't think
you'd better say any more.
Why did you come over there tonight?
It wasn't for the reason you said.
It was for the reason you said.
You said it yourself.
I was tryin' to make an alibi for you.
I was afraid those guys'd kill you.
You know I wouldn't look
at another woman.
There wouldn't be any women
chasin' after a guy like me.
Let's drop it, George.
You put words in my mouth,
and then you say they're not true.
I told you exactly what happened.
Oh, dear.
Everything's all right
with you and your pals now.
You're going to have lots of money...
- I've been thinkin' it over.
- I can hardly wait.
How soon will it be? What day?
It ain't going to be.
I'm droppin' out.
You're dropping...
You don't mean it. You can't mean it.
I'm afraid, Sherry.
This business tonight
kind of opened my eyes.
It made me realize the kind of guys
I was gettin' mixed up with.
- Before, all I thought of was the money.
- Just keep on thinking about that.
Think how disappointed I'd be
if you didn't get that money.
I'm afraid I'd feel like
you didn't really love me.
I don't see how I could feel
any other way.
Why should I have to do a thing
like that to prove that I love you?
What are you going to do?
I want to know right now.
All you've ever done
is talk about loving me.
That's all I've had
for the last five years, is talk.
Now that you have a chance
to do something...
All those things you promised...
Buy me things...
What are you gonna do?
There ain't a thing in the world
I wouldn't do for you.
Then you'll do this
for me, won't you?
- I guess so.
- It'd be perfect.
You have no idea how perfect.
I won't have long to wait, will I?
It will be within
the next few days, won't it?
- When will it be?
- You got your own way.
You wanted me to go ahead
with the deal, so I'm going.
Now, leave me alone, will you?
I'm sorry. We won't even talk
about it, if you don't want to.
You really love me, Sherry?
Of course.
You'll always love me?
Always and always.
Three days later at 10:15
on a Tuesday morning...
Johnny Clay began
the final preparations.
You want somebody to play with?
No, thanks.
I'm just looking for a friend.
You patzer. You missed the move.
Knight to knight's five.
Pawn takes knight, rook takes rook,
queen to rook for check.
Bother someone else.
You don't know what you're talkin'.
He couldn't do that.
Shut up! Make a move.
He's right.
I could've won your rook.
- Move, patzer!
- Stop talkin', or I'll call fisher.
I can't think with all this noise!
Good game, Maurice?
Johnny! My old friend.
How are you?
Good to see you.
Been a long time.
- How long have you been out?
- Not very long.
It was very difficult, no?
Yeah.
Very difficult.
You have my sympathy.
You have not yet learned that in this
life you have to be like everyone else.
The perfect mediocrity.
No better, no worse.
Individuality is a monster...
And it must be strangled
in its cradle...
To make our friends
feel comfortable.
You know, I often thought
that the gangster and the artist...
Are the same
in the eyes of the masses.
They are admired
and hero-worshiped...
But there is always present
others...
To see them destroyed
at the peak of their growth.
Yeah, like the man said...
Life is like a glass of tea, huh?
Oh, Johnny, my friend.
You never were very bright,
but I love you, anyway.
How's life been treating you, Maurice?
About the same as always.
When I need some money,
I go out and wrestle.
But mostly I'm up here
wasting my time playing chess.
But, you know...
I wouldn't know what to do with myself
if I didn't have this place to come to.
Maurice, could you use $2,500?
It has a pleasant ring to the ear,
quite musical.
What is it for?
For takin' care of a half a dozen
private dicks, racetrack cops.
I want you to start a fight
with the bartender at the track.
The cops'ii try to break it up.
You'll keep 'em busy as long as you can.
Make 'em drag you outta the place.
No gunplay, strictly a muscle job.
Would it be out of order
for me to ask for what it is...
That you are willing to pay such a price
to see me demonstrate my talents?
I would imagine it is for more than
just your own personal entertainment.
$2,500 is a lot of dough.
Part of it's for not askin' questions.
That sounds not unreasonable.
Still, I will probably go to jail,
and jails I've found unpleasant.
The food is very bad,
company's poor...
Beds are too small...
It'll only be a disorderly conduct
charge. Maybe 60 days, nothing worse.
If a man has money to spread around in
the right places, he can be comfortable.
I do not quite understand.
For what you want me to do,
you could get any hoodlum for $100.
I don't want any hoodlum.
I want a guy like you...
Someone who's
absolutely dependable...
Who knows he's bein' well-paid
to take a risk and won't squawk.
I was thinking if perhaps you cannot
work out some other arrangement.
2,500 I like very much.
But suppose I were willing
to forego part of it...
And take a share
in your enterprise instead.
- It's not mine to share up.
- Very well.
Since there will be details
to work out...
Yeah. I'll buy you a cup of coffee.
- It's beautiful, isn't it?
- It's exactly what I wanted.
You could take care of a whole roomful
of people with that gun.
May not kill 'em all, but they wouldn't
be good for anything afterwards.
I knew you'd take care of it, Nikki.
How long have you had this place?
Almost a year.
It's picturesque enough,
but there can't be much profit in it.
There isn't, but then there isn't
much trouble neither.
What are you thinking about?
A job, your kind of a job...
A job with a rifle.
- What kind of money, pops?
- Five thousand.
- Who do I have to kill?
- A horse.
- A horse?
- A four-legged horse.
- For that I get 5,000?
- For that and...
I figured there'd be a gimmick.
The gimmick isn't
as tough as you may think.
You shoot the horse, and if anything
goes wrong, you don't squawk.
- All I got to do is bump off a horse?
- It's a special kind of a horse.
For certain reasons, including your own
protection in case anything happens...
I'm not gonna give you the whole story,
just your part of it.
Next Saturday,
the $100,000 handicap is bein' run.
In the seventh race, the big race of
the season, a certain horse is runnin'.
He's one of the best three-year-olds
to come along in the last ten years.
He'a big money winner,
and he won't pay even money...
Because half the people there
are going to be down on him.
There's a parking lot less than 300 feet
from the northwest corner of the track.
From a car parked
in the southeast corner of that lot...
You get a perfect view of the horses
as they start into the stretch.
A man in a car parked in that spot
using a rifle with a telescopic sight...
Should be able to bring down
any horse with a single shot.
A man with your eye would hardly need
a telescopic sight.
That horse is worth
a quarter million bucks.
- The crowd would go nuts.
- Let 'em go nuts.
You can do it easy, and you shouldn't
have too much trouble getting away.
Red lightning will undoubtedly
be leadin' in the stretch.
He goes down, a couple of other horses
pile up on top of him.
There'll be plenty of confusion,
I'll guarantee that.
There's one more thing.
Suppose you do get picked up.
What've you done? You shot a horse.
It isn't first-degree murder.
It isn't even murder. The best
they could get you on would be...
Inciting a riot
or shooting horses out of season.
The way you put it,
you make it sound real simple.
Five thousand bucks
for rubbin' out a horse.
- Okay. How do I get it?
- 2,500 today, 2,500 after the race.
Okay. Crazy. Now tell me something.
What's your angle, John?
They'll probably call the race off,
and they won't pay off any of the bets.
Maybe, but what my angle is
is my business.
Five thousand bucks is a lot,
and that's what I'm payin' it for...
So nobody has to know my business.
All right. You'll have no trouble
with me. I'm with you.
- I'm lookin' for Joe piano.
- Who's lookin' for Joe?
- Patsy sent me.
- Patsy who?
- Patsy gennelli.
- Where did you see patsy?
Alcatraz. We roomed together.
My name...
Don't tell me who you are.
What can I do for you?
I want a place to stay
for about a week.
I don't want it cleaned, and I don't
want anybody else in it except myself.
I think I can accommodate you.
- So how's the boy?
- He's fine.
He's doin' it on his ear.
He's the best pitcher they got.
He told me to tell you
not to worry about him.
He's doing the book.
I won plenty.
- He's tough. Maybe he'll get a break.
- I know. Let's hope.
Here you are. You don't have
to worry about leaving anything here.
It'll be safe. I'm always here.
There'll be no maid service.
- Want to leave anything in there?
- Just this, and another bag next week.
Don't worry.
Nobody will disturb them.
- What'll it be?
- No charge. You said patsy sent you.
Sure, he sent me. He's a friend,
and I'd feel better if I paid.
It's a business arrangement.
I can afford it.
Then it'll be ten dollars a week.
I'll send the money
and the butts to the boy.
Thank you very much.
Have a nice time.
Four days later at 7:30 a.M ...
Sherry peatty was wide awake.
- Did I wake you up? I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
I just couldn't sleep somehow.
Can I get you anything?
Would you like more coffee?
No, I guess not.
Nice of you to offer, though.
I'm just nervous and restless.
I'll be all right.
- Go on back to bed.
- No, I won't.
Even if I don't get up to get
my husband's breakfast...
The least I can do is sit with him
while he has his coffee.
Gosh, you sure you feel all right...
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that
the way it sounded.
I deserved it.
I know I've been irritable and moody
and I haven't acted like I should.
It's just, I can't stand
living like this...
A crummy apartment
and a hamburger for dinner.
- You haven't been so bad, baby.
- Yes, I have.
But things are gonna be different.
We'll have so many nice things.
I'll stop thinking about myself so much.
Your problems will be my problems.
Whenever you're worried about something,
like now, for instance...
- Is it the robbery you're worried about?
- I guess it is a little.
I have no reason to.
I know it's going to be all right.
Naturally you'd be a little upset
at a time like this.
It's today, isn't it?
What makes you think that? Just
because I could sleep, it doesn't mean...
I know my Georgie.
He can't fool me.
I'm right, aren't I?
Today is the day we get that money.
No, you ain't. It isn't today.
If you don't stop pestering me...
Tryin' to find out something,
there ain't gonna be no money.
- How can you...
- I mean it. I'm gettin' fed up.
You heard Johnny. Stop butting in.
He'd call this whole thing off.
He told me something else, too,
which I neglected to tell you...
That if I did butt in,
that he'd break my neck.
He wanted to make you understand
that he means business.
All I've gotta say is
you've certainly changed your tune...
Since he and his friends
slapped you around.
I was pretty sore about that.
What could they do? You said yourself
they acted pretty reasonable.
- We had no reason to hold a grudge.
- I'm not gonna argue with you.
If you let people beat you up and then
take their side against your own wife...
But you did. I wanted to quit.
You wouldn't let me.
You said I had no reason to.
Anyway, Johnny didn't lay a hand on me.
None of the guys did, but Randy.
I was gonna tell you somethin'
about your friend Johnny...
But since you feel about him
like you do...
Take his word against mine.
What about him?
What were you gonna tell me?
Let's stop the conversation
right there.
What were you gonna tell me?
I don't think I can tell you
when you feel like you do about him...
Not havin' any faith in me
in keepin' secrets.
We won't have any secrets.
What happened?
I tried to tell you about this
the other night, but...
You were so upset and anytime I tried
to say anything, you cut me off.
What are you tryin' to tell me?
I tried to stop him.
I pleaded and I struggled.
It doesn't matter, does it?
The only thing that matters
is how I feel about you.
It is today, isn't it?
Earlier that morning at 5:00 a.M ...
Red lightning was fed
only a half portion of feed...
In preparation for the seventh race
that afternoon...
The $100,000 landsdowne stakes.
At 7:00 that morning,
Johnny Clay began what might be...
The last day of his life.
- What time is it?
- It's early yet. It's only 7:00.
You better go back to sleep
after I leave.
I just wanted to say good-bye,
till tonight, that is.
Everything's all set.
Should go perfectly.
But if it doesn't,
don't talk about this with anyone.
You'll be in the clear except for your
books. I don't think they'll be rough...
I'm not worried about that.
I'm not worried about anything.
I just wish
I could do more to help.
You've done your part.
I only hope we can do ours as well.
We'll probably never see
each other again...
After we split the money
and break up tonight.
In my book, you'll always be
a stand-up guy.
I don't know how to say this,
and I don't know if I have the right...
But I've always thought
maybe you're like my own kid.
You can say anything you want.
You've had a lot of rough breaks
and maybe you've made a few mistakes...
But after today...
The good lord willing,
you'll be a new man...
A rich man.
That can make a lot of difference.
You've got a lot of life ahead of you,
a lot of people to meet...
People of quality and substance.
What are you gettin' at?
Wouldn't it be great if we could
just go away, the two of us...
And let the old world
take a couple of turns and...
Have a chance
to take stock of things?
It can be pretty serious
and terrible...
Particularly if it's not
the right person.
Getting married, I mean.
You better go back to sleep.
The seventh race starts about 4:30,
if you wanna catch it on the radio.
I'll be back here about 7:00.
Keep away from the track.
Go to a movie or something.
See you later.
It was exactly 7:00 A.M.
when he got to the airport.
The weight is okay, Mr. Preston.
Is that all the baggage?
I'll have one more with me tonight.
I can keep that in the cabin, can't I?
Yes, but check in here at the counter
prior to flight time.
Flight 465 leaves at 9:00 p.M. Tonight.
- Thank you.
- Thank you for flying American, sir.
Stopping first at a florist,
he arrived at the motel at 8:15.
He was on schedule.
- Good morning, my friend.
- Good morning, Joe.
This afternoon a friend of mine is
stopping by and leaving a bundle for me.
- He's a cop.
- A cop?
He drives a prowl car.
- A funny kind of friend you have.
- He's a funny kind of a cop.
Let him in.
He'll leave this bundle about 6:30.
I'll pick it up right after that,
and that's the last you'll see of me.
- Would you come in for a drink?
- I'd like to, but I got a lot to do.
- If I did, everything'd be fouled up.
- I understand. I'll see you tonight.
So long. Take care of yourself.
He reached the bus station
at 8:45.
It was 9:20 when he arrived
at Mike's apartment.
So far, everything had gone off
according to plan.
Mike O'Reilly was ready at 11:15.
What goes on here?
This is no way
to get your strength back.
It's very good,
but I guess I'm just not hungry.
- I couldn't eat another bite.
- Another?
You haven't eaten anything yet.
I'll take something after a while,
after I've had my medicine.
- I'll have more appetite then.
- That's a promise. No tricks now.
It's a promise. You better go along,
or you'll be late for work.
Yeah, I guess I will.
Ruthie, things are gonna get
much better for us.
I know. I know, dear.
I know I've made a lot of promises
in the past, but...
This time it's not just talk.
We're gonna be rich, and soon.
You're gonna have a fine house
and doctors that'll make you well again.
Of course, dear.
You'd better go along or you'll be late.
Yeah.
- Mike?
- Yes?
On your way home tonight,
would you bring me some magazines?
Of course.
But I'm going to be a little late,
probably about 10:00.
Some of the fellows and me
are having a little get-together.
I understand.
Don't you drink too much beer.
Remember how it always
leaves you the next day.
Don't worry about that.
I won't be doing any drinking tonight.
I called mother. She'll be over
this afternoon to fix your dinner.
Thank you, dear. Good-bye.
Don't forget to eat your breakfast.
He reached the bus station at 11:29.
At 12:10, as it was his custom,
he arrived at the track.
What have we got here?
Who's the girlfriend?
That's how you spend your money...
On dames.
An old man like you
that ought to know better.
I ain't like you guys.
These posies are for my wife.
Besides, where do you guys get off
calling me an old man?
Why don't you buy your flowers
after work?
They'll wilt before you get home.
It can't be helped. After work,
the shops will all be closed.
Why don't you put them in some water?
The clubhouse steward
would put 'em in the refrigerator.
Perhaps I should, but...
It's getting late now...
- Why don't I do it for you?
- No!
I was just tryin'
to do you a favor.
The flowers are going in my locker.
Then I'll know where they are.
Okay. Suit yourself.
I'm sorry, bill.
I appreciate your offer.
After work, you know how it is.
Everybody'ii be in a hurry
to get away and...
Third and trumpet king.
It is my baby leading by a length.
Concentrator is second
by three-quarters of a length.
Second ending, moving fast
on the outside, is third.
And trumpet king.
It is my baby, concentrator
and second ending.
It is second ending,
concentrator and trumpet king.
It is second ending and concentrator
down to the wire.
It's second ending the winner
by a half a length.
Concentrator's second by two...
Trumpet king, third,
and my baby.
The result of the first race
now appears on the board.
Be sure to hold all tickets...
Until the result of the race
is declared official.
After the first race,
Mike was very busy.
Give me a double bourbon, please.
Don't you think
you've had enough, pal?
Your attention, please.
The horses are now on the track
for the second race at six furlongs.
At exactly 3:32
that same afternoon...
Officer Randy Kennon set in motion
his phase of the operation.
Hello, Fred.
This is Randy.
Check the dispatcher's office and see if
they've been gettin' me loud and clear.
I think my set's
a little on the blink. Sure.
What? He says it's okay?
That's funny.
It keeps goin' dead.
I don't think it's one of the tubes.
I'll keep foolin' around with it.
Give my regards to your missus.
When's the big day supposed to be?
Well, don't worry about it.
The sixth one is always the hardest.
Officer!
Thank heaven! Hurry! Come quick!
They're killing each other!
I always knew they...
He had timed the trip to the track
on half a dozen different occasions...
And he knew at just what point
he should be at precisely what time.
He knew the entire success of the plan
depended on his accuracy...
In arriving at the track
at exactly the correct moment.
A minute or two early was allowable,
but ten seconds late would be fatal.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
The horses are now on the track
for the seventh race.
The $100,000 added
landsdowne stakes at one mile.
And they're off and running!
At the start it is red lightning
breaking on top.
Early streak is second. I'm hoping
is third. White fire is fourth.
Earlier that afternoon, at 2:30,
Maurice was at the chess club.
He was to be at the track
in position at 4:00...
Just before the start
of the seventh race.
Fisher, I am supposed to be
back here tonight about 6:30.
If I'm not, I'd like you
to do something for me.
Sure. What is it?
I'd like you to call this number
and ask for Mr. stillman...
And tell him
Maurice requires his services.
Sounds pretty mysterious.
What's it all about?
There are some things, my dear fisher,
which do not bear much looking into.
You have undoubtedly heard
of the siberian goatherd...
Who tried to discover
the true nature of the sun.
He stared up at the heavenly body
until it made him blind.
There are many things of this sort,
including love and death.
Please remember to make that call
if I'm not back at 6:30.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
The horses are now on the track
for the seventh race.
The $100,000 added
landsdowne stakes at one mile.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
The horses are now on the track
for the seventh race.
The $100,000 added
landsdowne stakes at one mile.
- Yes, sir?
- Bottle of beer.
The horses are approaching
the starting gate for the seventh race.
The horses are at the gate.
Hey! Can I have some service,
you stupid-looking Irish pig!
What's the matter...
Come on, break it up!
It was exactly 4:23
when they dragged Maurice out.
At 11:40 that morning,
Nikki left his farm.
He arrived at the track at 12:30.
- Hi, there.
- Use the other parking lot.
- I don't like to trouble you.
- You're not troubling me.
There's no parking here,
and that's that.
Look, Mac, I'm a paraplegic...
And I want to get in this lot
to watch the races from my car.
That ain't my problem, mister.
My leg's bum too,
but nobody's feeling sorry for me.
I know what you mean, buddy.
- Get that in the war?
- Battle of the bulge.
Look, I know this is a lot of
extra trouble for you. I want you to...
- No. Skip it.
- I want you to take it.
Now go on, keep it.
It's all right.
- Thanks, mister. I'm sorry...
- Forget it.
Will you take down that fence? I'd like
to settle down before the first race.
- Okay?
- Sure, mister.
Your attention, please. The horses are
now on the track for the second race...
At six furlongs.
I had this layin' around, mister.
I thought you might like to have it.
Thanks.
That's very kind of you.
No trouble at all.
If you need anything else, just call.
I doubt if I'll need anything.
I'm getting along just fine.
But thanks anyway.
Who you bettin' on?
Anything look good to you?
- Red lightning.
- Huh?
- Red lightning in the seventh.
- So you're bettin' on him, huh?
Yeah. I got a little bet
down on him.
I guess I'd better be
gettin' back to work.
- Thanks for bringin' me the program.
- No trouble at all.
You sure there's nothing else
I can do for you?
Nothing at all. If I think of anything,
I can give you a yell.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
The horses are now on the track
for the seventh race.
The $100,000 added
landsdowne stakes at one mile.
The horses are approaching
the starting gate for the seventh race.
- Sure is a nice day, ain't it?
- Yeah.
Didn't think it would be when I first
got up today, but it turned out fine.
Kind of funny
when you stop to look at it.
Weather's almost the same
as it always is this time of year, but...
I sure appreciate
the way you treat me, mister.
It's not so much the money. Of course
I appreciate that too, but it's more...
- Forget it.
- No, sir.
I don't reckon
I'll ever forget it.
I brought you some luck, mister.
I figured you might need it.
Look. Keep your junk
and leave me alone, will you?
- Somethin' wrong?
- You're wrong, nigger!
Be a nice guy
and go on about your business.
Sure, boss.
Sorry to have bothered you.
My mistake.
And they're off and running!
At the start it is
red lightning breaking on top.
Early streak is second.
I'm hoping is third.
White fire is fourth.
Little Arnie is next.
Seymour's Darling and best seller.
Moving down the backstretch, it's
red lightning by a length and a quarter.
I'm hoping is second
by three-quarters of a length.
Little Arnie is third
by a length and a quarter...
And Seymour's Darling.
Passing the half-mile post...
It is red lightning
by a length and a quarter.
I'm hoping is second
by a half a length.
Seymour's Darling is third...
And Little Arnie
moving fast to the outside.
Into the far turn
it is red lightning...
In front by
a length and a quarter.
Little Arnie is second by half a length.
I'm hoping is third.
And a horse is down!
It is red lightning.
At the head of the stretch,
it is I'm hoping...
Taking the lead
by half a length.
Stop! Stop or I'll shoot!
Down to the wire, it is Little Arnie
going steadily, holding it and winning.
Nikki was dead at 4:24.
At 2:15 that afternoon,
Johnny Clay was still in the city.
He knew exactly how long it would
take him to drive to the track...
Park his car
and walk to the grandstand.
He planned to arrive just before
the start of the seventh race.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
The horses are now on the track
for the seventh race.
The $100,000 added
landsdowne stakes at one mile.
The horses are approaching
the starting gate...
For the seventh race.
Hey! How about some service,
you stupid-looking Irish pig!
Money room. Claude here.
Yes, sir, right away.
There's a riot downstairs.
Come on.
And they're off and running!
At the start it is red lightning
breaking on top.
Early streak is second. I'm hoping
is third. White fire is fourth.
Little Arnie is next.
Seymour's Darling
and best seller.
Moving down the backstretch, it's
red lightning by a length and a quarter.
I'm hoping is second
by three-quarters of a length.
Little Arnie is third
by a length and a quarter...
And Seymour's Darling.
Passing the half-mile post, it is
red lightning by a length and a quarter.
I'm hoping is second
by a half a length.
Seymour's Darling is third...
And Little Arnie
moving fast on the outside.
Into the far turn
it is red lightning...
In front by
a length and a quarter.
Little Arnie is second by half a length.
I'm hoping is third.
And a horse is down!
It is red lightning.
At the head of the stretch, it is I'm
hoping taking the lead by half a length.
Little Arnie driving on the outside,
second by three quarters.
Seymour's Darling is third
and early streak.
It is Little Arnie
and Seymour's Darling.
It's Little Arnie in front.
Down to the wire, it is
Little Arnie going steadily...
Holding it and winning it
by three-quarters of a length.
I'm hoping is second
Seymour's Darling
is third by a half...
And white fire finishes fourth.
Your attention, ladies and gentlemen.
Be sure to hold all tickets.
The stewards are conducting an inquiry
into the running of the seventh race...
And they'll view
the motion picture.
Get your hands up!
One move out of any one of you
and I'm gonna start firing.
You! Fill that bag up
just as fast as you know how.
You! Take that gun
out of the holster.
Be awful careful how you do it.
Now drop it.
Kick it over here.
Turn toward the wall.
All right,
now the money in the safe.
Your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
We have received
no exact information...
Concerning the spill of red lightning
in the seventh race.
However, jockey Danny Freed
appears to be unhurt.
- Your attention, ladies and gentlemen.
- Fill it up!
We have received
no exact information...
Concerning the spill of red lightning
in the seventh race.
However, jockey Danny Freed
appears to be unhurt.
All right, that's enough. Now put
the bag in the middle of the floor.
Get back over there.
Now, I'm gonna open this door.
Go through it and go into
the locker room, and close the door.
I'm gonna start firing through that door
15 seconds after you close the door.
Let's go.
Close it!
- Just a minute.
- What are you doing?
We interrupt this broadcast
to bring you a special news bulletin.
In one of the most daring and carefully
executed holdups in criminal history...
A lone bandit wearing a rubber mask
today took an estimated $2 million...
Stuffed into a large duffel bag from the
offices of the landsdowne racetrack.
It occurred during
the running of the seventh race...
And was apparently timed to coincide
with the shooting of red lightning...
Just as the horse, valued at $250,000,
was leading the pack at the far turn.
The jockey, Danny Freed,
escaped with minor injuries.
A man identified as Nikki Arane, who
allegedly shot the prize thoroughbred...
Was himself fatally wounded
by track police...
As he attempted to shoot his way
out of the track parking lot.
At this time, the most baffling mystery
that still plagues the authorities...
Is just how the bandit managed to
successfully get away from the track...
With the bulky duffel bag
containing the money.
A painstaking search of
the track grounds is being conducted...
On the theory that the money
may still be hidden there.
And now we take you back
to our regularly scheduled program.
No one saw the duffel bag
come out of the window.
That part of it worked okay.
Landed right at my feet.
I reported my radio out of order
before I went out to the track.
But the captain ain't buyin' it. He
thinks I was holed up somewhere drunk.
And if the captain's convinced, there
ain't nobody that can un-convince him.
Besides, no one's gonna think anything
of seein' a cop at the racetrack.
I mean, they won't get any funny ideas
about it and tie it in with the robbery.
Anyway, if they do,
it won't cut any ice.
Captain knows I was drunk,
and he ain't a man you can argue with.
So I guess I'll just have to
break down and admit it...
And take my punishment.
Yeah. That would be terrible,
wouldn't it, Randy? A 30-day suspension.
It's 7:15.
Don't worry. He'll get here.
He had to pick up the dough
at the motel where I dropped it.
There was a funny little guy name of Joe
piano there. Runs the place, I guess.
Hope Johnny knows
how to pick his friends.
I need another drink.
Why ain't he here?
Everything else runs on a timetable
till it comes to payin' us our shares.
Then the timetable breaks down.
He was supposed
to be here at 7:00.
- I think I hear the elevator.
- That'll be Johnny.
- Everybody up.
- What is this?
It'll be a massacre
if you don't keep those mitts up.
Where's Johnny?
What time's he due?
I've been sittin' out in that car
since 4:00 listenin' to that radio.
I heard some pretty interesting things.
Grandpa, what time's Johnny comin'?
Somebody give you
a bum steer, buddy.
Look around.
Can't believe you were tipped, huh?
Well, if I had a certain lady here...
- Where's the jerk? Where's George?
- Right here!
Forty minutes before, at 6:25,
Johnny reached the motel.
Due to heavy traffic around the track,
he was 15 minutes behind schedule.
Yeah? Who is it?
Oh, it's just a mistake.
I'm sorry.
Johnny arrived at the meeting place
at 7:29, still 15 minutes late.
It had been prearranged
and agreed to by all...
That in the event of
an emergency before the split...
The money was to be saved by whoever
had possession of it at that time...
Without any consideration
of the fate of the others...
The money to be divided
in safety at a later date.
After what he'd seen, not knowing the
cause or circumstances of the others...
Johnny had no choice
but to save himself and the money.
Ten minutes later, he bought
the largest suitcase he could find.
I'm back here, val Darling.
How'd it go, dear?
- Watch out.
- What happened?
Sherry... Why did you do it?
Do what, dearest?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I was just getting some clothes ready
to go to the cleaners.
So you had to be stupid.
You couldn't even play it smart
with a gun pointed at you.
You better get smart fast and get
out of here while you can still walk.
It's your friend.
Val? Is that his name?
Yes, and you better get out of here
before he gets here.
I'm sick, Sherry.
Call an ambulance.
The door's behind you.
Take a cab.
I love you, Sherry.
You'd better go.
You look terrible.
It isn't fair.
I never had anybody but you.
Not a real husband.
Not even a man.
Just a had joke
without a punch line.
Ain't fair.
American Airlines announces
the arrival of flight 808...
Dc-7 service from Chicago.
Sebastian and I are so excited.
We haven't seen daddy sweetums
for such a long, long time.
Would the nice man let us wait outside
so we could look at the airplanes?
You can stand outside
on the boarding ramp.
We'll be announcing the arrival
of your husband's flight very shortly.
He's a sweetums man,
isn't hims?
Let's hurry up real fast
and see daddy come off the airplane.
- Good evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Raymond Preston,
9:00 flight for Boston.
We'll be announcing the on-time
departure of this flight very shortly.
- Do you have any other baggage?
- It was checked through this morning.
I wanna carry that bag
with me on the plane, please.
I'm sorry. It's much too large. This'ii
have to check through as baggage.
Now, let's be
a little reasonable, huh?
The two of us together are not entitled
to one piece of luggage between us?
We have no objection
to one small bag.
But we don't have anything else.
It's already been checked through.
I see.
Even though it's getting close to flight
time, we can locate your other luggage.
You could transfer the contents
of this to a smaller one.
That won't work at all.
Now look.
Let me talk to
your supervisor, huh?
I'll be very happy to call him.
Mr. grimes?
Mr. grimes, could you
come down this way, please?
- What can I do for you?
- My wife and I are going to Boston.
Our luggage has been checked through,
and I wanna take this bag in the cabin.
It exceeds the maximum cabin size
for flight requirements.
It does look quite a bit too large
for the passenger compartment.
Sir, those are our flight regulations,
designed for your comfort and safety.
- I can't make the trip without it.
- You really can't?
- Absolutely not.
- In that case, I think we can...
I know it's past
cancellation time...
But under the circumstances
I think we might stretch a point.
We'll give you full rebate
on your tickets.
Wait a minute.
I don't want a rebate.
Well, sir, I don't know
what else to suggest.
It's close to flight time.
There are other passengers waiting.
Perhaps the gentleman's
worried about the contents.
- We'd be happy to insure it.
- We'd be delighted.
If you'd give me its estimated value
and tell me what's in it.
There's nothing in it.
Just personal items, things like that.
All right, check it through.
Thank you, sir. You'll find the service
to your complete satisfaction.
Flight 40, the new englander...
Dc-7 service to Boston
at gate eight.
No, Sebastian.
Was we frightened
by the airplane?
We go for trip
on nice airplane someday.
Come back here!
Mr. Preston,
we'll be announcing boarding...
Grimes speaking. What?
Oh, you're not serious?
Right out on the runway?
Yes, sir.
Right away.
Will passenger Preston...
Please report to
the American Airlines ticket counter.
Taxi!
Johnny, you've got to run.