THE DEVILS
"A painting is always
quite moral
"when it is tragic and it gives
the horror
of the things it depicts."
Barbey d'Aurevilly.
"Delassalle Boarding School"
- Monsieur Delassalle...
- Yes.
- It's about time you blew
your horn. - It's okay...
I'll get the things out of
the car.
- Your salads are rotten!
- You aren't paying for them.
Line up, please.
And be quiet.
Oh, what a pain.
- Lovely kids!
- Can't wait for the escape.
Get out!
Do your eyes hurt, dear colleague?
I hurt myself getting up.
You're up early. Last night,
I was doing my rounds...
about 4 A.M., and I heard screams
coming out of your room.
The chaste woman loves to
contemplate dawn, doesn't she?
You spent too much time with the
Jesuits, M. Drain.
Everyone can't be thrown out
of the school system.
Brute!
- "Tiene, Senora."
- Thank you, darling.
Oh, it's so nice!
We all need a vacation.
Our body needs to eliminate
its toxins.
Tomorrow, mademoiselle, I'll be
all naked, and you...
how did you plan this long
weekend?
I'll be home, in Niort.
Deux Sevres. Heard of it?
Sous-Prefecture Maine,
Bressuire and Partenay.
Getting some fresh air?
It warms up my heart, M. Drain.
It still has the smell
of the country.
A graceful instrument,
but with all the rains...
I prefer my old umbrella.
In my country, instead of your
ugly black umbrella...
you'd wear a sombrero
and...
spend your breaks in a hammock.
It's such a frivolous thing
to give an educator.
Does your teacher really look
that way, Jose?
Yes, sir. And he used to come
to school on a horse.
I'll never get used to it.
I told him it was
a horse to please him.
- It was only a mule.
- Go play, Joselito.
- What's the matter?
- Look.
- Miguel.
- Of course, Michel. Who else?
- Did you have another fight?
- He came back at 3 A.M.
How have you stood him for
so long?
He wasn't always that way.
At the beginning, he really
made me happy.
It was for your money.
Why are you trying to be nasty?
Don't you think...
life is hard enough for us?
I may be reactionary...
but this is absolutely
astounding.
The legal wife consoling
the mistress. No, no and no.
- What the hell are you both
doing here? - Nothing.
Nothing. Like kids. Nothing.
Come on and kiss me!
- Did you look at me?
- Are you still angry?
What about you, Cricri,
aren't you kissing your husband?
Let's see...
aren't you supposed to be
on break today?
I told her to stay.
- Don't you see how she looks?
- Exactly. She needs air.
And her shoes. Did you see
the soles?
I've always told her to buy
heavy shoes, the real things.
A sick person shouldn't worry
about her appearance.
- I'm not sick.
- She's delicate, you know it
Delicate? Yes, when she came
from Caracas.
Today, she's a cute little ruin.
She doesn't risk anything.
Ruins are indestructible
She'll bury us all. Won't you,
my little ruin?
That's enough. Go out and play
both of you.
Yes, a black little bottle.
She smelled it like that, and
it wasn't perfume.
I can tell you, they drink.
That's why they're always
together.
- What was in the bottle?
- Whiskey, idiot!
Please, I don't want to hear
about that anymore.
Patard, if you want to spend
your vacation here...
you'll have all the time to draw.
M. Patard, you heard.
You won't go on vacation.
Miguel, what's the matter?
- I didn't want to punish him.
- So don't threaten him.
Patard did very well on
his English quiz.
That's not a reason to
disgrace himself.
I won't have any regrets.
No. I can't. I can't.
I wasn't even able to get
a divorce. So!
- Do you still love him?
- Of course not.
- You can't understand.
- Am I stupid?
- Divorce is a deadly sin.
- Really!
And what about the knife
you carried around for a month...
- Wasn't that a deadly sin?
- I was jealous. I was mad.
But to concoct this thing... No.
As you wish. But think about it.
We'll never find a better
opportunity.
And we have just three days.
Everyone knows I am leaving for
Niort. You'll come and rest.
- Don't you believe in hell?
- Not since I was seven.
I do.
- Fish again.
- Not fish again.
It's the same fish as
last night.
- Make me two fried eggs.
- You're not gonna start, are you?
I put in a liter of vinegar
and a kilo of onions.
I'm not saying it's bad. But,
you can smell that it's fish.
It stinks.
Yes, yes, later, later.
No, thank you.
- Help yourself.
- I'm not hungry.
You must set an example.
My liver doesn't allow me fat.
M. Delassalle, may I ask
for a glass of wine?
- You already had two.
- Only one. Only one.
Well.
"Bonum vinum laetificat
coro mini."
- What is it? A bone?
- I told you I wasn't hungry.
I'm asking you to eat.
- Swallow! - I can't help it.
I just can't.
Swallow.
- Delicious fish, M. Raymond?
- Perfect. Perfect.
It seems extremely nutritious.
What these gentlemen need,
is a little hard time.
Be quiet or I'll keep you all
here this weekend. Swallow.
Everyone is looking at you.
Swallow.
- It's disgusting.
- Sorry?
Some things are hard to swallow.
I'm not talking about the fish.
M. Drain, throw
these hooligans out of here.
What is this supposed to be?
You're going to eat your fish
and shut up.
- I told you to throw them out.
- Yes, sir.
- M. Raymond, go help
your colleague. - Yes, sir.
Get out, everybody. What is this?
Get out and be careful.
What kind of a supper is it
for these growing boys?
A slice of sausage and
two spoons of mashed potatoes?
They should've eaten what
they were served.
- In the army...
- You're not an adjutant
- But a soup merchant. - I can't
buy coalfish for 3000 francs.
You'd rather make them sick.
As a kid, we used to buy whiting.
Coalfish was too expensive.
They need expensive fish.
I buy it but...
at a price that I can afford.
It's a mistake to buy on sale.
The fishmonger is not as stupid
as we are. He knows.
It's not his money. It's mine.
I'm paying for everything here.
I'm paying for the doorkeeper.
And M. Drain.
I even paid Germaine, Sabine,
Therese.
I'm paying you too, Nicole.
I accept it.
But when the kids are involved,
it upsets me. I...
I can't stand it.
Calm down. It's not good for you.
I'd like to die, and not see
him anymore.
Die darling.
Die, and do it quickly.
We'll have a nice funeral for you,
and we'll get rid of you.
The school won't suffer...
and I'll feel much better.
Well, children, have fun.
I have to wake up early.
I'll go and pack.
Well, so...
I'm leaving at 7 A.M.
Have a nice vacation, darling.
Take care. See you, the other one.
Have a nice vacation!
A three day honeymoon.
Oh no. Oh no.
Nicole!
- Nicole! - I'm up here.
I'm coming down.
What are you doing?
Be careful. Move back.
Those riding the bus,
raise your hands.
Will your sister still be
in the bathroom?
If we get there before ten.
You'll see, I made a hole.
- Give me the pack back!
- You'll see my sister naked.
- It's worth a pack a cigarettes.
- No! Give them back to me!
Soudieu, aren't you part of
our group?
No. We'll share a cab,
the four of us.
Money is pouring out of
your pockets.
Don't you have a suitcase,
de Gasquet?
The chauffeur will take it.
He's being paid for that.
Our personal chauffeurs don't do
their job right, dear friend.
Have a nice vacation, sir.
- You too
- Thank you.
Plantiveau, did madame come down?
I was ringing the bell when
they drove through the gate.
- I opened it.
- Both of them?
Madame Delassalle and
Mademoiselle Horner.
I thought you knew.
Of course, I knew. I just forgot.
Except that it's a problem.
Especially for these gentlemen.
One of you must stay to watch
those on detention.
- You'll feel funny about coming
back to Niort. - Why?
- That's where you had troubles
in high school. - Troubles...
I resigned, that's all.
- Do you still have your parents?
- No.
I've got a couple of teachers
living on the first floor.
- What? There are people in
the house? - I thought about it.
I thought about everything.
We are not risking a thing.
You're tired. Do you want me
to drive?
You can't drive.
I could never afford a car.
- This way, I cannot think.
- Good. So keep driving.
Keep your nerves for tomorrow.
We'll never have the courage.
- You don't know me.
- Yes, I know you very well.
You can wish someone's death,
but kill...
You must've wished my death,
didn't you?
I didn't. But he did.
He would say to me...
"Don't worry. With her heart
condition, it won't take long.
"After she dies, we'll share
the school."
It's horrible!
Don't you believe me?
What did you answer?
- Do you want me to be honest?
- Can you?
- I didn't know you that well...
- Don't talk.
I'd rather not know.
Watch the step.
MIle. Horner!
What a surprise!
Don't bother.
What a huge trunk.
It always upsets M. Herboux
when I take...
- more than a suitcase.
- Good evening.
Mme. Herboux, M.A. In grammar.
Mme. Delassalle, my principal.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hello.
Don't forget my rent.
By check, please.
Don't torture me.
I'm so embarrassed.
I thought of giving it to you
tomorrow or the day after.
But we didn't get paid for
the examinations in Vausson.
We were counting on that money.
But don't worry...
- I'll come tonight.
- No need. I'll come up tomorrow.
We're a little tired tonight.
Yes, she looks sick.
Make yourself at home.
Home, sweet home.
Turn off the light. It's a waste.
- Already? - Let's do it now and
forget about it.
Hello, operator. I'd like
a line to St. Cloud.
The number is Molitor 27.45.
Thank you.
I like to have my feet free.
When it's cold...
I put on ski socks instead
of slippers.
Well, what are you waiting for?
You see, it doesn't bite.
And it doesn't slap either.
Hello? Who is it?
Answer, for God's sake!
It's you!
From Niort. My compliments!
Do you think I can afford to send
you away in the Poitou?
What about the gas?
What are you talking about?
I'm telling you that
we need to separate.
Yes, I want a divorce.
You are young, you are strong.
You can make a nice living.
The school was part of my dowry,
so I'll take it back.
We'll start the proceedings
right after the holidays.
- What? - Don't give me that crap.
I'm coming.
I'll take a train
tomorrow morning.
I'll meet you at Nicole's.
- So? - He's coming tomorrow
on the evening train.
Well, Germaine?
You're nuts. You'll catch cold.
I'm not cold.
I'm suffocating.
- You've got fever.
- No, I'm just hot.
I thought you'd never come back.
That he'd get here before you.
It doesn't always go
as you want it to.
That's life. Everything was
closed.
Did you buy a tablecloth?
Yes, a nylon, waterproof one.
- It's too big!
- It won't be big for him.
Guess how much?
2500 francs.
That's how they make money.
Let's open it.
That way it won't look weird.
Well, let's not waste it.
- Here, it will cheer you up.
- No.
You should, it's not bad at all.
I've never had that before.
- You're supposed to put water in it.
- It would be a waste.
Hand me the small bottle.
- Won't he notice anything?
- Not a thing.
He'll sleep like a log.
- Will it leave any traces?
- None.
It's a sedative.
He'll digest it.
I'm sure he won't come.
That's him. That's his train.
Put that over there.
Stop, please, stop.
It's awful.
- We must fill it up.
- I can't do it.
I can't do it, not today.
We must do it, and you know it
as well as I do.
- It's either today or never.
- Then never!
Let's forget about it.
I can't handle this.
As you wish. But I must
warn you.
If you miss your chance
he won't miss his.
Not after your phone call.
I don't know. I just don't know
anymore.
Nicole, please, help me.
What for? It's beyond
your strength anyway.
I should have never trusted you.
I got involved too, and
you abandoned me.
Yes, you're right.
I'm not worth anything.
I'm just a ruin,
a little ruin.
That's what he said. But...
the little ruin will get
her revenge. She'll do it.
Even if she collapses afterward.
My only regret...
is that he'll never know
that I killed him.
Come on, before you were
giving up, now you're excited.
What you need is to relax.
Relax a lot. You must keep cool.
I will. I swear that I will.
I must go upstairs and see them.
Can't you stay with me?
If the Herbouxes look out
the window and...
- see him come in...
- You'll come right away, won't you?
As fast as I can, I promise.
Be brave, in half an hour,
it will all be over.
I'll find her a husband.
I'll redeem myself.
She's young, she'll be rich
and she'll be happy.
I wasn't expecting you tonight.
Mme. Delassalle is resting
and I'm not tired.
- May I come in?
- Please, do.
We were listening to the radio.
We've finished eating.
The drama is over.
Zapi Max starts in a few seconds.
Dear listeners, you've just heard...
"One Should Never Laugh
at Love" by Alfred de Musset.
God!
- Good evening, Michel.
- Good evening.
Come in.
So, are you proud of yourself?
Not so loud, the neighbors.
Don't worry. I don't want
to be noticed.
A man who runs after his wife
is ridiculous enough.
I left the school like a thief.
I had to hide from Plantiveau.
Hiding from my own doorkeeper!
It's humiliating.
I couldn't tell him where
I was going.
You have forced me to come,
what are you waiting for?
- What?
- Pack your bags.
- No!
- What?
- I'm staying.
- Are you refusing to come?
I thought that was clear.
I'll come back after our divorce.
- Have you decided to get a divorce,
you? - Yes.
With your religious beliefs?
I won't get married again,
that's all.
But getting a divorce is
like getting married...
we must both agree.
- My lawyer doesn't think so.
- You have a lawyer?
- Attorney Berthoux, 64 Victor Hugo.
- Berthoux?
You can check in the phone book.
I went to see him this morning...
and he assured me that I'd get
the legal separation quickly.
He told you that?
Funny lawyer!
- Of course, I told him...
- You told him...
all of our secrets...
about our private life.
You told everything to
a stranger?
An animal who enjoyed
every word of it?
You, the former nun!
I'm telling you, it's
disgusting!
Didn't you talk about us
to your lovers?
Do we still have secrets?
Is there anything that Nicole
doesn't know?
Her! If you believe her!
Two words, three lies.
There are details that
she couldn't have invented.
She can invent anything!
God knows what she told
the lawyer!
- I'll go see him, and put
things straight. - No!
- You won't stop me.
- No, later. Tomorrow.
- Right now, he must be having
supper -Well, I didn't eat.
- He won't receive you.
- We'll see.
When I tell him that I came
all the way from Paris...
Don't. I didn't see a lawyer.
I lied to you.
You too. It's contagious.
So, what about the divorce,
was that a lie too?
No, I really want the divorce.
It's the only way.
For your sake as well, Michel.
- It will be better for both
of us. - Come on, Cricri.
You can't be serious. Do you
know the price of a divorce?
- And what about the scandal?
- What scandal?
I'll have to take a lawyer
to defend myself.
And lawyers never stop talking.
Parents won't entrust you with
their children.
- They'll take the children away
from me? - Of course.
You'll go bankrupt.
Not that I care much.
If it were up to me, I would
have sold it a long time ago.
With your money and my contacts
I'd have gone into business.
We could have lived comfortably.
But you wanted this kid
business. I gave in.
- It was security.
- Big deal!
We traded in the big car for
a small one.
I gave up my training.
I used my old suits.
We are rich and we live like
poor people.
Do you know how I paid for
my trip?
I sold my dictionary,
my big dictionary.
And I did that for you.
Believe me that I don't regret
a thing.
But when you throw me out...
it upsets me, Cricri.
It upsets me a lot.
But anyway, you made me feel
miserable.
We used to fight, like
every other couple.
Well, girls, what about this!
Wait. Don't lie. You mustn't
lie now.
You made me very unhappy.
You might not have been aware
of that, but it's the truth.
- Ask Nicole.
- Please, don't talk about...
that bitch. She's setting you up
against me.
She exploits the fact that
you're sick. She has a good mind.
Yes. She's got knowledge,
taste...
- Taste? - Maybe. But
she doesn't have a good mind.
That's it. I'm firing her
right away...
and we'll replace her with a man.
A good, honest, old man.
- Michel! - For God's sake!
My Prince of Wales suit!
You idiot! Go get
a handkerchief, a towel!
It will stain and I'll
stink of alcohol.
Just go!
Here and here.
It doesn't pay to be nice
to you.
I will break you, girl.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Bring some hot water.
We're leaving now and we'll be
back tomorrow morning.
How long did you have to drive?
Ten, twelve hours?
Well, answer!
Can't you talk?
Eh, woman, another glass!
I don't know... I feel dizzy.
You can't measure anymore.
That's enough.
Nice color.
Stop looking at me with
your insane eyes.
Who's paying? The princess?
By the way, where is she?
Is she scared? Hiding?
She's upstairs visiting
the tenants.
Mademoiselle has tenants.
She never told me that.
- I'm exhausted. It's the train.
- Just lie down.
- Whose bed is this? Hers or yours?
- Ours.
That's a scream.
Shoes. Take off my shoes.
What's the matter with me
tonight?
I don't want to sleep.
We have to leave.
What are you doing?
- Just sleep.
- Why did you turn off the light?
I'm so tired!
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. Go to sleep.
- How did you get in?
- I came through this door.
- How many drinks did he have?
- Three.
He was very good.
He's dreaming.
He's ready. We can take him.
Take off his shoes.
- What the hell is she doing?
- She's taking a bath.
At 10 P.M.? Funny habits.
Oh, shit!
Tell me, sir, where are the
Straits of Mozambique?
Between Madagascar and Africa!
It is precisely located
between Madagascar...
and the Coast of Africa.
Bravo, sir!
32,000 francs!
I must ask you now:
What do you want to do?
- Do you stop or do you carry on?
- I will go on.
Of course, I carry on.
I was winning 32,000 francs and
I can't hear a thing now!
- Poor baby! - Bitches! Bitches!
Daughters of bitches!
I didn't even hear the question!
Midnight baths! The decline
of Rome!
It's a problem of enjoyment!
I have the right to send her
a registered letter.
And I'm not saying that
I won't do it.
The 17th at 10:05, 06 P.M.
- What are you looking for?
- His return ticket.
Here it is.
With the restaurant bill.
Burn it.
Let's go. You take the feet.
It's lighter.
Together.
The bronze...
The bronze on the mantel
Give it to me.
Now, the tablecloth.
The tablecloth.
It's over.
Did he suffer too much?
He didn't feel anything.
Let's go right away and bring
him back tonight.
What about our alibi?
When they find him, we'll have
to be able to prove...
that we were here the day
he died.
That's why I'm using
the idiots upstairs.
She still hasn't emptied the tub.
- So what?
- So I can't go to sleep.
When she opens the drain,
the noise will start again.
It won't fall on your bed.
I can't sleep under
Niagara Falls.
- Are you planning to stay up
all night? - I'm sitting down.
I'll give her until midnight.
- Here they are!
- They took their time.
When I passed by the cafe,
at twelve...
they were already there.
They must know how much
it costs them.
- Lf you were a landlord, and
I a school principal... - Sure.
We could also afford good meals.
Well, I'm going to take a nap.
Here we go, the flood!
- What's the matter?
- He's so ugly!
I've had it! They must get
the hell out of here!
Too bad you're leaving us
so soon.
It was so nice to have
company...
You know, school is starting
tomorrow.
For us as well as for you.
I just came to take my dishes.
It's quite heavy.
Wait a minute. Would you have
a piece of string?
A piece of string? No.
Wait. This might help you.
I'll try, yes.
Let me do it. It'll be easier
for you.
It won't work. Your trunk is
crammed too full.
- Let's take some things out.
- No, no.
Yes. I'll bring you the old
tin trunk.
It's very strong. It went
through the 1940 retreat.
- Start emptying the basket!
- No, it'll be fine.
- We're already late, aren't we,
Nicole? - That's what I told them.
Anyway, it's fine now.
We can load.
Attention! Clear the way!
On my command. One, two!
Now, it'll be easy.
A little kick in the ass.
I'll start the engine.
- That's it!
- As you say!
M. Herboux,
thank you for your help.
- Don't mention it.
- All the same...
- Here, this is for the road.
- Thank you, madame.
Drive carefully, the roads are
dangerous.
They have mobilized 1500
policemen.
You'll find one at every
crossroad.
Goodbye, madame.
And thank you again.
- Have a good trip.
- See you soon!
It won't be this time.
- A little bit earlier, or later.
- Great...
There is only one possible end.
We are monsters.
I don't like monsters.
If it's only him, I feel better.
Because...
the grain of sand falling off
the hands of providence...
I'll keep that for
my Sunday school lesson.
Well, don't stop!
It is about time!
All the gas stations were empty!
No wonder! It was crazy today.
Wait. There is always some
left in the bottom.
- 963 francs. - I only have
a 5,000 franc bill.
Come with me.
I'll get some change.
- Are you going to Tours?
- No, I'm not.
Could you give me a lift?
The bus driver wouldn't
take me.
He's anti-militarist, like me.
We are already two. Can't you
see there's no room?
I won't take room.
A second class soldier.
If I don't report,
they'll put me in jail.
Have some pity for a soldier.
Leave me alone. You're drunk.
Me? Hey you!
I'm being polite. And if
that's the way it is...
I'll just get into your car.
I won't let you. Do you hear me?
Nicole! Would you get out!
- What is it?
- Don't worry.
He's drunk. I know him.
He's not a bad guy.
You should be ashamed
of yourself, Robert.
Get out of here, or I'll push you
out myself.
The pig. What did he do?
The floor is all wet.
I'll clean it.
No, no need. We're in a hurry.
Thank you.
Start the car. There's a hole
in the nylon!
- Did you hear that?
- It sounds like the boss.
- He decided to come back.
- It's about time!
Is this the time to make all
this racket?
If we only ring,
Plantiveau won't open.
Three short strokes,
that's Michel's signal.
Plantiveau is a heavy sleeper.
I'll wake him up myself!
- Come on Plantiveau!
- It's you?
I thought it was M. Delassalle.
What? Isn't he here?
Do I know? Ask him when
you see him.
- You look tired.
- Are you surprised?
You can go.
- Sorry to have awakened you.
Good night -Good night.
Turn off the light.
For our number...
- we don't need spotlights.
- No music either!
Oh, not now.
- That's the bathroom light
- It's Pascual.
I heard he gets up every night.
He might be able to look out
the window.
- Can we see him from here?
- No.
Either the water is too dirty,
or we're too far away.
I'm telling you that we can't
see anything.
What's the point in staying here?
We're not supposed to discover
the body.
- Close the window. It's freezing.
- Shut up. It stinks in here.
Good news. The principal
didn't come back.
- He's in heat. - He's already got
two chicks. Isn't that enough?
Of course, not. When I grow up,
I'll have a lot.
Look at Napoleon and
Louis XIV.
All the big men used to have
a lot of chicks.
- Do you think you're Napoleon?
- I'm Falcon Eye.
M. Moinet, stop playing the fool.
I'm not a fool.
I am an Indian.
Then you can write:
"My absurd comments provoke...
"my friends' hilarity",
20 times.
What do I hear?
The principal is missing?
This is the third time,
dear friend...
that I drink my wine,
chemically pure.
Where is he? I saw him
the day before yesterday...
around eight o'clock. By
twelve, he was already gone.
And he didn't show up again?
That's not like him.
Poor Mme. Delassalle.
She has enough troubles already.
If she's no more worried than
I am, he can stay where he is.
But believe me,
he'll be back soon.
And we'll start drinking
bad wine again.
Did you notice?
This afternoon...
it seemed that he pretended
not to see the body.
The body was at the bottom.
- Do you think it will rise?
- It has to.
- When?
- How should I know?
- Tonight. Tomorrow morning.
- It makes me nervous.
We cannot ask to empty the pool.
Try to understand.
It's natural to empty a pool
when the water is dirty.
What we find inside
won't be natural at all.
I'll take the responsibility
for this.
In order to take responsibilities,
you have to be an adult.
You think like a child.
You're not worth anything.
How can you grade papers?
By mistake I just wrote
complete nonsense
- Well, erase it.
- I don't have an eraser.
If his body doesn't come up
by tomorrow...
I'll manage to have the pool
emptied.
And I hope we won't regret it.
Don't bite your nails.
I was not in the game.
- Look!
- I was expecting that.
Don't bring attention to it.
- I told you not to look.
- Do something!
My heart is about to explode.
You promised yesterday.
Give me the keys. We'll move
things faster.
That was clever. Go and bring
the pole.
Me! Me! Me!
Soudieu! Let's test you
on a 100 meters.
As for you, you need
some training in the shot put.
You're lucky. You have
a champion skin diver here.
- Soudieu! I forbid you!
- Let him! He's a champion!
What's happening?
It's taking him too long.
He might be drowning.
Did you see the bubbles?
Did you get them?
Say something!
I found it. It was shining
in the mud.
It looks like M. Delassalle's
lighter.
- And you didn't see...
- The keys!
It's chocolate soup
at the bottom.
Go get dressed. Don't catch
cold. We'll manage.
I think we'll have to empty
the pool.
You're right.
Send Plantiveau over.
What are you waiting for?
Plantiveau...
It's deep where you're standing.
- It's all right. I can swim.
- So what?
A lot of people who can swim
drown.
Because the ones who can't
stay away from the edge.
- I want you to empty the pool.
- Right now?
I'm not dressed for it.
I was going to the barber.
Do it now, Plantiveau.
It's urgent.
- Do it for me. - All right.
The fish will wait.
Only to empty
the pool will take an hour.
She's upset. Be cool.
Why are you staring at me?
Is something wrong with me?
Again. The surface of
a hexagon...
in relation to the radius
of the circumference?
Well, I'm waiting.
I'm waiting...
- 6 AB x 1/2 OH. - Thank you.
Good. Go back to your seat.
Take out your notebooks.
Wait a minute. I'll be back soon.
M. Plantiveau!
What happened to her?
It can't be true.
It's impossible!
- I didn't see well!
- You saw very well!
- He isn't there anymore?
- No, he isn't.
- Come in. What is it?
- It's the doctor, mademoiselle.
I think it comes from
the open space, the empty pool.
She suffers from agoraphobia,
and she got dizzy.
- It's possible.
- Nature abhors a vacuum.
An empty pool isn't worth
a full bottle, Plantiveau.
Is she feeling any better,
dear colleague?
Dr. Loisy is with her.
You'll take her pupils for
study hall, M. Raymond...
and you, M. Drain, watch
my class for a few minutes.
Mme. Delassalle might still
need me.
Of course. Did you notice?
She gives orders now.
- So, doctor?
- That's what we should all expect.
When it's used, it's used.
Where is the husband?
He should come here fast.
In the meantime, no emotions,
no vexations. Spare her.
Don't you think a specialist...
If you want, I'll call Bridoux.
He's 60 years old, but he's got
the best ear in Paris...
and he's the finest gourmet!
For him a meal is a meal.
Anyway, give her some
digitalis.
- The doctor said... - I don't care.
Close the shutters and go.
No. It would be too easy.
Much too easy.
Does a corpse that disappears
seem natural to you? Not to me.
If he's not in the pool,
someone took him out.
I asked Plantiveau if he
opened the door for anyone.
- He said no one.
- Why would he lie?
If no one went out...
the body should be around here.
I've searched everywhere.
The attic, the basements,
the garden. There's nothing.
No dirt, no footsteps.
There's nothing.
My head is about to explode.
It's crazy.
It's been crazy since
the beginning.
Not even a kid's game.
You took one of your
word problems
with leaking taps,
and tanks that empty...
and you planned
a murder from it.
In real life, this kind
of thing does not exist.
Bathtubs that we fill up,
swimming pools that we empty.
That was crazy. And I was
crazy to listen to you.
Come in!
Somebody brought back
monsieur's suit.
The one he's been wearing
lately.
- The Prince of Wales.
- Who brought it back?
- The dry-cleaner.
- What dry-cleaner?
I don't know. He came
on a bicycle.
He looked at the street name...
and asked again if it was
the right address.
A very conscientious
little guy.
Get to the point.
He said it was from
M. Delassalle.
So I asked him: "Did you see
M. Delassalle? Where?"
So he said:
"I didn't see him"...
but he asked me to bring
the suit home, urgently.
Well, should I hang it up
in the closet?
No. Leave it here.
It is his suit.
That's completely insane!
Wait.
Rue St. Ferdinand.
- Good morning.
- Excuse me.
Did you deliver a suit
this morning in St. Cloud?
- What's the name?
- Mme. Delassalle.
- Was there a problem?
- No. We just want to know who...
- brought this suit to you.
- We see so many of them!
If I remember well, it was
a tall thin man, dark hair...
with a bamboo cigarette holder.
There's a check mark.
The kid forgot something.
It was in his pocket.
Eden Hotel. Room nine.
Your husband seems to be
leading some life!
I can have the kid bring
the key, if you wish.
Do you know this hotel, madam?
It's a residential hotel.
Very cozy.
Come on!
First street on the right.
Number 27.
- I'll go.
- What if they ask you something?
It looks like
they don't ask questions here.
Don't go, it's a trap. Someone
wants to blackmail us.
At least, we'll know with whom
we are dealing.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm looking for M. Delassalle.
He's never here during
the day.
- When does he come back?
- Who knows if he comes back at all.
His bed is always neat. See,
no belongings, no bags.
Nothing. Some weird guest.
Did you ever see him?
Never, neither did
the doorkeeper.
He must come, after I leave...
and before the other guy
starts his shift.
But, why all these questions?
He's my husband.
I am Mme. Delassalle.
Poor lady! This isn't where
you should look for him.
You can trust me. His life
is somewhere else.
It's scary. What's happening
to us?
I don't know.
No one knows.
It doesn't make any sense.
80,000 francs. Shower repair,
and it's two years old.
Ah, this time it smells
the bailiff.
Pay them half. It's already
something.
- He was really dead, wasn't he?
- You're the one who should know.
- Why are you saying that?
- You killed him, didn't you?
- Me? - You are the one
who planned the whole thing.
I'm sorry, we planned it...
and you made the phone call.
You bought the tablecloth
to wrap him...
the drug to put him
to sleep.
I would have been unable
to do that.
- But you made him drink!
- You liar! I didn't want to!
You know I didn't want to!
You could've let him sleep
his whiskey off...
instead of carrying him
to the tub.
Who filled up the tub?
Who pushed him under water?
And who brought the bronze
from the mantel?
It's too easy.
You'll see whom the court will
hold responsible.
- You'll see.
- The court doesn't scare me.
We'll get what we deserve.
Well, suit yourself!
Go to the police! Go!
- I thought of that.
- To put the whole thing on me!
I won't let this happen.
I'll call the cops first!
Call them, but I'm warning you,
I'll tell them everything!
I have nothing to hide.
You were jealous, and killed him.
And I helped you because
I felt pity for you.
You were jealous because
it was over between you two.
You killed him,
and you know it!
So, what are you waiting for?
- Do you have my newspapers?
- Yes.
Be careful not to get dirty.
The ink is still wet.
- Christina!
- I have nothing to tell you.
- Where are you going?
- To confession. Do you mind?
Do you think you'll get absolution
if you don't turn yourself in?
- So I'll turn myself in.
- What about me?
I can't keep this up.
Come on, don't worry.
It's all over.
They found the body.
Read this.
"A Naked Corpse in the Seine"
- Why in the Seine? - What counts
is that they found him.
Everything fits.
The description...
The Bois de Boulogne bridge
which is very close...
a three day old death.
Our alibi is holding up.
They brought him to the morgue.
I read this, and I think
it's my husband.
Identity card.
Could you describe
M. Delassalle?
Dark hair, thin, dark eyes.
All this has already been written
in the paper. It's too easy.
- I want details.
- What do you want to know?
I don't know. You tell me.
If you tell me he had
an appendectomy...
- it's a detail.
- He's had the operation.
- Dentition. How many teeth?
- All of them, I think.
- Fillings?
- Maybe one or two.
- One or two?
- Two.
- Beauty marks?
- Yes.
- Where?
- On his shoulder.
Why didn't you tell me
he had a bracelet?
- He never had one!
- Really!
- What do you see on
his right thigh? - Nothing.
Try to think, above the knee.
I can't see anything.
So it must be a mistake.
Bring up number 4702.
You were right.
No bracelet and
nothing above the knee.
Please, follow me
to the identification room.
- It's not him.
- Are you sure?
- Yes! - I'm sorry, madame.
This rarely happens.
Taxi! To St. Cloud!
St. Cloud? Now?
Are you out of your mind?
I don't want to have supper
on a merry-go-round!
Excuse me...
Here we go!
Aren't you feeling well, lady?
Maybe it's the emotion.
The reaction only comes after,
doesn't it?
You should feel better since
it's not him.
Drive.
Do you feel better?
Let me introduce myself.
Alfred Fichet,
retired police commissioner.
But I didn't ask the police
for anything!
Didn't you inform
the police commissioner?
It was a mistake.
That's what they are for.
I didn't think about it.
I'll do it.
I'll do it myself. Just
out of principle.
One should not expect too much
from the regular police.
The police are too busy.
No. If you'd like, we are both
going to find your husband.
40 years on the job,
it's not to be ignored.
Now, I have plenty of time.
- No. Really, it's not necessary.
- What do you risk?
If I don't find anything,
you won't pay me anything.
And if I find something...
well, you'll judge for yourself.
You can't ask for a better deal.
Let's see.
- You've been married...
- Eight years.
- I don't understand what...
- Leave it to me. I know.
We are saying eight years.
It's boiling, mademoiselle.
- How long do you think
it can boil? - Five minutes.
How do I know.
He had his own keys.
He would go in, and out.
He was the boss.
And it was vacation anyway.
- Was he a little low-spirited?
- It was not his style.
It was more in his nature
to complicate his life.
- Maybe he was feeling sick.
- Couldn't be.
The man was very strong.
When he was younger, he was
a tennis champion.
Did he get a telegram
on Sunday?
A phone call? Sometimes, people
leave after a phone call.
I can't tell you, sir.
This Sunday I took my wife
to the park...
and when the school is closed,
we seize the opportunity.
There might be the hypothesis
of the accident.
Did M. Delassalle used
to drive fast, very fast?
He didn't have the car.
The women took it to Niort.
That's right. Don't you think
he could've drowned?
Drowned? He was a real fish.
This man could swim.
I see. Well, thank you.
The Alps separate Italy from
France in the southeast.
The Alps are very high
mountains.
There is Mont-Blanc,
the highest mountain in Europe.
In the east, there is the Jura...
That is quite reassuring.
I think you worried
a little bit too early.
On Saturday, your husband
was still here.
It's only been five days, and
you go look for him at the morgue.
The article in the paper
upset me.
A 30 year old man,
one meter seventy...
Dear madame, there are 100,000
men in Paris who fit...
this description. And this
doesn't include the tourists.
I guess you were thinking
of suicide.
Yes. Well, I don't know.
To commit suicide in the Seine,
one doesn't need to undress.
My hypothesis is much less
tragic.
When I say hypothesis,
I mean...
A woman! Of course, you're right.
I was stupid to worry and
to bother you.
- Take this.
- No, no. I won't steal your money.
Remember our agreement.
If I don't find out anything,
you don't owe me anything.
But, don't worry, I'll find him.
I haven't been
in a school for a long time.
In my days, it was
the local school. Charonne.
Less fancy. Much less fancy.
Ah, it was really different.
You emptied the pool.
You thought about this too.
- Not at all!
- Why not at all?
I dropped my keys in the pool.
- So in order to get them back...
- When was that?
- Yesterday. - Commissioner
Fichet. MIle. Horner.
- Our most devoted associate.
- Hello.
It was pure coincidence.
Really, the keys in the pool,
the husband in the morgue...
You dream too much about water
in this house!
May I look at his mail?
- You'll never find him.
- How do you know anyway?
- I see he has a typewriter.
- Yes, for the accounts.
You're right. M. Delassalle
is not a literary man.
Perhaps he doesn't trust
his spelling.
May I? I seriously can't
imagine him that desperate.
Let's take this seriously.
So we're saying:
Delassalle Michel...
- 34 years old...
- One meter seventy.
- Yes, I know. Dark hair. Eyes?
- Brown.
Average nose, ears... folded in.
How to find someone with
this description?
Well, we'll find him.
These pigs are so strong!
What was he wearing
the day he disappeared?
We were away that day, sir.
Of course! How stupid of me.
Here's what we'll do.
We'll look into
his wardrobe...
and we'll see what is missing.
One, two, three,
four, five, six. Six.
- What did the 7th pair look like?
- Brown suede.
- Tie?
- Red, with a white stripe.
You're sharp-eyed. He's got
at least 25 ties.
So, suit?
Suit!
So you know his ties
better than his suits.
I think it's a Prince of Wales,
grey.
Prince of Wales, grey.
- Like this one?
- Yes.
- Wait a minute.
- Is something wrong?
Mme. Delassalle has a heart
condition. We must spare her.
You should have told me.
It's not that urgent. I've got
enough to keep myself busy.
Take care of yourself.
I'll go visit downtown.
I still have friends there.
And don't worry. I'll be back.
- Plantiveau said he's a detective.
- A private one.
Everybody to the firing squad!
Heberge, if you're done with
your work...
I'll find something else
for you to do.
First, Latin. When the Middle Ages
lost everything...
they still knew Latin.
The Church understood it.
The last village priest
knew Latin.
I don't think that
the average priest...
is that clever.
It's not his job.
M. Moinet, what are you
doing here?
Aren't you supposed
to be studying?
- The principal punished me.
- Who?
- The principal.
- What are you talking about?
- It's the truth.
- What did you do?
I broke a window.
Maybe the principal came back.
Stop talking nonsense.
Tell me the truth, now.
- Who punished you?
- The principal.
- That's for lying!
- I'm not lying.
Let me handle this.
You're scaring him.
Tell me your story again.
And if you tell everything,
I'll lift your punishment.
- How did you break the window?
- With my slingshot.
- Then what happened?
- The principal opened the door...
and told me to go to bed
right away...
without picking up
the dead leaves.
It can't be him.
It's impossible.
You know he's not here.
You forget that this kid
is a pathological liar.
Last week, he told his friends
he had a fight...
with a lion at the fair.
With a lion!
He's a mythomaniac.
I just asked the other kids.
Nobody saw the principal.
But there really is
a broken window in the corridor.
He punished himself in order
to create this story.
Who knows? Obviously...
this is a case of
self-induced hallucination.
The kid broke a window
and in his subconscious...
he generated the idea
of punishment...
to match the principal's.
Darkness did the rest.
- Do you really think so?
- No. The kid saw himself...
being punished in the literal
sense of the word.
I think he's kidding us...
in the literal sense of the word.
- Give me your slingshot.
- The principal took it.
Don't you think you're a little
out of line?
I feel tired. I'm going
to sleep.
- Suit yourself.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight. Go get some rest.
M. Moinet. We've been
patient enough.
If you want to be stubborn...
go straight to the corner.
You'll get out only
after you tell the truth.
We'll see who gets tired
first.
I saw him. I saw him.
- Moinet couldn't have brought
this slingshot. - Certainly not.
- So who could've done that?
- It could be anyone.
- It's a coincidence.
- Coincidence!
Fichet at the morgue,
was a coincidence.
And the suit, and the hotel,
and now the students.
Is it a coincidence that
it's getting closer each time?
Please, calm down. My nerves
are going as well.
It's all getting clear.
There are no miracles in life.
Unfortunately.
Each time I close my eyes...
it seems that I'm going to see
him.
Don't talk. He must already
be in some condition.
Yes, if he's dead.
Listen, I've seen dead people
in my life.
Believe me, Michel is dead.
Really dead.
Lie down and try not to think
of anything.
With all I have on my mind...
If you don't get any sleep,
you won't last three days.
Dr. Loisy is very worried.
He asked Prof. Bridoux
to come tomorrow.
There you are!
What's the point now?
I'm finished.
- Stop that.
- Give me back my marbles.
- I don't have them.
- You took them, I know.
- I'm going to break your neck!
- Leave me alone!
- Give him back his marbles.
- Leave me alone.
- I haven't got them. Stop it!
- Come on, come on!
You can fight, but don't scream.
Mme. Delassalle is very sick.
Moinet, your punishment is
lifted... for now.
- Go for your picture.
- Thank you, sir.
A picture without the principals,
is not a school picture.
We'll do better next year.
Come on, children.
Do we put the bench in front
of the window?
- Why not in front of the door?
- What about the car?
There is a professor
from the university upstairs.
I must go. It's part of the job.
I'll show the professor out,
and I'll call you.
You overdid it.
You should really have a good rest.
- Will I be able to get up?
- We'll talk about this later.
- You will be fine here.
- Could I go out into the yard?
- Is it too much for me?
- Until the doctors say so...
you are not supposed to move.
Let's do it. Look at my hand.
Don't move.
One, two. Thank you. One minute.
I'll take another one.
You can go through.
Taking her to my clinic
would have been too expensive.
Between you and me,
there are no heirs.
I know. But people dying
in the clinic...
the hearse in front of the door,
I don't like that.
Neither do the patients.
- Let me see! - Be careful, kids.
It's still wet.
Great. Nobody moved.
Please... I came out fine.
This is the first time I've
had the position of honor.
When I show the picture,
they'll think I'm the principal.
- What do I see behind
the window? - Looks like the boss.
- You're nuts!
- Wait! Let me put my monocle on.
- Let me see, mademoiselle!
- Leave me alone!
- I didn't see anything?!
- You didn't miss anything.
It's some kind of shot-silk
effect.
The reflection of a cloud or
some spot on the window...
that reminds us of
the principal's features.
Maybe it's him!
He didn't want to interrupt us...
or this was just an innocent joke.
I can't see Delassalle playing
hide-and-seek.
But you, didn't you see
anything?
I was looking at the group,
being sure to see everybody.
Let's settle this once and
for all. Moinet.
You're such a great observer.
Did you see the principal?
Six hours in the corner,
thank you, that's enough!
The case is closed.
There wasn't anyone.
Thankfully. Really.
To hear people saying...
that people go in and out
of here...
without me knowing it, it's
offensive for a doorkeeper.
- I'm afraid.
- Me too.
We must go now.
Here, get dressed!
The doctors forbid me to move.
Where would we go, anyway?
To my place.
In Niort? Don't you think
he might be there as well?
He's more certainly there,
than anywhere else.
So, we'll travel, we'll go
anywhere.
It's not possible.
There's no point.
- I can't stay here anymore.
- So, just go.
What about you?
I can't leave you here.
Yes. You'll see. And you'll
get used to managing without me.
Besides, I don't want to see
you anymore.
For all that's about to happen...
for all that will eventually
happen...
I'd rather be on my own.
No, no, please!
- You hate me, don't you?
- Not at all.
Where is the little red
suitcase I gave you?
On the floor, by the closet.
So you really think it's time
for us to separate?
Yes, it'll be better that way.
- I hope you succeed and forget.
- Farewell, Christina.
"Tremble, she told me,
a girl worthy of me.
"The cruel God of the Jews is
stronger than you.
"I pity you for falling
in his fearsome hands."
- What are you doing here?
- I was just looking at you.
I came to make my report.
That's what I'm paid for.
But you were sleeping
so deeply...
Leave me alone.
I'm sick, very sick.
You'll feel better very soon.
Everything is fine.
Can't you have some pity for me
and let me die alone?
Do you think I'm not dying
fast enough?
What's the matter with you?
It's not the time to die.
I found him. He'll be here
very shortly.
It's wrong, and you know it.
You know he can't come back.
- Why?
- Because I killed him.
- This afternoon?
- Five days ago.
Five... So we mustn't be
talking about the same one.
- Five days ago in Niort.
- And you went to the morgue?
- His body disappeared.
- From Niort?
No, from here! We brought him
back in the truck...
in a wicker trunk.
When we got here, we threw him
in the swimming pool.
But you weren't alone in Niort.
- You were with mademoiselle...
- Horner.
Horner, yes. And didn't she
notice anything?
She was his mistress.
She helped me. - I see.
She was his mistress...
and she helped you. Well...
I wouldn't mind listening
to what she's got to say.
- She got scared, and she left.
- It was obvious...
It won't work. It's Michel's.
It was under water
a whole day.
Well, well...
Aren't you arresting me?
You should stop playing
with your nerves.
You need a strong sedative.
Goodnight.
Shall I turn off the light?
Tomorrow morning, you'll
wake up acquitted.
He disappeared. She's deficient.
In addition, Nicole
runs away.
- Doesn't it remind you of anything?
- Registering for unemployment.
I'm afraid. Here's the cop.
I found it under
the diving board.
- Isn't there a wicker trunk
around here? - Yes, sir.
- Above the garage.
- So, let's go.
It's starting to stink.
You wonder if anything happened
to Delassalle.
You're a witness that I didn't
know anything.
Me either, dear colleague.
Right. Let him manage alone.
I don't know why, but...
You think that we fucked up.
Me too.
M. Pacard. Moinet.
- Goodnight, sir.
- Goodnight.
Who's there?
It's over, this time.
She's was tough.
The bitch. She used to say that
she had a heart condition.
My poor darling.
You're all wet.
Go change your clothes.
In the bathroom, it took me...
more than one hour to get out
of the tub without making noise.
You must've suffered during
the trip in the trunk.
What about the dive in the pool
in the middle of the night?
She made life terrible for us.
I got scared more than four times.
Wasn't it worth it?
Now, we're rich.
Just by selling the school,
we'll get a lot...
Between 15 and 20
years in jail.
It'll depend on the judge.
Moinet, Moinet.
Wait a moment.
You again, Moinet. You should
be ashamed of yourself.
On the day
we're closing the school.
- Who gave you this slingshot?
- Mme. Delassalle.
- Who? - Mme. Delassalle.
She opened her door.
She gave me back my slingshot.
She said: "This is for you,
Moinet. Have fun."
You are impossible.
You know that she's dead.
- Her body was taken away today.
- She's not dead. She came back.
M. Moinet, go to
the corner.
I saw her.
I know that I saw her.
Don't be devils. Don't ruin...
the interest your friends
could take in this film.
Don't tell them
what you saw.
Thank you for them.
5@y3