lf this is truth
Then he is not the only FBl in Japan
lf l kill him, l will be
suspected as he is following me
lf want to kill him then l have
to kill the other FBl agents
Wei, Light
That FBl guy is not a criminal
Even though he is not
criminal, you kill him also
[ Catholic church of Mandala ]
Raye
Naomi
l'm sorry
They gather us immediately
We'll go to church later
But priest has arranged the time
Please explain for me
Akasakabashi Station
There are spaces between
the train and the platform
Passengers please mind to your feet
This train is heading to the city
Attention please, the doors are closing
Raye Penber, l'm KlRA. Please use
the walkie talkie inside the envelope,
l would like to talk to you
First time we meet
l am KlRA
l'm watching you all the time
Please look in front
Don't forget l can simply kill anybody
Are you really KlRA?
l'll let you see the proof
The young man who sitting beside you
is called Ozakitarito
He was arrested of being
suspected in many raping cases
However, due to the fear of the victims
and there were not enough
evidence so he's not prosecuted
He should receive the punishment
Ozakitarito
sitting at the right of the front seat
5 minutes after passing Akasakabashi
He will be difficult to
breath as if he is sleeping
Die of heart paralyse
Please remain calm
Don't get suspected by other passengers
Make sure he is dead
and pretend he is sleeping
Now you'll believe l'm Kira, right?
You merely want to prove
you're KlRA and kill people?
Please answer my question?
Tell me, the number of FBl
who has the same purpose as you
lf you do not answer
l'll kill all the
passengers here in sequence
There is 4 groups
There are 11people other than me
Do you know other agents' name and face?
Don't know
lt's true
l really don't know
So the name and the face of your instructor
You know him, right?
Next step, you have 5
pieces of paper on your hand
There is a blank paper on the top
Write down the name of your instructor
Please don't wrote wrong
lf the name is not correct
l'll know it immediately
At that time, please
prepare for the consequences
Parliament Chamber
Attention please, the
doors are going to close
l've got mail
So please open it
Next confirm the face of your agents
as well as in the blank paper
write down all their names
Good, sit for a while
Get down to the Shinagawa Garden
and take the walkie talkie together
Raye
Naomi
Raye, Raye
Raye
[Heart paralyse]
[After received the file of FBl agents]
Raye Penber
Heart paralyse
Cancel all the appointments
From subway in Akasakabashi Station
10:40, boards the fourth
coach of the subway train
Get in from the last door
Take down the envelope
He will die in 3 seconds after debus
Tokyo 5 people, Kanagawa 3 people,
Chiba and Kawogoe 1person
All die of heart paralyse
Besides, their instructor in Washington
also die of heart paralyse at the same time
FBl agents?
l've heard they were taking
the instruction from L
and investigated all the police
officers and their surrounding members
L's instruction?
Sir, about this case...
lt's really shock
FBl agents who investigated
KlRA secretly had became victims
All die of heart paralyse
ln other words, even though they're
not criminals, KlRA will kill them too
Everybody here might be the victim
Now, l hope everybody
may think about your future,
relatives and beloved ones
Then who will wish to quit
from this case may do so
Furthermore, l make sure we'll not
take any actions against you all
Those who have faith to kill KlRA
even though sacrifice his life
Only this type of persons may stay
At last, thank you for
your cooperation till now
How to investigate by 6 people?
No, Watari and me are here
l believe you all who are righteous
Sorry, we don't trust you
You never expose yourself
and only instruct other people
You stay alone in the safe zone
l can't trust this type of person
We'll depend our ability to investigate KlRA
Frankly speaking, l don't trust you
l don't agree with your tactic also
However, we still you in arresting KlRA
lf you really want to cooperate with us
then let us see your real face
l knew it
Liaison officer
Please follow me, l'll
bring you all to meet with L
This the first time we meet, l'm L
l am police officer Soichiro Yagami
l am Uki
l am Shuichi Aizawa
l am Kanzo Mogi
l am Sanata
l am Tota Matsuda
Wei, what do you want?
Matsuda
lf l were KlRA
All of you have dead
What are you talking about?
According to the statistic
At the time when KlRA kills people
at least he needs to
know their names and face
So since now everybody please
don't use your real name
As for me, please call
me as Ryuzaki from now on
Understood
One more point
l think KlRA is able to control the
behavior of the victims before they die
The prisoners who left their letters
and people who had weird actions
l think that were caused
by experiments from KlRA
Experiments?
l think he has the purpose
to kill the FBl agents
and he wants to know their
control power before they die
ln the same time, he passes me messages
through the letters from the criminals
ln other words, they're
controlled by KlRA also
There were 8 days in between the experiments
in prisons to the death of FBl agents
l afraid he met with one of the FBl agents
controlled that agent and got
all the agents' information
KlRA is able to find
out the investigations of
FBl and he is able to
do experiments in prisons
lt means he is the relevant
person in among the police officers
lt's because of that
So the suspected criminals have decreased
From his actions and behavior
KlRA is a immature and a person
who is not willing to loose
lt's same as me
Frankly speaking even though l'm lost
but
l will win at last
Let's win
Ryuzaki
We're not playing a game
We are solving a case
No matter what, we have the same purpose
[Bank robber, Ozuki, shot
in the bus] [Died in accident
when trying to escape, all
bus passengers were safe]
[ 11am, Bus Nanjing,Okugawa Office ]
[Stop the lnvestigation]
We keep it inside a box already
These are all the visual
when FBl being killed
lt's really trouble all of you
[ln front of Saitama,
rotary, CCTV recording]
This person
Ah, he is the person sat behind
l remember
l think he quarreled
with a young man in front
After that the criminal got into the bus
So how the young man look like?
He is a good guy
l'm not saying outlook appearance
l should say he is daring
Even though he was pointed
by the gun of the criminal
but he remained calm
Was he being interrogated by the police?
He disappeared in that commotion
You focus the criminals already, aren't you?
Yes
Who?
The family members of the
head and assistant head
Can you tell me the reason?
He is FBl agent. As everybody
sees when he was killed
he pointed at the train
Are you saying there was somebody inside?
And the person inside might be KlRA
How about her?
She is Raye fiancee
Originally she is a talented FBl agent
She worked for me before
May be she felt Raye had
something wrong so she followed him
Then unfortunately she saw his death
So shall we get her contact now
She is missing after Raye's death
So l guess KlRA might
be investigated by Raye
lt means the family
members of Kazuku and mine
Yes
1%%% to 3%%%
Don't you want to interrogate us?
No
Please allow me to install spy cam in
Mr. Yagami's and Mr. Kazuku's house
lnstall the spy cam
Don't you think we'll allow
you to use such tactic in Japan?
lf somebody discover it, we will be fired
This is not about position,
it's about human lives
Ok, do according what he said
Sir
but since you want to do it
so please investigate properly
But sir, your wife and
Sayu are inside the house
Of course l know
lf there is mistake, l'll be suspected
lt is no use to guard house forever
The installation will only carry 7 days
At least we cannot let
our head to guard his house
lt is truth, so
Mr. Yagami's house will be
guarded by Mr.Yagami and l
Other people will guard
Mr. Kazuku's family members
This person
Do you remember?
He was the person who followed Light
What happened to him?
He was dead
ln the process of investigating KlRA
He was killed by KlRA
Wei, Light
Why you plan the death
actions for few weeks?
lf one day l am hospitalized or cannot move
lf suddenly there is no death
person, it's easily to get suspected
You're so careful
New menu from today
Welcome watching Happy Sweets
[ Misa Misa's Happy Sweets ]
Now, let's announce the first menu
That's
can let enemies put on weight
called croissant and pudding
What happened?
Nothing
Can let enemy put on 5 kgs
Misa Misa's enemy
Still is Tazuka
So Misa Misa would like to make her fat
This is considered as a little devil
Croissant and pudding are ready
Let's all the enemies put on weight
Misa is so great
So who's the person Misa respect?
KlRA
Ah, Misa Misa is the devotee of KlRA
Did you think he is trendy, silent executor
All the youngsters say so recently
Furthermore, KlRA is my benefactor
What happened?
Misa, l've told you not to tell about KlRA
Ai, but
Advertising company is very
troublesome, please cut the part just now
No freedom at all
lt means we are not allowed
to ask private stuffs?
No, it's only this case is not so convenient
KlRA's stuffs are the hot topic now
lt's trouble you all
Light
Light, this is Miss Shioko
She wants to meet you, she
has something to ask you
This is the first time we meet
Nice to meet you
l want to do a cover on KlRA
Light, you met Raye before, right?
He is the FBl we met in
the bus being hijacked
Ah
ln the process of investigating KlRA
He was killed by KlRA
How would it be?
Don't you know it?
But
he followed Light before
Yes, so he suspected you're KlRA
So he was killed by me
This is what you wanted to say
As long as KlRA knows
the name then he can kill
So you use the bus hijacked
case to find out Raye's name
Ha ha, a strange lady
However, Raye did not die after meeting me
was three days after meeting you
Sorry if l offend you
lf l were KlRA, l'll kill
him after knowing his name
How would Light be KlRA
You
There is a limit of offend
l would have sue you so l
must record what you has said
This is because there were
other FBl agents besides Raye
lf you kill Raye immediately
then you would be suspected
so you must kill all the FBl agents
So you didn't kill Raye on the spot
Am l right?
All the agents has dead?
Why there is no such news?
As this is a confidential task
[ Shioko, remember she has something
to do, rush towards Kinoshita]
These are created by you
Sorry Light, l don't she
is this type of person
Then in the subway
You use your tactic to get
other FBl agents' name from Raye
killed all of them
[ Shioko, remember she
has something to do, rush
towards Kinoshita, die
when crossing the road ]
Shiori, don't waste time, let's go
Light Yagami
lt's no use if you want to kill me
because l gave you the fake name
Don't be too much
Raye is my fiancee
l'll find out the murderer of Raye
l'll let him receive the punishment
l think she is crazy
Fake name
Somebody troubles you again
Shinigami's eyes, you really don't want?
Ha ha, even the powerful Light
also don't know what to do
According the report from the installer
Light go check whether there are
other people entering his bills
He checked whether somebody
has entered his room
Only install many cameras in Light's room?
lt's because l look through his
character, lQ, habitual life and summary
Light is the person who is
close to the KlRA's image
Even if guarding like
this, we're wasting time
Even if it has 1% of possibility
We'll investigate any suspicious thing
lf not we're difficult to catch KlRA
Wei, Light, please bother me
Nobody will see it now
Give me apple
l want to eat apple
Apple
What happened?
L seems guarding me purposely
The condition of my room is
different from this morning
Somebody entered my room
l think this room has installed cameras
Light, are you looking down on L?
lf we're being guard then l
cannot eat apple inside the room
l've to check the cameras position
and find out the dead angle
He studies in the room most of the time
You must feel honour to have such a son
His ambition is to be a policeman
How to make Light not suspicious?
There are no suspicious movements
made during the observation
and KlRA can kill people at this time
He is innocent then
Are you waiting KlRA to kill people?
You may say so
Please allow me to install spy cam
in Mr. Yagami's and Mr. Kazuku's house
The third day
Brother, have your meal
l go to smoke
Chief, please take a rest
You don't have good
sleep for these three days
Family is being suspected,
how can l sleep well
Three hunted killers were killed
Two killers died in the jail
The news is confirmed
ls it true?
lt's too early to be happy
Don't you forget KlRA can
control the time of death?
When a new criminal is reported
then only we can know the truth
The fifth day
The seventh day
Mom, don't you worry?
Dad hasn't came back for a week
Mom has use to it
Dad is working hard now
Sayu must be hardworking too
Good
Ai, brother eats potato chips
after dinner? You will gain weight
lt's ok, l'll burn midnight oil tonight
l'm full
He's so fearfulness
45 US dollar and one million eight
thousand US dollar, ending the agreement
The petroleum price has
dropped to 60 dollar US
The high purchasing is the
main reason of rise this time
Next news
[ Edogawa, a child was
kidnapped, suspect is arrested! ]
The criminal who is involves in
kidnapping 5 years old girl is arrested
The arrested person is Kisha, 29 years old
[ Kisha (29 years old)
Police found Melisa body in his apartment
Last month 28th, other children
saw Melisa near to that area
Melisa was inside a red
colour car and missing
After that , Melisa's family got
the money request form the criminal
He doesn't read the news
We didn't report this news as we
are respecting the hostage's life
The arrested criminals is sent to
to the Boat Moat police station now
He is facing the media
and doing something weird
[ Why? ]
The fact after the trial...
lt seems there is something happened
Mr. Daisu
Here is Boat Moat, the
suspect Kisha has dead
On the way of sending
Kisha to police station
Kisha was in pain suddenly, it
seemed he was having heart paralyse
Mr. Daisu
Yes
This is indeed done by KlRA
Although the cause of death hasn't be
identified but it's most
possible done by KlRA
There is new criminal killed by KlRA again
Now the police station is in alarm
Light is not suspected anymore
Ryuzaki, it is enough
We'll updating the news from time to time
Ryuzaki
The family of Chief and Kazuku
are not suspected anymore
Ryuzaki,you're still not satisfied?
Watari, take back all the spy cameras
l know it
lt's great, Sir Yagami
However, we need to start
a new investigation again
Light, all the spy cameras were taken out
All
lt's great to eat apple when nobody see it
But Light
lf your sister eats that snack, how?
Original potato chips, only l'll
eat it among my family members
Call from Naomi Misora
Long time no see
After this l'll prove to
you that Light Yagami is KlRA
Use my life
[ Shiori ]
Wei, wei
Can l meet you now?
Where?
Art gallery
l want to see you also
How long will you take to arrive here?
l can go now
After 30 minutes
Light
lt's weird, Shiori?
Shiori
CCTV in the art gallery
Show it
Yes
l am at the entrance
Come in
Now, l'm at the front of the
drawing by Ekusuhso Kenak's
l got it
You know how KlRA kill people?
Ryuzaki, what happened?
Light
KlRA indeed is Light Yagami
You are still suspecting Light
Shiori
Light
l'm sorry
Light Yagami
lf you don't want her to be
killed then ask for forgiveness now
Ask for forgiveness from Raye
and admit you're KlRA
Contact the local police
Yes
You misunderstood
l am not KlRA
lf you don't tell the truth
l'll kill her
No
Even if l am KlRA
lt has nothing to do with Shiori
lf you want to kill then kill me
l want you to know the pain
of losing the beloved person
Don't, stop
As long as you don't hurt Shiori
Light
lt is so shameful
You as KlRA but can't even kill me
Only can cry and beg me
That's why l say l am not KlRA
You can't kill if you don't get their names
So let me tell you my real name
Naomi Misora
Naomi Misora, N for north
M for man
Good, since you've got my name
so kill me
Naomi Misora
What happen to the local police
They'll arrive soon
Cannot
Let them go later
What are you talking about?
The following is the wonderful part
This is not acting
Do you want to save your girl friend?
Then just kill me
Like how you killed Raye
Like how you killed other criminals
No need to use your hand
Just kill me
l've said l am not KlRA
Shiori
How?
How would it be?
Shiori
The criminal has gun
Shiori, be strong
Shiori
Light
We are kissing in the public
Shiori
Why?
Why you shot Shiori?
Shiori
Why?
Stop
This is the result of misjudge
The misjudge of Naomi Misora
was discovered by me
and her fault about telling
me she was Raye's fiancee
Nobody will use a fake name in the wedding
and church is open to everybody
lt's not difficult to find
out Naomi Misora real name
[ Raye Penber ]
[ Naomi Misora ]
Naomi Misora, commit suicide
For the purpose of her death fiancee
Lure the suspect out
to the art gallery
Kidnap the suspect's girl friend
At 14:15 15th April 2006
Let the hostage make a call to the suspect
Get the second evidence
By the guarding of the investigation team
Try to let the criminal expose his crimes
but as seeing the hostage was running away
14:55 tried to stop the hostage...
Then she became insane
and killed herself
Sorry
lf we could arrive earlier...
l go to order people to prepare a car
l've never thought Shiori would be killed
You also misjudge
The person who killed Shiori is me too
l definitely use the Death Note
That's weird
Shiori was killed by Naomi
but you cannot write an action
to kill other people in Death Note
lf the name written then
she'll die in heart paralyse
l knew it definitely
So l only gave instructions to Naomi
and then wrote down Shiori's
name in the next page
[ Naomi Misora, committed suicide,
lead the suspect to the art gallery ]
Shiori, killed by other people
She is involved in the
kidnapping case in the art gallery
14:15 15th April 2006
force to call boy friend
Try to runaway when police arrive
14:55 When the kidnapper shot
For the purpose of protecting her boy friend
and was shot to death
l didn't write about Naomi killed Shiori
l didn't write about Shiori
was killed by Naomi too
So did Naomi Kill Shiori was an accident?
lf from the point of killing Shiori
The percentage of success is extraordinary
lt's not accident
All happened according to my plan
l wrote Shiori was shot to death
and Naomi killed himself by using her gun
This is because normally
nobody will bring a gun in Japan
lf Shiori was killed here
Then it was done by Naomi
Do you know it, Ryuk?
Names whose be written
Their fate will be changed in naturally
So even though l do not
write Naomi killed Shiori
but all the things would
happen according to my plan
You're...a real devil
My Shiori died in front of me
Now if l give the reason of defeating KlRA
and wish to join the investigation team
Everyone will feel pity and believe me
Shiori
Light, you look like Shinigami than we do
Shiori was indeed loved you
Don't you love Shiori?
l also don't know
Misa, do you feel lonely
No, don't come over here
Wish to die...that's what Misa wants
l don't have that kind of wish
Let's go, let's go to parents' heaven
l want to die with you
You, are you kidding?
Do you know the consequences if you do so?
ln recording room, in
the lobby of TV station
l am watching you all the time
l want to die with you
To die for you is my mission
Bullshits
Misa doesn't want to go to heaven or hell
Don't be afraid, l won't make you pain
Stop
Help me, is somebody out there
Light
The car is here
Let's go home
Dad, l've a request
Say it
Please let me to join the investigation team
My beloved Shiori was killed by KlRA
l absolutely will not forgive KlRA
So, please let me to join
the investigation team
Welcome
This is the first time we meet, Light Yagami
l am L
Please use your smart brain to help us
to arrest KlRA
Before that, please apologies