Based on the true story Korean
war veteran Suleyman Dilbirligi
38th Parallel, South Korea
June 1950
5 years after
World War 2
Seol!
A bicycle!
I've made you a gift, honey.
Doesn't it look great?
Off we go!
She's a natural.
Make way!
My little girl's coming!
What's going on?
Nothing.
Nothing. Don't be afraid. I'm here.
-Hide!
-Where are you going?
Seol, quiet.
Don't make a sound.
If you keep crying,
you won't see Mommy and Daddy again.
Do you understand?
Seol. No crying.
This place!
Come out!
Iskenderun, Turkey - June 1950
-Suleyman!
Come on, man!
Suleyman!
I'll be right there. What's with the racket
at this hour? You wouldn't shut up.
Come on, man!
Thank God!
At frigging last!
Is your morning crap never done?
It's the same every damn morning!
A good deed on a summer's day.
You should try it.
Do you do it on purpose every morning?
The grooming, the outfit...
It never ends!
Your spit and polish is our
bread and butter as NCOs.
-Fix that tie.
-Keep tightening it. Good job.
Let's go! Let's go!
You're like a little girl I swear.
-You know what I dream of?
-What?
Folks in other countries
bike around the world.
What's stopping us?
Why are we stuck here man?
Yeah right! It's far enough biking to base
every day and you want a world tour?
Where have you been?
The girls are waiting.
Pedal up!
Can't you go a day
without seeing them? Huh?
I'm sweating buckets here.
-Shut up and you won't sweat. Pedal up! Up!
-Exactly!
Turgay!
-I'm not too late, am I?
-No, you aren't.
Don't worry, I put yours aside.
-It didn't rip coming down, did it?
-Of course not.
Oh my God.
Look at her!
Talk about gorgeous.
Your girls are great okay,
but she's really something else.
-Just look at her.
-Would she even look at you?
-Why not?
-Look at you.
What's wrong with me?
Put that tie properly for once
for heaven's sake.
You're a disgrace to the NCOs.
Enough with the tie guys.
I've had it.
If anyone mocks my soldiership.
I'll slap them with my marksmanship papers.
Don't get me going.
I'm not a mechanic like you guys.
I'm a marksman, OK?
I'm a crack shot.
I hit every time.
-Have a good one.
-Thanks.
Thanks, Turgay!
Nuran!
I'm in love with a young woman
I should say her name
Everything pulls me to her
My heart cries all the time
My love will never cease
She's gone and won't come back
Even if the long years have passed
I'd live with its dream
Dad says we're sending troops to Korea.
Suppose they send our--
Shh! Heaven forbid!
They're college educated.
They won't be deployed.
I don't know.
I'm just worried.
My heart misses her
-One, two!
-Three, four!
39th Military Infantry Division Command
-Left, right!
-One, two!
Suleyman, sit down.
It's an order. Sit down.
Why did I send for you, Suleyman?
As you may have heard,
we're sending troops to South Korea.
Yes, sir.
-May God make us proud.
-Amen.
Ankara has organized a battalion.
But we have orders to send reinforcements.
I had you in mind, Suleyman.
Your absence will be an issue for me.
But good, proficient soldiers like yourself
are needed over there.
What do you say?
-I'd be honored, sir.
-Bless you.
-You have anyone waiting for you?
-I do, sir.
Someone dearer to me than life.
Like my country.
-Don't those Koreans all look the same?
-Sure they do.
Only to you, though.
Suleyman.
OK, you're going as technical staff.
But this is war.
I can't imagine you in a warfare.
Don't let his look fool you.
-He's from Maras. It's in his blood.
-May God test no one with war.
If your life isn't in danger, why would
anyone kill anybody just for the kicks?
So we shouldn't drop
a few Commies over there?
Is that what you mean?
Those Commies are persecuting people there.
-So let's drop one or two.
-Quiet, hold on. Is he going with you?
My buddy's off to war.
Am I supposed to wait for him here?
Who'll look out for him there?
He doesn't have anyone.
Have you talked to your family?
Please send a message to Nuran
through Iclal.
I really have to talk to her tonight.
It's Ali leading you astray, isn't it?
He always wants more.
He just wants adventure.
But why are you going to Korea?
Don't say that.
The people there need our country
and my country need me.
I can't walk away from that.
-Celal is, though.
-But I can't.
That's what makes me who I am.
Don't you love me the way I am?
Yes, I do.
But it's so far. So very far.
What if you go there and forget me?
You can't mean that!
Is that what you're worried about?
I'm an orphan. My uncle sees me
as a burden. All I have is you.
You're my refuge, you're my anchor.
What if you too left this orphan girl?
I wouldn't. I wouldn't.
I won't. I'll write to you every day.
I'll take photos. You'll read, you'll see.
It'll be like I'm by your side. I promise.
You know I see you passing by each morning?
I save it in my mind.
You feel me too.
Don't you ever forget.
Remember my warmth.
Maras, Turkey
Nimet, dear.
A telegram has come.
-Do you mind reading it?
-Of course not, Uncle Huseyin.
It's from your son.
He's been chosen for Korea.
"I won't leave you worrying.
I'll write often.
Give me your blessing," he says.
I should go.
Mom will be waiting.
Turkey's proposal to send troops to fight
communism in Korea...
The other side of the world.
Good for those brave young fellows.
If only I had a son to send
and be proud of.
Turkey has committed to sending
a fully armed force of 4500 men.
Help him God.
Bring him back safe and sound.
Godspeed Suleyman.
My dearest Nuran...
As we sail away and the great big Iskenderun
becomes a small silhouette...
...I have a better idea of
how big the world is.
The world is big,
distances are far.
But I have two defiant fires
blazing inside of me.
One is the idea of being able to help
strangers.
The other is my longing for you
and the ever growing love between us.
That's why I'm not afraid.
Don't you be afraid either.
You and I possess two great riches that will
overcome everything in this vast world.
They are goodness and love.
"Dear Father, Mom mustn't worry
about my diet.
Although the Americans have
some odd eating habits...
...they take good care of us."
We get both eggs and powdered eggs.
You should see how Private Pepe Muharrem
talks with his mouth full...
...and spews powder everywhere
when he stammers.
Oh, son.
"My dear friends Celal and Ilhan...
Don't tell the girls
but we've all been issued arms.
We've begun target practices.
As you kept saying,
we're going to war.
The Americans show us films about weapons
and military formation and train us."
Pushing north of the 38th parallel
into North Korea...
"Lt. Mesut translates the films for us.
He's going to be the interpreter.
Our introduction was quite interesting."
-Sir.
-Suleyman.
At ease. You're in the motorized unit.
Where can I get diesel?
I'll siphon some from a jeep in the hold.
Great!
There are so many ants in my cabin,
they devoured me the whole night.
I told the Americans
and the assholes just laughed.
It happens, sir.
The blessed things climb
the hawsers in port.
Whatever. Bring some diesel
and I'll get the cabin cleaned out.
But then they'll die.
What are we supposed to do
besides killing them?
You feed them.
They're after their food, sir.
They'll flock to the sugar
and leave you alone.
You need to learn to live with them.
-Are you a Communist like me?
-No.
I'm not up on those things.
But there's a lot to learn from the ants.
Guys who wouldn't hurt an
ant are going to war.
Ali's a crack shot. Time and again
he shoots his bullets with other bullets.
Being determined to kill
the Communist North Koreans...
He doesn't get along with Lt. Mesut.
My love...
This one-month journey
will soon be over.
As I keep saying...
...don't think any bad thoughts.
-What's up, sir?
-They asked if we have any clerics with us.
So they've even learned about our
devotionals.
No, it's not about prayers or ablutions.
They've got their priests, right?
And they're not here to preach
on Sundays.
So why are they here?
It won't always be
you taking them out, Ali.
Suppose they kill us?
Every dead will be buried
according to their religion.
Busan - South Korea
October 1950
Welcome.
OK. Let's go, guys.
It's another 95 km north to Daegu city.
Daegu - South Korea
-My friends, this summer,...
...North Korea brutally invaded
the entire country.
But the Peacekeeping Force has driven back
the enemy to its borders...
...and freed South Korea
from the invasion.
Now it's time for the final blow
on the border.
Our destination is Kunu-ri.
For the first time, our Turkish armed forces
will be engaged in close combat.
Goddamn savages!
See what they've done to the country.
With what you saw on the way here,
now you know how sacred this mission is.
U.S. 25th Division - Kunu-ri
-My fellow friends,...
...this is the line
where that last blow will be delivered.
It has massive strategic importance.
Why are they scattered all over the place?
Suppose there's an emergency?
The Americans say the job is done...
...and that we'll be home in a month
for Christmas.
Come by the fire.
Let's eat some marshmallows and drink.
Marshmallows?
We came all this way to eat candy?
They cooked up a task to
keep us hanging around here.
Shoot a few guerrillas
and you'll feel better.
Dammit! We get here and
it's all over.
If it suits you.
The Americans ask and we do it.
What do you mean?
They've brought us here to exploit?
Don't they trust us?
Is that why they put us behind the lines?
Do you want to be useful to
your country like a true patriot...
...or do you just want to hunt Communists?
What kind of question is that?
Whose side are you on, sir?
Why? Are you going to report me
as a spy?
-Are you threatening me?
-No, but whose side are you on?
-Tell us and we'll act accordingly.
-Sir.
I was sent here because
I'm good at what I do.
Like all of us.
If we agree on it,
let's get back to work please.
We need to organize
this vehicle traffic stat.
Or we'll be immobilized
in an emergency.
What emergency, Suleyman?
They say the hunting party is over.
This is over.
This way!
Let's find the commander.
Find the commander!
We had orders to contact the 9th Corps
in case of emergency.
Communications are down.
Give me the permission and I'll go.
-But I need a good driver.
-At your command, sir!
-I want an interpreter, too.
-Yes, sir!
You get new orders and find us.
Any questions?
The war was over before our boys
even got to Korea.
Which means they'll be back early.
I pray he asks my uncle for my hand
as soon as he's back.
Celal and I are looking at rings, too.
So it'll be a double engagement in spring!
Iclal?
Shall we go to the wedding dress maker?
There's a gorgeous one on display.
OUR ARMY MAY COME BACK
WITH AN EARLY VICTORY
Let's pick up some speed.
It's all we can do without headlights
in the moonlight, sir.
I know. We have no choice.
Turn on the headlights.
Ali, on the right!
Evacuate the vehicle!
Nimet?
What is it, dear?
Nothing's wrong, I hope?
I have a bad feeling, Mom.
Ali!
Sir, were these your men?
I don't think they like you a lot.
Is everyone OK?
If we take the road,
we'll be sitting ducks.
We'll head through the forest instead.
Come on.
Damn you Pepe.
Didn't we bring you as a guard?
-Yes, sir.
-Then why don't you fire?
But, sir. I'm not used
to this infidel rifle.
And stop calling me Pepe all the time.
It gets to me.
Didn't you tell us that
your nickname was Pepe?
-Quiet!
-At least stop saying it now.
Stop!
God help us keep our sanity.
Motherfuckers.
They've butchered women, children,
everyone.
Keep your eyes peeled.
The guys who did it could still be around.
They're here.
I swear they are.
Ali, wait!
I think it's animals.
Sir...
...if we fire a round,
we'll find out.
Sure, and give away our position.
-Sir, let me take a look.
-Be careful.
Come here.
Come on, don't be scared.
I won't hurt you.
Come on.
Come here. Come.
Oh my.
You scared the shit out of us.
She's terrified.
She can't speak.
Our mission is important, Suleyman.
The girl will hold us back.
Sir, we can't leave her here.
Come on. Let's go.
She's cold, poor thing.
Suleyman, look at me.
It suits you.
Give me a break.
9th Corp Command
Un Hung-ni
-Don't go anywhere.
-Sir.
Can you ask about the girl?
What should we do?
Ask the general about the kid
when so much else is going on?
Sir, is the girl South Korean or...
...from North Korea?
I wouldn't know. Whatever.
She's clearly homeless.
Well for example, back home,
if you go south...
...I mean down towards Mugla.
You get these prominent cheekbones.
Hell, Muharrem!
You don't just stammer, you never shut up!
But since you like talking so much...
...go get some milk or something
to feed the girl.
She'll starve to death.
-She's cold, you know.
-Frozen.
-Maybe she needs to pee.
-I expect she'd find a way to say if she does.
She hasn't said a word yet, huh?
No, just whimpered all the way here.
We don't know her name either.
What do you think it is?
Let's name her.
-You think so?
-Sure.
What shall we name her?
Let's name her after my mom.
Her name shall be Naciye.
-Yeah right.
-Why not?
-She's a little kid. Naciye wouldn't fit.
-So what shall we name her?
Let's name her after your mom.
-What's your mom's name?
-Gulcin.
Nope. That sounds like a hostile name. No.
Then what shall we name her?
Let's find something.
How about Ayla?
-Ayla?
-She has a face like the moon, look.
And we found her in the moonlight.
Shall we name you Ayla?
-Bravo, sir.
-Great. OK.
-It's decided.
-Ayla.
You're such a cutie.
Gentelmen...
...this is a work of Chinese army
They are in the game too.
This war we thought was ending,
it's now just beginning
North Koreans do not stand alone now.
We're helping the southerners,
Chinese helping the north.
It's multinational on both sides now.
Now we provide you extra vehicles
and personnel.
My radio operator Captain Cage
he'll be company with you.
Capt. Cage is coming with us.
You'll be giving me the latest intelligence
in real time.
-They'll pass on information.
-We work together as a team.
Lieutenant Lee knows this area
like the back of his hand.
He will guide you along
the new secret route we've given.
Turkish forces are spread across
a wide area behind the enemy.
We'll contact these forces
with our new operation plan.
Let's go get them colonel.
Sir, I got a bottle of milk.
-Good man.
-There's milk powder, too.
Those Americans powdered everything.
Bring that blanket.
She's frozen.
I got her.
You got her?
My little bird!
-Here you go.
-Easy.
Let's go.
I'll explain on the way.
They find her middle of a massacre
on the way.
They couldn't leave her there
and they took her with them.
-That's pretty remarkable.
-Yes it is.
This was taken from Marshal Douglas MacArthur's
Korean War memories
Turks are interesting people.
We put a call up to the whole world,
they were the first responders.
You know, this war goes down in history...
...it won't be me,
it won't be you, pal.
Will be them the most mentioned
in the books.
You stay with the girl.
I'll take a look.
Aren't you hungry yet?
Look what I've got.
You want some milk?
Don't make a face.
I'll have some first, OK?
Damn it. I spilled it.
Definitely a spill.
Want some?
I just got disgrace call of the radio.
We need to get to Kunu-ri.
The captain says we need to get to Kunu-ri
right away, sir.
There is a narrow road up there
on the right side...
...we can use to get to Kunu-ri faster.
He says there's a road to the right
which will get us to Kunu-ri faster, sir.
Good idea. OK.
Ali, tell Sgt. Suleyman to take a look at
the captain's jeep.
The major wants you to fix the vehicle.
Take a look.
Wait two minutes and
I'll be back.
Wait. You can't come.
-Suleyman! Come on!
-Stop that. I'll get burned.
-I have to fix the jeep.
-Go ahead then sergeant.
Are you going to look after the girl
or the jeep?
Give her to someone else.
We're in a hurry.
Soldier!
-Yes, sir!
-You stay here.
Watch the girl. We mustn't let her
to be a burden on them.
Yes, sir!
He's going to watch her.
So she doesn't bother you too much.
He'll watch the girl.
He says let's not bother them anymore.
She's a little kid.
She won't be a burden.
If the lieutenant says so, OK.
I haven't let anyone take you away
so sit here and be good, OK?
Ali, get to the ignition.
Let's see what the problem is.
Goddammit!
Did they check nothing before leaving?
If they were my men,
I'd ax all leave for 3 months.
Of course! No problem.
Oh, boy!
Just ignite it.
There, that's the Suleyman we miss.
Just fire it.
Here goes.
Okay.
Not quite but anyways.
-Let's go catch the others up.
-Come on.
That girl hasn't taken her eyes off
you for the last half hour.
Hey, girl!
Come here. Come on.
Come here.
What a cutie.
Get the girl!
Ayla! Ayla!
-Suleyman!
-The girl's OK! She's OK!
Get under there, go on. Go on, under!
Stay right there.
We're up in the shit creek here. Fuck!
-Suleyman!
-Why does the damn thing take only six?
Suleyman, you have to do something!
Suleyman!
I'm trapped in here.
I can't look up, Suleyman!
You have to do something!
Ali, watch my six!
Ali, toss it over.
Send it.
Suleyman! Watch out.
They're flowing like a pack of dogs.
We're screwed if they get down here.
It's OK.
Don't be scared.
I'll get you out of here.
Ali, they're coming.
They're coming, Ali!
Suleyman, whatever you're doing,
do it fast!
I can't keep up.
Suleyman!
Read all about it! War starts again
when they said it was over!
Read all about it!
The world writes of Turkish heroism as our...
We have wounded in the mechanics' company.
Our estimated casualty rate is 20%.
We must be prepared for any news.
A casualty rate of 20%. Means one in
every five who boarded the ship.
Don't be like that.
Where there's God, there's hope.
Cries of "Allah Allah" are still rising
high above the Korean hills.
Kunu-ri is under enemy occupation.
A small Turkish convoy leaving Kunu-ri
at the last minute...
...came under heavy machine-gun fire.
We have wounded
in the mechanics' company.
With the Chinese now backing the enemy...
...a clash broke out at Kunu-ri,
this place on the border.
That's where Suleyman is.
I don't know what to say, Nuran.
We'll have to wait for the news.
I told him.
I told him not to go. I told him.
I knew it.
Nuran.
Ayla.
Suleyman.
Hey, you're back from death's clutches.
Where's my Maras Monster?
You're the man! Seriously.
The guy comes as an engine mechanic,
then he fucks up the whole damn place.
What the hell kind of guy are you man?
-You guys are OK, aren't you?
-You're still-- Yes, we're fine.
Are you OK? Is there a problem here?
Any pain?
-No, thank God.
-Where are your legs?
Stop it. Don't make me laugh.
I was so scared
something would happen to you.
But you, you're such a sweetheart.
Come here. Come on.
She's OK, too, thank God.
No cuts and bruises?
She hasn't left your bedside.
She's like a kitten.
Give them a drop of milk
and they never leave you.
But the Koreans rightly
wanted to take her.
When Ayla wouldn't go, Lee intervened.
He said he'd talk to base.
The number of orphaned children is
increasing
The number of children
looked after by the Turks isn't going down.
They're all our children.
They've travelled thousands of miles
to help us.
And they're fighting,
shedding blood for us.
Should they be looking after our children
as well? That isn't right.
The Chinese are now helping
the North Koreans.
It's hard to make time for that now
when we have to fight and pull back south.
The Turks have offered to open a school.
Lt. Lee is closest to the Turks.
What do you say?
It's safest if we keep the children
at the HQ...
...until a secure place is
built for them.
But the decision is yours, sir.
One, two... Three, four...
At ease, Suleyman.
The war's heating up, sergeant.
We'll be retreating, advancing,
we'll be maneuvering constantly.
As such, we can't have the girl with us.
I understand, sir.
Everything happened so suddenly.
-If we could find her parents...
-That's for the Korean authorities to do.
We've notified them.
We'll hear back in the next few days.
That soon?
Sir, she didn't leave my side
when I was sleeping. How can I--
That's what I'm talking about son.
Don't get any more attached.
It'll end up being hard
for her and for you.
Get back to work.
I've assigned Sgt. Sadik
to your command.
He's very capable.
He got a lot done in your absence.
Now, forget baby sitting
and go back to your duties.
-Off you go.
-Yes, sir.
Suleyman.
We're proud of the bravery you showed.
Fighting was heavy at Kunu-ri.
We sustained serious losses.
But we kept the Chinese out.
Thanks to us, all allied forces
were able to retreat unharmed.
And so the South Korean
authorities are...
...hosting a medal ceremony
to honor our gallant men.
Get yourself ready.
We'll be taking a trip.
But leave the girl with Sadik.
I don't want to see her there.
That'll be all.
Don't worry, sergeant.
Even if she doesn't have parents,
we're all her brothers and uncles here.
We'll give Ayla everything she needs.
I made her clothes myself actually.
You did?
They didn't come from villagers?
Where did you get the material?
It's the blanket you've put on her, sir.
I'm a bit of a tailor, too.
I saw the girl had no clothes.
I sized her up and out came a coat.
It'll keep her warm as toast.
-You mean you create from nothing.
-So they say.
I'm a bit crazy so
I've never won more stripes.
But may the Lord not be offended,
I'll create anything you need from nothing.
Thanks.
Ayla.
Look, I'm going to leave now
and you'll stay here with Sadik. OK?
I guess she understands.
OK then.
Oh God.
You can't come with me.
OK? You stay here. Here.
Oh, dear God.
It's forbidden.
I can't take you.
Shoo! What the hell is "shoo"?
Forbidden.
-Take her away.
-Forbidden? What the hell?
You're reverting back to yourself.
What are you trying to tell the girl now?
What can I do?
It's too bad but we can't take her.
I had a word with your doctor.
-He said she's older than five.
-Really?
Yeah.
She's in shock.
That's why she can't talk.
God knows, maybe she saw
her parents got killed.
It's a sick world.
Wow! Well, well.
Terrific!
We've come to a fairground!
Pass the camera and
let's take a photo.
-Good point.
-Let them be proud.
Just there is good, right?
You know where to push, right?
Just get on with your primping.
Fireball!
Come on.
Stand proud.
We saw in Kunu-ri...
...that we now share blood ties
not only with the Americans,...
...but also with the Turks.
The Turks have a famous saying.
I'd give my life...
...so my country would live on!
Long as this country lives on,...
...we will never forget the sacrifice...
...you have made in fighting with us...
...as brothers in arms.
Soldier...
...thanks for your service, pal.
We also confirm
with general Byeong Soon.
As you see we other all one big happy family
we have no doubt.
And she'll be healthy and happy...
...with you.
Until her family is found.
-He says we're one big family.
-I got that.
You don't have to interpret feelings.
Come here honey.
"As you can see, I'm very well.
Medals and accolades aside,...
...this little girl has
marched into our lives...
...and lit up the dark world of war."
He's fine.
Why the long face?
Smile a bit.
I don't know, Iclal.
I'm terrified something will
happen to him.
He puts his life at stake for that girl.
Suppose he'd died?
January, 1951
At ease, son.
Suleyman, these are from back home.
I asked my wife to send them.
Thankfully she has.
-How's our Ayla? Good?
-Thank you sir. She is fine.
-Five!
-Six!
-Seven!
-Eight!
-Nine!
-Ten!
-Eleven!
-Twelve!
-Thirteen!
-Fourteen!
-Fifteen!
-Sixteen!
-Seventeen!
-Eighteen!
There's a child here!
Throw it!
-Catch it dear!
-He threw it!
Come on, open your mouth wide.
Open! Open wide!
Good girl, Ayla!
You know my name?
My name's Suleyman.
What's your name?
Why won't you talk, sweetie?
We'll run out of milk at this rate.
Good night.
You can't sleep with us.
You should sleep here.
That's your place.
You sleep there, OK?
Go on now.
Attention!
Ayla is on the left!
-Four!
-Allah!
-Five!
-Six!
-Allah!
-Seven!
-One, two...
-Three, four...
-Left, right!
-One, two...
-Three, four...
-Left, right.
-One, two.
-One, two...
-Three, four.
March, 1951
34, 35, 36, 37...
38, 39, 40, 41...
42, 43, 44, 45,
46, 47, 48, 49...
50, 51, 52, 53...
54! End!
Attention!
Yes, sir!
She's speaking.
You've fed her.
It's not an easy task.
Left, turn!
Right, turn!
-At ease!
-Attention!
Permission to cry.
Laugh.
Laugh to the right.
Go on, laugh!
Laugh!
The girl can read Korean, can't she?
She read the page we gave her
once she was speaking.
She reads Korean
but can't say or write her own name.
She thinks her name is Ayla.
I don't get it either.
Since she's learning,
she mustn't just pick things up.
She must learn proper Turkish.
I asked some friends
and they sent some books.
Ayla. Look.
Give me a Marilyn film.
What's this crap?
No mummy.
No brother.
Daddy!
My sweet.
Daddy.
April, 1951
-One, two!
-Three, four!
Ayse, go to sleep.
You've earned your
shopping leave this weekend.
There's talk of going to Tokyo, but...
I've discussed that.
But it's a surprise.
First, we finish the book.
Come on, Ayla.
Swim, Ayse, swim.
Ayse, here's a bicycle.
A bicycle, yes!
My girl knows the bicycle too.
Well done.
-Bicycle.
-Yes, bicycle.
-Come.
-Where? Stop.
OK, I'm coming.
Where are we going?
OK, OK, I'm coming. Wait.
Bicycle.
Bicycle, yes. Whose is it?
How did you know it's here?
It's Sadik's.
Bravo. Now come here.
You play for a bit, OK?
I have a few things to do.
What's this, Sadik?
It's my addiction. I can't relax
unless I tinker with things like this.
-Where did you find all those parts?
-From the villagers.
Contact with the locals is forbidden.
What do you trade?
Our gears?
God forbid! I pay with cash
and my ration cans.
The parts are all broken anyway.
Worthless unless I fix them.
What will you do
when the bike's done?
You think they'd let you ride it here?
I'll sell it, sergeant.
We'll get Ayla some new clothes.
You bring Ayla into it as hush money
to Sgt. Suleyman...
...and carry on with your tricks here?
Is that it?
Nice ruse.
Shame on you, Sadik.
Not those gloves as well?
No, sergeant. I fixed a stove
and got those gloves from villagers.
But sewed the other things myself.
Just to keep her warm.
I have a sibling away from home, too.
You've got me all wrong, 1st lieutenant.
I'm not a dishonest man.
Dismantle the bike and
put an end to it.
I won't report you for now,
but if I catch you again, we'll fall out.
Eat up now.
We're fine here,
but men are dying on the fronts.
We'll share the same fate.
You think we'd get out of here alive?
There's nothing to fear but fear itself.
No man can live forever.
Not even the Prophet Suleyman.
Imagine, Suleyman the great.
When he, of all people, died...
Imagine that.
You're very quick to judge people, sir.
I am also confused, Suleyman.
So we shouldn't hurt any feelings.
My dear? Ayla?
Why are you crying?
What's wrong?
They said you'd died.
Are you dead?
Come on! Who said that?
They said even the Suleyman is dead.
-What did they say?
-"Even the Suleyman is dead..."
Oh, come on now.
That Suleyman isn't me.
He's somebody else.
It's just a fairy tale Ayla.
-I'm not that Suleyman.
-That's Suleyman The Sultan.
So you won't die, will you?
-No. I won't die.
-Was she crying for that?
I think we should take Ayla
to Tokyo for Children's Holiday.
-To cheer us all up.
-Great!
1st Lt. Mesut will pick on me nonstop,
whatever the excuse.
No, I won't.
Not on a holiday.
Tokyo - Japan
April 23, 1951
I watched you all day.
You took in this wounded bird,
you healed her.
Then you let her fly.
We'll soon be going back to Turkey.
How will you let her go?
Or how will she let us go?
-Sadik.
-Welcome back, sir.
Sergeant...
...I haven't told anyone but
we may have found Ayla's family.
Some villagers have seen Ayla.
-The ones you trade with?
-Yes.
A man came when you were gone to
say Ayla has a family.
They want the girl.
They say to bring her
or we'll be in trouble.
I'll talk to them whoever they are.
Alone.
You can't go alone. Let me come too.
I know a little Korean.
No man. You watch Ayla.
And especially don't let Ali hear.
Ayla. My dear, please read me
what it says here.
But first make me a promise.
You will behave tonight, OK?
Listen to Ali's radio.
I have a quick errand
but I'll be back. OK?
-OK.
-Way to go my clever girl.
Now read it.
Hello.
Sir!
I'm going to tell you something
but you didn't hear it from me.
Su-Su-Sul...
-Send for Suleyman and Ali.
-Yes, sir!
How could you let the man go?
Are you crazy?
God knows where he's gone.
Why did no one tell me till now?
-What if something hap...
-I told him not to go 50 times.
He wouldn't listen.
I said "don't go" but he did.
-What do we do now?
-Let's go.
Where is the man? Do we know?
How will we find him?
I know.
-Can you sign a vehicle out?
-No.
Actually, there's a vehicle but...
If Sgt. Suleyman sees, he'll kill me.
-Does that rusty bucket work?
-I take that as an insult.
I was going to bike around the world
and now look at me!
Don't move, you son of a bitch!
Get the hell off me!
Where are the Americans?
Tell me now!
Son of a bitch!
-I don't understand what you're saying.
-How many men are there in your unit?
-And forget Chinese!
-Tell me!
Get off me!
Tell me!
Don't move!
Let our man go.
We have more men outside!
Let our man go!
You're all dead.
Suleyman, move.
Move Suleyman.
Sadik, get the bike!
He fixed that damn bike, didn't he?
Go bro.
What did you say in there?
That the army outside would shit on them
if they didn't let you go.
Where did you learn it all?
The language from Ayla,
the lies from America.
Run! Sadik!
Sadik, where are you?
They'll cap our asses Sadik!
Step on it!
That's my baby!
Why do you go around doing this stuff
on your own?
I don't know.
I thought they were Ayla's family.
Suppose they really had been?
Step on it!
Step on it! Step!
Nice bike eh, sir?
Is it that bike?
Holy...
Hold the bike idiot!
We'll talk about it later.
Where are these men,
1st lieutenant?
What a bike!
Sgt. Suleyman is not too well, sir.
Pardon the details,
but he's got diarrhea.
He leaks everywhere.
So where's Ali?
Has he also got di...
Isn't he out yet?
Is he in the latrine?
We'll see.
Sir, forgive me.
That Marilyn of yours is coming.
Who?
She's singing a few songs for morale.
The colonel heard you were fans.
But unfortunately
a mission's come up for Ali...
...and since you have the stomach flu.
It's not meant to be.
Can't be helped.
-Which Marilyn is he talking about?
-Your Marilyn.
-What did you do?
-Screwed.
Let go! Get off!
I'll die if I don't see the girl today.
-I'd rather go AWOL than missing this!
-Grab him!
Suleyman,
I've been waiting all my life for this day.
Calm down.
The girl's here for two days.
Keep out of this, Suleyman.
-OK, I'm keeping out of it.
-If anyone stops me,...
...I'll shit on them today and tomorrow.
-Do it.
-Look.
Maybe I go today, I might wangle a date.
Tomorrow I'll say how I feel,...
...the day after that we'll be an item.
Why are you stopping me?
-Who's stopping you?
-Why are you stopping me?
Just listen my man.
Remember the lecture you gave me yesterday
about doing things?
-You want to go to jail yourself?
-Suleyman is right.
Look, we'll take Ayla today.
And I promise you...
We'll get her to sign one of these
with her own pen in her own writing.
And then a lipstick kiss on top. Huh?
What's that? Are these new?
Yes.
-She really printed and sent them herself?
-Yes.
-Would she sign one for me?
-Sure! Addressed to you in person.
"To dearest Ali, with love."
Tomorrow we'll go again together.
You can say you're Ali.
I'll be your translator.
-Huh? How about it?
-Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
-You promise?
-I told you.
-You promise, Suleyman?
-Yes.
-You promise?
-Of course.
Right, dear?
Getting an autograph will be tough.
-We promised. What do we do?
-I don't know.
If I don't get that autograph,
Ali would never speak to me again.
There's no going back.
I'm barging my way through sir.
Excuse me, excuse me.
I have a child with me.
Thanks.
Wave, Ayla. Wave.
She's looking.
Wave.
Come over little cutie.
Don't forget your big brother Ali!
Don't forget him.
Don't forget Ali.
Hi.
What is this.
Do you want me to sign this.
Yes?
For who is it?
Tell her dear.
-Ali.
-Good girl!
For Ali.
Okey.
This is for Ali.
Do you want me to kiss it.
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Kiss it! Kiss it!
Wait for me.
Start the music again.
Suleyman...
Sir!
Sir! Sir!
Sir! Help me! Sir!
Sir!
Medic! Medic!
Don't cry.
I'll never leave you.
July, 1951
Fellow soldiers...
...we've spent one year in Korea.
We've lost many of our fellow men.
God rest their souls.
But now it's time to go home.
Newly arriving troops...
...will take over from us gradually.
I thank you all very much.
-Forgive me if I failed you in any way.
-Thank you!
Ayla, come on. Eat it girl.
You don't play with your food Ayla.
A second unit of troops is coming, sir.
Yes, they'll take over from us.
We're going back.
First privates, then NCOs
and then us.
I'm happy for you.
I'm staying on as a volunteer.
I may return after another tour, sir.
Isn't it a little early to decide, Suleyman?
My love...
We've moved again,
this time to an old school.
The address is on the envelope.
News must have reached home by now.
Every day I listen to songs and the news
from home on the radio Ali left behind...
...and I think of you.
Please be patient for a little longer.
-Give me your blessing, sir.
-Come here.
-This is for you.
-Thanks.
Thanks.
Ayla.
F... F... Fa... Far...
Farewell...
My little lamb.
My love...
We're sending the privates
under our command home now.
New men are coming to replace them.
We're training them, too.
So you see,
I'm staying here a while longer.
-Anything for me?
-No, sir.
Why don't we know about it?
He left without telling us.
OK, we were proud.
But it's time he came back.
He's done his duty.
It's time we got him married.
They said he had a sweetheart
in Iskenderun.
On air now, we bring you Heroes Hour.
First up, a request
from Nuran Sayilgan of Iskenderun.
The song is written and composed
in the Maqam Suzinak by Sedat Oztoprak...
...and is dedicated to
Sgt, Major Suleyman Dilbirligi,...
...an NCO serving in South Korea.
So here we have "If you only knew
how much I miss you".
Oh, if you only knew...
...how much I miss you
Where are you?
You've stopped coming, my love
Honey. Now I understand
your chest pains.
But I don't want your hopes
to be dashed.
He's seen foreign lands.
He won't like this places now.
For two people to be togeth--
It's all right, Mom.
He's a good person.
He was like that as a child.
He deserves to be happy.
Just so long as he's well.
What does the song say, Daddy?
-It says "Go back."
-Where to?
Home.
I have a home, too.
Are you going to go?
Not without you.
You're the one I love
What do you mean you aren't going?
It's not your decision.
There are orders.
So long as you work for the Armed Forces
you have to obey those orders.
If not, you resign.
How can I, sir?
I have responsibilities at home,
people I made promises to.
That's my point son.
Isn't it tough on those people?
Isn't it tough on Ayla?
She calls me "Daddy".
She can't go on without me now.
If they let me have her,
then I'll go back.
Enough!
This conversation is over!
Ayla is Korean and she's staying here.
-Anything for me?
-No, sir.
Sgt. Suleyman.
The colonel's sent for you.
Let's go.
Let's go then.
At ease, son.
We have a landing ship leaving
on Friday.
It'll call at Izmir,
we have to send you with it.
We're going in 10 days ourselves.
We're handing the command
over to new Turkish officers.
You can’t stay here so pack up.
You don't understand.
What will happen to Ayla?
Our army has established
the promised orphanage in Suwon.
Ankara School.
Ayla will live there.
She'll go to school like her peers.
This lady here runs the school.
She brought some clothes for Ayla.
She wants you to give her.
All the children like Ayla
who've been cared for by our troops are...
...being taken in by Miss Ji-Min.
They're grateful to you.
But don't push it.
Besides, it'll be good for Ayla, too.
But Ayla won't leave me
just like that.
And I'd like to see
where she'll be living.
I'll go with him, colonel.
Don't you worry.
We did a good deed. It shouldn't
end this way. Let it end amicably.
You know why we're here Ayla?
You'll have wonderful friends here.
You'll get to meet them.
Do you want to look around
with your teacher?
But you can't go to school with me too.
See your friends all together there?
They're altogether, not scared.
You want them to think you're scared?
That you can't even come to school
without your Daddy?
-OK.
-OK. Good girl.
Come on. Say bye to daddy.
Go on.
I'm coming too, OK.
Here I am.
Ayla, say hi to your friends.
It's a good place.
It'll be even better.
Turkish Army will keep its support here.
My name is Ayla.
Way to go.
Say bon appetit.
Bon appetit.
Here you can study English
with your friends.
This is a terrific anthem, Ayla.
Anthem. Like a song.
-Like the ones on the radio?
-Like the ones on the radio, yes.
Ankara, Ankara, glorious Ankara
Look, if you learn to sing this anthem
better than everyone...
I'll always be proud of you, OK?
Anyone in trouble hopes for your help
You provide for them, glorious Ankara
Ankara, Ankara, glorious Ankara
Anyone ill-starred wants to see you
Anyone in trouble hopes for your help
You provide for them, glorious Ankara
Ankara, Ankara, glorious Ankara
Anyone ill-starred wants to see you
Anyone in trouble hopes for your help
You provide for them, glorious Ankara
Daddy!
You're going home.
You said you wouldn't go without me.
You said you wouldn't leave me.
I won't leave you. I won't.
We'll leave this place together.
Come on now.
Come on.
It'll be a bit tough,
but you won't suffocate.
You mustn't make a sound
on the ship, OK?
OK.
Once we're on the ship,
it will be easy.
I'll hide you away.
Don't you miss home, Sergeant?
You're late to return.
It's my duty, sir.
That suitcase is so huge.
What have you got in there?
Not a lot, sir.
Most of it's from the Tokyo trip.
I've talked about this place so much
in letters.
I'll open it if you want to see.
Sergeant...
...have a safe journey.
Thank you, sir.
Suleyman.
Suleyman, where's the girl?
Open the suitcase.
Do you know how bad this is
when everyone was so grateful to you?
I've begged everyone.
No one's going to file a complaint.
All I ask is that you board that ship
and go home.
When I came here,...
...I was told to leave everything behind.
So I did.
Now they want the same
on my way back.
I've already left Ali.
They can count that.
But I can't leave Ayla.
Even if I did,
she wouldn't let me go.
She's just a child.
She can't make decisions.
Nobody's separating you.
This war will end.
Go home, make a life, come back later.
Ayla will be here, in her country.
Believe me it's better that way.
Please think rationally.
A young tree flourishes in its own soil.
For God's sake, Mesut...
...do you really believe
what you're saying?
I believe in you.
I know that one day
you'll come back for her.
No crying.
Don't cry.
If I hear you've been crying,
I'll be very sad.
OK, maybe you can cry a bit.
But you mustn't cry once I've gone, OK?
Promise me.
-You promise?
-Promise.
Good girl.
Now I'm going to make you a promise.
I'll come back, OK?
I'll come back
and we won't ever be separated then.
You promise?
I promise.
Fathers strive for their children.
They live for the promises
they've made to them.
I'll be back.
I promise.
Iskenderun Turkey, 1951
Welcome home.
Thank you.
Ilhan was in Izmir to meet me.
What a treat it is being welcomed!
You've come back alone.
How could we not meet you
in a day like this?
Wow! Congratulations.
It suits you both.
Why didn't Nuran come?
I haven't heard from her in a while.
Didn't she get permission
or have you arranged a surprise party?
We're not the only ones
who get engaged Suleyman.
We didn't want you to hear it from us.
But you can guess.
Is it true what I've heard?
My uncle heard the radio.
The world is a big place for you but
this is a small place.
So what if he heard?
Why didn't you tell him everything?
You should've told him.
Why didn't you say anything, Nuran?
Am I a thief? Am I evil?
Am I a runaway? Dishonest?
You aren't a thief.
Neither evil nor dishonest,
but you are disloyal, Suleyman.
As for running away...
...you should've thought about that
when you chose to stay on.
I told you not to leave me.
But you cared more about that little girl
than this girl here.
I was given this engagement ring...
...and I hope you're given
many more medals.
Goodbye.
-I urgently need to wire some money.
-Sure.
Father,...
...I've returned by the grace of God.
I'm coming to Maras.
I want to marry a girl
you find suitable...
...and leave this place
right away.
With my love and respect.
Istanbul, 5 months later
Welcome.
Welcome to you too, ma'am.
I've had the house painted.
It's good as new.
Take down that sign, son.
Come in and I'll show you around.
-Good morning.
Won't you have something to eat?
I don't have time.
Have a good day.
Honorary Consulate of South Korean,
Istanbul
Sir! It's just us at this hour.
We're open 9 am to 5 pm.
Ahmet, I'm leaving a bit early today.
I trust you to take care of things.
The colonel's car has broken down
on the road, sir.
It's an emergency.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
I won't let you go today
without at least some tea.
Yes, but...
I have things to do, Nimet.
You're looking for that girl in Korea,
aren't you?
I know.
Come sit down and let's
talk about it.
There's nothing that can't be worked out.
I don't know how much you know.
We were ambushed one night.
That's where we found Ayla.
How could I leave her there?
I couldn't. She was so cute.
You should've seen her.
She had a face like the moon.
Ali was all for giving her a name.
Wait, I should pour it.
Well, basically...
...I promised the girl, Nimet.
Look. I've always been proud of
what you did for the girl.
I thought, "That's the man I fell for."
We're married now.
Please let me help you.
But how can you help?
Your girl is my girl,
your promise my promise.
I'll apply to wherever necessary.
Don't say I won't know what to do.
If you show me, I'll learn quickly.
I'm the wife of a Korean War hero.
I'll command respect wherever I go.
Just so long as you let me.
I'll start the inquiry myself.
Sure. Of course.
Please.
Mr. Suleyman...
...as you know,
I'm afraid the war is still on.
That makes communication very hard.
It's also impossible for us to
inquire under the name "Ayla".
But that's her name.
I mean, she doesn't have another name.
Well, Mr. Suleyman,
we're getting nowhere this way.
I'd say try your luck again now and
then but...
...it's no good unless you go there
and get involved in person.
Unfortunately.
I've written to Ankara School in Korea.
I'm hoping for an answer very soon.
We've a good chance of hearing back
one way or another.
It'll just take a little time.
We'll find the girl.
Has the girl forgotten her name, Nimet?
If they say your dad is looking for you,
she'd say it right away.
She hasn't forgotten.
I'm a girl, too.
No girl forgets her father.
When the war ends,
I must use my first leave to go there.
I need to be with her.
It's at least a week's journey.
Two weeks there and back.
How will you get so much leave?
There has to be another way.
I'm looking into it all.
The math is obvious.
Not even the state can help...
How will I manage on my own?
You aren't on your own.
Come on, get some rest.
It just needs a little time, Suleyman.
Just a little time.
Suleyman! Suleyman!
Suleyman!
Mr. Suleyman, are you all right?
Nimet, how are you?
Are you OK Suleyman?
47 years later...
-How are you Nimet?
I'm fine.
August17, 1999
Marmara Earthquake
The earthquake struck overnight at 03.02
and was felt most in Izmit, Istanbul...
...Ankara, Eskisehir, Adapazari,
Zonguldak, Bolu and Kutahya.
Woken by the noise and violent tremors,
citizens poured into the street.
The worst damage occurred
in Izmit, Adapazari and Eskisehir.
Some buildings collapsed
in Avcilar as well.
There had been fires broke out and
power outages caused a lot of panic.
Izmit, Golcuk has been razed.
Even Yalova! Yalova is razed too!
But I don't know how many people.
Where are you going Mr. Suleyman?
They say do not enter the buildings.
-Dad!
-We're still shaking.
Where are you going daddy?
Don't worry,
I'll see what he's up to.
Suleyman.
The children are worried.
She's my child, too.
Oh, Suleyman.
When you've survived a war...
...you don't care about death anymore.
It feels like you've dodged
the Angel of Death.
It feels like you have many years
ahead of you, but...
...it's been 50 years.
We could've died, Nimet.
But I made a promise.
I don't want to die
without keeping my promise.
Search and rescue continues, whole Turkey,
even the world is trying to help.
Our sister country South Korea is also is
by our side with all their means and support.
Both rescue parties and...
There are Koreans here, too. You see?
Good for them!
They're truly loyal people.
Maybe your Ayla has also came out
of loyalty to her father's nation.
Huh, Mr. Suleyman?
They've reached the injured.
What's he doing now?
Second half of the game for the third place
in the World Cup Series is about to start.
June 29, 2002
FIFA World Cup: South Korea - Turkey
Our national team has completed
the first half, 3 to 1.
Here comes Turkey...
-Turkey! Turkey!
-Shh! Stop running!
My father found a Korean girl there.
He's been looking for her for years.
-But how's he going to find her?
-That's a shame.
-If only he could go over there.
-But it's hard.
People barely even get to visit their
own family on holidays.
Right, Mom?
She must be an old woman now.
Who's to say she's still alive?
I keep saying the same thing.
So does my brother. Time and again!
But Dad won't listen.
Don't say that.
He gets upset.
Maybe she's already dead.
It's life.
But people are right, Mom.
Daddy.
I'm here, Daddy.
Suleyman!
Suleyman.
A newsperson or someone is
here from Korea.
They're doing interviews at the society
for the 60th anniversary.
They've said they want to help find Ayla.
They definitely want to talk to us.
My South Korean colleague,
Sung Joon and I...
...are working on a documentary
about the Korean War.
As it's the 60th anniversary...
Easy to say.
We're looking at veterans' stories,
what happened there.
Everyone has been talking about
the action they saw there.
Everyone is talking about
how they shoot people or get shot.
So I told them... We have a friend called
Suleyman, an NCO.
He saved a little girl there.
I was so excited to hear that.
I spoke to my colleague right away.
We want to make a documentary
of this story and also to trace Ayla.
If you help us, we'll find Ayla.
I can't believe you're saying this.
It's all I want in life.
But they say her name's changed.
She changed it after leaving school.
Don't you worry, Mr. Suleyman.
Look, everything's changed now.
There are records, archives.
But do you have any photos of Ayla?
Absolutely!
They're all there in my album.
I keep them immaculate.
There you go.
Just what we wanted to hear.
Shall we start right away?
Seoul - South Korea
National Archive Seoul
Almost everything was destroyed
because of the fire at the archives.
Most of the information we need is gone.
The shutdown the Ankara school
makes it harder.
The name Ayla,
it is nothing by itself.
We must learn her real name.
Couldn't we reach any of the students
who are still alive?
Some might remember Ayla.
They were classmates after all.
I thought that.
Here is the interesting list...
...my assistant is researching it.
Mr. Sung, there are some striking names
on the list.
Thanks.
We found those six students
who studied at this school at the time.
They never lose contact
after graduated.
They still meet every year.
I'm sure they remember Ayla.
Let's meet them as soon as possible.
Exactly.
Good evening, Mr. Suleyman.
We've found some graduates
from Ankara School in Korea.
They were students
at the same time as Ayla.
They're saying,
"Yes, we remember her."
A Turkish soldier brought her.
She sat quietly in a corner and
never joined in.
She never spoke to us.
She'd say, 'My dad's coming to get me.'
The teachers taught us all
a Turkish anthem.
That's when she joined in.
She'd sit in front
and sing louder than any of us.
And she'd say...
'If I learn this anthem well,
my father will be proud of me.'
Ankara, Ankara, glorious Ankara
Anyone ill-starred wants to see you
Anyone in trouble hopes for your help
You provide for them, glorious Ankara
Ankara, glorious Ankara
Anyone ill-starred wants to see you
Anyone in trouble hopes for your help
You provide for them, glorious Ankara
Mr. Suleyman, this is just a start.
We'll find someone
who knows her for sure.
I mean, even if she isn't alive, w--
She's alive.
You said you'd find her alive.
But now it's all about corpses?
Sebahat.
If you'll excuse me.
Ms. Ozge.
Look, you keep coming here
and telling my father stories.
But my father's heart won't take it.
Really it won't.
I don't want this to go any further.
-I understand.
-Good!
Sweetheart?
What were you saying there?
What kind of attitude was that?
I made a promise.
Fathers strive for their children and
live for the promises they've made to them.
Haven't I done that for you and
your brother?
Is it about me?
Are you afraid I'll die?
Bless you, my love.
Don't be afraid.
I won't die until my promise is kept.
-Hi.
-Hello Ozge.
We found Ayla.
We finally found her this time.
-Really?
-Yes.
It's a great news.
But there are other things
we need to talk first.
Okey. I call you from my office.
We reached a graduated.
She said, Ayla saw her sister
on to her twenties.
She said, her name was Kim Eunja.
Are you sure?
Is she Ayla?
Her misfortune so similar.
We did some research.
The woman had a marriage.
Unfortunately her husband died
at a young age.
Look at that.
It's her picture.
Poor woman.
She never had a life.
She is efforts to work.
She wanna be self sufficient
and not be bother on anyone.
She does cleaning work at school.
What do you think?
Shall we tell that Suleyman.
His daughter caused a lot of trouble today.
And she has her reasons.
Look, the photos are incredible similar.
We should try in any case.
We can't leave this here.
Fine.
I'll catch the first flights.
Arrange a meeting with that woman.
Let's go and meet her.
If she remembers Mr. Suleyman
after all these years....
...and feels like get in together...
...it will be worth our efforts...
...if these two people reunite.
Come in.
That's right.
Daddy...
Daddy. Daddy.
How could I forget my father?
Is he still alive?
Daddy...
Seoul
April, 2010
Seoul has gotten so big.
Who knows how my Ayla...
She's been through so much, Nimet.
I couldn't be there for her.
Isn't that Ayla?
Daddy!
Daddy.
Fathers strive for their children.
They live for the promises
they've made to them.
I promise.
After 60 years Suleyman and his daughter
reunited in Seoul on April th10th. 2010...
...and never separated after.
According to the Unicef reports...
...there are 28 million war-weary children
like Ayla all over the world.
1,5 million of them are living with us
in our country.
Isn't that Ayla coming?
Dear Daddy.
It's like as if I've seen you
just yesterday.
I can still feel
your callous hands.
We have to live long.
I wonder about you every second.
I thank you for raising
a little girl who left...
...in the middle of war and
accept her as your own.
I love, daddy.
Take care of yourself.
Your daughter...
...Ayla.