and you forgot that i
was in army for 5 years.
indians will not give me visa.
i'll take you there.
whatever happens,
my daughter could speak.
i can do anything for it.
i've think about it.
i'll take shahida to delhi
no one returned empty
handed from the God's beloved .
reaching to pakistan,
your daughter will speak
why the train is not running,
the tracks are under construction.
ok i'm sleeping.
shahida.
indians are saying they
couldn't find your daugher
listen to me.
let me go, i'll find her myself.
its across the border,
in other country.
so what.
i've to bring back my daughter.
to going back,
you'll need visa.
be patient, you'll find your daughter.
how?
my daughter is alone
in the strange country
you can't do anything..
i'll find my shahida by myself.
someone will be good person
in the india..
who will take care
of our shahida..
what is selfie.?
when we tak picture
is called selfie.
you danced like hero now,
yes I goes crazy for bajrangbali
you must have some name.
it seems that she's deaf.
she's illetrate..
write in hindi.
why you're following me again.
you lost in carnival from your parents?
say something..?
now you're in charming temple.
as like you're finding your parents,
they're also finding you
they'll come here,
you just sit here..
i'll be back.
if they takes some time...
so you eat that apple.
dont be hungry.
you can't leave this girl here.
why
her parents will come
here to report..
if they dont come so.
why not..
look at her face.
but you can't leave her here.
look her face,
and look their face.
they all are thug inside..
its police station,
not asylum
write your name address,
i'll call you when know about her.
till?
isn't your home here?
but where is?
somewhere must be..
i'll call the city names..
raise your hand on your city
are you from pratabgarh.
yes..
lives near station.
i'm living in delhi now a days..
why ? for job or girl?
its long story..
tell us we're not in hurry
she dont speak..
will you listen my story
i'm pawan..
people calls me bajrangi with love.
you call me uncle
whenever you speak.
my father was post master
no 25.. no 27..
for uncle ..
the health was important.
i was fail in wrestling.
dont laugh.
he won't reform
you can't do anything..
wrestling tickles me..
this honor wasn't suffiecient
for father, he was leader too
i wasn't interested in
any subject of father.
therefore he gave me
that name.. zero.
what happened?
father again..
to completing matriculation,
it took 20 years.
from matric to graduation,
i failed 10 times.
father had given up on us.
friends said, just cheat
and get passed..
i said...fail is okey,
but I'll not cheat.
so i reached 11th
times to give exame..
please come.
you must have breaked
your own record of failing.
when you did it 10th time.
so why you gone again.
i've accepted that
you're foolish.
you're zero..
listen to me..
why do i listen,
you're failed 10th times.
what else is remaing
to listen..
if you want to do something
for me..so please go from here.
delhi..i heared that there
is lactation of uncapable people.
i've a old friend there.
he'll get you job..
father i passed.
so what he said?
i knew he'll be in shock,
but will so hardly i didn't think
what happened?
father i'm going to delhi,
and the last wish of father..
i came to delhi
to dayanad.
i dont have change.
do you have 5 rupee,
so i can give you 10 rupee.
does'n't matter,
you keep it, in it 5 rupee are yours
so give me..
how can i give you, i've 5 in it mine
it does't matter,
you keep it.
how can i keep it..
so give me..
but mine are too
sister.
what..
your money
i dont want 5 rupee.
take it..
so give me..
i've half in it mine.
get change.
you..
you reached at home.
are you staking me
no sister.. i...
what i..
i told you i dont want money
was in my bus,
and staking me.
i'm not bully..
and I'm not following you
who are you..
i'm pawan.
get him down..
take this..
its special..
when we boil the potato.
we puts salt in it
you eat it..
is someone cooking meat,
in the near villa..
i said clearly..
now one will give house
on rent to other religion
you tell me what
work do you do?
i've come here fot find work
can't you find job in your school
do you still go to school
i dont learn..
but i teach..
go with her tomorrow
you'll find job there.
put beneath bed
before sleeping
here are mosquito
give me your hand..
excuse me.
trust me.
my name is not sister,
but rasika.
what next?
then one day trivedi came.
sit here.
how are you proshotum
father you says that every girl
finds shadow of her father..
i can't see your shadow
except in pawan.
if the matter was like that,
so why you called us and insulted.
who wants to stay here.
you will not engaged with rasika.
till you will not become
capable for rasika.
and for capable of it..
first condition is house.
which you'll buy by
your earned money
and you've 6 months,
or i'll find the capable boy
when she dont speak..
so how do you know she's hindu.
she's white..
till when will she stay here.
till she won't find parents.
and when will they?
when bajrangbali wishes.
did you ever traveled in air plane.
i did once.
do you know what they say in plane
first wear your oxygen mask,
then help others.
till when will you do social work
think about your life.
do hard work,
buy a good house.
if you can't do it..
so tell me now.
neither your time will waste
and of rasika's.
she's not orphan.
i she would be, ..
she has parents,
when bajrangbali told you
what happened to munni.
i couldnt find her.
we were eating together.
munni is not at roof too
whatever your best item is,
give this to her.
white like milk,
i thought she's brahamman.
she may be shatriya,
they eats meat and are white.
why she's crying.
take this colorful bengles.
take it.
bengles..
my money for bengles?
we dont want it.
she's kid..
stealing is bad thing..
you know i went to non-veg
hotel because of munni
but i swear i didn't eat anything
forgive me..
you know i'm helpless with munni
you gave me one hint
that she's shatriya.
what that.
wher's munni.
that..
munni is momaden
she was reading something.
but where is she...
what father will say
where is she,
betrayed in way.
she's 6 years old lost girl.
she can't speak..
what father will say.
do you know why i love you,
because your heart is clean.
this is all rubbish..
the other religion..
i can't say this to father.
but you can.
lets go..
she's alone inside.
father will thorow out the munni
if he'll find out something so..
means..
who wil tell him
i'll tell him..
are you crazy.
what happened to her..
dont know .
why are you dancing.
what she's doing.
you brought her calling
her brahamman..
you're the companion
of the helpless people.
i didn't do anything..
she was following me.
you'll give her to
pakistani embassy.
this girls country people
kills our country people
what is the fault of munni in it.
i know
but that country is her,
i'm not cruel.
but now i can't bear her
in my house.
she can't speak..
where is her passport.
how'd i know
so how do you know
she's pakistani,
in yesterday match.
when pakistan won so she danced.
and she kissed your flag.
so its mean she's pakistani
how do you know her..
i met her in carnival
what she was doing there.
how'd i know.
we can't do anything
send her home
i dont know anything.
i'll leave her here..
i'm saying it last time.
i'll call the security
i'll call my people,
and thorow you outta india.
i'm india..
i'm working for embassy
bravo bajrangi
i told you to send back the girl,
you shut the embassy.
will munni live with us
for one more month
it will not be neede.
there's a travel agent
near govind's office.
we dont make pakistani passport.
people came here to
make american passport.
england,germany ,japan too
but she's from pakistan,
what will she do in german
we can't do it.
i've the way for without passport.
means..
i know people who'll cross border.
i can request them
please request them.
we're in trouble
i'll talk till evening..
do you have 1.5 lac?
what're you doing?
withdrawing from bank.
this money is for our
house deposit.
but this time is more important
is to send munni back.
if i'll not buy house, so father
will marry you with someone else
you still couldn't understand.
banrangbali him self can't stop
me marrying you
i swear to bajranbali
reaching there.
how can i find her parents.
those agents has
many contacts.
look you dont worry
its father's number,
as she meet her parents call us
why you're crying..
he's taking you to pakistan.
he's taking you to
your mother.
this is no your country,
you can't stay here.
since i've find you,
there's trouble in my life.
please leave us.
go back to your house.
i beg of you
did you see a small girl,
she just came now. there.
sister..
which angle i'm sister.
now?
now I'll take money
to her house by myself.
are you crazy..
no passport, no visa.
you dont know anybody there
i've no passport and visa.
but I've ram in my heart.
and whose heart has ram in..
nothing is impossible for him
who are you
who are you...
this is our are..
when did i saiy its mine.
going to cross the boarder.
it will cost you 25 thousand..
if you have so come.
these wire has electricity.
after touching it.
human blood sucks.
look..this is mohammad
ali jinnah..have you seen it.
its pakistan rupee,
gandhi dont work there.
if you go by this way..
so bsf will see you
first they'll shoot,
and ask you sould about you
its not easy to cross the border.
i've setting both sides.
sit in the car.
i'm saying to fo kis goodness
just it will take 50 thousand..
you told 50 thousand.
one man 25 thouand.
munni is going to her house.
i recognized you after seeing you,
you're good guy
that side of wire,
pakistan comes after 10 min
there's 4 ways under the car.
i'm the deciples of bajranbali.
i dont do anything wrong.
are you crazy..
they'll shoot us.
lets go
i'll go after permission.
i understand you to see you
you're crazy.
are you indian..
but munni is pakistani
she lost with her parents.
so i'm going pakistan
i never heared this story before.
so why dont you go..
i'm decepiles of bajrangbali
just stayed here for you permission.
if you wanted the permission,
so why dont you go to emabassy
i went to pakistani emabassy
in delhi.
but the drove me out.
so how you reached here.
he's a agent.
he said he have both side setting
what's rubbish.
how come you came here.
by train..
where's drain.
send both of them back
fromt his drain..
and put the sand in the drain.
run away from here.
or we'll shoot you
i promised to bajranbali
till i dont drop munni home.
i wont' take rest.
we'll fix you now.
look, if you'd have passport
and visa.
eventhen i'd not allow you
to go from here.
right now..
go back.
i'm saying it for your goodness.
as i'll find the munni's parents,
i'll go back to india..
look, we'll come on round
after 10 min
in that 10 min..
you go there or there we dont know
but if we see you again.
this time we'll shoot you
if you call yourself bajrangbali decepiles.
so come back for sure.
i promise you
do one thing..
leave it...take it.
and bring tea and paratha.
if paratha will be cold,
so i'll make you cold.
where's hand cought..
what?
that you stole it..
find it in his bag.
look..
do i have it?
what a small girl do
with hand cought.
are you spy..
i'm not spy
and munni is pakistani
so she's pakistani?
and i'm sachin tendulkar.
there police has nabbed
the indian spy.
at the bilal's hotel,
taking to police station
you had pawan's call.
no
still he have boarded the munni
in the train..
didn't you say him that
call us from wagha..
he may have forget.
you may call him
i've reached to police station,
you come now.
tell us about your mission
tell us detail
how you enter in pakistan.
how many rupee are you getting
for this dangerous mission
why'd i get money
so you're doing it for country
what is the role of
a girl in this mission
as you see in our footage,
a indian spy and his partner.
are arrested in district chawla.
girl is so hard trained
that she didn't speak anything.
lets take it once more.
shut down.
what happened?
his phone is off.
i've taken the blastic interview.
the indian spy interview.
your channel will be no. 1.
he said..
he has taken indian spy interview.
what's this rubbish.
its problem
its okey.. tell him that
call me when he comes
till i'll keep ready the report.
told you many times.
have to take munni home
if you'll keep saying lie,
you can't go out ever.
i dont lie.
what happened munni.
you know the place.?
here's your home.
found it sir.
munni's house ..
whats your name.
she can't speak
can't speak..
why? dont have toungue
show me..
open your mouth
according to our sources,
indian spy is going in zero security
it is said that he'll be
shifted to islamabad.
look..
come fast.
that border's wire..
came from beneath that,
but with permission
you've come from india
to pakistan for finding her parents.
yes..
why.
if people like you would
be more in our country..
show me the picture.
speak properly...
he ran away..
do anybody recognize this place.
a man has boarded in
this bus wearing sweate
no..
no one like it boarded.
anyone from you seen
a guy with small girl.
no sir..
the girl was pointing on the
rocks picture about her home.
they took the photo
tonight you're safe in this place.
go from here in morning.
i can't go inside..
why? i'm not momeden
so what ..this place
is open for everyone..
therefore we never lock
the mosque..
its switzerland.
if you dont know so
move forward, no its switzerland.
look here is written in english
are you from switzerland.?
this kind of mountain
are in kashmir.
hey bajranbali what will
you make me do...
made me sleep in mosque,
made me wear burqa..
before cercumsize .
make us meet with munni's parents.
there'll be police on road.
you go by the field.
this all happened because of you
neither you stuborn
to send munni home, nor pawan lost.
because of you
he's stuck badly
now you do something.
what can i do in it.
if you didn't do anything.
so i'll go to pakistan to find him
its bad thing.
nothing go right by lieing.
you speaked again lady,
not cover up
you sit inside..
when I say hit self..
you fixed it in a min
its my duty to help travelers.
do i drop you somewhere.
what's your name.
she's dumb
what doctors says..
she can't talk also
its family problem
its all fate.
are you going to khanewal,
no, but i'll drop you
you drop us to highway..
i dont have any problem
i'll tell my officer,
so he'll drop you there.
i'm the sho of that area.
i was on leave today,
but going back on emergency
an indian spy is fugative here.
look he's our special guest.
and are very good mechenic.
drop them on their door
in khanewal.
thanks for you help..
will you have breakfast?
no.
just little more far..
i dont know the way
actually i eloped her,
and her father is angry
this is the area.
in the mess of marriage,
you forgot your home.
who is that girl.
and what she's doing.
but i dont have any daughter.
there's no gain to be
angry stading on road.
lets go inside..
and angry with me.
i married without your permission
are you angry..
please hit me.
and a girl is with them
what age.?
5 years.
and she's dumb..
dumb too
what're you seeing my face.
do the radio to hassan.
who is it..
will you break the door.
where are they..
your daughter and son-in-law.
i told you many times.
i dont have anyone.
so where are they
how'd i know..
they vanished after your leave.
i was thinking that
i'd surrender to police.
and pakistani police
will find the munni's house
dont even think about it.
you'll rot in jail for life.
as hard you're working for
finding her house will police?
then our munni will be send
to any orphange
i won't let it happen.
i swear to bajrangbali
that I'll send munni to her house
hate is easy saleable
but love,
what is the shrine of hazrat amin shah?
very famous shrine,
everybody's wishes comes true
so why didn't we go there.
you feel fever on the name of mosque
thanks god..
where are you
is someone near you.
no.
are you with spy..
he's not spy
he's good guy
he has come to take
lost girl to her home
but where are you now.
we're going to hazrat amin sha shrine
take care of yourself..
God protect you
i'm chandnawab,
i'm going to tell you about a guy
who came in our country
from border in dark..
and his name is bajrangi
like police i believed that
he's spy..
but now i know he's
not indian spy
so who's that guy.
why he penetrate here.
bajrangi is a normal guy
like us and his motive was.
love for a speakless pakistani
5 year girl.
who lost in india with her parents
he's not picking up..
pick up
greetings chandnawab
is everthing okey..
you went to shrine.
yes last night
now where are you ?
gojra.
okey I'll call you later.
atleast you said lie.
so you made me lie
didn't you see maha bharat?
is that a movie.
if you know that girl,
so put your number in website
from where this bus is coming.
where you want to go.
i'm asking from where it
is coming...you're strange
tell us first from where?
your village name is jahanabad
and before it..
its ussain
and before this..
its karimabad.
are you from sultanpur.
look this video..
chandnawab putted on internet
we checked the all gojra..
he's not here.
send the pictures from
this video
stop every car and check
greetings..
i'm chandnawab
and today i'm going to tell
you about a guy
came in our country
and his name is bajrangi
like police i thought he's spy,
but i know hes not
so who is he..
what he wants.
his only motive was love.
for a speakless pakistani girl
who lost in india..
bajrangi has only this
way to send her back
to this story..every
channel denied to show
nobody is interested in it.
so help bajrangi so he can
go back to his home
if you know this girl so..
what this press, media is thinking
he's indian spy for us
that girl's parents called us and
said that she lost in india.
but pakistani people has
sympathy for him
i want pawan's confession anyhow.
i worked all my life for
protecting this country
if this guy..
goes in the pakistani jail
so it will be against the
honor of our country
get the camera..
look bajrangi is on t.v
today the pakistani press officer
posted new video today
who is locked in pakistani jail
pawan chatravedi.
aka. bajrangi bhaijan.
who putted his life in danger
for a lost pakistani girl.
why he did ?
for money, fame?
no..
he did it with his clear heart.
he see her with love.
not enemy
but alas..
this god's man stuck in two country hate
and today the hate forced
him to hide like criminal
and we've to do this..
the people.
who wants to treat their kids with love.
lets finish this hae.
move forward to narowar
check post together.
billions people of both
country decide that.
nobody could stop him crossing
the border.
i completed my promise
made with bajrangbali
shahida is with her parents.
lets go
but this time not beneath the wires.
open the door..
i've your arrest order
if putting his life in danger
he brought back lost girl
so eventhen you'd not open the door.
i can't open this door.
this is pakistani people
if they can find true or false,
why not you?
so this guy should be
stopped crossing border.
but we are few soldiers..
and people are in mob