This way, quickly.
Loyalty and courage
still exist in this world.
Ritter von Greim
and Frulein Reitsch, how good...
...that the both of you arrived
more or less unharmed.
Sit down.
We came under heavy fire,
but still arrived in Gatow.
From there,
we couldn't continue.
We flew in a Fieseler Storch,
over the Russian lines...
...and landed on the
East-West axis, close to here.
Before landing, the Soviets
had a go at us.
A telegram from Gring.
Received yesterday.
Read
You see they spare me nothing.
Neither deception nor infidelity.
Neither infamy nor treason.
You end up regretting
your own kindness.
General Von Greim, I appoint you
Supreme Commander of the Luftwaffe.
I hereby promote you
to General-Field Marshal.
Mein Fhrer, I will not disappoint you.
A big responsibility
rests on your shoulders.
You must rebuild the
Luftwaffe from the ground up.
Many mistakes have been made.
Be ruthless.
Life doesn't forgive weakness.
This so-called humanity
is religious drivel.
Compassion is an eternal sin.
To feel compassion for the weak...
...is a betrayal of nature.
The strong can only triumph
if the weak are exterminated.
I've remained faithful to this law of nature,
and have never shown compassion.
I've always been ruthless
when faced with internal...
...opposition from other races.
And that's the only way.
Apes, for instance...
...kill all outsiders.
And what applies to apes,
most certainly applies to humans.
Himmler made an offer to surrender...
...to the Western powers.
Via Count Bernadotte.
Reported on English radio.
Himmler.
Of all people, Himmler.
The most loyal of my loyals.
That is the most terrible treason.
Gring, yes, he was corrupt.
Always has been.
Speer, yes, an absent-minded artist.
All the others: yes.
But Himmler?
Has he gone insane?
He must have told
them I'm sick.
Or perhaps already dead.
Leave me alone with Ritter Von Greim
and Frulein Reitsch.
And get Fegelein.
We don't know where he is.
What? He's Himmler's adjutant.
He must be available.
We haven't seen him for days.
I want a report immediately.
Stay, Doctor, Please.
You and Greim must go as quickly
as possible. Fly to Dnitz.
Tell him to do everything
it takes to punish Himmler.
We've decided to
die with you.
Thank you for this proof of loyalty.
But Himmler must die.
He committed treason.
He's no longer necessary
for my plans.
Do you think I'll just look on as
those Jewish swine slaughter me?
This is part of a huge decoy operation.
I've allowed the enemy...
...to invade the Reich.
And they think they've won.
But mark my words:
they'll have a rude awakening.
Dnitz is mobilizing in the north.
Kesselring in the south.
We'll surround the enemy
and crush them in a pincer movement.
From Prague, three armies will attack
the Russians, simultaneously, from the rear.
I didn't know we still had
so many reserve troops.
I made sure you'll soon have
a thousand of the most modern...
...jets at your disposal.
With those, you can make the
Luftwaffe ready for battle again.
I kneel to your genius, at the
altar of the Fatherland.
He'll be furious if he learns
that Hermann is gone.
Hopefully it's not what it seems.
The Fhrer would never forgive him.
It makes me feel sick.
My sister is carrying Hermann's child.
Don't be so glum, Frulein Braun.
You know the Fhrer as benevolent.
But he can also be quite the opposite.
Heil, mein Fhrer.
You too have requested to leave Berlin?
Mein Fhrer, as you know,
all medical departments...
...that fall under the SS and Himmler,
have left Berlin.
Himmler is a traitor.
He won't escape punishment.
Mein Fhrer, as Reichsarzt SS,
I have no more work here.
Your request to leave Berlin
is unacceptable.
My family...
If the Russians...
I must leave.
You've done nothing wrong.
Future generations will thank you
for your medical research.
I take all the responsibility.
We'll talk about it later.
Gruppenfhrer Fegelein cannot
be found. He's not in the bunker.
What, you can't find Fegelein?
Keep searching. I want to speak
with Fegelein. Immediately.
If he left just like that,
that's desertion. Treason.
Bring me Fegelein.
Fegelein. Fegelein.
Daddy, why are you wearing
your Sunday uniform?
Ernst, is something wrong?
No.
Thank you.
Brigitte is hungry too.
Ilse, you should eat something too.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
What is it?
Gruppenfhrer, you're under arrest.
What?
You're suspected of desertion.
Get dressed.
You'll come with us.
Like hell.
Search the room.
Let go of me.
You can't give me orders.
You won't have Hermann
executed, will you?
There's no doubt.
He wanted to flee.
What does it matter?
Everything's over.
Think of my poor sister.
She's pregnant by Hermann.
He collaborated with Himmler.
He's a traitor.
There's no compassion for traitors.
There's no mercy for them.
He'll be court-martialled
and executed.
What's the point of that?
It is my will.
You're the Fhrer.
Speak.
The Russians are advancing
more and more.
There are no more reserves.
Supplies from the air are impossible.
There's no ammunition
coming in anymore.
In the north, the Russians are standing
in front of the Weidendammer bridge.
In the East: Lustgarten.
South: Potsdammer Platz.
West: Tiergarten, about 400 meters
from the Chancellery.
How long can you hold out?
At most, two days.
Including the government district?
Yes sir, mein Fhrer.
As a soldier, I suggest we
flee Berlin. It's surrounded.
The battle of Berlin has killed
20,000 of our best officers.
That's what young people are for.
Your proposal is insane.
Complete madness.
Think of the thousands of wounded.
We can't help them.
Mein Fhrer, the orders have been written.
I give you my word...
The Fhrer cannot make an honorless
disappearance from world history.
Even if such a move was successful...
...I'll end up in another
troublesome situation.
I'd have to stay in the open air,
or on a farm...
...and wait for the end.
Wenck is advancing with the 12th Army.
He can join the 9th...
...and give the Russians
the final blow.
Wenck's an excellent fellow.
Send a telegram to Keitel:
Immediately report to me the following:
First:
Where is Wenck's vanguard located?
Second:
When will they attack again?
Third: Where is the 9th Army?
Fourth: where will they make a breakthrough?
You'll see, gentlemen.
I'll be right.
Wenck will come.
I want to know if Wenck
can do anything at all.
It's unlikely that Wenck's
small amount of troops...
What's unlikely about the offensive?
Wenck can't do anything anymore.
Then why don't you tell the Fhrer that?
Has everyone gone mad?
Do you think the Fhrer doesn't know?
He'll never surrender.
And neither will we. I've been
through that once. Never again.
Come on. I have to go.
Stop right there.
Heil Hitler.
You have to cut lengthwise.
In the mouth. One shot and you're dead.
Who will win?
Me.
You look very elegant.
I think we're all going to cry today.
Have we reached that point?
No, they'll be tears of joy.
What is it, Helga?
Helga, come.
Helga cries easily lately.
Excuse us.
I must go see your Uncle Hitler, children.
Good night.
Excuse me. I fell asleep.
Did you get some rest, my child?
In shorthand.
My political will.
More than 30 years have passed...
...since I made my contribution
as a volunteer...
...during the first World War.
During those 30 years,
I learned to think, act and live...
...out of love and loyalty
for my people.
Excuse me. The artillery...
Yes. Please sit down.
Centuries will pass...
...but from the ruins
of our cities and monuments...
...the hatred of the people...
...who did this to us,
will continue to flare up.
International Jewry
and its accomplices.
What is it, Herr Minister?
Imagine this.
The Fhrer wants me to leave Berlin.
He ordered it.
I've never ignored an order
from the Fhrer.
But I will ignore this order.
I'll stay with the Fhrer.
Please, Frau Junge...
...I want to dictate my will to you.
I'm typing
the Fhrer's will.
Good.
I understand.
Some other time.
Mein Fhrer, according to the racial law
I'm obliged to ask you:
Mein Fhrer, are you
of Aryan descent?
Can I see your identity card?
You're talking to the Fhrer here.
Alright then.
And you, Frulein Braun,
are you of Aryan descent?
Then there's nothing
to stop us.
I'm asking you now:
Do you, mein Fhrer, Adolf Hitler...
...take Eva Braun, present here,
as your wife? Answer "yes."
Do you, Eva Braun, take Fhrer
Adolf Hitler, present here...
...as your husband?
Answer "yes."
Then I declare you
man and wife.
Frau Junge.
Thank you. Krebs.
I'm happy you could be here.
Congratulations, but I didn't know about it.
When I had to sign, I almost
wrote Braun instead of Hitler.
I had to cross it out.
Is there a response from
our telegram to Keitel?
Do we have news of Wenck and his army?
No, mein Fhrer, I regret to report.
He's injured.
Everything will be alright.
You must go to the Fhrer right away.
At this hour?
How long can we hold out?
Twenty hours, no more.
The Russians are within
a few hundred meters.
For the moment we've brought
them to a standstill.
You know, Mohnke, the western
democracies are decadent.
They'll succumb to
the people from the east.
All the best. Thank you.
It wasn't only for Germany.
A message from Keitel.
1. Wenck's vanguard is
stuck south of Schwielowsee.
2. The 12th Army cannot
continue the attack on Berlin.
3. The 9th Army is
completely surrounded.
What do we do when the last
ammunition reserves have been exhausted?
I'll never surrender. Never.
I forbid you, and the other
commanders, to surrender.
Listen, Gnsche. My wife and I
are going to commit suicide.
I don't want my corpse
exposed by the Russians.
I don't want them to get me,
dead or alive.
I want to be burned
and never to be found.
Gnsche, I want you to promise me...
...that you will do
all it takes.
Mein Fhrer...
...that's a terrible order,
but I will carry it out.
Kempka.
Erich, I need 200 liters of gasoline.
Are you crazy?
Where will I get that from?
From the parked vehicles.
What's all that gas for?
I can't say over the telephone.
Come, please.
The Fhrer wants to see us.
Should I tell the Fhrer
you're indisposed?
It's only my collapsed lung.
I'll die soon anyway.
Excuse me.
Over here, Herr Professor.
One moment, please.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry to interrupt
your important work.
Mein Fhrer, keep faith
in the final victory.
Lead us
and we shall follow.
Come on.
Join the crowd.
Come. Have a drink.
Anyway there isn't much else we can do.
Do sit down.
That's better.
Yes sir, the situation is pretty shitty.
Can we sit down?
Please do, Frulein Br...
Frau...
You can call me Frau Hitler.
It's alright.
A pity we can't go outside anymore.
Only if you want
to die a heroic death.
Fritz, control yourself a bit.
Yes. Control.
Take cover.
Let's go.
What are you doing here?
I have to report to the Fhrer.
You can't right now.
Sit down.
Sit. Drink.
May I present Frau Hitler?
So young and so many decorations.
You must be proud.
Excuse me.
I'm not used to drinking anymore.
You can use our toilet.
If your hand shakes, the bullet
might only hit the optic nerve.
That's why it's good
to take the poison too.
When you bite through the capsule,
pull the trigger.
Will I have enough time?
The poison starts working
after one or two seconds.
Tornow, you too.
Come Blondi.
You know, Frau Junge,
I've known...
my husband for
more than 15 years.
But when I think about it,
I know nothing about him.
Even though he likes to talk.
I longed for Berlin,
but he's so different now.
He only talks about dogs
and vegetarian food now.
I hate Blondi.
Sometimes I kick her, and the Adolf
wonders why she's acting funny.
He doesn't want anyone to see into his heart.
I mean...
...he can be so caring
in his private life.
And then he says
those cruel things.
When he's the Fhrer, you mean?
Come, let's smoke another one.
I'm sorry.
You have so many worries
and here I am, whining.
Frau Junge, I'm giving you this coat
as a farewell gift.
I like fashionable ladies.
I want you to enjoy it.
What a surprise. Thank you.
I just don't know where and when
I can wear it.
Please, try to get out of here.
Promise me.
Thank you. That was very good,
Frulein Manziarly.
The time has come. It's finished.
The Fhrer wants to say goodbye.
Come with me.
You're the bravest mother
of the Reich.
Mein Fhrer, you've made me
the happiest woman in Germany.
Say hello to my beautiful Bavaria.
Children, what are you doing here?
We want to see Aunt Eva
and Uncle Hitler.
Have you eaten anything yet?
Only breakfast.
Stay here, I'll get something to eat.
I'll be right back.
Comrades, this is the
latest news from the outside.
Berlin is full of warehouses: There were
houses here, there were houses there.
Herr Gnsche,
I want to speak to the Fhrer.
Please, I have to.
Frau Goebbels, the Fhrer
doesn't want to be disturbed.
Please, Gnsche,
just for a moment.
Please.
Mein Fhrer, Frau Goebbels is here.
What is it?
Mein Fhrer, I beg you.
Leave Berlin.
Mein Fhrer, don't leave us.
What will become of us?
Tomorrow, I'll be cursed by millions,
but fate wanted it this way.
Get up. Come on.
Come.
Aunt Traudl, I like it
when it thunders.
Yes? Why?
Nothing can happen to us down here, can it?
No.
Direct hit!
Reichsleiter, it's over.
The Fhrer is dead.
There's daddy.
Are you crazy?
For that damned gasoline of yours...
Erich, shut up.
Stand back.
Come on, keep going.
Go on.
No, don't.
Let grandpa go.
Order. Order.
We must have order.
Order must be restored.
This way. We know the way.
You can trust us.
Hurry.
I was on the side of
the Red Beasts.
I supported the Bolsheviks.
Let's hope the Russians
got our message.
We'll soon find out.
Or not.
Nicely done.
Perfect.
Very good.
Comrade General,
the German delegation is here.
Already?
They're out front.
Ask them to wait a moment.
Come on, comrades.
Put these medals on.
My generals are still at the front.
You'll replace my general staff.
Act as if you're a general.
Everything must look official.
Let's go, comrade.
Don't say a word. Keep still.
Enter.
We know each other.
From the Kremlin, before the war.
I was an attach at the German embassy.
What news do you have, General?
This morning, Adolf Hitler and his
wife committed suicide in the bunker.
We're aware.
Surprising.
The new government
has authorized me...
...to open peace talks...
...between our countries, that both
suffered severe losses.
General, if you were me,
would you make peace with you?
That is my mission.
Notify your government of this:
Berlin must surrender unconditionally.
All those who capitulate
must lay down their arms.
Then we can talk.
My government will never accept
unconditional surrender.
Given the situation,
you have no other choice.
Surrender? Never.
That's shameful.
Years ago, I conquered
Berlin from the Reds...
...and I'll defend this city
to my last breath.
In the short time I have
as Chancellor...
...I'll never sign
a surrender treaty.
It's for the sake of the people.
The Fhrer's orders are final.
This is crazy.
We have to start negotiations.
I repeat, gentlemen:
I do not surrender.
Send a message to Marshal Zhukov.
Zhukov?
What's happening?
We're surrendering.
Then I must kill you.
The Fhrer forbids any surrender.
How long does it last?
About four hours.
Children, Doctor Stumpfegger has
the medication I told you about.
It's a bit bitter,
but it helps.
A sip for everybody.
Who wants to go first?
Heide, you're always so brave...
Have another sip.
See? That wasn't so bad.
Well done.
Helmut.
This medicine will make sure you don't
get sick in this damp bunker.
But it's not damp
in the bunker.
Well done.
Helga.
I don't want to.
What's that? Do you want to get sick?
Please, mommy. I don't want to drink it.
Don't cry, baby.
That doesn't help.
You have to drink the medicine.
Helga.
Come on, open your mouth.
Goodnight, children.
One day the lie will collapse...
...and there will be light
in the darkness.
Please read that.
One day the lie will collapse and
there will be light in the darkness.
Let's do it differently.
One day the lie will collapse...
...and truth will triumph once again.
At that moment, we will
stand above everyone...
...pure and...
...immaculate.
On April 30 1945, the Fhrer
committed suicide...
...and in doing so, deserted
everyone who was loyal to him.
You, soldiers of Germany, were loyal to
the Fhrer and were prepared...
...to continue the battle for Berlin,
...despite that ammunition
was in short supply...
...and further resistance
was pointless.
I hereby declare an
immediate cease-fire.
Each hour you continue fighting...
...prolongs the suffering
of the people of Berlin,
...and of our wounded.
In accordance with the supreme
command of the Soviet troops...
...I order you to stop
fighting immediately.
Weidling, former commandant
of the Berlin garrison.
A glass of water, please.
Dad, the Fhrer committed suicide.
We don't stand a chance.
So what? I want to get away.
How will we get through the lines?
It doesn't matter. I'm leaving.
We'll die.
Gerda, it won't be that bad.
If we stay, the Russians
will get us for sure.
All the best.
Come on, let's go.
Johannes, aren't you going?
I have to stay with the generators.
If they break down, the hospital
will have no electricity or fresh air.
Say hello to the Russians.
I will.
I don't need you anymore.
The game's over.
Doctor, the time is upon us.
Don't you see what's going on here?
I insist that you help us,
as a doctor.
Well then...
Go. You've done a lot.
Thank you.
Schdle, come with us.
I'm not going anywhere anymore.
Come on.
Listen up.
Tomorrow the General will hand
the city over to the Russians.
For soldiers, that means
becoming a prisoner of war.
I must give the Fhrer's will to the
new president, Grand Admiral Dnitz.
Those who wish to join me are welcome.
Tomorrow morning we must get through
the Russian lines. Questions?
I will lead the first of ten groups.
The women will come with me.
The other groups will leave
every 20 to 30 minutes. Good luck.
Are you alright?
Come on.
Stop. Turn out the light.
If those are Russians...
Then we'd be dead already. Flashlight.
We thought "Here comes Ivan."
See any Russians over there?
No, and you?
They haven't been here yet.
We've got to keep going.
Sturmmann Krger and his group
defended the Wolf Bridge...
...and he receives the Iron Cross,
second class.
Sturmmann Wagner took out two
machine-gun nests...
...and therefore, receives
the Iron Cross, second class.
Sturmmann Rauch has gotten
messages through the lines...
...and receives the Iron Cross,
second class.
The coast is clear.
Frulein Manziarly, we must go on.
I'm sorry, but I can't.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Get up, Gerda. We must go on.
The others are coming.
Oh my god.
Take cover, Mller.
Why don't you come with us?
No, we're not leaving here.
Good luck.
Halt. Who's there?
A German.
Herr Hewel?
Thank God, you're alive.
Where are the others?
I don't know, Frau Junge.
Somewhere. Maybe.
Most people from my group
must be dead.
I should have never
left that bunker.
I should have shot myself,
but I couldn't.
Eat something first.
There's always time to die.
Where is Adolf Hitler?
Adolf Hitler is dead. He shot himself
and his body was burned.
Where is Hitler's wife?
Dead, as well. Poison.
Where are their clothes?
I'll show you. Not there.
Come.
You stay with the women.
Come along.
I'm tired. I can't go on.
Find a way, Gerda.
We've already come this far.
I can't do it anymore.
Go see where the Russians are.
They've surrounded us.
What's going to happen to us?
Maybe you can get through.
Try. It's better than waiting here.
And you?
What will you and your soldiers do?
For us the trip stops here.
I'm not taking another step.
Think about it.
The Russians are upon us.
As women, you might have a chance.
Try it.
Good luck.
When you walk past the Russians,
don't look them in the eyes.
Remember that. All the best.
Herr Doctor.
My comrades want to surrender.
May I join you?
The Fhrer is dead. Do you want
to continue the war on your own?
I'm bound by my oath.
Then you'd best talk to
the Brigade Fhrer.
Enter here.
The Russians.
Gerda, let's go.
You go. I can't go on.
Please, Gerda.
I have to give it a try.
Don't be angry with me.
I'll be alright.
The Russians are evacuating the square.
So?
There's no opposition.
No shooting.
Then they'll be here within the hour.
What shall we do?
We can't surrender.
Just what does that mean?
When the Russians come,
we'll empty our weapons on them.
The last bullets are for ourselves.
That's rubbish.
Is this prestigious murder and suicide
our only option?
We're SS officers.
We can't outlive the Fhrer.
Who agrees?
Germany will need
young people like you.
You must have a girl
who's waiting for you.
After all this
she won't be waiting.
Do you have a photo?
She's pretty.
What will your family say
if you don't return?
They'll be proud of me.
An enlargement of this one is
hanging above the fireplace in my house.
I don't want to insist, but...
My decision is made.
Tell my bride hello,
if you survive your captivity.
Come and sit down with me?
Gladly.
Why do you want to continue living?
And you? Why do you want to die?
Do you see this?
The Fhrer gave it
to me personally.
A final decoration?
Maybe.
He gave it to me at his farewell.
I had to promise him something.
If the Russians catch me,
I have to kill myself.
Hitler made you promise that?
But why?
Maybe he didn't want me to be
forced to say anything about him.
But you're a diplomat.
You're under international protection.
Who benefits
if you comply with your promise?
There they are.
Don't shoot, comrades.
We surrendered.
The war is over.
It's over.
Unconditional surrender
occurred on May 7, 1945.
Hostilities were suspended
at midnight on May 8.
The war took the lives of
over 50 million people.
6 million Jews were killed
in German concentration camps.
Gerda Christian managed to escape
and avoid imprisonment.
She died in Dsseldorf
on April 14, 1997.
Dr. Schenck was released in 1953
by the Soviets.
He died in Aachen
on December 21, 1998.
Wilhelm Mohnke was released
by the Soviets in 1955.
He died in Damp, near Eckernfrde,
on August 6, 2001.
Helmut Weidling died in
captivity in 1955.
Werner Haase was arrested
in the bunker by the Red Army.
He died in captivity,
in 1945.
Otto Gnsche was arrested
by the Soviets.
He was released in 1956 and
died in Lohmar, in 2003.
Hanna Reitsch survived the war
and would break many flying records.
She died on August 28, 1979.
Robert Ritter von Greim committed
suicide on May 24, 1945.
Linge and Hentschel were
arrested by the Soviets.
Linge was released in 1955 and
died in 1980.
Hentschel was released in 1949 and
died in 1982.
Constanze Manziarly disappeared without
a trace during her flight from Berlin.
Albert Speer was arrested
in Flensburg, in 1945.
At Nuremberg he was
sentenced to 20 years.
He was released in 1966 and
died in London, in 1981.
Keitel and Jodl were sentenced to
death in Nuremberg and executed.
Hermann Gring was
sentenced to death.
He committed suicide in his cell
shortly before his execution.
Heinrich Himmler tried to escape
using a false name.
After he was unmasked,
he committed suicide.
Martin Bormann and Ludwig Stumpfegger
committed suicide on May 2, 1945...
...near the Lehrter Bahnhof.
Rochus Misch was released
by the Soviets in 1955.
He still lives in Berlin.
Traudl Junge was classified
as a "young follower."
She worked as a secretary and lived
in Munich, until her death in 2002.
Of course all the horror I heard
about during the Nuremberg trials...
...the 6 million Jews
and dissidents...
...and people of other races...
...who died, shocked me deeply.
But I still didn't make the
connection with my own past.
I reassured myself by thinking
I wasn't personally guilty of it.
And that I hadn't known
about the sheer size of it.
But one day, I walked
past a commemorative plaque...
...for Sophie Scholl,
here on Franz-Joseph Street.
I saw that she was my age...
...and that she was executed in
the same year I joined Hitler.
And only then did I realize...
that youth is no excuse.
And that it might have been
possible to have found out the truth.