Subtitles Resynced By .::NightRhyme::.
Enjoy
Love Me If You Dare
I like jacks, Monopoly,
but only when I am the banker.
I love marbles. I always win.
Snakes and ladders is dumb.
But less than checkers,
Rubik's cube and puzzle blocks.
Riddles aren't my thing; the
house-jumping is quite good for two persons.
Hide-and-seek is
quite good too.
Yet there's one game you must never play.
And I mean never!
Even if your best buddy wants you to.
And that's burying yourself in a block of cement!
This game started with a pretty house.
A pretty bus with no driver.
A pretty box...
and a pretty girlfriend.
No, in fact, I'm wrong.
It began a little earlier
with a disgusting,
meaningless word, like...
Metastasis!
Sure! Why not "mammoth" while you're at it?
And, it made Mommy cry.
Anyway, doctors suck.
Their words suck.
Their trousers suck.
So what could they know about moms?
And then, there are other nasty words.
Like, "Kowalsky".
Don't ask.
It means nothing either.
Kowalsky...
and also... Polack!
And... Dirty Polack!
Not forgetting.. Polack! Brassneck!
But all that means pretty much the same:
It means:
"l hurt, like nothing on Earth,
Mars, or even Altair lV!"
You like it, eh?
Me too, I find it pretty.
Let me see.
It's a treasure? A real one?
I've never seen such
a pretty merry-go-round, ever!
Never ever.
Maybe on Altair lV, but not on Earth.
I have.
Where? A real merry-go-round? It really exists?
Yes.. my angel, here...
and here.
And here too!
Julien, take the bus today,
I have to stay with your mom.
Off you go, my Ju-Ju...
Let's go.
Go, go, My Juju, go.
Your treasure!
Keep it.
My only treasure is you.
(screams)
(children cheer)
Dirty Polack!
Sophie?
You must be mistaken, I'm Dirty Polack.
Dirty Polack!
Sophie had nothing precious that day either.
So, I had to share.
You'll lend it sometimes?
Give and take back.
You really want it, prove it. Game or not?
That was it!
I think that's how it all really began.
My bus! My bus!
Game!
What did you do? What did you do?
Answer me!
Nothing!
Don't let him hit me!
He won't! Stop!
You've no right!
You shut up!
Answer me!
Don't let him hit me!
He will not. He dare not..
He won't! Game!
You don't have the right to beat him.
Stop! Be quiet!
Thinking back,
Dad never did like Sophie much,
right from the start.
The game just fell into place.
If Sophie had the box,
I'd do her every dare.
I do it to win the box back.
Then I'd get the box back,
and give her a dare.
Foolish game? Perhaps.
But this is our game.
One times seven!
Two times seven!
Three times seven!
21.
Four times seven!
28.
Five times seven!
35.
Six times seven!
42.
Seven times seven!
49.
Please show me some common
nouns that begin with "A".
A.
"An animal!"
"Animals".
Anybody else? Sylvie?
Apricot!
Very good, apricots!
Now, "B"...
Nouns beginning with "B"?
Yes, Sophie?
"B" for...
"Big-dick", "bonk"...
"B" for "beat the beaver", "bordello"...
"balls", "blow-job"...
Enough!
"Bug-eyed baboon", "Bitchbag"..
"Beat it bitchbag!"...
Think you're funny, miss?
What language!
I'm giving you zero,
"Z" for "zero"!
Go to the headmaster's office.
We'll see if the headmaster thinks it's funny.
Julien! What's going on?
To the headmaster's with Sophie!
"Boner".
What? "B" for "boner".
Didn't have time!
Discipline.
Discipline is the basic of respect.
Without respect,
it's the end of civilization.
The decay of the fundaments of the city.
Loutocracy!
And all thanks to who?
Miss Kowalsky and Mr Janvier, eh?
Game.
Say it again, Mr. Janvier.
If it's of interest, pray tell me.
What half-baked idea
crossed your sickly brain
to dare interrupt me?
You surely imagine,
Mr Janvier...
It was a great game,
only no one found it funny.
Separate them!
Separate them, Miss!
Separate us?
They were never game for that!
Mr Janvier... Come join your comrade,
Miss Kowalsky.
Great minds think alike, no?
Know the meaning of the
word punishment?
What future will she have if you don't
inculcate a minimum of education?
Hey, I'm not her mother!
Vulgarity is not on the curriculum
of the Academy,
Miss Kowalsky!
So I must, once again,
summon your parents.
Our parents don't speak French.
For them, "dick" means..
"hammer".
Anything else?
And you won't know what's hit you!
You're deprived of dessert,
outings, TV...
No more sweets,
no more comics,
and no more light in the corridor!
Now, go get your coat.
That's enough!
Cool, you too!
Straight to your room!
Julien, don't wake your mom!
Julien!
Julien...Mother!
We ate this neat thing in the canteen!
You stayed in bed all day?
Lucky you!
I had dictation!
Listen, Julien... A doctor came to see me today.
I made five mistakes.
And guess what?
Juju...
I got 10 in recitation.
Wanna hear it?
And I did something really silly.
Friends are like spectacles.
They make you look clever,
but it gets scratched,
and you tire.
Luckily, sometimes, you hit on far-out specs.
Me... I've got Sophie.
Now..
words beginning with "A".
Aardvark... Good.
Austria... Very good.
Ass...
Altair lV. Continue.
Game or not?
Game!
I'm giving you a zero, you hear?
Zero. Go to the headmaster's office.
Discipline.
Forever discipline.
Don't say I didn't tell you!
This time you're being warned!
You can kiss Eden goodbye!
Now sparks will really fly!
You, my dear,
in pain hall you bring forth children,
wear high heels,
undergo diets,
exfoliation,
face-lifts,
and what's more,
you'll have to cook!
And that's not all!
For you, my boy,
I've reserved the worst,
scourges and torments,
dinosaurs and volcanoes!
Godzilla, the A-bomb, Liz Taylor, Hitler, dead lndians,
noisy washing machines,
oil-slicks,
but above all...
moms, pretty and ill.
...And that way,
lives a March Hare.
Visit either you like,
they're both mad.
But I don't want to go
among the mad, Alice remarked.
Oh you can't help that, said the cat, we're all mad here.
I'm mad, you're mad.
Mother, will you die?
I don't read well?
Are you going to die?
Yes. Like everybody.
Is it because of me?
Because I do silly things?
Here!
Ask me to do something intelligent,
I swear I will.
I'm game.
Be quiet. Not for that.
Block your ears. Hard, harder.
Can you hear how I love you?
Nothing else matters.
Where were we?
Sophie can write with
her teeth, that matters!
It seems neither Alice, nor your mother
interest you as much as Sophie.
So... With her teeth. Easy!
And how about with her ears?
Can you? And flick spiders into the mashed-potato?
And rope-climb, blind-folded?
A glass on your head?
I don't believe you!
Think you're
the first to play dares?
Ok. Good night.
Mom!
What's the craziest thing you ever did?
Flew.
Flew? Flew where?
Across the sky.
Show me, come on!
Fly, fly!
Game!
Later. When?
Soon.
I promise.
The idea of reading him a story!
In your condition!
It's you who should be in bed.
Mom!
Will I be punished seriously or lightly?
It's just that...
Sophie invited me to her sister's wedding.
No!
Shh...
Her dress is awful!
So is her guy!
Anyway, if we wed one day...
You'll say no on the altar, game?
Game! Of course.
What'll you be when you grow up?
A tyrant!
Your people subjugated?
Totally!
With a harem and slaves.
I'll torture them every
Thursday, what about you?
Well, l...No, it's too silly.
Tell me!
You won't like it.
I told you. Tell me!
I'd like to be a flan.
A flan with apricots, or even plain.
Lukewarm, at the baker's.
In the window.
A flan? As in cake?
Of course! What else?
A flan is a flan!
A flan... a flan...
Yeah, of course, a flan!
That's brilliant!
Game or not?
Yes, game...
Not bad.
Not bad?
That's why men earn more than women?
Good workers have good tools.
My turn.
Show me your fanny.
No, that was my dare,
You have no right to copy.
Game or not?
Game!
That's it?
Can't see a thing!
See, women are smarter than men.
It's easier to just be friends.
Pull the cloth.
Game!
Now you. Harder!
Julien, I looked all over for you.
The violin teacher is ill...
We will discuss it later. Please come.
Mom!
My Julien...
My brave boy.
You'll get better!
You'll get better?
Game or not?
You don't have the box, darling.
It's not your turn to dare.
I'll go get it!
Stay, Julien.
Kiss your mother.
I'll go later, then you'll
show me how you fly.
What're you doing here?
Julien...
Please leave. Father doesn't like it.
Sure, I am only a partner to play with.
Hop for the next hour!
Game or not?
I do two and Mom gets better.
I do three, and she
comes home for my birthday.
Good!
I do four, and she will come
back home tonight healthily.
Mom!
Hello,
I'm Julien's dad.
Are you Sophie's mom?
I'm her sister.
I'd like to... Could...
It is or not?
Can Sophie sleep over... tonight?
You asleep?
Officially, yes.
It's rumored that you are pretending.
Yes, so I read in Paris Match.
Pure gossip.
Now, goodnight.
Tomorrow, can I sleep over at your place?
Can l?
No, never!
You must never come to my place, promise!
Why not? It'd be...
Promise!
Okay, then.
Good night.
That's how you get bad habits.
I don't mean breaking cups.
That's kinda fun!
I meant sleeping.
Sophie and me, from that night on,
have slept together for ten years.
On the morning,
something serious happened.
Right! On the morning,
Shit and damn!
What's the time?
My exam!
What exam?
Math.
You need not to take the examination. You'll fail.
I told you, I hate that!
Hey, watch it!
You're sick!
The feathers...
Julien!
What's all that noise?
Open up!
Shit and double damn...
Julien!
Open, or I'll come in!
Give me that.
Game or not?
No, not this morning.
I've butterflies in the tummy as it is.
What if this morning,
Sophie were to wear the bra?
Game starts again.
Miss Kowalsky.
Kowalsky,
Sophie Kowalsky.
The rules of the game hadn't changed.
What was called teasing as kids
might now be called perversion.
Pervasion?
It's a matter of taste, like Chinese food.
You like it, or don't.
Only if you're Chinese, you've no choice.
I'm Julien.
And I'm "Take a Hike"!
Life for me was like
playing Beethoven's 5th
with fingernails on a blackboard.
Miss Kowalsky.
Vectorial functions?
So, V1 by V2 is equal to
the product of their modules
multiplied by the cosine of
the angle of their two bodies.
You seem good at
vectorial functions.
Tell me if I'm wrong
Miss Kowalsky.
Tell me whether I was wrong.
Your vector is defined by an origin,
but above all by size in vectorial space.
Some vectorial spaces are hotter than others.
Care to develop
your theory with me?
It could be exponential.
You usually revise alone?
This makes me deaf.
The answer to intrinsic function
The solution of sub-function delta
Kowalsky
Minus 3m squared,
Minus 2m, plus 1.
Miss Kavasky...
I didn't authorize you to leave!
Fx has two distinct roots
If m is between -1 and 1/3
Gotta go, that's my sister.
You jerk.
Louder, I'm deaf.
It worked, didn't it? I did it!
Don't keep such a straight face.
What else can you do except seduce women?
Don't you see?
The examiner had the wrong name.
She thought you are Kawasaky
I fiddled the roll.
No result, you get no mark!
For her you're Kawasaky.
But it was fun, no?
A 20-minute firing squad, all eyes on my bra!
But what do you care! Your sugar-lumps.
Don't even know the chick!
I was just passing time.
And she knows nothing about math.
Aurelie Miller, a total bimbo!
Her twin claim to fame:
she laid lgor, the gym coach
and she's got really wild earrings.
Now you know all.
Jealous?
Me?
Yeah, you!
Lay all the sluts you like!
I just wanna pass, despite this!
Hey! You are jealous. Forgive me!
Just drop it!
As for Aurelie Miller, you have my blessing.
Hear she fucks great. Not much she hasn't.
You two seems like a pair to death.
Stop, Sophie.
I mean, why deprive yourself?
Just bring me back her earrings.
Game?
Miss Miller! Aurelie Miller?
Got a boyfriend?  Yes.
Now, you have two.
And you? Is that really your sister?
It's she who asked me to come.
Well, beat it!
Or I'll scream the place down.
Hey!
Yes, what is it?
Cute place you got.
I've shitty taste,
that's why I like you.
Miller Aurelie
Still no sign?
When will we meet again?
The third semester, maybe.
Aurelie, I beg you.
Give me your earrings.
They reflect your golden hair,
yet pale before your breasts.
Abandon your numbed
slave to their contemplation.
You're weird!
Really crazy.
Now be nice, let me go.
We've revised our functions, Iet's not get linear.
That's not like us.
Believe in love at first sight?
Yeah...
Naive!
Aurelie Miller, you failed the exam.
That's docked from my pay!
How was it?
I don't like blondes.
You did it! You bastard!
Tyrant.
That's enough!
Now she has nothing.
Except lgor, the gym coach,
with biceps bigger than his brain.
I already fucked him.
So how big is his biceps?
As big as your lQ.
You're into that?
As second choice, yeah!
What do you mean, second choice?
Who's first choice?
Your turn.
Your turn, quick!
Beat it, twerp!
Easy, lgor.
Heard of crazy wagers?
Blaise Pascal?
Seems not.
You're nuts!
Let's talk something else.
Kick his ass.
Say you regret it!
Come on, it was fun!
Say it!
It's not part of the game.
You should not have went.
Look, I'm in this state because I'm game for anything!
Now apologize!
You will get nothing from me.
Jerk, give me the box.
Kiss me.
Game?
Game!
I said, kiss me.
Are you off your rockers?
Get off my car, and I'll tell you.
Do you hear me? Get off and I tell you.
They're totally mad!
Get down! You hear?
Bloody idiots!
Hold me.
Love me.
Game!
For you this is a game?
No, a wager.
You threw it out.
Well if I did,
you didn't catch it.
Poor jerk,
you'll miss your bus.
It was time to grow up.
As a kid you think it happens gently.
But it whips you,
Iike a branch on the rebound,
or when your father says:
It's over, Julien!
Playtime's over.
You've an exam in two months. Remember? An exam!
So don't mess up,
or you'll mess with me.
Hey, Dad!
It's no big deal. Be Zen!
Zen!
You little lout!
You think I'm not Zen enough?
I'll tell you that
Your games killed the woman I loved
who you may recall was your mother!
You are so contemptible!
I didn't kill Mom.
I'm a contemptible person,
not a gentleman.
I'm so contemptible that
I brought you up alone! Shit!
You bastard, l didn't kill her!
Yes, I'm a bastard.
I can tear your face.
I can't believe that
Sophie poisoned you
To the point
that we never talk
Unless your girlfriend
has a wager on me.
You choose.
It's her or me, so...
Game...
Or not?
Sophie!
Hi, Julien. Looking for Sophie?
She's not in.
What are you doing here?
I told you never to come here.
You satisfied? Now that you've seen it?
You promised, we wagered.
Who cares? Listen...
I care!
I'm packing it in.
Sorry, I didn't know.
"Sorry",
that changes everything.
Come on, let's go.
Go where?
Stuff your pity.
You go by yourself.
Sophie, forgive me!
Beat it!
Game or not?
To forgive me,
One of the toughest dares I'd ever given Sophie.
But she never liked things easy.
This took her a long
time, maybe it's too long.
Meanwhile my dad's
bluntness had gotten to me.
Hello...
Is Julien in?
Please, Mr Janvier...
I've come to see Julien.
Is he there?
Julien? Can you hear me?
Not a word,
it's for me to speak.
You missed me?
Because I miss you, you tyrant.
You're a real tyrant.
It's so hard to be mad at you.
But don't kid yourself,
I still am.
I wanted to talk, forgetting the game,
just for once.
Like my dress?
I hesitated.
Nabbed it off my sister.
She has another red one,
like a thermonuclear warhead...
That's the one I should've worn.
I must've spent, I dunno,
3 hours before the mirror.
But I got there, see?
I'm pretty.
So, like it or I'll kill you!
No, wait...
Where was l?
The problem is, that...
even if you said
"l love it" I'd not believe you.
Julien, I no longer know
when you're playing...
And when you are not.
I'm lost.
Wait, I'm not finished.
Tell me you love me.
Tell me, because if I tell you first
I'm afraid you'll think it's a game.
Help me, please.
Thank you.
Hi.
Julien
Come to revise?
You got it!
It seems you are not.
Not now, please
When, then? Tomorrow?
One year later. I'm sorry.
Spare me your "sorrys"!
Urbanism! Do you really like this?
Just remember, Iow-cost housing,
that's my expertise.
We never did
speak about the future.
Us two.
I mean, both our futures.
"Both our futures"?
Funny,
I'd have said "our future".
But then I only live for now.
I guess...
I saw us going on
like this years.
You are an idiot.
OK, pass the exam.
Game or not?
I'm sorry.
"I'm sorry, Sophie".
Sure.
In fact,
we did talk about the future
once...
and weren't too far wrong:
You're becoming a tyrant,
and me a flan.
Stay. No, I don't want to delay you.
Stop your nonsense.
Go study, it's no problem. I've exams to pass too.
I'm studying men.
So you're taking sociology!
Not humans...
but men.
Males, guys.
I've a lot of catching up to do.
Well, this is a library
There is no better place to learn, is there?
Game?
Game!
Stop, you are doing something stupid.
Quit it!
Why? It was just a dare.
It's just a bet. Come
on, let me work over it.
I'll go study.
See you in a year.
What happened?
Hmm
You know what I am saying clearly.
No, I don't. Say it!
It is not easy to say that.
Can't it wait a year?
Here! Study with care.
Be careful.
You want to hurt me?
Don't be a fool, you never could.
You'll wait for me?
Is that a dare?
No.
Then, you'll see.
Sophie! Sophie, I love you!
I love you, I love you, come down.
What an idiot!
Look at the fool sitting on the chair.
wheezing as
an excuse or grimacing!
Excuses!
Wouldn't it be easier
to go take her in your arms,
whispering words of love every day?
While at the very sight
of her, your heart misses a beat.
Hey, I'm talking to you!
You hear me?
Of course you do.
That's just it.
What a total idiot!
And his troubles have only begun.
Yes?
Got an evening dress?
Not even an evening.
They're on me.
I've something
important to ask you.
What do you like to drink?
A coffee and...
And that's it.
Can we talk?
No.
Sorry, but we never
hit it off in certain things.
Stupid things... For
example, your shoes.
My shoes? Yes, it is funny.
Yeah... You look a right prat
in your Doc's and pressed pants.
It's such an eyeful,
I can't even listen.
Here, it's on the house.
I can't just take them off.
Up to you.
You wanted to talk.
On Mondays I finish at 7.
Come by later.
Okay. No.
In fact,
I've got my singing lesson.
You sing?
Yes, this is not my
life, it is only a job.
I guess it doesn't
fit our saving hero image,
but these past years,
I have lived!
I'd no idea.
Glad to hear that
you're taking lessons.
Want to be a singer?
That's you all over, profitability!
Lessons equals singing career!
Like giving 100 pounds to the
starving means you're Mother Theresa!
Damn it, I said I wouldn't talk to you.
Your shoes, your pants, they put me off.
Now let me work.
Hi.
Hello.
Okay?
Fine, and you?
Very well.
So, can I ask you to dinner now?
No.
Where are you going?
Ask less, get more answers.
You said you finish
at 7 on Mondays!
Today is Tuesday.
Wait for me.
I want to invite you for dinner.
Go away! You too?
Never seen such a jam!
A truck doing a U-turn...
Got someone?
What?
Have you got a lover?
Why did you ask me so?
No reason.
Just head-on dialectic
on the state of the heart.
Head-on dialectic!
Don't we say "conversation"?
So, you're in love?
You don't have to answer,
it is only a question.
I don't have someone else in my bed,
if you're wondering.
No one I can't change with the sheets.
He's a footballer, Sergei Nimov-Nemovich.
Or was,
ditched him this morning.
How could you
date a name like that?
I was sick of naming dates.
And since this morning?
Apart from Sergei?
Greg, his buddy, Jerome, his father,
A French, two and three Kevin's
Cinderella's prince,
the robots from Star Wars,
nothing too serious,
a heart up for grabs!
Chic restaurant, champagne!
You do things well,
I swear you were coming on to me.
Seems so unlikely?
Have you seen the girl downstairs?
She's wearing
the same dress I did last time.
How long ago was that?
Four years?
I saw.
Doesn't suit her.
A real blob!
Did I look that dumb in it?
Don't say that, you don't know her.
You didn't either.
Does it matter?
What brings you?
Got your diploma?
No, my diploma was
pure chronology...
Cheers.
Cheers for this moment, and
the things I have done for you.
I have waited for
years to tell you this.
Tell me what?
To tell you about myself.
But you have been talking about youself.
Then, let's say...
about my heart.
Sophie, I'm in love.
In love? Just like that?
No, not like this.
It's been years.
Years of silence.
I want to get married.
Do you agree?
You are asking me ?
Remember at my sister's wedding
when I asked you to say "no",
you said "game".
What do you say today?
You... you really want to marry?
For that, I need you.
Sure, can't marry by yourself.
I'm entrusting
them to you until the ceremony.
Listen...
Do you agree?
You agree?
You agreed.
She agrees! She agrees.
You will be my chief
witness at the wedding ceremony
Thank you, Sophie.
I will now introduce you.
My fiancee, Christelle.
She is beautiful, isn't she?
No.
That same dress, I bought it for her.
Remember?
You said I could never hurt you.
I can!
Gift.
It's yours. Now we're quits.
Introduce us.
Christelle, Sophie...
My future
My past
Rise, my children.
You will now exchange your vows.
Christelle
My child
Christelle Louise Bouchard
You wish to exchange vows
in the house of the Lord...
Christelle
Will you take as husband
Julien Antoine Janvier
to love and to cherish,
till death you do part?
I will
Yes, I will
And you
My son
Julien Antoine Janvier,
will you take as wife
Christelle Louise Bouchard
to love and to cherish,
till death you do part?
Julien!
Wake up, my boy,
your fiancee is waiting.
Will you..
take..
Christelle Louise Bouchard as...
Yes, I will
Good, so my children
if any know of a reason...
I do! I oppose this marriage.
on this marriage
Julien is already engaged to me.
Get her out of here!
Julien!
When will
she leave us in peace!
Julien, tell them!
Game or not?
Julien!
You've got a real problem.
Your mother died and left you in Oedipus.
You never fucked mom,
never killed dad.
And now at 25
you're begging instead of living.
No, dad.
Stop, Dad, stop!
Yes, I'll stop!
The whole damn lot!
Look at me,
Julien. And look well.
It's the last time you'll see me.
You pissed me about
once too often, now it's over.
Over! The game,
the humiliation.
From now on,
you don't exist!
You're out of my life.
Don't mind her,
it's a childish game.
Don't do this, it's a game!
Let go of me
What a bitch!
A first rate soul mate.
Isn't she just superb?
Ever ready to get splattered by a train.
It was just a joke!
A kids' dare!
Julien!
I mean, what's a wedding?
But fancy suits and champagne.
Just freeze the petit-fours
and foil-wrap the foie gras.
I already did. You can eat it next week.
Julien!
You love each other,
that's what matters.
Julien,do you hear me?
I can be a real chief
witness at your wedding.
I'll behave, I swear.
I won't spit, honest.
What's this?
Julien!
Julien, can I move?
Julien, don't joke.
Go to hell.
Okay. But you come with me.
We don't meet for ten years.
Game.
Hey!
Sophie...
Not a word, Sergei.
Game...
What?
Nothing.
So, how's that
First Division offer shaping up?
I don't know,
I've not called them.
Okay, then we'd better stop
seeing each other again.
Ditch me every week,
and I give a discount.
I'm sick of living cheap.
I won't spend my life
with a foot-dragger.
Think you'll keep me with
your crap apartment and two-bit wages?
I'll make money.
No, you don't get it.
I want the jackpot, the bonanza!
The Friday, the 13th super sweepstake!
I'm at least worth that?
You sure are.
Game,
set and match, Sophie.
Nothing could've been worse.
Nothing... Nothing for 10 years.
Nothing for
3652 days and 3653 nights.
The match was over,
the games, the spice of my life.
I wandered through life
just like in a Racine tragedy.
Hermione, for guys:
Where am I? What have I
done? What should I do?
What kind of passion has catched me?
What woe devours?
"May I not know if I do love or hate?"
Sophie me did bait,
flay me and slay me,
fuck me, chuck me,
and other silly rhymes...
And I ended up thinking
in the past,
resigning myself
to a bland existence...
Bring me the happiness that I've never
experienced since I was born.
Love, family, work...
the satellite dish.
Racine, I said.
Pure Racine!
Julien! The bin!
Julien! The garbage!
Julien! A kiss!
Julien... Children!
There you go.
What's the present for?
Shhh.
Don't say anything.
It's for
Mommy's wedding anniversary.
Can you keep a secret?
A dinosaur secret.
The secrets of espionage?
A spy secret. Or how about... Ectoplasm!
Right! An ectoplasm secret!
Here. Hide that for Mom
we'll surprise her tonight.
Mommy...
Don't look at what we're hiding for you.
I won't, I promise.
Meet my life at 35.
I had everything!
1 wife, 2 kids, 3 buddies,
4 loans, 5 weeks' vacation,
In the same box.
6 years, same company,
7 times my weight in hi-fi,
8 coitions per quarter,
9 times the earth in plastic, polystyrene,
and other non-biodegradables...
Using the packing which can't be untied.
10 years...
of not seeing my father.
Bliss!
The tyrant outfit
I'd dreamt of as a kid...
and now adult.
Having a speedo up to 210
and never doing more than 60.
Hello!
About 40 such
botch-ups with my dad.
96 fibs to my boss.
Yes, yes, Dorzac, here I come.
I'm on my way.
Be there in 10 years, I mean, 10 minutes!
Start without me.
Monday morning traffic...
Now 97. See you later.
Hi, Sophie? Game!
123 nightmares in which
I was a tyrant at last.
Yeah, I'm listening...
Yes, I will be right there.. okay.
The city had changed.
So has death.
489 hours in the cemetery
hoping she'd return to
sing me "La vie en rose".
Should have believed that I don't need her.
We can say...
That Mom flew thanks to the game...
I was way off the mark.
Sorry about this. Got the plans?
Gimme two seconds.
The clients are here!
Hello, sorry I'm late.
Let me show you the plans.
It's a 10-year study...
6 months. Just divide by 20!
What did I say? 10 years!
Sorry! It's a 10-month study,
I mean 6 months...
Hadn't heard from Sophie for 10 years.
The wager ended today
with metronomic urgency,
and no news, no sign of her.
Seems she'd forgotten me.
Not l.
Her.
How can I forget her?
When I see her husband all over.
He'd become a national hero.
"Sexy Sergei" of the women's press,
top goal-scorer of the year.
How I hated football.
I'm on my way.
Take a right, please.
Hi, it's Sergei.
I'm running late.
Sorry, but that's my private life.
Well?
Well...
I really can't say...
Is that the final cut?
I don't know... I...
Do you like it?
Yes.
As for Sophie's life,
I could just picture it:
It isn't like this...
It sucked.
Right, it sucks.
Yeah, the snippet sucks.
Sophie, we're working here.
I can't bear it...
It was hell dealing that contract.
Do you know who directed this snippet?
Steph and Daniel.
But even if it was Daffy Duck, Gandhi and the Pope,
it'd still suck.
This is not a game, Sophie.
Sergei! Yes?
I have the right to refuse,
haven't I? Haven't I?
Yes, you have.
Then, how can I decide?
You decide this snippet sucks.
Wait, something's digging into my back.
What's your teddy doing here?
Teddies aren't
usually made of tin.
Tell me Mr Sergei Nimov-Nemovich,
have you said hello to your wife recently?
Not since yesterday,
and have you Mrs Nimov-Nemovich,
Said you love your husband?
No, not for a 100 years.
Nor have l
ever said ornithorhynchus.
And I think it's high time I did:
Ornithorhynchus.
No doubt about it,
she'd forgotten me.
You have to go out tonight?
I hate football!
Dad, can you do this?
And this?
And this? And this?
Can you make a girl
cry on her wedding day?
Can you smile in the
unfortunate moment?
Keep silent for 10 years?
Just been on the phone with Margaret
about her insurance story.
I mean, I only did it as a favor.
Just because I head the agency
doesn't mean I'm the Salvation Army.
Are you even listening?
Yes? No more than
in the past ten years, no.
So, it's no.
Life after work does exist.
Got problems with Dorzac?
Look at me!
You should've married Dorzac.
Look what he brought you,
by courier.
The samples?
Why here and not the office?
I'd held my breath 10 years.
I felt like a dog
who'd pissed on the rug,
awaiting a thrashing.
And one Monday evening,
the blow fell.
How is it going?
Let me give you a hug.
Come meet Julien...
So great to see you!
And on our 10th anniversary!
Are the children here?
Yes, everyone is here.
Look who's here!
Sophie!
Hello, Julien.
Hello, Clo, I am delighted...
Be right back.
( Game or not? )
Can't you send an email from home?
Clo is here, why won't you stay?
Julien I want you to stay!
Sophie?
You okay?
Police?
Mrs Nimov-Nemovich here.
Come quick,
the maniac is back!
I already timed them before.
Takes a minute.
Not that!
It was my grandmother's!
Please!
10 years is long.
That way!
Good old Sophie!
We were back in the game!
Pure, raw,
explosive pleasure!
Better than drugs,
better than smack!
Better than a
dope-coke-crack-fix shit-shoot-sniff!
A ganja-marijuana-blotter
acid-ecstasy!
Better than sex, head,
sixty-nine, orgies, masturbation...
Better than banana
milk-shakes!
Better than the George Lucas box-set,
the Muppets and 2001!
Better than Emma Peel, Marilyn Monroe,
and Cindy Crawford's beauty spot!
Better than B-side of Abbey Road!
Better than Jimmy
Hendrix, the first man on the moon!
Better than the
Space-mountain, Santa Claus,
Bill Gates' fortune, the Dalai Lama,
Lazarus raised from the dead!
Schwarzenegger's testerone
shots, Pam Anderson's lips!
Woodstock, rave parties,
Sade, Rimbaud, Morrison and Castaneda!
Better than freedom,
better than life!
Hello? Yes?
It's Hospital Saint-Antoine.
May I speak to Mrs Janvier?
It's her speaking.
Your husband had a car crash.
Listen, I told you!
He's my oldest friend, we go way back.
Oldest friend?
And you never introduced me?
Have you introduced your team
to me? You see them everyday.
You mean,
you see this guy every day?
Sophie, who is this?
If it's who I think,
I'll kill him!
Too late for that.
You'll be alright,
Mrs Janvier?
To be honest,
I was real mad at Sophie for that one.
I swore that once up and
about I'd knock her for six!
And over time, you forgive.
Laugh about it, even.
After all, it's only a game.
Go!
Sophie!
Where have you been, Julien?
We were all looking for you.
I went to the toilet.
You okay?
I'm fine.
A night in casualty,
for our 10th anniversary!
Is this your idea of "pleasantly surprised"?
Does that hurt?
No, that's nothing.
Sorry for earlier on,
I don't know why l...
I don't know what's wrong with me.
Everything'll be fine.
I'm here.
I don't care about the break-in.
I just feel sorry for you.
Damn!
Prepare some Atarax for me.
Don't worry,
these things happen.
The after-shock.
What have I done?
Sophie!
Julien?
Sophie, forgive me.
Julien!
What an idiot!
Take me back to the hospital.
Sophie!
Take your umbrella!
You'll be soaked.
Game!
Julien! Look at me.
Say it!
Hold me close and
hold me near
the magic spell you cast
this is la vie en rose...
When you speak, everyday words seem...
...to turn into love...
Sophie, come back.
Shut up!
It's important to me.
Problem was,
I couldn't quite remember the words.
But my heart was in it.
All that could stop me
was a fist in the face!
You're sick!
Really sick!
Julien?
Please wake up.
Don't leave me alone.
Wake up, wake up!
I beg you!
Come back!
Please! I beg you!
Don't leave me alone.
No, that's too easy.
You don't deserve it.
Come.
Come and get it.
Julien!
Do you hear me? I know you do.
Come and get it.
Don't leave me.
Game or not?
The last game.
We'll never leave each other.
Never.
To win this game,
you need a pretty box
And a pretty girlfriend.
The rest doesn't matter.
There were a few things I was game for
even if you never asked.
For example?
Eating ants.
Insulting the unemployed...
Loving you like crazy.
And that's how we won...
Together... happy for
a long time, a very long time.
And deep in concrete.
We shared one last dream, a childhood dream,
the dream of an endless love.
"B"
"Bollocks" or "Bonk"...
but they're not worth much.
How's it spelt?
Never wrote it.
Anything else?
"Boner" won't work?
Does yours?
I'm sure you have demands.
And your children,
have you thought of them?
What'll they say when...
An orange one for you...
and one for me.
Like blue ones?
Because there's only one blue colored.
I'll give you the blue,
as you're cute.
and me the purple.
Okay?
I love you.
Sophie, is my best buddy.
End.