l am a stone.
l do not move.
Very slowly, l put snow in my mouth.
Then he won't see my breath.
l take my time.
l let him come closer.
l have only one bullet.
l aim at his eye very gently.
My finger presses on the trigger.
l do not tremble.
l have no fear.
l'm a big boy now.
Ready Vassili?
Now Vassili. Fire!
Fire, Vassili!
All civilians, get off!
Make way, let the civilians off.
This is a military convoy.
No one stays onboard,
but our valiant soldiers.
Convoy to Stalingrad.
Only for the soldiers of the Red Army.
Autumn, 1 942.
Europe lies crushed
beneath the Nazi jackboot.
The German Third Reich
is at the height of its power.
Hitler's armies are charging
through the heart of the Soviet Union
towards the oil fields of Asia.
One last obstacle remains.
A city on the Volga where the fate
of the world is being decided.
Stalingrad.
The Army and all citizens
of the Soviet Union
must defend every inch of Soviet soil.
Glorious comrades, Stalin has ordered
not another step backwards.
Let us go forwards, comrades.
Not a step backwards.
Listen to these letters sent by Russian
mothers to their sons on the front.
Volodya, our child,
l know that it is for our motherland...
...it is for our motherland
that you are giving your life.
Everyone here knows
that you will not fall back.
Everyone here is proud of you.
Your father is dead. Your brothers
are dead. Avenge us on the fascists.
Get in the boat!
Get back or l'll shoot.
Get back from the rails.
Over here, stretcher.
The one with the rifle shoots.
The one without follows him.
When the one with the rifle gets killed,
the one who is following
picks up the rifle and shoots.
The one with the rifle shoots.
The one without follows him.
When the one with the rifle gets killed,
the one who is following
picks up the rifle and shoots.
Soldiers of the glorious Red Army,
from now on it is either victory or death.
- Those who retreat...will be shot.
- l need a rifle.
There will be no
mercy for cowards and traitors.
lt's hopeless, comrades. Get back.
Fall back! Fall back!
lt's no good.
Get back. Get back.
ln the name of the Soviet Union,
not a step backwards, or we shoot.
- No retreat. Not a step back.
- No mercy.
- Deserters will be shot.
- Fire!
No mercy for cowards.
Russians, surrender.
You will see your home again.
This is not your war.
Join your German comrades.
They understand your suffering and will
care more for you than your own officers,
who are only sending you to your death.
The Third Reich is not your enemy.
The enemy is bloodthirsty Stalin
and his Bolshevik gang.
Fire!
Get his coat, comrade Commissar.
With your permission,
comrade Commissar.
- Which one should l aim at first?
- You should wait...till there's an explosion.
- Do you know how to shoot?
- A little.
Don't shoot.
He's looking at us.
Thank you, comrade Commissar.
Danilov. Political officer,
2nd class, 21st lnfantry.
On this day, September 20th 1 942,
a young shepherd boy from the Urals...
...arrived in the city of Stalingrad
on the banks of the Volga.
His name is Vassili Zaitsev.
Like thousands before him
he came to answer comrade Stalin's call.
Armed only with a rifle,
he quickly made the fascist invader realise
that from now on he would be punished
for every step he took in the motherland,
that from here on the only way was back.
What do you think?
l think Comrade Commissar
is being over generous.
By order of comrade Stalin,
no civilian can leave the city.
Get back there!
Stand away, or we will open fire.
Make way for comrade Stalin's envoy.
l carried out my orders.
l sent in all of my boys.
But the Germans engulfed us.
They have artillery, aircraft, tanks.
- And we, what did l have ?
- The sacred duty to resist.
l have to report to the boss.
Perhaps you would prefer
to avoid the red tape.
My name is Nikita Sergeievich Kruschev.
l've come to take things in hand here.
This city is not Kursk.
Nor is it Kiev, nor Minsk.
This city is Stalingrad.
Stalingrad!
This city bears the name of the boss.
lt's more than a city, it's a symbol.
lf the Germans capture this city,
the entire country will collapse.
l want our boys to raise their heads.
l want them to act like they have balls.
l want them to stop shitting their pants.
That's your job
As political officers, l'm counting on you.
You, what's your suggestion?
Shoot all the other generals who have
retreated and their chiefs of staff too.
Make some examples.
Deport the families of the deserters...
Give them hope.
Here, the men's only choices
are between German bullets and ours.
But there's another way.
A way of courage.
A way of love of the motherland.
We must publish the army newspaper
again and tell magnificent stories,
stories that exalt sacrifice, bravery.
We must make them believe in a victory
We must give them hope,
pride, a desire to fight.
We need to make examples,
but examples to follow.
What we need are heroes.
Do you know any heroes around here?
Yes, comrade.
l know one.
That's me. Vassili Zaitsev.
No. You're not dreaming.
lt's your name.
We made the front page.
They haven't changed a word.
Do you have any idea what this means?
lt's not the back page,
not the second page. lt's the front page.
They're going to reprint
our article everywhere,
in the Caucasus,
in the Crimea, even in the Urals.
Tomorrow morning,
Stalin himself will be sitting at breakfast
reading my words
memorising your name.
We're famous Vassili.
Kruschev loved the article.
He's promoted me to the general staff.
And you, to Sniper Division.
- Well, that's good.
- lt's very good.
- lt's very good. lt's great!
- lt's great!
lt's great for both of us
because we did it together.
Admittedly, l did all the hard work.
- You're very lucky l can't fight back.
- Why's that?
Kruschev told me to make sure nothing
happens to you. You're too important.
- l'm too valuable.
- Yes. Careful of my glasses, they're new.
Sorry, sir.
l'm famous. We're famous.
Vassili, the young shepherd from the
Urals, killed his 1 2th German officer today.
Today Vassili Zaitsev shot his 23rd...
One more colonel shot by...
He is an example to us all.
Today Vassili Zaitsev
killed his 32nd general.
More and more men and women from
the small branches of our armed forces
volunteer to join the Sniper Division
and learn the skills of Vassili Zaitsev.
l am a stone.
l breathe slowly.
l aim at the eye.
So it is you.
The great Vassili Zaitsev.
My mother makes the best potatoes
and bacon in town.
Sounds good.
When she sees you,
she won't believe her eyes.
- How many today?
- Only two.
And the last one,
why didn't you shoot him?
He was only a foot soldier.
lt wasn't worth giving away my position.
Bless you.
We know how much we owe you.
We pray for you everyday.
Every evening we listen to them
talk about you on Radio Moscow.
You've certainly managed well down here.
My parents used to store furniture
down here before the war.
Sacha, drop that right now.
lt's loaded.
- This way comrade Commissar.
- Thank you, comrade.
Good evening.
Comrade Zaitsev.
My God, where does
all this mail come from?
From all over the country,
Mrs Filipov, from all over.
This one's from the workers of the Kuzbas.
They want to name their mine after Vassili.
Right lets' start with the miners.
Come on, let's get to work.
Dear comrades from the Kuzbas,
l thank you for your letter of praise.
R-A-l-S-E.
l hope that l can live up
to your expectations.
A-T-l-O-N-S.
Expectations.
You're interested in German literature,
Mrs Filipov?
lt's all right.
lt's our neighbour.
Tania, we have guests.
l recognise you.
lt's Vassili Zaitsev.
l saw your picture in the paper.
Thank you for everything you're doing.
- And this is his friend, Commissar...?
- Danilov.
Tania's like a daughter to me.
She used to take care of Sacha
when l worked at the factory.
She even taught him German.
These books are hers.
- They're yours?
- She studied German at the university.
- Which university?
- Moscow.
- Shouldn't we...
- Yes, let's continue.
Your offer to name your mine after me is...
a great honour.
- H-O-N.
- Yes, l know, honour.
Shouldn't we try and make the point
that l'm not the only one fighting?
That's an excellent idea.
We can take it even further though.
Your battle for the production of coal
is...as worthy as mine.
There's no 'K' in coal.
Just one 'L'.
Tell me if l'm going too fast.
No, you're not going too fast.
ls there any other improvements.
Why don't you get some rest?
These letters can wait until tomorrow.
We should carry on.
We're not tired. Thank you, Mrs Filipov.
These people took the trouble
to write to us.
Tomorrow we may not be around
to write back.
l was expecting someone...else.
Certainly not someone so prestigious.
l imagine you have your reasons
for getting involved in this hellish situation.
My army is not designed
for this kind of fighting.
Yesterday, yet again,
l had to promote 25 sergeants
to replace the officers shot down
by their sharpshooters.
Those snipers are demoralising
my people.
This city...is no more
than a heap of ruins.
But the Fhrer's persisting.
He has made it a personal matter
between Stalin and himself.
We should trust the Fhrer's instinct.
He always managed to lead us to victory.
We shall be back home for Christmas.
How are you going to go about
finding this young Russian?
l'll fix it so that he's the one who finds me.
Vassili! Come on!
Time to get up.
They have a problem
in the department store. They need us.
Look, Vassili, he's hiding
in the department store, over there.
So far this morning, he's knocked off
five officers plus two machine gunners.
Look! Third floor.
Fourth window from the left.
Fourth window...from the left.
- See him?
- Yeah, l see him.
- You got him!
- Great shot.
Let's go get his dogtag.
Goodbye, comrade Commissar.
Thank you for your hospitality, Mrs Filipov.
- You can borrow whatever you like.
- What would they say at headquarters
if l came back with an armful
Goethe and Schiller?
There's some Marx too.
You were assigned to civil defence
at the 1 2th district?
No, l volunteered.
lt's such a coincidence
meeting you like this.
Comrade Kruschev was telling me
just yesterday
how desperately we're in need
of operators who speak German.
l can't. Our militia in this neighbourhood
is already short of men.
We'll give you a dozen soldiers
for everyone that speaks German.
l'd rather stay and fight.
Serving headquarters is fighting.
You'd be more useful there.
You stay here.
You cover us. We go.
Take care.
Ludmilla, come on.
Take the stairway.
- lt's a trap.
- l know.
Move back.
He's still here.
- They're coming straight for us.
- Ludmilla, stay where you are.
He's over there somewhere.
We've got to get out of here.
- We have to get out of here.
- Just stay where you are.
What are we gonna do?
Ludmilla, stay where you are.
Fuck this, l'm going.
Ludmilla, no!
What does this mean?
A shepherd from the Urals
receives a sniper's rifle.
A 7.62 3.5 power telescope,
pride of precision of Soviet production.
- l've seen that rifle close up.
- Have you?
l even touched it.
l know him well, Vassili Zaitsev.
Ludmilla and Anton were killed today.
And it was my fault.
l'm sure that's not true.
lt was a German sniper.
l walked them right into his trap.
- What else can you tell me?
- He didn't relocate.
A sniper who doesn't relocate isn't normal.
He was very good.
lt wasn't just his shooting,
it was his instinct.
He was a step ahead of me.
That's because
he knows everything about you.
His name is Konig.
Major Konig.
They've sent him here to kill you.
To find you.
We weren't sure
if the information was reliable.
He's come all the way
from Berlin to stop you.
You've caused him so many sleepless
nights, they've sent their top marksman.
- What do we know about him?
- He's a major in the Wehrmacht.
He's director of their sniper school
in Zossen.
Koulikov studied at Zossen
before the war.
He know all his tricks.
From now on he'll go with you everywhere.
A nobleman from Bavaria who hunts deer
against the shepherd boy from the Urals
who poaches wolves.
lt's more than a confrontation
between two nations.
lt's the essence of class struggle.
l'm glad you're so happy.
He had all the advantages.
Next time you'll be even.
No one shoots like you, Vassili.
She's been transferred.
l'll see if they're ready for you next door.
You look very smart in your new uniform.
Make sure they don't take it back
once you've finished.
They probably will.
l've heard the rumour about the German.
- l wanted to wish you luck.
- Thank you. l'll need it.
From what comrade Danilov tells me
you're going to win.
lt's time.
Vassili, come to my arms.
Put your cap back on.
You look more heroic.
This way, comrade Zaitsev.
l love this little fellow.
ls it true that you volunteered for the front?
How old are you?
Do you know what
this means for our country?
ls it true you killed
your first wolf when you were five?
How many fascists have you killed today?
lt's a sign the Germans
are starting to shit their pants.
Go on, tell us how you are going
to deal with him.
Or rather, no...tell it to the boss.
He likes good hunting stories.
Look at him with pride...
because he's looking at you.
The whole country is looking at you.
Forgive me, forgive me, Grandfather.
So it's not the wolf that chooses
the hunting ground...but the hunter.
And l'm sure your grandfather
taught you that.
Except in this case, l'm the game.
However, today what we're going to do
is lure the wolf out of his lair.
To where we want him to be.
You're the one whose life is valuable,
you go first.
No. We take it in turns.
Next time it's your turn to go first.
Then it's you, Volodya.
Son of a bitch!
These are new pants. l just took them
off a captain from the 251st yesterday.
16 months l spent in Germany
at the school in Zossen.
Of course those were the days
when we were friends with the Krauts.
When our Joseph and their Adolf
were walking hand in hand.
Near to the wire, 1 16 metres, right?
- 1 55.
- Whatever.
l don't make them send out a repair guy.
Let's relocate.
After the Germans invaded us,
it wasn't the same atmosphere anymore.
They threw me in prison.
''What were you doing in Germany?''
''Excuse me'', says l, ''but it was comrade
Stalin who sent me there.''
''Don't bring our glorious leader
into your treachery.
''Confess, spy bastard, confess.''
There wasn't a sickle
but there was a hammer.
And ''bang'',
it knocked out all, my teeth.
That's right.
Have no illusions.
That's the land of socialism
and universal bliss for you.
Hey, it's your repair guy.
l got him.
- lt's about soup time, isn't it?
- l'm going.
Well, get a move on, Volodya.
And try not to spill it on your way back,
you Marxist bastard.
Here's the enemy sniper activity
reported during the past 24 hours.
Two sentries shot
in the train station.
One artillery observer
in the northern sector.
One lieutenant from
the 24th Panzer Division.
Three telephone repair men
in the workers' housing sector.
They also tell me we've just taken
a prisoner who may interest you.
- l hope he's still able to speak.
- Excuse me, sir?
Nothing.
So tell us, Volodya.
Which building is he in?
There is no way l know that.
He moves around all the time.
He jumps...from one to the next.
- On which floor?
- l don't know.
We'll see about that.
Undress him.
Put him in one of our uniforms.
See? They're stubborn.
That's the good thing about the Germans.
You got to admit,
when they get an idea in their heads,
Let's see if our customer has arrived.
You ready?
And now, our famous shepherd
from the Urals,
who Major Konig thinks is an idiot,
gets up to make sure he has hit his target.
Major Konig sees him...
...aims for his helmet,
fires, reveals his position,
and is shot in turn.
Except...Major Konig doesn't fire,
because, Major Konig isn't there.
Don't you think that was strange?
That last one?
They sent him out
to get shot like the others.
lt's not natural.
Not without artillery,
without trying to cover him.
No, l was the one who was stupid.
They don't give a shit
about telephone guys.
lt's like us with the Ukrainians.
They'd never bother a major
over a few dead soldiers.
Tomorrow...we'll kill us some generals.
Whose turn is it?
Mine, l think.
You're such a cheater.
You can't fool Papa Koulikov, oh no.
lt's my turn to go first.
And it's your turn
to get a hole in your breeches.
To victory.
This sniper business
has been dragging on too long.
What's that little fella of yours up to?
He's probing, comrade Kruschev.
He's testing the Germans for weaknesses.
He's meticulous in his preparation.
Vodka...is a luxury we have.
Caviar is a luxury we have.
Time is not.
He's aware of that, we both are.
l assure you he will succeed.
Good...
lt seems your destinies are entwined.
Keeping you busy?
l picked this up from the kitchen.
lt's from the reception the other day.
Mrs Filipov might like it.
She'll be thrilled.
lt's very sweet of you.
- There's plenty more if you're hungry.
- You're Jewish aren't you?
There's nothing in our religion
that says you can't eat sturgeon.
My father had a premonition
all this would happen.
You mean the war?
He understood that
the hatred of the Jews ran deep.
He was saving up
to buy some land in Palestine.
He said it was the only land
that we truly belonged in.
The only land we had a duty to defend.
He insisted l learnt to use a rifle.
l learnt to shoot.
l know that in times of war
personal feelings should be put aside,
but l have a favour to ask you.
Of course.
Anything you want.
l want to be reassigned.
What's happened, Tania?
He shot him.
He shot him even though he jumped first.
Shot him on the run.
lt was an impossible shot.
l've never seen anything like it.
You've promised people
a victory l can't deliver.
l don't stand a chance against this man.
You mustn't talk like that, Vassili.
What if l told you
we'd found a way to track his moves?
We've got someone, Vassili.
Someone close to him
passing us information.
Next time you will be
one step ahead of him.
l promise.
Now l have a favour to ask.
From me?
lt's about Tania.
Come in.
He doesn't know you, but at that moment
you're closer to him than anyone on earth.
You see his face through the sign.
You see whether he shaved or not.
You can see whether he's married
if he's got a wedding ring.
lt's not like firing at a distant shape.
lt's not just a uniform.
lt's a man's face.
Those faces don't go away.
They come back
and they get replaced by more faces.
Did Danilov ask you to tell me this?
He likes you very much. l think he'd try
anything to change your mind.
Did he tell you why
l asked for the transfer?
This morning a list arrived at headquarters.
lt was a list of civilians
who'd been rounded up
and sent to Germany in a convoy
that left Stalingrad three weeks ago.
My parents were amongst them.
After 30 kilometres...
the German soldiers stopped the train
and forced everyone out.
ln the middle of a bridge,
they bound them together,
two by two.
Mothers with daughters
Husbands and wives.
They lined them up against the railing.
Then they fired
a single shot at each pair,
to save bullets.
lt worked.
The bodies of the ones who died
dragged the others under the water.
l know they died together.
They would never have let themselves
be separated.
That's Koulikov's rifle.
lt's a good rifle.
l know how he leaves the shelter.
He goes through the tractor factory.
The tractor factory is big.
l know exactly where.
He crawls through a gutter
under a grate where the vats are.
Then he goes out from the workshop.
ln between the two
there's a place where he's in the open.
lt's under a long iron foot walk.
Good luck, comrade.
l know exactly where he's waiting for me.
He'll be on the foot walk over the gutter.
We'll take him out from behind.
We'll get to the other end of the workshop
through these pipes.
Follow me.
You go that way.
l'll go this way.
Shit!
- lt's OK.
- You should go back.
No, l'll be all right.
No, you go!
Keep your legs in.
Come on.
Comrade Stalin is asking
for one last effort.
The fate of the motherland is at risk.
The fate of all those you love and cherish.
lt's for them that we fight today.
Listen to me, Tania. The Germans
are throwing everything at us.
lf they're lucky, one in ten of these
soldiers will come back alive.
You're highly educated.
You know languages.
Every intercept you translate
saves hundreds of lives.
Every message you decode
kills thousands of theirs.
You have a duty to survive.
Vassili was born to fire a gun.
That's what he knows.
You and l were born
for a different purpose.
lf Vassili were here,
he'd tell you the same thing.
Where is he? Where's Vassili?
Keep your head down.
- Tell me where he is.
- Stay into that pipe.
Stay in. Get your head in.
Slow down.
Don't shoot.
He's over there.
You see the pillar in front of you?
l need you to move round behind it.
Go!
Tania, l need you to find
a large piece of glass.
Piece of glass.
You see the kiln?
Behind me.
To the left of the factory.
- l can't hear you.
- Yes.
Do you see the two louvres?
Do you see the one with the broken slat?
- Yes.
- This is what l want you to do.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Three...two...one.
Hello, Sacha.
He was right where you said he'd be.
Nearly there.
He's very clever.
Tell me about him.
Why was it his grandfather who taught him
how to shoot and not his father?
His father's dead. His mother too.
- Does he talk about his father?
- No, he didn't know him.
Did he go to school?
He knows how to write.
He answers lots of letters.
- ls it girls who write to him?
- Everyone writes to him.
- ls there a girl he loves in his village?
- Not in his village. Here!
Does she love him?
Yes. Because he's handsome and brave.
And she's very beautiful.
She's from my neighbourhood.
She went to the university.
They are handsome together.
Later the two of them will get married.
At least, l think so.
And you, Sacha,
why are you helping the Germans?
Because they're stronger.
Because they're going to win the war.
And because you like chocolate.
All these people here
know they're gonna die.
So each night when they make
it back, it's a bonus.
Excuse me!
So every cup of tea, every cigarette...
becomes a little celebration.
Because for a lot of us,
it may be our last night.
lt's just something
you have to accept here.
Everyone has their time.
ln the forest the wolf lives for three years...
the donkey for nine.
Sorry, but that's got to be
a proverb from the Urals.
lt makes no sense to me whatsoever!
The donkey lives longer
because he's more useful.
Absolute sense!
There aren't any donkeys in the forest.
You made it up.
l'm a donkey.
People like you and Danilov...
have to survive this.
People who've read books,
had an education...
We'll need you when the war's over.
And if you survive?
What will the useless
Vassili Zaitsev do then?
l want to work in a factory.
My granddad took me to a factory once.
There was this man there.
High up on a foot walk.
He wasn't wearing blue like the others.
The people who were supervising didn't
really understand what they were doing.
But for him up there, it was simple.
lt was clear.
And l thought, one day...
l could be that man.
Sad to have a dream
you know won't happen.
Why shouldn't it?
You'll outlive us all.
You'll be the oldest donkey in the forest.
1 50 metres stand between
the Germans and the Volga.
Today the whole world is watching
these 1 50 metres.
They are what make Stalingrad
the capital...
...of the war.
Your friend, Tania.
- Have you seen her?
- She stays there with the snipers.
Tell the major our sharpshooters
will support the attack on the factory.
Vassili will be there.
- l need to talk to you.
- Sure.
You have to stop writing about me.
l won't get him cos l'm not good enough.
Sooner or later he's gonna find me,
he's gonna kill me.
l've warned you before not to talk like this.
This time it's different.
You've built me up and up
into someone l'm not.
l can't carry that weight anymore.
l want to fight.
l want to fight, just as a regular soldier.
l understand.
The thing is Vassili you're not a regular
soldier, you're an extraordinary soldier.
No. l'm what you've made me.
Nothing more.
Why are you telling me this now?
What's happened?
What's changed?
Did you speak to Tania for me?
Well, will she reconsider?
l don't know.
She should.
She'll be much safer. You know that.
lt'll be easier to get her reassigned
than you.
The Germans are preparing another
offensive in the city centre.
The propaganda battle's crucial for morale.
We need you more than ever.
Tell him what you know, Sacha.
There was dust on the major's boots.
Sacha has the major convinced
he's gone over to the other side.
- You know the risks he's taking.
- The dust was yellow.
There's only one place
where there's dust like that.
ln the back of the chemical factory,
a big heap along the tracks.
Well done.
Sacha, wait for me outside then.
You had no right to use him.
No, l didn't use him, Vassili,
he did it of his own accord.
Do you know why?
Because he believes in you.
Tomorrow morning we going take back
the chemical factory.
Sacha has informed the major
you'll be there.
So now you know
where you have to wait for him.
-ln the middle of an assault.
- l'm following orders.
l suggest you do the same.
Now, l'm aware of the risks.
You'll be fine...
...comrade.
That's the Germans up there.
Yesterday it was the Russians.
We're not very far now.
You're playing a very dangerous game.
l want you to win.
See there?
Keep going along the river.
lt's safe for a while.
He's dead.
We found this on his corpse.
Your reason
for being here ceases to exist.
Pardon me, Herr General.
l do not believe...
There's a plane bound for Berlin
tomorrow evening. You will be on it.
Until then l must ask you for your dogtags.
lmagine how Russian propaganda
would profit from your death.
lf you fall, you will fall unknown.
You've already had a near miss.
Also, please take this war merit cross.
lt was awarded posthumously to
a Lieutenant of the 1 16th lnfantry Division,
who fell here during the first days
of the battle.
He was my son.
lf the landing is captured everything's lost.
Come here.
What did l tell you?
You've been playing your fiddle too much.
lf it's confirmed that he's dead, we're sunk.
- Well, you're sunk.
- lt isn't true.
lt was intercepted
from their staff headquarters.
What do they have to do?
Dangle his body in front of our men?
They're lying.
That's good.
Very good.
Write it then. Vassili Zaitsev is not dead!
This is what he had for breakfast
this morning.
This is a picture of him
reading today's newspaper.
You're the poet.
What? You won't give up the riverbank.
l don't care of you've lost half you're men.
Lose the other half or lose yourself!
ls he back?
He should be back soon.
The German attack cut the lines,
that's why he's late.
Can we go outside?
l wrote to my mother about you.
She wanted me to tell you,
once this war's over,
if there's anything you needed,
our family will be there for you.
You know l'm here for you.
They're saying Vassili is dead.
Vassili Zaitsev will never see
his loved ones again.
Surrender.
This is your only future.
You're upset?
Because Zaitsev is dead?
You don't have to hide it.
There's no shame in it.
You're Russian like he is.
Don't listen to them.
lt's just a propaganda.
He isn't dead.
And do you know why?
Because l haven't killed him yet.
l'm going to tell you a secret.
Only you, because l know l can trust you.
But you must swear
you won't tell another soul.
Do you swear?
l found a terrific spot.
lt's by the exit from the train station.
l'll hide in the water tower.
Tomorrow l'll wait for him there.
You'll see. He'll be there.
He always is.
l also want you to swear
you'll stay home where you belong.
Do you swear?
We know he's alive and won't fail us,
because he is a part of us now.
Vassili is eternal.
Where have you been?
We've looked everywhere for you.
Didn't you hear? l was dead.
At least...noble sniper Zaitsev...
...Vassili was dead.
The real one.
Me.
l was asleep.
And l missed my chance.
Then l was curled up in a corner hiding,
from a man who wants to kill me.
l'll talk to Kruschev.
He'll send you back to your old division.
Where's Tania?
She's at the shelter.
- l've been to the shelter.
- l told her you weren't dead.
The major said so,
that the other Germans were lying.
He told me you were waiting for him
at the station.
My little Sacha.
l knew it.
l knew you weren't dead.
- How?
- Because we've only just met.
l prayed for the first time
since l was a little girl.
When l opened my eyes, Sacha was
there waiting to give me the good news.
l think he loves you even more than l do.
To the proper military authority.
l'm calling to the commander's attention
recent changes noted in attitude towards
fighting of soldier, Vassili Zaitsev.
He has attempted on several occasions
to escape his duties,
voiced doubts on our chances of victory
and made defeatist comments in public.
The inexplicable duration of his duel
with the Nazi sharpshooter
can only be explained
by his lack of belief in the Communist ideal.
Good morning, Sacha.
Once again, he knew exactly
where to find me.
Don't you think that's strange?
Apart from me, only you knew.
l don't hold it against you, Sacha.
You've done a very brave thing.
You've chosen your camp.
l respect that.
But it isn't my camp.
We're both soldiers.
We're both enemies.
So l know you understand.
l'm annoyed with you for not staying
at home as l'd made you swear.
l'm annoyed with you for obliging me
to do what l'll have to do.
l've never seen anyone frown
so much in their sleep.
How long have you been watching me?
All night.
You've been snoring away happily
for hours.
l don't snore, do l?
Like a pig!
l suppose l talk in my sleep as well?
There's something l should tell you.
On the train...
...coming here...
...we were in the same car.
l saw you.
You were reading and you fell asleep.
l didn't dare look at you,
you were so beautiful.
You were scary.
Afterwards, l couldn't stop thinking
about you.
lt made me smile.
Then l thought of all the men
who would get to hold you -
who'd make you laugh -
how lucky they were.
And now l'm the one lying next to you.
- Was l snoring?
- Like a pig.
Oh my God!
Tania, no.
No, get off me.
- Get off me.
- lt's what he wants.
This is what he wants.
He'll kill you.
He'll kill you, then he'll kill me too.
This is what he wants. l'll get him.
l promise l'll get him.
l'll get his rifle for you, l promise Tania.
l need you.
You have to leave now, Mrs Filipov.
Stalingrad may fall.
The last boats are leaving.
The Germans will be here any moment.
He's brought you a pass.
You'll be safe on the other side.
Gather your things
and we'll help you to the landing stage.
l'm not leaving. This is my home.
This is my Sacha's home.
l can't leave.
l must tell you something, Mrs Filipov.
Something very difficult to understand.
lt's about Sacha.
He's gone over to the Germans.
He won't be coming back.
Oh my God.
He's become a traitor.
The poor little thing.
What has he done?
So he's going to stay over there?
Yes. He's going to stay over there.
l shouldn't be saying this,
comrade Commissar,
but maybe it's for the best.
lf the Germans have won, he'll be safe.
l know it's wrong,
but perhaps he's made the right choice.
l need a doctor. A doctor!
l have a pass.
You must let her cross.
Please.
lt's useless. She'll never make it.
No, she will. She's my daughter.
She's my daughter, l beg of you.
All right, you too.
Put this one on the boat.
Where is he? Where's the major?
A few inches from your face.
l've been such a fool, Vassili.
Man will always be man.
There is no new man.
We tried so hard to create a society
that was equal,
where there'd be nothing
to envy your neighbour.
But there's always something to envy.
A smile...a friendship.
Something you don't have
and want to appropriate.
ln this world, even a Soviet one,
there will always be rich and poor.
Rich in gifts.
Poor in gifts.
Rich in love.
Poor in love.
Tania isn't coming back.
She's dead, Vassili.
She was cut down by shrapnel.
lt was quick.
l don't think she even saw it coming.
She was on her way back to you,
as soon as she had seen Mrs Filipov
to the boat.
She was coming back for you.
She was right.
You're a good man, Vassili.
l want to help you Vassili.
Let me do one last thing.
Something useful for a change.
- Let me show you where the major is.
- No, don't do that.
Don't do that!
Today, February
3rd, 1 943, is an ominous day for Hitler
and the endless columns
of thousands of German prisoners
lt is an unforgettable day of hope
for our motherland,
for the people of the Soviet Union.
After 1 80 days of growing combat
in the martyred city of Stalingrad,
and as a result of the valour
and self sacrifice of our soldiers
the commander of our glorious Red Army
received the unconditional surrender
of the German fascist invasion.
l cannot find the matching name
in the book.
This is this hospital's address
and this is her name.
- This is our address, but she's not here.
- We don't have her anymore.
This is the address of this place and she's
obviously been here. She wrote to me.
Believe me. There is no Tania Chernova.
l can't help you.
Subrip By 3bit