Attaboy! Keep him busy!
- One! Two!
- You got it!
Three! Four! Five!
Six! Seven!
Eight! Nine!
Ten! Out!
Come here, Jimmy.
Get that Sleeping Beauty out of here!
- Thats ten in a row, Jimmy.
- A knockout!
At one minute 46 seconds
of the second round,
tonights light heavyweight winner
from the great state of New Jersey,
the Bulldog of Bergen, James J. Braddock!
- Youre gonna be the next champ!
- How you doing?
- Just a few. Leave em wanting.
- Wanna sign my name for me?
Well, at least then they can read it.
Youve been getting stronger
with every fight.
You favor the right, sure,
but you got no stage fright.
And you have never been knocked out.
Youre in line. Thats all Im saying.
Youre gonna get your shot.
All right, let me see what weve got here.
$886 for Jeanette,
$772 for Lou and Whitey.
A thousand bucks for the ring fees,
my $2,658 and your $3,544,
makes $8,860.
Stick that in your mattress, Irishman.
When we get there,
you gonna come in and see the kids?
Its been a while. Come on.
They miss their Uncle Joey.
Thats very sweet.
You still married to the same girl?
- I was this morning.
- Congratulations. Ill take a rain check.
And would you tell her I undercharged
on the gym fees and no load on the towel?
- Ill be sure to point that out.
- I appreciate it.
Would you stop
up at the corner here, Frank?
Home to Jersey
for Mr. Adventure over here.
All right. See you, Frank.
Oh, I could kill you!
I like the sound of that.
I like the sound of that a lot.
- Jimmy.
- Yeah?
My sister.
Daddy, did we win?
Yeah, we won. How are ya Alice?
- Good. Thats wonderful, Jimmy.
- Hey, Howard.
Thank you.
So, tell me about it.
Was he a real slugger?
You know...
you could come and watch.
No.
You get hit, every time
it feels like Im gettin hit too.
And Im not half as tough as you are.
So...
- Tell me about the girls.
- Girls?
- I was at the Garden, it was a fight night...
- There was one. There mustve been one.
No.
- Blonde?
- Brunette.
Tall?
Like a gazelle.
I dont know how it is
she breathed up there.
Mr. Braddock!
Youre so strong!
And your hands...
theyre so big.
Youre so powerful.
Jimmy.
Im so proud of you.
Introducing two-times
state Golden Gloves titleholder,
in both the light heavyweight
and heavyweight divisions,
21 and 0, with 16 wins
coming by way of a knockout,
the Bulldog of Bergen,
the pride of New Jersey
and the hope of the Irish
as the future champion of the world,
James J. Braddock!
Mom, you woke me up.
You kicked the covers off, honey.
Go to sleep.
- I cant find my socks.
- Jim.
Im sorry.
Mama.
- Great.
- Im sorry, baby.
I washed em last night.
Took em right off your feet.
- Dont you remember?
- No.
You were out like a light.
How do I keep em this warm?
Mama, I want to eat too.
Mommyll get you some, honey.
Hey, Rosy-Rosy.
Good morning, good morning.
We got a notice yesterday.
Gas and electric.
Come on. Okey-dokey. There we go.
Ill get the milk.
Well, I think theres some left over.
Yup.
You know I got that fight tonight
at the Armory.
One guy. Abe Feldman.
- Its 50 bucks, win or lose.
- Thats good.
If I beat him, maybe I can
get my purses back up to $75.
That would be great.
Rosy.
Use your fork, please.
Who needs a cow?
Mama, I want some more.
Im sorry, sweetheart.
We need to save some for the boys.
Here you go.
You know, Mae, I dreamed last night
that I was havin dinner at the Ritz.
- With Mickey Rooney and George Raft.
- Really?
I dreamed I had a steak.
A thick, juicy steak.
Like this, Rosy.
Then I had a mountain of mashed potatoes
and I went back for ice cream three times.
Im stuffed. Im absolutely full.
I cannot eat another thing.
Want to give me a hand?
Jim...
Jimmy.
Boys, hurry up. Dont dawdle.
Lets try and sleep a little more.
Sure, business is bunk,
And Wall Street is sunk
Were all of us broke, And ready to croak
Weve nothing to dunk, Cant even get drunk
And all the while, They tell us to smile
Cheer up, gentle citizens
Though you have no shirts
Happy days are here again,
Cheer up, smile, nertz
All aboard prosperity,
Giggle till it hurts
No more bread-line charity,
Cheer up, smile, nertz
Sunny smilers we must be,
The optimist asserts
Lets hang the fathead to a tree,
Cheer up, smile, nertz
Here, Jake. Over here.
I need nine men, and only nine.
One. Two.
Three. Four.
Five. Six.
Seven. Eight.
Nine. Thats it!
All right, lets get a move on.
Come on! Get going.
Not a lot of work today.
See you tomorrow, all right?
Hey, Dad.
- No shifts today, Dad?
- What are you doing, son?
Im being good, Im being quiet,
Im being have.
Great.
Daddy! Daddy!
- Rosy-cheeks. How you doin?
- Daddy! Jay stole.
- What?
- Jay stole.
- Whats all this about?
- See? Its a salami.
Young lady, your brothers in enough
trouble without you tellin on him.
Its from the butchers, and he wont say
a word about it. Will you, Jay?
Will you, Jay?
OK, pick it up. Lets go.
Do not test me, boy. Right now.
Howard, stay here.
Marty Johnson had to go away
to Delaware to live with his uncle.
- Why?
- His parents didnt have enough to eat.
Yeah, well, things aint easy
at the moment, Jay. Youre right.
But theres a lot of people
worse off than what we are.
Just cause things aint easy, thats
no excuse to take whats not yours, is it?
Thats stealing, right? And we dont steal.
No matter what happens, we dont steal.
Not ever. You got me?
- Are you giving me your word?
- Yes.
- Goon.
- I promise.
And I promise you...
we will never send you away.
Its OK, kid.
You got a little scared. I understand.
Its OK.
Hes a very slow guy.
Just plants himself there.
So you just keep him steady,
keep him trapped in the middle.
Keep dancing around him, OK?
You know what to do. You know this type.
The guys a bum.
Two bits will get a guy a seat.
And that guy gets to watch you bleed
and call you a bum.
And I know I gotta take it from
him cause hes a paying customer.
I see.
Well, well, well, well, well.
Pardon me, miss.
Allow me to restate my position.
Mr. Abraham Feldman is a novice fighter
whose ass you should gently kick
until it is humped up
between his shoulder blades.
That is if it doesnt offend
your overly sensitive nature. God knows.
- Now, that breaks still a few weeks away.
- I know.
- You were gonna tell me about this when?
- Its fine.
Its not fine. No, its not.
What the hell? You dont tell me?
I owe everybody money, Joe.
I owe everybody money.
I cant get any shifts.
I aint got any cash.
I got it, I got it.
Screw them. Ill tape it double.
Thanks.
Keep up. Stay up.
Keep moving, keep your legs moving.
Here comes Braddock
with his long-time manager, Joe Gould.
Youre washed up, Braddock!
- And now for our main event...
- Hey. Which ones us, pal?
Hes up against Hymie Caplins
latest charge,
- young Abe Feldman from Schenectady.
- Six-rounder.
Some might recall that Braddock was
once a light-heavyweight title challenger.
His golden-boy peak ended
when Tommy Loughran handled Jim
over 15 rounds back in 29.
Since then, the oft-injured Braddock
has shown only a glimmer
of his early promise.
And the losses have started to pile up.
But Braddock continues to battle.
And here comes the popular
Abe Feldman.
He looks to be the real thing and showed
real moxie in his recent win over Birkie.
- Who whipped Latzo?
- I did.
Goddamn right.
Who KOd Slattery in the ninth
when everybody said he didnt have
a rainmakers chance in hell?
- Thatd have to be me too.
- Right.
And were sposed to pucker our assholes
over Feldman?
- The guy couldnt break wind.
- No.
Jimmy, Jimmy. Jimmy.
- Any place else youd rather be?
- No.
Good. Now what are you
gonna do about it?
Here we are halfway through the fifth
and its more of the same.
The boys clinch again.
- Hes crushing my guy! Get him off!
- Break, break, break!
The boo-birds have started flying.
They want action from these fighters.
Feldman sticks a left in Braddocks face.
Braddocks right hand
is his best and only weapon.
He'll show the left but it lacks snap,
and Feldman knows it.
Give these yokels a shot in the ass!
Feldman ducks a haymaker,
but fails to follow up.
Another big right by Braddock.
Theres the Braddock we all recall.
But its one at a time.
It may not be enough.
Come on!
The referee pulls the boys apart,
and theres the bell to end the fifth.
Easy now, easy. Easy, easy.
I saw that.
Bust it again? Im calling it, Jim.
You gonna use the left? OK. Good.
You get in there, but dont let him crowd
you. Work his belly, hammer his belly.
Last round. Come on,
you gotta show me something.
- You are giving me an ulcer, Harry!
- Shut up.
Work his belly with the left. You got it?
Give him the flapdoodle with the right,
because he dont know. Hes kinda stupid.
Last round. Last round. Go get him!
The left! The left!
Damn it. I wish he could find
his goddamned left.
Thats it. Change it up.
Southpaw, thats it!
Feldman prancing around,
looking for an opening.
But still few clean punches by the fighters.
Braddock still pawing away with the left.
Another ineffectual left from Feldman.
Braddock can hardly lift his arms.
Hes slow on his feet.
At least Gould in his corner is still
throwing punches, trying to urge his man on.
Go home!
No holds, Braddock.
Cavanaughs working harder
than the fighters.
Dry up!
Another clinch. Its as if 80 tough fights
have finally jumped on Braddocks back.
Cavanaugh pulls them apart. And hes
called the fight. Hes called the fight.
Its a no-contest. And the popcorn
and the peanuts are raining down.
And Im afraid to say
thats all these fighters deserve
for the show they put on tonight.
Its sad to see a fighter that was once the
caliber of James Braddock reduced to this.
Its all right, Jimmy.
Its all right, its all right.
An embarrassment, thats what it was.
- An embarrassment!
- Where the hells the purse?
You wouldnt have to be asking that
if you gave a shit about your fighter.
OK. OK. Hes fighting hurt.
Maybe you got fat and happy fighters
who can afford to rest between bouts.
- I dont know. Lucky you.
- Christ, he hardly gets a punch in!
Fights being stopped by referees?
Hes pathetic!
Fights like that keep people away.
Were revoking his license, Joe.
Whatever Braddock was gonna do
in boxing, I guess hes done it.
Wait a minute.
Thats all.
Oh, boy.
Mr. Johnston!
Jim.
- Whats going on?
- You didnt tell him?
Yeah, of course I told him.
He wanted to hear it from you.
Come on, Mr. Johnston. No contest?
I broke my hand. OK? Its legit.
You dont see me crying about it.
I dont see what you got to complain about.
I still put on a show. I did what I could do.
You know, we did that boondock circuit
for you - me and Joe. Remember?
I didnt quit on you.
And I didnt quit tonight.
I didnt always lose.
I wont always lose again.
- I can still fight.
- Go home.
- Go home to Mae and the kids, Jim.
Go home? Go home with what?
Go home with what?
A broken hand from Mount Vernon?
Mr. Johnston!
Baby?
What happened?
I didnt get the dough.
They didnt pay up.
They called it a no-contest,
said the fight was an embarrassment.
They decommissioned me.
- Jimmy, what happened to your hand?
- Its broken again in three places.
They said Im through, Mae.
Said I cant be a boxer no more.
Mercy.
OK.
Jimmy, if you cant work, were not gonna
be able to pay the electric or the heat.
And...
were out of credit at the grocery, so...
I think we need to pack the kids.
They could stay at my sisters for a while,
and Ill take in more sewing.
- Mae, Ill get doubles, triples.
- We could make two breadlines a day.
- Jimmy, you cant work.
- Mae, I can still work.
Jimmy, you cant work. Your hands broken.
They see me lugging this around, they
wont pick me. Not the docks or anywhere.
So Im gonna cover it up-
with the shoe polish.
OK?
- Im sorry.
- No.
No.
All right. Five, and only five.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five. Thats it.
- What the hell happened to your face?
- I got in a fight.
Yeah? What did you go and do that for?
Thats a good question.
Mike Wilson.
Jim Braddock.
Used to follow a pretty good
fighter with that name.
Theres some other guy going around
using that name now. Cant fight for shit.
A gambling manll lose
a lot of money on him.
Twice.
Hey, that hand aint gonna work.
You cant slow me down. I need this job.
I need the job too.
Whats wrong with the goddamn hand?
You see us falling behind, Jake?
Hes all right.
I appreciate it.
Ill get a cold beer.
- Just a water for me, Quincy.
- All I got today, big spenders.
Beer for him too. Im buying.
Dont hurt my feelings.
Its been a while but...
you dont have to twist my arm.
Yeah, I used to be a broker.
Still lost it all in 29.
Yeah, me too.
I had just about everything
I ever earned in stocks.
Even that taxi company. I mean, who
loses their dough on cabs in New York City?
Yeah. I thought that one was gold
for the grandkiddies.
You know theres people living in shacks in
Central Park? They call it the Hooverville.
This governments dropped us flat.
We need to organize, you know?
Unionize, fight back.
Fight? Fight what?
Bad luck? Greed? Drought?
No point punching things you cant see.
Well work our way through this.
- FDR, hes gonna handle it.
- Screw FDR.
FDR, Hoover, theyre all the same.
I come home one day,
I stand in my living room,
and between the mortgage and the market
and the lawyer meant to be working for me,
it stopped being mine.
It all stopped being mine.
FDR aint given me my house back yet.
Mama, why cant I go to school?
Is it because Im a girl?
Maybe. Hadnt thought of that.
Whos that man at our house?
Excuse me!
- Can I help you?
- Im sorry, lady. Youre past due.
No. No, you cant.
You cant. Theres kids.
If I dont, they let me go.
- They already let two guys go.
- Please.
This apartment is what we got left
that keeps us hangin on.
Lady, I got kids too.
$6.74.
How much to turn it back on?
Four months.
$44.12.
If I work 26 hours out of every 24,
it still wont add up.
We aint got nothing. Nothing left to sell.
All the guys you couldve married.
Yeah. What happened to those guys?
Its Howard.
Since this afternoon.
Bless us, O Lord,
and these thy gifts which
we are about to receive from thy bounty.
Jim.
Im all prayed out.
Where are you going?
I said where are you going?
Go ahead, you no-good bastard!
Go on, then! We dont need you!
All right. Help me.
Pick up some of that wood.
- I got it, Mama.
- Lets go, sweetheart.
Nice and warm.
Baby?
Look at mommy.
Sweet Lord.
Mommy?
Whats wrong?
Nothing, sweetheart.
Mommy will be right back, OK?
Howards fever was getting worse,
and then Rosy started to sneeze.
- Where are they, Mae?
- Jimmy, we cant even keep em warm.
Where are the kids?
The boysll sleep on the sofa at my
fathers. Rosyll stay at my sisters.
Jimmy, we cant keep em.
You dont make decisions
about our children without me.
What if they get really sick?
We already owe Dr. Macdonald...
If we send em away,
then all this is for nothing.
- Its just until...
- What else is it for?
If we cant stay together,
weve lost, weve given up!
I am not giving up!
I am trying to protect our children!
Mae, I promised him.
Outside the butchers
I looked him in the eyes
and I promised him with all my heart
I would never, ever send him away.
- You cant do this.
- You werent here.
You cant break my promise.
Jim, you didnt see. You werent here.
Im sorry.
Im sorry, Jimmy.
What are you doing?
Jim?
Jimmy?
Where are you goin?
Where are you goin, Jimmy?
That doesnt qualify you, sir.
What else can you tell me?
My wife is losing all of her teeth.
I got a relief order for her, and the doctor
says its due to insufficient diet.
Shes still nursing the baby on account
of we cant afford milk for the family.
I never thought Id see you here, Jim.
I want none of my fighters
going up against John Henry Lewis.
None of em. This guys an animal.
Well, I gotta tell you, he jumped up,
kicked his stool out of the ring.
He was furious.
He started to holler. I grabbed the mike...
Theres Jimmy Braddock.
The thing is, I cant afford to...
I cant afford to pay the heat.
Ive had to farm out my kids.
They keep cutting shifts down at the docks.
You just dont get picked every day.
I sold everything I got
to anybody who would buy.
I went on public assistance. I signed on at
the relief office. They gave me 19 dollars.
I need another 18 dollars and 38 cents so
I can pay the bill and get the kids back.
You know me well enough to know
if I had anywhere else to go,
I wouldnt be here.
If you could help me through this time,
I sure would be grateful.
Sure, Jim. Sure.
Good luck.
Jim.
Jimmy.
Here you go, Jim.
Good luck, Jim.
Im sorry, Joe.
I didnt... Im sorry.
What in the hell
do you have to be sorry about?
Jesus Christ, Jim.
How short are you?
About a dollar fifty.
OK.
- Were home! Were home!
- Were finally home!
Good.
Hey, all right.
Howard, dont jump on the bed.
Sorry, Mom. Read to me, Jay.
On his way up and down the stair,
he often paused to sniff,
but he never asked for anything...
Happy birthday to you
- Happy birthday, dear Howard
- Junior!
- Sarah!
- Jean!
Happy birthday to you
- Make a wish, kids.
- Blow!
Howard, come on. Theyre gonna
cut the cake up. You gotta line up.
- Looking forward to some chocolate cake?
- I liked it better when we had our own.
I can understand that.
- Hiya, Howard.
- Hi.
Did your dad ever tell you
I used to spar with him?
- You hit the Father?
- As often as I possibly could.
He was kind of tricky, though.
Hard to catch.
Go and get some cake. Go on.
Missed you at Mass, Jimmy.
I can get an extra shift on a Sunday.
- James.
- Excuse me.
Every day, fix the world.
How about fixing your family?
What kind of fathers too proud to cross the
street cause she cant have her own cake?
Youre drunk at church, for Christs sake.
- Is that a joke, Sara?
- Im just saying its enough!
- Hey, guys, wheres the ref?
- Stay out of it. Its between man and wife.
- How do you even call yourself that?
- Whatd you say to me?
- Get off me.
- A couple of drinks, no harm in that.
All washed up, cant get a fight.
Well, you wanna fight me?
Dont do this. I aint got no beef with you.
Come on! Cant make it in the ring?
Come on, Braddock!
I could take your head off. Come on!
Jim, no!
- You OK, baby? You OK?
- Get off me.
Go to hell. The both of you.
Jesus, Jim. He wasnt gonna hit me.
Mike! Wait!
What its all about is
rotating your body behind your fist. Bang.
Thats right. Right in the kisser, yeah.
Boom.
There you go. Yeah.
There you go. Good girl.
You got a better jab than your dad.
- Boy, you are a brave man.
- Not really. Maes at the store.
- Thats a good one, kiddo.
- Wanna go play while I talk to Uncle Joe?
Joe Gould.
- Still looking dapper, I see.
- Certainly. Gotta keep up appearances.
- Good to see you, Jimmy.
- Nice to see you, Joe.
Well, nice day.
Yeah.
You drove all the way out here
to talk about the weather?
Maybe I was in the neighborhood.
You ever think of that? A little fresh air.
Joe, this is Jersey.
Yeah. Good point. Yeah.
Good point.
I got you a fight.
- Go to hell.
- Come on. You want it, dont you?
Are we gonna tell
the Boxing Commission or not?
Yes. And theyll sanction it.
This one fight and one fight only.
- Its not a comeback. Its just one fight.
- Why?
- Cause of who youre fighting.
- How much?
- Just ask me who youre fighting.
250 dollars. Youre on at the big show
at the Garden tomorrow night.
You fight Corn Griffin, Jimmy. Number two
heavyweight contender in the world.
- Prelim before the championship bout.
- Joe, this aint funny.
No, its not. And it aint no favor either.
Griffins opponent got cut and cant fight.
We had to find somebody they could throw
in at a days notice. Nobody legit would...
Nobody would take a fight with Griffin
without training.
So I told them...
use the angle Griffins gonna knock
out a guy whos never been knocked out.
Youre meat, Jimmy.
- Are you on the level, Joe?
- Come on. Always.
- For 250 dollars, I would fight your wife.
- Now youre dreaming.
- And your grandmother.
- Teeth in or teeth out?
- Take em out.
- Then youre dead. Down, gone.
- 250 bucks?
- 250 bananas. Come here.
Programs here.
45 cents. Programs here.
I mean, for Christs sake.
A hundred and something fights,
you never been knocked out.
Who the hell
goes and sells his gear?
80 fights as a pro, 50 as an amateur.
How soon they forget.
Im so sorry.
Borrowed gear, borrowed robe.
Knock yourself out.
Hey, Joe.
You know, I might as well get an
Aooga horn and chase him round the ring.
Thats good.
- You been drinking?
- Are you trying to hurt my feelings?
Well, youre just too loose.
Youre spooking me. Sharpen up.
Come on, Joe.
We both know what this is, right?
I get to put a little more distance
between my kids and the street
and I get to say goodbye at the Garden.
Full house, night of a big fight.
Thank you very much.
Right, come on. Hurry up.
Lets get the lead out here.
What the hell was that?
- They ran out of soup on the line.
- Ran out of soup on the line?
How the hell are you supposed to fight
on an empty stomach?
Good evening.
Welcome to tonights broadcast
of the Primo Camera/Max Baer fight
for the heavyweight championship
of the world.
Hash is all they had, OK?
- Eat. Quick.
- You got a spoon?
For Christs sake. Its not there?
We gotta go anyway.
- One bite, Joe. Ill eat it with my fingers.
- Whoa, whoa! Hey, hey!
I dont have time to retape you.
Just sit tight and Ill find you a spoon.
For Christs sake.
Is that a ghost Im seeing?
An apparition?
Or is that James J. Braddock,
the Bulldog of Bergen?
How you feeling, Jimmy?
Hows that right hand?
Braddock, youre up.
- Sporty Lewis. How you doing?
- How you doing?
July 18, 1929.
New York Herald.
Proving he was too young and too green
and rushed to the top,
Loughran wiped the ring
with the Bulldogs career.
A sad and somber funeral,
with the body still breathing.
I dont fight the fights, Jimmy.
I just write about em.
Sporty, save the crap for the customers.
- Whos Jim Braddock?
- Get your pencil out. I got your lead line.
Im not kidding. Write this down.
The walk from the locker room to the ring
was the only time tonight Jim Braddock...
- Looking good, Jimmy!
- was seen on his feet. You got that?
Before the championship baffle,
well bring you a special bout,
featuring Charlie Harveys
soldier boy, Corn Griffin.
Griffin is the fella that ran rings
around the champion Camera in training.
His opponent? Looks like they dug
old Jim Braddock out of retirement
for one more fight.
Mike.
- What?
- Isnt that your buddy?
In this corner...
the sensational heavyweight slugger
from Fort Benning, Georgia,
whos punching a path to
the top of the division,
John Corn Griffin.
Corn Griffin.
His opponent, the popular battler
who has never been KOd
in more than 80 professional bouts...
- Quincy, beer. We got a fight.
- Coming right up.
...from North Bergen, New Jersey,
James J. Braddock.
Braddock!
Yeah!
The skinny from ringside
is that Braddock wont last two rounds.
Griffin is the five-to-one favorite.
Joe Gould claims
Braddocks right hand is fine.
Jimmy will need two good hands tonight.
Griffin storms out of his corner.
Things are up-tempo right away.
Come on, Braddock. Make a fight of it.
Get out of it, Jimmy!
Braddock takes a left to the body
and a right to the head.
Braddock giving ground now.
Get out of there, Jimmy!
- And Braddock is down!
- Shut up. I wanna hear this. Shut up.
Jim? Youre fine, youre fine, youre fine.
Stay down. Stay down.
- One. Two.
- Stay down. Whats the hurry?
- Three.
- Hey, listen! Work the left. Try two lefts.
Give him two lefts. Pop, pop.
- Double it up.
- Seven.
- Up, up, up, up. Lets go.
- Eight. Nine.
- Braddock, up at nine.
- Yeah! Come on, Jimmy!
Referee waving Griffin in.
Move in on that! Nice move!
Welcome to New York.
Thats more like it. Let me see that cut.
You look great.
It sure as hell beats working on the docks.
Say, the two jabs look sensational, they
look sweet! Hes loading up on you, see?
He opens up after you jab,
and you gotta come in with the right.
Real quick. Pop, pop. Bang.
But you gotta stop
some of those left hands.
See any gettin past my head?
Keep moving. Pop, pop, bang.
Griffin is still winging big shots.
He wants to be the first to stop Braddock.
Another big right hand.
Snapped Griffins head back with that one.
Griffin loading up.
- Move out!
- Another big flurry by Griffin.
Braddock hanging tough.
But, folks, he is taking a beating.
Thats two rounds more
than I thought he was gonna go.
Hes a half a step behind you.
Do you feel that? Pop, pop, bang.
- Stick with it. Stick with it.
- Busy, busy.
Six minutes of fury so far.
Braddock has the look of a man
trying to hold back an avalanche.
Griffin cuts him with the left.
Braddock is stepping in postholes.
Keep him in front of you!
Lure him in, Jim.
Jimmys finally moving his head.
Pick your spot.
Pop, pop - now!
Griffin is down!
Where the hell have you been,
Jimmy Braddock?
One. Two. Three.
Hes up at three.
The referee wipes his gloves.
Thats it! Thats it! No daylight!
Take it to him!
- Another big right by Braddock.
- Finish him, Jim!
Knock him back to the goddamn Ozarks!
Griffin is ready to go!
Break it up.
Get back.
Get back to your corner.
Jimmy!
This fight is over! This is incredible!
Corn Griffin,
the number two contender in the world
has just been knocked out
by Jim Braddock in the third round.
- What an upset!
- You son of a...!
Its pandemonium here in the Garden.
Settle down, for Christs sake!
Jesus H. Christ.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
Mary Magdalene, all the saints
and mothers and... Jesus!
Did I say Jesus?
Where the hell did that come from?
When my hand was broken, I had to work
down the docks and I had to use my left.
- So... Well, no, that and luck.
- Luck?
- Sheer, dumb-ass Irish luck.
- Dont give me that luck of the Irish crap.
Lucky? Thats something you aint been
in a long time, brother.
- Everybodys due.
- Due or not, Ill take it.
You had the left.
The left - but you were bouncy.
You were bouncy.
You went: pop, pop, bang!
Pop, pop, bang!
Unbelievable. Pop, pop, slide.
- Sliding, slipping. You were like a cat.
- I did that on hash.
Imagine what I wouldve done to him
if Id had a couple of steaks.
Jimmy?
That was one hell of a goodbye.
Here you go, fellas.
Jesus Christ.
Murder him, Maxie!
This is fighting? Why doesnt he
just hit him with a goddamn chair?
Griffin was supposed to fight Baer next.
He should kiss your ass
for saving him from that thing.
Throw him down, Maxie!
Give it to him, Maxie!
Ladies and gentlemen, the new
heavyweight champion of the world -
Max Baer!
Come on. Hes home.
I won.
I knew youd win!
- I knew youd win!
- You won, you won, you won!
Get the silverware.
So, was it like you said?
Or are they letting you back in?
No, baby. It was just one fight.
- Jake! Jake!
- I need seven men, and seven only.
One. Two.
Three.
Four. Five.
Thanks.
Braddock!
Listened in last night. Was that really you?
- Yeah.
- Didnt think Id be seeing you back here.
It came up at the last minute, you know?
It was a one-fight deal.
The purse was $250. My end of that
was a little less than half. It was $123.
We owed $118. Left me with five bucks.
- Makes you a rich man.
- Around here.
- Good fight.
- Thanks.
- Dock seven.
- Seven.
- Hey, Jim.
- Hey, Mike.
- Good fight.
- Thanks.
- I wouldnt have hit Sara.
- I know, Mike.
I couldnt live with myself
if Id have hit her.
I just get so angry with all this shit.
You know, if you were gonna win,
you couldve told me.
If I knew I was gonna win,
I wouldve bet on myself.
- Why cant you ever listen to me, huh?
- I dont know.
...to determine whether the strikers
were willing to submit to arbitration...
Why dont you go play with the boys,
sweetheart? Be careful.
- Hey, Rosy.
- Hi, Daddy.
Beep beep! Vroom, vroom.
You know, Joe Gould was just here.
- Yeah, I saw him.
- You did?
He thinks the commission might be
willing to reverse their ruling.
He thinks he can get me another fight.
He wants me to stop working
and get back in shape.
I thought it was just the one fight.
Well, yeah.
He fronted us 175 dollars so I can train.
Know what that is right there?
Thats a second chance.
Thats what that is.
Its not that Im not grateful,
or proud.
I am. Im so proud of you.
But we got off easy
when you broke that hand.
Were back to even now.
And nine months from now
well be back in the same boat.
Baby, please.
We just dont have anything left to risk.
Hey, hey.
Theres still some juice in these legs
and I can still take a few.
Baby, please.
Just let me take em in the ring.
At least Id know who was hitting me.
Im gonna go tell the kids.
- Jay. Guess what.
- What?
- I got another fight.
- Who with?
I dont know, but hes goin down.
Hey, Howard!
Jesus.
Joe, open the door.
Joe, open the damn door.
Dont hide in your fancy apartment.
I want to talk to you.
You are not gonna make my husband
your punching bag all over again.
We are just gettin by and you take him
from his work like a bloodsucking leech.
And I will not let you get him hurt again like that.
Do you hear me? I will not let you.
I guess youd better come in.
- How is it?
- Too sweet. Per usual.
Really? Go figure.
- Yours?
- Nice, thanks.
Sorry about that.
Just dont want folks
to see you down, thats all.
I didnt know. I mean, I thought that...
Yeah. Thats the idea.
Always keep your hands up.
So...
Sold the last of it two days ago-
so Jimmy could train.
Why?
Well...
Sometimes you have an instinct, Mae.
You see something in a fighter.
You dont even know if its real,
youre looking for it so bad.
Cant have no hope at all.
But this is crazy. I mean, you dont even
know if you can get him a fight.
Ill get him a fight. Believe me, if its
the last thing I do, Ill get him a fight.
Honey. Go get us
some of those crackers, would you?
She looks good wearing the pants.
Can you ever stop yours?
When he sets his mind to a thing?
I wish I could.
See, I never know
who its harder on - them or us.
We have to wait for them to fix everything.
And every day...
they feel like theyre failing us.
Really, its just the world thats failed,
you know.
Its a lovely apartment.
Thank you.
Now, what am I gonna go and do that for?
You saw the papers. The News had to print
extra copies the day after Braddocks fight.
People are sentimental.
Some people are sentimental.
Yeah? So tell me why I care.
Youre still sore over the way
Braddock took down Griffin, fine.
It was a heartbreak-
for a lot of people, yes.
But look.
You got an elimination series over who
gets a shot at Baer for the championship.
John Henry Lewis,
hes your number two in line.
Now, he already defeated Braddock
once in Frisco, correct?
Say you put Braddock
back in the game against Lewis.
Lewis wins, you get
your revenge on Braddock,
and your boy gets a topflight tune-up
with full publicity before Lasky.
And what happens? You make more money.
Now, say on the other hand,
by some minute, infinitesimal chance,
God forbid, Braddock beats Lewis,
you got an old favorite
go up and lose against Lasky.
And what happens?
Youll make more money.
James! Either way youre a richer man with
Braddock back in the ring than if hes not.
Come on. Dont be foolish.
We both know the name of this game.
And it sure as hell aint pugilism.
They oughta put your mouth in a circus.
What do you say?
Dont chase him.
Go around. Cut him off.
Time!
- I got you a fight.
- Who?
Youre gonna fight
John Henry Lewis again.
- Joey! I could kiss you.
- Please, not in front of the fellas.
- Aint John Henry one of Johnstons boys?
- You let me worry about that, please.
Now I know why you wont kiss me.
Youre all puckered out already.
- Brother, you have no idea.
- Lewis? Kicked our ass in Frisco.
- Whos this? Whos our ass up here?
- Joe Gould, Mike Wilson. Mike, Joe.
That guy aint been beat in ten fights.
But you win on a long shot
and thats a great payday for me.
- Thats great.
- Ill keep that in mind.
You got more important things
to think about. Come here.
Now, I aint gonna bullshit you, all right?
You win one, I can get you another.
Win again, and then things maybe
start getting serious around here.
Jimmy...
Win.
Thats it.
Thats it, James. Be a bully, James.
Aggression. Thats it.
Thanks.
I know this isnt what you wanted,
but I cant win without you behind me.
Im always behind you.
Thank you, baby.
I got a great idea.
Want to come along?
Come on. Just this once?
All right, all right.
OK, OK.
Ill make that a rain check, then.
Lewis still moving well here in the fourth.
He dances in and out
before Braddock can react.
Dont let him set the pace, Jimmy.
There you go, there you go.
Braddock slides to his right,
tries cutting down the ring.
- Knock him out, knock him out.
- Braddock!
Lewis spins his way up the ropes
and looks to resume control at the bell.
There we go. Suck it up, suck it up.
Deep breath, deep breath.
- Breathe, breathe.
- Hes even faster than I remember.
Yeah, yeah. Hes fast.
Big deal. Youre not so bad yourself.
What are you doin?
You beat this guy easy last time.
He aint the same guy.
Use your speed. Keep that jab
in his face and slide to his right.
You see that? Keep him in front of you,
cut him off. Right?
And let go with the punches.
Hit him. He aint gonna like it.
I guarantee you, the more you hit
this bastard, the slower hes gonna get.
Hes an old man, hes slow.
He cant keep up with you.
- Hows that cut?
- Hes all right.
Knock the legs out from under him.
Trap him in the corner and work him.
Do not fight this fight his way.
You make him fight this fight your way.
Lets go. You got him, you got him.
A left to the body, a right to the head.
A left-right-left by Lewis. His dancing
shoes are off. Its a fight now, folks.
- Work his body!
- Punching well with both hands now.
Toe-to-toe. No one giving an inch.
That left has some pop!
Jimmys hoping those body shots
will pay dividends.
Keep him in there! Stay with it!
Dont give him any room. No room!
- Outta the corner!
- Braddock pushing all the action now.
Lewis cant discourage him.
Tremendous pressure from Jimmy.
Lewis is running out of real estate
in this 24-foot ring.
Jump on him!
And Lewis is down.
Gotcha. Good boy.
- One.
- Getup.
- Two.
- Come on. Come on.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
The referee wipes his gloves.
Braddock steams back in.
Close it down!
A big right by Braddock. Lewis is a piece
of meat and Braddock is carving him up.
Braddock is now dominating Lewis.
Here comes Jimmy!
Side to side. Side to side.
In the tenth, riding high after his
dazzling victory over John Henry Lewis,
Jim Braddock has just hit a wall
named Art Lasky.
- He cant keep taking those body shots.
- Hes cracked a couple of ribs for sure.
Lasky walks through those jabs
and keeps working on Braddocks body.
Braddock wont fold. Hes making Lasky
work hard for every minute of every round.
Thats it. Get on him.
Laskys starting to impose his will,
showing why Johnston is making noises
about matching him with Baer for the title.
Break it up.
Break clean.
Dont sit down. Youre not tired.
Youre fine.
Get that thing outta here.
He dont need it.
Is he looking over?
Shake your head like you dont need it.
Shake your head
like you dont want it. Yeah.
- Why isnt he sittin down?
- Pay attention.
Now hell wonder: If Braddock is
such an old man, whys he still standing?
Whys he still coming at me?
Youre stronger than this guy.
Dont back up, dont back off!
This guy is a bull-rusher. Hell keep
coming at you all night, until you stop him.
He cant back up. You stop him.
You gotta beat this son of a bitch
from the inside out!
You hear me? You gotta get in there.
You get in there and hit him
and keep hitting until you break his nose.
You fill his face with blood.
Beat him from the inside out, Jim,
from the inside out!
Lasky continues to fire. Braddock
looks like hes finally starting to wilt.
Thats it. Thats more like it.
Back him up.
Lasky now looking to put a Grimm ending
to Braddocks fairy-tale comeback.
Lasky pounding hard shots to the body.
Braddock just took a tremendous shot,
a hard right to the head,
which knocked his mouthpiece
to the canvas.
Braddock just took Laskys best shot
and it didnt even faze him.
Get in there and take that sucker!
Hes showing tremendous determination.
Right in there, and get his nose!
Braddock comes in
with a hard shot to the body.
Laskys wilting under the pressure
from the Bulldog of Bergen.
Braddocks now back on the attack.
Another vicious combination by Braddock.
Lasky flowing blood from the nose.
The 15th and final round.
Braddock now looks like
the younger fighter.
The Garden is on its feet!
Jim Braddock will not be denied!
Theres the bell.
This one goes to the scorecards.
And the winner, by unanimous decision,
James J. Braddock!
Thanks, buddy.
- Max?
- What?
Max!
Jim Braddock just beat Lasky.
They made him the number one contender.
- Max, when are we...?
- Shut up.
- Maxie.
- Shut up!
Im not gonna fight Jimmy Braddock.
Hes a chump.
You tell Johnston to bring me
somebody who can fight back.
Youre gonna bust your contract?
Its done, Max.
Theres Braddock.
Hey, Mrs. Braddock.
- Saras here.
- Yeah?
- I got her to sleep.
- Hey.
Hey, Jim.
Mikes gone missing.
How long?
Three days.
Ive been staying at my brothers
since Jake cut him.
Jake fired him? I didnt know that.
You know how Mike gets.
All his talk, so much trouble.
Hes been sleeping nights
down in the Hooverville.
My brother didnt have room
for both him and us.
Mike said, you know,
if he had to stay down there anyway,
he was gonna try
to get everybody organized.
Somethings wrong, Jim. I know it.
Now Im hearing
theres some trouble in Hooverville.
He wouldnt leave me and the baby
for this long.
He just wouldnt.
I didnt know who else to come to, Jim.
Come on, out of the way.
Beat it. Move along.
Get the hell out of here, coppers!
Mike! Mike Wilson!
Mike Wilson!
We didnt do nothing. You let
these commies in here and start a riot.
Then what do you thinks
gonna happen?
Get over here. On your feet!
You pull a knife on me, you son of a bitch?
We tried to break up these agitators,
peaceful like, but they charged us.
- What is this?
- Horses got spooked, the wagons tipped.
Three or four of em got run over.
Theyre hurt pretty bad.
Go away. Come on, move.
Move back.
Keep those bastards back.
Get those guys next.
The ones who got trampled.
- Hey, Jim.
- Mike.
Youre gonna be OK, Mike.
- Tell Sara... Tell her...
- Ill tell Sara.
...Im gonna be late, Jimmy.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses as we
forgive those who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil...
Mae. Look up, Mae.
How about it, Pete, yeah?
Time-out.
Thats it. Keep your questions
short and to the point.
Were gonna start off with Frank Essex.
Frank Essex.
Take it easy, Petey. Jeez.
Frank Essex, Daily News.
A lot of reporters here today,
a lot of people interested in this fight.
What do you got to say
to your fans today, Jimmy?
I guess Im grateful for the opportunity.
I know that these days
not everybody gets a second chance.
I have a lot to be grateful for.
I have three beautiful, healthy,
troublemaking kids.
And I have the prettiest wife
a man could wish for.
Bob Johnson, Boston Globe.
Two days ago we ran a story about you
giving your relief money back.
Can you tell our readers why?
I believe we live in a great country.
A country thats great enough to help
a man financially when hes in trouble.
But lately I have had some good fortune
and Im back in the black,
and I just thought I should return it.
Listen, whats the first thing youre
gonna do if you make world champion?
First thing? Im gonna have to
go and buy some turtles.
I said to the kids when I left the house this
morning I was gonna bring back the title,
and they thought I said turtle.
So, naturally,
I dont wanna let em down.
But if I could bring back the title
and a turtle, they sure would be tickled.
You got that? Title, turtle. Right?
- Jake Greenblatt from Chicago Trib.
- Hello, Jake.
Its been a while. Whats changed, Jimmy?
I mean, you couldnt win a fight
for love or money, right?
How do you explain your comeback?
The truth is, Jake, for a number of years
there, we was fighting injured.
I broke my hand. More than once.
I got in a car accident one time I was
on the road, and I had to get that fixed.
Ihad a run of bad luck.
And this time around,
I know what Im fighting for.
Yeah? Whats that, Jimmy?
- Milk.
- Milk?
- Sporty Lewis, New York Herald.
- Sporty.
Actually, my questions for Mrs. Braddock.
Mrs. Braddock, my readers
would love to know,
how do you feel about the fact
that Max Baers killed two men in the ring?
So, how do you feel about that, maam?
Are you scared for your husbands life?
Shes scared for Max Baer,
is who shes scared for, Mr. Lewis.
How about one more question?
- Said downstairs you wanted to see us.
- Sure. Jim, come on in. Have a seat.
Right here.
Editorial says this fight is good as murder.
And everybody associated with it should
be hauled into court and prosecuted after.
Theyre getting letters from people
saying youre their inspiration.
Like you saved their lives or something.
If you ask me, its a lot of crap.
But Im not getting hung out to dry
if something happens to you.
Youre all heart.
My hearts for my family.
My brains and my balls are for business.
- And this is business. You got me?
- Got you.
You will know exactly
what youre up against.
And my attorney Mr. Mills will witness Ive
done everything in my power to warn you.
You know, I seen the Camera fight.
- Cameras height saved him.
- He was knocked down 12 times.
Exactly. It wouldve been worse
if he was shorter.
Baer had to punch up to hit him.
Took a little something off.
Thats Frankie Campbell.
Stand-up fighter,
knows how to take a punch.
His style familiar, Jim?
- Like looking in a mirror.
- He dont need to see this.
Hell see it or Ill call off the fight.
Do you see that combination?
Campbell didnt go down
on the first punch. He was a tough guy.
Second one killed him, on the spot.
Just cut it off, will you?
The autopsy said that his brain was
knocked loose from the connecting tissue.
Consider your ass fully covered, OK?
Run it again.
Remember Ernie Schaaf?
Nice guy. You lost one to him in 31.
Ernie took one of those on the chin
from Baer. He was dead and didnt know it.
Next fight, first little nothing jab put him
to sleep forever. Detached brain, they said.
Joe
No snappy comeback?
It aint my skull
the guys gonna try and stove in.
You want to think about it?
You think youre telling me something?
What, like boxings dangerous,
something like that?
You dont think triple shifts or workin nights
on scaffolds is just as likely to kill a guy?
How many guys died the other night living
in cardboard shacks trying to save on rent?
Guys just trying to feed their family.
Cause men like you
have not yet quite figured out a way to
make money out of watching that guy die.
In my profession - and its my profession -
Im a little more fortunate.
All righty, then.
You guys have dinner here tonight.
Take your wives. Its on me.
Well snap some pics on your way out.
You change your mind,
at least we got some press out of it.
Good. Come on.
Its gorgeous. Its gorgeous.
Jimmy.
- Can we get silver faucets?
- What do you want, a dozen?
Listen. A little bird told me to check
the evening editions. Lets see what we got.
Boxer Jim Braddock
has come back from the dead
to change the face of courage
in our nation.
Thats nice.
- Sporty Lewis wrote that.
- Sporty Lewis?
Get this:
In a land thats downtrodden,
Braddocks comeback
is giving hope to every American.
People ready to throw in the towel
are finding inspiration in their new hero.
As Damon Runyon has already written,
hes truly the Cinderella Man.
- Cinderella Man?
- Yeah.
I like it.
- Its kinda girly.
- Oh, brother. This is gonna be fun.
- Excuse me.
- Jim.
- Im not quite finished yet.
- I beg your pardon, sir.
Thank you.
You know what? I got the bill here.
Johnston, hes a big spender.
Hes gonna leave a big, big tip.
Its a real peach.
Gotta love the guy, right, sweetie?
- Look at this!
- This is me.
Jimmy.
Oh, boy.
- You think Johnston set that up?
- Yeah, I think maybe.
A few extra pics for the dailies.
From the gentleman who just arrived.
Mr. Baer said to wish you bon voyage.
Dont open it. Well take it with us.
- Hey, Joey?
- Yeah?
- Get the coats.
- Whoa, whoa, Jim.
Jim. Jimmy.
- Well, if it aint Cinderella Man.
- Thanks for the champagne.
Youre doing great publicizing the fight.
I appreciate it.
I hope its gonna be
a very successful night for both of us.
You keep tellin people
youre gonna kill me in the ring.
I got three kids. Youre upsettin
my family, particularly my wife.
Listen, Braddock.
Im asking you sincerely
not to take this fight.
Now, you seem like a decent fella.
People admire you.
I really dont want to hurt you.
Its no joke, pal.
People die in fairy tales all the time.
- Max!
- Jim! How about a shot?
- Smile.
- There you go.
- Just smile.
- One more.
Yeah, the smart thingd be
for you to take a fall.
Circus acts over, old man.
- Right here.
- Great.
I think Ill go a few rounds
with the dancing Baer.
Very good. OK. OK.
Hey, well see you in the ring.
How about that, champ?
Yeah? Come on. Lets go, Jim.
Max, my wife Mae.
You oughta talk to him, Mae.
You are far too pretty to be a widow.
- Thats not nice, Max. Not nice.
- Maybe I can comfort you after hes gone.
Hey! I said shut your goddamn mouth,
you punk!
Sorry. Send me the cleaning bill.
Get that, boys? Now hes got his wife
doin his fighting for him.
Yeah. Aint she something?
Get me a drink.
OK. Three-punch combo, OK?
Pop, pop, bang. Come on.
Yeah. Thats good.
Keep your thumbs tucked in,
keep your elbows in.
All right, thats enough now.
- Theres some sting in that.
- Thats enough, please.
Yeah, good. Bang.
- I want a turn, Dad.
- Wheres the defense? Get your hands up.
I want a turn.
Pop, pop, bang.
Pop, bang, bang.
Come on, Howie.
Thats enough! No boxing in the house!
No boxing out of the house. All right?
No boxing, period.
Youre gonna stay in school,
and then go to college and have professions.
Because youre not gonna have
your skulls smashed in too.
Do you understand me?
Is that clear?
Why dont you get ready for bed?
I... used to pray...
for you to get hurt just enough
so you couldnt fight anymore.
And when they took your license away,
even scared as I was,
I went to the church
and I thanked God for it.
Cause I always knew a day might come
when it could kill you.
- I just knew it, Jimmy, and now its here.
- Hey. You just got the jitters.
Hes killed two men, Jimmy.
Whats worth it? Huh? Whats worth it?
I have to believe I got
some kind of say over our lives.
OK?
If things are bad, that we can change em.
We can make things better for our family.
But I need you to be safe!
- Nothings safe, and without that...
- So much!
- Nothings safe at all.
- I need you to be safe. All right.
I have stood by for all of it.
Until now.
Not for this, Jimmy. I just cant.
So you train all you want. Make a show of it
for yourself, for the papers.
But you find a way out of that fight.
Break your hand again if you have to.
So how's he doing?
Hes old, hes arthritic,
and his ribs havent been right
since the Lasky fight.
Whats the bad news, sunshine?
- Joe. The reporters are here.
- Jesus.
Right. Get rid of that
goddamn rib protector. Jimmy!
Press is here, boyo!
Get bouncing around in that ring!
Showtime, big smiles!
Youre the belle of the ball!
Baer dont need to know
about no goddamn ribs.
Bye, Dad.
Come on. Lets go. Lets go.
Lets go. Come on.
- Look! Its Braddock!
- Jimmy!
Theres Braddock!
Hey, this is your night, Bulldog.
- Give him a good fight, now.
- Were with you, Jimmy!
Youre gonna beat him, Bulldog!
- Well, look whos here.
- Hi, Aunt Alice.
Come on in.
No radio, all right?
- Yeah. Sure.
- All right. Be back soon.
- Hello, Mae.
- I came to pray for Jim.
So did they.
Yeah.
They all think that Jims...
fighting for them.
- Yeah?
- Who beat that John Henry Lewis?
- That Braddock guy.
- Correct.
Who whupped that Art Lasky punk?
- James J. Braddock.
- Correct again.
Now, refresh me on this one.
Who was it that took that Corn Griffin
and turned him inside out
with no questions asked?
Who was that?
I used to think it was me,
but now i'm kinda thinking it was you.
No, dont you sell yourself short.
At some stage, you think maybe
well do some taping, maybe?
Why not, why not?
Lets see. Hows that?
What?
Excuse me, maam.
You cant win without me behind you.
Thats what Ive been trying to tell you.
Maybe I understand some
about havin a fight.
So you just remember who you are.
Youre the Bulldog of Bergen
and the pride of New Jersey.
Youre everybodys hope,
and youre your kids hero.
And you are the champion of my heart,
James J. Braddock.
You know, youd better go home.
You know, boxers hang around
places like this
and you dont want to get tangled up
in that kind of crowd.
A nice girl like you.
OK.
Ill see you at home.
Please, Jimmy.
Ill see you at home?
See you at home, baby.
Madison Square Garden Bowl...
the biggest pugilistic event
of the year.
Max Baer versus the
Cinderella Man - Jimmy Braddock.
In a moment, the contestants for tonights
bout will be making their way to the ring.
God Almighty.
Jim Braddocks rise to number one
heavyweight contender
has truly been miraculous.
Never in all my years
have I seen this arena so quiet.
You can do it, Jimmy!
James J. Braddock, the Cinderella Man,
who just a year ago
was standing in a bread line.
Braddocks a tremendous underdog
with the betters,
but you wouldnt know it
from the crowds reaction.
People buying tickets looked
as if they were spending their last dollar.
But theyre here now, and 35,000 strong.
Listen to them!
We understand Max Baer
has left his dressing room. There he is.
Baer has the look and swagger
of a Hollywood star.
Tonight therell be no playacting, not with
Braddock in the ring. This fight is for real.
The tables been set:
lets get to the main course.
Gentlemen, I gave you the rules
in the dressing room.
- One minute to midnight, Cinderella.
- Your clocks about ticked down, asshole.
Tell laughing boy no backhanding.
- No holding and hitting on the breakaway.
- No low blows.
- Tell this bohunk no manhandling.
- Watch your language, you nasty little shit.
- Holy mackerel, it talks! Look at that.
- Keep your hands up at all times.
Touch gloves and come out fighting.
Good luck. Go to your corners.
Ill kick his Mick balls up to the roof
of his mouth. That oughta taste familiar.
Come on, Jimmy boy!
Come on, boys.
Get some pictures here. Come on!
You can do this. This guy is made for you.
Have a picnic, all right?
Theres the bell, and the fight is on.
The boys come out and immediately
Braddock shoots a left to Maxs jaw.
Thats it. Take it right to him, Jimmy.
Now, now.
He snaps Braddocks head back
with two uppercuts.
Its always the question of which Max will
show up in the first round- killer or clown?
It looks like hes enjoying himself,
mugging for the crowd.
A big flurry by Braddock.
A vicious right to the head.
Take it easy, pal.
Ill let it go a couple of rounds.
Madcap Maxie is heavily favored to put
the long snore on Jim in the first round.
That right hand is dynamite,
especially with his man on the ropes.
Hes gonna carry him for a couple of rounds.
Break it up. Break it up, I said!
Jim survived the round
and looked pretty good doing it.
Braddock will not be bullied, not tonight.
When he does this horseshit, knock it off.
Hes trying to thumb you.
And then slip inside of there
and shorten up the punches, right?
Shorten em up. Thats your turf.
Inside is yours.
- Put him down, Braddock!
- Come on, Braddock!
Well, no one expected Braddock
to go past the first round.
- Stay inside of him.
- The experts were wrong again.
- Shorten em up!
- Theres the bell. The second round.
Now add some salt on it!
Braddock lands a hard right to the head.
Max swats him away with utter contempt.
He appears to be toying with Braddock.
Theres no other word for it.
Struts around the ring
without a care in the world.
Sharp and vicious. Clip it, short. Good.
Knock that out.
And Max responds with swinging rights
and lefts. All power punches from Maxie.
Braddock comes back
with a vicious right to the head.
Cover up. Cover up.
Is that the right spot, Jimmy?
Break it up. Make it clean.
How are those ribs?
OK. All right.
Take it easy. Just breathe.
- Deep breaths. Relax.
- Good rhythm.
Youre looking great out there, Jimmy.
You look great.
Hey, Jim? Jim?
If he goes for your body,
drop the elbows on him.
Teach him a lesson.
Break his goddamn hand.
That round was tough to score.
Braddock landed several right hands.
And those thunderous body punches
by the champ
should pay dividends in the later rounds.
In the fifth, Baers smile is gone.
Jimmy comes in there with a hard right,
then neatly slides up to Baers left.
Avoiding the counterpunch,
Jimmy sticks a jab.
Now the crowd is jeering
and even laughing at the champ,
and Maxies none too pleased.
All right, break it. Break. Break, break.
Baer backhands Braddock
across the face. Thatll cost Maxie.
- You lousy shaygitz!
- Thats a warning, Max.
Im sorry.
- Hows that wife of yours?
- Break!
- Does she talk about me?
- Break off the wrastling. Break it up.
Quit fooling around, Max.
- Low blow!
- Keep em up.
Wake up, you wet son of a bitch!
Max salutes the crowd.
Hes one of a kind, folks.
Say my name in her sleep?
Baer took a chinful of Braddocks head
in that clinch.
Thats it! Work his body!
She miss me?
Baer grips Braddocks head in a headlock.
Hey, Max!
You gonna punch him or pork him?
Thats your job, asshole.
Jimmy fights his way free,
gets a shot to the head.
You kidding me? You watching this?
Youre gonna get hurt.
Braddock keeps punching.
They hammer each other toe-to-toe.
Keep your hands up and mouth shut.
You watching the fight,
or the cute guy in the front row?
Take a seat, Maxie. Hes nothin, nobody.
The guy has got nothin.
Jesus. Sit down.
Give me the sponge.
- What are you doin?
- Dont worry about it.
- Quit screwing around.
- Relax.
Give me the goddamn water.
Ten seconds!
Hit this guy. Hit him! Hit him!
Cut him down to size!
Shit.
In the seventh, the boys come out again.
And Max is all business now.
- Get him!
- Come on!
Slide it, Jimmy!
Braddock starting to look his age here
as Baer pushes him around the ring.
Baer swings hard to the body.
Braddock gets in a right to the head.
Jesus Christ.
Baer with a tremendous shot.
That was the hardest blow in the fight.
Baer pounds him again,
with another right to the head.
Push him, push him!
Braddock gets in a vicious uppercut.
- Baer keeps on punching.
- Johnny!
Thats enough.
Break it up, break it up.
Youre gonna go home in butcher paper.
Butcher paper!
All right, let me see that nose.
Get it out, get it out. Let me see it, Jim.
Thats nothing.
Thats a piece of cake.
Keep your head up, breathe
through your mouth. Breathe, breathe.
All your ugly friends are down from Jersey.
They dressed up nice, came to see you.
Youre putting em to sleep.
Youre not turning him anymore, Jimmy.
Come on, pick it up. Spit that out, boyo.
Good boy. Good boy, good boy.
Good boy. Come on.
The boys go after each other immediately.
- Braddock gets in a left to the body and...
- Mae.
Its the cops.
Braddock stumbles away.
Baer tries that right again.
They come together.
Braddock swings a left and a right.
Please, Ma.
Braddock sticks out a left.
Baer still after him.
Another left, and a hard right!
Thats knocked Baer for a moment.
Baer tries that right again.
A hard right to Braddocks head.
Braddock is hurt. His legs are gone.
Braddock sticks out a left. Another left.
Neither man will back down.
Its a slugfest, folks.
And theres the bell.
James J. Braddock has exhibited
a lot of heart here
over 11 grueling rounds
with the champion.
Nobody expected him to last
more than a few innings with Baer,
yet here he is,
and hes held his own.
But now we head
into the championship rounds, folks.
Jim? Look at me.
I swear to God, boyo. Win, lose or draw...
Thanks, Joey. For all of it.
Son of a bitch.
All right? Stop talking. Get in there!
And bury him!
Come on, Jimmy!
Here in the 12th, James J. Braddock is
showing this crowd what heart is all about.
Jimmy seems to be timing that left
and has slapped it away several times.
You stay with him! Son of a bitch!
Braddock with a shoeshine.
Left-right, left-right!
- Am I seeing what Im seeing?
- Finish him, Jimmy, finish him!
Braddock! Braddock!
Maxies glamour-boy smile
is now a bloody grimace.
This crowd is definitely hoping
for a Braddock victory.
But Mr. Baer might have something
to say about that.
Holy crap!
Low blow!
Jesus!
- Hey! Why not just kick him in the balls?
- Joe, back in your corner.
What are you afraid of, you son of a bitch?
- Come on, ref.
- Jesus Christ!
McAvoy is on the verge
of losing control of this fight.
Knock him on the ground, Bulldog!
- Last round.
- Thats right! Next champ!
You won this one. Its a cinch. It is yours.
But I want you to play it cagey now.
All right?
I know you dont like laying back,
but I want to stay away from his right.
Do you understand me? Stay away.
Right hand.
Youre behind. Are you listening to me?
You wanna lose the championship
to this goddamn nobody?
This is your night.
Stay away.
Put him down! Put him down!
Use the right hand, right hand.
This is it. This is your shot.
- Ten seconds!
- Finish him.
Its the last round, Jimmy.
There aint no more.
You play this bastard smart
and they cant take it from you.
One more round. McAvoy is at center ring,
waiting for the fighters to join him.
Touch gloves.
The boys touch gloves at center ring.
And now theyre right back at it!
No, Jimmy!
Leave him alone!
Stay away from him! That aint laying back!
Braddocks corner is yelling at him
to stay away from Baer,
whos looking for the knockout.
Stay off him, Jim. Come on.
Right hand, Max!
What is he, stupid?
Step away, step away!
trying to survive this brutal onslaught.
Stay off him!
Looking good, Maxie!
Thats the uppercut.
Stay the hell away from it.
Baer cutting loose with thunderous shots.
A left to the body.
Baer, again with the right.
Braddock covering up, trying to hang on.
Baer looking for the knockout. He doesnt
want this one to go to the cards, folks.
They pound each other with lefts and rights.
Braddock blocking with his gloves and
elbows. Snaps a big right to Maxies jaw.
Baer smashes him with a big right.
Braddock is back on the ropes.
Braddock lands a crushing right!
Maxie desperately wants
to keep the crown from slipping away.
Jesus Christ!
Stay with him.
Both fighters are tired.
Baer is trying wildly for the knockout.
Jimmy is still standing. And hes not
only standing, hes moving forward.
This is the finish. Both boys are tired.
This is not boxing, folks.
This is a walloping ballet.
- Ten seconds!
- Son of a bitch.
Theres the bell!
Its over! This fight is over!
Son of a bitch!
What a fight! Unbelievable!
Braddock came into this fight
the biggest underdog in pugilistic history.
For 15 rounds
he gave it everything he had
against the younger, stronger champion.
We are waiting for the decision.
Its over.
McAvoy. McAvoy.
- What?
- Help me out. Howd you score the fight?
- Nine-five, one even.
- Which way?
- You have to read it in the papers, Sporty.
- No, come on!
What the hell is this crap?
They take this long to make a decision,
theyre gonna decide to screw someone.
- Make a decision!
- Theyre gonna rob this poor bastard.
Unbelievable bullshit.
Come on, make a decision here!
The crowd, on its feet for almost
the entire fight, is still standing,
yelling for who they clearly believe
to be the winner of this fight.
Well have to wait and see
how the judges scored it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have your decision.
Its unanimous.
Winner and the new world champion,
James J. Braddock!
You son of a bitch.
Jim Braddock has defeated Max Baer
for the heavyweight championship
of the world!
He won!
You earned it.
Hell of a fight.