The King of Kalangarh is sending
his son abroad to study.
Jack and Jill went up the hill
to fetch a pale of..
Bastard.
-All the responsibilities given to
people, they've ruined it all.
Do you drink?
- Yes.
l loaf around as well.
l also see prostitutes.
And if someone bothers me,
l beat them too.
He has more then that.
What more he has?
Motor cycle.
- Does he have a motor cycle?
bungalow and all?
Does he have money?
What more does he have?
l have a mother.
You should run for elections.
FrOm Rajputana Party.
You should run forthe big election.
What's in running forthe
college elections?
The society can be changed
just like this.
What change does he want to bring?
l've come here to study.
We have to fight a war.
Awarforfreedom.
Awarfor our land.
What you're doing is insanity,
not a freedom fight.
Do you know who l am?
- Prithvi.
Then you must know everyone
with red face?
Yes.
Then what's the use of
putting red color on the face?
What have you brought?
- Pratha (fried bread)
Pickles?
- l didn't brought that.
Why not?
- l forgot.
Will l eat Pratha with grass?
You can if you want to.
Stupid.
- YOu.
- You stupid.
Eat it orthrow it away.
You're going to have a good
thrashing today.
You'll have a good one.
Sattu was looking foryou.
He Was tOO angry.
Absolutely mad.
Even more mad then being mad.
He was saying, he'll send you to
London to hostel.
Will mom allow him to send me?
He' can't send me to London.
Stupid Sattu.
l'm not that pretty.
Bring Water.
Get it yourself.
Will you bring it or shall
l slap you?
What can you do?
- l'll bite you.
l'll scratch you.
l swear Sattu, l didn't smoke.
Why are you slapping me?
l'm yourfather, not Sattu.
But Grandma calls you ''Sattu''.
She's my mother.
But my mothertoo calls your Sattu.
Why are you beating me?
Don't look at me.
ls yourteacher lying that
you smoked?
First decide why are you
beating me.
For l have smoked?
Orfor l call you Sattu?
You shut up.
He's going abroad Kaushaliya.
lt's decided.
He'll die in abroad.
lf he stays here, he'll ruin
our respect and honor.
Have you seen his manner?
He calls his father by name.
Then what should l call you?
When l call you father, Kaushaliya
looks at me.
Shut up.
Pack his luggage.
He's leaving tomorrow.
TOmOrrOW?
- You should thank me that
l've given you two a night,
to hug and all.
Sattu has gone mad.
- Keep quiet.
l'm growing up.
HOW grOWn up?
Grown enough foryou.
Paro, l've gone crazy.
l too am going crazy.
Come quickly.
You're going crazy,
l already have.
l have too.
Youjust said you are
gOing crazy.
l was before
but now l've gone totally crazy.
Do you touch yourself?.
Tell me.
Send me one of your photo.
You already have it.
Without clothes.
Are yOu crazy?
lf you ever said again that
you're Karan, l'll kill you.
Do you know how bothered l was?
l had to go farto do it.
My heart was beating too fast
as if it was coming out.
As if everybody knew what
l was carrying with me.
And that photo guy...
He was staring like anything.
Like he didn't have any wife.
Bastard dog.
Will you scan it or shall
l do it myself?.
Why would you?
l'll scan it perfectly and make
the photo look alive.
Don't you understand me?
ParO!
l'm coming.
Today there's a wedding.
Dev son, how are you?
Uncle, l'm fine.
After a long time,
l'm seeing you.
What's on your dress?
l don't know
lt seems like turmeric.
lt smells like turmeric.
lt is turmeric.
ParO!
What are you looking
for on the floor?
My earring.
What's in you ear?
ln my ear?
Earring.
Paro! Come outside.
Yes.
What's in your hand?
lt looks like turmeric.
lt smells like turmeric.
lt is turmeric.
Paro, go outside.
Welcome sir,
myself, Suneel.
Come please.
COme
All the sugarcanejuice comes
here to be processed.
And here we check whether
the sugar is prepared or not.
Greetings sOn.
Are you drinking it for
the first time?
NO?
Hand won't reach there?
-Why not?
lt's too tight.
Shall l rip it?
l won't let you.
Leave my hand.
l'm strong.
l too am strong.
l love you.
ParO!
- l'm coming.
- COming.
What are you doing there?
- Nothing
l'm coming.
You father will get killed
some day.
What were you doing?
There has been a queue
in the bathroom.
What?
What if dogs eat
all the food?
DOOr...
There has been a queue
in the bathroom.
Do something.
What shall l do?
Find some way?
Are yOu anxiOus?
- Yes
Then it's good.
l'm Rasika.
Dev
l know you've studied
in London.
l too am going there.
Oxford.
- Really?
Yes.
-Very impressive.
l'm from Delhi.
Kaushaliya Aunt said, we need to
bring some stuff from the farm.
Did she?
Shall we go?
Lets gO.
l was so bored there.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Yes,.
Have you guys done it?
Done what?
S. E. X.
l want your room key.
Why?
My Dev is here.
Then why should l give
you the key?
Give it to me please.
l love you.
lf you want to do it with
Dev then get his room key.
Why don't you understand?
lt's too crowded and a
wedding is going on.
Have l refused you ever?
l love you.
Look at yourself.
How come you love me?
You should be grateful that...
GO aWay nOW.
What happened?
lf there's a chick in this area,
it is only Paro.
You are right.
She can break the bed.
Who can take her?
She can kill.
Greetings sir.
Where were you?
- l went out.
Really?
- Yes.
Brother!
- Here she comes.
Papa!
When did you come?
- NOW.
HOW are yOu?
l'm fine.
Are you fine?
Of course.
l swear on my dead mother,
she's too hot,
killing hot.
l couldn't stand up fortwo days.
lt was that painful.
Sir, you can't find talent like Paro's.
You're lying.
My dead mother shall die again
if l lie.
Shejust asked me to come
inside the room some moments ago.
l denied her and pushed her back.
But why do youjust taking fire
on your eyes only.
l swear, just give her a signal.
She'll come running afteryou.
l'm surprised.
You haven't used heryet?
l'm sorry.
Hey, what did you do?
What happened?
Please go outside.
But what happened?
Leave me alone please.
What happened?
Nothing.
He turned out be useless after
studying in London.
But tell me what happened.
Come outside, l'll tell you.
What are you doing?
You said, do something.
So l'm doing it.
Move your hand.
You're hairy!
You're an expert!
How many guys have practiced on?
Get your hands off of me.
HANDS OFF.
Where are you going?
- Let gO.
At least tell me what's wrong?
Let gO.
Paro go inside yourfather
wants to talk to you.
Sit down.
NO.
Look child, Bhuan Singh came from
Delhi he's a business man.
Have you seen him?
- Bhuan Singh who?
That girl Rasika's brother.
He likes you.
He Wants tO marry yOu.
So what?
They're very rich.
l'll marry Dev.
Whatever l'll do.
l'll do with him.
Why would Mr. Satpal marry his son
tO yOu?
Why wouldn't he?
He loves me.
l know that he thinks of you
as his own daughter.
But child, Dev studied in London
and you here.
l topped in college.
Devjust passed.
At least talk to them once.
l won't disrespect myself.
- But you would disrespect me.
At least meet the boy.
Everything alright?
Paro, come sit eat with us.
Where are you going?
You're Mohan's sister. right?
- Please don't tell my brother about this.
Get Out.
What were you doing with her?
The things you do with Sunil.
With Sunil!
What did l do with Sunil?
Tell me.
That's why you broke the bottle
on his head.
GO.
- l didn't do anything with that dog.
l know everything.
Sunil told you that?
When?
When l broke his head.
You go or l'll break your head too.
You broke his head after driving
Rasika around.
lt's okay if you do it.
and l do it...
l'm going.
l came here to tell you that someone
has asked for my hand in marriage.
Good.
Go and destroy someone else's
home.
You're not worth for my family.
Manager's daughter will always be
manager's daughter.
Go and see yourface in the mirror.
Bad hair.
You have no style.
Are you mad?
You won't do such thing.
She's about to get married.
How beautiful Paro looks.
Her marriage is fixed.
Did she tell you?
Don't know what kind of girl
yOu Want?
l've thinking along the years.
That l'll marry you with her.
Paro will stay our own.
But yourtaste has been ruined
in London.
You drink vodka instead of whiskey.
You eat fish instead of chicken.
You're running after skinny girls
instead of real girls.
What will happen of you?
then?
l say it because l like it.
you are best.
you are the best.
Police arrested Karan Yadav in School
mms scandal.
he is the young man who..
made a mms of a student
Karan says that's his girlfriend.
but with our information, that student
is underage and she study in class 12.
n.O.. n.O.
l can understand.
l have seen it too.
but still l want to marry her.
l will wait.
my mOm..
what are you doing Natha Singh..
you didn't take out the potto..
you read all this stupid things
in English.
that's why you are getting spoilt.
yOu are ansWering me.. !
first you killed my son.
now you want to kill us all?
see how she is looking..
like she will eat me..
what l say, we should kill her.
otherwise we will lost the remaining
respect.
put your eyes down.
or l will take them out.
you will go blind then.. you understand?
mOm..
how much?
here its the biggest room.
its been three months, its empty.
here means..
we are not in hurry.
you are still underage.
what you don't like, till you don't like,
you don't have to do it.
old memories vanish like steam
stay here..
complete your 12th class, give the
exam.
you want admission in any collage,
tell me.
here lot of foreigner girls study.
they also work with us.
here study on study time, and work
on working time.
look ahead.
did you thought of any name?
yeah.. Chander Mukhi.
fine name.
why you are asking, what is the name?
yOu Were missing me?
l need some time.
how are you?
fine.
key?
key..
its a habit of white people, it will
not quit that easily.
Gandhi Mahatma.
son of great father.
look there.
with Vodka.. with Vodka..
can l have one more?
sorry Sir closing time.
excuse me..
yeah!
where are you going from here?
Bell house.
we will get the bell.
if you want to drink then have go
to the bar.
don't go there.
leave my hand.
ok.
we will make you unconscious with
whisky.
then we will left you naked after
stealing everything from you,
the garbage truck will take you.
you really want to drink?
yeah.
what is your name?
what you are doing in Delhi?
nothing.
any disease?
nojust asking.
what is the name of this place?
nice drinking place has no name.
cOme Sir.
come here.
you came after a long time, yourtable
is ready.
yea ask...
coke, with vodka.
l can deliver at you home.
write, one whisky, one vodka, one black
rum, all right..
andjinn..
notjinn, jinn made you gay.
kill a cat in Delhi, eat it but don't pet it
it will cost a lot, have to pay the?
very good
Sattu, l need a car, please tell that to?
stOp it
l'm in Delhi, let's meet sometime
where can we meet?
Where?
l'm right here
Has your brother returned?
from honeymoon?
yeah! he is
Than should l fetch you from your place?
hanging up now!
see yOu!
Where are you?
you should have told me
You should have told me
l would have brought the car
Where are we going?
My hotel
What will we do there?
Yes master, say?
l need a gal.
-Where did you take herthat night?
Today is Saturday
COme!
Have opened a suite foryou
Sit sit..?
sit.. be comfortable
She is already with someone
You need a regular or...
Took 15 minutes
Last time you slept in the middle
l'm Chanda
l'm Dev
Can l have a drink?
Why?
Will take bath from it
Should l?
Vodka please
Mini bar is separately charged
Why are you so angry?
l can cool you down in 2 minutes
Shall we?
- NO
Why not?
Yourface has made me off.
Am l that ugly?
Even mOre
Then where's the pretty one?
Want it?
Why are you wearing the school girl outfit?
''All American gals'' watched that series?
Want tO see?
Have watched a lot in UK
Really! So were you in UK?
London
Don't tell anybody l did this
Don't want a queue outside
Holy God! seems like you earned the whole?
What did you do?
l was about to eat when...
Move What happened? What happened?
What happened?
Tell.. come on tell
Chanda what happened inside?
come on tell
lf he will come again l will
fall in love with him
Already half way in it
What happened?
What?
Why do they let drunk people get on the bus?
Sir, ticket please
Just look at your age
You drink and get in fights
Don't your parents say something about it?
lf l had a son like you
l would have beaten the hell out of him
Would have make him come in to senses
What are you staring at?
Haven't you seen a woman before?
He ate it
What!
l'm here
Go to showroom
Get whatever coloryou like
Are you alright?
l am alright
Come meet us son if you get time
Let me talk to him
l am hanging up
He hung up
Why don't you tell him that you are ill?
More so you brought him a new car
Let it be
He is young.. let it go
You have spoiled him a lot for no reason
You spoiled him in childhood
l did it in his youth
What happened to him?
Need to talk to Paro
Dev! it's 11 pm
lt's important
She is sleeping
Then wake her up
Dev! l also need to talk to you
About Rasika. Shall l talk to
you oryourfather?
Will call you later
What is this? You drink like this?
You room is so dirty
When was the last time you took bath?
l love you a lot
You stink
First take a shower, then we will talk
l have made a mistake
Go, take showerfirst
GO!
Oh my god! Such a dirty towel
l am getting a new one
Can't you change it by yourself?.
Ma'am he never leaves the key at reception
And when we ask he tells to come later
Madam, bed sheet.
- here.
Bring the carton and put
rest of the bottles in it.
Anything else?
- NO.
Here.
How long you haven't washed your
clothes. How can you stay so dirty?
l love you Paro.
Rasika has told me everything.
Rasika is lying.
- l know everything.
lt good that l got married, waiting
foryou would have been useless.
Are you happy?
Yes.
Bhuan Jee is a good man.
l would have called Dev Jee
if we would've got married.
Let the clothes stay in there for
a while.
What do you want?
- l said l love you.
l want to love you.
Peoplejust love.
What's wanting to love?
What happened?
Next time call me in the day time.
Are you really happy?
He has two kids.
- They're lovely, they love me very much.
You don't love me.
You can't love anyone but
yourself.
You should get married to this
mirror, bathroom mirror.
Don't drink too much.
Some things you get very fond of
that you hate everything else.
l'm going home.
Forget about me.
And go and take care of your work.
And you go take care of you
old husband.
He's old by age.
But not in bed.
Then what are you doing here? You
should've stayed on top your old superman.
With him l don't need to be
On tOp.
Making fun of me?
NO.
Just reminding you of your place.
What happened?
Would you say something?
Your lover very depressed.
He threw his purse at me.
Don't let him go, keep him with
you. 10 days, 15 days.
Until then l'll empty his purse.
Give me his purse.
Are you in love?
You'll get your money.
Give me his purse.
She's gone mad.
- Keep mouth shut, you pimp.
His purse.
Did you sleep?
There's coffee in the coffee maker.
What's your story?
- StOry?
l mean, how did you...
- Become a whore?
l have a client.
He can't even say whore.
Saying whore is out of fashion.
She did the right thing.
You don't love her.
l love her.
- Then you would've been with her.
When you found out that lt was
yourfault, there was still time.
But your ego is biggerthan you,
not once you told herto stop.
l'm okay since l accepted it all.
Are you okay?
- You say that l'm not okay.
Whateveryou say.
You're the boss.
What are you so happy?
What else l should do?
Tell me.
l have ears.
Why are you taking her side?
She's right.
-what?
She's happy.
People move on.
l have.
People used to look at like l'm
a murderer, No one used to talk to me.
lf the whole world has seen me.
what was l suppose to do?
How did they find out that it was me?
MMS was never shown on TV.
Nor my photo was published
anywhere.
Because everybody downloaded it.
Everybody had fun watching it.
lnstead of me being a father,
lnstead of hugging me...
...and telling me that it's alright
child, forget about what happened.
He shot himself.
Look at me.
lt's alright child, forget about what
happened, everything will be alright.
How much?
Keep the change.
yes.
l love her very much.
Still?
FOrever.
Chanda l love you too you know.
You're such a slut.
Sleep more if you want.
Where are you going?
College.
Will you be here when l come back?
Do you know one thing?
-What?
Her name is ParO.
He love her. He doesn't think
about you. He'sjust fucking you.
Why are you doing this?
Once a women likes the taste.
Then she isn't worth spending life
with.
Meaning?
- Remember l said.
ln Delhi, Kill the cat,
eat the cat.
Oryou'll have to pay the price
with your heart.
she will come in afternoon.
its already afternoon!
you? yeah l have talked to you, you
ask me for my photo.
when she will come by the way?
l can get eraser here right? by the way
my medical certificate is okay.
this foryour slut.
and that's for who?
you left the door open?
what you remember?
Sattu.
check your statement,
sign it.
we will have further discussion in
the way.
now you listen what l am saying.
you have to understand one thing.
can we stop some where, l have some
work.
what work?
l want to tell my friend that l am
all right.
she don't have phone.
come quick.
what are you doing here? don't come
inside, you will get me in trouble.
ljust need a rum, l will pay you
later.
nOW gO.
all right buddy,
don't come again.
l don't want money, your work has done.
you go, you work has done.
here's your medical report.
your bale can be cancel anytime.
just because the death of father, you
got this chance, don't spoil it.
you are going there only for his funeral,
afterthat you have to go to Delhi.
and then you cant leave Delhi.
and when you go there make attendance
in the police station.
there is my guarantee in court,
you understand?
what you have done? why you
have done it?
you were such a nice kid, why you are
doing this to yourself, you have everything.
its better if they put him inside and
nevertake him out ofjail.
here is some money, give it to advocate.
and for me?
gO..
you don't love me, you can love no one
but yourself.
go spoil someone else home, you are
don't suitable for our home.
are you making fun of me?
l am showing you your worth.
you know one thing?
what is your name?
My name is Sadpal Singh.
let do one thing.
why not we go somewhere else for
picnic,
we will have drink.
drinking, eating and staying on me.
make you throat wet.
take all the money.
leave me Delhi again.
you will leave me to Delhi?
lets move from here.
you are sad?
l love her very much.
here's the bill.
here's your bill, take out the money.
what happen?
bar is closed..
l cant have one more?
nO. nO.. get Out nOW.
all right.
200, 300..
here it is.
what happen? are you looking for
the wallet?8
no, someone must have cut your
pocket.
check in the bag,
there is nothing.. you check.
its expensive,
it don't look like expensive.
let me see thejacket.
there is nothing..
you can get your money by selling
both of them.
throw him out.
cOme, get up.. mOve.
mOve.. mOve.. get up.
don't come here again.
let's go inside.
you have any thing to drink?
what is your name?
from today your name is Dwage.
yOur Or mine?
Hello.. Dev..
is Chanda there?
she is gone.
you are safe, there is still time,
learn something.
otherwise you would lost like that
guy.
you must have any photo of her..
then from where she came on the
railway station?
there must be some place where she
could go.
be right back.
greeting Sir.
remember me?
where are you looking? yeah she will
cOme.
take it.
l don't love Paro.
even l never look her carefully.
when you left from there?
some day when you left.
why?
you get this for me right?