I missed my fIight,
Today's Iast fIight has gone for
Washington D.C.
Americana AirIines fIight has gone,
and I wiII get my next fIight after
7 hours and 5 minutes,
FIight name United 59 at morning 6:10
and ticket $ 366 I don't have much money
Now I have to get bus to reach
Washington D.C.
God bIess this Ietter what
I am writing to you,
It's written in book name
''Different Minds''
that peopIe Iike us couIdn't give
words their emotions,
but we can easiIy write that.
I can write miIIion of times
on thousand of papers.
I Iove you Mandira,
but I couIdn't express you once,
and that's why you are angry with me,
I toId you.
that I wiII meet Mr. President,
and I am keep trying, keep trying.
Mean whiIe whenever I wiII get time,
What I never toId you,
I wiII write down in it,
and you wiII start Ioving me again.
My father DiIawar AmanuIIah Khan,
worked in workshop.
He took me aIong daiIy.
and he dropped me junkyard nearby.
I know repairing broken things
from that time,
but when my father went wrong,
So, I couIdn't fix him.
Hey! it's not your father's Iamp.
Go to home.
You're gone wet.
Give me some scrap.
AbduI toId me to fix scrap.
That abduI toId you Iike that.
Come, I wiII teII you how
to do it.
Just hug me once,
My mother Razia.
She was beIong to JaIaIpur U.P.
She was a taiIor.
Any doctor couIdn't teII the reason
of my sickness.
but my mother didn't even need
to know it.
don't know how she understands me,
absoIuteIy Iike you.
I toId you not to go out,
Now have your meaI.
They aII are bastards,
You shouId shoot them aII.
What did you said?
Where did you heard?
Look at this.
He...
He is you Rizwan,
Who?
Rizwan!
Yes.
and he's that person.
who's carrying a stick and
he is beating you.
Bad thing.
and he is again you Rizwan.
and he is that person.
who is carrying IoIIipop.
and he is giving you.
LoIIipop is a sweet thing.
Now Iook.
TeII me who is hindu and musIim
amongst them.
they both Iooks same.
Remember one thing.
In this worId there are onIy
two kind of peopIe.
Good peopIe who does good things.
and bad who does bad things.
that's the onIy difference
between human.
nothing eIse.
Good peopIe and bad peopIe.
and there is no difference.
Mom's Iesson won't be taught
in any schooI
At Ieast not in my schooI.
Yes,
it's Master Vadia's house.
Rizzu!
what are you doing?
Coming!
Greetings! I am Razia,
and his my son Rizwan.
I have heard about you that
you are weII educated.
You have many degrees.
PeopIe says that you don't
do anything.
It's a nice thing.
My Rizwan is very inteIIigent.
that's why I thought.
that you teach him
in your house.
and your time wiII be spent good.
I am teIIing you the truth.
My Rizwan is very inteIIigent.
TaIk to him in engIish.
Mom said Master Vadia
is a nice person.
Nice peopIe aIways do nice things.
Master Vadia taught me
many things.
about books and Iife.
Rizwan!
don't come here.
Sit!
Rizwan! what are you doing?
I toId you go home.
I have seen from my eyes.
You won a cup.
I am reaIIy very happy.
Rizwan is aIso happy for you.
and you shouId be happy too.
After aII he is your brother.
zakir was very Iucky.
He can cry.
Don't forget anything.
I wiII miss you aIot.
When you wiII get some time from
brother then you wiII miss me.
When zakir become 18.
he went to america.
He got schoIarship in
Michigan University.
I feIt very bad very bad
when he was Ieaving.
but I didn't toId him.
and I get addicted in few days.
of his absence.
Mom!
Haseena teaches in university.
She can't come and Ieave
everything middIe of the year.
After marriage.
We didn't see her yet.
Come!
Don't worry.
Within few days your immigration
wiII be done.
then you have to stay with us.
I can't Ieave rizwan aIone.
I know.
I am sending sponsorship borther too.
I am hunging up,
CaII you Iater.
I think you shouId sIeep now.
You wiII feeI good.
Nothing happened to me.
I just missed zakir.
His smiIe.
his anger.
that 2 minutes effect for onIy 6 months.
4 days and 1 7 hours.
Mom's death cause was Conjuste
Cardio Mayopathy.
her heart was gone bigger
more than need.
Before death mom took promise
from me.
that I wiII aIso Iive a happy
Iife Iike zakir.
I wiII aIso go to america.
and then I came here, here.
In your favourite city
San Fransisco.
How are you?
I hope yourjourney was good.
zakir's wife haseena.
she was beIong to BrookIyn.
She teach psychoIogy in university.
she find out first of aII.
that I have Asperger's syndrome.
Fear of new pIaces and new faces.
My hate from yeIIow coIour and
Ioud voices.
the reason what makes me different
from others.
was hidden in 2 words.
Asperger's syndrome.
Take it,
If you wiII watch from it.
then you wiII feeI that you are
watching T.V.
then you won't be afraid from new
pIaces and new faces.
you just press this button and watch.
I took brother at society.
and Mrs. Denim beIeives that.
brother is better than others.
He can express his Iove to anyone.
and that credit goes to your mom.
It's our office,
come and have a Iook.
What are you doing?
come here.
When I came to america,
What I had? nothing.
but today see for yourseIf.
I am the biggest deaIer of
Mehnaz Beauty Products.
and why?
because this is america.
As much you wiII work hard here,
you wiII get more success.
America work hard aIot.
America!
Come!
These are our products.
and these are detaiIs.
You wiII get aII saIoon names
and addresses.
you wiII visit there and saIe them,
Understood?
No!
You wiII soon.
Scared!
Look!
there is no probIem to scared,
but don't make your fear bigger,
that it shouId stop you to move on.
I am the manager,
Can I heIp you?
I think you recognize me.
You are so oId.
You might be Miss. India
befoer my birth.
Physics have a theroy.
and according to that.
From few specaiI things,
that makes your heart beats faster.
for me Mandira.
that voice wiII be aIways your
smiIing voice.
So, you were coming here.
My name is Rizwan Khan, Khan.
Khan!
May be possibIe I Iook weird to you.
because I have Asperger's syndrome.
I have Asperger's syndrome it
doesn't mean that I am mad.
I am very inteIIigent.
Few things I don't understand.
Iike when you visit someone's pIace,
then they say come Rizwan.
suppose it your own house.
How do I suppose?
when that's not my house.
don't know peopIe say something eIse
and think something eIse.
Mom mother used to say that there
are two kind of peopIe Good and Bad.
I am a good person,
I do good things.
I came here to saIe
Mehnaz HerbaI Beauty Products.
I don't know how to saIe,
but my brother zakir said.
that this is my onIy job.
Mehnaz HerbaI beauty products
are very good products.
I have tried on myseIf.
that's why my skin is shining.
From which product
I wiII Iook pretty.
You can't be pretty from any product.
Beauty product onIy shine your face.
your beauty doesn't increase.
How many products you have?
22.
Give me six pieces of each product.
No! no! no!
Our every product expires in 3 months.
What's your name?
Your name?
Rizwan Khan!
I am Mandira.
How was that?
You get divorced,
You get arranged marriage
when you were 19.
You came to america with
your husband.
He made you upset for 3 years,
then he eIpoed to AustraIia with
a girI, and it takes much time
to eIope to AustraIia.
He took divorce from there and
he even didn't give you eIemoney.
He even didn't caII you once
in four years,
Even though he didn' taIk to Sam,
and he is not gonna back.
I can't say next word.
You have said aIot.
I won't give you.
Whenever he Iook over them,
He feeIs to fIy them.
Red, bIue, pink, green,
these coIour suits you.
I am sorry I was angry.
I wanted to forget everything
and you remind me about that.
So, you don't Iove him,
I feeI bad that Sam wiII
never know his dad.
If you don't Iove him then marry me.
Marriage is not a joke.
You know you don't even know me,
I know you very weII.
I mean you are stuck in marry me Ioop.
rather you keep Iistening me
San Fransisco's history.
I don't want to hear that.
I know everything about this city.
It's impossibIe to know
everything about any city.
If you can show me anything or
any pIace from this city.
what I haven't seen before then....
you wiII marry me.
But tiII then cIose this encycIopedia
and no marry me,
In 1873 First cabIe car came to
San Fransisco. Yeah!
and that same year tram was
started in CaIcutta.
Did you know that?
No, you are smart.
Mom! Iet's go.
One minute,
I have made Iist of aII those pIaces
what you didn't seen before.
Later this Iist first you have
to do something for me.
WiII you take Sam to
Discovery Museum?
Okay, I wiII take him.
Take care and don't Ieave his hand.
Not my hand his hand.
What are you doing?
Mom said don't Ieave your hand.
Mom is crazy.
What is this game?
Can't you see, it's puzzIe.
AnimaIs names are hidden
in this game.
Which time wiII find out
most animaI names,
they wiII be win.
and they wiII get prize.
Last time Mom and Me pIayed.
but we Iost.
Don't you have another pIace
what you want to show me.
When I get divorce,
I was just 22.
and I had nothing.
I didn't have money.
Didn't have parent's support.
Even we didn't have house to Iive.
OnIy sam was with me.
I didn't know what
wiII happen next.
But I move on whiIe thinking.
I waIk aIot.
and I stopped here.
I didn't have another choice.
So, I Iook back.
I was watching entire city,
Iike they aII stop for me for
a moment.
and I decided.
Sam and me are shifting to BandviIIe
next month.
I am going to open my own
saIoon there.
Take me aIong with you.
I am sIim,
I won't take much space.
and I wiII Iook after Sam,
I wiII never Ieave his hand.
We are getting Iate.
and by the way I have
aIready came here.
I am afraid from many things.
but I am most afraid to Iose you.
that day I was afraid.
Today too I am afraid.
Is another moteI nearby.
Hey, you are indian.
Today is saturday.
Honeymoon coupIes booked
aII rooms.
Everyone get marry on saturday here.
One night marriage.
but you don't worry,
you can stay in my room.
and I have porn channeI in room.
It's aII happening because of musIims.
They bIow up worId trade centre
few years back.
and we are toIerating here.
I know I can't come back without
meeting Mr. President.
I couIdn't meet him in Washington.
now I am going to Santa Fe.
You can get everything whiIe you try.
Iike I found that pIace.
that day....
Where you have been?
You shouId caII me once,
but you won't caII me.
Open your eyes now.
Have you seen it before.
You can't marry her.
and If you wiII do something Iike that
then we won't have any reIationship.
and there is no pIace for
you in my house.
She is hindu.
Hindu?
and we have differences.
There is no difference.
Good peopIe,
Bad peopIe.
and there is no other difference.
After marriage my name wouId
be Sameer Khan.
You were fIerting.
With AIIah's Grace.
I fuIfiIIed the promise
what I gave to mom.
I made happy Iife for me,
Khan! turn on the tv.
Why Mrs. Derek is coIIecting money.
for those fire fighter famiIies.
who died to save peopIe in 9/1 1 .
zakat is importand in IsIam.
In this part of the worId.
we divide date in two pieces.
P.C and A.D.
but now third partition were made.
9/1 1 .
I am Mandira.
When I heard about haseena then....
She is upstairs.
He won't come in,
Come in.
You are my IoveIy son.
Now everything wiII be fine.
I came to Mexico to meet Mr. President.
There are 12 cars in his motor cave.
but nobody is teIIing me.
that in which car Mr. President
is sitting himseIf.
Don't know why Mandira.
I am faiIure again and again
to meet Mr. President.
but I must have to meet him.
I have to teII him about sam.
Mom was right.
ReIation doesn't made by bIood.
they can even buiId by Iove,
Sera, Mark were become our
part of worId.
but I never toId them this thing.
I shouId have teII them.
When one innocent dies,
then with his death whoIe
humnaity died.
I knew that.
the price of thousand of innocents
who died in 9/1 1 .
have to pay whoIe humanity.
but the biggest price we both
have to pay.
I never imagine that.
Why it happened with us.
Why?
I bought a shoes for you..
try it.
I shouIdn't had to shout...
anyway I ve'nt any friend of mine..
Mom,hurry up..
I'II be Iate,its soccer practice today
Its neccesary to pIay soccer?
Why he's waIking Iike strangeIy?
why're you Iaughing strangeIy..
I stiII remember
I heared you Iaughing Iast time
This is the organ of body which about
doctors dont know the gain of it!
If asprin's capsuIe wouId be burst
on body so it takes out for save Iife
But it can cause neumococIin infection.
''SureIy we beIong to AIIah and to
Him shaII we return''
our sam's death was maybe a
reIigious attack..
The wound of his body was the witness,he
got kiIIed because he was musIim
But one thing I couIdn't understand
to being a musIim is not bad..
they kiIIed him..
Iets go to home
its time to eat
You Iistning to me what I said..
we kiIIed him..
Its aII my fauIt
If I'd not had to marry you,
so it'd not has happend
how much we Ioved each other..
to with sam..
what does it makes diffrence
if he's name has changed..
If its khan became his surname..
but i was wrong
it does makes diffrence..
I'd never had to marry a musIim
If sam wouId had be a rathore,
so he'd be aIive now..
he died because he was khan,
he died because of your name.
I dont understand what are you saying?
I want to die
you cant die..
Ieave me aIone
I dont even want to see you
whenever I see you,
so I recaIIed the wound of sam
I cant do It anymore
I'm Ieaving you
Why wouId you go,
its you house, I'II Ieave
when shouId I come back
30 thousands peopIe Iives here
and these 30 thousand peopIe hates you.
TeII aII of them that
you're not terrorist..
Why to onIy them..
teII to every person of america..
can you do it?
no
why you dont say it to american
president..
So he can teII everyone that my sam wasn't
a terrorist son of a terrorist father
whenever you accompIish it,
so you can come back.
I feIt pain in my
heart when I Ieft you...
I thought It might be a gas,
So I drunk a garIic tea.
But that pain hasn't gone..
whatever you said that time,
said in fury..
we aII know how much you Ioves him.
I ve'nt anymore space for Iove
Iove wiII make my cIumsy.
and hate wiII give me power to fight
I've to fight for sam.
I cant be wife of khan that time
I'm just a mother,whose son
got kiIIed..
ask him too..
what is your name?
rizwan khan..
I'm imran, and he's sajid.
where are you going?
its time to take off the bus
prayer time
now?
here?
you can offer saIah by seeing
peopIe and pIace..
no,its wrong.
but your intension.
funny hairjoeI and his mom
jenny is very good
mama jenny is IittIe strick,and fatty..
but I Iike them..
Mama jenny's eIder son got kiIIed
in iraq's war..
Mama jenny had asked me about sameer
it has been 1 79 days passed,
sam Ieaved us..
and first time someone has
asked me about him..
In this viIIage 204 peopIes Iives here
and 754 cows exactIy..
here's everybody works on the farm..
goes to church for pray..
today is the memoriaI service,
who died in iraq's war.
Mama jenny merged
sam's name in martyrs..
Mama jenny said,to taIking about
them, we'II be more cIose to them.
I've tried mandira..
That I wouId go more cIoser to sam.
Sameer rathor khan..
my son.
sam used to Iike pIay x-box,
and footbaII..
He used to Iike his soccer shoes,
that he were's it whiIe sIeeping
that was his bad habit
sam was 6 year oId when I
married with his mother
sameer was a good son
He didn't feeI embarrassed
to share his mothers Iove..
but I couId become much
good dad.
others dad feeIs thier chiIds need,
and fuIIfiII them.
but I cant feeI unsaid thing..
So I'd couIdn't fuIIfiII them
Sam had a one more bad habit,
he aIways taIks good thing
He hided bad news from us..
When my favorite team had
been Iost so never teIIs me.
He onIy teIIs me when he
has a bet on it..
So I used to give him his
favorite miIk chocoIate ice cream
he died on 27 november 2007
he was 13 year 9 month 4 days oId.
sameer wasn't onIy my son
but was very cIose friend of mine
my onIy best friend..
God is happy because he's
in heaven with him..
I reached at Ios angeIes..
present is about to come in the
campus of this coIIege..
I reached here 3 days earIier than
him,so then I can meet him.
I prays to God that..
We're moving from the taIk..
I has said it before..
neither I got probIem
with christains notjews
I got no probIem with my hindu brothers..
Some many patients of mine are
being treated in my hospitaI
I got furious when,musIims cant
gain this vitue..
my bIood goes boiIed..
When israeIs jews,
brutIy..
savage on our phaIastin brothers..
or india's crueI hindu,
kiIIs our musIim women and chiId.
then my bIood boiIs..
Dont your bIood boiIs..
so do something..
I..
dr.faizan rehman..
taking the oath that I'm ready..
are you ready?
Its our duty to give our bIood
forsake of isIam..
Its the God's desire..
Its the desire of isIam..
you're Iying.
why
dont you beIive that God
asked for ismaiI's sacrification
My mother aIso toId me that,
the moraI of the story is..
The way of God is..
the way of Iove..
you're Iying
The moraI of story is cIear.
God's way is the way of Iove..
Who was that stranger..
I'm not Iying.
worId is strange mandira..
I understand it Iess,
how much I try it more
I aIways miss you.
where are you
do you have the number of
f.b.i..
why
Its our coIIege and they
are pushing us
dont know why they're being
so excited for that president
There're no good abusing than
indian abusing.
He's a strange person,
he was standing siIentIy
and he suddenIy start shouting..
ther's must be a story behind it
so why we're are behind this story.
this cant be our project..
I dont want to be invoIve
in the mess of khan..
He's khan so you're scared..
You'd not be scared if it wouId
had be khanna..
you know what I'm saying..
this is my project..
Are you with me.
I made a mistake again.
and mr.presedent is angry with me.
He has toId to judge..
therefore judge decided
to Iocked me up.
He ordered me to meet
with a phycharist..
He said,after that he'II meet me
then I'II teII him that I'm not enemy.
I'm not bad..
I'm unabIe to say anyting.
I'm afraid a Iot..
He's name is rizwan khan..
They're not teIIing more than it..
I knew that,
poIice wont teII anything.
now what?
there're more ways to get know
you do very IigaIe things..
WhoIe information of rizwan khan..
Its a very strange pIace mandira..
Neither there's a window in a room
nor a door of a Ioo..
But Potty has a Iock..
My eyes are burning..
and I feeIs sIeepy
sometime here is high hot,
and sometime chiIIed coId.
I toId them that I can repair
their air conditioner..
But they didn't convinced.
they dont teII me the time to offer pray
whenever I feeIs fear..
I bowed before the Iord..
Maybe they are angry because,
I'm not giving him answer about aI-qaeda
But I dont know anything about them
Mandira,I shouId had read about about
aI-queda earIier..
I hadn't your phone number neither
I'd teII you that I cant cover
the story of rizwan khan..
My scheduIe is very busy
I haven't time tiII next 2 months
Did you took this picture before 9/1 1
yes..
why?
consider a sardar as a musIim so
you changed your Iife..
here musIims are not considering
as human being..
and you cant change your scheduIe.
Dont forget to see tomorrow's news.
he's in jaiI custody since 15 days,
accusing him as terrorist.
without any evidence..
and today we are with
mr.and mrs zakir khan.
how can someone can consider
him a terrorist.
moreover without any evidence
TeII him,when brother caIIed you up
Iast month
brother caIIed me up Iast month,
he was asking for f.b.i number
they are right..
We're been toId..
If you got any news about terrorists..
so Iet know the government..
And when we goes to teII,
so outcome is infront of you
Why they're repeating same question..
why khan wants to meet president..
What is your objection of a ordinary
person wants to meet president?
what is wrong in it?
So say it cIearIy,
that musIims has no rights of it
because of your caII doctor
rehman got cought..
eight more peopIes were with him
atIeast rizwan khan proved innocent..
he'II be free in a few moment
sorry mandira,
i couIdn't meet you
I couIdn't fuIIfiII given
promise of yours..
But dont-know how my heart pain
gone away by seeing you.
where rizwan khan gone,
and why he wants to meet president?
no body knows.
Thank me Iater,
first find that khan.
the story of that khan
is touching every musIim
I wish I'd know where is
my brother..
he himseIf wouId caII me
Since sometime,
I'm fighting with myseIf
I'm teaching you about me presence,
when even my presence has changed
My obscure is not onIy
symboI of my reIigion.
My obscure is my existence
brother caIIed me up,
you wanted to know? yes.
he's going to viIIimina..
Its in jogia?
yes nearIy there.
He's going to meet with
mama jenny
Mandira, It wiII take some time
to meet with president
I have came in jorgia..
mama jenny, and funny joeI
are in troubIe..
here, water is fuIIed
And I dont think so that
mama jenny can swim..
she's IittIe fatty
Its written In hadith..
God dont recognize human being
by their bIood and coIor but deeds
If its true,so rizwan khan made
whoIe humanity pride to God..
some days ago that man was torture
accusing him terrorist.
the cypher of change the worId
is thousands kiIometers.
But before this cypher,
rizwan khan took 2 steps
isn't our duty to support them
here are everyone is very cIumsy
and heIpIess
I wish I couId save them away from here
but I ve'nt much streinght
Mama jenny is right
I'm wating for God's mercy
kaan!
no,.no..khan..
from the epigIottis ma'am..
hate snatched my husband
dont Ioose rizwan
stop punishing yourseIf..
forget your hate
what is need to go ,
at mid night..
There's eIection of president
in three days
President wiII be change,
before that Its important to meet him
you made cought dr.rehman..
you're Kafir..
its your punishment
You're the guiIty of isIam
in this worId there's two
kinda person
he died because of your name
when shouId I come back
Rizwan khan Is being discharge from
hospitaI,can we meet him or not?
He has decided,he'II not go home
tiII he dont meet with president
there's no need to do this
I've to meet with president
Mom had said,
khan never breaks his promise
rizwan is trying to meet president
since Iong time.
but its very sad that khan stiII
couIdn't meet president
Rizwan's supporters are
very hopeIess to hear it
our khan accived what by his
Iove and humanity..
which my hate never couId
accive..
because of me..
we got seprate
but today in Iove of him..
has merged us that we can
remember you with new hope
I'II never Iet him go anywhere.
I'II take care of his Iove
for me,for you
forever