When the union's
inspiration through
the workers' blood shall run
there can be
no power greater
anywhere beneath the sun
yet what force
on earth is weaker
than the feeble
strength of one?
But the union
makes us strong
solidarity forever
for the union
makes us strong
...Of unprecedented violence
and with
the strike now entering
its fourth month,
the government today insisted
that it will push ahead
with plans to close 20 pits
with the loss of
over 20,000 jobs,
an action that
Mr. scargill says
will destroy
entire communities.
You can
look back in 10 years
and you can say, "in 1984,
I was proud and privileged
"to be a party
to the greatest
struggle on earth."
I left my number.
Just in case.
Everything's at stake for me.
I'm 27 year old. Right?
Maybe see you on the march,
then?
I'm fighting for their
jobs for future,
not just for me own.
We've used us savings up,
we've no money left.
All we've got now is us pride
and self-respect
and we'll carry
on keeping that.
The prime minister today
defended her position.
I can't change my style.
It has to be a style
of firm leadership.
One isn't here to be a softie.
You're here to be a good,
firm leader.
Hey, mark,
do you want to play ball?
Tomorrow, buddy.
Here you go, mark.
Great. Thanks.
I've spoken to the council
about your deviant parties.
There's no need to do that.
Just knock on the door,
we'd let you in.
They're sending a policeman.
Oh, I do hope so.
Mark.
Thanks.
...The riot squad,
the helmeted policemen
with their plastic shields,
were deployed
after smoke bombs
were thrown.
The violence continued...
Thanks, dad.
At one stage,
the pickets nearly broke
through the police barricade.
Two, four, six, eight!
Is that copper
really straight?
Two, four, six, eight!
Is that copper
really straight?
Two, four, six, eight!
Is that copper
really straight?
Two, four, six, eight!
Is that copper
really straight?
Two, four, six, eight!
Oi, grab hold of this,
will you, mate?
Oh, no, sorry.
Just for five minutes,
till me friends get here.
Come on.
It... it's just that I don't
really want to be too visible.
Is it your first pride?
Yeah,
first anything.
Yeah, well,
this is the best way.
You need to throw yourself in.
The thing is
is that I'm actually
from bromley.
Well, don't worry about that,
we're a broad church.
No, I mean,
it's the train.
It's further out
than people think and I...
Oi,
I've been dragging this thing
on me own
since marble arch.
What, are they buckets?
Surprised you have
to ask that question,
Mike, coming from accrington.
Mike, does anything
get rid of love bites?
No. Where's mark now?
Right,
listen up, everyone.
Where exactly
have you been?
I want everyone
to take a bucket
and start rattling.
This is for the miners.
Miners?
We agreed on a banner, mark.
It's a show of solidarity.
Who hates the miners?
Thatcher.
Who else? The police,
the public and
the tabloid press.
That sound familiar?
Surely, mark...
The only problem we've got
that they haven't
is Mary whitehouse.
And that can only
be a matter of time.
Mark...
I know, it's not been planned.
It's not been thought through
but it's a really
good idea, isn't it?
Isn't it?
What am I supposed
to do with this?
Give it to the lesbians.
They love a banner.
Oh, for God's sake.
Right, looks like you're
off the hook, mate. Good lad.
Whatever
mark says, we do it.
Don't ask me why.
Disgusting.
Yes.
We're collecting
for the miners
and their families, guys.
Gays and lesbians
support the miners
and their families.
I was wondering,
do you need a hand?
Well, well,
if it isn't bromley.
I mean, my last train
is actually not for ages.
Gays and lesbians
support the miners.
...support the miners.
Guys,
support the miners.
Gays and lesbians
- Collecting for the miners.
- Dig deep.
Support the miners.
Come on.
Support the miners!
It's just a couple
of the lads
from college
and one of them
lives in chislehurst.
So he can't be
too late, either.
I've got my key.
Just mind yourself
on that last train.
There's weirdos and
all sorts on there.
Thanks, mum.
It makes none,
but now you have gone
and you must be
looking very old tonight
the devil will find work
for idle hands to do
I stole and I lied and why?
Because you asked me to
but now you make me
feel so ashamed
Oi, bromley.
Over here.
I'm hiding
from that girl.
Why?
She broke my heart
at a smiths concert.
I've never met
a lesbian before.
Really?
I've never met anyone
who irons their jeans.
I live at home.
No shit.
Is that where you got
that lovely broach?
That's embarrassing.
It's today.
What are you, 10?
I'm 20.
I wouldn't go
spreading that around.
You're illegal,
darling.
Sixteen for the breeders,
21 for the gays.
Did you learn
nothing on that march?
You're still a minor.
Jesus.
Victory to the minors.
Don't make a mess, okay?
They've counted it.
Well, come on,
you've collected
as much as anyone.
Stephanie.
Were you with Jeff
in the bell last night?
For fuck's sake.
It's a bruise, okay?
My neck is bruised.
No red wine
on the floor, please.
Ashtrays.
It was a pretty
good march today.
Not much in the way
of beatings or abuse.
Hardly any petrol bombs
or swastikas.
Is it me or are
the police getting soft?
It's funny.
They've stopped hanging
around outside
our clubs lately.
What's that about?
Do you think
they've finally got sick
of all that Donna summer?
No, never!
My guess is they
went somewhere else.
To pick on someone else.
My guess is that
while we're enjoying
a temporary reprieve,
they're here.
Giving these poor sods
the shit we usually get.
Now, these mining communities
are being bullied
just like we are.
Right?
Bullied by the police.
Bullied by the tabloids.
Bullied by the government.
Do any of them need a hug?
No. What they need is cash,
and they need it urgently.
Yeah, because the miners have
always come to our aid,
haven't they?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Why don't we talk about today?
Today, with only
a couple of buckets,
we raised nearly 200 quid.
Right,
think what we could achieve
if we really started trying.
I'm from durham.
Well, you know exactly
what we're
talking about, then.
I know those bastards
kicked the shit out of me
every morning on
my way to school
and every night
on my way home.
We are
proposing to meet
at least once a week.
And just to do
as many collections as we can.
Oh, and...
And we've got a name.
Lgsm.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
It's not very catchy.
It's a support group, Steph,
not a skiffle band.
Right, come on.
Let's have a show
of hands, shall we?
Who's in?
Guys?
Come on, guys,
please.
Oh, come on, guys.
Is that it?
We've actually been
looking for things
that we could do together
as a... as a couple.
Well, this is perfect.
Youse can
feed the miners
and your relationship.
How many's that?
That's six.
It's better than five.
Not as good as seven.
Jonathan.
Oh, God.
Here come the gay libbers.
Brilliant party, geth.
I'm sure you could use
the back room here
if you're looking
for a base, that is.
We are... uh, we are.
That's amazing,
gethin, thank you.
Well,
what about me and Jonathan?
Or is it exclusively
for the under-25s?
Oh, no, of course not.
Everyone's welcome.
touch me, baby,
tainted love
are you sure
Jonathan's interested?
He's at a bit of a loose end
at the moment.
He just needs something
to occupy him. A project.
What about
bromley over there?
I've... I've just started
catering college.
Good.
Congratulations, all of you.
You're the founder members
of lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Terrific.
Let's bring down
the government.
Support for the miners.
Give generously.
Put your hand in your pockets
for the miners.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners!
National union
of mine workers.
Oh, hello.
I represent a group
called lesbians and gays
support the miners and...
Hello? Hello...
And there's
the desired consistency.
It's glossy and wobbly.
Glossy and wobbly.
Jonathan.
Why don't you go
out with them today?
Because I've got
better things to do
than run around
with a bunch of kids.
What happened to
gay lib, Jonathan?
I don't know.
What did happen to it?
Is that gethin's boyfriend?
Jonathan. He stabbed
susannah York
with an ice pick.
He's an actor.
Support the miners.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners, sir.
support the miners.
We've raised money
and we're looking for
a mining community to...
Repeat the name
of the group, please?
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Somebody will
call you back
in due course.
Sure,
but you've said that before
and we...
They'll call back.
They will.
Mark, face it.
They're on strike.
They're busy.
They don't want
to take our money
because we're poofs.
And a dyke.
They'd rather starve.
Maybe we should just
hand the money
over anonymously.
I mean, we don't have to
say we're gay, do we?
No.
Well, at least then
we'd be helping.
No, this is a gay
and lesbian group
and we are unapologetic
about that.
Jesus, why are you even
wasting time with all this?
Mark.
They will call us back.
It has nothing to
do with the fact
that we're poofs.
And a dyke.
They will call us back.
End of meeting.
They're never
going to call us back.
Someone needs to go with him.
First rule of the group.
I'll go.
Thank you, Steph.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Pervert!
First rule of the group,
comrade.
Nobody collects alone.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Lesbians and gays support...
Gethin.
Gethin, come on.
You're supposed
to be a bookshop.
We don't have maps, mark.
It's a gay bookshop.
People ask for the poems
of Walt Whitman.
I hope there's
a good reason why
I've been abandoned
in the street?
Let me just get this right,
so we are going to
pick a mining town
completely at random
and just ring it,
is that the plan, is it, mark?
Yeah, the town hall,
the council.
What, it's as easy as that?
Why not?
We bypass the union
all together.
I think it's inspired.
So do I.
See? Even bromley agrees.
Right, here we go.
A-ha.
So, what do we want? Um...
Somewhere north...
Industrial?
Humberside. Is...
Is that a place?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Give it to me.
If it's miners
you're looking for...
There. Wales.
Of course.
That's a big
fucking coalfield.
That's the brecon beacons.
That's a coalfield, there.
And that is.
All right,
and what are we
supposed to do?
Stick a bloody pin in it?
Do you know people, gethin?
No, I haven't been
back there in 16 years.
Why not?
Well,
let's just say there isn't
always a welcome
in the hillsides.
Shall I get you
the phone book?
Well, what's the worst
that can happen?
Oh, hello.
I represent a bunch of
screaming homosexuals.
May I inquire
about your communal baths?
What's that got to
do with a strike?
Nothing.
I'd just like to inquire.
All right, all right.
Thank you.
All right. Oi!
If we're going to do this,
we need to take it seriously.
Come here.
Right.
0-1-9...
What's the welsh for lesbian?
Hello?
Yes.
I see.
Yes!
Solidarity forever
solidarity forever
it really didn't
occur to you to
get a description?
Well, she were off
the phone that fast.
Maybe we should
try and look
more obviously gay.
Achievable goals,
please, Jeff.
- Shut up. That's him.
- Are you sure?
Oh, my God,
he's coming towards us.
How did you know
it were him?
It's the same
as in a nightclub.
It's all in the eyes.
I'm dai Donovan.
From the dulais valley.
Right.
You must be mark.
Yes, hello.
Hiya. Mike.
Steph.
Hello.
Joe.
Jeff.
Dai.
So, lgsm.
What does that
stand for, then?
You get a garbled message
over the phone.
I thought the l
was for London.
London something.
I never dreamed for a moment
it was l for...
Hi.
This money you've raised,
it's all from gays
and lesbians?
Mostly, yeah.
Right. There we are.
This is just the beginning.
Oh?
Mmm-hmm.
We've got big plans.
Well, I'm not going to
pretend I'm not surprised.
You can see that.
Truth told,
you're the first gays
I've ever met in my life.
As far as you're aware.
That's true.
And you're the first miner
I've ever met.
Yeah.
Now, I... I want you
to do something for me.
I want you to go
back to your community
and convey my thanks.
My personal thanks.
And the thanks
of all the people of dulais.
Yeah,
of course we will.
- Won't we?
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Won't we, mark?
Who fancies a pint?
I'm the shy boy,
you're the coy boy
and you know
we're homosapien, too...
you can have five minutes.
Are you sure about this?
Dead sure.
Yeah, but for dai...
Oh, I'm all right, lad.
Trust me, dai,
if you can handle this,
it's going to make
a huge difference.
What's he going to do,
take his clothes off?
I'm just going
to say thank you.
Well, don't blame me
if you get bottled.
Right, shut up, you fuckers.
Ooh...
Thank you. Right, listen.
Some of you know me.
My name is mark Ashton.
Commie!
I'm going to invite somebody
onto the stage now
who wants to talk to you
and I want you
to listen to him.
He comes from
the dulais valley
in South wales and he, um...
Well, he's a striking miner
and he has something
he wants to say to you.
I've had a...
I've had a lot
of new experiences
during this strike.
Um, speaking in public.
Standing on a picket line.
And now I'm in a...
A gay bar.
Well, if you don't like it,
you can go home.
As a matter of fact,
I do like it.
Ooh.
Beer's a bit expensive,
mind.
But really,
there's only one difference
between this and a bar
in South wales.
The women.
They're a lot more
feminine in here.
What I'd really like to say
to you tonight is thank you.
If you're one of the people
that's put money
in these buckets,
if you've supported lgsm,
then thank you,
because what you've given us
is more than money,
it's friendship.
And when you're in a battle
against an enemy
so much bigger,
so much stronger than you,
well,
to find out you had a friend
you never knew existed,
well, that's the best feeling
in the world.
So, thank you.
When two tribes go to war
a point is all
that you can score
oh, my God.
I haven't even
finished this one.
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Support the miners.
So you're the only girl?
That's right.
I'm the l in lgsm.
Good speech.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I've worked a few
tough crowds myself
over the years.
In politics?
In panto.
Oh, right.
Okay, lgsm,
over here, please.
That's something
else we could use.
What's that?
An official photographer.
Jesus, mark.
We don't even have
an official typewriter.
Nice and close, please.
I could do it.
I've got a camera.
It's a really good one.
I'd be happy to do it.
All right, bromley,
if you're sure.
Course he's sure.
Never let it
be said that lgsm
discouraged youth enterprise.
Right, then.
What are you going
to say, "cheese"?
Victory to the miners!
Martin, come on.
Tell them you've run
a whole canteen before.
You're not just
packing food parcels.
Go.
And don't look
so bloody worried.
It's not
the first day of school.
What do they need
to come here for?
We sent them a thank-you note.
Every other support group
has been invited.
Every other support group was
approved by
the whole committee.
Oh, I see.
Dai had to make
a snap decision.
This is all my fault.
He was in London,
Maureen.
What would you have done?
Told them to keep their money?
I'll tell you exactly
what I would have done...
But they raised
the money.
All right,
I run a civil meeting here.
If you want to
scream and shout,
get on the pickets.
I don't have a problem
with what they are.
None of us do.
It's the men.
Well,
you bring a load of gays
into a working men's club,
you get trouble.
I'm sorry.
No other group
has raised as much money.
I'm not disputing that.
Or been so consistent.
Then why don't you
just invite them?
I'm sorry,
but everyone's saying
they don't have a problem.
Good, they've
raised the most money,
so invite them.
And who the bloody hell
are you?
- You did what?
- I know.
But hefina,
she's like the head honcho,
absolutely terrifying,
well, she obviously
can't stand this Maureen.
Kids, mind the fish fingers.
What's the matter?
You told me not to
sell myself short.
I'm not talking about that.
Gays and lesbians!
We're trying to
fit in here, sian.
What?
Volunteer, I said.
Run the canteen.
They didn't want me
on the canteen.
They wanted me
on the committee.
All right,
so keep your head down.
Do the paperwork.
Don't start
stirring it all up,
inviting a load of
gays and lesbians.
Oh, it's like that, is it?
You know,
I had you down
as many things
but prejudiced was
never one of them.
I'm not prejudiced.
No?
I'm a realist.
I know what small towns
are like, sian.
And I know exactly
how those lads
are going to react.
You think so?
I know so.
I'm standing on
a bloody picket
with them day after day.
It was a majority decision.
The committee decided.
Well, I hope you
and your bloody committee
can guarantee
their safety, sian,
I do, I really do.
All aboard the deviants bus.
No pushing,
no community singing.
And absolutely
no back-chatting the driver.
Right, where are we going?
Wales.
Fuck me.
Someone better roll me
a little spliffette.
What I'd like to know is
what bromley told
his mum and dad.
Yeah.
I just...
Oh, it's no big deal.
Come on.
I said that
I was doing so well at college
they were sending me
on a residential course.
Doing what?
Choux pastry.
Bromley! Bromley! Bromley!
Bit late in the day
for that, isn't it?
That's the fourth one
I've done.
Fast as I put them up,
they pull 'em down.
I'm running out of staples.
Every woman is
a lesbian at heart
every woman is
a lesbian at heart...
you can't possibly say
that every woman is a lesbian.
Why not?
'Cause they're not.
Esther rantzen
isn't a lesbian.
My mum's not a lesbian.
How do you know?
How do I know my mum's
not a lesbian?
What he's trying
to say is you can't
make grand,
sweeping generalizations.
It's not acceptable.
Every woman is
a lesbian at heart
every woman is
including Reggie's mum
Look at the map.
We should have
turned left at that village.
How can
that be a village?
It doesn't have any vowels.
- Hang on a minute.
- Yes?
I think so.
Are we here?
We're here.
Oh, my God.
Come on, let's go.
Right, then.
I guess we just...
I think I'm starting
to freak out slightly.
Dai, your gays have arrived.
Good to see you again.
Good to see you.
Hi, there. Welcome. Welcome.
Come on in, everybody.
Great to see you again.
Great to see you again. Hello.
Come on in.
Welcome, everybody.
This is my wife, Margaret.
Hello.
How are you?
This is Gail and sian,
who wrote to you.
This is hefina,
who chairs
the welfare committee.
This is Gwen,
and this is cliff,
our club secretary.
Um,
I'm going to officiate you.
Oh, good.
Hold that and
name here, please...
Mmm-hmm.
And in the corresponding box,
the group or
organization you represent.
In this case...
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Yep. Quite. Absolutely.
Thank you.
Thank you very much
for having us.
Now, I'm hoping you can
clear something up
for me about lesbians.
Not now, Gwen.
It's something I was told
in the covered market
and to be honest with you,
it did surprise me.
Let them get settled
in first, shall we?
Oh.
Now,
who's making the speech?
A... a speech?
It's no big deal.
One of you just
has to go up on stage
and say a few words.
Just so we know
who you are, like.
I'll tell the band to shut up
and we'll push you on.
And welcome, all of you.
To be honest,
I never thought you'd come.
Anybody else feel like
appointing themselves leader?
Didn't think so.
Many Miles from home
but I'm walking, walking
walking for you
now, then,
ladies and gentlemen.
We're joined once again
by one of our support groups,
lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Will you welcome
their spokesman
onto the stage? Thank you.
Thank you, dai.
Thank you, um...
Falling leaves.
Actually, dai Donovan
made a speech at our local pub
and he's a pretty
tough act to follow,
so maybe now is the moment
for my musical tribute
to Judy garland.
Look, we raised this money
because we want to help you.
And that's it.
And we'll keep on
trying to help you
for as long as you want us to
because we've
been through
some of the same things
you've been through.
Listen,
if one in five people is gay,
then one in five miners
must be, too, right?
So that's at least
a fifth of you
who's pleased to see us.
Thank you.
Thank you for
inviting us here.
Thanks.
One, two, three, four...
Them falling leaves,
they say that summer's done
the wind and rains,
they say so too
but ain't no winter skies'll
ever shadow the sun
while I'm with you
night, everybody.
Goodnight, dai.
There we are. All settled in.
It's teething problems, love.
Everything will be all right
once they start to mix.
I'm not talking
about running away.
I'm talking about
making a dignified exit.
Tomorrow before dawn?
We can't just waltz
into a town like this
and expect them
not to...
Slit our throats?
Just be cautious.
I don't know
about anybody else
but I don't have
to travel to wales
to get my head kicked in.
I can very easily
get that at home.
Anyone who wants
to go should go.
But I came here to help.
Yeah, but they
don't want your help.
Well, they can tell
me that to my face.
Until that time,
I'm a member of lgsm
and I'm going to do
what I set out to do.
No hiding, no running away,
no apologies.
Me, too.
Yeah.
And me.
This is a welsh castle,
mind.
None of your Norman rubbish.
According to legend,
the maiden Sabrina
came here, see,
and became the goddess
of the river severn.
How'd she manage that,
then, cliff?
By drowning.
"Sabrina fair
listen where thou art sitting
"under the glassie, cool,
translucent wave"
and so on.
I grew up
in northern Ireland.
I know all about what happens
when people don't
talk to each other.
That's why I've
never understood,
what's the point
of supporting gay rights
but nobody else's rights,
you know?
Or workers' rights
but not women's rights.
It's...
I don't know, illogical.
There's a lodge banner
down in the welfare,
over 100 years old.
We bring it out
for special occasions,
you know.
I'll show it to you one day.
It's a symbol, like this.
Right? Two hands.
That's what
the labor movement means.
Should mean.
You support me,
I support you.
Whoever you are.
Wherever you come from.
Shoulder to shoulder.
Hand to hand.
Dai!
There they go.
They're bringing them in
from London, from Bristol.
All over.
They're
pulling the lads in
for anything now.
Well,
they can't do that.
There's two from my street
in custody right now.
Lee and Carl.
Where's your humanity?
We're citizens
of this country, mind.
Citizens.
No, I mean,
they can't do that.
It's totally illegal.
A police officer has
the right to stop you
if, and that's
the important word here,
if he has
reasonable grounds
to believe
a crime is going
to be committed.
Now, you're absolutely
sure about this?
Police harassment, dear.
I could set it to music.
And if he does?
Then he must
formally charge you
within 24 hours
of that arrest.
But "reasonable grounds"
means concrete evidence
that can stand up
in court.
It doesn't mean
he doesn't like
the look of you.
That's the same
whether you're standing
on a picket line
or trolling down
clapham high street
in full drag.
Hefina,
tell Martin to mind the kids.
Where you going?
The police station.
She's finding her feet.
Right, gentlemen,
listen to me.
A police officer
only has the right
to detain a group of people...
You need evidence
to stand up in a court of law.
They need concrete evidence.
If you keep them
for longer than 24 hours...
No proof. No proof.
And I will not be
leaving this desk
until you do.
We've got all day,
so chop-chop.
Nobody said anything
about hiding who we are.
Yes, they did. You.
I just think if everybody
takes it easy on the...
Flamboyance.
Then we're more
likely to fit in.
I'm sorry, just to be clear,
when you say flamboyance,
you mean gay?
And when you say everyone,
you mean me?
Jonathan.
Good.
It's just I haven't
spoken 1950s
in quite a while.
Over here, please.
We're packing parcels.
You'll stay for a pint?
No, you're all right, cliff.
Welfare's had
a change of atmosphere,
if you know what I mean.
I don't know what
you mean, Lee, no.
He means these faggots.
Oi.
If it wasn't for
those people over there,
you lot would
still be in the Nick.
What?
He's right.
They make me sick,
that's all I know, dai.
That's enough.
Physically sick.
- Gays?
- From London.
They were the ones, Carl.
They got you out.
I thought sian got us out.
They told her...
They told her what to say.
Carl.
It's you lot, is it?
The gays.
What's going on?
No, it's all right.
It's all right.
We're lgsm. Lesbians and gays
support the miners, yes.
My name's mark Ashton.
You'll have a pint,
will you, mark?
What I was told
about lesbians
really did shock me.
It can't be true,
can it?
You're all vegetarians?
Actually,
Zoe and I are both vegans.
So, you live together like,
you know, husband and wife.
But what I want to know is...
I know what
you're going to say.
Which one does
the housework?
Oh, well, that's...
That's not what I thought
you was going to say.
Are you joking?
Certainly not.
It's embarrassing
enough they spend
one night on
dai's floor, Maureen.
From here on in
the hosting committee's
going to bloody
well start hosting.
I'm sorry, not me.
I'm concerned about aids.
What?
It's not
a trivial matter, sian.
They've issued leaflets.
I don't mind
taking more, hefina.
Not the lesbians so much
because of their cuisine.
But I'll take an extra gay.
I tell you
something right now,
Maureen Barry,
if you get aids,
so help me God,
I'll nurse you myself.
Though how you're
going to get aids
from a couple of sleeping bags
in your extension,
I don't know.
Listen, it's fine.
No. I can take
another one
and so can cliff.
Think it's going to be
that easy, do you?
You just bulldoze
the whole village
into thinking
the same thing as you.
I don't need to
bulldoze anyone.
It's you who's
got the problem.
They're all in there
getting along perfectly well.
Oh, really?
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
I'm just talking to
kev about something.
You can talk to kev
any day of the week.
Get over there and find
a gay or a lesbian right now.
Look, hefina,
I've shaken their hands.
I've bought them a pint, see?
I don't want to
labor the point, do I?
I might, you know,
give them
the wrong impression.
Right.
Oh, right.
Because you're so
bloody irresistible,
is that it, Carl Evans?
Listen to me.
I've seen you dancing
round my back yard
with no clothes on
since you were this high.
And I can tell you right now,
these gays have
thrown better away.
Now, move yourself. And you.
Red, gold and green
karma, karma, karma, karma,
karma chameleon
this is a first, this.
Men on the dance floor.
You can't be serious!
Welsh men don't dance,
do they, sian?
Never.
Can't move their hips.
Well, why don't we show them
what they're missing?
Karma, karma, karma, karma,
karma chameleon
See,
I want you to feel me, too
so just listen to me, baby
can't stop me now
hear what I say
my feet want to move
so, get out my way
I'm going to have my say
I'm going to
every discotheque
I'm gonna dance,
dance, dance, dance
ooh,
till the break of day I say
shame, shame, shame
shame on you,
if you can't dance too
oh, my God.
He's amazing!
I say shame, shame, shame,
shame, shame, shame, shame
shame on you,
if you can't dance too
come on! Come on!
Don't stop the motions
if you get the notion
you can't stop the groove
'cause you just won't move
got my sunroof down
got my diamonds in the back
whoo!
Whoo!
Shame, shame, shame
shame on you
if you can't dance too
I say shame, shame, shame,
shame, shame, shame, shame
shame on you,
if you can't dance too
shame, shame, shame
shame on you,
if you can't dance too
I say shame, shame, shame
shame, shame, shame, shame
shame on you,
if you can't dance too
God, I miss disco.
Everyone back to mine
for a nightcap.
What? Go to bed, cliff.
I promise I'll do it, man.
For God's sake.
He always gets like this.
What did I
bloody say to you, eh?
Showing us up in
front of our guest.
Don't worry.
You're going to love it.
Cheers, mate.
Oi. What the hell
was that about?
He's going to give
him dance lessons.
Are you joking?
You'll start
prancing about like that?
Listen,
if you're going to spend
the rest of your life
standing at the bar
wishing you could
speak to Debbie Thomas,
that's fine by me.
I'm going to be
a woman magnet.
Where the bloody
hell did you get that?
I don't know
why you're so het up.
They're going in the morning.
Well, this strike matters
to you two, does it?
Of course it does.
What do you
think people will say
when they hear about this?
We're being
backed up by perverts.
You want people
taking the piss, do you?
Scabs? Coppers?
Calling us
all sorts of names?
No.
I know one thing.
Your father would
never have stood for it.
That went well, considering.
Considering?
Sometimes people
can surprise you,
that's all I'm saying.
I never had
a problem with it, sian.
Well, I'm glad to hear it,
because this is Joe.
Bye.
And he's going to
be sleeping in our house.
How do?
Nice to meet you.
No need to do the full
Barry white, Martin.
He knows
you're heterosexual.
This is fine.
I think we should
take him to the door.
No. Just here, please.
Just drop me here.
All right.
Oh, leave him alone.
Hang on a minute.
What is it?
Got to keep up
the fiction.
See you.
Mmm. Was it fun?
It was the best experience
of my entire life.
Making pastry?
You wanna start something,
you start it with me!
Lesbians
and gays support
the miners.
Thank you.
Let's keep
it moving, girls.
Just put it in.
Victory to the miners!
Lesbian and gays support
the miners.
Any donations, sir?
Don't worry about me freezing
to death in Brixton, will you?
Aren't you going
to ring your mum?
What for?
A long-distance
queer-bashing?
Hi.
Here you are, love.
Why don't I pretend
to be your girlfriend?
That way you get an alibi
and I get to watch
the sound of music.
Come to ours, Steph.
Can I?
Yeah.
Orphans of the storm.
No queen's speech.
No Carols.
Oh, sounds like heaven.
Support the miners.
A very happy
Christmas to you, too.
There is now a danger
that has become
a threat to us all.
It is a deadly disease
and there is no known cure.
- The virus can be...
- That one for you...
...passed during
sexual intercourse
with an infected person.
Aids.
Anally injected
death sentence.
Will you switch that off,
please, Tony?
But it's spreading.
Thank you.
So protect yourself.
Hello?
Can I speak
to Jonathan, please?
Uh, no, he's being creative
in the kitchen, I'm afraid.
Uh...
Take a message.
I just wanted to thank him
for his beautiful card.
Homemade, too.
My husband was particularly
impressed with it.
I'll be sure to tell him.
Is that a welsh accent
I can hear?
Uh, oh, maybe. The remnants.
I haven't been home
in a long time so...
Well,
we're looking forward
to seeing them
all back here soon.
And wish Jonathan
a happy Christmas
from all of us in dulais,
will you?
Of course.
Of course I will.
Nadolig llawen to you,
my love.
Nadolig llawen.
The 1:00 news
from the BBC.
The coal board
called a press conference
in near despair today
after the collapse
of last night's talks.
The strike entered
its 42nd week.
The union responded
with a renewed attack
on the government's
latest cuts to benefits
for the families
of those on strike.
They're calling it an attempt
by Mrs. Thatcher
to starve the miners
back to work.
Severe weather in england
and wales is
set to continue...
Bloody hell.
It's bricked up.
Oh, Jesus.
Let's get the stuff unloaded
and shared out
as fast as possible, yeah?
What the bloody hell
am I doing?
Right, come on, then,
you heard him.
There's noises
in the village.
Small voices.
Nothing we can't handle
but...
They want to go back?
They've been told they'll save
the pits that go back first.
They won't but,
uh, desperate people,
they'll believe anything.
Tell him about the bus.
Our bus has broken down.
And our gas
has been cut off, so...
We're having baths next door.
We're playing for
a tin of beef now.
Remember, all your proceeds
to the strike fund,
ladies and gents,
so please dig deep.
There's a pair for you.
Happy Christmas.
There you go.
Not even Kim wilde's
got them in orange.
Ah...
This is gethin.
Ah.
Hello.
He's a little nervous.
Jonathan.
There's no need
to be nervous, boy.
With a good
welsh name like that?
Where are you from, then?
Rhyl, originally.
No. No way.
Listen here, see.
We don't mind the gays
and the lesbians, that's fine.
But don't you dare
be bringing people
from north wales down here.
Stupid bugger.
That bus is a lifeline.
It takes them into the picket.
It takes the food parcels
to the remotest villages.
Without it...
All the fours, 44.
We need to start thinking
in larger chunks of money
because without it
they're going to fail,
it's as simple as that.
I'm sorry,
but when are you going
to address my question
about a women's group?
Blind 70.
Stella, this is important.
I know.
But this group has absolutely
no Democratic process.
What do you need
a women's group for, anyway?
Thee and me, 23.
To address the women's issues.
Singly and in
a safe environment.
What is unsafe
about this environment?
Kelly's eye,
number one.
I'm a woman, Mike.
Okay?
I'm also a lesbian
and a feminist.
Listen, love, I don't care
if you're Arthur scargill.
Don't talk during the bingo.
Tickety-boo, 62.
Drink to me
only with thine eyes
Thirty-six.
For God's sake,
leave him alone.
He's not a girls' world.
But we love him, mum.
Okay. Design speed.
It's called
the great Atlantic fault.
And, uh,
and it starts here in Spain
and then it goes
under the bay of biscay
and then it comes
up in South wales.
And then it goes
under the Atlantic
for Miles and Miles and Miles
and it comes up
again in Pennsylvania.
My father used
to talk about it.
And mine.
The dark artery.
That's it. Yeah, that's it.
And you could
take a miner
from wales or Spain
or America
and you could
show them that seam
and they would recognize it.
There's no other coal like it.
It's perfect. Pure.
I lost my younger
brother to that pit.
Thirty-six years old.
But without it, these villages
are nothing, they're finished.
That's what I'd say
if I ever came face-to-face
with Margaret
fucking Thatcher.
That's what I'd tell her.
The pit and the people
are one and the same.
Yeah. Well...
Welcome home, son.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Listen to me, everyone.
I just want to say something.
Get your feet
off those seats.
- We've let you down.
- No.
No, we have.
We haven't collected enough.
We haven't raised
enough awareness.
We know that.
Now, it's not enough
to always be defending.
Sometimes you have to
attack to push forward,
and that's exactly
what we're going to do.
When we get back to London,
and you have my word on this,
we are going to...
We're going to do
something so spectacular.
It'll be so incredible,
so effective,
that the national coal board,
I promise you this,
will come crawling
on their hands and knees
In full drag,
to beg you for forgiveness.
Now, victory!
Victory to the miners!
Well done.
Whoo!
Victory to the miners!
As we come marching,
marching
in the beauty of the day
a million darkened kitchens
a thousand mill lofts gray
are touched
with all the radiance
that a sudden sun discloses
for the people
hear us singing
bread and roses!
Bread and roses!
As we go marching, marching
we battle too for men
for they are women's children
and we mother them again
our lives shall
not be sweated
from birth until life closes
hearts starve
as well as bodies
give us bread
but give us roses!
As we go marching, marching
unnumbered women dead
go crying
through our singing
their ancient cry for bread
small art and
love and beauty
their drudging spirits knew
yes,
it is bread we fight for
but we fight for roses too!
Go back to
where you came from!
We've come to take
back our welfare.
What are you talking about?
From all your bloody queers.
What the hell's going on?
There's normal
people who wanna
drink in here as well,
you know?
You listen to me.
Those people in
there are our guests.
Yeah? Well,
they wanna watch themselves.
Leave it, Martin.
Come on, for God's sake, man.
Come on, leave it.
Come on, Martin.
You so much as lay one finger
on anyone inside that hall,
and so help me God,
I'll break your bloody arms
and legs for you.
Come on.
Come back in. Come on.
Bent bastards!
There you go.
I know it's freezing
but at least
the beers will be cold.
- You want a beer, anyone?
- Yeah, over here.
I've got one,
thanks, dai.
Here you go, Alan.
"Say not the struggle
naught availeth,
"the labour and
the wounds are vain,
"the enemy faints not,
nor faileth,
"and as things
have been they remain,
"if hopes were dupes..."
Oh,
that's more like it.
Maybe you want
to give me kisses sweet
but only for one night
with no repeat
and maybe you'll go away
and never call...
I'm Gary.
Oh.
Hi.
I want to
learn to dance.
We need to make
something happen.
Yeah, well,
we do now, yeah.
Something big. An event.
Something bigger
than we've ever tried before.
Why don't you come inside?
It's a fraction warmer.
It's morale.
That's the thing.
It's just as
important as money.
We need to keep them up, Mike.
Because the minute
they start to feel
like a lost cause...
I know. I know.
And there's nothing worse
than a lost cause.
In my sleep
countin' troubles
instead of countin' sheep...
I'm in wales
and I don't have to pretend
to be something that I'm not.
I'm home. And I'm gay.
And I'm welsh.
That's right!
Get him another beer
before he starts singing.
What I don't understand
is why you never
came back before.
My mother.
She couldn't accept me.
Not then, perhaps.
She's religious.
She hasn't said
one word to me in 16 years.
And what about you?
What words have
you said to her?
It's gone away in yesterday
now I find myself
on the mountainside
where the rivers
change direction
across the great divide
you got a sweetheart,
have you, love?
I'm a gobby
northern lesbian, Gwen.
I tend to scare 'em off.
Look.
That's my William.
Forty-four years
I had him with me
and I wish you as many
with someone one day.
And as happy.
Jesus, I'm pissed.
Alan, no!
Give us a hand,
will you, Steph?
He's thrown up again.
Margaret, I am so sorry.
Alan pritchard,
so help me.
"For many years now
we have been
force-fed an agenda
"that has
represented homosexuals
"first as victims,
now as heroes."
Margaret Donovan
could be reported.
All those people
in her house.
"The homosexuals
have been told
"that it is us,
the normal population,
"and not them,
that is out of step.
"Any society that accepts
that sick deception
"is swirling headlong into
a cesspool of its own making."
Well, they want to see
what's going on up here.
They'd have a field day.
Why don't you
come over to dai's?
Just for a minute.
I think if you met
one or two of them...
Have you seen this, cliff?
About the gays?
I don't believe
what they say about us, Lee.
Why should I listen
to what they say about them?
Get inside, you.
And shut up.
You're a respected woman,
Maureen.
People follow you.
You could set an example.
You're the backbone
of that committee.
You work hard.
You've been both mother
and father to those boys.
Sitting on your own
in the dark, Maureen?
You wanna take that rod
out of your arse
for a minute.
Good luck.
Morning.
Thanks.
Hello?
I'm in a phone box
so I'll have to be quick.
I got a story
for your news desk.
Hello, mum.
Bye, bromley.
See you.
Hello, sailors.
Morning, ladies.
Come on, maries.
What are
they going on about?
...With your bum chum.
- What's going on?
- Wait till you see this.
Jesus.
"Perverts support the pits.
"A gaggle of gays
and lesbians has 'come out'
"in favor
of the miners' strike.
"Our editor says,
"'we knew
the miners were desperate,
"'but now we have the final
and compelling evidence
"'that they are finished.'"
"does anyone
else hear the bottom
of the barrel being scraped?
"From where I'm sitting,
the noise is
pretty deafening."
Unbelievable.
Who did this?
It'll have to
go to a vote.
But I'm warning you, we can do
without this kind of trouble.
This isn't trouble,
it's mischief.
Jesus, man.
We've had worse
than this before now.
Every day they're
out collecting for us.
It's the men, dai.
They've already
got their wives
supporting them, and now this.
Gays. The whole country
laughing at us.
It's about dignity.
It'll have to go to a vote.
Right.
They're calling
an emergency meeting.
A vote.
Dai's speaking up
for us, of course,
but it's done a lot of damage.
Yeah, but we're not going
to let a little thing
like this break...
Down! Get down!
What's going on?
Bastards!
I don't care
about what they do,
but it's a distraction.
It's distracting people
from the strike.
And then
there's the children.
I mean,
what example is it
for kiddies
to have gays
and lesbians roaming around?
It's unnatural.
There used to be
a tradition in wales
of honoring your guests.
Do you remember that,
ladies?
Respect? Generosity?
Hefina...
There's only one
thing that's unnatural
about this whole
bloody business.
Betraying the community.
And when I find out
who sold that story,
believe me,
they'll know
what it feels like
to be ashamed.
What the hell are we doing?
Now, let's just get
this finished, mark.
No, no, I mean,
what the hell are we doing?
They would never
have known we were here
if it wasn't for this article.
So?
So they would
never have found us.
So, what are you saying, mark,
I should just
send them the bill?
Do you know how many people
read this paper?
This is our chance
to do something spectacular.
We could never
drum up this kind
of publicity
in a million years.
Mark, don't you
just think we ought to
hold back and regroup?
There isn't time to regroup.
This is a news item now.
Today.
We have to take
advantage of that.
They called us perverts.
Bromley,
it's time for
an important part
of your education.
Hands up in this room
if you've ever been
called a name like that.
Now, there is a long
and honorable tradition
in the gay community
and it has stood
us in good stead
for a very long time.
When somebody
calls you a name...
Am I right about this,
Jonathan?
Dead right.
You take it
and you own it.
That's what my heart
yearns for now
love and pride
I love you.
You owe me.
That's what my heart
yearns for now
It's
a fundraising concert
and we're
looking for bands to...
No, no. No, no, no,
I am in no way
suggesting that sting,
or indeed any other member
of the police, is a pervert.
Cool. Cheers.
Oh, I can probably
get you some more,
next week if you want.
He'll call.
Okay.
Take your hairdryer
blow them all away
in you I've found a story
I want to keep hearing
in you I see all colors
not just black or white
Oi! Oi! Oi!
In you I find a reason
and hope for all dreamers
there are no gay artists
on this label. I'm sorry.
They don't have to be gay,
that's the point.
This is a coming together
of all different people...
Reception.
It arrived about 10
minutes ago, Barry.
Yeah, well, you could
come down and get it.
What the bloody hell
do you think you're doing?
That's the number
for gay switchboard.
You never know, one of them
might need it one day.
We'll be back
in good time for the vote.
Right-o.
Any problems,
we can be reached
at the bookshop.
You're
gonna miss this train.
Rowena Roberts has had a baby.
She needs an extra box.
I can't hear you.
Rowena Roberts
has had a baby.
Strange.
I can't... I can't...
I can't hear you.
She needs an extra box.
Some love and pride
that's what my heart
yearns for now
love and pride
and the difference is
this is open to everyone.
Okay?
Gay, straight,
it doesn't matter.
We want people
to come together
to show their support.
And why should
gay people like me
support the miners?
Because miners dig for coal,
which produces power,
which allows gay people
like you to dance
to bananarama
until 3:00 in the morning.
Next question?
Are you all right?
Yes, you. The cute one.
I've never met a pop star.
I have. Max boyce.
He was playing swansea grand
the year our Jane was born.
What's funny about that?
You need to push the t-shirts
and the badges
as hard as you can.
This is a fundraiser.
Make sure people
are buying stuff.
Is he in charge?
He's the
official photographer.
We don't want it
to be all churchy.
Do you know what I mean?
It's a christening.
Yeah,
but the readings don't all
have to come from the Bible,
do they?
You can have
all sorts of things
nowadays.
It's more open.
Meeting's tomorrow afternoon.
3:00 sharp.
We'll make it as long
as we leave early enough.
And the vote?
At the end.
Single question,
can we continue
taking your support
in the light of recent events?
"Recent events."
Mmm.
You won't have anything
to worry about,
I'm telling you.
When they see
what you make out of this.
If we make
anything out of this.
Are you joking, man?
You're already famous.
Give it here.
"Bronski beat are
to headline a benefit
"for the miners
at the electric ballroom."
"Pits and perverts
is being organized
"by the London
lesbians' and gay men's
support the miners group."
Got the name wrong.
"The event is
open to everyone,
gay or straight,
"and will be
a real festive occasion
"through which
we can express our solidarity
"with the mining communities."
Five pounds for a t-shirt,
anyone?
Five pounds for a t-shirt.
Don't dawdle, love.
Get indoors.
Support the miners!
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen.
To the gays.
To the straights.
And to the as-yet-undecided.
Welcome to
the electric ballroom,
Camden, for this,
the first ever
pits and perverts
benefit ball!
Tell me why
tell me why
contempt in your eyes
as I turn to kiss his lips
broken I lie,
all my feelings denied,
blood on your fist
can you tell me why?
Can you tell me why?
This is the first gay club
we've ever been to.
Yeah? As a matter of fact,
we're not gay, either.
Oh.
We're miners.
That's perfect.
Hide me. Hide me.
Hey. Why?
If you see Steph,
perhaps you'd give her this?
They want me to
join their breakaway group,
lesbians against
pit closures.
Strictly women only.
I don't think
I could trust myself,
do you?
Are you going to
take my picture, then?
Can you tell me why?
Well, it's incredible
to see such a mix
of people here tonight.
Gay and straight.
Can you see what
we've done here?
By coming together,
all of us,
by pledging our solidarity,
our friendship,
we've made history.
Back in our...
Back in our
miners' lodge, in wales,
we have a banner.
And it's old, it's very old.
Maybe 100 years.
And it's this,
two hands together.
Joined like this.
Well, I tell you now,
you've worn our badge,
"coal not dole,"
and when the time comes,
you have my word on this,
we will wear yours.
Shoulder to shoulder.
Hand to hand.
Come on,
then, that's right.
We're off out for the night.
I hope you ladies
aren't going to let me down.
What?
We want to see everything!
Don't we?
What, everything?
Even the rubber scene.
You spin me right round,
baby
right round
like a record, baby
right round, round, round
you spin me right round,
baby
right round
like a record, baby
I want your love
Sorry, ladies.
This is a men-only venue.
Oh, don't be daft, love.
We've come all
the way from powys.
Evening.
Hello.
Blue-eyed dressed
for every situation
moving through
the doorway of a nation
pick me up and
shake the doubt
baby I can't do without
how'd you get into
that leotard, then?
Um, talcum powder.
What?
Talcum powder.
Oh. Lily of the valley, I use.
Mark?
Oh, my God.
Mark Ashton.
Tim.
Oh, this is insane.
I'm bumping into
everybody tonight.
How are you?
You still changing
the world?
- Bit by bit.
- Tim, come on.
I haven't been home
in four days.
Haven't you?
I'm on a farewell tour.
Where are you going?
You are a beautiful man,
mark.
I miss you.
Please take care
of yourself. Okay?
Please.
Come on.
Please take care.
Come on,
then, girls.
That's enough.
Back to ours.
Bedtime. Come on.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
You're lighter
than your husband.
Mmm.
Do you know what I was
when I met Alan?
Drunk?
Sixteen.
Think that's ridiculous?
I was pretty then.
You're pretty now.
It all goes South,
doesn't it?
Love. Looks.
Everything.
That's cheery.
Sod it.
I always thought sex was
for the men, really, anyway.
We just put up
with it, don't we?
Keep them quiet.
Okay.
I will listen to
a certain amount
of drunken bollocks, Gail,
but sex is not
just for the men,
it's for the women, too.
Believe me.
Oh, yeah.
Gail, come on.
No carpets.
This is Laura Ashley.
I've seen it before.
Where?
Cardiff.
What I
want to know is...
What's this?
Hefina, you put
that back immediately.
That's nothing.
Here,
look what else I've found.
You never
went under his bed.
When was the last time
you saw anything like that?
Huh? When? When?
Don't those women
ever sleep?
Jesus, God,
that takes me back.
Mum.
So, what were
their names again, boys?
Mine was Jess.
And mine was Carol.
Six
straight people asked me
if they could
join us last night.
You're joking?
We should set
up another group.
Straights supporting gays
supporting miners.
Right, that's it,
we're off.
What about bromley?
He's too late.
You've got
a meeting to get to.
The vote, remember?
Okay.
Surely you've got
his number, Steph?
Nobody's got his number.
He still lives at home.
I'm sorry, but mark's right.
If we're going to
get there by 3:00...
He's blown it.
Come on, let's go.
Oh. What a shame.
He was sucking face
till the lights came up.
I wouldn't waste any time
feeling sorry for him.
Can I please
have an aspirin?
What the hell's this?
Plans change, cliff.
It's not my fault.
No answer.
They must be on their way.
Okay.
I can't speak in front
of all these people, cliff.
I can't.
I know you think
you know what you want,
Joe, but you're so young.
That's what the law's for,
to protect you.
I didn't know
who I was at your age.
It's such
a terrible life, Joe.
It's lonely.
Is that what you want?
No family?
Hiding from people at work,
from everyone?
Keeping secrets?
Come here.
Oh.
So now cliff will speak
on behalf of the lgsm.
The floor's yours, cliff.
Um... w...
Well,
what I want to say abo...
About the gays and lesbians...
Why don't you do
us a poem, cliff?
Poem! Poem! Poem!
I want to propose that
this meeting is unlawful.
I want to propose
that this meeting
was brought forward unlawfully
and that most
of the people here
aren't even
from this village.
All right.
Let's bring it
forward to the vote.
There we go.
Two hours to spare.
Hefina heddon, you drive
like a bloody lunatic.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Gwen, look after the gays.
Right-o.
3:00.
You can't dictate
when the committee sits.
You told us 3:00.
And then we had to change it.
Bloody disgusting
way to behave.
If you weren't up in London...
It's invalid.
This whole decision
is invalid.
We can fight it.
We've got one fight, dai.
The fucking strike.
Or have you
forgotten that, all of you?
Dancing around in London.
The trouble with those people
is they jump on the bandwagon.
- What?
- It's well known.
They pretend
they're backing you,
but what they're really doing
is pushing their own agenda.
Gay rights.
What?
We've seen articles,
hefina.
Christ Jesus help me.
You better shut her mouth
or I'm going to
do it permanently.
No, come on,
that's enough.
An official
letter will be sent.
I can't...
I can't listen to this.
To thank them
most sincerely.
But the vote was
we won't be accepting
their support any more.
They're causing
us embarrassment,
dai, that's the thing.
And we're not
strong enough, not now.
We're struggling
to survive as it is.
Oh, that reminds me.
Courtesy of those people
and their agenda.
Jesus Christ.
I don't suppose you opened
your mouth, did you?
Didn't want to
rock the boat,
is that it?
There's bloody thousands
here.
You think you've known
someone your whole life.
Turns out they're
a complete stranger.
I'd say the same
about you, cliff.
I'll tell you something.
If you think this is what
my brother would have wanted,
you're wrong.
We came to help
you win and if we're
not helping, we have to go.
This was all you.
No.
It was.
All right.
Take my advice.
Don't give it
all to the fight.
Save some for home.
There's more to life,
you know?
You girls have
opened my eyes.
I'm going to
extend my repertoire,
you'll see.
The vegan Delia Smith.
Bye.
Take care, now.
It's a bloody travesty,
man.
- I don't accept it.
- Gethin...
I don't.
They can't stop me
from collecting money.
How can they?
- Don't be crazy, gethin.
- Geth...
Somebody better tell
lesbians against pit closures.
What now?
What do you mean?
What are we doing?
Where are we going?
It's over, Mike.
Were you not
paying attention?
We lost.
And I don't know about you
but I'm pissing off.
Where?
Anywhere.
I'm out of here.
What about the rest of us?
Do you think
it might be possible
that just for once
you could make your
own decision, Mike?
You what?
Do you think
that just for once
you could stop following me
around like a fucking spaniel
and let me have
a life of my own?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think I could
manage that, yeah.
Good. Piss off,
all of you.
Leave me alone.
Oh, fu...
Lesbians and gays
support the miners.
Never mind the miners.
There's gay people
dying every day.
That's what you should
be thinking about.
Not the bloody miners.
Asshole.
Excuse me?
Excuse me.
I only want to talk to you.
Now,
I tell you what we'll do,
let's come over here.
This is the key
you swapped it to.
Oh, well,
we'll leave that there...
Now,
just come over here, my son,
and get yourself a nice...
Is Joe there, please?
No, I'm afraid he's out.
Can you tell him
that his friend gethin's
in hospital?
It's very important.
He's, um...
He's in St. Thomas' hospital.
He's been beaten up.
Yes,
of course I'll tell him.
And will you
tell him that Steph
called round to
see how he was?
Who was that?
Tina. She wants
a lift in the morning.
You're back at the jobcentre
tomorrow, don't forget.
I should have...
I should have said more.
I could have.
I could have spoken better.
If you're going to cut,
cut it straight.
Triangles.
I'm gay.
I know.
I've known for a little
while now, cliff.
Since the gays arrived?
Well, I can't speak
for the rest of the village
but speaking for myself,
since about 1968.
Well...
Yeah.
What's that?
It's the new van.
About time, too.
What the hell's this?
New van.
Courtesy of our gay friends
down in London.
I'm not getting in that.
Then you'll have to stay here.
In you get, lads.
Quick now.
You a lesbian, are you, love?
That's right.
We're just off to swansea
now for a massive lez-off.
Britain's longest running
national strike is over.
Amongst scenes of
bitterness and anger,
num delegates
voted narrowly
for an organized return
to work on Tuesday.
Tomorrow most of britain's
coal miners will
return to work.
They say they'll march back,
heads held high.
It's almost a year
to the very day
since they walked out
and embarked on
a course of action which...
Joe,
have you seen the news?
Thank God for that.
Joe?
Bloody hell!
Mark!
Where are you going?
I'm leaving.
I was trying to make myself
feel better and I failed.
I've been virtually
under house arrest.
Stuck with my parents.
I haven't seen anyone.
I've tried ringing Steph
but she's always...
Why don't you leave?
I did, last night.
I didn't even tell
them I was going.
That's not leaving,
it's running.
What are you going to do now?
Stay here.
And do what?
And get a job down the pit?
That's all they need,
a trained pastry chef
with a camera.
When are you going to
get some guts, huh?
You're a member
of lgsm, bromley.
So stop sneaking
out of your mammy's house
in the dead of night
and stand up for yourself.
Have some pride.
Because life is short, okay?
It's short.
Okay?
What should I
tell the others?
Nothing. I wasn't here.
You're a mad bugger.
I'm taking you
home after that.
In the van.
No arguments.
Will you give this
to Jeff, please, Joe?
Of course I will.
Come on.
What about gethin?
Is he okay?
Gethin?
The last I heard
he was back on the ward.
I don't like meltis fruits.
Well, then, maybe you won't
go through them quite so fast.
Help me out with these,
will you, bromley?
Stay in bed.
Keep an eye on
Jonathan for me,
will you?
He needs to take
care of himself.
It's you
we're taking care of,
you daft sod.
If you could just make sure
he's got some groceries in.
Gethin...
He's HIV-positive, sian.
He's not supposed to smoke.
And he needs to eat properly.
Please. For me.
Gethin.
Hello.
This is my mum.
Come in.
Back then, when they knew
even less about this thing,
they gave out numbers
with each diagnosis.
One, two, three and so on.
Course, when they got
into the high thousands, it...
I'm number two.
Nobody knows
what's keeping me alive.
I think it's the grass.
What are you
going to do now?
Make you some soup.
Drive back to wales.
No, I mean with your life.
I'm a wife and mother, love.
My life goes
back to normal now.
Well, it shouldn't.
You've a first-class mind.
You should do something.
Go to college.
Don't waste it, sian.
There are young people
dying every day now.
Good people.
Clever, promising.
Don't you dare waste it.
Oh, shit.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
What the hell is this?
And where have you been?
Hello. You must be
Joe's mum. I'm sian.
Will you please
remove your van
from my property?
I hope you appreciate him.
'Cause there's
a whole village
back in wales
who thinks he's a hero.
Joe.
Mum,
he's done this on purpose.
It's all right,
I'm leaving.
I hope one day
we can be friends again, mum.
Oi, you got something
to say to your sister?
I've got something
to say to you, Jason.
You're a dick.
And Tina, that tight perm
doesn't suit you.
It never has.
I'm sorry.
Joe.
You all right?
Cheers.
While you've been away,
I've been changing my act.
You watch.
Demure and accommodating,
that's me.
The lesbian lady di.
I think I'd find that
a tremendous disappointment.
I'm glad you
came back, bromley.
It wasn't
the same without you.
Thanks.
I'm glad I came back, too.
If we were normal,
this is when we'd kiss.
There's the rest of it.
Thanks.
"Screw you, Thatcher"
or "fuck you"?
I can see the appeal of both.
Jonathan,
"screw" or "fuck"?
"Screw."
It's more visceral.
Attention, attention!
We have reason to
believe that there are
known homosexualists
and a confirmed lesbo
inside these premises
and that they are armed
with sewing machines
and glitter.
A-ha.
Now that you have made
yourselves known to me,
I have a question
for the notorious
accrington sodomite
known as Mike Jackson.
Will you please put that down?
We have a very
good relationship
with our neighbors.
Mike.
I behaved
like a prick before.
Do you forgive me?
Just... just get up here
and sew something, will you?
There you go, bromley.
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
Right. Now, get to work.
And just for
future reference...
My name's Joe.
You tell 'em, bromley.
Bromley! Bromley! Bromley!
Bromley! Bromley!
Oi, haven't you heard
about the miners, dearie?
They lost.
Have you heard?
No politics.
What?
Mark's over with
the steward now.
No politics?
No slogans.
We're a mardi gras,
apparently.
There was
a general feeling...
Amongst who?
Amongst the committee
that people have
become tired of politics
and that this year,
the tone should
be celebratory.
With affirmative slogans
and a positive atmosphere.
Horse shit.
If you insist on marching
with your banner,
you'll have to march
at the back with
the fringe groups.
Mate, we're lgsm.
We fought
alongside the miners.
Congratulations.
But now it's time
for a party.
What?
Bollocks.
Complete and utter bollocks.
What's lgsm's position?
We're going to march.
Yes,
but with banners or without?
With.
With. This is
a fucking demonstration.
That's why we've decided
to lead the fringe groups
at the back.
Why would you be leading it?
Sorry?
I'm not getting
rid of the banner.
Listen...
There's got to be
some kind of compromise.
Why?
Because that's the way
you get things done.
No, it fucking isn't.
Listen.
Why does everything
get so aggressive
with you lot?
Listen to me! Listen to me.
Whether we march
with banners or without,
the important thing
is that we march together,
all of us.
That's what this whole thing
has been about
since the beginning
and that is absolutely
how it is going to end.
Together, us united.
Bloody hell.
Ah, yeah!
I can't believe you're here.
I can't believe
you're here.
All right?
Where are my lesbians?
Hi.
Hey.
Hi!
These are all cucumber.
No butter.
Stork sb every one.
I can't believe you came.
Miners, see?
We love a bloody good march.
Right,
where do you want us?
You lot.
I'll tell them.
There's too many of you.
What?
You'll have to
go to the front.
You'll have to lead.
We're not losing
our banners, mate.
What do you mean...
What's he mean,
too many?
What's he on about?
I think he means them.
Caerphilly.
West glamorgan.
East glamorgan.
Abercrave lodge.
Aberdare lodge.
Bargoed surface lodge.
Fernhill lodge. Mardy lodge.
Blygrathc lodge.
Cambrian lodge.
Ferniside plant.
Mountain ash lodge.
Dulais valley lodge, onllwyn,
and haverfordwest lodge.
South wales num headquarters.
The gays and lesbians
have been
absolutely magnificent,
there's no other word for it.
You must have
found it a bit weird.
A load of gays and lesbians
descending on you like that?
Why on earth
would we have
found that weird?
This way, guys.
We're at the front.
Come on, guys.
We're at the front. This way.
Not worried
about being too
visible this time?
Shut up and march.
There is power in a factory
power in the land
power in the hand
of the worker
but it all
amounts to nothing
if together we don't stand
there is power in a union
now, the lessons of the past
were all learned
with workers' blood
the mistakes of the bosses
we must pay for
from the cities
and the farmlands
to trenches full of mud
war has always been
the bosses' way, sir
the union forever
defending our rights
down with the blackleg
all workers unite
with our brothers
and our sisters
from many far-off lands
there is power in a union
now, I long for the morning
that they realize
brutality and unjust laws
cannot defeat us
but who'll
defend the workers
who cannot organize
when the bosses send
their lackeys out to cheat us?
Money speaks for money
the devil for his own
who comes to speak
for the skin and the bone
what a comfort to the widow
a light to the child
there is power in a union
The union forever
defending our rights
down with the blackleg
all workers unite
with our brothers
and our sisters
together we will stand
there is power in a union