Big House, Vantage Holdings
Presents
In association with Showbox,
Mediaplex lnc, lSU Venture Capital
Hanwha Venture Capital,
Hancomm, Michigan
Venture Capital and
Daishin Venture Capital
a Bidangil Pictures production
Executive producers
CHEONG Eui-seok, KIM Sun-yong,
JHUNG Seung-koo
Co-executive producers
KIM Woo-taek, JHE Min-ho,
PARK Jae-su, PARK Joon-tae,
CHO ll-hyung, KANG Tak-young
Executive producer
CHIN Hee-moon
Starring KIM Yoon-suk
And HA Jung-woo
Director of photography
LEE Sung-je
Lighting director LEE Choi-o
Production designer
LEE Min-bog (AURA)
Location sound
KIM Sin-yong (LIVE)
Edited by KIM Sun-min
Music by KIM Jun-seok
CHOI Yong-rock (M&F)
Sound supervisor
CHOI Tae-young (LIVE TONE)
Visual effects by
KIM Tae-hun (MIX)
Line producer CHOI Moon-su
kay, a little more.
Produced by
KIM Su-jin, YUN In-beom
You had some more space.
How could you park like that?
Its all right.
I'll be out in a jiffy anyway.
Written and Directed by NA Hong-jin
This way.
Sir, so is that your car?
You bitch,
you're dead if I catch you.
The Chaser
Yes.
I'm back!
I'm sorry, sir.
Two of our girls ran away.
Business has been bad lately.
I've already put
such a big advance on those girls.
But sir, I can't get that much money
ready in three days.
Once I collect the money from them,
and pay you back...
Turn it off, asshole!
Can't you see
I was on the phone?
You have no fucking manners.
Did you hand them out?
- Yes, sir.
- Go hand out some more, idiot!
Dumb asshole.
Yes.
Where?
Hapjung district.
Provence Motel, room 301.
I'll send her now.
- Hello.
- Hey.
You came fast.
Seong-hee,
you don't look so young.
- How old are you?
- Thirty.
You took good care of yourself.
Nice body.
Why? Need to go pee?
- Yes.
- Later.
- No.
- Go later.
I told you to go later.
- What's wrong?
- Let go.
- Just wanted to take some pictures.
- Let go!
Okay, I'll pay you instead.
Let go, you pervert!
What?
Crazy assholes.
Where is she?
You fucking slut!
You call me a pervert, huh?
Watch your mouth, bitch!
You want to die, huh?
Come here, you bitch!
- Mister.
- You're dead!
She's leaving.
Calm down.
- Get out!
- Come here, bitch!
- Mister.
- Come over here!
- She's leaving.
- Bitch...
Come here, you bitch!
You're dead!
- She's leaving now.
- You bitch!
- Calm down...
- What the fuck...
Who the hell are you?
I'm her guardian, asshole.
Sit down.
Kneel down.
Cover yourself!
So what are you going to do?
Let's settle this.
Satisfied?
There you are.
Let me see.
I'm quitting for real.
Don't call me.
Hey!
Did you find the girls?
Where did you find the car?
In Mangwon district.
Did you call the police?
You crazy?
Report girls who
ran away from me?
I told you they didn't run away.
You used to be a detective.
Then go find them
instead of ripping people off.
You crazy bitch,
who says I'm ripping people off?
I'm the one
who's being ripped off.
Bitches get a big advance from me
and then disappear.
Ask any asshole on the street
what it means.
Whether they've been sold
or ran away.
Rotten bastard.
Hey!
Hey! Seong-hee!
That damn temper of hers.
Meathead
What?
This bastard keeps rejecting the girls
and now there's no one left.
There's Mi-jin, idiot.
She wants to rest
because she's caught a cold.
Cold my ass. I'm hanging up.
What the fuck's wrong
with everyone?
Mom.
Mom!
What?
Take the medicine.
Bring me my cell phone, honey.
Filth
Yes, Jung-ho.
Where are you?
I'm sorry. I'm very sick.
Where are you sick?
I think it's a cold.
I also have a fever.
I'll take a day off.
A cold?
In the middle of summer?
Are you with a guy?
No.
Are you trying to run away
like the others?
What are you saying?
You better get to work
before you regret it.
Okay?
Why aren't you answering me?
Jung-ho, please.
Where do you live?
I'm going over right now.
Where is it?
Okay, I'll go.
Call Meathead.
Yes.
Damn it.
What's this?
You have to go?
I'll be back soon.
Yes, a Matiz.
I'm wearing a white cardigan
over a dress.
Did it turn on?
Yes.
4885?
4885...
I've heard of it.
4885?
Know this number?
Yes, sir.
He's a complete wacko.
Mi-jin went to serve
that bastard.
Ji-young
Mi-jin
Shit.
Where did she go?
To Mangwon district.
Yeah, it's that bastard.
He sold them.
It's me.
Just answer yes or no.
Are you with
that bastard now?
Your customer.
At a motel or his home?
Are you going to his house
in your car?
Okay, listen carefully.
Memorize his address
as you go into his house.
Just do as I say.
Don't get me upset.
Soon as you go in,
tell him you'll take a shower.
Then text me his address.
Simple, right?
Don't let him be suspicious.
You die if you screw up.
I'm finally lucky.
Shouldn't we report it?
Want to see
this business go down?
Look after the office.
Yes, sir.
Who is it?
My manager.
Your boss?
Yes.
Something wrong?
No, he's worried
that I'm sick.
Which way shall I go?
Over there.
Park in front of the guard post.
What a tough life.
The mayor of Seoul.
At the market at this hour.
Jung-ho, what's up?
Gil-woo, are you busy?
I'm busy, why?
Remember what I told you?
- What?
- About my girls running away.
They didn't run away.
They've been sold.
The same guy called for
the girls.
So?
Going to catch that asshole?
- Yes.
- Where are you?
Mangwon district.
Are you busy now?
I told you I'm busy.
I don't know
how many of them there are.
I might be outnumbered.
Could you send
a few ofyour guys at least?
History will be the judge!
Get the hell out!
Gil-woo?
Damn it.
It's here.
Mangwon district, 24-1
Something wrong?
No.
Come in.
Okay.
- Coming?
- Yes.
I'll take a shower.
Sure, it's over there.
Mangwon district
Sending
Message failed
I think I left the condom in my car.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Mi-jin
Your call cannot be connected.
Damn it.
Mi-jin
- Your call cannot be connected.
- What the...
Hey.
Do you know Ji-young?
Haven't seen her for a while,
have you?
Hush, hush.
She kept screaming,
so I cut off her tongue.
Good.
Mi-jin.
Scared?
Do you want to go home?
Why do you
want to go home?
Tell me why you should live.
No reason?
Spare me.
Please let me live!
No reason, right?
Wait! I have one!
I have a daughter.
She's seven years old.
Nobody would even know
that you're dead.
Nobody will look for you.
Don't move.
It won't hurt at all.
None of them felt any pain.
It hurts if you move around.
Damn it.
9256-4885
Your call cannot be connected.
Damn it.
Who is it?
Sorry to disturb you so late.
Is Mr. Park home?
Who are you people?
Please leave
There's no one
by that name here.
Mr. Park hasn't come
to church lately.
There's no sign of him.
There's no such person here.
Then did he move?
I don't know.
Oh, goodness, it's Pungsan.
- Honey, isn't that Pungsan?
- You're right.
How'd you get so skinny?
Let's go.
Wait a minute. Look at her.
Why are you being
so stubborn?
- Pungsan!
- I'm sorry to disturb you.
Let's go.
Something's not right.
Wait a minute.
Sorry.
Actually, he's sleeping.
Come inside.
- Do you live around here?
- Yes.
Have you seen a guy and a girl
with long hair and a pale face?
No, I haven't.
- They were just here.
- Sorry.
Why do you keep on
bothering me?
Damn it.
Fuck.
I'm busy so just give me
your number.
The insurance will cover it.
I said
just give me your number.
Forget it. Just go.
What?
It's all right. Just leave.
Don't lay one on me later.
Just give me your number.
Mister!
I'm all right, okay?
Sir.
I made a mistake,
so I should make up for it.
It's okay.
Give me your number.
I'll take care of it, okay?
I said it's all right.
I'm really okay,
so can you move your car?
You don't have to pay me.
No, give me your number.
I'll pay for the damage.
You're hurt.
Isn't that blood?
What are you talking about?
Move your car!
I said move your car!
Are you deaf?
Lady, move your damn car!
Pull out!
- Pull out!
- Hey, 4885.
It's you, huh?
Oh, brother.
Son of a bitch.
Answer it, asshole.
You're dead meat.
Get out.
Hey! You!
Hey!
Son of a bitch.
Stop, you son of a bitch!
Wait till I catch you.
Son of a bitch.
Why are you running away?
Think you'd get away?
Asshole,
what did you do with my girls?
You already sold them?
Asshole, who the hell are you?
Ji Young-min
Anyang city
What the hell?
Where's your house?
Answer me.
Answer me now.
Anyang city.
That's your address on paper.
Where do you live now?
Not talking? You block me?
You son of a bitch.
You pain in the ass.
- Move, now!
- Move your car back!
Come here.
Bastards.
You caused this mess,
asshole!
Move.
Out of the way.
- Hey, Miss!
- What kind of person did do that...
Move.
Out of the way.
What are you doing?
Get out!
Get in the car.
If there's an accident,
you should go around.
This won't solve anything.
Move your car.
Reverse!
Move back!
Sir!
Hey, you!
You can't park like this.
Is that your car?
Yes.
Are you a cop?
Yes, I am.
Show me your badge.
I left it at the police station.
This is 390.
Come in Mangwon station.
ID check.
What station do you work at?
I was in a task force unit
two years ago.
Let's call them.
Let's go to the station first.
But my girls are being sold
this very moment.
Shut up! Let's go and talk!
You son of a bitch.
I told you to shut up!
Damn it.
No answer?
No cell phone, either.
Nothing he says makes sense.
All we need to do
is go to his house.
Please write it all down,
frankly.
Yes, sir.
People like him need to be deported.
How dare you impersonate a cop!
Asshole, tell the truth.
Where did you sell the girls?
Be quiet!
Why are you shouting?
Ask that bastard directly.
You're out of line.
Ask him!
Don't just get on my case!
You really sold them?
Are you crazy?
Sorry.
He just wanted me to ask.
This is fucking insane.
Block them, idiot!
Be quiet!
Which hospital?
St. Mary's Hospital.
I'll call you from there.
Why'd you throw shit on
his face, you crazy bastard?
Yes, Captain.
I'm on my way now.
How can I stop someone
who pops up out of nowhere?
Hey, cover the seat first
before he gets in.
Yes, the rest went to
the hospital.
Yes, I'll bring him in first.
Mr. Ji Young-min,
whose car is that?
- Pardon? Car?
- Yes.
It belongs to someone I know.
Who is that person you know?
What?
What's his name?
I can't remember.
Do you know his number?
It's at home.
Something wrong?
No, it's strange you don't know
the car owner.
I have a very bad memory.
Okay, just keep writing.
Mr. Ji, does your number
start with 01 1 or 01 6?
01 6
I thought
you didn't have a phone.
What?
Where's your cell phone?
At home.
Then why did you lie?
Tell me your number.
It's 4885, right?
No.
Come on, I can find out easily.
Did you sell the girls?
No.
Come on,
did you sell the girls?
I said no.
I didn't sell them.
- I killed them...
- What?
- Nothing.
- You just said something.
- What?
- You said that you killed them.
Yes.
What?
Yes, I killed them.
Whose shit is it?
Is it yours?
History will be the judge of things!
Damn you all!
- Crazy asshole.
- What a crazy...
We're in deep trouble for this.
This is crazy.
I've been suffering.
They've stopped the water supply
and I haven't washed for ages.
Jung-ho
I can't even flush
my own shit.
Shut the hell up!
Be quiet.
What?
I'm busy now.
What are you talking about?
How do you know
whether he killed them or not?
Anyway...
Yes.
Nine of them?
He said he killed nine people?
Hey, Jung-ho.
Bastard.
That Son of...
Detective Oh.
Yes?
Remember
the Mapo murder case?
- Three murdered women?
- Yeah.
How many occurred
in Mangwon district?
All of them happened
in Mangwon.
In the ally at dawn.
Really?
Why?
Never mind.
What shall we do?
Let's take him in first.
His statement makes sense.
It does, doesn't it?
Bunch of idiots wasting time.
What did you say?
You're way out of line.
Watch what you say.
He's pretending to
be crazy now.
Hey!
Shut up, you pimp.
You're worse than
this asshole.
You sell out your old police badge
to pimp girls.
Take him to the car.
- Yes?
- Put him in the car!
Yes, sir!
We're not taking the blame
for him beating this guy up.
Let's not be like this, okay?
Let's go.
Hurry up.
Hello.
Gil-woo!
Where are you going?
Those idiots are holding him.
- And just...
- Hold on.
Can I help you?
I'm from the Task Force Unit.
Where?
The Task Force Unit
at the Seoul station.
You must've come
for the Mapo case files.
No, I came for that guy.
What?
I'm taking him in.
Sorry to wake you up, sir.
What is this all about?
It's a bit complicated.
Damn it!
Who is this?
Yes, this man is...
Is he the shit thrower?
Yes, I believe so.
Crazy bastard,
why'd you throw shit at someone?
What is he saying?
Looks like he has to urinate.
Would you like to talk to him?
Forget it.
So are you sure about this?
Yes, Gil-woo is.
Don't use him as an excuse.
- Sorry, sir.
- Okay.
You son of bitch!
Why is it so noisy in here!
Sir!
Crazy bastards.
Who's Ji Young-min?
Are you Ji Young-min?
Yes.
What happened to your face?
Are you all out of your minds?
Sir, we didn't do anything.
Shut up!
Come outside.
Come out now!
- Have a good life.
- Let me loose.
Who beat him?
- Well...
- They did it?
- I don't know, sir.
- Find out who beat him
and then bring him in.
Yes, sir!
- You know the situation we're in?
- Yes, sir.
We're all dead if this case fails.
Yes, sir.
Who did this to you?
That guy inside.
- Who?
- Hey!
There's more than
one in there!
That man over there.
Come here,
you son of a bitch.
You lie to all of them?
You son of a bitch!
- Chill.
- That little...!
Cut it out.
Let's go to the station first.
Jung-ho, you can do it there.
Right, let's go.
Gil-woo, come here.
Let's go and do it, okay?
You're sure about this, right?
Yes, I'm sure.
- Absolutely sure?
- Yes, I am.
Okay, let's go.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
- Wait! Stop!
- Why?
Where'd that bastard go?
- Who?
- Jung-ho.
Damn it.
There's that bastard.
Hey!
Come to the office!
- Okay.
- You better come!
Okay!
Owner:Kwon Hae-gab
Damn bastard.
Hey.
Hey!
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
What did you kill the girls with?
With a chisel.
The ones to crack stones?
Yes.
- Is that right?
- Yes,
it was a narrow
blunt instrument.
Okay.
I need to pee really bad.
Let me out.
Shut up.
Or else I'll yank your dick out.
Detective.
What?
Kim Mi-jin is probably still alive.
What's he talking about?
Kim Mi-jin.
The girl that guy was looking for.
Where is she now?
In Anyang city?
Why?
Why would the victim be there?
Wait, stop the car.
That's just his address on paper.
He lives in Mangwon district.
That's where I caught him.
Bastard hangs up the phone
before I'm finished.
Car registration
Who is it?
Do you know this man?
No.
These keys?
I don't know.
Look carefully.
It's the first time I've seen it.
Where did they go?
They were going to some meeting,
but I don't remember.
Yanpyung 11a.m.
Yangpyung?
Yes, I think so.
Yangpyung is...
Anyway, they must've past
the corner store.
What took you so long, idiot?
What happened?
What about Mi-jin?
I couldn't find her.
What?
See that store
across the street?
- Yes.
- See that alley next to it?
- So,
Search every house from there
to this address with this.
- What is this?
- Find houses
with basements,
where the cell phone wouldn't work.
Where is this house?
Come here.
- See that top over there?
- Yes.
Where the hell
are you looking, idiot?
That top over the cross.
Yes.
Right there.
Why don't we just report it?
They know already.
Then why
go through the trouble?
Just do what I say, asshole.
We have to find Mi-jin.
I got it.
Search every corner!
Okay!
Shit.
If you make an arrest
without a warrant,
you need approval by
a prosecutor within 1 2 hours.
1 2 hours?
Yes.
What if it isn't approved?
We have to release him.
Shit.
Where are you?
It's already two.
What have you been doing?
Why'd you go to Mangwon
after Anyang city?
Then you should've dropped off
the shit thrower.
Sit down.
So did you hit them with a chisel
or hammer them with it?
Used the hammer, of course.
Give me your hand.
Relax.
Why'd you kill them like that?
I choked them and used knives,
but they were too painful.
I saw how pigs were killed
and did the same.
And then?
- Hang them on the wall.
- What?
Yes?
Hang what?
Their bodies, of course.
Say ah.
And then?
You know that muscle
behind the ankles?
- The Achilles tendon?
- Yes.
I slice it with a knife.
- Of the dead body?
- Yes.
Why?
To drain out the blood.
Otherwise they're too heavy to lift.
That's right.
That's how
the corpses get lighter.
So what did you do next?
Leave it around for a day,
drain out all the blood and mess.
Then I ax the bodies
and bury them.
Where?
Yes?
Where'd you bury
the dead bodies?
Here and there.
Here and there is where?
Tell me exactly.
Well...
You wouldn't have buried
nine people in your front yard.
Not nine.
What?
It's twelve.
Why twelve? Wasn't it nine?
Come to think of it,
it was twelve.
Are you kidding me?
Gil-woo!
Just tell us what you remember.
You're doing well.
I was driving
and the Equus popped out.
It slammed into my car,
and this rat was driving.
That's why you beat him?
No, I held on to him
and called 4885.
- And his phone is...
- Hey.
Just answer what I ask you.
So you beat him, right?
It was you
who messed up his face, right?
What are you doing?
Yes? Now?
Yes, sir.
The chief wants to see you.
Testimony
First, press your finger.
Go to Mi-jin's house?
Yes, go with him.
- Why?
- To do a DNA test
on the blood
on his shirt and her samples.
So you actually believe
what this bastard's saying?
Hey! Just go!
I doubt this bastard killed anyone.
Just search the neighborhood.
Hey! Jung-ho!
Give me a break.
Does it taste delicious,
you bastard!
Why do you keep hitting him?
Is this time to eat chocolate?
Hey! Jung-ho!
Bastard.
Is it true that the suspect
threw human feces?
Have you identified
the suspect?
Almost there.
Turn right and go straight?
Straight in?
Steps?
Downstairs?
The first one?
Okay.
Anybody home?
Anybody there?
Of course nobody's here.
What shall we do now?
Let's go to
the owner's house.
Move, move.
What is that?
You scared me.
You should've answered
if you were inside.
- Is this the police?
- Hey, you!
Strangers are breaking in.
Mapo-gu Sangsoo-dong 21-1 5.
They're coming inside!
Give it to me.
Who the hell are you?
I'm asking you.
Are you Mi-jin's daughter?
This place is a mess.
What are you doing here?
Go stay over there.
Why are you
taking someone's hair?
You little prick, go away.
Why are you taking her hair?
Aren't you going to sleep?
You go to sleep.
You're just like your mom.
What about my mom?
You little brat.
All done. So what now?
Leave, of course.
What's your name?
Take it.
Call me
if you get into any trouble.
Let's go.
Damn it.
According to witnesses,
Bastard made me
lose my appetite.
Where's my mom?
She's working.
Then why'd you take her hair?
For a DNA test?
You're unbelievable.
My mom isn't working now,
is she?
Something happened to her?
Don't you have
somewhere to go?
How much did you search?
I'll be there soon,
so search around some more.
Also, do you know anyone
who can look after a kid?
Okay, bye.
Look behind you!
Is there a cigarette?
Yes.
Get back there.
Throw it out the window.
Is it gone?
Yes.
Is there a burned mark?
Damn it, nothing's helping me.
What a day.
You called my mom before,
right?
Didn't you ask my mom
to go to work tonight?
I'll send you back home
if you keep bothering me.
Filth.
What did you say?
What? Filth?
Get out!
The Mapo murders
are also included.
But who's this woman
that's alive?
He seems to be lying.
She's probably been murdered.
Except for the Mapo murders,
they were killed at his house
and you can't find the bodies?
No, sir.
If you don't know the address,
it means
you don't know anything.
The suspect can't remember
the address,
but we can find it quickly
if we start searching in the morning.
Why aren't his motives
written down?
He kept on talking gibberish.
No particular motivation.
Then make one up!
What the hell is this?
Yes, sir.
You know
the situation we're in?
- Yes, sir.
We die if we blow this.
Get this right
if you want to keep your jobs.
So that the mayor's incident
shuts up, okay?
- Yes, sir.
Who is it?
The police. Open the door.
Sit down.
Sit comfortably.
Yes.
Lady.
How can a sister
not know where her brother lives?
We really don't know.
We haven't seen him
for a long time.
How long?
About three years.
Where did he live then?
In prison, right?
Yes, in prison.
What a screwed-up family.
Now let's put things
in order, yes?
Like I said before,
your brother and brother-in-law
sold three of my girls.
But I've paid twenty thousand
for those girls.
What shall we do about that?
Let's sign a contract.
Why aren't you answering?
Byeong-soo!
Are you all right?
Everything's okay.
He was like this
ever since he was a baby.
My son was bleeding
when I came back home.
My damn brother
was the only one home.
Ever since then,
I barely saw my brother.
Where are we going?
I said where are we going?
We're not looking for my mom,
are we?
Be quiet!
Let me think.
Is your name Oh Eun-shil?
Why?
Your eyes are very pretty.
Shut up.
Why'd you cut your hair
so short?
You'd look sexy with long hair.
- Hey!
- Yes?
- You want a beating?
- No.
Just sit and
don't screw around.
You're not wearing
any perfume.
You must be on your period.
Smells fishy.
Is this a call-girl massage parlor?
Let me ask you something.
What's up?
We're in deep trouble.
That asshole has done this
twice before.
What are you talking about?
The prosecutor called.
Young-min said he killed
someone before.
But he was freed since
there wasn't enough evidence.
The prosecutor ordered him
to be freed.
The chief is going to
have a fit.
We're screwed.
You want to die?
Did you kill them or not?
Answer me, you bastard!
Young-min,
you told us everything before.
What's wrong with you?
Turn the camera.
Let me ask you once more.
Did you kill them or not?
I'm sorry.
Who the hell
do you think you are?
You must think
we're some damn clowns.
I checked.
Noryangjin station's warrant
was rejected by the judge.
Eunpyung station was like us.
Both stations
had insufficient evidence.
Screw them.
That asshole is the murderer.
He can't make that kind of statement
if he hadn't killed them.
That's right.
So do you want to let him go?
Or search that neighborhood
to find some evidence?
Listen carefully.
He said he buried
the victims,
- Right?
- Yes, sir.
It means he buried
the victims somewhere else.
He couldn't have buried
all 1 2 bodies in his front yard.
- In the mountain!
- Yes,
but are there
many mountains there?
No, sir.
No, there is only one.
Sungmi Mountain.
- Am I right?
- Yes, sir.
Go search there.
Find the dead bodies.
Are you really a cop?
Show me your badge.
I can't believe this.
You're not a cop, are you?
Fuck.
Fuck?
Get lost.
Repeat this number,
016-9265-4885.
9265-4885...
Find it.
See if anyone's coming!
Here.
Hyun-ju
Where is she?
Not here.
She disappeared on this day?
Don't know.
Not knowing doesn't resolve things,
you bastard.
You didn't even look for her?
Where's your dad?
He's in Brazil
Brazil?
Where in Brazil?
Rio de Janeiro.
What?
The old capital of Brazil.
What's he doing there?
Working.
Have you seen your dad?
No.
Did you talk on
the phone with him?
Damn.
What a bitch.
Better off saying Saudi Arabia.
Eat up.
What a damn temper.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Damn it.
Shit!
I've found it.
- Where?
- Right here.
Hee-jeong
Where is she now?
- Yes?
- Where's Hee-jeong?
She's gone, too?
She went to a customer.
He's a complete lunatic.
So do you know
where he lives?
No.
Then where were you two?
Somewhere around here.
Was there anything
strange about him?
A lot.
Tell me.
His dick wouldn't get hard.
Watch what
you say around the kid.
I mean,
his penis didn't get erect.
So?
No matter how hard I tried,
it wouldn't work.
He said
he wasn't drunk, either.
That meant he was impotent.
Why'd an impotent bastard
call me then?
Then what?
What else?
I treated him like a king
so that I can keep the money.
Then he kept calling me,
asking me to live with him.
I got aggravated
so I didn't answer.
Then that crazy bastard
started sending me
strange pictures.
He was covered with blood
and said he'd kill me.
He kept bothering me like that
for several days.
Do you still have the pictures?
Are you crazy?
I erased all of them.
Okay.
Did he do something?
He killed someone, didn't he?
Hey, mister!
Mister!
Hey...
Don't go anywhere.
- Where is it?
- Over here.
Here.
Are you sure this is it?
Yes, look.
Is this the wrong place?
Tell me what's going on.
Search some more
with the keys.
Why?
Mi-jin isn't here, idiot!
Let's go.
Meathead!
- Where did he go?
- I don't know!
You go over there.
I told you I'd pay you back,
asshole!
I have to live, too!
Why'd he call me out
in such a hurry?
It's a big headache.
Damn it.
- Eun-shil, go wash up.
- Okay.
Did you laugh? Did you?
Get up, asshole.
We have a guest.
Son of a bitch.
Wake me up if anyone comes.
Where is Kim Mi-jin?
I don't know who she is.
Where is she?
Where is she? Answer me!
Spare me.
Where is she?
I really don't know.
Spare me.
We shared
the same prison cell.
He visited me four months ago.
He needed a place to stay
for two weeks.
I haven't seen him
since then.
Oh yeah, I saw him once.
He came in and took his bag
while I was asleep.
What sort of bag?
A large black bag.
It had all kinds of tools in it.
What tools?
Just tools.
Like a chisel,
hammer and saw.
Did he say
where he was going?
No.
Who painted all this?
He did.
No.
Then what about a girlfriend?
Have you ever had
a girlfriend?
Yes.
How long was
your relationship?
About a year.
Then you must've had
sex with her.
Why? Are you embarrassed?
Just tell me.
Have you ever had sex
with your girlfriend?
Mr. Ji.
Have you ever had sex
with a woman?
Why do you want to know?
Don't answer
if you don't want to.
I'll ask something else.
At your house...
I asked you.
Why you do you want to know?
I thought that
you might be impotent.
How would you know?
Have you seen it?
Because assholes like you
mostly are.
You're impotent, aren't you?
When you see a woman,
you want to have sex
but you can't.
So you kill them
with a chisel, right?
You think
the chisel is your penis.
The pleasure from hammering
the chisel on a woman's head.
Stop it.
You killed young women
because of that pleasure.
Stop it. That's not it.
That's not why.
Are you curious?
I'll tell you.
Why'd you kill them?
Come here.
I'll tell you why.
Come over here.
- Just sit down.
- I'll tell you.
Go sit down, you bastard.
Sit.
I'm right, aren't l?
You want to have sex,
but your body can't.
So the women...
- What do you know?
- Let go!
What do you know?
Stop it!
Why do you keep
bothering me? Why?
Bravo.
Hey, where's the kid?
What?
Where's the kid?
- What?
- You dumb ass.
Go that way, idiot!
Over here! Hurry!
- Hurry!
- This way!
Are you her father?
You didn't sign here.
From now on,
we're searching
Mangwon to find
Ji Young-min's place.
The residents will be awake,
and we'll have more backup.
We have no warrant and
no approval, so by twelve,
bring back any evidence,
if you need to fake it, got it?
Yes, sir.
You call that a response,
you bastards?
Yes, sir!
Tell me where it is!
Where is it?
Answer me, you asshole!
Tell me!
Where is it? Where is it?
Answer me,
you son of a bitch!
What's the matter?
What is it?
Go inside.
What happened?
What did he say?
He confessed.
Mangwon, 893-1.
- Move your ass!
- Get in there fast!
Dig deep all around, got it?
Yes, sir.
Run inside!
Hurry up!
Dig inside!
You bastard!
Where were you?
You can't dig
with a walkie-talkie, idiot!
Come over here.
There's something strange here.
Not there, come over here.
There's something strange.
Yeah?
Hey, hang it over there.
Yes, sir.
Is there anything?
Look, isn't this blood?
Not blood.
It looks like hot sauce.
It is hot sauce.
Asshole.
That means he's worked here
up until six months ago.
Yes.
And you didn't know
when he came and went?
How would I know
if he sneaked in here at night?
Do you know
how many people he's killed?
Shit, this is crazy.
I really don't know anything!
- Don't yell at me.
- It's not here.
Get out.
- If we find...
- Mi-jin isn't here.
We're right here.
Her car is parked here.
This doesn't make sense.
Why doesn't it?
It's more than a 20-minute walk
from her car to here.
It's here.
Five minutes away.
Let's search there.
With the men we have,
we can finish quickly.
He told us
he buried them here!
That asshole is talking bullshit!
You bastard.
What's with you?
Is it because of the money?
When will you get
your act straight?
I don't believe this.
Ji Young-min is on his way now.
Let's talk when he comes.
Why do you move so slowly?
I'm sorry, sir.
Hey!
I told you to cover his face.
- Sorry, sir.
- Get the mask.
Morons.
Get moving!
Put him in the car!
Yes, sir.
Move your asses, will you?
You seem busy.
Ji Young-min, you should say hi
if you had seen me.
Take off your cap.
Damn it, you ignorant cops.
Have you lost your mind?
Suspect of the Mapo murder case
was arrested.
It's pitiful, isn't it?
I understand.
Shit splashes on the mayor's face.
You must be scared to death.
Set Young-min free this instant,
and bring your men back.
How about we do this?
The DNA results will be out soon.
If people find out about this,
how would they react?
A cop who got shit
on the mayor's face
forced an innocent citizen
to be a serial killer to save face.
But that citizen's face
was pulverized.
Stop what you're doing and tell me
who did that to Young-min.
Drag him down here now.
I'll do everything
to get him fired.
What the hell's wrong with you?
- Jung-ho!
- Let go.
Jung-ho, come here!
He's calling me, idiot!
He's calling me, asshole.
You better watch it!
You have to hurry and go.
Where to?
Stay still, asshole.
Bastard.
Hurry and catch him!
Are you out of your minds?
Why?
What's with this?
What?
Jung-ho!
What's going on?
The chief said to bring you in!
So why'd you hit him, idiot?
Go away!
I'll chop you down!
It's all over!
We have to give up the case
and set Young-min free!
Why? Are you crazy?
We don't have any power!
The prosecutor told us to!
If he goes out,
what about Mi-jin?
She's dead.
She died a long time ago!
So put that down now!
Why would she die,
you asshole?
Grab that bastard!
Catch him! Run faster!
Over there!
That way! Hurry!
- Catch him!
- Run fast!
Bastards!
Catch him!
Stay still, you bastard!
- Make him not move!
- You sons of bitches!
Hey! You sons of bitches!
Let go!
Open the door!
Get in!
Get in there!
Why didn't you just kill me
with the hoe?
That's enough.
Give me a cigarette.
Ji-man, give me a cigarette.
Damn it.
Give it.
Give me a lighter.
Kyung-suk,
still working back door?
Buy your mom some good food
after ripping off businesses?
It's you who's made big money,
you bastard.
Kyung-suk and l
made some money back then.
Shit, but I was the
only one who got fired.
Isn't that right?
Is your wallet full
from sucking that pig's ass?
- Does your mother know that?
- What the...
Give me the key.
Hurry.
Where's Ji Young-min?
He's probably out now.
Shit.
Taxi! Taxi!
Anybody here?
Yes?
- Oh, my goodness!
- Call the police!
Hurry!
Ma'am.
Ma'am!
Yes.
Oh, hello.
- Cigarettes?
- Yes.
What happened to your face?
It was some lunatic.
Why are there so many lunatics
in this neighborhood?
What's wrong?
I'm scared to death.
Stay with us for a while.
- Why?
- Well,
some lunatic locked up a girl
and tried to kill her.
Is that so?
Maybe it's the same guy
who hit you.
Have a nice day.
Just stay here a little longer!
- Why?
- What if that lunatic comes here?
Why would he come here?
That girl is here.
Just wait here
until the police arrive.
Help yourself to any drinks.
What's taking the police
so long?
When did you report it?
It's been quite a while.
Why aren't they coming?
- Ma'am.
- Yes?
Do you happen to have
a hammer or a club?
Why?
Well, I don't have a club.
Here's a hammer.
Seeing you stand there like that
makes me feel safe.
Just stand there like that,
and when that lunatic comes,
pound his face, okay?
Hey.
Wake up.
You're really unbelievable.
How did you get out?
Damn it.
What happened?
Gil-woo! Gil-woo!
Mi-jin!
Mi-jin...
Gil-woo... Gil-woo!
- You have to leave.
- Stop.
Don't push!
Hey!
Gil-woo!
Look after the kid.
He sent me
a strange text message.
He covered his body
with blood.
Hurry and tell me.
Right there.
What about
the telecom company?
No judge's approval
on Sunday.
Tell him to issue it
before I kill someone!
What bastard was it?
Who spilled the beans?
I told you to watch
your mouth!
Jung-ho.
Jung-ho, it's me.
You're not answering
your phone.
Don't get mad and
listen to me.
I want to quit.
I really can't take it.
I'm too scared to do this job.
Mangwon church
Here doggie, doggie.
Here you are.
May I help you?
Do you know him?
Mr. Park Dong-won.
He worked in construction.
He helped to expand
the church recently.
I saw him then.
He made that cross.
He's very talented.
PARK Dong-won
If you ask Mr. Park,
he may know him.
Mangwon district, 24-1
Where are you going?
Let's go inside.
Where is he?
Here!
Freeze!
You bastard,
what are you doing?
Jung-ho, put it down.
Jung-ho, that's enough.
Get it right over there!
Where are all the reporters?