LOST
HOBART, AUSTRALIA 1987
Thank you.
Saroo.
Hello, I'm Swarmina.
I'm John, this is Sue.
Hello there.
Hello. Here
this is for you.
Good on the plane?
Hey, good?
It's all right.
She is...
Mommy and...
Dad.
And we are so
happy to meet you.
A boat.
Amazing
This is where you live.
Down there,
that's the living room.
Television.
Do you know what a television is?
Pictures.
Water.
You can open it.
Do you want me to cut it up for you?
Pepper
What was that? Pepper.
Yes, pepper. That's right.
Sauce. Sauce?
Salt. Salt.
Very good.
Hi.
So you've come a long way haven't you?
Little one.
I'm sure it hasn't been easy.
One day you will tell me all about it.
You will tell me everything.
Who you are, everything.
I'll always listen.
Always.
Yes good.
Go easy on me, yeah? Yes.
It's all right.
Ready?
Here it comes!
How did you do that to me?
All right.
Dad, Mom, Saroo...
Mantosh.
Yes.
Hello again!
Saroo, my goodness, look at you!
Hi.
My gosh, we've been so excited!
This is Mantosh.
Hi!
Hi, Mantosh.
This is Saroo, I'm Sue...
This is Saroo, your brother.
And John... Hello mate!
Show Mantosh what you drew.
He did a picture - Yeah...
It's been a long flight. Yes Yes Yes.
You must be hungry.
We're going to get something to eat.
Would you like to join us?
Ok that would be nice.
John stop!
Stop, stop!
Come on, John!
I know I know...
It's okay. Just play with your toys.
No, no, no,
do not hit me, my friend.
You're all right.
It's all right.
Come on, it's okay.
Look, it's a boat.
It's better now.
I'm okay.
Hey!
I'm all right.
We're going to miss you.
It's only Melbourne..
It's across the water.
Saroo...
Our beautiful boy.
May this bring you all
that you could wish for.
And then some. Thanks Mom.
Thanks Dad.
From the moment you came into our lives...
Mother. "No, no let me finish.
From the moment you came into our lives,
You were all that we
could have hoped for.
More, more than we hoped for,
really.
And, uh,
more work that's for sure.
You've really embraced every opportunity.
We're very proud of you, son.
Very proud and very excited about
this next chapter in your life.
Cheers! To success!
Are you still waiting on someone?
Or can I take this plate away?
Yes, you can take it. No, you can leave it.
No, take it.
I'd like to keep it.
Thanks.
You don't really think
he'll turn up, do you?
No just leave it, son.
That's a nice one It's a good one,
it's local.
Mantosh?
Yes...
Sorry, I didn't make lunch.
What's that course again?
Hotel Management.
So you're going to
go and learn to what?
Manage your hotel?
Well, have fun.
Any bills you need to pay?
You can give us a job when you come back.
Please could you not do
anything wrong while...
Yeah, yeah "That's going
to make mom more unhappy,
than you're already doing.
Why do you think I stay away?
We see ourselves as United
Nations of hospitality schools
And we like to think that we teach
a global and balanced perspective.
You're here because you have a dream.
We're here to help make
that dream a reality.
Yes and I saw firsthand how
the hospitality industry
can really bring infrastructure
to communities that need it.
But I also saw, too,
a lot of the problems that they cause.
Which is why the community
groups need to be involved
Every step of the way and they
need to be taken seriously.
And...
And I guess I want to help facilitate that.
Give them a voice.
Saroo.
I want to run hotels that put
all the profit into my pocket.
Let's start with where you are from,
shall we?
So born in Australia?
Yeah No...uh
Calcutta.
I've got family in Calcutta.
My cousins are quite mad.
Which part?
I'm adopted, I'm not really Indian.
But you like cricket tho, right?
Ah, you like cricket...
You go for the Aussies or Indians?
I like the Aussies, mate.
This is going to be interesting.
Ok. Saroo...
Why did you choose this course?
What else do you want to get out of it?
Hi!
Welcome! Thanks for coming!
Hi how are you?
Do you guys like Indian food?
That's all we have...
It smells so good!
I've tried copying from someone.
Well, I say flashlight, what would you say?
Lampo de poche.
Lampo de poche?
Flashlight is...
Fine.
What do you say?
Torch.
If you want to eat with your hands,
Use the naan like the spoon
No, let's use the naan.
And how do you say taxi?
Taxi. Taxi.
It is the same in every language.
You want a fork, Saroo?
He's like my father.
You want another beer? Yes please.
Are you ok?
Saroo?
I'm not from Calcutta.
I'm lost.
Howrah station is enormous.
You must have been freaking out.
I once went through there on a pilgrimage
to Puri and I missed my connection twice.
You didn't speak Bengali?
I didn't even know it was called that.
How long were you on the train?
A couple of days.
A couple of days?
Saroo, what was your hometown again?
Ganestlay.
I must have had it wrong
because it doesn't exist.
There must be something
else that you do remember.
The platform...
I fell asleep on it. Next to the rain tank
That was only a few stops from Ganestlay.
There are thousands of
stations with rain tanks.
Okay, that was a long time ago.
Have you heard of this new program,
Google Earth?
It's incredible.
You can find any place from anywhere.
Listen to me, we can find out how
fast passenger trains went back then.
We took that speed and multiplied by
the hours that you were on the train.
That's it.
We create a search radius.
And inside there you'll find
the stations with the rain tank.
Yes, but it can take a lifetime to
search all the stations in India.
Did I say all the stations?
Ok even half... "Really, guys,
I don't want to talk about it"
Did your parents try to find you?
What? Of course they tried to find him.
No I just mean maybe if they tried to
find him maybe they left a paper trail
What paper trail?
My mom couldn't read or write.
What does she do?
Labourer.
She carried rocks.
Your mom?
My mother died four years ago.
I'm sorry.
My dad is still so angry with her.
Not for getting sick obviously.
Just for refusing chemo..
She just knew herself, you know?
She knew what her terms were.
She knew how she wanted to live.
Just couldn't accept that.
I guess.
And how do you feel?
I miss her.
What do you think of
Bharat's search radius idea?
What is that?
Is that your dance? Is that how you dance?
Oh god!
It's all right.
You can't keep going on like this.
Let me help you.
Let's go for a run.
What?
Lucy!
Come on.
Hold on.
I've got a cramp.
I never show anybody this.
They're beautiful.
I do enjoy it. My little hobby.
Oh wow look at Mantosh! Uh huh.
I'm so glad he's coming tonight.
Cheeky little thing.
Pure energy.
But incredible.
So sweet.
He's been hard to control but...
he is very, very smart...very
I mean, he could do anything if
he just learned to control it.
With that energy he could do it all.
Saroo is very protective of him.
I've been blessed.
Very blessed.
Your mother showed me all
your old little trophies.
Mom you didn't.
I had no idea you were so athletic.
That's only half of them.
There's plenty more in the garage.
Where are you going, mate?
I can barely get him off the couch. Lucy...
Why can't you just tell
them what you're doing?
Don't.
Tell us.
They will understand... What?
Come on.
Eat while it's hot.
Are you hungry? Yeah.
What?
What have I missed?
Nothing.
She looks upset.
She's not upset.
Saroo knows everything.
He's an expert.
He's a manager.
Why are you here?
He's here because he's your brother.
No, he's not.
We're different. Hey now, Saroo!
Saroo...
All right.
It's all right.
Hey no, no...
It's all right,
it's all right Please. Stop!
Don't move.
Nice work, mate.
I hate what he's done to you.
I'm sorry.
Saroo!
Saroo.
Hey!
Hey...
Be with me.
Stop please... Hey!
Look at me.
Look at me!
Can this wait? Where are you?
Can this wait until we get home?
Yeah? Home?
What home?
You mean where I'm alone in one room
and you're alone in the other room?
Come on.
Stop, Lucy.
Please.
Saroo!
You need to face reality!
What do you mean? Reality?
Do you have any idea what it's
like knowing that my real brother
And mother spend every day of
their lives looking for me?
How every day my real
brother screams my name!
Can you imagine the pain they
must be in not knowing where I am?
25 years, Lucy. 25!
Why didn't you tell me that?
And we just wander about
In our privileged lives.
It makes me sick.
I have to find them.
They need to know, ok?
I've never stopped you.
I want to help.
I can't do this anymore.
You deserve more.
Don't you do that!
Don't you dare do that!
This is on you not on me.
Saroo, are you there, mate?
I meant to tell you
that I fixed the tiller.
Now we can take her out.
We can head up the coast.
Saroo...
Mate, your mom is not well.
We've lost track of
Mantosh, she misses him.
You know how worried she gets...
We know you quit your job, mate.
She's worried about you, son.
I've been visiting her.
Every night I walk those streets home.
Home from the dam.
Home from the station.
I know now...
Every single step of the way.
And I imagine that I'll
whisper in her ear
"I'm here, it's all right."
What is she like?
Beautiful.
How was New York?
It's the same.
So what brings you back?
My funding came through.
That's great!
See!
They know how good you are.
I miss you.
I saw your mom.
She's not doing very well.
I'm worried it would kill her
if she knew I was searching.
You underestimate her.
She needs you.
What?
What if you do find home
and there is no one there?
And you never stop? You
just keep searching?
And you don't know what happens over time
Change, the entire world has changed.
I don't have a choice.
Stay.
I can't.
John heard Mantosh
is out on the boats
Doing a lobster run.
He's due back tomorrow.
So he'll be flush with cash
back on the hard stuff.
I'm sorry you couldn't have your own kids.
What are you saying?
We...
We weren't blank pages, were we?
Like your own would have been.
You weren't just adopting
us but our past as well.
"I feel like we're killing you."
"I could have had kids."
What?
We chose not to have kids.
We wanted the two of you.
That's what we wanted.
We wanted the two of you in our lives.
That's what we chose.
That's one of the reasons I fell in love
With your father.
Because we both felt
The world has enough people in it.
Having a child is no guarantee
to make anything better
But take a child that has
suffered like the two of you
Give you a chance.
That's something.
I bet you never imagined
it being this hard.
It's not a matter of hard
It's not a matter...
There's only one path for me.
And that's how I think
That's how this happened because
When I was 12
I had a vision.
Some people would say it
was a breakdown but it
My dad was an alcoholic you know that
He was not a good man.
He was out of control
I was standing out in back of our house
I was looking out across this field
And I just wanted the
earth to swallow me up.
And I...
I felt an electric current
that was like a shock,
A jolt through my whole body.
And then I saw...
A brown-skinned child
Across that field.
And he was standing beside me.
He was right there and I
could feel it so strongly.
And for the first time in my
life I felt something good...
I felt good.
And I knew it was guiding me.
And I knew I'd be fine.
It was... at that moment
I could see my future
Right there.
Because I always believed that I
could get this family together.
And now...
I don't know.
Where
Mother... What's happening?
I don't understand
You don't talk to me anymore
I need you, Saroo.
Mantosh!
Sorry for what I said at dinner.
Ganesh Talai...
Ganesh Talai.
Ganestlay!
I found home!
Please wait for me.
I'm here.
So this is where you've been
I did not want you to feel
that I was ungrateful.
There wasn't a day I
didn't want to tell you.
Saroo.
I really hope she's there.
She needs to see how beautiful you are!
Hi, I used to live here.
I...used to...
Can I help you?
That's me. I'm Saroo.
I used to live here.
You lived here?
Yes yeah I used to live here.
I'm looking for Guddu, Kamla, Shekila.
My mom.
Come.
Come with!
Come with me.
Just come.
Mom.
Saroo?
Saroo...
I'm sorry.
I am so sorry.
Yes, the watermelons!
Tarabuja! Yes, tarabuja!
Guddu?
Where is Guddu?
Where is he?
Guddu is no more.
He is with God.
Shekila.
Shekila?
And your brother.
It's me, Saroo.
Hello mother.
I know you'll be sound asleep.
I just want to say that I'm safe.
I'm safe and the questions
have been answered.
There are no more dead-ends.
I found my mother.
She thanks you both for raising me.
She understands that you are my family.
She's happy just knowing I'm alive.
I found her,
but that does not change who you are.
I love you mom...
So much.
And you, Dad.
And Mantosh.
Saroo!