- S. Bueno.
- Family is everything.
No?
Now, do you love your son?
S.
Now... do you understand?
You have a $10 million insurance policy.
I know that.
Georgina!
Obey me, I will love you.
Come on.
That's how it works, huh?
- Simple.
- That's right.
Mwah.
She got a sister?
How's business?
The Japanese are here in a big way.
Cheap labor, factory space.
But they feel a lot safer living
over the border in El Paso.
I ferry them back and forth.
They think I'm John Wayne.
- Ah.
- Come on.
- I live like a king down here.
- Yes, you do.
- You been workin'?
- Yeah. No.
Nah. Been movin' around,
you know.
Colombia, couple of places I can't name.
Nothing catches my fancy.
Oh.
You think God will forgive us
for what we've done?
- No.
- You don't?
Me either.
- How long you staying?
- I don't know. I just... you know.
I wanted to see you, Ray,
see how you're doin'.
You know, I came by on impulse.
Well, I could do with some impulse.
What happened?
Family paid the ransom...
then they sent the kid home
after a couple of days...
minus an ear, of course.
Now every mother in Mexico City with a little
bit of money wants bigger and better bodyguards...
my own wife included.
I hate to break it to you,
but she's right. She's right.
Look, Sammy, all my clients have, uh,
kidnap and ransom insurance.
I have a policy. A.I.G.
My dad gave it to me.
Yeah, I know.
I got it for your dad.
But what are you gonna do in 60 days
when you can't renew it?
- You can't because you don't have a bodyguard.
- I had to let Emilio go.
You gotta please Lisa.
I mean, hey, ass like that's hard to find.
Look, a bodyguard's
like anything else.
You get what you pay for, okay?
You could do this.
You get one that's got a decent rsum.
We're not looking for
goddamn Superman here, right?
Get someone cheap
till you renew the policy...
and then, uh...
then fire the prick for whatever.
Incompetence.
All kidding aside, the most important thing
is that your daughter goes back to school...
and that your wife gets to save face.
This way, you won't be the only
unprotected family in the neighborhood.
That's right. A bodyguard.
Your Spanish is good enough.
- You're crazy.
- You even look the part.
In my state,
I couldn't guard a corpse.
It's rich guys flashing their cash.
It's all for show.
- Nothing's gonna happen. - Yeah? You
think they'd hire a drunk, a has-been?
You have to keep it under control.
What if there was, you know, say,
a kidnapping attempt? What do I do then?
You do your best. They're not gonna be
paying you enough to perform miracles.
- I don't know.
- It's not exactly a scam, Crease.
- Even at half speed, you're pretty damn good.
- Yeah.
Bodyguard's gotta be close
to people though.
He gotta talk all the time,
and I'm no good at that.
You'll be the silent type.
People are gonna appreciate that.
Bodyguard. So who's the guy?
Samuel Ramos. He's a young guy.
He owns one of the plants in Jurez.
Yeah?
The Jap car industry is in the toilet.
He's trying to persuade Ford
to partner with him.
I think he's in trouble.
His family lives in Mexico City.
He asked me if I knew
anybody he could trust.
- And you thought of me.
- Yeah.
Take a job, Crease.
Breathe some air.
Then decide if you want
to stick around or not.
Besides, I'm glad to see you.
I got nobody to talk to down here.
Listen, my wife wants someone
presentable and polite.
You'll be the fifth candidate
she sees this week.
Your rsum's quite impressive.
Sixteen years of military experience,
extensive counterterrorism work.
I'm surprised anybody could afford you.
What's the catch?
I drink.
How does that affect you?
Well...
coordination, reaction time.
If top professionals try to kidnap
your daughter, I'll do the best I can...
but the service will be
on par with the pay.
What if amateurs tried?
I'd probably kill 'em.
Is that likely?
No.
No one is to know about your drinking.
That includes my wife.
Lisa!
My wife, Lisa.
And this is John Creasy.
- You're an American.
- So are you.
It's all in there.
Would you like a drink?
Yes, uh, Jack and water'd be good.
- Have you done much of this kind of work before?
- No, ma'am.
But he has a lot of experience
in related fields.
- You have a family, Mr. Creasy?
- No.
Pita.
- Thank you.
- Yes, Mom?
Honey, this is, uh, Mr. Creasy.
In English, honey.
Um, do you wanna show
Mr. Creasy to his room?
- This way, Mr. Creasy.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Just like that?
I think it's nice...
that he's an American.
I think it's terrific. You sure?
Thank you.
I feel better now.
- Hola, Bruno!
- Buenas tardes!
That's Bruno, the gardener.
And, um, that's Maria, the cook.
- Hola, Maria!
- Hola, Pita.
We fixed the room up two weeks ago.
It's nicer than before.
You've got a TV and C.D. Player.
What kind of music do you like, Mr. Creasy?
I don't know.
- You don't know?
- I don't know.
That's Bird.
Emilio forgot to take him
when he left.
Emilio was my last bodyguard.
Have you protected a lot of children
before, Mr. Creasy?
Creasy. You can call me Creasy.
And no, you're the first.
Creasy.
Bye, Creasy.
So long.
Bye, Bird.
Ow.
- School tomorrow, peeps.
- Does that mean we can get a dog?
Dad promised me one
when I went back to school.
Yeah, we'll see.
If you get a dog,
will you give up your bear?
You're getting too old for him.
- How'd you like Mr. Creasy?
- Creasy.
He said to call him just Creasy.
- Uh-huh.
- That isn't disrespectful, is it?
No, not if he asked you.
Here. There you go.
- He's like a bear too.
- Yeah?
A big, sad bear.
- Is he sad?
- I think. Or something.
- Good night, honey.
- Night.
- Oh, can you get me some floss in the morning?
- Floss?
- Yeah, the strawberry kind.
- Oh, sure.
Good night, Bear.
Creasy Bear.
What's that one for?
La Virgin de Guadalupe.
Business. For Toyota, for Ford.
If one dies, maybe she can
resurrect the other one.
I don't know.
She likes him.
- What are you talking about?
- Creasy.
Pita likes him.
Pita loves school.
Pita would love Count Dracula
if he took her back there, honey.
Okay?
- Hey. Are you okay?
- I don't know.
Okay?
I don't know, Lisa.
I'm trying.
Come on, Bird.
That's right.
That's right. Come on.
All right. Home to Emilio.
You're home free, baby.
- Where are you from, Creasy?
- The U.S.
- I know, but which state?
- No state in particular.
You can drive and talk
at the same time.
No, I can't, Pita, so, please,
let me just do my job.
Are you going to stay?
My last bodyguard left.
Somebody gave him
more money than we could.
I guess that makes me
a bargain then, huh?
Being black... is that a positive or negative
for a bodyguard in Mexico?
Time will tell.
There were 24 kidnappings
in Mexico City in the last six days.
- Four a day.
- Yeah?
- Twenty-four? - Twenty-four. What
do you think about that, Creasy?
- I think that you know entirely more than you should.
- Well, thank you.
Hola, Miguel.
- See you later.
- You have to sign.
- What?
- You have to sign in, show them your I.D.
Buenos das. Come on.
Right there.
- Hola, Manuel.
- Hola, Pita.
- Hola, Pita!
- Hola!
Pita! It's so good to have you back.
Sister Anna, this is
my new bodyguard, Creasy.
Sister Anna, the headmistress.
Seor Creasy.
Hurry. Class is about to begin.
- Go, go.
- Bye, Creasy.
- Madre.
- You must look after our Pita.
It is not good that she's late today.
I'm very sorry. I, uh... I'll have to get
used to the rules. It won't happen again.
No offense, but I regret
that your profession needs to exist.
So do I, Madre. So do I.
Do you ever see the hand of God
in what you do?
No, not for a long time.
The Bible says,
"Be not overcome of evil, but overcome... "
"Overcome evil with good. "
I'm the sheep that got lost, Madre.
When you were a kid, Creasy,
did you like school?
- I don't remember.
- You don't remember?
No, I don't remember.
It, uh... Nah, I didn't like it.
Why not?
Because it wasn't a school like yours.
There was no, uh... no Sister Anna.
Were you unhappy?
Being unhappy, Pita, that's a state of mind.
I really don't remember.
What happened to your hand?
- It's a birth defect.
- No, it's not.
Look, no more questions, okay?
- It really wasn't a question.
- It sounded like a question.
Look, I got a job to do. Hey!
No. Gracias. Gracias. No. No.
Listen to me.
I'm being paid to protect you, okay?
No, no, no. I'm being paid
to be your bodyguard.
Look at me.
I'm not being paid to be your friend.
I'm being paid to protect you,
so no more questions. That's it. Period.
- You hear me?
- Yes.
- And no crying.
- I'm not crying.
Well, don't start.
You gotta understand, this is a job.
In order for me to do...
In order for... Wait a minute.
Yeah, come in.
Mr. Creasy.
I just wanted to make sure
you have everything you need.
I'm fine, thanks.
Is the food all right?
'Cause, uh, Maria told me you didn't eat.
Uh... yeah, the food is great.
I just wasn't that hungry tonight.
So you, uh, read the Bible?
Yeah, sometimes.
- Does it help?
- Yeah, sometimes.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Sure.
How are you doing with Pita?
Fine. Fine.
Soon as she figures out that I'm
not her new toy, we'll be fine.
- Yeah, she told me about that.
- Okay.
- You don't have children, do you?
- I told you I didn't.
Well, they can be tenacious
when they want something.
- And Pita just wants to be friends.
- Okay.
But you're paying me to protect her,
right? Not to be her friend.
Right?
So, uh...
look, maybe this isn't
gonna work out.
Maybe your husband should find
somebody who's a little more sociable.
No, you're right.
You're being paid to protect her...
and I'm confident that you'll do that.
I'll be coming with you tomorrow.
I hope that's all right.
You think God
will forgive us for what we've done?
I'm tired of killin', Ray.
You think God will forgive us
for what we've done?
In my state, I couldn't...
I couldn't guard a corpse.
Talk all the time.
You know, I'm no good at that.
You know how they say...
a bullet always tells the truth?
Yeah.
- Hey.
- Crease.
What's wrong?
Hey, listen, you-you ever have a...
a nine-millimeter round
that didn't go off?
Well, yeah. Failure to fire.
I know.
Failure to fire and-and-and, uh...
You know, I pulled the trigger
and... and... and...
click, nothing.
You're talking about a bad primer.
Yeah, I... Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
But I... You know, right, dimple.
Dimple on the primer.
That may be.
Well, like we used to say...
a bullet always tells the truth.
Crease?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
What were you shooting at?
Yeah, I'm sorry, Ray.
I'm sorry I woke you.
No, i-it's okay. Nothin'.
I was watchin' TV.
Okay.
All right.
Pita, you have a pencil?
Thank you.
It's hard to get used to
the traffic down here.
Yeah. I'm very sorry.
- See you, baby.
- All right. See you later.
- Hey. Don't forget your towel.
- Oh, thank you.
Bye. Buenas das.
- You're a strong swimmer.
- I never win.
Thanks.
- So what do I do?
- What do you think you should do?
You're the fastest one in the water,
the slowest one off the blocks.
- What do you think that means? What do you gotta do?
- Get faster off the blocks.
Get faster off the blocks.
- Our big swim meet is in three weeks.
- Yeah?
- I was gonna enter the 150 freestyle.
- Yeah, you'll be fine.
You'll be okay.
- I'll still be slow.
- You're not slow.
I never finish better than third.
All right.
Maybe you are slow then.
Go! Vamos!
Vamos, Bird!
Vamos!
How do you think he got out?
- I let him go.
- It's better to be free, right?
It's better for him.
Actually, he was driving me crazy.
Good night.
- See you in a couple of days. I love you.
- All right. Love you.
Be good. Come on, Lise.
- All right, sweetheart. We'll call you from Detroit.
- Okay.
- I love you.
- Love you.
- Okay. Bye, honey.
- Seora.
- Bye.
- Oh. Gracias.
- Okay. Bye, honey!
- Bye.
- I love you.
- Love you.
I hate leaving her.
Concentratin'?
Eyes are closed?
What happened?
- I flinched.
- You flinched? The gunshot holds no fear.
- Say it.
- The gunshot holds no fear.
The gunshot holds no fear! Say it.
- Louder!
- The gunshot holds no fear!
- That's good.
You welcome the sound.
In fact, it's the sound
that sets you free.
You are a prisoner on this block
until that sound sets you free.
- Are you ready? Are you ready?
- Yes. Yes.
- Are you set?
- Uh-huh.
- Creasy?
- Hmm?
- What's a concubine?
- Why do you ask?
It's in my history book.
- Oh.
- It's like a wife, right?
Yeah. Yes, uh... Can I see that?
- Kind of a wife.
- Right there.
But the emperor of China
had 1,000 of them.
Um...
Okay, like nowadays in-in the West,
they have one husband for one wife.
But in the olden time cultures,
they had, uh...
you know, different...
uh, different rules.
- Why, you feel sorry for the husband?
- Yeah.
Can you imagine my mom
multiplied by a thousand?
Creasy. You're smiling.
- What?
- You were smiling.
- No, I'm not. No, I was not.
- You were.
- You're not now, but you were.
- You were smiling. I wasn't.
- You were.
- When?
- Like five seconds ago.
- I'm not smiling.
- A second ago you were.
- You said five seconds ago. Now that's six.
- Six seconds ago I wasn't smiling.
- Ten seconds ago.
Ten seconds ago I was smiling. Okay, in
the next 10 seconds, let's see who smiles first.
- You smiled already. See? You did.
- Mmm!
- No, that wasn't a... That was a smirk.
- Yeah, you...
That's not a smile.
A smirk is different.
They both start with "S," but they're
not the same... Do your homework.
You were.
Bang!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Come back, come back.
Bang!
Stop, stop, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop, stop. Come here.
Hurry up, hurry up. Set.
Bang!
You don't flinch when you hear
the gunshot, understand?
You listen for the sound.
You don't anticipate.
- Concentrate on the sound.
You understand me?
They're gaining on you!
Go, go, go, go, go, go! Stop! Stop!
Come on, get out.
Let's go again. Let's go again.
- Gracias. Come here, girl!
- Daddy!
Oh, I missed you so much.
- I missed you too.
- How are you doing? I got a surprise for you.
- You do?
- Ready?
- Huh?
- You got me a dog! You finally got me a dog!
- You bought me a dog, finally! Oh, my God!
- What do you think?
- Oh, my gosh.
- Just what I wanted. What's his name?
- Sam, like Dad.
Great! Come on, Sam!
Come on, Sam!
- State.
- Mm-hmm.
Bhutan.
It's a Himalayan kingdom.
They were having some problems
with their royal family not that long ago.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
Any more questions?
- Do you have a girlfriend?
- What?
- No.
What kind of question is that?
You're supposed to be studying history.
- That is history. Creasy history.
- No, that's ancient history.
- No more questions.
- Who was your very first girlfriend?
Nonya. Nonya business.
That's who.
- Okay?
- Hi.
Tomorrow after you drop off Pita,
could you take me to get my hair done?
- Yes, ma'am.
- All right.
Well, um, I'll leave you two
to your history.
- Good night.
- Good night, honey.
- Okay, now ask me.
- Ask you what?
Go, Pita, go. Go! Go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go.
Bravo! Muy bien!
- 10.99.
- Yes!
Whoo!
- I'm tough, Creasy.
- No such thing as tough.
There's trained,
then there's untrained.
- Now, which are you?
- Trained.
Trained. Okay. Let's go again.
- Here.
- Stand here near the finish line.
Okay. Hey.
I'm a prisoner in the block
until the gunshot sets me free.
- Don't smile, don't fool around if you want to win.
- Okay.
- You want to win? Trained or untrained?
- Trained.
Go.
- Seor Creasy, nice to see you.
- Oh, good to see you, Madre.
Pita's parents are away
on business in Jurez. I was...
Today you are her father.
Pita Ramos!
I won! Creasy! I won!
- Okay.
- I won!
- Once upon a time, when we were young...
- When I was young.
Well, when we were young
and he was younger...
all heads turned our way.
We made a deal
to take the world together.
Yeah, then one day
I got a call, and he said...
"I'm in love! I'm in love!
And I'm moving to Mexico. "
And... I said...
- "What happened to the plan?
What happened to it?"
I said, "The plan's right here. "
Yeah. Yeah. And what'd I do?
I hung up, then I met Alicia...
and then I went,
"Oh, now I got you! I got you. "
I got it. Can I kiss her? Is that...
Absolutely!
Hey, what are you doing?
- You got me.
- Okay, I think now is a good a time as any.
I bought it with my own money.
Open it.
It's St. Jude,
patron saint of lost causes.
Wow.
Well deserved.
Thank you, Pita. It's beautiful.
You're welcome.
- Dad.
- Yes, sweetie?
Can I talk to you?
Yes.
I don't want to play piano.
I want to swim.
It's not open for discussion,
honey, okay?
Mr. Lozzi's a very, very famous teacher,
and if he accepts you as his student...
you're gonna play the piano.
Whatever.
Baby.
- I love you.
- I just want what's best for you, you know that?
- Okay.
Okay, honey.
If you broke all my fingers,
then taped them back together...
I wouldn't be able to play piano,
but I could still swim.
Sam, get back.
Don't be a crybaby.
You're tougher than that.
Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
- Remember the day you wanted the pencil?
- Yeah.
I know why.
- Yeah?
- You wanted the license number off of that car.
I wrote it down in my notebook.
I got it all but the last number.
I'll get it from you lat...
Can you belch?
Burp. Can you burp?
That's good. That's very good.
- I just had a Coke.
- All right. Listen.
Now, this teacher,
this famous teacher...
He teaches a lot of rich kids
and plays for the symphonies, right?
- Right.
- You belch every few minutes while you're practicing.
- Okay.
- You apologize to him, but you keep belching.
- You'll offend every sensibility he has.
- Okay.
Very good. You'll be back in the pool
in 24 hours, I guarantee you.
Right, Sam?
- Hola.
- Lupita Ramos?
For you, Creasy.
Thank you.
- How does this look?
- Good.
- Hmm?
- Hola, Pita.
- Hola.
- Bye.
Gracias.
Pita.
Pita!
Run!
Creasy!
Creasy. Creasy.
I can't...
Come on!
John W. Creasy is under arrest
for the murder of two police officers...
of the Judicial Police.
Creasy!
Also involved in the kidnapping of...
Excuse me.
Everybody relax, okay?
Relax, Sammy.
I know she's your little girl.
When I tell you everything's gonna be
all right, everything's gonna be all right.
Seor Ramos.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Victor Fuentes, Anti-Kidnapping Division,
Policia Judicial.
Excuse me. I'm Jordan Kalfus.
I'm the family attorney.
Speak slower, please.
My Russian is better than my English.
Well, I'm conducting the negotiations, and
we neither need nor want police assistance.
We're gonna...
We're gonna handle this thing ourselves.
Seor Ramos,
two police officers were killed...
during your daughter's abduction.
I have a written order
from Ministerio Publico...
authorizing our participation
ex-officio.
If you want to speak to
Attorney General Diaz, it's on me.
No. Okay.
The kidnapper will tell you
to deliver the money alone.
Por favor, don't do that...
or you will find yourself
in a real Mexican hell.
No mariachi.
No tequila... and no Pita.
Crease.
When I heard it was
this hospital, I was so pleased.
There is a pastry shop nearby.
Delgado's. They have
the best pastries in Mexico.
Oh, Miguel Manzano...
director of the A.F. I...
and a former director of Interpol...
in Rome.
- And you are?
- Friend of his. Rayburn.
Rayburn?
Hola.
Do you love your daughter,
Seor Ramos?
Yes. Yes.
- Do you want to see her again?
- Yes, I do.
Seor, if your daughter's life...
is as important to you
as it is to me...
you will do as I say.
- Yes?
- Okay. Yes.
- Crease. Can you hear me?
- Hmm.
You got four of them. All dead.
- Pita.
- It's, uh...
It's been two days.
They're negotiating a ransom.
These things take time, Mr. Creasy.
Crease.
Don't fuck with me, all right?
Do you have the 10 million?
Do you have the money?
- Yes, we have the money.
- Now if you do as I say...
the girl will be returned
exactly as she was taken.
But if you deviate from
the process in any way...
I swear,
you will never see her again.
I understand. Listen, I-I too worship
la Virgin de Guadalupe.
I ask you if you understand.
Hello, sir.
This is, uh, Mr. Ramos's attorney.
He's going through a very difficult
time here, but he understands.
Do you understand?
Repeat the drop instructions.
Okay, the money, 10 million,
U.S., will be divided into...
two 15-gallon black canvas bags,
each containing five million...
which will be checked
at the bank by the K.R. Agent...
then driven to the house in an armored car
where it will be transferred to the delivery car.
You got a flat tire here.
This is for you.
Hello. Yeah.
Listen, I need a driver
to drive Samuel.
No. Why?
He's got a bad ticker.
He's got a heart condition.
Look, he's a nervous kid
who doesn't respond well to stress.
All right.
But the car will not be powerful.
Remove the trunk lid.
Use the maid's Valiant Acapulco.
You will arrive at
La Diana Fountain at 1:00 a. m.
You will drive around
the circle two times.
Samuel will remove his shirt
and hold it out the window...
to I.D. The car.
There is a pay phone
on the southeast corner.
The phone will ring.
He will answer and wait for instructions.
There is a map on the top of the phone.
Follow it.
Perfecto.
- What are you doing? He said no phones!
- Relax. Relax.
- I'm just trying to protect your daughter.
- Just get me there, please.
- What's going on?
- Hospitals can be very dangerous places.
Especially when you have
killed two corrupt cops.
Leave the money
in the trunk of the white car.
Then return to your car.
Do not look back.
Remember, I'm a professional.
If you keep your word,
I will keep mine.
- Hello.
- Mr. Ramos.
You betrayed me.
You killed my nephew.
You took my money.
Seor Ramos...
All right. Get out of here, all of you.
Get the fuck out of my house!
Okay, this is Lisa.
I'm Pita's mother.
And I'm very sorry for whatever happened
to your nephew, but I beg you...
This conversation
is not being recorded.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
I wish we had talked sooner, senora.
I'm really sorry.
Now it is too late.
Fuck off! Get the fuck out
of my fucking house now!
Get out! Get out!
Hey.
Hey, Ray.
- Where am I?
- Well, it looks like a dog hospital.
Manzano was afraid the cops
were gonna kill you.
How ya doin', Doc?
What's the matter?
She's de... dead, Crease.
It's a mess.
Somebody hijacked the drop,
and, uh...
the kidnapper's nephew was killed...
so he k... he killed Pita.
No.
Did you recognize any of these men?
No. Does that make me a suspect?
No.
It would be convenient, but no.
Um, maybe you should show me
some pictures of some Mexican cops.
- Maybe we'll get somewhere then.
- Those were all policemen.
Bad judicial cops.
Protected by a brotherhood.
Brotherhood?
A brotherhood called La Hermandad.
You all set?
- Hmm?
- Right arm. Here.
- Okay?
- Yeah. I'm all right.
Let's go.
- Somebody's on us.
- Yeah. Lois Lane.
- Who?
- Mariana something, works for Reforma.
Newspaper journalist.
Maybe she thinks you're a scoop.
I'll get you up to the border.
A friend of mine will take you to San Diego,
drop you right at the naval hospital.
- I'm not going, Ray.
- What are you gonna do?
Let's take a ride by the crime scene.
She can follow us.
Buenos das.
Mr. Creasy?
A lot of people are looking for you.
I'm Mariana Garcia Guerrero.
Reporter for Reforma.
- Nice to meet you.
- I found this across the street.
Open it.
It's Santa Muerte.
Death worship.
- They've put a curse on you.
- Ha. They're a little late.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm gonna get in my truck and leave.
I can help you.
There's a brotherhood
called La Hermandad.
It protects high-ranking
government officials, corrupt police...
and organized crime at a level
that is too difficult for me to reach.
Okay.
And I think that you and Lupita Ramos
are victims of this organization.
I want to expose them. Talk to me,
give me your story, then I can help you.
Please.
Help me do what?
You're gonna help me do what?
You're a stranger here, no?
That's right.
You're going to need friends
that know their way around.
Okay.
Okay, friend that's gonna help me.
A pleasure to meet you. Tell your driver
to keep his distance next time.
All right, friend?
S.
You'll be stateside by supper time.
I'm gonna need some help
first though, Ray.
If you don't stop bleeding,
you won't last a day the shape you're in.
- Is that a yes or is that a no?
- Yeah.
But I'm done killing.
I told you that.
- Okay.
- Anything else is yours.
- You're talking about war.
- Exactly what I'm talking about.
Can you help me?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Creasy.
Hmm.
- What are you doing here?
- Oh.
Came to get my stuff.
Couldn't find my Bible.
I thought it might be in here.
- I borrowed it.
- Okay.
It's crazy, huh?
One week we're figuring out
which nightclub to go to...
and the next thing
I'm reading the Bible.
It's a good thing.
You hold on to it.
I keep thinking,
if only we hadn't...
It's like, um...
my whole life,
all I've ever thought about...
was what I could get for myself.
Even with my own baby.
She needed me so much,
and sometimes...
I felt like I had nothing to give her.
Just, um, I don't know what to do.
- What are you gonna do?
- What I do best.
I'm gonna kill 'em.
Anyone who was involved.
Anybody who profited from it.
Anybody who opens their eyes at me.
You kill 'em all.
Yla Browning.
Hola.
Yeah, it's me.
- Mr. Creasy.
- Okay. I need the license...
Well, no, excuse me.
I need the name and address of someone
whose license number is...
C-5-T-K-8.
That's C-5-T-K-8.
I got everything but the last digit,
so I need 10 possible matches.
And when do I find out
which of the 10 it is?
- Eventually.
- Well, where do I reach you?
I'll call you.
Jordan, Angola, Lebanon.
Yes, I know all of that.
He's an assassin. And you want to help him
identify the owner of a car for him?
- Mariana.
- S.
Gracias.
Ciao.
Now, Jorge Gonzales.
Okay.
What are you gonna do?
What I do best.
Anyone who was involved.
Anybody who profited from it.
Anybody who opens their eyes at me,
I'm gonna kill 'em.
Oh, God!
"Oye Como Va. "
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Okay? Ahora.
Huh? You know who I am?
Correct.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
No s nada.
No s! No s!
Hmm?
La Voice.
Okay.
Okay. Well.
Wait, wait, wait.
Give me one cigarette, please.
- S.
- Okay.
Bueno?
Okay, my friend.
It's off to the next life for you.
I guarantee you,
you won't be lonely.
Revenge is a meal best served cold.
- La nia.
- No.
No? Vamos.
No?
Hmm?
I heard you speaking Spanish.
You're American, right?
- And so are you.
- Yeah.
- Get out of here. Where are you from?
- I'm from New Jersey.
- You from New Jersey?
- Yeah.
I'm from New Jersey.
All right, listen to me.
All right. Everything
is done up by cell phone.
You just wait around for calls,
and we don't even have a fucking number.
Who pays you?
We got an A.T.M. Card. We take out 200
fucking measly dollars every two weeks.
- Two hundred dollars?
- Yeah.
- What's the PI N number?
- The what?
The PI N number.
Code number.
- Yeah.
- Good. You wouldn't lie to me, right?
- I'm not lying, man.
- Did you kill her? You didn't kill her, did you?
No.
Don't lie to me. Don't lie to me!
Did you kill her?
Oh, man, you're making me
fucking nervous.
- Did you kill her?
- No way. The fucking boss did, or his brother.
- We never see his face.
- You're not lying to me, are you?
No. Goddamn it! I'm telling you the truth!
Tell me, who?
You never see whose face?
Well, we were in the other room...
and he was yellin' at the girl
'cause his nephew got killed...
and the money got stolen.
Wait, wait. Wh-What?
Somebody stole what money?
- The ransom money at the drop.
- Who? Who stole it?
- He said some fuckin' crooked cop took it.
- Who?
- Fuentes.
- Fuentes?
Yeah, that's right.
All right? Huh? Jersey boy?
Yeah. Now.
- This Fuentes guy?
- Yeah.
He's a lieutenant for
the Anti-Kidnapping Division.
Fuentes is. What'd you do?
- Oh, man.
- Tell me about the girl. What'd you do?
- Huh? What'd you do?
- I just do what they told me.
- You do what they tell you to do?
- Yeah.
Did you say good-bye to her?
Answer my question.
- Did you say good-bye to her?
- No!
- You didn't? Here's your chance. Say good-bye.
- Oh, shit!
Say good-bye to her.
Fucking let me go!
Rico?
Okay. Okay.
- No?
- No.
S.
- S, Guerrero.
- Listen, it's me.
Yeah, it's me. You know anything about
a young girl being kidnapped recently?
- She's about 12 years old?
- Yes, that's last night.
- Do you know something?
- What's her name?
Uh, Camilla. Camilla Valencias.
Camilla?
Se llama Camilla?
- S.
- Okay. I got her.
Where are you?
- Creasy, what happened?
- It's okay.
Sit down. Relax.
She's okay. She's okay.
You got banking connections?
Yes, I have connections.
Okay. The PI N number's 4747.
I wanna find out who's
putting money in that account.
4747.
What do you know
about a cop named Fuentes?
He's with the Anti-Kidnapping Division.
He's the one who drove
Samuel Ramos to the drop.
- Fuentes?
- S.
- Who is she?
- You can ask her later. She'll tell you anything.
- What do you know about him?
About Fuentes?
Three years ago they caught him with $50,000
and a dead body in the trunk of his car.
- Huh.
- Never charged.
Arresting officer couldn't testify
'cause he was dead.
- Is he La Hermandad?
- Mm-hmm.
- You know where he lives?
- He lives in a judicial compound.
He travels by motorcade.
Creasy, he's better protected
than the president of Mexico.
He's gonna need it.
You gonna take care of her?
- Yes. Well, how can I find you?
- I'll find you.
This is my jurisdiction.
I want this man as much as Creasy does.
He'll deliver more justice in a weekend
than 10 years of your courts and tribunals.
- Just stay out of his way.
- I plan to.
I will even help him, if I can.
But, uh, I would like to
understand him.
Give me that.
Pita Ramos...
that's a number to you.
You know, one more dead,
but a number.
What was she to Creasy then?
She showed him
it was all right to live again.
And the kidnappers
took that away, huh?
And they're gonna wish
they never touched a hair on her head.
A man can be an artist...
in anything... food, whatever.
It depends on how good he is at it.
Creasy's art is death.
He's about to paint his masterpiece.
I don't have anything else to say.
Shh. Shh.
Forgiveness is between them and God.
It's my job to arrange the meeting.
Don't move.
Put your hands down. Put 'em down.
Seor John W. Creasy...
is under arrest for the murder
of two officers of the Judicial Police.
He's suspected
of possible involvement...
of possible involvement in
the kidnapping of Lupita Ramos.
Can you hear me? Huh?
Know where we are?
We're under the bridge
where the deal went bad.
The ransom got stolen.
You wanna tell me what happened?
- Have you heard of La Hermandad?
- Yes, I have.
- Do you know what it is?
- Yes.
I'm the president of La Hermandad.
- You're the president?
- Yes.
The president? Wow.
Look at me.
Oh, you can't.
I'm sorry.
How's that?
Let me show you what I got here.
See this? This is a charger. It's used
by convicts to hide money and drugs.
They stick it in their body.
They tuck it up their rectum.
You familiar with that?
This... Look at me.
Pencil detonator.
Timer, used as a receiver-transmitter.
C-4. Highly explosive.
You put 'em all together,
you got a bomb.
Not very sophisticated,
but very powerful.
That's what you have in your ass right now.
Don't move. Don't move.
Don't move.
Cheap watch. Pager watch.
Used to send a page to the receiver
that's up your behind right now.
So, I'm gonna send you a page...
which you will receive...
in five minutes.
Now.
You got less than five minutes
to tell me what went down...
between your men and the kidnapper.
I have nothing to do with the kidnapper.
- Four minutes and 30 seconds.
- Nothing. I don't know him.
You don't know?
Four minutes and 25 seconds.
Four minutes and 20 seconds.
Are you sure?
Okay.
I got all the time in the world.
You don't, but I do.
- Hey, relax, relax, buddy.
- I'm relaxed.
You got three minutes, 59 seconds.
I saw the opportunity,
and I got lucky.
And?
And I had my men ready as we
got instructions where to go.
You had your men ready
to steal the drop.
You had your men ready to kill
one of the kidnappers, yeah?
You've done this many times.
- One of the nephews of the head kidnapper...
- Bingo. Bingo. Bingo.
- Bingo, yeah. You've done this many times, huh?
- Many times, yeah.
- Yeah. Killed many victims too, haven't you?
- Come on, sir.
- We just make out as best we can.
- "As best we could"?
Two minutes, 47 seconds.
Wait-Wait a minute. Come on.
- I have a little gift for you.
- For me?
- Yeah. Come on. Come on.
- What do you got?
There was no $10 million.
There was one half in the bags.
The ransom was $10 million?
They put it in two bags.
- Five million in each bag, right?
- Two bags, true.
But one has half paper...
the other only paper.
Maybe your men stole it.
Whoever did it
took it before the exchange.
Okay. At the Ramos house...
before the exchange,
who put the bags in the car?
- Guess what.
- What?
Ramos lawyer, Jordan Kalfus.
- Jordan Kalfus?
- Yeah.
Pedro.
Sir? Please.
I- I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry for the girl.
It was just business.
You know, I'm a professional.
That's what everybody keeps saying.
"I'm just a professional. "
Everybody keeps saying that to me.
"I'm just a professional. I'm just a professional. "
I'm getting sick and tired of hearing that.
You understand me?
What are you going to do now?
What am I gonna do?
I'm gonna leave. I gotta go.
- Yeah. I got...
- Come on. Come on. What about me, huh?
- What about you? You got 40 seconds.
- Come on.
- Thirty-five.
- A last wish, please. Please.
Last wish?
I wish you had more time.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Hola.
- Mariana, it's me.
- Creasy, where are you?
Listen, I got something
that looks like banking codes...
from Bank Coast in the Cayman Islands.
- I need it translated as fast as you can.
- Whose account is it?
Jordan Kalfus, and it looks like
U.S. Deposits and withdrawals.
Give me the same thing
on Samuel Ramos.
Samuel Ramos. That's it?
- That's it.
- Okay.
Gracias.
- Creasy.
- Samuel.
Honey?
What's going on?
That's what I wanna know.
What is going on?
Huh, Sam?
I'm gonna ask your wife a couple
of questions, okay?
You move...
you make one sound...
I'll snatch the life right outta you,
you understand?
What happened, Lisa, hmm?
Were you in on this?
- Or was it just your husband, huh?
- Am I in on what?
You know what I'm talking about... Pita's
kidnapping, her death. Were you a part of it?
- Pita got killed because the ransom got stolen.
- Shut up!
Yeah, the money was stolen.
You're right. He's right.
The money was stolen by Victor Fuentes.
How much was stolen though, huh?
- $2.5 million, right?
- What are you talking about?
He knows what I'm talking about.
$2.5 million. That's what Victor got, isn't it?
- What are you talking about?
- 2.5 million.
2.5 million to your lawyer
Jordan Kalfus...
that he put in an account in the Cayman
Islands, but he won't get a chance to spend it.
What happened to the other five, Sam?
Huh? That's 2.5, 2.5.
What is five from 10?
That's five. What happened
to the other five, Sam? Tell your wife.
- It's your chance to talk.
What happened to the other five?
- You got a wife, Creasy?
- No, I don't have a wife.
Then you'll never know how hard
it could be to tell your wife the truth.
No, you have a wife!
You tell me what happened!
It was in this room
that my father prayed.
- I don't give a fuck about your fucking father!
- My father prayed.
He prayed that his gambling debts and his
infidelities would be forgiven right in this room.
- Samuel! I love you!
- What, Lisa?
- Tell me the truth.
- I didn't inherit a kingdom! That's the truth!
You wanna know the truth?
I inherited his debt and his mess.
- I inherited his lawyer Jordan...
- You tell me what happened to my baby!
Say it! Say it! Say it!
Say it! Say it! Be a fucking man!
Jordan told me she'd sit in a room...
and watch cartoons all day...
and she'd eat ice cream
and we'd have her back in two days.
He lied to me!
That's why he's fucking dead!
I did it!
I did it, Lisa!
I agreed to the kidnapping.
I did it for us...
for the three of us.
I'm so sorry, Lisa.
You kill him.
You kill him or I will.
Huh. You know, they say a, um...
a bullet always tells the truth.
It never lies.
It didn't work for me, Samuel, but maybe...
Maybe it'll work for you.
I'll pray for you.
Gracias.
- Hola?
- Hola.
- Mr. Creasy?
- Yeah, it's me.
I traced the PIN for you
and I have an address.
Yeah?
The cardholder is Reina Rosas Sanchez,
the wife of The Voice. "
She lives in Los Arcos,
apartment 26D, Via Appia.
- Good.
- And another thing.
Pick up today's paper and you'll have
a picture of The Voice. "
Good. Thank you.
Shh, shh, shh.
Jos? Qu te pasa?
S.
Okay.
Hmm?
S.
Okay. Uh...
- S?
- S.
Aurelio Rosas Sanchez. Okay.
Okay.
S.
Huh?
Momento.
Hola, Daniel.
Seor Creasy.
Yeah. Yeah, I got your family here.
Your brother doesn't look too good.
Yeah, Reina, she's what,
about eight months?
Huh? You wanna negotiate?
The most important thing
in life is family.
Do you agree?
I agree.
And there you are.
You have my family.
Well, most of my family.
My wife and I are separated.
You know how that is.
Now, tell me seriously,
h- how much do you want?
Ah.
Your brother wants to speak to you.
Yeah, hold on.
I'm gonna take your family apart
piece by piece. You understand me?
Piece by piece. Shut up!
I don't want your money!
Do you understand me?
You understand me? I want you.
I'm listening.
I'm listening, Daniel. I'm listening.
All right,
I will give you a life for a life.
Whose life?
What are you talking about?
Whose life, Daniel? I want you.
I will give you her life for your life.
And in exchange,
I will get my life back.
- What life? Whose life?
- The girl's. Pita's.
- Pita's dead.
- Creasy!
I'm a businessman.
A girl dead is worth nothing. She's alive.
All right.
I want proof of life. You hear me?
I want proof of life.
I want... I want...
I want the name of her bear.
What does she call her bear?
You tell her to tell you...
to tell me what she calls her bear.
- Yeah?
- Creasy.
She calls the bear Creasy Bear.
Okay.
O- Okay.
I give you your brother,
you give me the girl.
- All right.
- Where?
Hello?
Lisa, listen to me. Don't hang up.
I think Pita's alive.
I can't take this anymore.
Take the road to Puebla.
Get off junction 34, south side.
I'll meet you there in two hours.
So where is she?
She's right over there.
You see those two cars out there?
Pita's kidnapper, Daniel...
this is his brother.
Here.
I'm goin' up on the bridge to get Pita.
If anything goes wrong,
you put it to his head.
You pull the trigger, all right?
You understand?
You don't...
Let him loose until she's with you.
You got it?
And you don't wait for me, okay?
Yeah.
- You'll be all right. You okay?
- Yeah.
Creasy!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
They didn't hurt you?
Hi.
Your mother's waitin' for you. She's right
down there at the end of the bridge.
- Okay? You go home.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Where are you goin'?
I'm goin' home too.
I'm goin' to Blue Bayou.
Oh, Hey.
I got something for you.
I got the last number too.
I love you, Creasy.
And you love me, don't you?
Yes, I do.
With all my heart. Pita, go.
- Go. Run.
- Bye.
Vamos!
- Pita! Baby, come here. It's okay.
- Mom!
- Come on! Okay, I'll let you go now.
Mom!