Put some stones in the vase
or it'll fall over.
This bloody wind!
Polish the letters well.
There are so many widows!
The women here
live longer than the men.
- Except poor Mom.
- Mom was lucky.
Raimunda, don't say that!
She died in dad's arms,
and she loved him more than anyone.
Burned to death!
That's the worst way to die.
They were asleep.
They didn't even realize.
Even so, how can you say
something like that!
Hello.
- Is that everything, Mom?
- I'll get the rest.
This is wonderful!
Good Lord!
- Is this Paula?
- Of course.
She's all grown up!
Give her a kiss.
She's got your father's eyes.
- How are you?
- Not good.
Don't say that.
I want to give my grave the once- over.
With this wind, you can't keep it clean.
- It looks lovely.
- Cleaning it relaxes me.
I often come and sit here on my own,
and time goes by.
We're going now,
we have to see Aunt Paula.
- Come and see me afterwards.
- Sure.
How's Paco?
He's fine, he stayed
in Madrid, working.
Mom,
does Agustina really come
and clean her own grave?
Yes, it's the custom here.
They buy a plot
and look after it all their lives,
like a second home.
- That freaks me out!
- It's tradition here.
- Shall I drive?
- Yes.
Aunt Paula!
Who is it?
Raimunda!
- Don't take all day.
- Don't rush me.
I don't like going back
in the dark.
Be nice to Auntie, don't laugh at her.
- All right.
- This house still smells of Mom.
How are you, Aunt?
You're very thin!
Have you had the baby?
- Fourteen years ago.
- Doesn't time fly!
And who are these?
Who do you think?
Sole and my Paula!
The same name as me!
And Sole.
Shall we go into the dining room?
That Sole looks like a right sourpuss.
For Heaven's sake!
...the wind carried
the cinders to the bushes.
The result is the most tragic fire
in the last 13 years.
- Mind if I turn it off?
- No, I can't see it anyway.
Fires are dreadful.
That's how your grandparents died.
- Why did I come in here?
- I don't know.
To talk?
- To get some food?
- Yes!
Look in the sideboard.
I'm very shaky on my pins.
Look, wafers!
Just like mom's.
Eat up.
How was the cemetery?
Your mother is delighted.
Did you scrub the headstone properly?
Of course.
She likes it to be clean.
If she could, she'd clean it herself.
But, of course, she can't.
Of course, she can't.
Don't you feel lonely
in this big house?
You'd be better off in a home,
where you'd be looked after.
I'm fine as I am.
- I'm going to the bathroom.
- Well, go!
You can't live on your own.
I'm worried about you.
How do you manage your meals?
Very well.
Agustina brings me bread,
your mother does the cooking
and if I need anything
I call the store and they bring it...
I'm fine.
What a lovely touch!
Look!
It's got your name on it.
Shall we go?
Yes.
We're leaving now.
I'm so shaky on my pins.
- Don't get up.
- How could I not get up?
Next time I come back,
I'm taking you home with me.
Yes, next time.
What matters is that you come back.
You've gotten very wobbly.
- Take care of yourself.
- I will.
Mind how you go!
We'll do that. I love you lots!
- Shall we go to Agustina's?
- Yes.
Come in!
Well?
- How did you find your aunt?
- Bad.
Terrible.
She's gotten very shaky.
I don't know how she copes.
he does very well
without going outside.
She eats a stick of bread every day.
She leaves the money for me.
Let's go onto the patio.
She's in an awful state, love.
She doesn't know what year it is.
She talks about mom
as if she were still alive.
For her, she isn't dead.
She can't accept it.
Sit down for a while.
I'd like to pay you something
to look in on her every day.
I won't accept anything!
I'm very happy to do it.
I'd take her home,
but I'd have to throw
my husband out to make room.
But we have to do something.
Every morning, before I go shopping,
I tap on her window
and I don't move until she answers me.
I keep an eye on her.
I really appreciate that.
I like to think...
someone's doing that for my mother,
wherever she is.
Look! Wasn't she cutting edge then?
The only hippie in the village.
Look at her plastic jewelry.
- They're awesome!
- First- rate plastic.
Every time I smoke a joint
I think of her.
That's a fine example
you're setting for Paula!
- There's still no news?
- Nothing.
It's like the earth swallowed her up.
- And your sister Brigida?
- Her?
She's in Madrid,
she's a big hit on trash TV.
Mom, I'm out of credit!
Good, we'll get a break
from the telephone.
- You can use mine.
- She'll bankrupt you.
In that case, no.
As I was saying,
Brigida is on so many shows
she can put a deposit
on an apartment in Madrid.
And she's going to make a record.
- She always liked singing.
- So did this one.
Remember when you and she,
you must've been thirteen,
went to an audition for child singers?
Hey, you never told me that!
It was your granny's idea.
She was up for anything.
Talking of mothers,
maybe yours hasn't shown up
so as not to ruin
your sister's career.
Mom would love to be on television.
She'd go crazy.
Want some?
I grow it myself. Look at the plants.
We have to leave.
Did you report her disappearance
to the police?
Brigida thinks it isn't necessary.
She's said it so often on TV.
Yes, but you have to report it
to the police, not say it on TV.
I don't know.
In any case, it's not
the first time she's left home.
But never for so long.
It's been over three years.
Don't give up hope.
And take care of yourself,
you don't look well.
Your oleander looks wonderful.
Yes, it didn't get aphids this year.
But I've really lost my appetite.
Maybe it's the joints.
No, if it weren't for them,
I wouldn't eat at all.
Your father's eyes.
A joint makes me feel a bit hungry
and it relaxes me.
Safe journey!
Guess what I saw upstairs
beside the bathroom!
What?
- An exercise bike.
- That freaks me out!
Why would auntie want a bike
if she can't walk?
Exactly, she's lost her mind.
Don't talk like that about her.
She didn't even recognize us.
It's the wind.
That goddamn East wind here
drives people crazy!
The wafers are delicious.
How can she bake those
when she's as blind as a bat?
Hello, Regina.
- Going to work?
- Got no choice, love.
- Why not give her a lift?
- Where are you going?
To the club. If you drop me
in the center that'd be great.
- All right.
- Thanks.
See you later.
- Hi, dad.
- Hi.
Hello.
Well?
Did you have fun?
In the cemetery?
You kidding me?
- Were you having a party?
- Me? What do you mean?
Paula, sit properly. Close your legs!
Will you bring me another beer?
Are you kidding?
Go on, please.
Haven't you had enough?
You have to work tomorrow.
I'm free tomorrow, and the day after too.
How come?
I was fired.
Hang on.
Christ Almighty!
I'll get a job on Sundays,
it's my only free day.
I'll get a job, but let me
watch the game in peace.
You can forget about soccer.
There'll be no more cable.
We're a poor family
and we'll live like one.
Paula, put that phone down!
Your supper's here if you want it.
Are you angry?
I'm worried about my aunt.
She's worse than ever.
She didn't even recognize
Paula and Sole.
- I don't know how she manages.
- But she does.
Leave me be.
What's wrong?
I'm worn out and I have to get up early.
I'll do the work.
Don't be a pest!
Don't call me a pest.
Sorry.
What are you doing here?
- Waiting for you.
- What for?
I called to tell you to buy bread.
you loads of times
I don't suppose you
thought to buy any.
You're soaked.
How long have you been here?
A while.
Where were you? With your pals?
I wasn't anywhere.
Why didn't you answer the phone?
What's wrong?
Is something wrong?
Tell me, what's happened?
Where's your father?
He's...
Where?
In the kitchen.
What happened?
I was in the kitchen,
with my back to him
and suddenly dad jumped on me.
He was drunk.
I asked him what he was doing
and he said he wasn't my father.
I pushed him away.
But he got up
and put his arms around me.
I pushed him again.
He unzipped his pants.
He kept saying that it wasn't wrong
and that he wasn't my father!
I took a knife from the drawer
and I threatened him
but it was only to scare him.
He didn't believe me.
He said I wouldn't dare
and he jumped on me.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Go and change, or you'll get pneumonia.
Remember, I killed him
and you saw nothing, you weren't here.
It's very important you remember that.
Don't open!
Who can it be?
I don't know.
Go to your room.
Raimunda, it's me, Emilio.
Coming!
Hi there.
I'm sorry, I know it's late,
but I'm going to Barcelona tomorrow.
I want to give you the restaurant keys
in case anyone comes to see it.
I don't mind, It's just I'm never at home.
What about Paco? He's always here.
Paco...
He finally got a job.
He's starting tomorrow.
Are you hurt?
Women's troubles.
But now that I think about it,
with Paco working
I'll have more free time.
- Give me the keys, I'll sort it out.
- Here.
This is my brother's home number.
The other is my cellphone.
- You're leaving tomorrow?
- In the morning.
Tell me, how much are you asking?
I always liked your restaurant.
It's a pity you didn't like
the owner too.
Emilio, please...
For the lease, five million,
but it's negotiable.
We'll miss you.
And I'll miss you girls.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Is Emilio leaving?
- Yes.
- Go back to your room.
- I want to be with you.
You'll have to help me later.
Don't answer!
It'll be one of your pals.
Answer it, tell them you can't talk.
This is no time to be calling.
I can't talk...
What do you mean? It's your Aunt Sole.
Put your mother on.
It's Aunt Sole.
Tell her I'm busy.
She's busy now.
Put her on, it's important.
Take the phone, Mom.
Sole, I've got a pile of ironing
and I was out working all afternoon.
Agustina rang.
Aunt Paula is dead.
- When?
- A little while ago.
Aunt Paula is dead.
Just a minute ago I was thinking
of bringing her here.
She died all alone!
Don't cry, pet.
Listen, Agustina said
we're not to worry.
She and Squinty will lay her out
before we get there.
Auntie had everything organized.
She even chose her coffin
and paid for everything.
It's incredible that
she was so lucid at the end.
I can't go to the funeral.
I'm truly sorry,
but I'm very busy.
How can you not go!
What will people say!
I can't go, not remotely.
You have to go on your own.
On my own?
No way. You know
I'm terrified of the dead.
But you needn't see Auntie.
I'll tell Agustina to make sure of that.
And if they ask for you?
Say I've had a gallbladder
operation... anything.
I'll go later, but today
it's not remotely possible.
I don't understand you.
Auntie loved you so much.
And I loved her.
I'll explain it to you some day,
and that day, you'll flip.
I'm flipping now.
Take a tranquilizer,
I'm going to take one too.
And you go tomorrow morning.
All right?
I guess...
The door!
Wait!
You stay here.
Stay here and keep watch.
I hope it hasn't changed
since I worked here.
DEEP FREEZE
Stay where you are!
Sorry.
What do you want?
Is the restaurant open?
Why?
Give me a hand.
We're shooting a film in the area
and I'm looking for somewhere
we can all eat.
Do you know
any restaurants around here?
How many are you?
25 and 5... 30.
Come on, help me.
I can do it for you, if you want.
We were going to close today.
So, lunch for thirty.
At what time?
We stop at 3:30, and we're very close.
- Around 4:00?
- Yeah.
And, tell me, how much...?
Ten euros a head.
That's fine.
I'm sorry I shouted at you,
but you scared me.
- Well, I'll see you at 4:00.
- Sure.
Thanks a lot.
It's 10:00!
- Two kilos.
- Give me another two kilos.
How much are the potatoes?
1.60 for four kilos.
- Give me eight kilos.
- Sure.
Hello, Regina.
Hello, you're carting quite a load!
I have to make lunch for 30.
- Could you lend me 100 euros?
- I'm broke, love.
I've just bought
a chunk of pork this big.
I could use that. I'll buy it from you.
It cost me 10.80, It's all I have!
I'll pay you tomorrow. Come on!
I'll bring it over to you now.
- Thanks, love.
- I'll have to diet today.
It'll do you good.
Hey, Ines! Back from the village?
I got here yesterday. How are you?
Did you happen to bring
any sausages or chorizo?
I certainly did! The sausages are great.
My mother-in-law orders them
specially for me.
- I need a kilo or so.
- Why's that?
- I have to cook for 30.
- Who's coming?
I'll tell you later.
Can I buy them? I'll pay you tomorrow.
- Sure, it's no problem.
- Thanks.
Did you bring anything sweet?
I brought some cookies
that melt in your mouth.
With the way your glucose
and cholesterol are,
I can't believe you brought cookies.
It's my only vice. Three boxes.
You shouldn't eat them.
- What do I do, give them away?
- Sell them to me.
At least let me taste them.
You can eat three or four
but don't stuff yourself.
- Bring them round to me, love.
- I'll do that.
Thanks.
Bye, pet.
Who'd like some pork? It's delicious.
You too?
Some pork? It's delicious.
Agustina?
Is that you?
Soledad,
daughter.
Sole,
I have to talk to you.
Sole!
There, there.
Take it easy.
Where is she?
Upstairs, in my mother's room,
the best room in the house.
I brought her here
to give her a better wake.
Thank you so much.
Come on, we're the principal mourners.
Good afternoon.
I spoke to your sister.
She's just had an operation.
Yes, what timing.
She said you're not to see the body.
Don't worry, you won't have to.
Say hello to Vicenta's daughter.
We'll let her rest a while,
she's very tired.
Come on.
Over here.
It was late at night.
I'd had supper and I was
watching the television.
I heard someone knocking at my door.
I wasn't sure, but just then
I heard the same noise,
and I asked, "Who is it?"
And a voice answered,
"Agustina".
I wasn't afraid.
I went outside but I saw no one.
I looked over at your aunt's house
and the door seemed to be open.
I thought it was odd,
so I went in.
I called your aunt
but she didn't answer me.
How could she answer me, poor thing?
I went into her room
and I found her there, in bed,
as still as a little bird!
It was her spirit that warned you.
But was it Paula's spirit
or the other one's?
One of the two.
I can't say who it was, I didn't see.
But just as I'm listening to you now,
someone or something
warned me that Paula had died,
and opened the door so I could go in.
Come into the kitchen.
I bet you haven't eaten yet.
No.
Not since last night, but I'm all right.
I thought as much.
This'll do you good.
Don't give me any more! That's enough.
What did the women mean?
It was just talk.
You know what villages are like.
They were talking about my mother.
Some people say they've seen her.
They say she came back
to look after your Aunt Paula.
Has she not appeared to you?
No. What about you?
No, but those things happen.
I know.
My grandfather, God rest him,
appeared to my grandmother.
At first she was frightened.
Eat up!
Then she asked him what he wanted
and his spirit told her
there was a promise
he hadn't fulfilled.
She carried it out
and the whole village
went with her to the cemetery
where they left my grandfather
so he'd rest in peace.
And he never appeared again.
That isn't just a story I heard.
I lived it.
Do you want to go
into your aunt's house
in case you want to take anything?
No, Raimunda will come later.
Tell her it went very well
and the whole village came.
I'll do that.
I'm going to miss her so much!
Go on.
Let me out, Sole!
Let me out! I'm your mother.
I won't do anything to you.
My mother is dead.
If you're anything,
you're her ghost or her spirit.
Whatever you say,
but get me out of here.
I'm in the trunk of your car.
Really, mom, the things you do!
Soledad,
daughter,
don't be afraid of me.
I'm your mother.
Aren't you going to give me a hug?
Now, give me a hand.
Take this.
- Auntie's suitcase!
- Yes.
What is all this?
Clothes, and some valuables Auntie had.
A good thing I hid them
before the neighbors arrived.
Except for Agustina,
they all went through everything,
but I'd got there first.
You'll have to give Agustina a gift,
she's been so good.
Better than your sister.
There was such a fuss
when she didn't turn up.
If you'd heard
what Squinty said about her!
Thank heavens you came.
I'm wrecked after the trip.
- Are you sleeping here?
- Yes, where do you want me to go?
What a sight!
I'm not surprised I scared you.
Do you still have the illegal hair salon?
That's how I make my living.
- Is that the guest room?
- Yes, that's it.
Tomorrow, you can give me
a color and a trim.
And I need dark glasses too.
I don't want to be
stuck in the house all day.
I have to go out.
Nobody knows me here.
In the village, I couldn't
even go to the front door.
I need a bit of air.
Are you staying for long?
- You want to throw me out already?
- No, I'm just asking.
I'll stay for as long as God wills,
if you don't mind.
When you tire of me,
you just have to say so.
But for a separated woman,
who's better company than her mother?
Unless you've got yourself a sweety-pie.
No, mom.
I'm alone, like always.
Not anymore.
Answer the phone.
- Are you back?
- Yes.
You were out of range so I rang Agustina.
She said it all went very well.
The whole village came.
I've been thinking about you all day.
I really wanted to be there.
Hang on, Sole.
What do I owe for the drinks?
They're on the house.
- Well, tomorrow, same time.
- Sure.
- The crew were very happy.
- I'm glad.
If you don't mind,
and even if you charge more,
could the helpings be more generous?
Tomorrow, you'll have food
coming out your eyes.
- Great, see you then.
- So long.
Sorry, Sole.
Have you got a job in a restaurant too?
Yes, I've taken over Emilio's place.
Good Lord!
He was sick of it,
but that's not the only news.
Paco has left us.
That's why I couldn't go to the funeral.
We were having a row when you rang.
I knew something was wrong.
Did he hit you?
Paco wasn't violent.
He's just gone,
forever.
He'll come back, you'll see.
I doubt it.
Why are you so sure?
You can tell these things.
Well, so long.
So long.
'Bye.
None of the three of us
had any luck with men.
Raimunda and I didn't, but you...
Me, what?
Dad adored you.
Raimunda says that you were lucky,
you died in the arms
of the person you loved most.
Your sister isn't a bad person
but she's got a nasty streak.
I was blind about him
and he cheated on me
until the day he died!
- What do you mean?
- It's true.
I kept that quiet all my life.
I never wanted you two to know.
But let's drop it. I don't want
to talk ill of the dead.
- Is he going to appear?
- I hope not.
And your husband?
What about him?
Might he turn up some day?
I doubt it.
I haven't heard from him in two years.
All the better. It'll just be
the two of us together.
- The pork cost you... 10?
- 10.80.
- I'll give you an extra 3 euros.
- Thanks, love.
And I'll pay you for four boxes
of cookies, not three.
Thanks.
I don't want you to think I'd cheat you.
Could you help me with this?
I can't move it on my own.
- Where are you taking it?
- To the restaurant.
You're the expert in removals.
Where do we...?
Get a hold of it,
tip it over, but not all the way.
- Otherwise we won't get it through.
- Is this all right?
Now, straighten up, to the right,
more to the right...
- We can't see anything.
- I'll guide you.
Careful, it'll come this way.
All the way...
Don't rush it.
Are we at the door?
The elevator is here.
Wait, wait. This has to go in straight.
I'll take this end.
You take it.
You're doing fine.
Good Lord! This is tough.
Careful!
Call it from downstairs.
I want them to see
we don't use frozen food.
It's all natural, fresh every day.
Over to the corner.
- And the other freezer?
- It's broken.
So you're taking over the restaurant?
Yes, at least until the crew
finishes the film.
Then I'll see.
You can count on me.
I make great desserts.
And I can serve drinks at night.
I don't know if we'll work nights,
but I'm counting on you.
- Sure.
- And thanks.
Mom...
Is there anything you want me to do?
Cut my hair.
I mean,
is there anything
you left undone in life
that won't let you rest in peace?
People always leave things undone,
or done badly,
and I'm no exception.
But I don't know if they can be fixed.
And if they can,
it's up to me to fix them.
My clients will be arriving soon.
What'll we do?
Look after them. I'll help you.
But I can't say you're my mother.
They know I'm an orphan.
- I'll say I'm a foreigner.
- A foreigner?
From where?
Dominican Republic?
No, there are lots around here,
they'd notice your accent.
Chinese?
- Madrid's full of Chinese.
- Who'd believe you're Chinese!
Something we don't have around here.
Russian!
Do I really look more
Russian than Chinese?
Yes, the Russians are like us.
Look, whatever you hear,
keep your mouth shut.
And don't let them see
that you understand us.
I'll show you how everything works.
In the bedroom, I cut, dry and color,
and here I wash their hair.
If the client is tall, lift this up.
If she's small, put it down.
This towel is to keep you from slipping.
And I keep this here
because up above it's very uncomfortable
and if it's down there
I have to bend down so often
I wreck my back.
I get a lot of backaches too.
And the shampoo is measured out.
Sit down.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Just one towel
or the client will feel suffocated.
I'm the same.
And then, with that same towel,
you dry her hair a bit
so it doesn't drip down her back.
It's all so well organized.
You're very smart, love.
Hello.
She doesn't speak Spanish, she's Russian.
They're in a terrible state.
I took her in out of charity.
When I saw her begging in the street,
she reminded me of my mother.
Don't trust all the old women you see,
especially Russians.
There are lots of mafias.
People take advantage of you.
Are you getting streaks?
Sit down here.
Wash hair, yes.
- She was a hairdresser in Russia.
- How do you communicate?
With signs. She understands
everything. She's sharp.
She'll speak Spanish in no time.
Yes, look at all the top models
who are Russian.
Heavens!
- So, Russian?
- Russia.
The water,
not hot,
not cold.
Very good.
Hello.
Hey, there.
We have a day off tomorrow.
Then we'll have one too.
We need a break.
And we finish up next week.
We wanted to have the wrap party here.
Great.
Do you want a sit-down meal
or a buffet?
A buffet would be great.
And we'd like to have
the terrace just for us.
That's no problem.
Don't look at me like that,
you make me nervous.
Same here.
Go and have a drink, I'm working.
All right.
She's been strange
since she came back from the village.
If she asks you about Paco,
you know nothing.
And it's true.
The less you know the better.
And above all
don't keep thinking about it.
Hello.
- Are you with someone?
- No.
- I'm going to the bathroom.
- What for?
I'm dying to piss.
It's broken.
I'm waiting for the plumber.
I'll throw some water down,
for Christ's sake! I have to piss.
Hello!
What's wrong with you?
- I'm at a difficult age.
- You're not the only one.
- I'm going to trim your hair.
- No, I know you.
- Just the ends.
- Less than a centimeter.
Tell me,
has your dad not come back?
No. He said goodbye for good.
That's incredible.
I just don't understand.
It smells of farts!
What's your mother up to?
What?
She's such a pain!
Ever since she was a child.
And in those days
we didn't have a bathroom.
We did it in the yard.
We'd be waiting for her all day.
All day long she'd be in the yard,
with the hens.
This dressing gown...
It's Mom's.
I know that.
And the smell?
What smell?
In the bathroom and here.
It's as if Mom had just been here,
farting her ass off!
Don't you smell it?
The way she used to fart!
And she could never hide it
because she was the first to laugh!
It's as if I can hear her now.
Don't be silly!
Why did you bring these clothes?
No wonder you have nightmares.
You give away dead people's clothes.
Aunt Paula's suitcase!
The antique dolls!
Her jewel case!
What were you going to do with this?
Nothing.
You were going to keep it.
Really, Sole.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I didn't bring the case.