He says, "Christmas."
So I say to him...
Should we go shopping?
The kid's 16.
He says,
"But, Uncle, it's Christmas."
How much you taking off?
Uncle Azim...
This is him.
The kid I am talking about.
He looks okay to me.
Ekrem, how you doing?
He looks okay, yeah,
but he won't do
one lousy thing for me.
Here. Look, Ekrem.
Take this.
Azim, please.
You see? We had a deal.
Now he's backing out.
Azim, leave the kid alone.
It's obviously
some psychological thing.
Take the fucking ustura
and finish this Rus!
Please, I need help.
Do you need methadone?
For methadone,
I need to see prescription.
Was she hemorrhaging
when you found her?
Yes.
Did you get a name?
No.
You're all right, sweetheart.
Stay with us, all right?
Baby's in distress.
Her stats are very poor.
Fetal heart rate's
at 60, 58, 57
and free falling.
Speak to me.
Placental abruption.
We need to get
the baby out now.
I'm afraid
we've lost the mother.
Okay, enough.
Call it.
Unidentified woman died
December the 20th, 23:13.
Baby girl born
20th of December, 23:14.
Did you sleep?
A bit.
Mum...
Mmm-hmm?
Are you okay?
Of course not.
It's Christmas.
Anna, where did you get this?
It's your own fault
for giving him
something to play with.
Well, I can't read Russian,
can I?
I told you, Uncle Stepan.
I found it in
the handbag of the girl
who died in my ward.
Do you always rob
the bodies of the dead?
Yes, actually.
We all do it.
It's one of the perks
of working at the hospital.
Did you know
that your daughter robs
the bodies of the dead?
I'm looking
for an address.
You have an uncle, Anna,
who doesn't steal
the things from the dead.
Not even their secrets.
Oh, don't go
all momentous on us, Stepan.
Lift your elbows.
You should put this
into her coffin.
Bury her secrets
with her bodies.
Body.
Singular.
My name is Tatiana.
My father died in the mines
in my village,
so he was already buried
when he died.
We were all buried there.
Buried under the soil
of Russia.
That is why I left,
to find a better life.
So...
You go pick up Azim
and you bring him back here
with his bitch of a wife.
Da, da. Okay.
Then I'll think of an excuse
and we can get away.
Who the fuck's that?
Maybe somebody sent your dad
a hooker for Christmas.
Man, you're so fucking
unbelievably disrespectful.
Hey, you got work to do.
Move!
See you.
Oh, no. We are closed.
Yes, I know.
I'm a midwife.
Then unless one of
my daughters is keeping
something from me,
you have the wrong address.
I was hoping to speak
to the manager.
Khitrova?
My dad was Russian.
What was your father's
first name?
Ivan.
Ivan? So you are
Anna Ivanovna.
Now come.
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
I must stir, I must stir,
or the borscht dies
in my hands.
Today, it is family.
Here is my son, Kirill.
Hurry, hurry, hurry,
hurry, hurry!
Come, come, come on.
Hurry! Hurry!
More glasses for red
over there.
My angels.
My angels,
you must practice more.
You know, you must...
You must make
the wood cry. Show me.
This is an old card,
from before the renovations.
But if she had worked here,
I would remember her name.
Perhaps she ate here once.
Try it. Try.
Try this.
My God, that's amazing.
My dad made borscht
just like that.
Anna, I'm so sorry
I couldn't help.
It is sad.
Very sad.
It's all right.
I'll probably
find out more once I get
her diary translated.
Her diary?
Yeah. I found it in her bag.
Okay, Anna,
this is how it will be.
You will bring the diary
and I will translate it
for you.
And if we get the names
of any relatives,
I will call them myself.
I can just get my uncle
to translate...
And when you come,
I will make you
some more borscht.
Like your papa used to make.
So tomorrow?
Shall we say 7:00?
Well, then it's settled.
But, for now,
you must forgive me.
Goodbye, Anna.
Anna.
You always work
at Trafalgar Hospital?
Yes. Always.
Yeah. That's good.
Nice bike.
Ural.
You don't see them anymore.
It was my dad's.
How much do you want for it?
It has sentimental value.
"Sentimental value."
I've heard of that.
Not staying for party?
No.
Nor me.
Chauffeurs don't get invited.
You want to go
for a drink instead?
Anna, how is it
that your boyfriend wasn't
here to carve?
I don't live
with Oliver anymore,
Uncle Stepan.
I'm living back here
for a bit.
For as long as you want.
I knew he would
run away from you.
He didn't run away.
Christ, you make me sound
like a burning building.
Black men always run away.
Oh, Stepan!
I'm not allowed to be honest?
He was a doctor, Stepan.
What has that got
to do with anything?
It is not natural
to mix race and race.
That's why your baby
died inside you.
Oh, shut up, Stepan!
Anna, please...
You're just how he was,
stupid, bloody,
drunken Russians.
Hello.
Yeah. It's a panda.
Coast is clear? Yeah? What?
No, not "beach."
I said "coast."
It's an English expression,
you fucking baboon.
It means...
It means, there are no police?
You're sure? Good.
No. My father
is not involved.
The driver stays down here.
Calm down.
Do you really think
I do this kind of thing?
He is not a driver.
He is the undertaker.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I don't like him.
I have converted
the upstairs rooms
into a private social club.
Some gambling, some drinking,
smoking, food, dancing.
It has been
the most surprising...
Hey.
Hey, Ekrem.
Be calm.
Slowly.
I got tickets, Azim.
It's with Chelsea.
They said there was
no tickets.
But I got tickets
for the Chelsea game.
Okay. Okay, okay.
You go watch DVD now.
Come on.
Azim?
Yeah?
He knows to say
he hasn't seen us, right?
He don't know anything.
He's been touched
by the angels.
Yeah. It's him.
He was like a brother
to me.
And now, he looks like
a fucking ice cream.
Hey! Show some respect
for a dead man.
Respect?
This is respect.
Okay, Kolya,
he's all yours.
Show some respect.
Pederast!
Have you got hair dryer?
Have you finished
cutting his hair?
I thought you might want
6.50 from his pocket.
Better burn wallet.
Okay.
Now I'm going to do his teeth
and cut off his fingers.
You might want to leave room.
You too.
Wait...
Aren't we going to
weight him down or something?
No.
If you want to dump body,
this is best place.
This is the best spot
to get rid of a corpse.
Let's go.
One...
Two...
Three...
The current will keep it down
until past the barrier.
I am so excited this morning.
Yesterday a friend came back
to our village
and he told us
all about the places
on the map that I look at,
Paris, Amsterdam, London.
He's been there for real.
He says the future
of everything was already
happening at all those places.
Anna.
I wasn't expecting you
so early.
Is that okay?
I copied the whole thing.
Where is the original?
Well, I was
going to keep it.
Thought I might give it
to Tatiana's daughter
some day.
I will need my spectacles
and a clear head.
Today, I broke my rules
and I drank vodka.
Tomorrow, I will translate it.
And then I will bring
what I've done to your home.
Where do you live, Anna?
Not far.
But I can just drop by
and pick it up.
Or maybe I can drive you home.
It's okay.
I've got my bike outside.
Come on, Kirill.
Get out.
Okay. Okay.
Get up, Kirill.
We're partners now, man.
Yeah, yeah.
You know?
Hello.
Sorry.
Where's your fucking keys?
We went to Kurdish place.
They don't even
celebrate Christmas.
Papa! What did I do?
Is it Merry Christmas,
or what?
I think he's had enough.
Who the fuck are you
to tell me, "Enough"?
Papa. Hey, Papa!
Papa!
Christ!
You've got water in it.
Water?
What makes you think that?
Joke.
Postmen used these
in my village
when I was a boy.
Russian copy. BMW flat-twin.
Same.
What?
Please.
Allow me.
Get bus.
You have far to go?
Just across the park.
I am driver.
I even do limousines.
Please.
If Semyon, my boss, finds out
I let guest walk home
in the rain,
he will fire me.
Have you ever met
a girl called Tatiana?
I met a lot of girls
called Tatiana.
She was pregnant.
In that case, no,
I never heard of her.
She died on my shift.
I thought you did birth.
Sometimes birth and death
go together.
She came in
with needle punctures
all over both arms.
Probably a prostitute
at the age of 14.
Do you think
Semyon's son knew her?
I am driver.
I go left, I go right,
I go straight ahead.
That's it.
You'll take the next right.
How much do I owe you?
Christmas present.
Morning, sir.
Morning.
How are you?
We think he might
be Russian Mafia.
And he was a member
of vory v zakone.
Stars on his knees means
he'd never kneeled
before anyone.
In Russian prisons
your life story is
written on your body
in tattoos.
You don't have tattoos,
you don't exist.
This one was a captain.
And he's been
professionally processed.
There was something else.
It was in his jacket.
Anna?
Yeah?
Stepan, come here.
Tell her
what you told me.
What? Stepan, what?
I'm late for work.
Who gave you that?
It was on the dresser.
Mum, you can't go through
my things.
You wanted him
to translate it.
Right and you didn't want to,
so I found someone else.
No, Anna.
You don't go to
someone else with this.
You don't go to anyone.
Nasilovaniye means rape.
Igla means needle.
Prostitutsiya...
Perhaps you can guess.
I'm going to wash my hands.
Anna,
Stepan said that this girl
ended up in the hands
of the vory v zakone.
Do you know what that means?
Look,
if I don't find a relative
in the next few days
they're going to put Christine
out for fostering.
Once she's in the system,
she'll never get out again.
Who named her Christine?
I had to call her something.
Sounds like Christmas.
She's so beautiful.
If I can persuade Stepan
to translate it, will you
leave the rest to the police?
Tell him I've heard
bad words before.
So which one are
we going to fuck?
What do you care?
Serious.
Pick one.
Come on.
Let me enjoy myself.
Hear me.
You are going to fuck
one of these girls.
Okay. Okay.
You're going to fuck
one of these girls now!
That's an order.
What's the matter with you?
Who are you going to fuck?
Calm down, Kirill.
I am recommending you
to my father.
I have to be sure
that you ain't
no fucking queer.
That's enough, Kirill.
Enough?
Siberian ox...
You don't tell a vor
what is enough.
I'm taking you to
my father's favorite stable.
He comes here himself
because they're all clean.
So now I'm going to
watch you fuck
one of these bitches.
So you can prove me
that you are no queer.
Psycho.
So, which one is it
going to be?
That one.
When I was little,
London was like
a place in the Bible.
I wasn't even sure
if it was real.
My friend has told me
there is a place in London
where they pay girls to sing.
He said if I sang in
this restaurant I would
make more money in a week
than my father would
in a year.
Very nice.
You did it very nice.
Yeah? Really?
Thank you, brother.
So, if my examination is over,
get the fuck out of here
while I get dressed.
What's your last name?
Tell me your last name.
Kirilenko.
Where are you from?
Ukraine.
Which village? Which town?
Irpen.
Outside Kiev.
Stay alive a little longer.
Understand?
My friend said
he would get me to Amsterdam
and from there we could
find a way into London.
I have been practicing
my singing and have even
rejoined the church choir.
I'm also practicing
my English.
My friend says his uncle
owns a restaurant
where you can sing.
He's sure this man
will take care of me.
Let's go to sleep now.
Hello, Anna.
I came on tiptoes.
How did you get in here?
There are always open doors,
Anna Ivanovna.
I'm afraid you're not
allowed in here.
Please, Anna.
Let me speak.
I translated the diary.
I was shocked to discover
that my son, Kirill,
is mentioned many times.
I have known for some years
that he has strayed
from the path
I set out for him.
His mother...
His mother died
when he was very young.
What did it say about him?
Many bad things.
But please, Anna,
let me deal with him.
If the diary should
find its way to the police...
I mean, some of the things
my son did
are illegal.
And he is a good boy.
I don't care about him.
I care about the baby.
Of course. Of course.
That is the baby.
So sweet.
I have made some enquiries.
I have found out
an address for Tatiana's
family in Russia.
That's where
the baby belongs, no?
Perhaps we can do a deal.
Do you understand me?
It's okay.
He was just leaving.
So you know where I am,
and I know where you are,
Anna Ivanovna.
I was thrown down the stairs,
and fell onto some sacks,
like potato sacks.
Kirill came down after me...
"Kirill came down after me...
...and he hit me
until I was bleeding.
- "...and he hit me
"Then he tried to rape me
but he couldn't do it.
"He just got madder and madder
and kept hitting me.
"In the end
his father came down.
"It was the father
who raped me.
"He shouted at his son,
"'lf you don't break a horse
it will never
be tame, Kirill.'"
Hello, dear.
How was your night?
Stepan's arthritis
is playing up.
I'm taking dictation.
Do you want some tea
or something?
He came to see me.
The man from the restaurant,
he came to the hospital.
I told you this!
I told you that...
I know and it's my fault.
It's no one's fault.
I have a friend from Ukraine
who's got a gun...
Stepan!
...from the war
in Afghanistan.
Don't talk about guns.
I dealt with the vory v zakone
when I worked for the KGB.
You never worked
for the fucking KGB.
I was an auxiliary!
What did this man want?
He wants the diary.
And in return he'll give us
Tatiana's family address.
Christine's family.
You cannot do deals
with those people.
This isn't a deal.
It's an exchange
of information.
Have you already forgotten
what I just read to you?
We have to be practical.
I think he was threatening
to harm the baby.
Then it's settled.
No!
Stepan!
This isn't our world.
We are ordinary people.
She was an ordinary person.
Come here.
I've got present for you.
From France.
Old as fuck!
Here.
Open one.
Old is good with wine.
Sixty quid a bottle anywhere.
Except I got this for
10 quid a case, man.
From where?
From where, you don't ask.
Now,
if Papa says okay,
I can start telling you
about the serious stuff.
Import, export.
This booze is just like gifts
for Papa's friends.
The real import stuff is
from Kabul.
You understand?
Papa! You scared me.
What's wrong?
We're just sampling.
Your friend Soyka is dead.
Yeah?
So what? It has nothing
to do with me.
No, no, no. Don't lie to me.
Papa, believe me.
I said don't lie to me!
Papa. Papa!
Don't lie to me!
Kirill. Your dad is right.
No point lying to him.
What are you saying?
Azim's nephew slit
Soyka's throat.
Kirill paid him to do it.
Shut your fucking mouth!
Your dad always
knows the truth.
It's okay, boss.
You don't have to worry.
What? I don't
have to worry?
I got rid of body myself.
Police won't find anything.
My son commits a murder
on my own doorstep.
A fellow soldier.
And no one thought
to tell me about it?
Vory v zakone code says,
"Never speak to anybody
about your captain."
Kirill is my captain.
When I find out
what happened,
we do what we have to,
to clean up situation.
Soyka was spreading lies
about Kirill.
About your family.
It was the right thing.
I decide what's right
and what's wrong.
You do not kill a vor
for no reason.
You know as well as I do,
Soyka was talking to police.
For a driver,
you are well-informed.
I have connections
with Chechens exporting cars.
They tell me Soyka speaks
to Russian desk,
Scotland Yard.
Kirill did the right thing.
He did a good thing
for our people.
They will appreciate that.
Yeah, Papa! I swear.
Shut up!
If you are so well-informed,
you will know Soyka
has brothers.
That's okay.
Kirill has got me.
It's okay?
Okay.
Get boxes out of sight.
So you heard him, patsan!
Now you get these boxes
out of sight.
Ok, ok.
Here.
Thank you.
How can you eat?
I'm hungry.
That's their driver.
Here he comes.
Meet in public place...
Lot of people around.
Very wise.
And I see
you bring bodyguards.
Also very wise.
When I was
in the KGB, we knew how to
deal with scum like you.
And you did what there?
Stepan.
Anna?
Okay.
Thank you.
Now, you give me the address.
What address?
Tatiana's family.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
See? You see?
I told you it would
happen like this.
I told you this.
Anna!
She was 14! Read the diary.
She was 14 when he raped her.
You bastards murdered her.
Calm down.
Anger is very dangerous.
Makes people do stupid things.
Please, forget any of this
ever happened.
You're in very wrong place,
Anna Ivanovna.
You belong in there
with nice people.
Stay away from people like me.
Devil!
Motherfucker!
Stepan!
I'm not sure
I can carry on another day.
The windows won't open,
so I can't throw myself out.
They inject me every day
with heroin.
Sometimes I think
this is all a hallucination.
It's always good to have
someone who I can trust
to do simple tasks.
In this business,
sometimes the biggest danger
comes from
the most stupid things.
You can't afford to
be careless in any area.
So, what was the lie
Soyka was spreading
about my son?
It was nothing important.
Kirill had him killed
for nothing important?
I don't like to repeat this.
For me, you will repeat it.
You play with the prince
to do business with the king.
If you want to
do business with me
you must be open with me.
Thieves in law.
So what was Soyka saying
about the prince?
That he's a drunk.
And also,
a queer.
My only son.
You know,
it never snows in this city.
It's never hot.
London is a city
of whores and queers.
I think London is to blame
for what he is.
Why don't you go home?
Cold gets into my bones.
Also, KGB would
be waiting for me.
FSB.
They are called FSB now.
Whatever they call them,
they are worse even
than the KGB were.
The midwife said
she had an uncle.
A Russian.
I met him.
So you know
what he looks like.
Yes, yes.
She said he has
read the diary.
You cannot trust a Russian
with that kind of information.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Perhaps you can
deal with him.
I thought that
I should bring it back
before it got stolen.
Lot of villains around.
I have address you wanted.
Small village
outside Novokuznetsk.
I know it.
Not good place
for kid to grow up.
Especially not little girl.
If you want my opinion,
she would be better off
in London.
Maybe with you. Why not?
So you've read the diary?
How can you keep doing
what you're doing?
I'm just a driver.
Why'd you bring me this?
I don't know.
I was passing.
Your uncle.
It's true he was in KGB?
I don't know.
Does he live with you?
I fixed it.
Should be okay now.
Hey! Hey!
Excuse me.
Just calm down.
Listen to me.
Just calm down, all right?
Take it easy.
Arsenal!
Wanker!
Arsenal! Arsenal!
Chelsea!
Arsenal!
Wanker!
Chelsea! Chelsea!
Arsenal. Arsenal!
For my brother...
They were going to kill me.
Those Chechens are savages.
What did they say
about my son?
They said
they would spare me
only if I delivered
Kirill to them.
You are being
very, very honest.
I... I fear you
more than I fear them.
Never again do business
with any member of my family
behind my back.
Never.
I will never listen
to Kirill again. I swear it.
Do they know
where to find Kirill?
They are like wolves.
Do they know
what he looks like?
No.
They have just arrived
from the mountains.
Tell them you will
deliver Kirill to them.
And tell them
to give you two days.
Two days.
I know now, for sure,
that I am pregnant.
It hasn't begun to show yet.
After I was raped
they made me take pills.
But I guess it was too late.
I am condemned to give birth
to a new life.
But first,
I will try to find a way
to end my own life
and spare this child the pain.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
I was passing.
Well, if you're passing,
just pass.
You keep on going, bitch.
Nikolai, come on.
You should go now.
Family's important
to you people, isn't it?
To "you people"?
What's she talking about?
I didn't catch it.
Tell Semyon,
the baby I delivered
last Sunday is his daughter.
What did she say?
I don't know.
When he raped her,
she was a virgin.
Then they gave her pills.
He has to be the father.
Kirill! Kirill!
Shut up, bitch!
Fuck her, Kirill!
Forget her.
She was 14.
She was just a child.
You don't pronounce
the name of my father.
You stop talking shit
about him.
You don't look
at her anymore.
That's an order.
Tell him what I said.
Tell him what?
There is nothing to tell.
Slaves give birth to slaves.
Tell him what I said.
Yes, you know,
the girl you fucked
the other day in front of me.
The Ukrainian bitch.
Anyway, so,
the police arrives,
some ordinary fucking police.
They just kick down the door
and ask for her by name.
Then they just
take her away.
Like some fucking punter
just might have given them
her name or something?
What gives
the right to the police
to take our women?
I don't know.
Fuck police. Hey, Papa.
I've never seen
so many old people
in one place.
Whose party is that?
The angel of death?
She is one hundred years old.
I know.
Kirill,
go down into the cellar
and bring up some brandy.
Twelve bottles.
Kolya, you hear that?
Go down in the cellar.
Get 12 bottles of brandy
for Papa.
No, no. He stays here.
I want to talk business.
Business?
What business?
Papa! What business?
His business is my business.
Go to the cellar, Kirill.
And take your time.
So, did you deal with
the old man?
Good. Good.
It's time you joined us.
Thank you...
Papa.
You, my dear friend...
... don't think ill of me.
In this wilderness...
... simply bury me.
My dad swapped
a little girl from Georgia
for this shit.
Don't feel bad for
what happened up there.
It's just how he is.
He plays people
against each other.
That's all.
I understand more and more
how he's like.
Here.
Let's drink to
the little Georgian girl.
I drink alone now?
He offered me stars.
I accept.
You think
I didn't know already?
He told me before.
It was my fucking idea.
He said now
there are a lot of things
I have to teach you.
It will take long time.
I've been protecting you
until now.
Yes, yes, Kirill.
Hey...
You think
I don't know things
that you don't know?
I am a vor by birth.
The star's
a fucking birthmark for me!
I know.
Don't you forget it.
Where the fuck do you think
you're going?
We've got to celebrate.
Come here.
Help me with the bottles.
Your dad don't need
bottles anymore.
Beautiful building...
Good evening.
Is everything ok?
Yes, everything's fine.
We can see
that you were in prison
in Siberia...
...and that you were a thief.
My father was
a government worker.
He fixed the cars
of officials.
I began by selling
the spare parts
when I was fifteen.
You have no forced tattoos?
None.
You were not cooperative?
I spent two years
in the punishment block.
You went through the Crosses
in St. Petersburg?
I was in solitary confinement
a dozen times.
I was called 'T he Stump'
because they couldn't
shift me.
Your father was a bitch
and a weak fucker for
working for the Government.
Right?
That's right.
He means nothing to me.
My mother...
You have no mother.
She was a whore anyway.
Yes.
I have no mother
and no father.
There is only the code,
the vory v zakone code...
...which I have
always followed.
That is why there is
an empty space
above your heart...
...where the stars will go.
And an empty space
on your knees.
I am dead already.
I died when I was fifteen.
Now I live in the zone
all the time.
I tried to
get hold of Stepan.
If he's not at home,
he's usually at his sister's
but she hasn't heard
from him at all.
He did spit in
that awful man's face.
I don't think
the driver would do
anything to Stepan.
How do you know?
You haven't spoken
to him since, have you?
You're late.
I know.
I'm cold.
Let's go in.
Semyon recommends these places
for business meetings
because you can see
what tattoos a man has.
Come on.
We have a lot to cover.
Let's cook.
What you were saying
about Kabul?
Yes.
Our lines to Kabul are broken
every two or three weeks.
Why?
The Americans.
Fucking NATO.
Valery Nabokov
imports flowers
and television sets
into this country.
The television sets are
one in ten.
That means
one in ten have cargo
inside them.
Where do they unload them?
I will tell you
when I return
from the bathroom.
Okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
I will be back.
Soon.
"Where do they unload them?"
Kirill is in there...
...there, there.
You will see the stars
there on his chest.
Well done.
Are you okay?
Finish him off.
Enough.
My uncle,
the one who spat in your face,
he's disappeared.
If we don't hear
from him soon,
we're going to the police.
Do you know where he is?
Yes. Scotland.
Edinburgh.
Five-star hotel.
Edinburgh?
Your uncle knew too much.
I was told
to send him to heaven
with bullet in his head.
Instead I sent him
to Edinburgh
with first-class ticket.
He's okay.
He's old school,
he understands situation.
Exile or death.
His hotel is called Caledonia.
Hello.
Hi.
Nikolai Luzhin, please.
For that patient, I will need
your security clearance
information, please.
You got my message.
Using a dead body
to file a progress report
is original.
It must be against
FSB regulations.
You didn't come here
to give me flowers...
No.
In view of what's
happened to you
and in the light of
other violent incidents
associated with you,
the Russian desk
at Scotland Yard
have made an official request
to the Russian embassy
that your undercover operation
in London be terminated.
You have gone beyond
what was agreed.
If they terminate
operation now
they will be wasting these.
So you tell the Russian desk
you have seen stars
over my heart.
Tell them
I'm through the door.
Tell them I'm going to
replace Semyon
as boss of
London organization.
What drugs are
they giving you?
I need you
to take Semyon
out of the picture.
I want you to arrest him.
Arrest him for what?
Rape.
The girl was 14.
And, of course,
she will testify?
She is dead.
But she had Semyon's baby.
If you can prove baby was his
and girl was underage,
that is statutory rape.
You have baby,
you need Semyon's DNA.
For poetic reasons
I suggest you take his blood.
What are you looking at, baby?
You.
What were you and Grandpa
shouting about last night?
Nothing, baby. Nothing.
Sounded like something.
It's just that
someone I know got hurt
so I blamed it on Grandpa.
Did you fight each other?
I heard banging.
No.
It's not a fight
if one of you
doesn't fight back, right?
Maria, go upstairs.
Go upstairs, I said.
So, Papa, what did
they want from you?
To poison me.
They took blood from me
with a needle.
Probably the same needle
they use for the junkies
and whores and blacks
and queers.
Now I probably have
the fucking queer disease.
Why would they want
your blood, Papa?
Goodbye.
Good night.
Where have you
taken Christine?
Tell me, you bastard!
You've taken her!
He took her, didn't he?
What are you talking about?
I saw Kirill. I thought...
Forgive me.
Forgive me, baby.
Sorry.
She's just a little girl!
She's just a little
fucking devochka, Papa!
Kirill.
Let me take the baby.
Please, she's cold.
We don't kill babies.
This will be bad for us.
Your father has gone too far.
You're either with him
or with me.
With him or with me.
I swear I didn't know
my Papa was setting you up.
I know.
I know, Kirill.
Give her to me.
Your father's going away.
The family business
will be yours.
It's our time.
You're the boss now.
You're the boss.
Now we are partners.
That's right.
Why don't we go home?
Come on.
I'll take you home.
No.
We're missing
the fucking party of the year!
Happy New Year!
Let's go.
Come on!
That's an order!
You are okay?
I need to know who you are.
Why did you help us?
How can I become king,
if king is still in place?
Bless you.
Goodbye, Anna Ivanovna.
It's okay.
Nikolai!
My little Russian doll...
We're gonna go
and get something.
Should we see Mama?
Yeah. Come on.
Yeah, come on.
Here she is.
There's your Mama.
Here she is,
my little angel.
My muffin.
Are you hungry?
Are you?
Who wants dinner?
My name is Tatiana.
My father died in the mines
in my village,
so he was already buried
when he died.
We were all buried there.
Buried under the soil
of Russia.
That is why I left,
to find a better life.