[Woman On P.A.] Welcome to New Tokyo International Airport. Welcome.
- Welcome to Tokyo. - Thank you very much.
My name is Kawasaki. Nice to meet you. I've heard of you. Thank you.
For you. Thank you.
And Mr. Mori from Suntory. Hi.
And Miss Shibata. Hey, I need that.
And Mr. Awinami. Nice to meet you.
All right. Thank you.
And Mr. Tanaka. Thank you. Thank you.
And we will pick you up in the morning?
Okay. Okay. See you tomorrow.
Great. Short and sweet. Very Japanese. I like that.
- My pleasure. - Yeah, get some sleep, will ya?
We're all... You're all really tired, I'm sure. See you tomorrow.
Good night. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you... What's this?
Something good? Mm-hmm.
[Elevator Bell Sounds]
Thank you.
Mr. Harris, welcome to Park Hyatt Tokyo. Yeah.
This way, please.
Mr. Harris, pleased to welcome.
Thank you. Have a nice stay with us.
This way.
Mr. Harris, welcome to Park Hyatt Tokyo.
Thank you. Enjoy your stay with us.
Thank you very much.
@ I'm in your arms @
@And you are kissing me @
@But there seems to be @
[Man #1] Finish this drink, then we'll go to a jazz club. [Man #2] Yeah.
[Man #2] You see that guy? [Man #1] Yeah.
[Man #2] You know who that is? [Man #1] It's not him.
[Man #1] It looks like him, but it's not him.
[Man #2] Can you believe it? [Man #1] Okay, maybe it is.
[Man #2] He's here with us. I'm gonna go talk to him. [Man #1] Shut up. Shut up.
[Man #2] Bob? Bob Harris? You're awesome, man.!
Sunset Odds. Loved it.
Man, that car chase... I couldn't believe it.
[Man #2] Four buses... And he took that thing and everything exploded.
I heard he did his own driving. Did you do your own driving?
I did. Cool.
[Man #1] So, what are you doing here? [Man #2] Yeah.
Um, seeing friends. Seeing friends.
[Man #2] Yeah? Great.
[Man #1] We're here on business.
[Woman] @I can see it in your eyes @ Later.
See you, Bob. Keep it up.
Are you awake?
John.
[Whispers] Go to sleep.
[Phone Rings] [Man] Moshi moshi.
[Man] All ri... Yeah, I'm coming down.
Okay. [Phone Hangs Up]
I gotta go to work. [Sighs] Okay.
I love you. I'll see you later. Okay. Bye.
Mr. Bob-san.
[Speaking Japanese]
Suntory whiskey. [Continues In Japanese]
[Japanese]
[Continues In Japanese] Suntory time.
Um, he want you to turn, look in camera.
Okay?
That's all he said? Yes.
Turn to camera.
All right, does he want me to... to... turn from the right,
or... turn from the left?
Passionate. Camera. Passion.
Right side, and, uh, with intensity.
Okay?
Is that everything? I mean, it seemed like he said quite a bit more than that.
Whiskey.
Gently. [Continues In Japanese]
Tension.
Like an old friend, and into the camera.
[Director Speaking Japanese] Whiskey.
It's Suntory time! Okay?
- Okay. - Okay?
For relaxing times,
make it Suntory time.
Cut-o.! Cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o.!
Uh, could you do it slower...
and with more... intensity?
Suntory time.
For relaxing times,
make it Suntory time.
Cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o.!
[Woman] Hello?
[Trembling] Lauren?
[Lauren] Charlotte! Hey!
Hey. Oh, my God. How's Tokyo?
It's great here. It's really great.
Um, I don't know... I went to this shrine today. Mm-hmm?
And, um,
there were these monks and they were chanting.
And I didn't feel anything. You know?
And, um, I don't know...
I even tried ikebana, and John is using these hair products.
I just... I don't know who I married. Look, can you wait a second?
Just hold on. I'll be right back. Okay, sure.
Sorry. What were you saying?
Nothing. It's okay. I'll call you later. Okay?
Okay. Have the best time. Just call me when you get back.
Bye. Love you. Bye.
[Mutters] God!
At the fitting today, they had all these...
rock and roll clothes,
but the band wasn't tough at all.
The label guy just kept saying, "More lock and loll,"
but it's just so much better if they're just skinny and nerdy like they came in, you know.
They're making them wear all these Keith Richards clothes, and it's just ridiculous.
They should let them be who they are. Don't you think?
Yeah, that's exactly what I was saying.
But then you try to... I mean, you know...
[Stammering] That's what I think.
Do you think this is done?
[Stammers] I don't know. I don't know.
Would you... Would you please stop smoking?
I like to. I don't really smoke that much.
It's just so bad for you, though.
Well, I'll stop later.
Welcome back, Mr. Harris. Yes, Mr. Harris.
Please. Thank you.
Mr. Harris? Yes?
Mr. Kazu sent me. Oh?
May I enter?
Thank you.
Do you like massage?
I don't think l... I like massage anymore.
Mr. Kazu sends premium fantasy.
My stockings..."lip" them.
[Giggles] "Lip" my stockings.
Yes, please.
"Lip" them.
What?
Hey! "Lip" my stocking!
Hey! "Lip" them? "Lip" them? What?
"Lip" them. Like this. "Lip" them.
Rip them? "Lip," yes.
You want me to rip your stockings? Yes, "lip" my stockings, please.
Rip your stockings. You want me to rip your stockings. Yes. Please? Please? Please?
All right, I'm gonna rip your stockings, and you tell Mr. Kazu we had a blast.
Oh, no! Mr. Harris! Oh, my God!
Don't touch me!
Mr. Bob Harris, don't touch me!
Just "lip" my stocking!
Oh, no, Mr. Harris!
Oh, no! Help! Help! Yeah... Yeah.
Help, please! Help, please! Okay.
Mr. Harris, help, please. Careful with those.
Oh! Help, please! Help, please! Come on. Come on.
Let me go, Mr. Harris!
Oh, no! Let me go! Come on. Come on.
Ohh! Let me go! Let me go. Oh, crap.
Please let me go. With pleasure.
Oh, no, Mr. Bob Harris, don't let me go! No!
No! Oh, no, Mr. Bob Harris! [Muttering]
Ohh! Oh, please.
Let me go, please!
[Chuckles] Mr. Harris.! Good morning.
We just got a request from Tanabe Mori. He is theJohnny Carson ofJapan.
It is a big honor to be invited to his show.
Can you stay here until Friday?
Uh, I'm surprised and honored, but I think I need to check with my agent.
Okay. Mm-hmm. I believe I may have a previous commitment.
Sure. I understand.
Shall we go? Yes.
[Man On Phone] I think you should do it. No, hear this, Fred.
I gotta be on a plane Thursday night.
We're looking into it, Bob.
They really want you to stay and do that talk show.
Apparently, he's a really big deal...
Johnny Carson ofJapan. Yeah.
Bob, these people are paying you a lot. Would you please consider it?
I already have. L-I gotta get out of here.
As soon as I can.
[Transmission Breaking Up] All right, you're scheduled to leave Friday, but we'll hold it for you Saturday.
You're breaking up, Fred. There's no reception in this studio.
Forget it. Call me back.
So, can you put your hand close your face, please?
I'm sorry, Naka. What?
Can you put your hand close your face?
I don't get that close to the glass until I'm on the floor.
How's this? [Shutter Clicks]
Yes. You want a whiskey?
This is not whiskey. This is iced tea. If you gave me real whiskey...
I need mysterious face.
Can you show mysterious? Mysterious.
I think I know what you want. You want this, right?
I need more mysterious and, uh...
More mysterious. Yeah. I'll just try to think, "Where the hell's the whiskey?"
You are a movie star, yes?
Yes, I should be doing movies, yes, but... And "Lat Pack."
"Lat Pack." You know "Lat Pack"?
Rat P... Rat Pack?
Rat Pack. Yes, please. Oh, right, right.
I need more tension, please. [Clicking Continues]
More t...
You so gentleman, yes?
A-ring-a-ding-ding. Yeah.
ʥȥ顱 ֪ʥȥ顱
"Sinatora." You know "Sinatora"?
Old Blue Eyes. Yeah.
That's good. Yeah.
That's more of Dino. That's Dino. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Great.
Joey Bishop would you like? Yes. Just change film.
Are you drinking? No?
Am I drinking? As soon as I'm done.
Okay, close your hand, please. Huh?
Close your hand. Yeah... Close it?
Yes. Close your face, please.
Close my... Yes. Sorry.
[Shutter Clicks] And, uh, 007?
He drinks martinis, but okay, I got it. 007, yeah.
"Loger" Moore?
"Loger"Moore? "Loger" Moore.
You know "Loger" Moore? Roger Moore?
Yeah. Okay. L... l...
- I always think of Sean Connery. Seriously. - No, no.
Didn't you get the Sean Connery one over here? No. "Loger" Moore.
Yes. [Shutter Clicks]
"Loger" Moore? No...
More. Please.
You mean "more," or "Roger Moore"again? Yeah. Yeah.
And sexy.!
@Are you going @
@ To Scarborough Fair @
@ Parsley, sage @
@ Rosemary @
@ And thyme @
[Man] He's really sad. [Scattered Applause]
Thank you. We're glad to be here.
We're Sausalito.
They're beautiful. They're beautiful, yeah. You know?
Send these over to that table over there.
[Man] Old temple? [John] An old temple?
Yeah. Oh, beautiful, man.
Excuse me, sir. From the woman over there.
Oh! Oh, th-they are? Really?
Yeah, yeah. Wh-What's... What's...
Is Japan... Is it mainly Buddhism here?
Yeah, it's Buddhism.
[Woman] CD or...
Yeah, CD. Playing her...
Oh, she plays... guitar? Guitar. Guitar.
That's a beautiful job.
Help!
[Kawasaki] Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning. Good morning.
Are you okay? Yeah. Fine.
[Kawasaki] Car is outside. Shall we go?
[Woman] That's what I told him.
But if... Yeah.
He never listens. Yeah.
John?
Oh, my God! John! What are you doing here?
Uh, oh, w-well, you know, uh, w... I'm just here, uh, shooting a band.
What about you? I'm here promoting that action movie I did.
Hyah! You know! [Laughs] I'm doing 20 million interviews a day.
It's crazy. Ohh!
God, it is so good to see you! Yeah. Yeah.
So, how long are you gonna be here? We're here for a week.
I'm gonna go shoot in Fukawaka.
Ohh! Oh, it's amazing!
Yeah. Oh. Oh, yeah. It's amazing.
You know... Oh, this is... this is my wife, Charlotte.
Hi! It's really nice to meet you! Hi. Nice to meet you.
Hello! [Laughing] Yeah.!
Wife? [Laughing] Yeah. Yeah.
John. John. Huh?
You are my favorite photographer.
Oh, come on! No, you are. I only want you to shoot me.
It's true! [Laughs]
I have the worst B.O. Right now. I'm so sorry.
No, no, no. But, listen, um...
- Let's all go out for a drink sometime. - Yeah.
You know? Call me. Okay? Yeah. Okay.
Listen, I'm under Evelyn Waugh.
Oh, oh, oh. Shh. Okay?
Okay, arigato, arigato.
Aah! [Laughing] Moshi moshi.!
Evelyn Waugh?
What? Evelyn Waugh was a man.
Oh, come on. She's nice.
What? You know... You know, not everybody went to Yale.
It was just a pseudonym, for Christ's sake.
Why do you have to defend her?
Well, why do you have to point out how stupid everybody is all the time?
I thought it was funny. Forget it.
Hey, John, we gotta go. Oh. Yeah.
[Man On Headphones] Did you ever wonder what your purpose in life is?
This book is about finding your soul's purpose or destiny.
Every soul has its path, but sometimes that path is not clear.
The Inner Map Theory is an example ofhow each soul begins with an imprint,
all compacted into a pattern that has been selected by your soul...before you've even gotten here.
[Woman] You know, I guess the reason why I likeJapan the best...
out of all Asian countries...
is because I really feel close to, um, Buddhism.
I really feel... I really believe in reincarnation.
That's part of what drew me to Midnight Velocity as well,
because although Keanu dies,
he eventually gets reincarnated.
So there's hope... There's hope in reincarnation, I think.
[Reporter] What was it like working with Keanu Reeves?
He was always so... He was always, you know, giving me ideas...
and, you know, really helpful.
He made me feel really comfortable, so...
And we both have two dogs, and we both live in L.A.,
so we have all these different things in common.
So, you know, we both really like Mexican food...
and yoga and...
karate!
[Reporters Laughing] [Woman Translating IntoJapanese] Mexican food. Yoga.
Konnichi wa. Hello. Hi.
Hai. Okay. Hai. Hai. Okay.
He got married a couple of times...
[Sighs] To some nice women.
Beautiful women too. I mean, you and I would be crazy for these women.
But there were always rumors.
I never liked his acting,
so I never gave a damn whether he was straight or not.
Thank you... Hi. Thanks.
What can I get you?
Um, I'm not sure.
For relaxing times, make it...
[Bartender, Bob] Suntory time.
Um, I'll have a vodka tonic.
[Laughs] Thanks.
So, what are you doing here?
Uh, a couple of things.
Taking a break from my wife, forgetting my son's birthday,
and, uh, getting paid $2 million...
to endorse a whiskey...
when I could be doing a play somewhere.
But the good news is, the whiskey works.
What are you doing?
Um, my husband's a photographer,
so he's here working and, uh,
I wasn't doing anything, so I came along.
And we have some friends that live here. How long have you been married?
Oh, thank you.
Mmm. Two years.
Twenty-five long ones.
You're probably just having a midlife crisis.
Did you buy a Porsche yet?
You know, I was thinking about buying a Porsche.
Twenty-five years.
That's a... Well, it's impressive.
Well, you figure you sleep one-third of your life.
That knocks off eight years of marriage right there.
So you're down to 16 and change.
You're just a teenager at marriage.
You can drive it, but there's still the occasional accident.
What do you do?
I'm not sure yet, actually.
I just graduated last spring.
What did you study?
Philosophy.
Yeah, there's a good buck in that racket. [Laughs] Yeah.
Well, so far it's pro bono.
Well, I'm sure you'll figure out the angles. Yeah.
I hope your Porsche works out.
Cheers to that, huh? Cheers to that.
Kanpai.
Wish I could sleep.
Me too.
@@ [Pop] One, two, three, and okay.
@@[Continues] All right.
One, two, three, four.
And one, two, three, four.
And one, two...
[Video Game: Girl's Voice] Wait.! Take me with you.!
[John Laughs] How'd it go, huh?
Oh, it was good, you know. I'm tired. Ohh.
Yeah, l-l-I gotta go downstairs and meet Kelly for some drinks.
She wants to talk about some photo thing. Maybe I'll go downstairs with you.
Oh, you wanna come?
Yeah, sure.
Okay. Yeah.
@ You @
@ Stepped out of a dream @
Everybody is always, like, "Kelly, you are anorexic."
And I'm, like, "No, I'm not." I eat so much junk food, you wouldn't believe it.
Just because I have a high metabolism.
Because I thought you were anorexic too.
Everybody does. Everybody thinks that. Yeah, 'cause you look so...
Thank you! I know, but it's...
I mean, I eat whatever. I have a really high metabolism.
Yeah. But, um...
My dad was an anorexic.
Really? Oh, really?
He, um, fought on the American side of the Bay of Pigs in Cuba.
He was taken prisoner, and the whole time he was there they tortured him about food.
Every day they told him they put poison in the food.
So they would always make themselves throw up after every meal.
That's horrible. That's terrible.
That's some crazy shit.
You don't think he sounds kinda goofy? No!
You know that break beat, right? Well, I been takin' it to some next level shit.
Like, I'll take that and put a delay on it, so it's like...
So it's, like, evolving, the beat.
So it, like, sounds hella large on the track. You know what I'm sayin'?
You don't listen to hip-hop? Uh...
Oh, my God! You guys gotta listen.
I tried this power cleanse. It's so amazing.
Okay, promise me you'll try it. Will you try this power cleanse?
I did it last week, and it's amazing. I'll be right back.
It's so good to get the toxins out of your body.
With all, like, the pollution, all, like, the...
Hello. Hello.
You ever switch seats? [Chuckles]
Uh, I like this one. If I fall, someone will notice.
So, you having a nice time?
Can you keep a secret?
I'm trying to organize a prison break.
I'm looking for, like, an accomplice. [Laughs]
We'd have to, first, get out of this bar.
Then the hotel, then the city, and then the country.
Are you in, or are you out? I'm in.
Good. I'll go pack my stuff.
Get your coat. [Chuckling] See ya.
I hope you've had enough to drink. It's gonna take courage.
Oh, look. The label got me these.
Mmm, I love Cristal. You wanna have some?
Well, I'm... [Stammers] I gotta go. I mean, l...
Y-You know, you don't have to stay.
I mean... You don't have to go, do you?
[Laughs] Well, l... [Stammering]
I know. You're gonna be working the whole time.
I'll have a much better time here. I'll call Charlie and those guys. Yeah! Call those guys.
And I'm gonna be back on Sunday, and l...
I love you, you know.
[Whispers] Okay? [Whispers] I love you.
I'll see you. Okay? Yeah, it's just gonna be a couple of... a couple of days.
I love you.
[Giggles] Hello.
Hello. How are you?
Good. How are you?
It's a cool pool, isn't it? Yeah, it's nice.
Get any sleep?
Not yet. [Chuckles] How about you?
No. Not yet.
[Both Laugh] How long you staying for?
I'll be in the bar for the rest of the week. [Laughs]
Well, that's good.
Um, I'm going out with some friends later, if you wanna come.
Sure. Okay. I'll see you later.
Okay. See ya.
"Bob, which one do you want for your study?
I like the burgundy, but whatever you want."
Which one is burgundy?
Hold on! [Giggles]
Hold on.
[Giggles] You really are having a midlife crisis, huh?
Really? Yeah, I was afraid of that. Mmm.
I kept telling myself that I just wanted to be ready in case we go to war tonight.
My bathroom is messier than yours.
And it's not like you're not tryin'.
Here, will you cut the tag out for me? Sure.
You're too tall.
Uh, anybody ever tell you you may be too small?
Whose is this? "A Soul's Search: Finding Your True Calling."
I don't know.
I have that. Did it work out for you, then?
[Laughing] Obviously.
Where's your shoes? They're over here.
- Where's your room key? - It's in my bag.
- And where's your bag? - It's right here.
Let's go. Wait!
There's the elevator. I gotta go. Hey! [Giggles]
Hi! How are you? Hi, Charlie!
Um, Bob, this is Charlie Brown.
Hi. Nice to meet you. How are you? Nice to meet you.
- This is Bambi. - How are you, Bambi?
His real name's Hayashi, but... Why do they call you Charlie Brown?
Everybody say, "He looks like Charlie Brown." You know, Snoopy, man.
Oh, I'll be right back.
Bob, over here. These are my friends. Very beautiful.
ǡB Ǥߤ
She's "B," and she's Rico, and she's Myumi.
ߤãҽб  ޣ
- Myumi. How are you? I'm Bob. - Oh! Bob.
Bob from United States, man.
Ahh! Hi, Bob.
Maybe you'd like to sing backup for me.
- [Charlie] This is my surfing teacher. - He's your surfing teacher?
Sometime, sometime. You're a surfer?
[Speaking French]
Oh, oui, oui. The emperor's house? Cool.
[Continues In French]
Yeah? Yeah. [Continues In French]
Cool.! Right.
You don't have anything... Do you have anything b...
Hey. Hey. How you doin'?
- Good. How are you? - MyJapanese is getting better.
We started speaking English.
Charlie.
- [Gunfire] - Ooh! Get out, guys!
- [Bob] I'm leaving! - [Charlotte Laughing] They'll sting.!
- Who are these guys, anyway? - [Charlie Shouting In Japanese]
[Bob] Oh, no. [Gunfire Continues]
Come on!
[Charlie] Hey, guys! Over here!
Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Wait! Our tour guide!
[Charlie] Hurry up.!
Yeah? Gorgeous.
Gorgeous? Blonde and black.
[Male Singer] @ Well, it's a feelin'I get @
- Cheese. Cheese-o.! - Cheese!
Yeah, yeah... Hi. @It's a feelin'I get @@
Hi, I'm Hans. Nice to meet you.
I'm Charlotte. Nice to meet you.
Last weekend, I went surfing. Right.
About seven people, you know. Some friends.
And we camp over there on the beach.
[Laughing] In fact, we made a kind of...
Wait. What kind of weed is it? I don't know.
@Baby, when I saw you turnin' at the end of the street @
@I knew our time was gone @
@Into blank pages @
@Just understand I was afraid to be a simple guy @
@I tried my best to smile @
@But deep inside my heart @
@I felt like the shell that a crab comes in @
@I guess I couldn't live without things @@
@ God save the queen @
@ A fascist regime @
@ It made you a moron @
@Apotential H-bomb @
@ God save the queen @
@ She ain't no human being @
@ There's no future @
@ In England's dreaming @@
@@[Rock]
@ As I walk through @
@ This wicked world @
@ Searchin' for light in the darkness @ [Cheering]
@ Of insanity @
@ I ask myself @
@ Is all hope lost @
@ Is there only pain @
@ And hatred @
@And misery @
@And each time I feel like this inside @
@ There's one thing I want to know @
@ What's so funny 'bout peace, love and understanding @
[Cheering] @ Ohh-oh-oh-oh-ohh @
@ What's so funny 'bout peace, love and understanding @@
@ I'm winkin' at ya @
@ Gonna make you, make you make you notice @
@ Gonna use my arms @
@ Gonna use my legs @
@ Gonna use my style @
@ Gonna use my sidestep @
@ Gonna use my fingers @
@ Gonna use my, my, my @ [Charlie] @My, my, my @
@ Imagination, oh-ohh @
@ 'Cause I'm @
@ Gonna make you see @
@ Nobody else here No one like me @
- @ I'm special @ - [Falsetto] @ Special @
@So special @ Special?
@I gotta have some of your @
@ Attention Give it to me @@
@@[Pop] Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Bob Harris.
Thanks. This is hard.
[Clears Throat] Oh, Jesus.
@ I could feel at the time @
@ There was no way of knowing @
@ Fallen leaves in the night @
@ Who can say where they're blowin'@
@As free as the wind @
@ Hopefully learnin' @
@ Why the sea on the tide @
@ Has no way of turnin' @
@ More than this @
@ You know there's nothing @
@ Tell me one thing @
@ More than this @
@ Ooh, there's nothing @@
@@[Karaoke Continues, Singer Faint, Indistinct]
@@[Rock]
[Man] @ Close my eyes @
@Feel me now @
@I don't know @
@How you could not love me now @
@ You will know @
@ With her feet down to the ground @
@ Over there @
@And I want you, love, to know @
@ You can't hide @
@ Oh, no @
@From the way I feel @@
[Lydia On Phone] Hello. [Bob] Hey.
Hello, Bob.
[Bob] Hey, you know, those carpet samples... you were right about the burgundy.
It wasn't even close.
Blows the others away. I'm glad you like it.
I saw a great house tonight that you would've loved, and...
that burgundy would've been good in this house, really. Really?
A guy designed his own house and built it.
Oh, yeah? I wish I'd seen it.
He's a fashion guy. All these fashion people were there.
And, uh, there were Japanese surfers there,
and the guy was playing really, really, really great music.
I should've found out what it was and brought some...
I'll bring some back. I'll try to find out.
That sounds great. Can you hold on?
[Girl Crying]
You have to have something for breakfast.
Do you want some cereal? Tell her I said she's gotta eat something.
I'm just trying to get her to eat something.
Yeah. Tell her I said she has to eat something.
Your dad says eat something. No.
Eat. Tell her I said so. She won't eat anything. Forget it.
Look, I'm glad you're having fun.
It's not fun. It's just... It's just very, very different.
Maybe that's good.
Um, I have to get the kids off for school, okay?
So, can I call you in a while?
I might not be up. It's-It's, like, 4:00.
Well, you better get some sleep. You have work in the morning.
No, actually, they gave me tomorrow off.
That must be nice. Hmm.
All right. Well, thanks for checking in. I gotta go.
All right. Have a great, great night. All right.
I mean, I guess have a great morning, huh? [Chuckles]
Good night, Bob. Good night. Good night.
[Phone Clicks Off, Dial Tone] I love you.
That was a stupid idea.
I was feeling tight, you know? Mm-hmm.
Shoulders and neck. Mm-hmm.
So I called down and, and had a, uh,
shiatsu massage in my room. Mmm, that's nice.
And the tightness has completely, uh, disappeared... Mmm.
And been replaced by...
unbelievable pain.
Just staggering, unbearable pain. Ooh, that's too bad.
Yeah. I'm in pain.
I got my foot banged up, and... Wanna see it?
[Grunts] How do you say no?
Oh, my gosh. I know.
That's... How... When did you do this?
I did it the other day. It hurts, you know?
Didn't you feel any pain? Your... Yeah, it really hurt.
It was... Yeah. That toe is almost dead.
I gotta take you to a doctor. You can't, uh, just put that back in the shoe.
No. I don't think so.
Well, you either go to a doctor, or you leave it here.
He's smiling. You like that idea?
See, they love black toe over in this country.
You got a sharp knife?
Gotta be, you know, in this country... somebody's gotta prefer a black toe.
Uh, "brack" toe.
Or we should probably hang around until someone orders it.
Hey, what's with the straight face?
Hospital regulations. Get in there.
All right. Thank you. All right.
Careful, okay? No, don't!
No! Hey, use the horn, fella.
Let's try "mixed internal." [Laughing]
Yeah. Switched to beer, huh? Go.
Go. Go. You might want to switch to sake.
Stop.
Yeah. We need a doctor. Hai.
Uh... For, uh, her... emergency room.
It's not an emergency. I just hurt my foot.
Okay, do we fill this out? We go over there?
Which number?
We're not going to another hospital, so whatever you say is okay.
Could you put that back in the garage for us?
[Speaking Japanese] Irun desuka.
"In desuka"? Irun desuka.
Nihon ni.
Japan.
Japan. "Appuh."
Japan "appuh." Japan...
"Appuh." "Appuh." After?
Japan... "Appuh." Nannen.
"Nannen."
How's that song go?
- Is that for me? - [Door Closes]
Yeah, it can be for you.
[Charlotte's Voice] Hey, Bob, it's Charlotte.
Um, I'm going to meet Charlie and those guys at this place called Orange around 10:00,
so I'll fax you a map on how to get there.
I hope you can come and meet us. Bye.
@Suckin'on my titties like you wanted me @
@ Callin'me all the time like Blondie @
@ Check out my Chrissie be-Hynde It's fine all of the time @
@Like sex on the beach is @
@ What else is in the Teaches of Peaches
@Huh, what @
@Suckin'on my titties like you wanted me @
@ Callin'me all the time like Blondie @
How long have you been here? I couldn't say.
Where's Charlie and those guys?
Um, they're takin' a dance class.
[Woman Laughing] @ Why, what @
@ What, right @
Can I get you a couple drinks? Let's go.
Okay. Okay.
@Like you wanted me Callin'me all the time like Blondie @@ Thank you.
[Horn Honking] He's got blockers.
They've got room to run.
He's cutting back. He cut back.
He's dancin'. He's dancin'. Where'd he go?
[Charlotte] There you are.
Say "Hi."
Hi. You ready?
Come on.
@@[Piano] Thank you, Tokyo!
@Nobody does it better @
@ Makes me feel sad for the rest @
@Nobody does it @
@ Half as good as you @
[Laughing] @ Baby, you're @
@ The best @ You two.
Both of you.
@ I wasn't lookin' @
[Laughing] @But somehow you found me @
@I tried to hide from your love,yeah @@
[Man Speaking Italian]
[Woman] No, no. Not here. [Speaking Italian]
- It must be over there. - [Man Continues In Italian]
You know, the first time I saw you, you were wearing a tuxedo at the bar.
You were very dashing.
I liked the mascara.
But the first time I saw you was in the elevator.
Really? You don't remember?
I guess you do kind of blend in, huh? [Chuckles]
Did I scowl at you?
No, you smiled. I did?
Yes, it was a complete accident. A freak. I haven't seen it since.
Just that one time. Like that, but bigger.
Bigger. Yeah, big... big...
Well, not that big. [Chuckles]
[Woman On TV] My goodness.
Marcello, come here. Hurry up.
[Charlotte] Why do they switch the "R"s and the "L"s here?
Oh, for yuks. You know, just to mix it up.
They have to amuse themselves. 'Cause we're not makin' 'em laugh.
Let's never come here again, 'cause it would never be as much fun.
Whatever you say. You're the boss.
I'm stuck.
Does it get easier?
It gets easier.
Look at you.
Thanks. [Chuckles]
The more you know who you are,
and what you want,
the less you let...
things upset you.
I just don't know what I'm supposed to be.
You know?
I tried being a writer, but...
I hate what I write.
And I tried taking pictures,
but they're so mediocre, you know.
Every girl goes through a photography phase.
You know, like horses?
You know? Take, uh, dumb pictures of your feet.
You'll figure that out.
I'm not worried about you.
Keep writing.
But I'm so mean.
Mean's okay. Yeah?
What about marriage? Does that get easier?
That's hard.
We used to have a lot of fun.
Lydia would come with me when I made the movies,
and we would laugh about it all.
Now she doesn't want to leave the kids, and...
she doesn't...
need me to be there.
The kids miss me, but they're fine.
It gets a whole lot more complicated when you have kids.
Yeah. It's scary.
It's the most terrifying day of your life the day the first one is born.
Yeah. Nobody ever tells you that.
Your life,
as you know it,
is gone.
Never to return.
But they learn how to walk, and they learn how to talk, and...
and you want to be with them.
And they turn out to be the most...
delightful people...
you will ever meet in your life.
Hmm, that's nice.
Where'd you grow up?
Um, I grew up in New York,
and I moved to Los Angeles when John and I got married.
But it's so different there.
Yeah, I know.
John thinks I'm so snotty.
You're not hopeless.
[Man] Mr. Harris? A fax for you. Yes.
Okay. Can you send it up?
Do you think you can kick it under the door, slide it under the door, please?
Do you want I send it to your room? Just slide it under the door, please.
Thank you. Okay. All right, bye. Thank you, Mr. Harris.
Hey, Ms. Kawasaki. It's Bob Harris.
Yes, I would love to do his talk show.
I would.
Mm-hmm. I would love to change my plans and stay.
American movie star.
Ladies and gentlemen,
[No Audible Dialogue] Mr. Bob Harris!
Come on.! Da de da de, da de da dah.
Come on, Bob. Come on, Bob.
Bobby, come on! Bobby, come on!
Whoo! Nice to meet you.
He said you guys are e-mailing together.
Ah. He wants to show you his dance.
Japanese dance step. Uh... Uh... Japanese dance.
Do l... Do I have to dance with him?
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby, Bobby... [Speaking Japanese]
Welcome, Bob. He was saying, "Welcome, Bob." What?
Hello? [Lydia] Bob?
Hi, Lydia. Is this a bad time?
No, it's always a good time.
Look, um, your burgundy carpet isn't in stock.
It's gonna take 12 weeks. Did you like any of the other colors?
Whatever you like. L-I'm completely lost.
[Sighs] It's just carpet.
That's not what I'm talking about. What are you talking about?
I don't know. I just want to get healthy.
You know, I want to take better care of myself.
I would like to start eating healthier.
I don't want all that pasta.
What?
I would like to start eating, like, Japanese food.
Well, why don't you just stay there, and you can have it every day?
How are the kids doin'?
They're fine. They miss their father.
But they're getting used to you not being here.
Do I need to worry about you, Bob?
Only if you want to.
Bob, I got things to do.
I gotta go. Okay.
I'll see you... I mean, I'll talk to you later.
Okay. Okay, bye.
Bye.
[Applause] [Woman] Thank you. Thank you so much.
We'll take a really short break, and we'll see you in a minute.
Hi. Uh, champagne. Thanks.
I got it.
[Chuckling] Have a rough night?
Um, I'm going to that place, that sushi place in Daikanyama.
You wanna come? Yeah, but I can't right now.
@Midnight at the oasis @
@Send your camel to bed @ Yeah, I guess you're busy, huh?
@Shadows paintin'our faces @
@ Traces of romance in our heads @@
Hello? [Muffled] Hello? Bob, it's me.
Hello? [Clear] It's Lydia, your wife.
Oh, I'm... I couldn't hear ya.
Hey, you want to talk to Zoe? Yeah.
Zoe, come say hello to your father.
[Zoe] No. Uh, she just ran into the other room.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay, um, her ballet recital is Sunday. Don't forget.
I didn't forget.
Well, travel safely. I'll see you soon.
[Zoe] Mommy! Okay.
Well, she is closer to your age.
You could talk about things you have in common,
like, um,
growing up in the '50s.
Maybe she liked the movies you were making in the '70s,
when you still were making movies.
Wasn't there anyone else there to lavish you with attention?
I'm switchin' to beer. Okay?
ӥ
Biru?
I can't tell the difference.
We'll have two of these, okay?
[Alarm Continues] [Woman On P.A. System] To your nearest exit...and leave the building.
Await instructions from the authorities.
That was the worst lunch.
So bad.
What kind of restaurant makes you cook your own food?
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow.
I'll miss you.
@@ [Rock] @ I'm so into you @
@ Whoo-hoo @
@ When you walked into the room @
@ There was voodoo in the vibes @
@I was captured by your style @
@But I could not catch your eyes @
I don't want to leave.
So don't. Stay here with me.
We'll start a jazz band.
@I am so into you, baby @@
Good night. Good night. Okay.
Good night.
[Elevator Bell Sounding] Okay.
Okay. Good night. Good night.
[Water Running]
Good morning, Mr. Harris. Have a nice flight. Thank you.
Thank you. [Woman] Good-bye
I'll be one minute.
Charlotte, I'm down in the lobby, and I'm leaving now.
Um, I was calling...
to see if you still have my jacket.
If you could you bring it down, but you're not there,
so this is good-bye, and, uh...
So,
I guess, good-bye and enjoy my jacket which you stole...from me.
[Woman] Hello. Hello.
How are you? I'm good. How are you?
Mr. Harris... [All Speaking At Once]
Thank you for coming Enjoy your, your trip? I had a great time.
I had a very good time.
Excuse me. Ar-Aren't you Bob Harris? Yes, I am.
I'm such a big fan. So nice to meet you. Thank you very much Nice to meet you.
What are you doing here in Japan? I have to go right now. Excuse me one second.
Oh, okay. Well...
Hi. Thank you. Hi.
You're welcome. Thought I'd missed you.
Are you going right now? Yeah. And my bodyguards are in here.
All right. Aren't you gonna wish me "Have a good 'fright,"' or something?
Okay. Well, bye. All right.
- Can I take one more picture? - Sure.
[Speaking Japanese] Hai.
[Woman Continues In Japanese] Hai.
Hey, hold on here. Let me out. Thank you.
Hey, you.
[Whispering, Indistinct]
[Man] @Listen to the girl @
@As she takes on half the world @
@Moving up and so alive @
@In her honey dripping @
@Beehive @
@Beehive It's good, so good @
@It's so good @ All right.
@So good @
@ Walking back to you @
@Is the hardest thing that @
@I can do @
@ That I can do for you @
@For you @
@I'll be your plastic toy @
@Eating up the scum @
@Is the hardest thing for @
@Me to do @
@Just like honey @
[Woman] @Just like honey @ @Just like honey @
@Just like honey @ @Just like honey @
@Just like honey @
@Just like honey @@
[Man] @Free @
@ To learn @
@Last time @
@ With you @
@ You're always @
@ Wonderful @
@I wanted you @
@I do @
@Free @
@ To go @
@I know @
@ You @
@ City girl @
@ You're beautiful @
@I love you @
@I do @
@I @
@ Could love @
@All night @
@ With you @
@ City girl @
@ You're beautiful @
@I love you @
@I do @
@I do @@