Fourteen.. Fifteen..
Sixteen. Prime.
Eighteen. Prime.
Twenty.
Twenty-one.
Twenty-two.
West Virginia Collegiate Institute is the
best school for Negros in the state.
It's the only school, past the eighth
grade, anywhere near here.
Isosceles. Scalene
Equilateral
Rhombus
Trapezoid
Katherine's in the sixth grade.
They want to take her early.
Tetrahedron,
Dodecahedron
They're offering a full scholarship.
All you have to do is get there.
Ms. Coleman.
Why don't you solve the equation
on the board?
We took up a collection amongst the
teachers and such,
It's not a lot.
But it's enough to help get you
settle down
That's more than kind, Ms. Sumner.
If the product of two terms is zero,
then common sense says at least
one of the two terms
has to be zero to start with
So, if you move all the terms over
to one side,
you'd put the quadratics into a form
that can be factored,
Allowing that side of the equation
to equal zero.
Once you've done that,
it's pretty straight forward from there
In all my years of teaching,
I've never seen a mind like
the one your daughter has.
- Katherine!
- Hurry on now, love
You have to go.
Let Mommy take you in.
You have to see what she becomes.
Ok, try to turn it over, now!
Katherine?
Mary!
Somebody!
Katherine! Quit staring off into space
and turn the damn car over
I got it.
I'm not deaf
I wonder some times.
Here it goes.
Yeah, it's the starter.
That is definitely the starter.
The starter's startin' to make us late.
We all go end up unemployed driving around
in this pile of junk to work everyday.
You're welcome to walk the 16 miles.
Or sit on the back of the bus.
I won't do neither.
I'll hitchhike.
Girls,
No crime in a broken down car.
No crime being Negro neither.
Button it up, Mary! Nobody wants to
go to jail behind your mouth.
I'll do my best, sugar.
Not a great place for the three of
ya'll to be havin' car trouble.
We didn't pick the place, Officer.
It picked us.
You bein' disrespectful?
No, sir.
- You have identification on ya?
- Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
We're just on our way to work.
At Langley.
NASA, sir.
We do a great deal of the calculating
Getting our rockets into space.
- All three?
- Yes, sir.
Yes, officer.
NASA, that's somethin'
I had no idea they hired...
There're quite a few women,
working in the Space Program.
Damn Russians are watching us right now.
Sputniks.
You girls ever meet those Astronauts?
The Mercury 7?
Absolutely
Yes, sir.
We work with those gentlemen all the time.
Those boys are the best we got.
- I'm sure of that
- Yeah
We gotta get a man up there
before the Commies do.
- Yes!
- Absolutely.
Whole damn country's counting on ‘em.
That's for certain
Hard to be of service broken down on
the side of the road, though.
Right! Right!
Well, you need a tow or somethin'?
No, thank you, Officer.
I think I got it, Just give me that..
Just need to
bypass the starter
She is good at this stuff
That a girl
We're all set.
Hell. Least I can do is give ya
an escort.
Imagine ya'll are
running late to work.
Oh, no sir! We wouldn't
want to bother you.
That would be wonderful, Officer.
Thank you so much, sir.
- Follow me!
- I'm driving!
Hurry up, Dorothy!
Before he changes his mind!
- We're coming!
- Hold your horses!
Yes!
- Mary! Slow down! You're so close!
- Well, be quiet. He said to follow him!
He didn't mean you hit him behind!
Dear Lord..
I don't even know where to begin!
Oh! I'll tell you where to begin!
Three negro women are chasing
a white police officer
down the highway in Hampton, Virginia
1961.
Ladies, that there is
a God ordained miracle!
Starting tomorrow,
I'm riding the bus
Show me
No, exactly
Ascent angle: 46.56.
Approaching 7400 mph
118 seconds.
Second stage. Success.
Korabl-Sputnik-4 is orbital.
Orbital entry is established.
Russian orbital entry is established.
Jim Webb.
Yes, Mr. President
We certainly are, sir.
It looks like they've achieved at least
one orbit, maybe two
Zvezdochka is ready to go again.
So is our comrade, Ivan.
A brave space traveler.
We have proven life can be sustained
in space.
Now, we will be first to send a human
A damn dog!
And a damn mannequin!
And then a 1.6 megaton
RDS-37 thermonuclear warhead
drops down in the
middle of Des Moines.
Well, that's a pretty big jump, sir.
What?
- Just there's that..
- Who the hell is he?
Paul Stafford.
Our Lead Engineer, Mr. Webb.
I think what he meant to say
is that speculation, at least
on our side of the equation
by definition, can be..
Just a little dangerous.
Dangerous?
You know what's dangerous,
Mr. Stafford?
Inaction, and indecision.
Russians have a spy
satellite lapping the planet,
taking pictures
of God knows what!
The President is demanding
an immediate response.
No more delays.
Alan Shepard, John Glenn, your uncle Bob.
Doesn't matter,
just get us up there, Harrison
We can't justify a space program
that doesn't put anything in space.
How did that feel in there, Paul?
Do you think you enlightened
the Administrator?
No, he didn't look enlightened to me.
- He look enlightened to you, Sam?
- Not particularly.
And just so you know, he's not
wrong about what he said in there.
You know that, right?
Because now that they can get up there,
a bomb will follow.
That's what happens to all our good ideas.
I imagine there is too
Where's the machine?
Any day now, Mr. Harrison.
- Any day now.
- Yes, sir.
What's it called?
- The initials...
- The IBM.
International business machine.
Space is a business
I need a mathematician.
- I'll put in another request, sir.
- Another request.
Jesus Christ! We don't have
a single person, in this entire building,
that can handle Analytic Geometry?
That's what I've been told.
Well, tell me something else, Ruth.
Like we're going to find such a person
before the Russians plant a flag
on the damn moon.
Ladies, ladies
If you're tardy, you don't
get an assignment
if you don't get an assignment
you don't have a job.
Eleanor. Data Reduction, Building 202.
Data Reduction?
Well. You're welcome to join the
charmers in Magneto-plasmadynamics.
Oh! No, ma'am.
Thank you, Data Reduction's just fine.
- Mary.
- Present.
The Mercury 7 prototype
has arrived for testing.
Mr. Zielinski's requesting you.
For permanent assignment.
- Are you serious?
- Get moving.
Oh! Thank you, Jesus!
- Thank you, Jesus! Oh! Thank you.
- Mary
Keep it inside
I'm sorry, Dor
All right, Mrs. Late
You'll also be..
Mrs. Mitchell.
We're on double time this mornin', girls.
I need these calculations before lunch.
The Space Task Group needs a computer,
ASAP.
Someone with a handle on
Analytic Geometry.
We can't fill the position outta
the East Group.
Permanent or temp?
Everything's temporary, Dorothy.
- You have someone?
- Oh! Yes, ma'am.
Katherine's the gal for that.
She can handle any numbers you put
in front of her.
I'll check her credentials.
Didn't think of comin' all the way
down here.
Here.
Pinch press those out.
Mrs. Mitchell!
If I could.
My application for supervisor, ma'am.
Was just wondering if they're still
considering me for that position.
Yes.
Well, the official word is: no.
They're not assignin' a permanent
supervisor for the Colored Group.
May I ask why?
I don't know "why."
I didn't ask "why."
We need a Supervisor, ma'am.
We haven't had one since Ms. Jansen got sick
It's been almost a year.
Things are workin' just fine as is.
I'm doing the work of a Supervisor.
Well.
That's NASA, for ya.
Fast with rocket ships.
Slow with advancement.
Get those trajectories calcs worked out.
We need ‘em for the Redstone test.
Mach 1 tunnel test, T-1 minute.
No shoe is worth your life
One.. One moment!
Shut it down.
If we alter the exterior from smooth
to corrugated, the capsule might
have more stability,
But the friction,
it's under during reentry..
Most shield erosion occurs
on the posterior side abutting
the retro-boosters.
Conclusion?
The area closest to the boosters
is closest to the heat.
Coupled with rising temperatures
on reentry,
the contacts soften.
We could consider another fastener
other than bolts.
Yes
Yes.
There's another opening in
the Engineer Training Program.
Flat head rivets would reduce wind drag.
Mary! A person with an engineer's
mind should be an engineer.
You can't be a Computer
the rest of your life.
Mr. Zielinski.
I'm a Negro woman.
I'm not gonna to entertain the impossible
And I'm a polish Jew whose parents
died in a Nazi prison camp.
Now I'm standing beneath a space ship,
that's going to carry an astronaut
to the stars.
I think we can say,
we are living the impossible.
Let me ask you..
If you were a white male,
Would you wish to be an engineer?
I wouldn't have to.
I'd already be one.
Skirts must be worn past the knee.
Sweaters are preferred to blouses.
No jewelry.
A simple pearl necklace is the exception.
Your supervisor is Mr. Al Harrison.
Director of the Space Task Group.
You'll write research,
proof calculations, so forth.
Don't talk to Mr. Harrison lest
he talks to you.
Not many Computers last
more than a few days,
He's been through a dozen
in as many months.
Come on, keep up
Things move fast around here
Your clearance.
They've never had a colored in here before,
Katherine.
Don't embarrass me.
This wasn't emptied last night.
I'm sorry. I'm not the..
Custodian.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Mr. Harrison's Computer reporting.
Take the desk in the back.
I'll get your work in a..
Bit.
Mr. Harrison won't warm up to you,
don't expect it.
Do your work, keep your head down.
Thank you.
Go on. Get settled.
Paul,
Why are we still losing shingles off
the heat shield?
Well, We're working with a
prototype of the capsule, Al.
It's little as one third the size..
- I get that. So..
What do you do with our
million dollar fan, Karl?
- Turn it down?
- No, I don't think...
Hey! That was a joke.
Paul, if the heat shield comes off
what d'you think happens to our astronaut?
I know.
So we're gonna..
We're gonna come up with a solve, right?
Yes, sir. We're working on it.
Ruth, what's the status on that Computer?
She's right behind you, Mr. Harrison.
Does she handle Analytic Geometry?
Absolutely. And she speaks.
Yes, sir. I do.
- Which one?
- Both.
Geometry and speaking.
Ruth. Give me that.
Do you think you..
You think you can find me the Frenet frame
for this data,
Using the GramSchmidt...
With Orthogonalization algorithm.
Yes, sir.
I prefer it over Euclidean coordinates.
OK. Good.
Good. Then, I'm going to need it
by the end of the day.
Yes.
I'm also going to ask you to check
Mr. Stafford's math
as well as others on this
floor from time to time.
I can.. I can handle that, Al.
I'm sure you can, Paul.
I'm sure they all can.
But if that were the case,
Shingles wouldn't be flying off the
heat shield now, would they?
Excuse me, could I have
everyone's attention for a moment?
Thank you. Just a..
Just to be clear..
In 14 days the Mercury 7
will be here for training.
And I have no doubt in my mind
that they're going to be
asking us questions about our work.
I think that's a pretty reason
we're giving. We're putting a human..
On top of a missile and
shooting him into space
And it's never been done before.
And because it's never been done.
Everything we do
between now and
then is going to matter.
It's going to matter to their wives.
To their children.
I believe it's going to matter to
the whole damn country.
So this Space Task Group will be
as advertised.
America's greatest engineering
and scientific minds
are not gonna have a problem
with having their work checked,
are they, Paul?
No, sir.
Good. So let's have an amen, damnit
Amen.
All right!
My numbers are spot on.
I'll double check them, sir.
No problem.
- I'm not gonna be able to..
- Work on what you can read.
The rest is classified.
You don't have clearance.
Excuse me...
May I ask you where the ladies' room is?
Sorry, I have no idea where
your bathroom is?
Yes, sir.
Ah! Yes.
- Ruth!
- Yes, Mr. Harrison.
Where's that girl with the numbers?
On a... break.
We take breaks now?
My God, where have you been?
Are you finished yet?
Almost.
He said about the end of the day?
The end of the day around
here was yesterday.
I need those done first.
He wants those done first.
- OK!
- Get going.
Mr. Harrison.
Oh! Yeah, just set up,
you know.
And Stafford's heat shield calcs?
It's hard to be sure, sir.
Hard to be sure.
You know what we're doing here?
Trying to put a man into space, sir.
That's right.
That's right. So you can
throw that in the trash.
Excuse me?
I said you can throw it away
Here.
It's not an insult to your work.
It's just..
.. Obsolete.
That's how fast things are moving around here.
If I said I was sorry,
I'd be saying it all day.
What I'm asking you to do.. What I'm
asking everyone in that room,
all my... geniuses,
is to look beyond the numbers.
To look around them.
Through them.
For answers to questions we don't even
know to ask.
Math that doesn't yet exist.
Because without it,
we're not going anywhere.
I mean, we're staying on the ground.
We're not...
flying into space. We're not..
Circling the earth. And we're certainly
not touching the moon. And in my mind..
In my mind, I'm already there.
Are you?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Because I don't need another smart girl
with an adding machine.
Can I go, sir?
Go? Yeah. Go, yeah.
Yes, you can go
I'm saying this is so much.
I'm not saying that.. I..
We've been waiting for hours.
Next time you take the bus.
She's in a mood.
I haven't been late one day in ten years.
Haven't been out sick.
Haven't complained. My work's on time.
It's done right. It's done well.
It's not fair, that's a fact.
What's not fair is having
the responsibility of the Supervisor,
but not the title or the pay.
Watching you two move on.
Now don't get me wrong.
Any upward movement is movement for us all
It just isn't movement for me.
Truth be told, Dorothy, I don't really know
if I can keep up in that room.
I'll be back with the Computers in a week,
or out of a job entirely.
Oh, please! You're better with the numbers
than anyone in the cabin and you know it.
Make that pencil move as fast as
your mind does, you'll be fine.
And you. Have some respect! Get
your damn feet off my dash board.
This isn't your living room.
I sound like a supervisor, don't I?
A mean, ole salty one.
Riddled with authority.
No question.
You don't mess with, Mrs. Vaughan.
Turn that music up
- Goodnight, Katherine!
- Bye, Kath!
Goodnight, ladies!
See you in the morning.
- Hey baby
- Hello, mamma.
I was fixing to call the National Guard.
Sorry, Momma.
New assignment.
Space Task Group.
Oh my word, that sounds important
It's a promotion?
Might be a slight promotion.
But you want the job, right?
I think so.
It's a challenge. But..
Well, it's nothing you can't handle,
Katherine.
Thank you, mamma.
- Are they asleep yet?
- They're pretending to be.
They're not pretending well enough
Thank you, mamma.
Love you.
This is my bed!
What are you doing?
It's not fair how Joylette gets to
sleep by herself cause she's the oldest.
Yes it is fair
Constance, Kathy, sit.
Now, I understand you want to be grown.
And have your own space
So whoever sleeps in that bed,
in Joylette's place,
will also do the dishes,
take out the trash,
and do all of Joylette's chores
That's okay. Never mind.
She's not so terrible to share with.
OK.
Then don't let me come home and find you
like this again, you hear me?
You're supposed to been asleep,
a long time ago.
We just wanted to say goodnight.
You've been gone for 300 hours.
I work a full-time job now. You all know that.
I have to be mommy and daddy.
I miss your father just as much as anyone
He's with his angels.
Yes. He's with all his angels.
And he's watching over us.
Every minute. OK?
That's why we have to be strong.
All right?
- Yes, Mamma.
- Yeah get some rest, OK?
- Mamma?
- Yes, baby.
Are the Russians fixing to attack us?
Where'd you get that from?
We had to hide under our desks today.
All scrunched up.
OK, baby. That's called a drill.
It means ..
You practice safety, just in case
something happens.
Truth is, we don't know what
they're doing up there.
- You're going up to space too?
- No, baby. But..
I'm going to do what I can help those
brave men get there. Yes, I'm.
You could fly up to space if you wanted to,
Mamma. You can be an astronaut.
- Did you draw this?
- Yes, mamma.
Is that me?
You see this?
Oh, my goodness, I love you, baby.
- Me too
- I know, I know. Come here.
All right!
Now this time really go to bed.
I love you all.
Goodnight.
I love my picture, baby.
- Praise God!
- Hallelujah!
Praise God that change is coming.
From the Southern Christian
Leadership Conference,
to the good Reverend Dr. King,
Hallelujah!
To the students sitting in
at lunch counters in North Carolina.
His faith in us has no limits
The good Lord..
Has our very own women..
Workin' on rocket ships!
And we have National Guardsmen
defending our freedom
Give a shout of praise for Colonel
Jim Johnson.
Returning home by the grace of God,
to set up a National Guard unit
right here in Hampton.
- Can I get a "Hallelujah" in here?!
- Hallelujah!
I just don't understand..
I just.. I don't..
I don't understand.
I don't want to talk
about this again, OK?
A female engineer?
A female engineer.
We're Negro, baby. Ain't no
such thing. Understand it.
It's not like that there, Levi.
You can't "apply" for freedom. Freedom
is never granted to the oppressed.
It's got to be demanded. Taken.
Stop quoting your slogans at me.
There's more than one way to
achieve something.
I don't want any greens.
I tell you about interrupting?
Here, try this, baby.
You gonna eat them greens too.
Kids need to eat their vegetables.
You'd know that if you was at home.
You better settle down, Levi Jackson.
Lest you want this female's mind
right here, in front of everybody.
All I'm saying
Don't play the fool.
I don't want to see you get hurt.
NASA's never ever given you gals your due,
having a couple of extra degrees
ain't gonna change that.
Civil rights ain't always civil.
I don't want any greens either.
No lip, little miss. Your brother
gets them, and so do you.
I hear he's planning on staying
in the area.
Well. That's good for him.
Katherine,
go find your way over there.
That Colonel Jim is a tall glass of water
That he is.
Tall. Strong. Commanding.
- And I bet he's like that day and night.
- Mary
It's Sunday
Please, have some shame.
I will not.
- Mm. I think he's smiling over here.
- At you
- I'm not smiling back.
- You're all teeth right now.
I am not
- He's coming over
- Now, why would he be doing that?
- Because Mary's waving at him
- No! Ladies, I'm not..
Too late. Fix your hair on the side.
I'm Dorothy Vaughan. That's Mary Jackson.
I believe you met her husband, Levi.
Yes, ma'am. Good to meet you all.
And Ms. Katherine Goble.
She's not married. She's a widow.
With three beautiful little girls,
so well-behaved.
Angels on earth, is what we'd like to call 'em.
- Dorothy, slice-a pie?
- I'd love one
Excuse me
You already have a slice-a pie, Doro..
Well, I was just
- fixing my three babies some plates.
- May I help?
Sure.
Ah! Fruit salad!
Pastor mentioned you're computer
at NASA
- Yes
- What's that entail?
We calculate the mathematics
necessary to enable
launch and landing for
the Space Program.
- Pretty heady stuff!
- Yes, it is.
They let women handle that sort of..
That's.. Not what I mean
What do you mean?
I am.. Just surprised something so..
Taxing
Mr. Johnson
If I were you, I'd quit talking right now
I don't mean any disrespect
I'll have you know, I was
the first Negro female
student at West Virginia
University Graduate School.
On any given day,
I analyze the manometer levels
for air displacement
friction and velocity.
And compute over 10,000
calculations by cosine,
square root and lately
Analytic Geometry.
By hand. There are 20 bright,
highly capable Negro women in the
West Computing Group,
and we're proud to be doing our
part for the country.
So, yes
They let women do some things at NASA,
Mr. Johnson.
And it's not because we wear skirts
It's because we wear glasses
Have a good day
Scott, welcome to Langley.
Welcome to Langley.
Right here, Gentlemen
That's Alan Shepard.
US Navy pilot. He could be
the first man in space.
That's Scott Carpenter and
Walter Schirra.
Also Navy pilots.
All under 5'11", 180 lbs.
IQs over 130.
And handsome must
be a requirement too.
How could you possibly be
ogling these white men?
It's equal rights. I have the
right to see fine in every color.
That's John Glenn.
He's the only Marine Corps pilot.
Gentlemen, if we may..
Much to see around here.
We haven't shaken all the hands yet.
- We have a fairly tight itinerary, Colonel.
- Ruth, it's fine.
- He's coming straight.
- Look around ahead.
Ladies. Didn't wanna
run off without saying hello
They seem to be
in a big rush around here.
The Russians certainly aren't
slowing down any.
They can't build the refrigerator, how
the heck they beat us into space?
What do you ladies do for NASA?
- Calculate your trajectories.
Launch and landing.
- I can't get anywhere without the numbers.
- No, sir.
Mary Jackson, Mr. Glenn.
Engineering. And I'm proud as
the devil to be workin' with you.
Thank you, Mary.
John!
- I must take it inside
- Yes, sir.
Guys!
Mr. Harrison wants you
to confirm launch
and landing for the
Redstone Rocket test.
I cannot work on what I cannot see,
Mr. Stafford.
It's illegible.
Those numbers have already been
confirmed by two engineers
in this department, and myself.
This is more or less
a dummy check.
This one, like make a two. Make
a double. OK? Get it?
No one thought to measure these things.
I'm afraid, not. Sir.
Would you like us to stop?
No. No, just..
I see, no. Just keep going.
In fact
- Use.. Use the big hammer
- Yes, sir.
Come on, use the big hammer.
You heard the man. Let's go!
Ma'am.
Our runner can pick up your work, Dorothy.
You need to be workin',
not walkin'.
Oh! It's break time, ma'am.
No trouble at all.
Well, since you made the trip
you can take that batch over there
Sure thing, Mrs. Mitchell.
You need somethin' else?
Yes, ma'am.
I was wondering if you knew what
they're building over in the Tech Wing.
It's called an IBM.
A mainframe machine.
Apparently, it can do our calculations
in a fraction of the time.
Guess that's good for NASA.
Hurry on, now.
Best if you do it in one trip.
Excuse me
Is that correct?
Yeah
Whose work is that?
I said, whose work is that?!
Katherine Goble, sir.
How did you know the Redstone
couldn't support orbital flight?
That's classified information
It's top secret.
Well, it's no secret why the
Redstone test keep failing
its flight for sub-orbital flight,
but it can't handle the weight of the capsule
and push it into space.
Numbers don't lie.
And you figured it all out with this?
Half the data is redacted
What's there tells the story
if you read between the lines.
The distance from launch to orbit, we know.
Then mass we know.
The Mercury Capsule weight, we know.
And the speeds are there.. In the data.
You did the math.
Yes, sir.
I looked beyond.
And how do you know about the
Atlas rocket?
That's not math.
That data's not here. Like he said,
it's classified.
I held it up to the light.
- You held it up to the light?
- Yes, sir.
Yep. There it is.
Atlas
What's your name?
Katherine Goble.
- Are you a spy, Katherine?
- Am I what?
- I'm saying, are you a Russian spy?
- No, sir.
I'm not Russian.
She's not Russian, sir.
All right then, we have
nothing to lose here.
Give her everything she needs
to work on Shepard's trajectories.
Without redaction.
Are we clear now?
Right.
Are we sure about this?
What's the issue, Paul?
You heard her.
She's not a spy.
I.. I just don't think it's a good idea.
You know what I think is a good idea?
Darker ink.
I think darker ink is a good idea.
Ruth, could pass it along?
Yes, sir.
- Thank you, Katherine
- Thank you, sir.
This interrogation is over
You can probably get to the
moon and back with this.
Just not the bathroom.
At least they're not
blind to what you do.
It's not going to matter soon.
This IBM's going to put us all out of work.
What can we do about it?
Only one thing to do
Learn all we can.
Make ourselves valuable.
Somewhere down the line a human being's
going to have to push the buttons.
That's right.
Oh, mercy
Well, she must be lost.
NASA doesn't commission females
for the Engineer Training Program.
That position is available to any
qualified applicant.
Right. Except you don't have
the educational requirements.
I have a Bachelors Degree in
Mathematics and Physical Sciences.
It's the same as most
engineers around here.
Well, we now require advanced extension
courses through the University of Virginia.
It's in the Employee Handbook.
An addendum.
Case you haven't read it
Every time we have a chance to get
ahead, they move the finish line.
I just follow the rules around here.
And I expect..
Everyone who works for
me to follow them as well.
There are no special circumstances
for anyone.
You all should be thankful,
you have jobs at all.
"For those that cannot attend classes
at the University of Virginia,
Advanced Extension Courses are
available at Hampton High School."
That's still a segregated school, Mary
Virginia acts like Brown vs. Board
of Education never happened.
They'll never gonna allow a colored woman
just take classes at an all white school!
- Sounds about right.
- That's all you're gonna say?
Well, I'm not going to sit
here all day and listen to you
complain about the way things
are, we're tryin to play cards.
Petition the court. Fight for what
you want. But quit talking about it
- I've been complaining?
- For days
Ladies
Not one more peep about work.
Deal me in
Katherine,
come on
You
Yeah! I needed this!
Thank you!
Don't give her any more Katherine
I can't. She drank it all.
Yes.
I'm fine
I'm as fine as I've ever been.
You're as drunk as you've ever been.
Come on! Let's dance, girls.
Come on, Kath!
Let's dance.
Go dance, Katherine.
Come on!
We're gonna teach you how
Keep going, here! All right.
Slow! Here slow down.
Segregation must go!
Don't pay attention to any of that. We're
not part of that trouble. Go on.
Leonard..
We must have done it.
We don't want any trouble in here.
Oh! I'm not here for any trouble. Ma'am.
What are you here for?
A book.
You have books in the colored section.
It doesn't have what I'm looking for.
Well, that's just the way it is.
Well, you know better...
Get your hands off my boys.
Don't touch them.
You have a blessed day.
Separate and equal are
two different things.
Just cause it's the way
doesn't make it right.
Understand?
Yes, mamma.
You act right, you are right.
That's for certain. Understand?
Yes, mamma.
You took that book, mamma?
Son, I pay taxes.
And taxes pay for everything
in that library.
You can't take something
you've already paid for.
FORTRAN is a new and exciting language..
Used by programmers to communicate
with computers...
It's exciting, as it's the way
of the future.
And everybody smile.
Everybody smile.
Make a wish!
Leonard, you need to get you a job now.
Two girls!
- Well, look at that.
- Look at what?
What a surprise.
I'll say.
- Howard must have invited him.
- Mmm. Hmmm.
Let me go help him
with those flowers
I believe I owe you an apology.
Well, is that it?
Can I make it while we dance?
I'm afraid I simply misspoke the other
day, Mrs. Goble.
I've been away for a long time.
I imagine, I'm just out of practice.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. I was hoping you would allow me
to start over?
Mm-hmm.
So, the thing is..
I have an interest in getting
to know you better.
Mm-hmm.
You are one tough customer. Huh?
You haven't said you're sorry yet
Right.
Of course.
I'm sorry, Katherine.
For what, Jim?
Underestimating you.
And any other woman like you.
Though I don't imagine there's many.
That's good practice, right there.
We interrupt this musical programming
with breaking news.
The Soviet news agency has announced
that Russian cosmonaut,
Yuri Gagarin, has become
the first man in space.
Gagarin completed one full orbit around
the planet in 108 minutes.
Stay tuned to the station for more
details, as they become available.
Well,
I guess that puts us behind the curve.
The Vostok 1 rocket,
delivered Russian cosmonaut
Yuri Gagarin, 3KA capsule
into orbit at 6:07 UTC.
Reentering Russian Air Space at 7:55 UTC.
Proving conclusively
that man could survive orbital space flight
Gagarin was awarded the Order of Lenin
Well..
They beat the pants off us.
Let's go..
Just learn how to fly to space.
And has been proclaimed a national hero.
This is a day of unprecedented triumph
for the Russian space program,
And a crushing blow for America
in the race for space.
I want to thank everyone for staying.
I know it's late, and
after what we just saw
I'm sure everyone's
probably anxious to go home.
But before we do, I just have
to ask the question
The same one
I've been asking myself all the way
over here, which is
How the hell did we find ourselves
in second place in a two men race?
Anybody?
Paul?
I think Glenn said it pretty well.
They're just outworking us.
And the reason I have to..
Think that is because I refuse to believe
that the Russians are smarter than us,
or that they have more technology.
Or that they care more.
But I don't know? Is that possible?
Is it possible that it actually means
more to them?
We're in the fight of our lives, people.
Not on some epic joyride!
I just saw seven faces
who weren't sure that
we can get there.
This is our problem.
And so, as of right now,
There's only two things you
need to know going forward
One is, staying here working late
that's gonna be a fact of life.
And two, don't expect your
paychecks reflect the extra time
it is gonna take to catch
up and pass those bastards.
For those of you that can't
work that way, I understand 'em
thank you for
what you've done.
For everyone else,
I suggest you call your wives..
And tell them how it's gonna be.
I'll start with mine.
- Sam, keep it up
- Yes, sir
End of the day.
Okay. We're looking good...
Try!
- Sir! It might be the selector latch!
- I'm taking a walk!
We're honored to serve our country.
So, we don't think about..
Danger.
No time to be scared.
We got a job to do
Mrs. Jackson!
Colored seats are at the back
of the courtroom.
Thank you, ma'am.
So, which one of you wants to go first?
The IBM 7090 Data Processing System,
It has a capability of solving of over
24,000 multiplications
per second!
- Holy Moses, that's lightning fast
- They'll never get that to work.
It'll run eventually. And when it does
we have to know how to program it.
- Unless you'd rather be out of a job?
- No!
Mr. Z.
I got a court date.
Computer uses it as its high speed storage
unit
An information holding device.
So you have a brain
That, I can work with
that's in the wrong spot
That a girl!
- Ruth!
- Yes, sir.
Get the Cape on the line.
Shepard's trajectories need to be updated.
Where is she?
Where the hell have you been?
Everywhere I look you're not
where I need you to be.
And it's not my imagination. So where
the hell do you go everyday?
To the bathroom, sir.
The bathroom
To the damn bathroom!
For 40 minutes a day?
What do you do in there?
We are T-0 here.
I put a lot of faith in you.
There's no bathroom for me here.
What do you mean there's
no bathroom for you here?
There is no bathroom!
There are no colored bathrooms
in this building,
or any building outside the West Campus.
Which is half a mile away.
Did you know that?
I have to walk to Timbuktu
just to relieve myself
And I can't use one of the handy bikes.
Picture that, Mr. Harrison
My uniform...
Skirt below my knees, my heels
and simple string of pearls.
Well, I don't own pearls.
Lord knows you don't pay the
coloreds enough to afford pearls!
And I work like a dog day and night,
living off a coffee from a pot none of
you want to touch!
So, excuse me..
If I have to go to the restroom
a few times a day
There you have it!
No more colored restrooms.
No more white restrooms.
Just plain old toilets.
Go wherever you damn well please.
Preferably closer to your desk.
Here at NASA,
we all pee the same color
Heard you were fighting the flu.
Thought you could use some soup?
Hot meal for the girls.
Come on, in.
Excuse me
OK, ladies
Let's say grace..
Bow your heads.
Dear Lord!
Thank you for this meal..
We ask that you blessed this food,
so that it may bless our bodies.
In Jesus name, we pray.
Amen.
It's a history day here at Cape Canaveral,
and here what we can expect; Alan Shepard and
Freedom 7 will be launched into space
at an altitude about 116 miles an hour.
- Dorothy! Come on or you'll miss it!
- I'm coming.
Freedom 7, we're gonna have to
bleed off some of the pressure
the liquid oxygen tank
that should reduce the temperature
inside the capsule, over
Any day now, Capcom.
Fix your little problem,
and light this candle
Roger that, Freedom 7.
Standby.
Move to final countdown sequence.
Moving to final countdown sequence.
Roger that.
And we're at T-10..
9... 8... 7... 6...
.. 5... 4...
3... 2...
1...
Zero!
We have ignition
And we have liftoff!
Get up there
Get on up there.
Trajectory is good.
Yaw is okay
Switching to manual roll.
For the eyes of the world
now look into space,
to the moon and to
the planets beyond..
And we have vowed...
that we shall not see it governed
by a hostile flag of conquest,
but by a banner
of freedom and peace.
We set sail on this new sea,
because there is new
knowledge to be gained
and new rights to be won
We choose to go to the Moon in this decade
and do the other things
not because they are easy,
but because they are hard.
Suppose we should all thank President
Kennedy for continued job security.
Gus Grissom's up next.
Another suborbital flight with a Redstone.
Our last shot before we strap
Glenn to the Atlas..
And.. Pray we can brıng him back down.
Yes, and I imagine he'd like us to have
the math worked out beforehand.
Good work, gentlemen.
Go have dinner with your kids.
Then...
let's get back to work.
I think it's high time that
I kissed you, Kathe.
Oh. And why's that?
Figure you're attracted to me
the same as I to you.
Is that right?
Or you would have told me to
get going a long time ago.
Haven't kissed a man in a long time.
Almost forgot how to.
The FBI has arrested four white
men accused of throwing a fire
bomb into a Freedom Riders' bus
south-side of Anniston, Alabama.
- Hi, baby!
- Hello!
- The kids don't need to be watching this..
- They need to see this
Everyone needs to see this.
We think we're rendering a
great service to our nation.
For this is not a struggle
for ourselves alone.
It is the struggle to save
the soul of America.
Mary Jackson.
Petition to attend courses at
Hampton High School.
Good morning, your honor.
Hampton High School is a white school,
Mrs. Jackson.
Yes, your Honor.
I'm aware of that.
Virginia is still a segregated state.
Regardless of what the Federal
Government says, or regardless what..
Supreme Court says our law..
Is the law.
Your Honor,
if I may.
I believe there are special circumstances
to be considered.
What would warrant
a colored woman attendin' a white school?
May I approach the bench, sir?
Your Honor,
You of all people should understand
the importance of being first.
How's that, Mrs. Jackson?
Well, you were the first in your family
to serve in the Armed Forces.
US Navy.
The first to attend University.
George Mason.
And the first State Judge to be re-commissioned
by three consecutive Governors.
You've done some research.
Yes, sir.
What's the point?
The point is, your Honor...
No Negro woman in the State of Virginia
has ever attended an all white high school.
- It's unheard of.
- Yeah! Unheard of.
And before Alan Shepard
sat on top of a rocket,
no other American had ever touched space.
And now, he will forever be remembered
as the US Navy man from New Hampshire.
The first to touch the stars.
And I, sir.
I plan on being an engineer at NASA.
But I can't do that without taking them
classes at that all-white high school.
And I can't change the color of my skin.
So, I have no choice.. But to be the first.
Which I can't do without you, sir.
Your Honor,
of all the cases you'll hear today,
which one will matter in a hundred years from now?
Which one will make you the "first?"
Only the night classes.
Mrs. Jackson.
- How late did you say it was gonna be?
- No more than 5 minutes sir.
Gus Grissom's coordinates..
I'd like to get a jump on
John Glenn's trajectory.
Do you have any idea what you're asking?
An orbital launch
with an Atlas Rocket is going to take time.
Is there a problem?
Mr. Harrison...
I was wondering....
I've been wondering my whole life.
So just... Spit it out.
Well, sir.
I'd like to get a jump on
John Glenn's trajectory.
This isn't about plugging in numbers,
this is about inventing the math.
I think we talked about that, right?
It doesn't exist.
I can do it, sir.
Do you know any idea how exacting
these calculations have to be?
It's like shooting a sawed-off shotgun
from a thousand feet,
and getting that one beebee through a hole
so tiny, you can't even see it.
I'm an excellent shot, sir.
How about Grissom's numbers. Paul?
They've been spot on.
Give Glenn's orbit a go.
But you run it all through Stafford.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Computers don't author reports.
Capcom, this is Liberty Bell 7
loud and clear
ok, it's nice ride up to now
Liberty Bell 7 capsule is taking on water.
Gus Grissom is out of the capsule. Rescuers
are now going to pull him from the Ocean waves.
Unfortunately,
Liberty Bell 7 capsule..
.. Is lost.
Mr. Harrison, Taxpayer money sank in
the ocean along with your capsule.
What makes you think you can
bring John Glenn home safely?
Let me say first that discovery is never
for the sake of discovery, Gentlemen,
but for the sake of human survival.
It will always come with the risk.
Whoever gets there first, will make the rules.
That's been true of every civilization. And so..
I think the bigger question for
this body to consider is..
Who do you want calling the shots in space?
We have to know what's out there, Senator.
We have to touch the stars. If
only to ensure our own survival.
And only a man can do that.
We'll get John Glenn home safely
because we have to,
because he has to tell us what he saw.
The Redstone Rocket went straight up.
But the capsule..
.. Didn't have enough speed to go
into orbit. So came back down.
Essentially it's a triangle..
Earth, sub-orbit, Earth.
That math was known.
That took Shepard,
took Grissom.
That cannot take Glenn.
Now, The Atlas Rocket..
That can push us into orbit.
It goes up
delivers the capsule
into an elliptical orbit.
Earth's gravity keeps pulling it,
but it's going so fast that
it keeps missing the Earth.
That's how it stays in orbit.
Now, Getting it back down...
That's the math we don't know.
Yes, Katherine
So, the capsule will spin
around the Earth forever,
because there's nothing
to slow it down?
That's right. Slowing it down at precisely
the right moment,
by precisely the right amount
That is the task.
Yes, Katherine
So, it means to move from an
elliptical orbit.. To a parabolic orbit?
Yes.
That's the Go/ No Go.
Now, this point is a pin head.
- We bring him in too soon..
- He burns up on reentry.
That's right. We bring him too late,
and he's pushed out of Earth's gravity.
Any changes to mass, weight, speed, time,
distance, friction... or a puff of wind..
Would alter the Go/No Go.
And we start our calculations.. Over
Yes.
So, we need to be able to
choose this re-entry point.
This Go/No Go.
This has to be exact.
Sam
These are the latest Redstone numbers
and current capsule data.
Obviously, we know the launch spot
The Pentagon Briefing should illuminate
where the Navy needs the recovery zone.
When we work backwards from there.
And the rest is on us.
So, let's get to work.
- Mr. Stafford.
- What, Katherine?
If I could attend the briefings, I
would be more useful to the project.
Pentagon briefing is a closed door.
Yes. But if we don't
have the information,
of the changes.. We can't keep up.
I need those changes as they occur.
- As you said, it's a pin head.
- Katherine, that's the job.
You asked for this assignment.
So just calculate with what you have.
Or we'll find someone who can.
OK.
That'a girl.
And what the hell are you doing?
You can't be in here
Who are you?
I'm with the West Computing Group.
Dorothy Vaughan, sir.
Well, this is a very
delicate piece of equipment.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm just trying to be helpful.
Bill, we've got numbers.
What kind of numbers?
Well, I'll be.
What's your name again?
Dorothy Vaughan.
Dorothy Vaughan...
Sir, the parameters
for Friendship 7.
Oh, this is all moot. We're
altering the window on the capsule.
When did this happen?
6 minutes ago. The mass is changing.
Start over.
Sir.. If I could attend briefings..
I could stay current..
Katherine, we've been through this.
It is not possible.
There's no protocol for women attending.
There's no protocol for a man
circling the Earth either, sir.
OK. That's just
the way things are.
Colonel Glenn's launch coordinates
accounting for the window change, sir.
I've told you this: Computers don't
author reports. Fix it.
Those are my calculations.
My name should be on it.
But it is not the way this works.
Paul.
What's happening here?
Mr. Harrison,
I'd like to attend today's briefing.
- Why's that?
- Well, sir, the data changes so fast.
The capsule changes. The weight and the
landing zones are all changing everyday.
I do my work, you attend these briefings.
I have to start all over.
Colonel Glenn launches in a few weeks.
We don't have the math figured out yet.
- Why is it she can't attend?
- Because she doesn't have clearance, Al.
I can not do my work effectively
if I do not have all of the data,
and all of the information
as soon as it's available.
I need to be in that room,
hearing what you hear.
Pentagon Briefings are not for civilians.
It requires the highest clearance.
I feel like I'm the best person
to present my calculations
- You're not gonna let this go are you?
- No, I'm not
Let her in? She's a woman.
There's no protocol for a woman attending.
Okay, I get that part, Paul.
But within these walls,
who... makes the rules?
You, sir. You're the boss.
You just have to act like one. Sir.
You keep quiet.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Gentlemen
This is Katherine Goble with our
Trajectory and Launch Window Division.
Her work is pertinent to
today's proceedings.
Come on.
Go get her a chair.
We have a confirmed
launch window..
- Give her your chair.
- Yes, sir.
We have a confirmed launch window for
friendship 7. Let's discuss a landing zone.
The Navy needs a singular landing zone.
20 miles square is what we can
service for retrieval.
Outside of that,
we risk the capsule's recovery.
We'd like 3 possible recovery areas.
We can't cover half the damn ocean.
With all due respect,
our capsule's being altered daily.
We're orbiting the Earth at...
what's the speed now?
17,544 miles per hour.
At the time the rocket delivers the
capsule into low space orbit.
That's one hell of a speeding ticket.
OK.
So we have the vehicle's speed,
the launch window and for argument's sake,
the landing zone is The Bahamas.
Should be enough to figure the Go/No Go?
- Yeah! In theory, sir.
- We need to be past theory at this point.
We'll be able to calculate a
Go/No Go with that information.
When exactly is that gonna happen?
Katherine.
Have a go at it?
The Go point for re-entry
is 2,990 miles
from where we want Colonel Glenn to land.
If we assume that's The Bahamas.
At 17,544 miles per hour..
Upon reentry..
370..
At a descent angle..
Of 46.56 ..
Degrees..
Distance..
OK!
So, that puts the landing zone at...
25.0667° North,
77.3333° West.
Which is here
Right here.
Give or take 20 square miles.
I like her numbers.
Thank you.
That of course is assuming the ..
Capsule hits the reentry point exactly
How do we insure that?
That's the math we don't
have yet, gentlemen.
We're working on it.
Katherine
What's it gonna take to make
this thing worth the price tag?
We're just getting up to speed here,
Mr. Harrison.
I need more man power.
I mean Programmers.
Folks to feed the cards.
Then get them, for crying out loud.
Right?
- You're the IBM man, right?
- Yes, sir.
Pull them out of the sky if you
have to, but let's get ahead of
- this thing. Or I'm not paying you.
- Understood
I got that one
I'm not paying any of you!
- Me?
- Temporarily. Yes.
We need the IBM for Glenn's launch.
The Lead Engineer says you're good
with the cards, programming and such.
What about the girls here?
Human computers can't calculate an
orbital flight in the time we have.
- They'll stay put for now.
- What about after "now"?
After the Glenn launch, NASA's
dissolvin' the Computing Groups.
I'm not accepting reassignment.
Unless, I bring my ladies with me.
Excuse me?
We're going to need a lot of
manpower to program that beast.
I can't do it alone.
My girls are ready
They can do the work.
Ladies!
We've been reassigned.
Leave your calculators.
You won't need them where we're going.
Welcome, ladies!
Do you know what your job is, Paul?
To find the genius among those geniuses.
To pull us all up.
We all get to the peak together,
or we.. Don't get there at all.
Yes. Well.
Good night, sir.
I don't know what time
I'm coming home.
The class ends at 9.
You got something to say?
Thought you might need these.
You can refill ‘em with any weight
lead you want.
See, you just hit the top like this.
Lead comes out
You put the new lead in..
And.. New pencil
You will make a fine engineer.
- You think so?
- Yes.
And nobody dare stand in the way of
Mary Jackson's dreams. Myself included.
- Don't make me mad again.
- Yes, ma'am.
And don't make me late either.
You don't really want me to make you?
Hi, gentlemen.
Tonight we discuss Planck–Einstein.
Wavelength relationships..
Yes?
I'm Mary Jackson.
I'm enrolled.
Well. The curriculum is not designed
for teaching... a woman.
Well, I imagine it's the same as
teaching a man.
I don't see a colored section.
Should I just take any seat?
Thank you.
OK.
Planck–Einstein...
The problem is when the capsule moves
from an elliptical orbit to a parabolic orbit.
There's no mathematical formula for that.
As we can calculate launch, landing
but without this conversion, the capsule
stays in orbit, we can't bring it back home.
Maybe we've been thinking about this
all wrong.
How's that?
Maybe it's not new math at all.
It could be old math.
Something that looks at the problem
numerically, and not theoretically
- Math is always dependable.
- For you it is.
Euler's Method.
- Euler's Method?
- Yes.
- That's ancient.
- But it works!
It works numerically.
That's it!
Let's type it up.
Dorothy.
Mrs. Mitchell.
You're working late today?
Seems always happened that way
Yes.
Seems to.
Thank you.
I hear the IBM is at full capacity.
You certainly have a knack for it
My father taught me a thing or
two about mechanics.
You know, I have a few girls in the East Group
that have an interest in learnin' more about it.
- It is the future.
- I may bring ‘em by, if it's all the same to you.
That's not my decision. Ma'am.
That would be the supervisor's.
Yes. That's true.
Well.
Good night, Mrs. Mitchell.
You know, Dorothy...
Despite what you may think..
I have nothin' against ya'll.
I know.
I know you probably believe that.
Goodnight, Katherine.
Good night!
- Mamma.
- Hey, baby
Hi!
Hey!
Please don't tell me I miss
someone's birthday
- No, you didn't
- No, you didn't, mamma
Madame...
Your seat.
Thank you
Well, is it my birthday?
No, mamma.
You're all look so pretty
Mamma,
What's going on?
Good evening, Katherine.
- So, you are not gonna say anything?
- It's not my place.
You, really?
Okay, I'm not going to do this all night...
Oh, mother of mercy.
That's for me?
Are you sad, Mamma?
- No! - It's okay, Mamma.
- He's a good man.
I know.
I know. I just. I can't help it.
He hasn't even asked you yet.
I know, but he is..
You are, right?
If ya'll let me.
Go on. She's already crying.
- This was my mother's ring.
- It is beautiful
- She and my father were married for..
- For 52 years.
I figure it's about as lucky as a ring
as you can get.
The day I met you, I called my mother...
I said: "Mom!
I met the woman I want to marry."
What'd she say?
She said: "She must be something,
Jimmy. Really something."
Then what'd you say?
I said: "No, She is more than Something,
She is Everything."
I planned on this being more romantic.
I'll make that up to you real soon.
But I know marrying you..
Includes me and the girls as well.
Amen to that.
I do.
- I didn't ask you yet.
- Hurry up!
No pain, please!
No, girls. No tears.
The Mercury Atlas Space vehicle,
which will putt John Glenn
the first American into Earth orbit,
has already undergone 5 unmanned
flight tests.
NASA has confirmed that the
IBM 790 data processing
system has been utilized to confirm all of the
mission's long and recovery system calculations.
The modifications and equipment installations
are progressing on the schedule.
Them, Here
- You wanted to see me, sir?
- Have a seat
Is there something wrong, Mr. Harrison?
No. There's nothing wrong.
In fact our IBM is churning out numbers
in fractions of the time any human can
Present company included.
That's good then.
Maybe.
The thing is, the Cape is now insisting on
doing all the backups down there. On site.
I see.
So, we won't be running backups here.
And truth be told, we can't keep up
with that IBM anyhow.
Long story short, we no longer need a..
Computer in this department.
Progress is a double edged sword.
Let's have you report back
to the West Group for now.
- I'll see if we can find another assignment.
- Thank you, sir.
Katherine, I'm..
I'm sorry about this
It's out of my hands, if you
can believe that.
I understand.
Katherine..
We heard you got engaged.
Yes.
That's thoughtful of you.
- They're lovely.
- Mr. Harrison's idea really.
Although I suspect his wife did
the picking out.
I can't imagine he has an eye
for anything but numbers..
Now, you have a great wedding.
You did good work around here, Katherine.
I don't think I felt a thing
the first time I did this.
I was so nervous.
- This is as beautiful as you were back then.
- You think so?
Just a little older.
And a little fuller...
But you look good.
Here we go. Again.
That'a girl
.. And Colonel John Glenn will be
the first American to orbit the Earth.
As you can see, there are thousands of
people here to witness this historic event
Paul, something's off here. These landing
coordinates don't match yesterday's.
The IBM just ran them.
So then the IBM was wrong yesterday, right?
Or the damn thing is wrong today.
Paul, Am I right?
- It appears so.
The IBM has been spot on up to this point, John.
But we'll run it again,
to see what it comes up with.
I'll be honest with you, Al
When I fly, I fly the machine,
Right now, it seems like this machine
is flying me.
We're on the same page, John.
Our guys are on it.
Let's get the girl to check the numbers.
- The girl?
- Yes, sir.
- You mean Katherine?
- Yes, sir. The smart one.
If she says they're good,
I'm ready to go.
- All right. We'll get into it.
- Roger!
Sam!
Go find Katherine Goble.
She needs to verify Glenn's Go/No Go
or we're staying on the ground.
Yes, sir.
I'm looking for Katherine Goble
- It's Katherine Johnson now.
- They need you to verify these coordinates.
All right.
Give her some space to work.
A truly historic day for America..
The country has waited for several months,
through many failed unmanned Atlas rocket tests
and 10 scheduled manned attempts,
which were canceled for various
mechanical or system complications.
All the final tests and checks are being conducted,
John Glenn is ready to board the Friendship 7.
But today we remain truly optimistic
and it's a go day in all regards
the capsule is ready, the rocket itself
is a OK, and the weather here at..
- Anything from Langley?
- Not yet.
We're being told the mission control at Nasa
is conducting a final check
of the launch and recovery coordinates
including the go/no-go calculations
so crucial to a safe and successful launch
and recovery
After years of waiting, and months of delays,
col. Glen is finally ready for that space flight
we've been waiting for with so much anticipation
- We are still a go.
- Yes, sir.
That's it.
What the devil are you doing?
Are you taking a break?
You have the time?
Sir.
Pad 14.
Katherine!
Come on
Sir, we've got Pad 14 on the box.
Alright, let me in there.
This is Langley.
We have the coordinates confirmed.
Standby, Langley.
We can confirm the Go/No Go
point for re-entry is..
16.11984 degrees latitude
- 165.2356 degrees longitude.
The launch window is a go.
The landing coordinates match.
That's very good news, Al.
It's a little hard to trust something
you can't look in the eyes.
That's right, Colonel.
Katherine did manage to calculate
a few decimal points further than that
hunk of metal.
Well, I'll take every digit ya got.
Be sure to thank her for me.
- Gentlemen! Let's launch this rocket.
- Good luck, Friendship 7.
God speed, Langley.
Here at Cape Canaveral the countdown
has resumed as Colonel John Glenn
is now aboard Friendship 7,
high above the Atlas rocket on Pad 14.
A height of over 93 feet ..
These pictures are from Cape Canaveral, Florida
Deck entry is now moving back.
We're go for launch.
The Mercury Spacecraft umbilical is out
T-10 seconds, and counting
8.. 7.. 6.. 5..
4.. 3.. 2..
1.. Zero.
Ignition.
It's getting bumpy along here.
Roger that.
You are in Max Q.
Roger that Capcom
Twenty seconds to SECO.
- The trajectory is still be "OK".
- Go for SECO.
Zero G. And I feel fine.
John Glenn reports everything looks good
Oh, that view is tremendous.
Roger that, Friendship 7.
- You are go for orbit.
- Thank you, Capcom!
All right. 10.5 hours to go.
If we make 7 round trips.
I could use a coffee.
Well, as we approach the end of day
here on the Eastern seaboard..
Colonel Glenn is just beginning
his third orbit.
Three quarters of the way
across the African continent.
We see he is currently over Zanzibar, which
is the next tracking station coming up.
Thankfully the Friendship 7 capsule is..
New assignment came down the pike.
Always changing round here.
It's hard to keep up.
Seems like they're gonna need
a permanent team to feed that IBM
- How big of a team?
- 30 to start.
Thank you for the information,
Mrs. Mitchell.
You're quite welcome... Mrs. Vaughan.
We have a warning light!
Capcom 7,
I have a warning light.
Standby, 7.
Sir, we have a warning light!
- What are we looking at, Paul?
- The heat shield may have come loose.
7, will you confirm the landing
bag is in the OFF position?
Affirmative, Capcom.
Al, we need to get him down, now
He could burn up on re-entry.
Come on, babies!
There's a man in space. We don't want to
miss it, so we gonna home.
Something's wrong with Glenn.
- Oh, my Goodness!
- What's going on?
- Let's go.
- Ya'll follow me.
We've just learned, the Friendship 7
is in danger of losing its heat shield.
Have you heard any banging noises?
Or anything of this type at higher rates?
That's a negative, Capcom.
Tell him not to jettison
the retro-package.
NASA is confirming there is some sort of
malfunction with the capsule's heat shield,
and it may not stay in place.
If the heat shield is loose... The retro-
package straps might hold it in place.
- Will that work?
- It will work.
It will hold it until he reaches the
Go /No Go point. It will work!
He has to override the 05g.
Do it.
Friendship 7...
We're recommending that the retro-package
NOT, I repeat, NOT be jettisoned.
This means that you will have
to override the 05g switch.
Roger!
Is there a reason for this? Over.
Standby, 7.
Not at this time, 7.
Roger, that command.
I will make a manual 05g entry,
and bring the scope in.
Over.
He knows.
Without a heat shield,
there's no way a Colonel Glenn
can get back through
the Earth's atmosphere.
The heat is simply too overpowering.
A malfunction in the automatic control system
is causing the spacecraft to yaw
in a skid like fashion
thus putting the Friendship 7's
re-entry point in jeopardy
even now, col. Glen is
skidding towards the US
and he must begin the retro sequence
You're going to be using
fly-by-wire for reentry.
You'll need to maintain a zero angle.
Over.
Roger. I'm on fly-by-wire,
back-it up with manual. Over.
Keep talking to him.
Roger. The weather in the recovery area:
3 foot waves, 10 miles visibility.
Capcom, you're going out
He's crossing the
communication black-out zone.
There's a real fireball outside,
and it's getting a little hot here!
Friendship 7.
Do you copy? Over.
Again.
Friendship 7.
Do you copy? Over.
Friendship 7. Do you copy? Over.
Loud and clear, Capcom.
Roger that.
How are you doing?
My condition is good.
But that was a real fireball, boy
Roger that.
Let's get you all the way home.
Here's hoping these landing coords still hold.
Approaching 16.11984.
- Roger that!
- Approaching -165.2356. In 3, 2, 1.
Engaging chutes.
Beautiful chutes.
How we're lookin, Capcom?
Your Go/No Go is good.
Landing coordinates are spot on, 7.
Roger that, Capcom.
I've always wanted to swim in
the Bahamas. Over.
John Glenn has splashed-down,
and is being recovered.
John Glenn has splashed-down safely
and is being recovered by USS Noa.
Katherine!
- Nice work.
- You too, Mr. Harrison.
So..
You think we can get to the moon?
We're already there, sir.
Girls..... This is Mrs. Vaughan.
Your supervisor.
- She'll show you how things work.
- Yeah! Come on in