- Mr. Vale.
- Yes.
I'm Barbara Watson.
Yes. Come in.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Ah. May I take your coat?
No, thank you.
Uh...
would you like something to drink?
No.
Shall we get started?
Uh, okay.
Let's try it again.
The same thing?
Yes.
And remember...
fingers curved like a tunnel.
Okay.
Don't flatten.
Make room for the train.
What?
It's something I tell my kids.
If the fingers are curved, like this,
then there's room for the train
to pass through the tunnel.
Thank you.
Uh, next Tuesday, then, same time?
No. Uh, I don't think
I'm going to continue with our lessons.
Oh, no.
You're giving up?
No.
Oh.
Okay.
Well...
good-bye.
Good-bye.
Uh, Mr. Vale.
May I ask?
How many teachers
have you had before me?
Four.
Well, for what it's worth,
learning an instrument
at your age is difficult,
especially if you don't possess
a natural gift for it.
I'm not saying this to be mean.
But if you do decide to give up,
I'd really like to buy your piano.
Okay.
Each stage of experience
is really the exception to the rule
because the conditions there
that made trade mobilization
to the Middle East successful
weren't present
in the developing countries.
Yes?
Hi.
Come in.
Paper. Uh, sorry it's late.
Why is it late?
I had some personal
issues to deal with.
I'm sorry, but I can't accept it now.
I mean, I... I really had a...
I'm sorry.
Uh, you know you still haven't given us
the syllabus yet?
I know.
Yeah?
Hello, Walter.
Hi, Charles.
You got a sec?
Sure.
Walter, Shelley can't make it down
to the NYU conference
to present your paper.
I'm gonna need you to cover for her.
Why can't she go?
She's been put on bed rest
till she has the baby.
I wish I could, but now is not
a good time, Charles.
Well, I understand,
but you co-authored the paper,
and the Dean wants it presented.
He wants to keep
Shelley on track for tenure.
I just don't think I can,
with the start of classes and my book.
You're only teaching one class, Walter.
So I can stay focused on my book.
Charles, I would really rather not go.
Well, I'm sorry, but there really
isn't another option at this point.
Charles, the truth is...
this is really Shelley's paper.
I just agreed to co-author it
because she asked me to.
I'm not really prepared to present it.
Now, look, Walter,
you can take it up
with the Dean if you want,
but as your friend, I wouldn't advise it,
not with that argument.
Hello?
Aah! Aah! Aah! Get out!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Get out!
You stay away from me!
You leave me alone!
No. I... It's... It's okay. I... I'm...
It's not okay! My boyfriend is coming!
I'm... I'm... I'm not going to hurt you.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
This is my apartment.
This apartment does
not belong to you!
- How did you get in here?
- My name is Walter Vale.
- I have keys! This is my apartment!
- What the fuck!
Ow! Ow! God! Aah! Please!
- Zainab!
- I'm in here!
- Shut up!
- Aah!
- All ri... Okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Who are you?
Qu'est-ce que c'est a?
a va?
Oui, a va.
C'est qui?
J'tais dans mon bain.
Lui, il tait l.
- Did you touch her?
- What?
- Motherfucker, did you touch her?
- No! No! No!
Il ne m'a pas touche.
Mais comme il est entr,
il a dit qu'il avait la cl.
Do you have keys?
Yes, of course I have keys.
This is my apartment.
- Show me your keys.
- All right.
Here.
I've had this apartment for 25 years.
So why haven't you been here?
Because I live in Connecticut.
I haven't been down here in a very long time.
Are you friends with Ivan?
Ivan. I don't... Who's Ivan?
I'm sure he's called the police!
- Did you call the police?
- No.
- You did not call the police?
And you don't know Ivan?
No. Who is he?
- He rented us this place.
- I don't know him.
He said it belongs
to his friend who is out of town.
I don't know who he is.
This is my apartment. I assure you.
Shit!
Je t'ai dj dit
de faire confiance  personne.
T'as jamais sign
un contrat.
Shit.
Hey, look.
We don't want any trouble.
We will get out of your apartment.
Here. Take your keys.
It's all a mistake. I'm sorry.
Okay.
We will leave. Okay?
Yeah, okay.
How long have you lived here?
Two months.
We will pay you if you want.
Yes, so, uh, we will go.
I'm sorry, again.
Thank you for understanding.
Go get the valise.
Okay, okay.
Good-bye.
Tarek.
- Tarek.
- What?
Uh... you left this in the apartment.
Thanks.
So you know where
you're staying tonight?
Yeah, sure. We're goin' to some friends'.
You like classical music, huh?
Yes.
Me, too.
Do you play the piano?
No.
Do you?
Me? No. I play the djembe.
Hmm.
Okay. Good night.
And thanks again for letting us stay.
Um... you saved me a lot of trouble,
if you know what I mean.
We'll be out of your way
in a couple of days. Okay?
Good night.
Good morning.
I made some coffee.
Thank you.
And... have a good day.
Good-bye.
Walter Vale.
Thank you.
And that will be on the last day
of the conference.
I hope you can all attend.
And now I'd like to welcome
my distinguished colleague
and the winner
of the John Bates Clark Award...
Professor Stephen Kriegman.
Thank you, Shiva.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Mr. Vale?
Yes.
Oh, my goodness. How are you?
It's me.
Jacob Koningsberg.
Do you remember me?
- I'm sorry.
I... I used to live on the third floor
- with my mother.
Your wife used to give me piano lessons.
Oh, right, right.
How are you?
Oh, my goodness.
I haven't seen you in so long.
We thought that you
sold the place.
You haven't met Sprinkles.
This is Sprinkles. Say hello.
Hello. How is your wife?
Oh, my wife passed away.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
My... My condolences to you.
She was a lovely woman.
Honestly, I could
listen to her play piano for hours.
How is your mother?
My mother is fine.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for asking. She's in Florida.
So I'm living alone now, and it's nice,
but I tell you, there are so many
new people in this building,
- and Mr. Sprinkles and I...
- It's nice to see you again, Jacob.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you. Welcome home.
Thank you.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Stop it.
Come on, honey.
We find that,
under these circumstances,
financial globalization
can be beneficial.
Empirically, it's good institution
and quality of government
that will allow third world countries
to benefit and harvest
the fruits of globalization.
Great stuff, huh?
Maybe we should have 'em
come play inside.
Uh, you coming?
In a minute. Uh, I gotta make a call.
- Oh. Uh, see you inside.
- Okay.
- ##
- Hey, Walter.
Welcome home.
Hi.
How was the conference?
It was fine.
Sorry about the pants. I...
I've been practicing
like this since I was a kid.
You... You don't have
to stop practicing.
Really? it won't bother you?
- No. It's fine.
- Great.
Hey, uh, Zainab's going to make dinner,
if you want to eat with us later.
Okay. Thank you.
I'm sorry.
That was my mother in Michigan.
If I don't call her every day,
she thinks something happened to me.
Yeah, I'll have a bit. Thanks.
You sure you won't have some?
I don't drink.
She's a good Muslim. I'm a bad one.
Are you finished?
Yes. Uh... can I help you?
No. Please.
It's the least I can do.
Well, thank you for dinner.
It was very good.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
So what's the conference about?
Economic growth
in developing nations.
That's us. Syria, Senegal.
So have you written some books?
Three, and I'm working on a fourth.
- Four books.
- Mm-hmm.
Wow. That's great.
My father was a writer. A journalist.
Is he still writing?
No. He died before we left Syria,
almost nine years ago.
Sorry.
Me, too.
- Tarek.
- Mmm.
Mmm. We have to go.
I have a gig.
Walter, you can come if you want.
Oh, no. I've got some work
I have to get done. Thank you.
Okay. Well, maybe another time.
Okay.
- Bye.
- Good-bye.
You know, you are very sexy
when you're mad at me.
Hello?
If you don't mind, I think I will come.
Cool.
Let me get my coat.
Hohh!
He's very good.
Yes.
- The whole band's very good.
- Yes.
I'm sorry, guys.
Yeah, well, let's go.
Very good.
Really? You liked it?
Yeah. It was very good.
I was not sure.
I thought it's too loud and you know.
Tarek?
Oh.
Hi.
Sounded good, Walter.
I'm sorry. I...
No. Don't be sorry.
That's what it's there for.
I was lying
on my bed, listening to my music,
and then I was, like...
what's that crazy rhythm I'm hearing?
Sit. Come on. I'll show you.
Just put your feet flat on the ground.
Now take the drum
between your legs like this.
Now you want to take
the inside edge off the ground
with your ankles, like this.
Great.
You're okay?
Okay.
Now, Walter, I know
you're a very smart man,
but with a drum
you have to remember not to think.
Thinking just screws it up. Okay?
Okay.
Now, give it a couple of bangs.
Not so hard. You're not angry at it.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Okay.
Better. Did you think?
No.
Good.
Now, one more thing, Walter.
You listen to classical music,
so you think in fours.
1, 2, 3, 4.
Dah, dah, dah, dah.
This is an African drum,
so we're gonna be playing in threes.
Tak tak tak.
You have to forget your classical.
Leave it behind. Tak tak tak.
1, 2, 3.
Come on, follow me.
Tak tak tak.
1, 2, 3.
Don't worry. Start again.
Good.
Don't worry.
Again.
Good.
You got it.
Go...
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Don't worry.
Don't worry. Go again.
Good.
That's it.
Now, keep it going, and I'll do this.
There you go.
1...
Hohh!
Hello.
Hi.
Is Tarek home?
Uh, no. He, uh...
he went to look at another apartment.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Tarek's been giving me drum lessons,
and I was just practicing.
Don't worry. I'll keep my pants on.
What?
Nothing.
It's just that earlier, uh...
No, nothing.
Which is due, in large part,
to the delay in African infrastructure
and the slowdown on steel imports.
Hey, Walter!
How did the presentation go?
Oh, fine. Thanks.
Cool.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Let's go.
- Can you grab this drum?
- Yeah.
Okay.
You might want to take off
your, uh, name tag.
Oh, okay.
You hungry?
Yeah, I'm starving.
You like shawarmas?
Yeah, I like sharmas.
Shawarmas.
Here. This is for you.
For letting us stay.
Oh. Thank you.
It's Fela Kuti. You know him?
Nope.
- You don't know Fela?
- No.
Then, Walter, you're in for a treat.
He started the whole Afrobeat movement.
Oh, and his drummer, Tony Allen,
was just... whoo, scary, man.
You want to play drums,
you have to listen to this.
Okay. I will.
Ooh.
Did you make these?
Yes, I made these.
Ooh.
- How much?
- Which one?
Mmm...
this one.
That's $35.
Will you take 30?
No. 35.
Okay.
My daughter will think this is very cool.
Where are you from?
Senegal.
Oh, I was in Cape Town
two summers ago.
It is so beautiful.
- Thank you very much.
- What's your name?
Uh, Zainab.
Zainab!
So pretty.
- Thank you.
- Your change.
How far is Senegal from Cape Town?
About 8,000 kilometers.
I told this guy yesterday
I was from Israel.
He asked if I ever visited the Holy Land.
Hey, look who it is!
- Zev.
- What's up, Tarek?
How are you, man?
Good, man.
Hey, honey.
Hi. Hi, Walter.
Hi.
Her stuff is great, right?
Beautiful.
She made me this.
It's very nice.
So Walter and I
are goin' up to the park
to play for a little bit, okay?
Tarek. Remember I told you
we have to pick up
my new table today?
He said he'll only hold it for today.
Oh, I know, I know. No problem.
Tarek, you always say "No problem,"
and then you are late or you forget.
I know. I... I will not be long.
We will go up and play,
and we'll come back to help you.
It's a promise, habibti.
It's always habibti
when you want to win, huh?
Good-bye.
Bye.
He closes at 5 p.m., Tarek.
No Arab time.
No, not Arab time.
Real time, habibti.
Don't habibti me, man.
What does habibti mean?
Habibti? It means "beloved one."
Does she know that?
I always wanted to play down here.
It's supposed to be good money.
Why haven't you?
Maybe we could do it together...
split the profits.
What do you think?
I think I'll just watch.
Come on, Walter, it's easy.
You just wait until you feel it.
Yeah, let's go.
Oh...
That was fun, right?
Oh, yeah.
How are your hands?
They're...
Oh, shit. We have to get home.
Zainab's gonna kill me.
I'm on Arab time again.
What is Arab time?
It means I'm late by an hour.
All Arabs are late by an hour.
It's genetic. We can't help it.
I think that's our train.
I'm gonna need a token.
No, I got you. I got you.
Here's our train. Come.
Here, I got you. Let...
I'm stuck, man.
Here, take it.
This way, please.
What are you doing?
NYPD.
Step this way, please.
Police? What do you want?
You jumped the turnstile, man.
I did not jump it. I paid.
Sir, he... he paid... Please.
But he paid...
Sir, stand over there!
Got anything else, Tarek?
No. Where you from?
I'm from Syria. Why?
What's in the bag?
It's my drum.
Put this back in your pocket, please, sir.
Step over here.
- Why? I'm sorry...
- Step over here, please.
What did I do?
Oh, come on. Come on.
- I don't think that's necessary.
- Yeah, well, we do.
You can come down to the station
- and make a statement if you want.
- But he didn't...
Sir! That's all I'm saying!
Now, step back,
or we're gonna take you in, too.
Where are you taking him?
10th Precinct.
Walter, take the drum.
Tell Zainab what happened,
but don't let her come.
I will call you.
Don't let her come.
Where's Tarek?
He was arrested.
What?
Yes.
In the subway.
Arrested?
It was just a misunderstanding.
They said he'd be
released later tonight.
How could this happen?
He knows better.
He wouldn't do anything wrong.
No, he didn't.
He didn't.
I'm sure it'll be okay.
No, it won't be okay.
No, I went down to the precinct
and made a statement.
That doesn't matter.
We are illegal.
We are not citizens.
And when they find out, they're going to...
Excuse me.
Well?
They moved him.
To where?
To a detention center in Queens.
He was turned over to Immigration.
They said we can see him
tomorrow night.
Visiting hours are 5 to 10.
I cannot visit that place.
I'll end up there, too.
Zainab?
Yes.
I brought some Chinese food home,
if you'd like to eat.
Oh, no, thank you. I'm not hungry.
Okay. Well, if you change your mind,
I'll leave some in the fridge.
Thank you.
Have you heard from Tarek?
No. Not yet.
Oh. Well...
I made an appointment
with an immigration attorney
for tomorrow morning at 11.
No. We can't afford that.
That's okay.
Thank you, Walter.
Walter.
I was in detention...
when I first arrived, for five months.
How did you get out?
They... closed the facility
and released some of the women.
They didn't release any of the men.
We'll get him out.
Good night.
Okay.
Yeah.
Sir, that detainee has been moved.
He was here yesterday.
Well, he's not here now.
That's all I know.
You can call I.C.
The number's on the wall.
Where?
On the wall by the phone
and the water fountain.
Next.
Sir, step aside, please.
Hi. I'm here to see Tarek Khalil.
Have you been here before?
No, sir.
Hello?
May I see your driver's license, please?
Yes, it is. Um...
the one you...
Hi, papito.
Hi.
Walter. Thank you for coming.
Of course.
How is Zainab?
She's upset. Um...
I have a... a letter from her.
Oh, you can't give it to me.
It has to be sent to me by mail.
Oh.
But... But you can put it up to the glass.
Go ahead. Open it up
and press it up to the glass
so I can read it.
It's okay. It's allowed.
You want to say hello to pap?
Oh...
Thank you, Walter.
So how are they treating you?
It's very depressing here.
There's no privacy.
The lights are always on.
You need anything?
No. I just want to get out of here.
Well... Zainab and I met
with a lawyer today.
Yes? What did he say?
Well, he's... he's gonna
stop by tomorrow and see you.
Tarek. Zainab said
that you were denied asylum.
You mean when we came here?
Yeah.
Did you go to your deportation hearing?
In Michigan.
Yeah. We did everything they told us to.
Okay.
Let's go, man. You gotta get off.
Bed count.
I have to go.
They have to do a bed count.
Usually, I can visit for one hour.
Could you come tomorrow?
- I will. Yeah.
- Good.
Good-bye, my friend.
Good-bye.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay. Bye.
Walter, I'm going to leave now.
I have a cousin who lives in the Bronx.
I'm going to go
stay with him for now.
You don't have to go.
You can stay here.
I think it's better I leave.
Um... you know how to reach me
if you need to.
Is it okay if I leave
Tarek's things here for now?
Uh, my cousin's place is...
not very big.
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
Hello?
Oh. Hi, Charles.
Oh. Wait. I'm sorry. Wha... What?
Yeah. The conference went very well.
Yes.
No, uh, actually, I'm still in New York,
and I'm doing some research for my book.
Why?
When's the meeting?
Wha...
Oh. Okay.
All right. I... I'll, um...
I'll leave first thing tomorrow.
Yeah. I'll see you at 3. Bye.
I thought you said
you went to the hearing.
We did. I remember it.
Well, then why is there
a final order out on you?
He didn't know yet. He just said
that unless they can find a way
to reopen the case quickly,
they're going to deport me.
I don't even understand it.
Walter, there are guys
who have been in here for years.
I can't do that, Walter. I'll go crazy.
He's trying to deal with the case
as quickly as possible.
I know. I know. It's...
It's just...
Look, maybe we
should call your mother.
No. No. I don't want her to worry.
Yeah.
Tarek, um...
I have to go back to Connecticut.
When?
Tomorrow.
But I'll be reachable
by phone if you need anything.
And I'll be back to visit. It's not far.
Okay.
Just please...
don't forget about me in here.
No, I won't.
So have you been practicing?
Yes.
You should go back to the drum circle.
No.
Okay, but listen to that Fela CD.
That will help you.
- I promise.
- I will. I will.
So show me what you...
you've been working on.
What?
Show me. Why not?
Here?
Come on. I need some music, man.
Don't worry. They can't arrest you.
At least, not yet.
Mmm...
Come on.
Good.
Oh, no. An elbow.
Hello.
Oh, I'm sorry. I must've got
- the wrong apartment.
- Can I help you?
I'm looking for my son.
Excuse me.
Uh, are...
are you Tarek's mother?
Yes.
Well, this is Tarek's apartment.
I j...
I share the apartment with him.
He didn't mention
that he lived with someone.
Well, I'm not here very often.
I... I live in Connecticut.
Is Tarek here?
No. He's not here now.
Uh, come in... please.
Please.
Thank you.
Oh, my name is Walter. Walter Vale.
I'm... I'm Mouna Khalil.
I'm sorry to show up unannounced.
My son hasn't called me for five days.
I keep trying his cell phone,
but he doesn't answer.
Would you like to sit down?
Thank you.
Mr. Vale?
Is my son all right?
Yes.
He's been arrested.
He's being held in a detention center.
Where?
In Queens.
Uh, they're tying to deport him.
How did this happen?
He was stopped in a subway station.
Uh... he didn't... didn't
do anything wrong.
I'd like to go there, to Queens.
Okay.
But, Mrs. Khalil, um, the lawyer m...
Uh, I just don't
think it's possible for you...
Mr. Vale, I know I cannot visit Tarek.
I just want to see the place
where they're holding him.
Okay.
I can take you there.
Thank you.
Could we go now?
So have you been
to New York before, Mrs. Khalil?
No. Tarek wanted to come to New York
to play music.
I did not want him to, but...
Do you have
any children, Mr. Vale?
A son. He lives in London.
And your wife?
My wife passed away.
I'm sorry.
That's it.
- This is where the prison is?
- Mm-hmm.
It doesn't look like a prison.
I think that's the point.
How many people are in there?
Tarek said about 300.
There's, uh...
There's a coffee shop on that corner.
- It's not very nice.
- I'll wait there.
Walter. I thought you were leaving.
I was.
Tarek, your mother is here.
What? My mother? Where?
She's waiting outside.
When did she arrive?
Today.
Man. Why did she come?
She can do nothing for me.
Well, she said
she hadn't heard from you.
Walter, listen to me.
She... She can't stay here.
She doesn't know
anyone in New York.
I'm sorry, but you must get her
to go back to Michigan.
Okay. Okay, I'll try.
Thank you, Walter.
I have a note from her.
Need anything else?
No, thank you.
Hello, sir.
Hi.
How is he?
Oh, he's good. He's good.
Um... but...
he's very concerned
about you being here.
I will not leave.
Mrs. Khalil, I don't... I don't think
your being in New York will do any good
because we have a very good lawyer
working on Tarek's...
Mr. Vale.
I will not go back to Michigan
knowing that my son is in that building.
Even if I can't see him...
I will stay here.
Shall we go?
Uh madame?
Bye.
Mr. Vale?
I'm leaving now.
Thank you for your help.
Where are you going?
I'll find a hotel.
You can stay here.
You can use Tarek's room.
Thank you for your offer,
but I cannot accept it.
I don't want to impose on you.
You're not imposing.
Please. I would like you to stay.
Thank you.
But I will manage.
Good-bye.
Um... Mrs... Mrs. Khalil?
Please.
I was with Tarek
when he was arrested.
He was in the subway
in the first place because of me.
So...
please.
Even if it's just for one night.
Um, the bathroom is across the hall.
Thank you, Mr. Vale.
No. Call me Walter.
And I'm Mouna.
So... do you need anything else?
No, thank you.
Well... good night.
Good night.
Okay?
Bye.
Oh. Good morning.
Morning.
Mmhh...
Tarek says hello.
How is he?
I can't really tell.
He wants me to leave.
Well... you're welcome to stay here
as long as you need to.
Thank you.
That's very generous of you.
Well... thank you for the paper.
You're welcome.
Do you spend a lot of time in the city?
No, no. Not really.
I'm just here
presenting a paper at a conference.
Well...
You wrote it?
Mm-hmm.
Congratulations.
I co-authored it, really.
And what happened after the hearing?
We appealed. It took two years.
And your appeal was denied?
Yes.
And did they send you
your bag-and-baggage letter?
- No.
- What's that?
Basically, it tells you
where to show up and be deported.
But you didn't receive it?
No. I would remember this.
Did you move?
Eventually, we had to.
But we had our mail advanced.
Is it possible that it
just never got there?
Yeah, it's happened before.
And pre-9/11, it wasn't much of a priority
trackin' people down,
but if you got it and you just ignored it,
then there's nothing I can do.
So... you can help him.
I'm gonna try.
But you should know it's still a long shot.
The government's approach
has changed radically.
It's very black and white now.
Either you belong, or you don't.
Tarek's lucky.
Most of them don't even have lawyers.
Lucky.
Relatively speaking.
We just have to move quickly
to get an emergency stay,
and then we'll stick with a motion
to reopen, pending his green card application.
Yeah?
Okay.
Can you explain
what that means, please?
Actually, I don't have
the time right now.
I'm sorry.
I have to be in court very shortly.
How long will he be in detention?
I can't predict that. I am sorry,
but I am gonna have to wrap this up.
Do you have any children, Mr. Shah?
Yeah. Two kids.
And for what it's worth,
my uncle was deported
after raising a family here for 23 years.
If I can get your son out... I will.
Thank you.
Where are you from?
Queens.
Which one is she?
The one closest to us.
That black woman?
Mm-hmm.
That is Zainab?
She's very black.
Mm-hmm.
Zainab.
Oh. Hi, Walter.
Uh, Zainab, this is Mouna Khalil...
Tarek's mother.
- Oh...
- Hello, Zainab.
Oh, I...
It's a pleasure
to meet you, Mrs. Khalil.
You, too.
Uh... I'm s... I'm sorry.
I... I didn't know
you were coming.
Neither did I.
Your jewelry is very nice.
Oh.
Oh, thank you.
Do you think we can go out
for a cup of tea sometime?
Oh... yeah.
We could go right now.
I... I am...
I'm just watching Zev's table,
but I... um...
I just need to... find someone to...
Hey.
Hi.
Is it a necklace?
I think so.
I like that one in the front.
Um...
It's all handmade.
Ooh.
I've lived here for two years,
and I was in France
for a year before that.
Do you miss home?
Yes, sometimes.
But I don't want to live there.
Do you miss Syria?
Sometimes, too.
I miss Damascus...
the smell.
But this is my home now.
When did you meet Walter?
Walter? Uh...
about ten days ago.
Ten days? That's all?
Mm-hmm.
How did you meet him?
Uh...
through Tarek's friend.
Ivan. That's how we
ended up living there.
You live there, too?
Just for a little while.
Oh.
So... have you spoken to Tarek?
Yes.
He called me this morning.
He sounded in a good spirit.
I was so afraid this was going to happen.
Tarek used to tease me
that I worry too much.
But now...
I just don't know what to do.
I miss him so much.
I'm sorry.
Zainab.
I'd like you to do something for me.
I'd like you to show me
something you and Tarek like to do,
somewhere you like to go.
Like what?
Whatever you like.
Okay.
So what is in Staten Island?
I don't know.
We would just go there
and then come back.
We never got off.
Why?
It was free.
We felt like we were going somewhere.
Oh. That's where the Twin Towers were.
I never saw them, but... Tarek did.
Oh. And...
there's the Statue.
And behind that is Ellis Island.
Sometimes Tarek would point at the Statue
and jump up and down
like we're arriving
in New York for the first time.
It was very funny.
Can you go up in the Statue?
Oh, yeah.
I think so.
You haven't been there?
No.
Never?
Nope.
Oh.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Hey, Charles.
What's that?
Um, yeah. I'm still in New York.
I'm sorry, Charles.
I couldn't make it back yesterday.
I said I couldn't make it back!
Well, I'm on a boat.
A boat!
Listen, Charles, I'll explain it to you
when I see you.
But I have to go now,
so I'll call you back.
Bye.
You went on the ferry?
Yes.
No.
- My mother, too?
- She liked it.
You know that they don't even have
an outside space here.
They just have a room
with its roof cut out.
Really?
Some crazy stuff, man.
And they seemed to get along...
Zainab and my mother?
Yes. I think your mother
likes her very much.
My mother's not going home, is she?
I don't think so.
I know she's thinking about my father.
Why?
He spent seven years in jail in Syria
because of something
he wrote in the newspaper.
By the time
they released him, he was very sick.
He died two months later.
That's why we moved here.
Would you like a glass of wine?
No, thank you.
Mouna. Um...
I need to go back to Connecticut
tomorrow, for work. I told Tarek.
How long will you be gone?
Um, I don't know yet. I...
I'll try to get back
and visit him as soon as I can.
Walter, you don't have
to keep visiting him.
I'm sure you're busy.
I'll see what I can do.
Dinner will be ready soon.
Oh. Okay.
Walter. Do you go to Broadway?
No, not really.
Tarek sent me the CD
I think I know every word.
Tarek is teaching me the drum.
Really? How is that going?
Well, I... I sound a lot better
when he's playing with me.
How's your teaching?
My teaching?
Yes.
It's fine.
How many classes do you have?
Well, I have a lighter schedule
so I can focus on my book.
Your book?
What is it about?
Well, it... covers quite a bit,
so it's hard to explain.
You're almost finished?
I'm close.
Ahem.
You don't like
to talk about your work?
Mmm, it's, uh... just not a process
that's easy to talk about
with somebody who's not a writer.
Oh.
I shouldn't have
spoken to you like that.
It's okay.
- I'll get it, sir.
- Thanks.
Well...
um, you have my number
if you need anything.
Thank you. I'll be fine.
Here.
Thank you.
Have a safe trip.
Thanks.
Good-bye.
Good afternoon.
Hi, Mouna. It's Walter.
Uh, no. I was, uh, just checking in
to make sure everything was okay.
Okay. Oh, good.
Uh, you know... working.
Okay. So... good.
Good night.
Walter.
Hello.
I didn't expect you so soon.
Um, I just was cleaning a bit.
I love this CD.
Is it your wife?
Yes.
She was beautiful.
Thank you.
These are different glasses?
Mm-hmm.
They're new?
They are, yeah.
They're nice.
Thank you.
I was going to cook some lunch.
Are you hungry?
Yes. That would be nice.
Okay.
Mouna?
Yes.
Mmm, I was wondering.
Um, uh, Thursday night.
Do you have any plans?
No, Walter. I have no plans.
Okay. Well, then, I thought...
maybe we might do something.
Okay.
- They keep moving people.
- To where?
I don't know. I think
to other detention centers.
Two Moroccan guys were just moved.
They had no idea.
Suddenly, they were just gone.
Has anyone said anything to you?
No. No one in here knows anything.
This is not fair.
I am not a criminal.
I have committed no crime.
What do they think?
I'm a terrorist?
There are no terrorists in here.
The terrorists have money.
They have support.
This is just not fair.
- I know.
- How do you know? You're out there.
I'm sorry. I... Um...
I sit in here at night, and...
I keep thinking about Zainab.
I just want to live my life
and play my music.
What's so wrong about that?
Okay.
Okay. Please do.
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay. Bye.
What did he say?
That he'd make some calls,
but they can move him
to another facility at their discretion.
What facility? Where?
He said it could be anywhere.
Upstate Pennsylvania.
There's even one in Louisiana.
Louisiana?
Where they had the floods?
Mm-hmm.
But that's too far.
Yeah.
Did the lawyer say anything else?
No. He didn't know anything else.
It's just like Syria.
Okay.
Bye, habibti. Good-bye.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
That's okay. How is he?
He says hello.
He wants to make sure
you're practicing your drum.
I am. So...
You look very nice.
Thank you.
You, too.
Okay. That's good.
Thank you, sir.
You ready?
For what?
Well...
uh, I thought we'd go see this.
Really?
Yeah.
Now?
Yeah. Is that okay?
Yes. That's wonderful.
Thank you.
I'm so excited.
Okay. Don't move.
You know...
I think that show
was really kind of scary.
It was a little scary. Yeah.
Yeah.
Are you finished?
Yes. Thank you.
How was everything?
- Great.
- Very good.
Actually, I think
I'd like a glass of wine, please.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't even think to ask.
It's okay.
It's not every night
that you see The Phantom.
I'll have a Cabernet.
Cabernet.
Two, please.
Excellent.
Well, I haven't been to the theater
in a long time. Me, neither.
There's a place in Syria called Malula.
It's a very big outdoor theater.
It's beautiful.
We used to take Tarek there
to see concerts.
- Here you go. Two Cabernets.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Well.
Cheers.
Mmm.
Mouna. Um...
I'm taking a leave of absence...
uh, for the rest of the semester.
Ahem.
Really? Why?
Well, I thought I might
spend some more time in New York.
Walter, you don't
have to do this. You're busy.
No, I want to.
But you have to be in Connecticut.
You have your teaching, your book.
No, it's fine. Really.
This is not your problem, Walter.
It's okay that you're busy.
I'm not busy.
Not at all.
The truth is I haven't done any real work
in a very long time.
But you just
presented your paper at the conference.
No. No. No, I didn't even write it.
I just read it.
I've been teaching
the same course for 20 years,
and it... doesn't mean anything to me.
None of it does.
I pretend.
I pretend that I'm busy,
that I'm working, that I'm writing.
I'm not doing anything.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I really appreciate you telling me this.
Um, Walter.
What would you do if you didn't teach?
I don't know.
It's kind of exciting not to know.
What time is it?
Uh, 12:30.
My God. Is it?
Yeah. I think that happens
a lot in New York.
It's...
Thank you, Walter.
It was a lovely evening.
It's the most fun I had in a long time.
Yeah, I told Tarek
I was taking you tonight, and I did.
I think he was happy about it.
Thank you.
Good night.
There's a message from Tarek.
Something's wrong.
What did he say?
He said they were moving him.
He didn't know what it meant.
We should go.
Okay. When do you expect him?
All right. When he gets in,
could you have him
call me as soon as possible?
Uh, please.
It's an emergency. Thank you.
God, he's still in court.
Come on, come on,
come on. Can you hurry?
Sorry, sir.
I hate this feeling.
Um... I'm here for bed 38... Tarek Khalil.
Visiting hours start at 5 p.m.
What? I'm sorry. Excuse me?
- Visiting hours are at 5 p.m.
- Oh. Um,
it... I... I understand.
But this is e... extremely urgent.
Could you please check for me?
Thank you, sir. I appreciate it.
He is no longer with us.
Well... wh...
What does that mean?
I'm not sure.
What do you mean you're not su...?
I mean was he moved to another facility,
another state, what?
I don't know.
I just know that that detainee
is no longer at the facility.
Well, coul... could you please find
someone who... who does know?
I would appreciate it.
- Hold on.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Yes. Khalil. 38?
Okay.
Yes.
- Sir?
- Yes? Did you find him?
He's been removed.
Removed to where?
Deported.
Deported?
When?
He was deported this morning.
How can that be?
No, he...
Um... sir, is, uh...
Is there any way that I could contact him?
I don't think so.
You don't think so.
What kind of an answer is that?
I'm sorry, sir.
That's all the information that I have.
Okay.
Now, please step away from the window?
You can contact I.C.
if you have any further questions.
The number's on the wall.
Sir?
Step away from the window, please?
Sir. For the last time,
step away from the window.
You can't just take people away like that.
Do you hear me?
He was a good man, a good person.
It's not fair!
We are not just helpless children!
He had a life!
Do you hear me?
Do... I mean do you hear me?
What's the matter with you?
Walter.
What?
Let's go.
There is nothing we can do.
Let's go, please?
He did nothing wrong.
Are you okay?
Walter, I need to go back to Syria.
I should be there for Tarek.
When are you going?
Tomorrow.
It's best for me to be there
as soon as possible.
You won't be able to come back.
I know.
Good night.
Mouna?
I'm sorry.
I am so sorry.
Yes?
It's my fault what happened to Tarek.
We did receive the letter
telling us to leave.
I threw it away.
I never told him.
We were here for three years
before the letter arrived.
I had found a job.
Tarek was in school.
Everybody told me not to worry...
the government didn't care.
And it appeared to be true.
And then...
after a time...
you forget.
You think that you really belong.
It's not your fault.
Stop.
Zainab and I picked it out specially for you.
Thank you.
Oh. It's very nice.
Let me see it.
I like it.
- So do I.
- Mmm.
You look cool.
Cool?
Yes.
You're very cool, Walter.
Delta flight 275
now boarding at Gate 3 for Syria.
Delta flight 275, Gate 3 for Syria.
Thank you, Walter.
Thank you for everything.
I don't want you to go.
I don't want to go,
habibti.
Oh...
Subtitles by LeapinLar