My darling,
My heart belongs to you.
No matter what you've done,
I still love you.
I love you.
While you're locked in there
all those years,
I'll be locked up out here,
waiting for you.
I want to send a letter
to a guy who cheated me.
Mr Z Amaro,
thank you for what you did to me.
I trusted you
and you cheated me.
You even took the keys
to my apartment.
Dear Jesus,
You're the worst thing
to happen to me.
I'm only writing because
your son Josu asked me to.
I told him you're worthless,
and yet,
he still wants to meet you.
-Address?
-Jesus de Paiva.
Sitio Volta da Pedra.
Bom Jesus do Norte,
Pernambuco.
Dalva,
-My hot pussy...
-Pussy?
Your body against mine,
rolling around in the motel bed,
our sweat boiling,
me, I still...
-I still feel...
-Infatuated.
-That's it, infatuated!
-I don't know the exact address.
-I need it.
-Okay, then write:.
Third house after the bakery,
Mimoso, Pernambuco.
Cansano, Bahia.
Carangola, Minas Gerais.
Town of Relutaba, Cear.
Muzambinho, Minas Gerais.
Hello, Mrs Dora.
-How are you, Mr Pedro?
-Okay.
-See you tomorrow.
-See you.
CENTRAL STATION
Irene!
-What?
-Come on up! Now!
-Coming...
-This piece of crap...
is as old as I am, isn't it?
Sit down here.
Not again, Dora.
I want you to know that
I disapprove of this, okay?
Here, give me a hand.
Read this one.
I saw your ad
in the personals column
and your description was
the only one that interested me.
This jerk wrote the same thing
to ten different women.
I'm tall.
I have brown eyes, straight hair,
and an education.
-They say I'm good-looking.
-He's as ugly as a worm.
Education? He can't even write.
Trash?
Dear Jesus, you're the
worst thing to happen to me.
At least
try and show up for your son,
-he still wants to meet you.
-She says the boy wants
to meet his father, a drunkard. In
fact, she just wants the guy back.
Don't tear this one up!
The kid wants to...
-meet his dad and reunite the family.
-So what?
-You'll ruin it for them.
-He's a drunkard and used to beat her.
-So the boy's to grow up fatherless?
-Better than living with a drunk
-who'll beat him. It's decided: trash.
-But isn't it her first letter?
It'll be an exception!
I've had enough of this,
I'm leaving.
-He'll smash her face in...
-So? It's not up to you! It's her face.
-Okay, I'll put it in the drawer.
-No, you'll send it tomorrow.
The trash or the drawer... I'll
send it next week if we decide...
Liar! Those letters stay
in that purgatory for years.
I'll send it next week.
Sit down. Let's get back to work.
-You can be a pain in the ass sometimes.
-They say many people often lose...
control during Carnival. I'm one
of them. We both had a good time,
-but let's forget it now."
-Oh, I like this one.
You do?
Really? Really? Really?
I haven't heard from home for a while.
I don't think they get my letters.
Our postal service sucks, you can't
trust them. Or maybe they've moved.
-You think so?
-One buck, Mr Sergio.
See you, Mrs Dora.
The other day I sent a letter
through you. Remember?
Did you send it?
-No, I'm sending it today.
-Good! I want to tear that one up...
and send another.
I think I was too hard on him.
Go ahead.
Dear Jesus,
Your son Josu wants to meet you.
He wants to visit you
since he don't know you.
Doesn't know...
He doesn't know you
and wants to visit.
I'm on vacation next month
and can come with him.
Then I can see Moiss and Isaas.
You know what... I'm dying to
see that bastard again!
-You're experienced, what do I say now?
-How should I know?
-Help me, please.
-You think about it and come back.
The truth is,
I still like him a lot.
Jesus, I miss you so much. It's awful
to wake up without you next to me.
If I had one strand of black hair
left on my head, I'd leave it...
-for you to tear out.
-That's great!
Wait for me, I'm coming back.
Love... What's your name?
Ana.
-Put this in the letter.
-There, it's in the letter.
-Shall I send it or not?
-Send it. How much?
Two bucks...
Minus one for the unsent letter.
How do you know she'll send it? She
hasn't even put it in an envelope.
Don't be rude.
-She's helping me.
-Next!
Give me your hand.
Hey, my top!
Come on, Josu!
-What happened?
-A woman got run over by a bus.
Is she dead?
She's gone to meet her Maker.
Mom!
Thank you, ma'am.
I want to send a letter to my father.
Start writing!
Dad, come to Rio
because mom's been hurt.
-Got any money?
-Yes.
Show me.
-Who do you know in Rio?
-My mother.
-Who else?
-Go on, write the letter like I said!
-Only if you show me your money.
-Then give me my mother's letter.
I've already sent it.
Now go away.
-Give me the letter!
-I said, scram!
Get out of here.
Move it, kid. Scram!
Come on, beat it!
Get out! Beat it!
Hey, kid. Wake up.
Want a sandwich?
-Not hungry?
-I've eaten, thanks.
Special offer! Today only!
All beauty products one buck!
-Combs half-price!
-Everything's good. I have...
so many customers, I can hardly
handle them all. I'm saving up...
to go back to school.
Thief! Nab him!
Mr Pedro!
Go get him!
Don't move!
Don't move! Don't move.
Shut up! Don't move.
Wait...
don't shoot! I'll return it...
-Good evening, Mrs Dora.
-Evening.
Leaving already?
-Hey, son.
-I'm Josu.
Josu, is it? Let me see me your top.
Oh, I see... Your mother told you...
not to talk to strangers.
She's right.
-But you needn't be afraid of me.
-I'm not.
It's all right, Mr. Pedro.
I know the boy.
Then I'd like to talk to you.
Hey, there...
Josu Fontenele de Paiva. Paiva from
my father, Fontenele from my mother.
How admirable! That's very good.
Mine is Isadora Teixera.
Would you like to come home with me,
Josu de Paiva?
-I told you, I'm waiting for my mother.
-She won't be coming.
-You're lying!
-She won't be coming, son. She's dead.
Do you have any relatives
here in Rio?
An aunt?
Answer me.
Look...
Take this.
If you change your mind, you just
follow me. Okay? I mean it.
Come in.
Where's your husband?
I don't have one.
-And your children?
-No children, no husband,
-no family, no dog.
-Then I can use the bathroom?
-Go ahead.
-Where is it?
Over there.
It's hot as hell today!
I'll go freshen up in the bathroom.
I have a guest this evening.
This is Josu.
Was it good?
-See what a demanding guest he is?
-His mother's cooking was better.
No, she was a lousy cook, too.
Hey, you should be a little
more grateful... you brat.
-Irene, what kind of work do you do?
-Guess.
You seem like a teacher, like Dora.
Except that she's a letter writer.
You're right,
we used to be teachers.
-You've no husband either?
-Neither of us.
-So who takes care of you?
-We look after ourselves.
Your mother lived on her own.
Who took care of her?
Me, of course!
And your father
never showed his face?
He works too much.
He's a carpenter.
He works with wood. He makes
tables, chairs, doors, tops...
-houses... all by himself.
-Wasn't his father a...
-Well, what do you want to do?
-I'm going to be a truck driver.
Our fathers used to drive big trains.
Yeah, and they were drunkards, too.
It sucked.
You okay, Josu?
What are you doing?
You sneaky rat!
Can you read? You think
I won't mail your mother's letter?
Well, you're wrong, kid.
It's been so hectic...
-I haven't had the time yet.
-Give it, I'll take it to my father.
Are you crazy? Do you know where he
lives? Far away, on another planet!
-I'll get there!
-You'll never get there. Never.
I think the best thing is if I mail it
tomorrow. I promise I will.
Do you swear you promise?
-I swear I promise.
-You're not going to lie again?
No.
-Where are we going?
-You're going to a great place.
-Hello, Mr Pedro.
-Hello, Mrs Dora. Hi there, son.
We're late.
Hello, Pedro. Please come in.
-Yolanda, this is Mrs Dora.
-Nice to meet you.
Now, I'm not sure what he's told you,
but as you can see...
we treat our children
as if we were one big family.
They'll all be going to wealthy
families in Europe, the States...
Once you're loaded with dollars,
you won't forget us, right?
Let aunty see your tongue now.
-Go on.
-It's okay to be rude.
-That's it, great!
-I'd like more information.
We'll talk about it.
What's your name again?
Tell me, Josu...
Are you into video games?
And would you like an ice cream?
-No, thanks.
-Then let's go play with Shirlene.
This is for you.
Pedro told you how much...
$2000.
-$1 000 for you.
-$1 000.
It's all there.
Bye, Josu.
Oh, my goodness!
Blessed Virgin, mother of God!
We made it to the remote control age!
-Is it in stereo?
-But this stupid thing doesn't work.
Maybe the batteries are dead.
How'd it go with Josu
at the Juvenile Division?
Very well. He'll be in one
of the best children's institutions.
-I talked to the judge.
-Which institution?
The Padre Jesuino Vidal Foundation in
Pelotas, state of Rio Grande do Sul.
But I thought he'd be nearby
so we could see him.
It'll give you a chance to
visit Pelotas, you love to travel.
-This thing doesn't work.
-No, Dora. Like this.
Can I go see him
in the Juvenile Division?
No, I think he must've already
left for Pelotas.
Where did you get the money
to buy that TV?
-I sold a gold ring a while back.
-You're lying...
Otherwise,
you wouldn't bother to explain.
Right, I'm lying! You know everything
about my life! Now let's watch TV.
Where did you get the money?
Tell me the truth. Please...
A friend at the station knows people
who find families to adopt children.
-I can't believe you did that!
-He'll be better off.
Better than in an institution here.
Don't you read the papers? They aren't
adopted. Their organs are sold.
It's not that at all, I went there!
He's too old to be adopted, Dora.
Damn it, Irene! I've had enough of
you! Let's just leave it, all right?
There's a limit to everything, Dora.
-Hi.
-Hi...
-I was here yesterday.
-Yes...
It occurred to me afterwards that you
might be interested in other children.
We don't need any more right now.
They're lovely children,
have a look. Look at this one...
Yolanda! Who is it?
Hold on,
I'll have a word with my partner.
Let me sleep, damn it...
But look how many...
This one's so cute.
She's on to something.
What kind of work is this?
We're not a 24-hour pharmacy here!
-I never said we were...
- Yesterday I went to bed at dawn.
-After you got me into that big mess.
- You're always complaining.
You're a born complainer. If you're
not happy, you can get out!
-Quick! Josu, wake up! Hurry!
-What are you doing here? Go away!
-Let's go.
-No!
-Come with me.
-Liar! Go away.
-Come on.
-No, you're no good!
-Hush!
-I'll call Yolanda.
You'll call no one
What's going on? The bitch!
You old cow, I'll get you!
-You'll die, you fucking bitch!
-Old bag! Sleaze!
I'll get you! I'm going to kill you!
You goddam bitch! You're already dead!
Esperanto Street, in Cascadura.
I'm sorry, I've changed my mind.
Hello?
-Who is this?
-Guess.
-I'm glad you called.
-Irene, listen carefully.
If a big guy with a mustache
comes around asking for me, you scram!
And don't you invite him
in for coffee, okay?
-Well, actually...
-I don 't believe it.
Yes...
He's there?
If he is, say something crazy.
Milton, I can't see you, I've made
plans to go dancing with a friend.
Say no more.
Where are you, Milton?
At the barracks?
I'm at the bus station.
And I'm in deep shit!
Is that cute little friend of yours
on duty with you?
Josu's with me.
I've taken him away.
I always knew
you were a good soldier.
Irene, do me a favor. Lock up my
apartment. Got that? Lock it up.
And watch out for yourself.
-One last favor.
-What is it?
Could you lend me 200 bucks? Send to
Bank of Brazil in Bom Jesus do Norte.
Here's your ticket.
We'll be off soon.
Take it, kid.
I'm trying to help.
-I'll go by myself.
-I'm going with you.
-I don't want you along.
-Why not?
-Because I don't like you.
Like I said, you're no good.
How will you get there, then?
Give me some money for food.
When I get there,
my dad'll pay you back.
-Stupid idiot...
-Give me my mother's letter.
What's the shirt for?
Getting married?
It's for when I meet my father.
What are you looking at? Go back
to the bus, I've something to buy.
-Is it far still?
-What?
-My father's house.
-Watch for the road signs...
they'll tell you.
-How do they measure a kilometer?
-A kilometer is a kilometer.
-1 000 meters.
-I know. But how can they be sure?
-How do they count them?
-They make it up.
Do you think that man is a father?
-What?
-That man there.
Do you think that man there
has children?
He doesn't look like a father.
But this one does.
I know the type.
Just like my father.
A saint in the house
and a real prick outside.
Someone once said:
"Are you Dildo's daughter?"
That was what they called him:
"Dildo".
Prick! Prick!
I don't like riding the bus,
I prefer taxis.
You shouldn't. You should always
take the bus, not a taxi.
The bus has a defined route
with definite stops,
while a taxi can take
any route and then gets lost.
Why?
That was in a letter my dad wrote to
my mom saying he was tired...
of riding the same bus everyday,
meaning my mother,
and he'd decided to take a taxi,
meaning another woman.
But my mother took a taxi, too,
a space taxi...
She died when I was your age.
-Get back to your seat.
-I'm Josu Fontenele de Paiva. Paiva...
-from father, Fontenele from mother.
-Look at that, folks!
The kid's fucking drunk!
-Prick!
-You drunkard!
The old bag's drunk!
Fucking hell! If I were your mother,
I'd let you have it!
-You're not, you're not related to me!
-You'll end up a drunk like your father.
Just like you!
Why'd you come with me anyway?
I wanted to help.
Hear that?
I wanted to help you!
Benemerncia!
Ten minutes.
Excuse me, please. I'm with my nephew
who's meeting his father...
in Bom Jesus do Norte.
This is as far as I go, however.
Could you make sure
the boy gets to this address?
I don't know, it's complicated.
What if something happens to him?
Wait a minute...
This is for you.
Go on. Please take it.
-A ticket for Rio.
-Sixty bucks.
You should have
stayed on that bus.
You were right,
you're better off without me.
I'd arranged everything for you.
Why don't you want to
leave me now?
If you want to talk,
I'll be over here.
Where's your backpack?
Where is it, kid?
Don't tell me
you left it on the bus!
I've decided not to go to Rio.
Can I get a refund for my ticket?
I can't refund
your money now, ma'am.
The bus to Rio just left.
-Want some?
-No, thanks.
Yes... Thank you.
Here, help me out.
I can't eat all of this.
You don't look well.
It's my heart,
it's suddenly sped up.
With your little finger,
press in time to your heartbeat.
Like this?
STRENGTH IS lN EVERYTHlNG,
BUT ONLY GOD IS POWER
Going to Bom Jesus
to fulfil a vow regarding the boy?
Yeah, talk about a vow!
Where do you live?
Here.
And your wife?
Here we go again!
Why do you always ask that?
I'm married to the road.
I have no family.
So you're like her.
Please excuse me, I've got to unload.
I'll be about 20 minutes.
Give the man a hand, Josu.
Nice to see you, Mr Ben! Long time
no see! How long has it been now?
I'll get the other one.
You can stay here.
The boys and girls of today
are being converted at young age.
It's wonderful. They're a generation
raised in the values of Christ.
I always see them in church now
wherever I go things have changed.
They'll be living
in a different world,
more in keeping with God's will.
There's a Reverend...
who's been inspiring them.
-What've you got?
-Let's go eat in the truck.
For Christ's sake, kid...
Put it in my bag! Right now!
-I'll take it back.
-Why?
Go on. If your father knew,
he'd thrash you! Want to go to jail?
Put that in here and
go wait for me in the truck!
I'll try my best to bring
that Reverend here in two weeks.
We'll see what he can do
for the youngsters in our parish.
Ma'am! May I see
what's in your bag?
You heard me,
let me see what's in your bag.
-She's a friend, Mr Ben.
-Show the bag. The matter's settled.
Ben, even though we're friends
and we're brothers in faith...
I won't let you humiliate
a woman I know, my friend... Joana.
Okay, it's all right.
I must've been mistaken.
-Thank you.
-Don't you want to get anything?
There's nothing worth
buying here.
Don't you ever do that again.
All you had to do was ask. Look what
I got with the money I had left.
I even had enough to buy this.
You didn't have any money left.
I did, too.
Here, eat this.
-Liar!
-What?
You didn't buy anything,
you stole even more.
-Show some respect, I'd be your mother.
-My mother wouldn't steal...
-or drink like you.
-Yeah, your father's the one who drank.
No! He built the house and
he can make anything out of wood.
Your father was a drunkard, boy.
Know what that is, a drunkard?
You're a liar and so ugly
no one will marry you!
You look like a man, don't even paint
your face. You're not like Irene.
Even with tons of paint
on her face, she didn't marry.
-You should always steal sausage.
-I hate sausage.
-Would you like some?
-No, thanks.
I'm sorry about what happened
back in the store, Mrs...
Dora. But I liked "Joana".
Have some.
Mr Ben is a good guy,
but he tends to be suspicious.
WITH GOD I FOLLOW MY DESTINY
The boy wants to be a trucker
when he grows up.
Then you'll have to carry
a lot of flour...
To buy a truck like this,
you think it's cheap?
This is a small one, I want
a huge one with a turbo engine.
Could you let the kid
get behind the wheel?
Sit over here. Careful now,
don't hit the accelerator.
It can get cold here in the Serto.
Coming!
-Where are you from?
-I'm from Vitria da Conquista.
But I left there a long time ago.
Since I've been on the road,
I feel like I've changed my life
ten times over.
You meet many people and then you
never see them again. You two...
for example. We'll probably
never see each other again.
We don't have to lose contact.
I'm cold!
I'm coming!
Excuse me...
In Rio, I had two girlfriends.
Did you know that in Rio
all women have sex before marriage?
All of them.
-What'll you have?
-We're just keeping him company.
Not at all. I insist on treating you.
Make that three portions.
-And I'll have water... What about you?
-A beer.
And your son?
A Coke.
-What do you do, Dora?
-I was an elementary school teacher.
No, she's a letter writer. She makes
money writing letters for people.
After I retired,
I started doing that
to help make ends meet.
Don't you like table football?
Go and play.
Go play, kid!
No, I can't have any.
I'm an Evangelist.
I'm sure He's not watching you
up there.
I want to tell you something.
I'm really glad I missed that bus.
Really glad.
Listen, I'll be back
in just a second.
-Could I borrow your lipstick?
-It's almost finished, keep it.
Thank you.
Why did Csar leave?
Don't you have an answer
to that, like you usually do?
He got scared. He's one
of those queer men, isn't he?
No... He isn't.
Can I tell you something?
You look a lot prettier
with lipstick on.
-Good afternoon.
-Afternoon.
-You wouldn't be going to Bom Jesus?
-I am, but it's far, it'll cost you...
ten bucks per person.
My mother taught me that.
Want some?
-No, thank you.
-Yes, thanks.
Sure, you're a growing boy.
How many under the belt?
-I'm nine.
-At that age, I could've ate a cow.
-Have some, it's good.
-No, got too many under the belt!
Too bad...
Mom always said dad would show me
the Serto one day.
I wonder where she is now?
Do you think
they gave her a decent funeral?
Come on, come with me.
Put your mother's
handkerchief there.
-Are we going to my father's house?
-Yes. Are you happy?
What's the matter?
Don't tell me
you've changed your mind now.
I don't want him to see me
all dirty, like a beggar.
Your father will like you, Josu.
Don't worry.
The problem is...
-will you like him?
-I do like him.
Listen... Your father's not
the person you think he is.
You don't know him,
he built our house...
I know! I know all that by heart.
You'll soon be with your father...
If you like, I can ask if you can
stay with us for a few days.
Do you know where this is?
Go on, Josu.
Ma! There's a boy here.
-Anybody there?
-Yes?
-Does Jesus live here?
-Yes. Would you like to see him?
-Yes, is he home?
-He's gone out. You can wait. Come in.
-Thank you.
-Afternoon.
She's here to see your husband.
-Did you offer her coffee?
-No, thanks.
Could I know
why you want to see my husband?
I'm sorry...
I can only tell him.
Your friends have been waiting...
to see you.
I've come from Rio.
I must talk to you in private.
Okay. Maria, mother,
please excuse us.
Go on, boy! Get out!
-Tell me.
-I've brought this boy to you.
His mother died.
He's got no one else but you now.
-What's your relation to him?
-We're not related.
Why did you bring him here, then?
Let's just say
we're friends.
Is he a good boy?
Yes...
He's a good boy.
This letter is for you.
That's not me. I'm Jess.
The letter's for Jesus...
who used to live here.
Wait a second.
Here, this is his new address
in the new settlements.
He won a house in a lottery
and so he sold this one. But...
Let me tell you...
He drank it away, house and all.
-Dora! Everything okay?
-Did you send the money like I asked?
Yes, the money's already there
in Bom Jesus da Lapa.
Bom Jesus where?
Isn't it "da Lapa"?
I found no truck to get away
from this godawful pilgrimage.
-Where are we going?
-To hitch a ride on the road.
-We're walking?
-Yeah, walking!
Hell! What did I ever do to God to
deserve this? You're my punishment.
-I'm hungry.
-You think you're the only one?
We've no money, no food,
nothing left!
-Understand? Nothing!
-What's us going to do?
I don't know. I don't know. Your
parents should never have had you.
Now it's me who has to put up with
you. You're a curse, you're a curse!
Oh, hell!
Where are you going!
Come back!
Come back here!
Thank you!
Thank you, Jesus.
Here I am, Lord. I beg of you,
I'm praying with...
all my heart,
with all my soul, Jesus.
I'm a Franciscan from the bottom
of my heart. Oh, Jesus...
-Bless my people! Bless my pilgrims.
-I'm a sinner, Jesus!
For the blood of Christ! Look at the hardships...
I must bear! I suffer
in my flesh, my bone...
my blood, in my body,
like our Lord, Jesus Christ!
Protect me, mother! Bless me, mother
for the blood of the Holy Ghost.
Burn, Lord! Burn...
Flood the darkness with light, Lord!
Let us keep away evil...
and let the light come through!
Josu!
This commerce, this madman's fair, is
the fair of the devil and the...
merchants of the temple, this is the
carnival of Satan! He's down below...
jumping for joy! The evil beast
roars with laughter at...
the sight of such shamelessness!
For a few coins,
I'll tell your fortune.
-I've no more money.
-You pay me what I deserve.
-You pay if I deserve it. What a pest!
Where are you going, Josu?
Sir, how much is a photo
with the saint?
It's three bucks.
That much?
-That's the price...
-Does it include message to the saint?
No, only the photo of you
and the saint.
Don't want it?
Josu, what are you doing
at this stall?
Miss! She's a writer.
She'll send the saint a message.
Can you?
Only one buck.
Letters! Send a letter home,
a message to a saint!
Letters! Only one buck!
How much to send a message?
-One buck.
-One buck?
Two, if you want us to post it.
-Holy shit!
-lf it's okay, wait in line.
Is that right? Shall I start?
Criseldinha,
I've come here from Itabaiana.
I walked all the way,
along the road.
I'm fulfilling the vow I made
to come here...
if Bencio agreed to marry me.
Thank you, Jesus,
for answering my prayers.
My husband has stopped drinking.
Leontina Emerentina,
I am now the happiest man
in the world.
-How long has he been away?
-Four years.
-You've had no news at all?
-No.
Love to mother,
Maria Adalgiza Bezerra.
Josefa Maria da Silva
in So Bento do Una.
To my fianc, Joo Pedro da Silva,
in So Paulo.
To our father,
Jos Alves da Silva...
Thank you, baby Jesus, for answering
our prayers. Thank you for bringing...
us rain. I came to Bom Jesus and set
off ten colored rockets in your honor.
Sebastiano. Here you are.
Your letter.
We're rich.
We can even eat.
Let's shake.
I'll shake you up!
Come on, let's go!
I'll get you this dress
as a present.
-For me?
-Yes, for you.
-How much is it?
-Five bucks.
You'll look much nicer
in that dress.
I'm beat.
-No, don't do that.
-Should we tear them up first?
Give them to me.
I'll do something with them later.
Will we look for my dad tomorrow?
Yes, there's a bus that leaves at
lunchtime. Come, you can sleep here.
-Good night, Josu.
-Night, Dora.
-Do you always go to bed like that?
-You don't expect me to sleep naked?
-Sleeping naked is much nicer.
-Well, take off your clothes if...
you like. I don't mind.
What? Are you embarrassed?
I bet you've never seen
a woman naked.
-I've seen loads.
-Sure, your mother.
Not true! I've seen other women.
-You might've seen, but only that.
-I had sex with them.
-Oh, you did? How did you do it?
-It's not something to...
-discuss with women.
-So I've got a real man...
in my bed!
How long will it take to get there?
How long?
Stay here, I'll be right back.
Dora! The bus!
It's packed.
Could you tell me where F Street is?
-Hey you! Where's F Street?
-That's the new street...
the paved one.
It's that way.
-They're all the same.
-Yeah, you're right.
-Did your mom have your dad's photo?
-Yes.
-Can you remember his face?
-Sometimes I can remember...
but then it gets blurry.
I forget my father's face, too.
Damn photos shouldn't be there to
remind us. We should be able to forget.
I left home at sixteen, and never saw
my father again... Except for once...
years later, I saw him in the street.
I froze, then found the courage...
to go up to him. "Remember me?" I
said. "Do you recognize me?"
I could see he hadn't recognized me.
He didn't recognize...
his own daughter.
He said:
"How could I have forgotten
such a lovely girl like you?"
I told the rat
I'd made a mistake and left.
I heard he died soon afterwards.
You understand?
-What did I do?
-You'll soon forget me, too.
-I don't want to forget you.
-Even so... you will.
Mr Jesus!
Jesus doesn't live here anymore.
-Do you know where he lives?
-No. Vanished into the wilderness...
no one's heard from him since.
Thank you.
So he'll never come back?
-I don't think so.
-I'll wait for him.
It's no use, Josu.
He's not coming back.
Why don't you come with me?
I'd really like that, kid.
You know that.
I really would.
Let's go.
-The father's vanished.
-What are you going to do?
-I can't leave the boy here on his own.
-Of course not.
You know him,
he's really a good kid.
Are you coming home with him?
-I'm not sure what to do.
-What do you mean?
I've made so many mistakes in Rio,
you know that, Irene.
-So what are you going to do?
-I want you to sell my fridge and...
-my sofa... What else have I got?
-The TV?
Yeah, sell the goddam TV.
What are you going to do?
When I'm settled somewhere,
I'll call you.
Two tickets back to Bom Jesus,
please.
Not till tomorrow morning.
What about to somewhere else?
Nothing till tomorrow.
This is the end of the world here.
-How do I get out of here?
-Tomorrow.
Not till tomorrow.
Okay... Two tickets for
the first bus tomorrow morning.
Are you looking for my father?
-Your father?
-Yes, Jesus. I was told...
-some strangers were looking for him.
-That's right.
-Do you know him?
-I'm a friend of his.
-What a coincidence, meeting his son.
-Not really...
given the size of this place.
Nice to meet you. I'm Isaas.
-Nice to meet you, Isaas.
-Are you visiting?
I was in the area and I remembered
an old friend who lived here.
Then you must come to the house
for a bite.
People don't often come to visit dad.
I insist...
You're not going to refuse me.
And who's this?
-What's your name?
-Geraldo.
Geraldo, Mrs Dora, please.
I insist. Come...
Come here, Geraldo.
Know what a tongue twister is?
"Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers."
Now you say it.
"Peter pecked a pick of paper..."
What a dope!
This is where me and
my brother moved...
after father left. Moiss!
Guests from far away!
Moiss, this is Mrs Dora,
a friend of father's. Imagine!
-Hello...
-Hello.
Mrs Dora, how
long is it to get here?
It depends on the way you come.
Moiss is dying to see Rio. They
say it's nice...
-but full of crooks.
-You find crooks everywhere.
We took this land and are squatting it,
Mrs Dora. All of it. We took this...
house after dad lost the other, and
put in this carpentry workshop.
Moiss grinds away here
all day long.
He's even better than father now.
He can make tables, chairs, everything.
We even sell things to the capital.
Go on, Geraldo.
You can get closer.
Hey, the kid plays pretty well!
No praise,
his head's already big enough!
I play okay,
it's just that they're lousy!
Give it to her...
She can read it for us.
What's she got to do with it?
She's dad's friend. We can trust her.
Show it to her, please.
Then I'll get it.
All right, get that damned letter.
This came six months ago, from dad to
Ana Fontenele. She was the woman...
he was with after mother died.
Nine years ago, Ana Fontenele took
off to Rio. She was expecting...
-our little brother.
-Dad waited two years for her...
to come back. He stopped working
and started drinking all the time.
He sold the house to pay his debts.
One day, I woke up to find dad gone
and a half-empty bottle...
on the table. That worried me. For dad
to leave a bottle half empty...
something serious must have happened.
He vanished, but it was better for us.
We saved money...
Our lives improved.
-Don't say that, Moiss.
-I will say it!
You know father...
He's an okay guy.
Okay?
I'm going to ask her to read it.
Yes, ask her.
It's a letter to Ana, not to us.
Dad never cared about us.
But Ana never came back,
so we can open it.
You don't mind reading it to us,
do you?
Not at all.
So? It says where he is?
Go on, read it.
"Ana,
my misfortune. It was hard to find
a letter writer to tell you...
that I finally understood
that you went back...
and found our new little house,
while I'm here in Rio
Looking for you.
I hope I get back before this letter,
but if it arrives before me,
do as I say:
wait for me.
I'll be coming home, too."
The letter arrived
six months ago.
He's been held up.
"I left Moiss and Isaas
to look after things."
To look after things?
That's a joke!
"Ana, I may work in the mines for
a month before coming home,
but I'll be back. Please wait.
Then we'll all be together:
me, you,
Isaas,
Moiss,
and Josu...
...and Josu,
who I can't wait to meet.
You're a bad-tempered mule,
but I'd give all I have to...
see you again.
Forgive me.
It's you and me, for life.
Jesus."
He'll be back.
No, he won't.
Yes, he will, one day.
Did my father really say
he wanted to meet me?
-Of course he did.
-I know he didn't.
Hey, folks. Come inside. I fixed up
dad's bedroom for you, Mrs Dora.
Thank you.
-Tongue twister, boy.
-Again?
Say five times very quickly:
"How now brown cow." Now say it.
"Say five times very quickly..."
You dope!
Josu, I haven't sent a letter
to anyone for a while,
but I'm sending you this one now.
You were right. Your father will
come back, and he surely is...
all you say he is.
I remember riding with
my father in his train.
I was just a little girl, but he let
me blow the whistle the whole time.
When you're driving down the road
in your big truck,
remember that I was the first person
to have you put your hand on the wheel.
It will be better for you
to stay with your brothers.
You deserve much more
than I can give you.
If you miss me one day,
look at the picture...
we took together.
I'm telling you this because
I'm afraid you too may forget me.
I long for my father.
I long for everything.
Dora.