Good morning, Mr Blake. My name's Amanda.
I've got a couple of questions
here for you today
to establish your eligibility for
Employment Support Allowance.
It won't take up much of your time.
Could I just ask firstly,
can you walk more than 50 metres
unassisted by any other person?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Can you raise either arm as if to
put something in your top pocket?
I've filled this in already
on your 52-page form.
Yeah, I can see that you have
but, unfortunately,
I couldn't make out what you had said there.
Yes.
Can you raise either arm to the top of
your head as if you are putting on a hat?
I've telt you, there's nowt wrong
with me arms and legs.
Could you just answer
the question, please.
Well, you've got me medical records.
Can we just talk about me heart?
D'you think you could
just answer these questions?
Okay.
So was that a yes, that you
can put a hat on your head?
- Yes.
- Okay, that's great.
Can you press a button
such as a telephone keypad?
There's nowt wrong with me fingers either.
I mean, we're getting farther
and farther away from me heart.
If we could just keep
to these questions, thank you.
Do you have any significant difficulty
conveying a simple message to strangers?
Yes. Yes, it's me fucking heart.
I'm trying to tell you but you'll not listen.
Mr Blake, if you continue
to speak to us like that
that's not gonna be very helpful
for your assessment.
If you could just answer
the question, please.
- Yes.
- Okay.
Do you ever experience any loss of control
leading to extensive evacuation of the bowel?
No. But I cannot guarantee
there won't be a first if we divvent
get to the point.
Can you complete a simple
task of setting an alarm clock?
Oh, Jesus. Yes.
Can I ask you a question?
Are you medically qualified?
I'm a health care professional
appointed by the
Department of Work and Pensions
to carry out assessments for
Employment and Support Allowance.
But there was a bloke out in the,
er, in the waiting room,
he says that you work
for an American company.
Our company's been
appointed by the Government.
Are you a nurse? Are you a doctor?
I'm a health care professional.
Listen, I've had a major heart attack.
I nearly fell off the scaffolding.
I wanna get back to work, too.
Now, please, can we talk about me heart?
Forget about me arse, that works a dream.
Piper, you lazy bastard.
Will you get out of bed
and do some housework!
China!
Sorry, Dan, just got a text
to go to work. I'm late.
Did you enjoy your chicken tikka masala?
- How did you know that?
- Cos I can bloody smell it.
How many times have I told you about
leaving rubbish lying about the place,
stinking it up?
- Can I dump it later? I'm running late.
- No. Now!
Dan...
Erm, I've got a big favour to ask
I'm expecting a package. Really important.
They've changed my hours, so I won't be in.
Can you keep an eye out for the postman?
If you swear nae more rubbish.
- Catch!
- Don't you fucking dare.
- I'll kick your arse into next week.
- Okay.
Daft as a bloody brush.
When can I go back to work?
Ah, not yet, that's for certain.
You're making progress.
I think if we just
continue you on the same dosage.
And, yeah, rehab exercise.
We'll see if we can
the pumping capacity to increase.
- Yeah.
- And it might.
But if not, we might need to look
at fitting you with a defibrillator.
Keep up with the exercise, keep moving.
That's gonna build you up.
But you need to be rested as well.
Well, I'm a bit of a night owl, you know.
I got into the habit
when I was looking after the missus
before she passed away.
How you doing, son? How you doing?
- All right.
- How's the old ticker?
Ah, you know, me marathon days are over.
But, you know,
I'll be fine in a month or two.
Ah, well, be leaving that Viagra alone.
I'll keep it for you, shall I?
Aye, I probably need it more than you.
Right, well, owt you want here?
- Have a look
- Oh, that's nice, aye.
Meranti, aye, African Meranti.
It's great, man.
So, er, d'you reckon
you'll get back to Ferguson's?
Depends on the work, I suppose.
I mean, you know what it's like.
It's up and down.
Aye, well.
Gotta see this.
There you go.
Oh, that's a lovely piece.
Aye, I'll have the...
I'll have the lads drop it by for you.
Erm, are you all right?
I'm on the mend.
I mean, I can get your shopping
sorted out for you, you know.
Like, the heavy stuff and that,
like, it's nae bother.
Thanks, Joe.
You know, I like to get out and about.
Gives us something to do.
Well, give us a shout if you need anything.
I mean, I mean that.
You, you gave us a big fright, you know.
BBC Radio Four, it's twelve minutes to 1:00.
Now the shipping forecast,
issued by the Met Office
on behalf of the Maritime
and Coastguard Agency
at double-O-1-5
on Tuesday the 20th of October.
There are warnings of gales
in Trafalgar, Fitzroy...
Please be aware
that this call may incur a charge.
You will be charged at the rate
set by your service provider.
This number is for benefits enquiries only.
If you are calling to make
a new claim for benefits, please redial,
0800-055-6888
to help answer your query as
quickly as possible.
We are sorry, but all our customer service
agents are busy at the moment.
Please hold and we will answer your call.
Oi! What are ye playing at?
I knew it was ye! I knew it was ye
letting your dog shit round here.
I'm walking me dog.
I knew it was you bringing your dog
in here, shitting all over the place.
Oh shut your mouth,
you stupid baldy bastard.
Oi! Ye, if I come down there,
I'll rub your bloody face in it, man!
Take it to your own place
and let it shit round there.
- Go and get a bag and clean that up.
- Aye, I'm gonna get a bag
I tell you what, ye talk shite!
Here, look, you just get a bag!
- Come back here and bloody clean that up.
- Oh, shut up, man, will you!
Hey! I'll come and shite
in your garden, shall I?
Shut up.
Hello?
Thank you for waiting.
Please continue to hold and we will answer
your call as soon as possible.
Morning, mate.
Got a package for Mr Max Million.
- "Mr Max Million"?
- Yeah. Mr Max Million.
My address?
Yeah, definitely this address.
- Where's it from?
- China.
Oh. Give it here.
D'you know how long
I've been on this phone?
One hour, forty-eight minutes.
Jesus Christ, that's longer than
a football match. It'll cost a fortune.
I'm sorry, sir, but it's been very busy.
There must be some mistake.
I've got a serious heart condition.
I'm in rehab and the doctor's
told us I cannae go back to work.
Now, I was getting the benefits
fine until that bloody assessment.
I see you've only
scored twelve points, er,
and you need 15 to obtain benefits.
Oh, points, that's your game?
I'm sorry, sir,
but according to our health, er,
health care professional,
you've been deemed fit for work.
So she knows better than my doctor,
a consultant surgeon and a physio team?
Well, I wanna appeal.
Well, that's fine, but you'll have to first
request a mandatory reconsideration.
What the bloody hell does that mean?
It means the decision
maker will reconsider it
and if he comes to the same
decision, you can then appeal.
Right, well put us down for that, then.
Okay, sir, but you must wait
to get a call from the decision maker.
Why?
To tell you what the decision is.
But that's already been decided.
It is, but you're supposed to get the call,
before the letter.
Well, is he gonna change his mind?
No, the call's just to discuss the decision.
Well, I know what the decision is,
I've got the letter here in front of us.
D'you want us to read it to you?
But he should have called you first.
But he didn't.
But he should have.
Well unless we've got a time machine,
we're pretty much knackered,
divvent you agree?
Er, he has to call you first, sir.
Listen,
can you not just put him on now,
so I don't have to waste any more time?
I can't do that, sir.
Where is he?
He'll give you a call back when he, er,
- he gets the chance.
- When?
I don't know, sir.
This is ridiculous, man.
On the one hand, Jobseeker's Allowance,
only for those able and ready to work.
But if you're ill, you have to apply
for Employment and Support,
get an assessment carried out.
Well, I've done that
but they've knocked us back.
Right, well if you've been
deemed fit for work,
your only option is Jobseeker's Allowance.
Or proceed with the appeal on
Employment and Support.
Well, can you give me a form for...
You know, erm, Jobseeker's Allowance
and then an appeal form
Employment and Support?
You have to apply online, sir.
I cannot do that.
Well that's how it is, sir.
Or you can phone the helpline.
Listen, you know,
you give me a plot of land,
I can build you a house.
But I've never been
anywhere near a computer.
D'you know what, we're digital by default.
Oh, here we gan.
I hear this all the time on the phone,
"I'm digital by default."
Well I'm pencil by default.
Look, I mean, what happens
if you just cannae do it?
There's a special number
if you've been diagnosed as dyslexic.
Right, well can you give us that?
Cos with computers I'm dyslexic.
You'll find it online, sir.
I must ask you to leave now,
if you've got no appointment.
Right, can I help you?
Yeah, I'm here to see about
changing my work coach.
Thomas Armstrong, please.
Hang on a minute, Thomas, hang on.
Erm, would you like to take a seat?
Oh, I just need a minute. I just felt...
I'm just feeling dizzy, you know.
- Come and sit down.
- Oh, cheers, thanks.
Could you move up, please, love?
Thanks, pet, thank you.
- All right. I'll just get you a glass of water.
- Thank you.
Oh, thank you, pet. Thank you.
Are you all right? You look a bit pale.
It's just so bloody confusing,
all the jargon.
I mean, there must be some mistake.
I'm just ganning round and round in circles.
I've, I've really gotta
get this sorted out.
Oh I can understand that,
but you were late.
Thomas. You sit here
and drink your water, pet.
Thank you.
So now you're gonna sanction me so, er...
- No, I'm not gonna sanction you.
- I may not get any money for a month.
I'm gonna refer you to the decision maker
and they'll make the decision
- on whether they're gonna sanction you.
- That's ridiculous...
I'm not actually making the decision,
they're gonna do that.
And then if they do decide
to sanction you,
then you will take a 40%
cut in your benefits.
I know what it is,
I don't need you to explain it to me.
- I'm more than aware...
- Well there isn't anything else
anybody can do today.
So what I'm gonna have to do is,
look, I think I'm...
I've decided to...
Are you gonna put me in for a sanction?
I have to, I have to follow the rules.
And the thing is if you're gonna,
be aggressive with me
- then I'm gonna have to ask you...
- It's not about me being aggressive.
- I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
- I'm trying to explain to you a situation
and you don't care.
- Er, security. Security?
- I don't know why people like you do this job.
I'm referring you to the decision maker.
It's all the same thing.
I don't wanna hear your language
- I, I beg your pardon.
- Listen, I, I'm sorry, love,
- but you're gonna have to leave.
- Yeah, all right, frankly,
take your hands off me.
I'm gonna speak to the manager,
- I don't wanna speak to you.
- The fact is I'm just trying to explain...
- Sorry?
- I'm just explaining...
Well it's not you I wanna speak to...
- You can go back up there.
- Right, come and talk to me then
- if you've got something to say.
- Okay. Sorry.
All right.
I've tried to explain to the woman,
I've never been to Newcastle before.
We've just moved up here from London.
I've been here a few days,
I don't know where I'm going. Okay?
I was on the bus, it's gone the wrong way.
We've run, got off the bus,
run so that I wasn't any more late.
She just don't wanna know and now she's telling
me she's gonna refer me for a sanction.
What I want you to do is listen to me. Okay?
The lady's told you what's right.
There's rules here,
rules that we have to stick to. Okay?
- It isn't against you, but you have a duty.
- Oh, mate, listen,
- I'm not saying it's against me.
- You have a duty to be here on time.
And I'm explaining to you
why I wasn't here on time.
- D'you know what? I understand, right...
- I got lost.
But what I gather now
is the decision maker...
The decision maker's gonna be
sending you a letter through the post.
So you're gonna have to wait for that.
- And then nobody...
- Yeah, I've got... My kids
have gotta start school tomorrow.
I've got about 12 quid in my purse.
- D'you know what?
- All because you can't just calm down
- and listen to people when they talk.
- Right.
- You have to do this.
- Right, d'you know what,
- I've listened to you. You've created a scene.
- With your rules.
- I think you need to...
- I've created a scene?
- You need to leave the building.
- If I was gonna create a scene,
you'd know about it, trust me.
I'm sorry, love,
but you are gonna have to go.
This is ridiculous.
- Jesus Christ!
- What am I supposed to do?
- Who's first in this queue?
- I am.
D'you mind if this young lass signs on first?
- No, no, you carry on.
- There you go.
Now you can go back to your
desk and let her sign on
and do the job that the taxpayer
pays you for.
- This is a bloody disgrace.
- Listen, all right,
this doesn't have to involve you.
Everybody's trying to do their job here
and you're creating more of a scene again.
But, look, you're not listening to her.
She's out of the area.
She's just been a few minutes...
Can you not let her sign on?
She's got two kids with her, man.
- What's wrong with you people?
- Right, listen, this isn't your concern.
I want you to get out as well. All right?
I need you to leave.
We need to do this right. Yeah.
- All right.
- Listen, listen, listen...
- They're just gonna call the police.
- Phone the police.
Can we get some perspective in here?
You need to go or we're gonna
phone the police. All right?
Come on. Thanks very much...
Can we have a bit of perspective,
please, here, man?
- Away, don't be silly.
- Shouldn't even have this job.
- Come on. Please.
- Come on, get out.
- All she needs is help, man.
- Let's get going.
- Just let her sign on.
Let's get going, all right.
Please.
I don't know what's wrong
with you lot, I really don't.
I need you to keep going for me, okay?
- You want me to take one of them bags?
- No, it's all right, I'm fine, pet. I'm fine.
- Where's Dylan?
- I don't know.
Dylan! Come on!
- Honestly. Honestly.
- He's a handful, isn't he?
I can't sit down for five minutes
without him getting in trouble, can I?
Right.
- Good, good choice.
- She loves spaghetti.
Hey, you cannae go wrong
with spaghetti on toast.
Spaghetti, spaghetti on toast, isn't it?
Where's your brother gone?
- Dylan!
Come on.
This, this is what he does.
He runs, he runs off.
- He's a handful, in't he?
- Come on!
Where ye been, on an adventure?
Dylan, not on the fences.
- It's just here.
- Mum, look, she's back, she's back.
She's back.
Tell you what, if it's the last thing I do,
I'm gonna make this place a home.
You don't know how to fix a cistern, do you?
It's driving me insane.
- Yeah, I'll have a look at that.
- Yeah?
I can fix owt, me, pet,
apart from computers.
- Straight up. You show him...
- I'll show him.
Dylan, can you stop it? Get in.
Hello, Mum. How are you doing?
Yeah.
Yeah, all right. All right. Yeah.
It's nice, it's nice.
There's plenty of space.
And, erm, yeah, it looks like they've put...
There's a nice bit of fresh carpet down.
The, the walls are all
nicely painted and that.
No, I know, Mum. Well, look, once...
Once you're feeling better and we're settled,
then you'll have to come up. You can come up
with Auntie May and stay, can't you?
Yeah, they're nice, yeah, friendly.
Friendlier than London.
Yeah.
D'you wanna have a word with Daisy?
All right, hold on. Talk to Nana.
Hello, Nan.
- Hello, Daisy. How are you?
- Good.
- Yeah? D'you like it?
- Yeah.
- Are you happy?
- Yeah, very.
I miss you, too. Bye.
Bye-bye.
Hello, Mum.
All right. That's all right.
All right, I'll speak... Yeah, I've gotta go
but I'll speak, I'll call you tomorrow.
- All right.
- All right, love you.
- Love you, too. Bye.
- Bye, bye, bye.
So what are you doing up here, Katie?
It started when we got
kicked out of the flat.
We got in a bit of trouble.
It was ridiculous.
In Dylan's room there was a leak
coming through the wall,
coming through the top of the ceiling
down the wall.
And it was making him really sick.
Weren't it, Dais?
- Remember when Dylan weren't well?
- Yeah.
We had to run all the way to the hospital.
Yeah, he was in and out the hospital.
I was talking to the landlord about it,
spoke to him.
And cos I complained, kicked us out.
What, they can just do that?
- Just throw you out?
- Yeah, yeah.
So we got out of there.
We was in a homeless hostel
for about two years, waiting on a flat.
Yeah. But it was close to their school
which they loved, so...
We just had to stick it out.
But we was in one room,
the three of us were in one room.
Like eating, sleeping, all the rest of it
and Dylan was just climbing the walls.
Honestly,
like boxed in like that, so, yeah.
They eventually offered me a flat,
so the good news was it was a flat.
Bad news was it was up here.
And they couldn't give you
anywhere near your family?
No, not in London.
They're, they're moving out the likes of me.
It's just too expensive for 'em.
So how's the kids taking it?
They're brokenhearted about leaving school.
Especially Daisy. She's furious with me.
Having to leave her friends and her nan.
I mean there was nothing I could do about it.
I couldn't have Dylan boxed in like that.
- Ah, she'll make friends soon enough.
- That's what I've told her.
And I've got a plan.
We got a little garden now and they've
each got a room of their own.
I'm gonna get a part-time job
and then I'm gonna go back to me books.
- Oh, you at college?
- Open University.
Yeah, I mucked up a little bit at school
so it's like a second chance.
But that all fell apart a little bit when
we was at the hostel,
but I'm not gonna give up.
Can't, can I?
Good on you, lass.
It's bloody freezing in here.
Oh, it must be a short.
Right, where's your fuse box?
There's nothing on the metre.
The kids are starting school and
I wanted to get 'em some nice new clothes.
And I thought I was gonna
get me money tomorrow.
Right.
I'll bring me tools round
and I'll sort this place out for you.
- Will ya?
- Yeah, course I will.
Shouldn't take long.
Right, thank you.
"Max Million", to my fucking address?
- China, what's in this box?
- Dan, it's not what you think it is.
Don't jump to conclusions.
Shift that bloody rubbish
and shift your arse.
I wanna see what's in this box.
Oh my God. Wow.
- What d'you think of these?
- Bloody trainers?
- Trainers.
- These are only the best, Dan.
- Very best.
Aren't they, Piper?
Aren't they?
Stop it, man, I've got brittle bones.
Anyways, I've got a test for you, Dan.
- Go on, open it.
- Open that.
What's the difference?
Yeah. What's the difference
between them two?
They look the same.
- Bang on, brother.
- Exactly.
The difference is, they'd have cost me
150 quid on the high street...
And I'm gonna sell those for 80 quid.
Cheap counterfeits to my fucking address?
I could have the Chinese Mafia
or the bloody Customs at me door.
The brass neck of the bloody pair of you.
Dan, these are not counterfeits.
They're from the same factory as these.
Exactly the same quality.
Continuation of the same run.
- D'you not believe us?
- It's fucking genius.
How d'you manage this?
Well I know a guy from Guangzhou, don't I,
who works in the factory.
Yeah, works in the factory.
He's football mad.
He knows everything
about the teams, the players, everything.
So we do the deals by e-mails.
I send him the money by PayPal,
then he sends me the package by post.
Me, you mean.
Honestly, Dan, I did mean to say,
like I get them sent to different mates.
You know, small packages
like not to attract too much attention.
They usually get through.
I'll be able to tell all me mates
I knew both of you
before you were arrested.
See these trainers, Dan,
these are the future.
No more crap jobs.
No more shit from that warehouse.
D'you know what the bastards
did this morning?
Got us in at 5:30.
Unloaded one truck.
Guess how long that took?
Forty-five minutes.
And you know how much I got paid?
Three pound and seventy-nine pence.
Waste of my fucking time.
It's worse than China.
I'm gonna make it big
one day, Dan. I'm serious.
Hi there, can I help you?
You look a bit lost.
Aye. I have to apply
for Jobseeker's Allowance...
- Right, yeah. Mmm-hmm.
- And I wanna use one of them
to get on to that Internet web thing.
Right, you could do that today.
We're a bit busy at the moment.
If you can come back a bit later,
would that be okay?
- And then contact Job Centre Plus.
- Mmm-hmm.
And, here we are. "Claim Jobseeker's".
- Okay? So double-click on that one.
- Okay. All right.
And then we need to scroll
right the way down here to continue.
And that's your,
that's your form there for you.
So you need to run the mouse up the screen,
click into there and pop your postcode in.
- Run the mouse up the screen, yeah? Okay.
- Yeah.
- No. No, not quite like that.
- No?
- What you need to do is get your cursor...
- "Your cursor"?
It's a fucking apt name for it.
So when you're moving your mouse,
- you see what I'm doing with my hand?
- Aye, right.
- Look at my hand.
- Aye. Oh, right, it moves like that.
- And then continue.
- Right, okay.
- And then you start from there. Okay?
- Okay.
- I'll leave you with it. Okay?
- Right.
Right.
Excuse me, pet.
You couldn't help us with this, could you?
Yeah. What is it?
I'm just filling this in.
I'm just... I cannot get the...
This keeps darting all over the place.
What do I do? Do I get on to that and...
Do you just...
I mean, how do you get this down?
Right, so you're controlling this,
and you click on this bar.
- Right.
- And then you pull it down.
- Oh, right.
- And then you get...
- What, do I hold that on there, do I? Okay.
- The rest of it. Yeah.
- All right, then I can just...
- On the left side.
What, what, so I hold this
and just pull that down?
- Yeah, and click the left.
- And click...
- Click to the left.
- Yeah. Right.
And I just put that in there?
Oh, that's right, thanks very much.
- It's fine.
- Aye.
You're a star. Right.
Right, have I done it right? There we are...
Oh, bloody hell. What's this now?
"Error"?
Well, what have I...
Here, mate, you divvent know
what I've done here, do you?
- This error thing.
- Yeah, that's a big thing.
Do you? I don't know, I was just
filling in the thing and it just went...
- There we go.
- Oh, oh, yeah, there we go.
We're back on, right.
- You're sorted, yeah?
- Hey, can you just hang on
just for two seconds so I divvent
go back here again. I'll...
Just, just, just, I'll just like do
a couple more questions.
Yeah, I'll just stand over here, don't worry.
Er... "Are you a Br..."
- Yeah.
- "Yes". Right. I do that.
- Right. What?
- Yeah.
- What's...
- Then you should continue.
Should be all right.
Right, okay.
What's...
It's, it's, it's not bloody, it's not...
- Well nowt's happening now.
- Yeah, just give it a second.
Just give it a second.
But it's just not mov... I mean, look,
it's not even, it's not even moving.
- Let me try, right.
- What? Here, get that.
This is driving me mental, this.
I mean, what have I done now?
- It's frozen. Yeah.
- It's frozen?
Well... Well, can you defrost it?
No, mate, I can't.
Think your time's up.
- What?
- Your time's up.
- Me time's up?
- Yeah, I'm sorry, mate.
Oh, sorry, mate, yeah.
- I'll just leave you to it.
- Oh jeez.
- Do you have a partner?
- Er, no. She, er, she's passed away.
- Oh, I'm really sorry to hear that.
- Thank you.
D'you have any dependent children
aged under 20 living with you?
No, I don't.
It's really important we get this filled in
because we need to get the process started.
Yeah.
Excuse me, Ann. Can I have a word, please?
Could you just give me 30 seconds, please?
We're just getting...
Well, actually,
can I have a word now, in my office?
Thank you.
- Right.
- Jesus, I've got you into trouble now.
- I'm really sorry.
- It's me that should be sorry.
You just carry on, you're doing good.
You know, Ann, we've spoke
about this before.
That isn't acceptable.
- I think in this case it's quite reasonable...
- Come on in the office.
The thing is you're setting a precedent.
It's not acceptable.
Oh, bugger. Bugger, it's...
Jesus...
I don't believe this.
No, I only want my share of the football.
Right then, that's the only team you
need to know in the northeast, is Newcastle.
What other teams do you know?
- Er, Middle... Middle-borough.
- Middlesbrough, aye.
- Middlesbrough. Yeah.
- Middlesbrough.
You know, you divvent need to think
about them either. Aye?
There you go.
Er, we only have one Wagon Wheel left,
so I cut it into four.
But you can have two pieces
considering you're the host.
Oh, there you go.
I'll put your tea down there.
- Oh, hang on.
- Barclay's Premier League.
Here's the big question, Stan Li.
Did you say "Stan Li"?
Yeah. Stan Li from Guangzhou.
Are you two winding me up?
No, that's not our style.
Can you hear me, Stan Li?
Favourite player in the Premier?
Charlie Adams, Stoke City.
Get the fuck out of here.
Are, are you taking the piss?
EPL is crazy money, man.
Charlie Adam. Four million.
No ego.
Team player.
Tough guy.
You see his goal against Chelsea
from his own half?
Boom!
The ball flies up, over Courtois' head.
Cross the line, line. Goal!
He's not in China.
He's in the bloody takeaway down the road.
You two, you're taking the piss.
Okay, Stan Li,
I'll e-mail you my best price. Top price.
I'm gonna see how I get on selling
these ones I've got, okay?
So I'll let you know.
Best price, no bullshit.
Remember, Charlie Charlie, all good money.
Okay, no best price, no more trainer.
No more business.
No more talkie-talkie. No more...
# Swing low, sweet chariot
# Coming for to carry me home #
Right, Dan.
Check your National Insurance Number.
Yep, that's okay.
Press that button right there, Bill Gates.
- What, this one here?
- That one there, "Send."
Huh. It's taken me bloody days
to get this sorted out.
Well done, son.
Jobseeker's Application done.
Dan, don't know why you're applying
for that after your heart attack.
Right, now I'm printing your appeal form
for Employment and Support Allowance.
But you can't appeal till they carry out
a mandatory reconsideration.
Is that printing out now?
You mean, they could have
given it to me just like that?
Dan, they'll fuck you around,
I'm warning you.
Make it as miserable as possible.
No accident. That's the plan.
I know dozens who have just given up.
Well they've picked the wrong one
if they think I'm gonna give up.
I'm like a dog with a bone, me, son.
I have a note on the screen, sir,
that you're awaiting a call
from the decision maker.
Jesus, 55 minutes to hear all this again.
Am I in a time warp?
You can't proceed to the appeal
or the mandatory reconsideration
till you have the call
from the decision maker.
Well, can you ask him to phone us
now, because I've got no income.
I've got no pension
and I've still got the bedroom tax.
I'll make a note on my screen, sir.
Well can you not give him the note now?
You know, put it in his hand?
This is a call centre, sir.
Hey, Dylan. D'you want a shot
at the screwdriver?
What kills more people,
coconuts or sharks?
He likes bouncing that ball, doesn't he?
Pardon?
That ball.
He likes bouncing it, doesn't he?
Well, it started in the hostel
where we had only one small room.
Why d'you think he does that?
I think he's missing his friends.
But he also does it when he's angry.
People never listen to him,
so why should he listen to them?
There you go. And we don't need
any glue, nothing like that.
Now you give me a hand
and we'll stick this up.
Right, you go that end and I'll go this end.
And we'll stick this up here.
Yeah? Just pass it up here.
Aye, right. You do the bottom edge.
That's it.
The sun heats up all
the air in these bubbles...
And it'll keep your room nice and warm.
Can you go into my tool bag there,
there's a piece of cloth.
Can you open it?
Eh?
- What do you think of that?
- It's gorgeous.
Well it's a little present for
your new room.
- Now...
- Thank you.
- Where shall we put it?
- Up there, maybe.
Okay, hang on.
I'll get a hook and hang it there.
Yeah, what do you think?
It's great.
It'll look like you're under the sea.
And the sun will shine on them.
I think there will be fine, yeah?
I'll light these candles.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
- Now hang on.
- That one's big.
It is. Now there's four candles. Right?
Mind you don't burn yourself.
I won't burn meself,
don't worry about that.
But thank you for thinking about us, Daisy.
Put that in there like that.
And I put this one in here.
Now there's four candles in there, right.
And they last for four hours.
I'll put this small pot over. Right?
Block the hole off up there.
And then I put this big pot over the top.
Now it takes a little while
but it'll take the chill off the room.
And if you just put your hand
over there now, you'll feel it, Daisy.
If you just put your hand over there,
you'll feel it starting to warm up.
- Huh, can you feel it? Yeah?
- A little bit.
- What about you?
- Yeah, a little bit.
Were you a soldier, Dan?
Was I a soldier?
Oh, more dangerous than that.
I was a carpenter.
Right, grub's ready.
- Yay!
- Go round that way then, Dylan.
Good boy. There's yours, poppet.
Right, put Sweet on there.
Sit down nicely then.
- And, Dan, this one's yours.
- Oh, no, not for me, thanks, no.
That's yours. All right?
Here you are. All right?
- Well, where's yours?
- I had mine earlier.
I'm just gonna have a bit of fruit.
You said that yesterday,
and the day before.
All right, eat up then.
Looks delicious but, you know,
it's a wee... It's a wee bit early for me.
Please, Dan. It's the least I can do.
- Thank you, Katie.
- All right.
What was that sound, Mum?
Oh, babe, one of the tiles just fell off
the wall in the bathroom
where I was cleaning it.
It's the middle of the night.
- I know.
- You should really get to bed.
Okay. I'm gonna go to bed.
I'm gonna go to bed.
I just wanted to
get all the cleaning done in there
so you can have a nice bath tomorrow.
You like a bath, don't ya?
Yeah?
So you're gonna go up
and get into bed and wrap up nicely.
Okay, good girl. Give me a kiss.
Go and get into bed.
- All right? Good girl.
- Promise me you'll get to bed.
I promise you I'm gonna go to bed.
- Good night.
- 'Night, baby.
Daniel Blake?
If you'd like to follow me, Mr Blake.
If you'd like to just take a seat.
This is the Claimant Commitment form.
You must commit yourself to spending
35 hours a week looking for work.
Now that can be newspapers, agencies,
and online via the Universal Job Match.
You just fill in the details.
But you must prove that
you've done this as well, mind.
Well I've been told by my doctor
that I'm not supposed to go back to work yet.
Then you should apply
for Employment and Support Allowance.
I have, but I've been knocked
back by some quack
and now I'm trying to appeal.
Okay. Well that's your choice, Mr Blake.
No, it's not my choice.
I've got no other form of income.
Do you want to sign this or not?
You just need to put your
signature here. I shall date it later on.
Thank you.
Now can I have a look at your CV?
"CV"?
You still don't get this, do you, Mr Blake?
This is an agreement between
you and the State.
No, you still don't get it.
- No, you must...
- I'm desperate to go back to work.
- If you're desperate to get back to work...
- Unless the doctor tells us...
You need to have an up-to-date CV,
in order to help you look for work.
Now, just hold it right there.
There's a CV workshop
that I would like you to attend
and it's this Saturday at 9:00.
No, thanks, I'll sort that out on me own.
No, Mr Blake. This is a formal direction.
You will attend if you want to proceed
with your Jobseeker's Allowance claim.
What happens if I don't?
Then you will be referred for a sanction.
Ten seconds.
Ten short seconds.
That's how much a typical employer
spends flipping through a CV.
Fact.
Sixty applications for every low-skilled job.
For a skilled job, it's twenty to one.
Fact.
Costa Coffee advertised eight jobs.
D'you know how many applications
they got from that?
Over 1,300.
Fact.
So, what does that mean?
We should all be drinking
a lot more bloody coffee.
Yeah, d'you wanna share that with us?
I said, we should all be drinking
a lot more bloody coffee then.
This is serious business
and people have only got
one shot at this, all right?
Well if you can count, it's obvious.
There's not enough jobs. Fact.
Yeah, well, you'll be at
the back of the queue, won't you?
For those of us in the real world,
what that means is...
"You must stand
"out from the crowd."
Get noticed. Get smart.
It's not enough these days just to, er,
just to show you have the skills.
You have to prove
how keen you are. How dedicated.
Okay...
What I'd like you to do now
is to, er, format your CVs.
And, remember, all of these
have to be typed up in a clear font
in hard copy.
And we're also gonna need
a digital version for online.
And some companies,
they're demanding CV videos,
sent in by smartphone.
How about that?
Okay? Let's make a start.
Are you taking any blokes on, mate?
I'm a joiner, you know
I'm just looking for some work, you know.
Not at the minute. Er, all manned up.
Okay, can, can I give you my CV?
And then if you can get in touch...
- Excuse me, mate.
- Yeah.
D'you know if anybody's
taking anybody on round here?
Er, no, we're not taking anyone on.
Er, I'll tell you what you could do.
If you try about three units
up on the left there,
they'll probably...
They, they might be havin' one.
- Okay, thanks.
- Okay? Cheers, mate.
- Your best bet is to see him.
- Is he the boss? Him?
He's, he's the supervisor.
That's the boss there.
Excuse me, mate. D'you know if
they're taking anybody on here?
Have you got any jobs ganning?
No, you haven't?
Hey, mate, I'm looking for some work.
- Is there anything ganning on around here?
- There's nowt here, mate. There's...
There might be something,
erm, a bit further up,
- if you try one of the other estates, but...
- Yeah?
...nothing doing on here.
Help you, mate?
Aye, I was just looking for some work, mate.
I was wondering if you had
anything ganning on?
I might have.
- Aye?
- Done this graft before?
- You got any experience?
- Oh, I've got 40 years of experience, mate.
I can turn me hand to owt.
Can I give you me CV?
Way-ay, course, I'll have a look at it.
There you go.
Cheers.
- Daniel?
- Aye, that's me.
I'm Harry, by the way.
Well, you've got plenty
of experience, like, I've gotta be honest,
I'm absolutely sick of young'uns.
Half the time they divvent turn up.
When they do, they cannot be arsed.
Dylan, Dylan, come off the road, come on.
Come on.
Dylan, come on. Catch up. Come on.
- Is this the, er, queue for the food bank?
- It is, aye.
D'you know how long we'll be waiting?
Oh, a canny long time, I reckon.
We've been here ages already.
Okay, thanks. Cheers.
- Hello.
How nice to see you.
Have you brought your little dog today?
Thank you very much, thank you.
Is it just food for yourself
and the two children, Katie? Thank you.
Would your children have
a drink of juice and a biscuit?
Would you like to go and see Agnes?
Agnes?
Could you do a juice and a biscuit, please?
- Jackie?
- Yeah.
Would you be able to
help Katie with her shopping today, please?
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Hiya, Katie. Thank you.
So, we've got one adult and two
children, yeah? Come with me.
- We'll start with the vegetables, yeah?
- Okay.
Right.
I'll give you one side
and we'll share it, yeah?
- Couple of onions.
- Is there anything we can do for you, hun?
- No, I'm fine, thanks.
- Are you sure?
- Aye, all right then.
- Toiletries, yeah?
Okay...
Have you just moved up here?
Your accent's not from here.
- You're not a Geordie girl.
- Yeah. Yeah, been up a little while.
Just come up from London.
Right. Nice accent.
Can you understand the Geordies?
Almost.
Right, over here.
I think we need another bag.
Have we got one?
Did you bus here?
- No? Well, sometimes.
- Well, sometimes.
She likes tea sometimes.
- Well, I'll just keep going in with stuff.
- Yeah.
And then you tell me
what you don't need, yeah?
Have you got any sanitary towels?
- We don't have sanitary towels, no.
- No? All right, not to worry. It's all right.
- Don't really donate things much like that.
- Yeah.
It's a shame, they should.
Right, right, if you open your bag. Rice?
- And a couple of toilet rolls?
- Mmm-hmm.
Yeah?
We'll go to the food.
It's falling out me bag.
- You can put...
- I've got this one. Right.
Erm, tins in yours. Put them in there.
Can you see anything else you want?
- There you go.
- Okay, thank you.
- Erm, there's pasta sauce over here.
- Mmm-hmm.
I'll get you some pasta sauce?
The pasta sauce...
And there's, er, pasta here as well.
I'll get you a pasta.
Hey, pet, are you all right?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Come and sit down. It's all right.
It's all right, it's all right.
Come and sit down.
Come and sit down, it's all right.
Oh...
Okay, it's all right.
It's all right, it's all right.
It's all right. D'you want a drink?
- D'you want a drink?
- I'm really sorry...
- What's the matter?
- It's okay, don't worry.
- I'll get you a drink.
- Mum, what's going on?
It's okay. It's okay
I'm just really hungry.
- Okay, don't look at me.
- No, no, no, it's okay, it's okay.
There's no harm done.
I can't cope, Dan.
I feel like I'm going under.
Look, you'll get through this, darling.
- Thank you.
- You'll get through this.
Katie, listen to me.
This isn't your fault.
You've done amazing.
Dumped up here, on your own with two kids.
You've done nothing to be ashamed of.
Come on, you're okay.
Come on, wipe yourself.
Come on... You're okay.
- If my mum could see me...
- It's okay.
Look, these people are here to help you.
You know, you've done nothing
to be ashamed of.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, no, you're all right.
- Can I get you anything else?
- I just felt really faint.
D'you need some paper
tissues or baby wipes?
- I'll get you some baby wipes.
- Thank you.
I felt really faint.
Katie, can I get you something to eat?
Would you like some soup or something?
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
If you could get her some water.
Sure, yeah, anything. Yeah.
You not want some food?
- Yeah, please, get...
- Even something sugary.
I'll get you a doughnut or something.
Yeah, yeah?
There's no middlemen.
Straight from the factory.
Same quality as the shop.
- Same quality, exactly.
- Well, you're gonna have to do us a deal.
I couldn't pay 80 quid for this, though.
If you go to the shop, they're 150 pounds.
- A hundred and fifty quid?
- I'm selling these for 80 pounds.
- Only 80 quid.
- See, they've still got the stickers on.
Why are they 80?
The reason they're 80 is because
there's no middlemen, nothing.
- No middlemen, whatsoever.
- You and Piper, the top new businessmen.
That's my driver, Dan.
I'll give you a bloody driver.
So no-one's worn them before?
No-one's wore them. Nothing, look.
Check the quality yourself.
I'd probably wear them for the gym.
I couldn't say 80 quid, mate.
This is too expensive for 80 quid.
- They're 150 pound in the shop.
- A hundred and fifty pound, yeah.
- Oh, Dan. You all right, mate?
- Hello, Joe.
- Aye, I'm all right, mate, aye.
- How are you doing?
Erm, listen, we're ganning, erm...
We're away down the pub the night.
There's a load of us ganning.
There's a band on, you know.
We're gonna sink a few pints.
D'you fancy, fancy coming down?
Aye, I'd murder a pint, mate, but I daresn't.
I've been telt to lay off the sauce, you know.
- Oh, really?
- But, listen, tell the lads I'll come down
and pop into the sawmill, eh?
Oh, aye, aye, aye.
You know, if you fancy it anyway,
we're all going down.
So we might see you later, mate.
- Nice to see you, man.
- See you then. Ta-ta, see you.
Message for Daniel Blake.
Mr Blake, this is a call
from the DWP decision maker.
You should soon receive a letter
which states that you have been
deemed fit for work
and not entitled to Employment
and Support Allowance.
If you need any further information,
it's available online. Thank you.
Fuck's sake.
- Hello?
- Hi, is that Daniel?
Yes, it is. Hi.
Hi, Daniel, it's Harry Edwards here.
We spoke the other day
at the garden centre...
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- ...when you came down and handed your CV.
- How are you doing, mate? Are you all right?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm fine, thanks, yeah.
Er, listen. I tell you what, mate,
I've been going through all the CVs
I've had handed over
the last couple of weeks.
And I really like the look of yours.
Erm, you've got the experience
I'm looking for.
I was wondering if you could possibly, er,
pop by tomorrow and that for an interview?
Oh... I'm really sorry, er, Mr Edwards,
but, you know, er, my doctor's told
us I cannae come back to work yet.
So you're not actually
looking for work, then?
Well, it's hard to explain, you know.
So, well, what's the point
of handing in your CV
if you're not looking for work?
Well it's the only way
I can get me benefits, you know?
"Benefits"? So you prefer to be on
benefits than do a day's graft?
You know, I thought you were
a genuine bloke.
You know, I've spent a lot of time
going through them all.
I've... I was gonna put some graft your way.
You've just wasted my time completely.
Why don't you just sod right off!
Listen, that's not...
- That's your change and your receipt.
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much. Have a good day.
- Bye.
- Thank you, bye.
Excuse me, madam.
I think you've been shoplifting.
Would you like to come with me to
the manager's office and we can sort it out?
I haven't been shoplifting.
Okay, you have, and I've seen you.
So if you'd like to come with me...
No, I've got a receipt. I've got, I've just,
- the lady there's just served me.
- Okay, and if everything on your receipt
is all you've got on you,
then there's no problem.
If you'd just like to come this way
to the manager's office.
No, I'm not going to the manager's office.
You just stood there and watched
her serve me, I've got a receipt.
I can lock the door and call the police.
You're talking about locking the
door and calling the police.
Would you like to come with me
to the manager's office?
No, because I've just, you've
just watched me...
Okay, and we'll sort that out.
Okay, and if everything
on the receipt's in your bags,
- then there's no problem.
- You don't need to shout at me.
Okay, if you'd like to come this way.
She's just, you've just stood
there and watched it...
- Okay, then we'll sort it out.
- ...and serve me with, didn't you?
And she's given me a receipt.
Just this way.
Ivan, I'll take it from here.
What's your name, love?
- Katie.
- Katie?
- Katie Morgan.
I'm really sorry.
I haven't done anything like this before.
I've paid for these.
What are you gonna do?
Katie.
It's between me and you...
It's got nowt to do with the store.
All right?
They're paid for.
Get yoursel' away.
Thank you.
Hey, hang on a second. Hey, hang on...
I'm sorry about that, I am.
Can I get a quiet word?
Look, if you're in trouble and you
need money, I can help, okay?
Look, a nice girl like you,
I can definitely help.
That's my number. My name's Ivan, okay?
Ring me any time, all right?
Okay?
Come and have a look at this.
That is a miracle.
He's been sat there for about 15 minutes.
What's this, Dan?
It's a cassette.
What's a cassette?
Plays music. Come here, I'll show you.
All right.
You pop that in there.
Oh, no, you gotta take it out the case first.
It'll not play like that.
Right, you put that in there like that. Yeah?
And press that button there.
Bit more. Harder.
That's it.
It was Molly's.
She recorded it off the radio.
Shipping forecast.
It's on late at night.
Sailing By. D'you like that tune?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, Molly loved it.
It's nice, isn't it?
So how'd the interview go?
Oh, nothing's working out
with the school times at the minute.
So I went to, erm, some of the agencies
and put my name down on the waiting list,
cos I could do cleaning in the morning.
Went to some hotels.
Went round all the cafes.
Must have walked for bloody miles.
Well, I can pick the kids
up for you, you know.
Till I start work again.
Dan. The answer is "coconuts".
Correct.
What's he talking about, "coconuts"?
Ah, shall we tell your mum?
- Go on.
- When I was bouncing my ball on the stairs.
- What stairs?
- The stairs in our house.
- Yeah.
- Dan asked me a question.
What, what question did he ask ya?
"What kills people more?
- "Coconuts or sharks?"
- Mmm-hmm.
And I said coconuts.
And you got it right?
- Is that right?
- Yeah, he's right.
Is that Molly?
Yeah. Yeah, that's Molly, yeah.
Let's see that, Dais.
Show me that one.
"Molly." Like the name.
What was she like?
She was special.
Yeah, she was special, Daisy.
Not easy.
She was up one minute, down the next.
Smart and funny. Huh.
Ah, that lass made me laugh.
Kind.
She had a big, big heart.
But...
She said her head was like the ocean.
Dead still, then wild.
Never knew where she'd end up next.
I mean, the music helped that.
But then she'd hit the rocks.
"Where'll we sail to tonight, Dan?"
That was our little joke.
Her last words to me were,
"I wanna sail away, Dan,
with the wind at me back.
"That's all I need, Dan."
Do you have any children?
I'd have loved that, Daisy. No.
- Do you miss her?
- Dais.
It's okay.
She was crazy.
Hard work.
But I loved her to bits.
I'm lost without her, really.
- There you go, pet.
- Oh, thank you.
That must have been hard for you, Dan.
I mean, did you look after her
right till the end?
Well, you know, I thought it'd be
a relief when she passed away.
Cos it was difficult to go into work,
you know, when she was ill.
And after you've been looking after
somebody for so long...
It seems to take over your life, you know.
- Yeah, and you forget your own.
- Huh.
Well she was lucky to have you.
Daisy's dad, I thought was
something really special.
He turned out not to be.
Me mum tried to warn me about it,
but I was 18, so I didn't listen.
And then I did the same
thing with Dylan's dad.
You're a young lass,
you got your whole life ahead of you.
And when you get back
to those books, you'll be flying.
Yeah, I can't look at 'em, Dan.
They really upset me.
- You gotta keep a hold, you know.
- Mmm-hmm.
You're doing your kids proud.
I mean, we all need the wind
at our back every now and then.
- Don't we?
- Mmm. Yeah.
Well that's not good enough, Mr Blake.
And how do I know you've actually
been in contact with all these employers?
Well, I walked round the town.
I gave out me CV by hand.
Well, prove it.
- How?
- Well, did you get a receipt?
Take a picture with your mobile?
With this?
I give you my word that's what I did.
That's not good enough, Mr Blake.
What about the Universal Job Match online?
I went to the library,
there's my appointment card.
Did my head in. And I tried my best.
It's not good enough.
Can I look at your CV?
All right.
Did you not learn anything
at the CV workshop?
You'd be surprised.
Not good enough, Sheila?
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to refer you
to a decision maker for a possible
sanction for four weeks.
Your payment will be frozen.
You may be entitled
to Hardship Allowance if you apply.
Do you understand?
And if you are sanctioned, you must
continue to look for work and sign on.
If you don't, you may be sanctioned again.
And it's likely to be for thirteen weeks
on the second occasion, and thereafter.
And likely to be the maximum
of up to three years.
Would you like me to write
you a referral to a food bank?
Dan, you're not leaving, are you?
Aye, I'm off to the Bahamas.
Nah, I'm just sick of the old stuff.
I need a change.
Are you okay, Dan?
I'm fine, son.
You don't look okay.
No, really, I'm fine.
You haven't given us a row
about leaving the rubbish out.
I'm okay, China, really.
If you need anything, Dan, let me know.
Absolutely anything.
I mean it, Dan, anything.
I know, son.
Twenty, forty, sixty, eighty, a hundred.
Twenty, forty, sixty, eighty, two hundred.
All right?
Aye, fair enough.
Anything else I can help you with?
No, that's it.
What about these?
Good quality hand tools.
Nae chance. I'll be ganning back
to work soon enough.
Well, the offer's there.
Now these look nice. How much d'you want?
They're not for sale, mate.
Give us a ring if you change
your mind. See you now.
What are you doing?
Oh, you're freezing.
What's wrong?
Well, erm, the girls at school
are making fun of me.
They're what?
The girls at school are making fun of me.
Why are they making fun of you?
My shoes fell apart.
Oh, did they?
But we glued them back together.
- Mmm.
- They fell apart again?
All right, we can get you
a new pair of shoes.
We don't have the money.
Don't you worry about that,
we can get you a new pair of shoes.
Okay.
One of the girls heard about
what happened at the food bank.
And they're saying
things to you about that, are they?
We'll get it sorted, don't you worry.
D'you wanna sleep here with me?
Yeah? All right, babe,
roll over then. Tuck in.
That's it. Roll right over. I'll tuck you in.
Good girl.
Hello?
Hello, is that Ivan?
It is, yeah. Who's that?
It's, it's Katie,
the girl at the supermarket.
You gave me... You gave me
your phone number.
Okay, I remember you.
Yeah, I was, erm... I was ringing about
the work that you were talking about.
It's nice to meet you.
You don't need to be nervous
with me. I can see you're in pain.
You don't... You don't need to be, all right?
I'm gonna help you. Okay?
So, don't cry, right.
I don't want you to cry, I'm gonna help you.
I know the situation. Ivan's told us a little
bit about you and, you know,
and that's what I'm here for.
I am gonna help you.
Hey, ya.
- All right?
- Yeah.
Did they, er, they go down all right?
Nae bother. Both fast asleep. How'd it go?
Yeah, it was good, it was good.
It was a, it was a single-parent meeting.
One of the mums came and spoke
to me afterwards, she was really nice.
Ah, there's some good people round, yeah.
Yeah.
Make sure you take care
of yourself, Dan, won't ya?
- Course I will.
- All right.
- See you soon.
- Good night.
- Give my love to the kids in the morning.
- I will do.
- Thank you.
- 'Night.
Dan, it's me. Erm, thank you
for coming round tonight.
Daisy woke up and she forgot to ask
you about her school project.
She's, erm, she's gotta interview
somebody about their work
and she wants to speak to you.
Oh, and they, they loved all your stories.
She said that Dylan was just
laughing and laughing.
It was lovely. Nearly made me cry
when she told me.
All right, I'll speak to you soon.
Sleep well. 'Night.
I've come to see the girl.
Okay. Come in.
Erm, do I pay you?
No, you pay the girl. It's that door there.
Right.
Oh, no, Dan.
Katie, you don't need to do this.
You shouldn't see me like this.
I'm sorry.
No, this, this is cut off. This is separate.
Can you... You need to get out.
Listen, I couldn't speak to you in the flat,
I need to speak to you now.
Dan, please, get out.
Oh, Katie, please, I need to speak to you.
I just wanna speak to you. Katie!
Dan, please, just go.
Dan, please, I don't want you here!
Will you just go, please!
- I've built you a bookcase.
- What?
For your books.
Oh, Dan. Please, just go.
- Please, just go, I don't want you here.
- This is breaking my heart.
Dan, please, just leave me alone.
I've got 300 quid in my pocket.
I can buy the kids fresh fruit.
If you can't deal with it,
I can't see you any more.
Listen, I've gotta go back inside.
D'you understand?
I don't wanna speak to you any more.
And don't show me any more love.
Cos you're gonna break me, Dan.
I don't understand.
So what jobs have you actually applied for?
It's a monumental farce, isn't it?
You sitting there with your
friendly name tag on your chest, Ann,
opposite a sick man looking
for nonexistent jobs,
that I can't take anyway.
Wasting my time, employers' time, your time.
And all it does is humiliate me,
grind me down.
Or is that the point,
to get my name off those computers?
Well, I'm not doing it any more.
I've had enough.
I want my date for my appointment
for my appeal for Employment and Support.
- Have you not had that yet?
- No.
Please listen to me, Dan.
It's a huge decision to come off JSA
without any other income coming in.
Look, it... It could be weeks before
your appeal comes through.
You see, there's no time limit
for a mandatory reconsideration.
I've got a time limit.
And you might not win.
Please, just keep signing on.
Get somebody to help you
with the online job searches.
Otherwise, you could lose everything.
Please don't do this. I've seen it before.
Good people, honest people, on the street.
Thank you, Ann.
But when you lose your self-respect,
you're done for.
I'll be seeing you gentlemen later.
Oh, wait until security sees this.
What's going on here?
What are you fucking playing at?
- Aye-aye. You cannot touch us.
- Well that's clever, in't it?
It's me new art installation.
Eh? Certainly can, lads. Come on.
Look at this, you got all the technology.
- Look at this!
- I can't believe it.
I cannot believe it, man.
What have you done?
This is me new hobby.
Shall I put that on my CV?
Did you stop, even for a second,
to think about the consequences
of what you've done here?
All I know, mate,
is if I divvent get my appeal date,
I'll be here every day doing this.
- Unbelievable. Every day?
- Every day.
Tell you what, Ben,
just phone the police. Okay.
I cannae... Listen, mate,
I cannot believe this now.
This is out of our hands.
We're gonna have to phone the cops, man.
Well, if youse had done your job
like you should have done,
I wouldn't have had to resort to this.
I cannot believe it. I cannot believe it.
Go on, lad, give him a hand.
Yes!
Words of wisdom!
You're the man, wee man! Eh?
Fucking eh? Yeah!
Are youse out of work, mate?
Are you fucking... Are you Daniel Blake?
I am Daniel Blake, yes.
Hey, this is Daniel Blake!
Fucking look at that. Yeah!
Yeah! Hey!
You look fucking freezing, pal.
Here, have my jacket.
- No, no.
- No, come on, man, have my fucking jacket.
It's all right, son. Look after yoursel', eh?
Keep yoursel' warm like.
You're a gentleman.
So what's, what's your appeal all about?
Liar!
You're... You're under arrest
on suspicion of criminal damage.
Hey, a miscarriage of justice, eh.
Slow down. Whoa. Back off.
All right, all right, all right.
What the fuck's going on? Eh?
You should be arresting the wankers
who came up with sanctions. Eh?
That preachy baldy cunt. What's his name?
Ian Duncan fucking what's-his-face.
Aye, and the posh dicks in their mansions
who came up with the fucking
bedroom tax for disabled...
Listen, youse are all gonna
be out of a fucking job anyway.
Privatizing you, eh?
All the fucking Tories, man.
Aye, members of the fucking big club, eh.
Fucking posh Eton twats.
Sir Daniel fucking Blake, pal!
Hey, should be a statue made for you, pal.
Fucking Sir Daniel Blake!
Yer a fucking beauty!
Yay!
So, what happens now?
Right, this is a copy of the caution sheet.
Because you fully admitted the offences
and you've been of good
character in the past,
we're cautioning you for the offence
of criminal damage,
under Section Five of the Public Order Act.
But please remember
that these can come back
and haunt you if you re-offend.
So try to keep yourself out of trouble.
Aye.
- See him out, please.
- This way, Mr Blake.
Dan. Dan!
Come, I need to talk to you.
We called you loads of times.
Dan!
Mum's been so sad lately.
Why don't you speak to her?
Don't you have credit on the phone?
I see you.
We understand what happened to your heart.
Mum spoke to one of your neighbours.
We didn't know about it.
It's cold out here.
I'm freezing.
Please, Daisy, I'm not feeling very well.
I made you some couscous.
And Dylan sent you his lollipop.
He's really missing you, too.
Just go, Daisy, please.
Can I ask you one question, Dan?
Did you help us?
Suppose so.
So why can't I help you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Daisy.
I'm really sorry.
You know, I'm not usually a nervous person,
Katie, but I'm nervous about this.
It's only natural, Dan.
I just want it done, you know?
Yeah. Well, you're prepared.
You got all your papers.
You've got a good,
good person representing you.
And then when you're done,
you can come, come to dinner to celebrate.
The kids are really looking
forward to seeing you.
Hi, er, Daniel Blake. I've come for my appeal
for the reinstatement of my...
Employment and Support Allowance.
- Daniel, hi. Hello. Are you all right?
- Hello.
- Hi, I'm Katie. I'm a friend of Daniel's.
- Hi.
- You're here for support, yeah?
- Yeah.
Daniel, your appeal will be heard by
a legally qualified chairperson and a doctor.
- Aye, fingers crossed.
- Yeah...
If I lose this appeal,
I'm out on the streets.
Well, we've got some updated
reports here from your GP,
your own consultant and your
physiotherapist.
And they're all furious.
You're gonna win this, Dan.
I do this every week.
- I bet me life on it.
- I told ya.
Just be yourself,
answer the questions and relax.
I'm really confident.
D'you have any questions?
Well, I've got one or two things
I'd like to get off me chest.
- But will they listen?
- It's the least they can do.
And can I go in with him?
I'll certainly ask. Would you like her to?
- Yeah. Definitely, yeah.
- Yeah?
Okay, I'll certainly ask. No problem at all.
All right. Thank you.
My pleasure.
I'll just go and see what the score is.
- Yeah.
- Sounds good, don't it?
Look at them.
It's funny, they've got
my life in their hands.
Thanks, Katie, for coming.
Thank you for asking me.
You stubborn old bastard.
I think I'll go and freshen up, yeah?
All right.
Can somebody, er,
phone an ambulance, please? 9-9-9.
There's a guy collapsed in the toilet.
He's flat out.
Phone 9-9-9. Somebody, please.
Dan!
No! Dan!
Just had a heart attack.
Yeah, two breaths, please.
Oh, Dan!
- Just the two breaths...
- Is he breathing?
Oh, Dan.
Listen, we're trying to help
him as much as we can.
No, no, no, please keep going,
please keep going. Don't stop.
I'm afraid we've lost him.
No, don't say that,
please don't say that. No.
- No, please!
- I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
- Please...
- Where's the ambulance now?
- Please.
- No response at all.
Please. Please try again.
Erm...
They call this a "pauper's funeral"
because it's the cheapest slot, at 9:00.
But Dan wasn't a pauper to us.
He gave us things that money can't buy.
When he died, I found this on him.
He always used to write in pencil.
Erm...
And he wanted to read it at his appeal
but he never got the chance to.
And I swear that this lovely man,
had so much more to give,
and that the State drove him
to an early grave.
And this is what he wrote.
"I am not a client, a customer,
nor a service user.
"I am not a shirker, a scrounger,
a beggar, nor a thief.
"I'm not a National Insurance Number
or blip on a screen.
"I paid my dues, never a penny short,
and proud to do so.
"I don't tug the forelock, but look my
neighbour in the eye and help him if I can.
"I don't accept or seek charity.
"My name is Daniel Blake.
I am a man, not a dog.
"As such, I demand my rights.
"I demand you treat me with respect.
"I, Daniel Blake, am a citizen,
"nothing more and nothing less."
Thank you.