BLACK BOOK
I'll take a photograph.
You are disturbing the lesson.
You may watch, but don't take pictures.
I don't speak Hebrew ... but you speak Dutch?
Aren't you Ellis de Vries from The Hague?
Ronnie?
El, what are you doing here?
- I live here, this is my country.
- Are you Jewish?
- What are you doing in Israel?
- Accompanying my husband.
Him, with that collar.
George. He suddenly 'got religion'
because of the war, the doctor says.
So, a lot of Jesus and no sins like that.
It's nice and quiet at night.
The last man I saw you with,
wasn't he a Canadian?
That's him. That's my Canadian.
How the hell did you end up here?
Bye sweetheart. I'll write.
I'll send pictures. Bye Ellis.
It's "Rachel Rosenthal." I'm married.
- Write down "Rachel Rosenthal"
- Address?
- De kibbutz Stein.
- Shalom. That's what it's called, isn't it? Shalom?
Shalom!
And Jesus said
"Light of the world,
light of life"
Jantje, Stientje, you're up today.
Good morning, Mrs. Tjepkema.
Good morning, children.
- Good morning, miss
- Good morning, Rachel
We promised not to say Rachel
anymore, remember? Never.
It's clearing up. Tonight
I want the stables clean.
- OK, boss.
- At your seats, go.
Father, could you do a prayer?
Our guest probably learned
a new text.
Good, close your eyes.
And Jesus spoke again to them:
"I am the light of the world."
"Who will follow me, shall not walk in darkness"
"but will have the light of life."
- Amen.
Amen.
Beautiful, and no slip of the tongue.
Stientje, give her a plate.
If the Jews had listened to Jesus,
then they wouldn't have had
all this suffering. Then again ...
Please begin.
Here.
Hey, you there, girl!
English music is forbidden!
But not for naked girls!
You're not funny. You scared me.
I thought you were a Kraut.
How can I make it up to you?
Have me on the boat.
- I'd like a one of those ciggarettes, too.
- Jawohl.
- What's that crazy guy doing?
- Getting rid of ballast, so he can ascend.
Get down.
- What are you going to do?
- That's my hideout!
Wait, look: Germans.
You can't go back, come.
[Unknown voice]: Enjoy your meal, boy.
Hey, take it easy, boy.
That voice on the record ...
- That's you.
- That was me.
In the old days. Before the war.
First you sing, then you
have to keep your mouth shut.
Here, my Dad caught these for us.
That's sweet of him.
Will you light the stove?
- It's nice.
- You can keep it.
- Really?
- A souvenir for the one who saved me.
How sweet.
Thank you.
- With a positive side effect.
- What do you mean?
Now I don't have to spit anymore
bible texts to get food.
Sshhh ...
A car. It's a gasoline engine.
Miss Stein?
Rachel Stein?
I know you're here.
The Germans found your pass at the burnt out farm.
Helmsman Maalderink, the Krauts know
you were in the neighborhood.
They wrote down the number of your sail.
- Says who?
- Come on ...
One plus one is two, even for the Krauts.
A hidden jewish woman dissappears,
and the only sailor around to help is you?
- What are you doing here?
- Warning you.
Soon the SD will come and arrest her for transport to Poland.
And you and your family will be put in jail for aiding Jews.
How did this news reach you?
The police report of the krauts landed
in the hands of the The Hague police.
- They gave it to us.
- "Us"? Who's "us"?
"Us" is "us". Be happy that there're
so many good cops in Holland.
I wanted to tell you one thing: Hide.
Now.
Good night.
- Wasn't I clear enough?
- You have to help me and Rob to go into hiding.
With 'us' you mean The Resistance. You're
with them. So you can help us, right?
- Maybe yes, but it's dangerous.
- We'll take that risk.
Please don't let us down.
Please?
There's an escape route, through the Biesbosch.
I can get you to liberated territory.
Cross country, now?
That's madness.
In a few weeks the Tommys will
be here and Holland will be liberated.
Your Tommys have been cut to pieces at Arnhem.
Choose: come with me or take care of yourself.
Wait -- we'll come.
Be ready tomorrow, two o'clock.
I'll pick you up.
Don't bring too much, but make sure
you can hold out for a while.
It's here. I'll wait on the corner.
- Yes?
- I'm here for the notary.
I am Rachel Stein.
Follow me,
I will check for you.
[Mrs. Smaal]: Wim, there's girl called Stein
here. Do you have a moment?
My husband can see you now.
- Smaal.
- Rachel Stein.
My father said to call on you for help, if ever I was in trouble.
Every young lady can call herself Rachel Stein.
My parents and my little brother.
What can I do for you Rachel?
My hideout was blown up.
I have no papers, nothing.
I have a chance to cross over to liberated area.
- Really?
- Yes.
I will need money to live.
How much?
At least enough to last me a year.
100,000?
No, that's impossible.
Half of it?
In dollars and jewels, if possible.
I don't want it to take up too much space.
You'll have to sign the receipt.
I have to justify this to your father later on.
Do you know where my parents are?
No, I don't know.
And I don't want to know.
- Where do I sign?
- Here.
Hold on, you don't want to check first?
No, I trust you.
Rachel, you can't trust someone blindly.
Those times are over.
Checkpoint: Show me you papers.
Van Gein, from the SD, with a load of arrested Jews.
10 pieces
- Check. You may continue. Have a good trip.
- Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler.
Come out.
Let's go.
Rachel. Rachel.
Max. That's my little brother.
- We're here too.
- Mum.
My girl.
Sshh ... Be quiet, come, come
- How did you get here?
- Through him.
- He said you were going to cross.
- Then we wanted to go too.
This is Rob, he helped me.
Hi.
Don't push, be careful, go forward.
Come and sit.
Please, sit.
- Hurry up, boy.
- He's just had an operation.
- 4 days ago.
- I'm sorry, I didn't know.
- Could you throw away the plank?
- You're not joing us?
No, the skipper will take it from here.
Safe travels.
Lady, take that off.
It glows too much in the dark.
I keep it on even in my sleep.
Then move up your collar: the Krauts see everything.
Let's go.
Look: gingerbread. Saved it for a party.
That means now.
What happened to you?
Acute appendicitis. He almost couldn't join us.
My notary found us a doctor just in time.
- He operated secretly.
- On the kitchen table.
Did Mr. Smaal know where you were?
Of course. He gave us the address of the hideout.
Odd, he kept repeating he didn't know.
No, careful.
- Where was your hideout?
- In the attic of a boring grocer's.
- A socialist, but still good.
- But Brussels is better.
- Now, we'll never be separated again, right?
- Right.
- Why are we going east?
- How can you tell?
I used to be helmsman on a big ship.
Before the war.
Before the war I was on the Holland-America line. I'm zigzagging
Excellent.
Get out.
Show me your cargo.
- Open up.
- But she's dead.
- It's a very bad disease.
- Typhus.
Open it.
Close it.
Man, I almost choked.
We never get any complaints.
At least a centimetre of space.
Look.
- Can't go any wider, otherwise they'll notice.
- No, I mean in the rain.
I could hardly keep my face still.
Come.
You can clean yourself up over there.
Here, use this.
I don't know how I will ever be able to thank you.
- You could untie these ...
- Take a hike, Joop.
Instead thank the people who found you
for warning us instead of warning the SD.
We'll dye that.
Dad?
Kuipers.
Ellis de Vries.
You'll get used to the name.
Do you have a good ID?
All fine, dad. More than real.
Yes.
- Did you ever do any cooking?
- Yes, I used to at home. Kosher.
There's no demand for that anymore.
- Sorry.
- You can stay here,
but you'll have to work.
The harder, the better.
Her whole family was murdered by the SS.
Someday we'll get back to them, Ellis.
Five Months Later
Ellis, come here.
We need a substitute.
Could you be a replacement?
- Work is work.
- Even if it's dangerous?
What do I have to lose?
Your life.
- She'll travel with me tomorrow?
- Yes.
The new courier, Ellis
- I am Hans.
- Ellis.
Have a seat.
Ok, everybody knows the procedure:
the Kuipers group handles the technical side ...
- Hello.
... we as KP will give cover.
- What time will he arrive?
- 7:30
- Wind direction?
- North-north-west.
Then you'll take the lead, Joop:
south-south-east
- Red.
- You stay at 200 meters, Kees.
No further: I am not Jesse Owens.
- Blue, Kees.
- And I give the signs.
Any further questions?
Then pass on the gin.
And what's my job in this boys club?
You can play my fiancee.
Just kissing around somewhat.
You'll be playing a couple.
So the Krauts won't be paying attention.
Just kissing? That's all?
Boys.
To the Queen.
To Wilhelmina, Tim.
You old communist.
Cheers.
One minute to go. Let's begin.
Okay, can you take this?
Chocolate ... haven't had this for 2 years.
Ellis, you'll be carrying this tomorrow.
Be careful, there's radio equipment in there.
Music, nice.
Are we going to swing?
A transmitter/receiver.
I'm going to plant a microphone in the head office of the SD.
- But that's heavily guarded, right?
- I am a maintenance technician at the phone company.
The Krauts need us all the time.
I can walk in and out, no problem.
Everything's prepared.
I was just waiting for this.
- Is my stuff in there too?
- Here.
I can't take this across the street.
'Handle with care' it says.
There's still some suitcases left in the office.
Start loading up, guys.
Hands up!
Don't move!
Oh my god, we took 5 lives.
What have we done?
It was them or us, Theo.
Let's load up, we have to leave.
I'll check outside.
Goddamn. He's such a cold one, Hans.
- He's a top marksman.
- And if he had missed?
He never misses. Hans was the best marksman of Pro Patria.
- What's that?
- A student shooting club.
THE student marksman club.
Hans, Maarten and I  were members.
And we work together, helping the Jews.
Hans is great, he'll get you through anything.
No Kraut to be seen.
They were working on their own.
Take off their uniforms.
We can use everything.
We'll have to give them a Christian burial.
Oh yeah?
There are lots of deep holes here, Theo.
You can throw 'em in there by yourself.
That's my gun. What did you think?
What did you think I was thinking?
Check. Keep your ID's ready.
We're in love right?
Well ... here it goes.
Open all suitcases.
I'll shoot. You pull the emergency brake.
Leave the train and run. Don't think of anything else.
Stay away from me, you dirty bastard!
[In German]: Good day.
- Can I help you?
- Thank you.
Heavy, huh?
Beautiful ladies should not carry heavy bags.
My records and my phonograph.
- Thank you.
- You like music?
- Very much
That's my job: I used to be a singer before the war.
- Ellis de Vries.
- Ludwig Mntze
Open your suitcase. Papers.
Exciting?
Very exciting.
For me that is.
Postage stamps -- I loved those as a child.
- All those far away countries.
- I've collected them since I was six.
Probably why I studied geography.
Inspection.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Move along.
Yes, Captain.
Can I look?
I'll be very gentle.
Poland ... France ...
I always collect the countries where I'm stationed.
First Poland, then France, and now here.
You've stopped with our Queen.
The Wilhelmina stamps from the Dutch Indies.
I don't know if I'll ever get them complete.
Hauptsturmfhrer, over here.
No, these are mine.
I'd be glad to take you home
so you don't have to carry them.
That's not necessary, I'm being picked up.
Thank you very much.
Maybe I'll see you around.
I'd like that.
Good bye.
- You flirt very easy.
- Yes, well men ...
Mntze, he's called. Quite a nice guy.
Chief of the SD. Because of him, lots
of people of the resistance have died.
And a man like that collects stamps?
If he ever faces the wall after the war,
I'll be glad to say "Fire".
- Watch out.
- Sorry.
Look, he found something.
Watch it.
Mr. Gerben, it's our car.
Don't touch that.
- Open up. Open!
- It's jammed.
Jesus.
They've seen the weapons!
- Get out!
- Run!
Stop there!
- Gerben.
- Goddamn it.
Gerben.
- You're too late, they'll get you.
- He's my son.
If they get you, we're all fucked.
You know too much: They'll beat it out of you.
Mr. Kuipers, there's nothing more we can do.
Here, take everything to Silentium.
Ellis, you take the suitcases to the drop point.
Here Hans, call them.
Tell them there's a contamination here.
Thanks to that arse Mntze, they now have Tim.
Wait a minute.
Please tell them the soup kitchen is now closed.
You met this Mntze in the train, right?
- And he kinda liked you?
- The bastard adored her.
Oh, don't overreact.
He showed me his stamps. He's collecting Wilhelmina.
[Hans]: The soup kitchen will be closed.
How far would you be willing to go with him.
How far?
- You mean sleep with him?
- That's a rude way of saying it.
I like things to be clear. Is that what you mean?
How far would you go? For Tim. For the others.
As far as Mntze is willing to go. OK?
A deadly sin: A good suit for a dead body
while everyone else walks in rags.
The customer remains king.
Where did she put the suitcase?
Over there, in the office.
You think of everything.
And for that fucking Kraut.
Go away. This is none of you business.
- After the train incident, maybe a little?
- No, not even a little.
Alright. I'm here for the suitcase.
There.
Goddamn. It's soaking wet.
- Has it broken?
- I hope not: it's insulin.
There's a dying need for that.
Imagine a diabetic without his insulin.
- He can say bye bye.
- Tell me about it.
You have it as well? I never noticed.
No I don't. I am healthy.
Stop watching.
At the revue, there was diabetic comedian.
He always injected before a performance.
Then he had to eat a lot of chocolate
if he injected too much. A never ending bother.
Yes, but still better than dying of pain.
British bastards. At least half of it is broken.
The hospital will be happy with that.
Don't ask. Then I can't give away any secrets.
It stings, doctor.
It stings, it stings, it stings!
Shall the doctor have a look at it?
So I am still the first.
Yes?
Wim, the girl is here again.
This time she looks like Jean Harlow.
Rachel, you're back?
We never got any further than the Biesbosch.
And your parents and Max ... they joined you didn't they?
Suddenly there was a Kraut patrol boat and ...
Stupid coincedence
Strange. Everybody's dead and I can't cry for them.
- Who fared you over?
- A skipper. Also dead, I think.
But someone brought you to the Biesbosch, right?
A man from the underground.
Who was that?
van Gein, he was called I think.
Disgusting. My sympathies.
I am supposed to work for Queen and country
by getting friendly with a high ranking SD officer.
Maybe even sleep with him.
You're on your own with that.
Can't help you with that.
No.
But maybe there's something in here that can help me.
I am here to see Captain Mntze
Really? Why?
It's about the royal house.
Queen Wilhelmina in person.
Send her to Captain Mntze
You are expected. Wait over there.
Ms. de Vries ...
What a surprise. To what do I owe the pleasure?
I have family in the dutch Indies.
They always wrote.
My mother kept the letters.
I have softened the stamps off for you.
With steam.
Amazing.
Beautiful, very nice.
Good day.
Put it over there, Ronnie. I don't
want to damage these lovely stamps.
- Shall I serve you?
- No don't bother, I'll do that.
Take some of the chocolate. It's British.
We got them by chance.
Take some.
What were you planning to do with these stamps?
Nothing special, they were in a drawer in my place.
Almost all the Wilhelmina stamps I don't have ...
If you see anything of interest, take it.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Yes.
Close the door.
Captain, your car is ready.
Already?
Take my hat and coat please.
Too bad, duty calls.
I haven't been able to choose yet.
Then I'll leave them here.
Thank you.
I think I ate too much chocolate.
Is that bad?
I don't get it everyday.
I have to go to a party.
There will be much more to eat there.
What if you could go home and pick up
your phonograph and records and join me?
How about I sing?
Even better.
Without the SD from The Hague.
All our successes would not have been possible.
Your fight against the terrorists is our fight.
With the Fhrer, we fight for a free Europe.
Heil Hitler.
And now music. Franken.
# die Fahne hoch
die Reihen fest sind geschIossen
# SA marschiert
mit ruhig festem Schritt
# Kam'raden, die Rotfront
und Reaktion erschossen
# marschier'n im Geist
in unser'n Reihen mit
# Kam'raden, die Rotfront
und Reaktion erschossen
# marschier'n im Geist
in unser'n Reihen mit
Ms. de Vries?
Everything okay?
The champagne didn't go down well.
I'm not used to any alcohol anymore.
But I'm alright now.
Shall I sing some?
General, ladies and gentlemen ...
It is my great honor to present you Ellis de Vries.
She will sing for us.
Any requests?
Lola. Die fesche Lola.
Yes, Lola, Lola
# ich bin die fesche Lola
# der Liebling der Saison. ich hab'ein
Pianola. zu Haus in mein'm Salon.
# ich bin die fesche Lola
mich liebt ein jeder Mann
# doch an mein Pianola
da lass ich keinen 'ran
Lola, Lola
# ich bin die fesche Lola
der Liebling der Saison
Ich hab'ein
Pianola. zu Haus in mein'm Salon.
# und wer mich will begleiten
da d'runten aus dem Saal
# den hau ich auf der Saiten
und treff'ihn aufs Pedal
Lola.
Bye
So?
So what?
I'd like to see your stamps.
There's quite a lot of them.
I have lots of time.
I don't have any toothbrush for you.
Brushed.
Not bad.
From the capitalists we kicked out.
The loot is for the winners.
Exactly.
You sing well.
Where did you sing?
In Berlin. Cabaret, revue.
You should have continued.
There's no need for that anymore now.
Your hair is normally black.
Blonde is in fashion now.
Or this fashion will help you survive,
for instance if you're a Jew.
So what?
Are these Jewish?
Also blonde. A perfectionist.
- Oh, sorry.
- Come on in, girls are allowed.
Do you also have to pee after sex?
You were really great tonight.
Did he hire you, Mntze?
You came looking for a job, right?
No, though I am searching for one.
But I am not a party member
Neither am I, although I do agree with them.
Holland is, after all, a piece of Germany.
We all speak a sort of German dialect.
Oh, nice: real soap.
And good food and great drinks.
What more do you want?
[Franken]: Ronnie?
Make sure a high-ranking Kraut never gets enough of you.
- Gnther, over here.
- Ronnie?
Are you playing with each other?
We were talking about work.
Ellis would like to work for us.
Someone who sings such good german is hired right away.
That is if ...
you pass the inspection.
If that isn't healthy, I don't know what is...
No No! these are reserved for Captain Mntze.
- Where were you?
- On the toilet.
Franken offered me a job.
Good idea. You can start helping with the Fhrer's birthday tomorrow.
You're married, I see.
You have nice kids.
Was. I was married.
Not anymore?
No, not anymore.
Gering, had sworn ...
... that no English bomb would fall on Germany.
Christina was with the children in the wrong hideout.
And I wasn't there.
Bulls eye.
To not have anything, Ellis ... isn't much.
I know.
For you it must be a beautiful sound.
Sshhh ...
You haven't told us anything.
I don't know anything. Someone else put those weapons in the car.
You are just a little piece of shit on our road to final victory.
In a few weeks, the Russians will throw
you in the sea, along with your executioners.
For you.
And for your comrade Stalin.
Dirty bastard.
What a filthy language.
Wash his mouth.
He's holding his breath.
Up
Within the hour you'll talk.
- Are we here alone?
- The rest fled back to Germany.
Could you come and sit here?
So we can sit next to each other.
Type it out and copy it 15 times.
You have spots on your uniform.
It's nothing, just water.
Hurry up, there will be more to do.
If you read, I'll type.
Let's take these off, with them I can't type.
- Are these real?
- Of course, what did you think?
Got it from Gnther. Nice, huh?
His safe is a real treasure hole.
- Open sesame.
- Yes just like that.
There's a whole box full of diamonds.
Right.
Let's see: 1945, 19th.
There we go.
Ellis? You can start.
The terrorist Timotheus Kuipers gave the following ...
You can speed up a little bit.
... statement.
"I am a member of a resistance group.
My father, is head of the group "Gerben Kuipers".
Boring, huh?
Ellis?
What are you doing here?
To talk with the Germans about justice.
Justice? Here?
People of the resistance have no rights, but
as a lawyer I try to help them nonetheless.
With a guy like Franken? A waste of time.
Tim's microphone.
How did you know I was here?
I do not underestimate you.
That Mntze guy is quite nice, don't you think?
Could you give me a hand? We have to
decorate the hallway for the Fhrer's birthday.
Mr. Smaal, you are here.
Come in.
No the piano should go there.
Some more
- Thank you.
- Good bye.
That looks great.
Don't forget to put the Fhrer in the right perspective.
- Give me a spotlight.
- Captain.
The execution order for the three terrorists.
Tomorrow we shoot'em.
Just sign here.
Absolutely not.
No one is getting shot.
But they confessed, they have to be shot.
Fhrer's order, you know that.
I am in command here.
No executions if I say so.
Dismissed.
Heil Hitler.
Jesus, if even those Germans start to
fight among each other, where will it end?
To me! Follow me!
Ellis?
- Ellis?
- I'm coming
- What are you doing here?
- To cheer him up.
- The nicest one is for you.
- That's sweet. Are you coming with me?
- Actually I have to go home.
- So I won't be seeing you tonight?
Of course you will.
I just have to pick up some clothes.
Oh Honey ...
My little animal.
Animal ... ahh ...
- It works.
- Ellis.
- Ronnie, Ronnie...
- Yes, yes, cum, cum
- Jesus, what a horny animal.
- Just a dirty Kraut whore.
- We'll get those after the war.
- Shave 'em and put their heads in tar.
- And after that shoot'em.
- Come, don't be so primitive
That's not what we fight for.
Damn, that fucking phone.
Don't stop, keep going.
I almost came. Watch it, you're dripping.
- Franken.
- Yes, send him in.
We'll continue tonight. And now go.
Cas.
- Good day, how are you?
- Fine.
Sit down. I still owe you money from last time.
- What's that?
- He's opening his safe.
There's a new list before you on your desk.
Not many ... is it still worth it?
Easily half a million.
I think this will be the last ride.
- I know that voice.
- Sshhh ...
What?
- It reminds me of the man who helped us flea.
- Shut up.
- Shit, the generator's cutting out.
- I'll fix it.
- You can count it.
- Don't have to.
When can you have the next transport ready?
They live close together. Maybe 3 days?
That's him. That's van Gein.
Those rich Jews always come from the same circles.
None of your business.
If I wanted to, I could find out who your informant is.
This could cost you your head.
Or save mine after the war.
After the war, I won't be here.
Come let's have a drink.
To the next load of stupid Jews.
So it wasn't a coincedence, that German boat.
It was a trap. They're just working on a list.
What list?
Jews with money. They promise to take them to Belgium,
but instead they kill them.
- How do you know?
- Because I've been set up too!
Because I've seen my whole family being slaughtered.
Jesus, Ellis ... that's horrible.
- Who is this van Gein?
- He poses as someone of the resistance.
He tells Jews that they can run for it,
just make sure to bring your money.
Franken, waits for them, kills them, and then robs them.
So now there's a new list of potential victims.
We cannot let that happen.
We don't know who they are or where they are.
- What if we just kill Franken?
- Yes, stop that bastard.
No! If we kill him, 20 to 30 hostages will line up against a wall.
We don't shoot Franken and 20 to 30 jews will be killed.
Is the life of a random Jew worth more than a good Dutchman's?
Who decides that? You?
Franken will not be liquidated.
Van Gein. We kill him and it ends as well.
No killing. Mr. Smaal, your call.
On behalf of Gerben, I am negotiating a truce.
We do no more attacks, and Mntze promises not to retaliate.
Might work.
Ah, so that's why that fight happened between Franken and Mntze.
Gerben, congratulations. You saved your Tim.
Him AND others. Is that a problem for you?
Me? No. If those are the 'good' Dutchman
That's enough, Ellis. Gerben is chief.
If he says no, than it ends there.
Good day to you.
Ellis.
Things are the way they are.
That microphone of yours is absolutely brilliant.
Ellis.
I agree with you. We can't let those jews be slaughtered.
Gerben is also right. We can't just kill van Gein.
What if he just dissapears?
Franken will know. He'll have people shot.
Or he'll think van Gein has deserted.
After he just promised a new list?
Van Gein is trying to cover upfor after the war, says so himself.
If he disappears, Franken will think he just ran.
There's one thing, Kuipers and Smaal pass by too easily.
Someone has been setting up Jews for a long time.
van Gein has a suspect.
He'll have to tell us.
If I have to I'll beat it out of him.
Come. I'll round up my boys.
I can't. I'm meeting Mntze.
You alone know van Gein's face.
We can't do anything without you
You must be in on it.
That's him.
Let's go.
Give me your shawl.
Now.
It's empty.
Theo.
- Shoot. Shoot.
- I can't.
- Shoot!
- I can't!
Goddamn!
Bitch! Goddamned bitch! I'll goddamn ...
You curse.
Blasphemer.
That's enough, Theo. Theo, come!
Aah! Be careful man.
Flesh wound, Kees.
You got lucky.
The bullet must come out, though.
Ellis, take the chlorophorm.
Breathe deeply, Kees. Yes, like that.
Oh God, that shit doesn't work, you dick!
Expriry date 1941.
Jesus, this stuff is way over due.
- That's why van Gein wasn't knocked out.
- What's still good after 5 years of Krauts?
Your choice: A hit with the hammer, or some booze and bite your teeth.
Booze, dick.
- Cheers.
Kees, think of something nice.
Okay
Gotcha.
Thanks, dick.
Guys, cheers on a happy ending.
van Gein delivered the krauts tons.
Tons? You mean millions.
Come on Theo.
Damn those Dutchmen.
They killed my best soldier.
That brave warrior and comrade handed me millions.
And now he's dead, shot by goddamned terrorists.
I shot a man. I am bad.
That was justice. He's a murderer, you're not.
Yes I am. I am just as bad as the Nazis.
I said no, didn't I?
I said goddamn NO, didn't I?
The bastard had to die.
Besides, what does it matter?
That Tim, will face the firing squad. Dick.
Along with forty other hostages.
Because you as a resistance hero had to go and shoot van Gein.
Jesus, Gerben. Forty? How do you know?
From the microphone we placed on Franken.
His best man killed.
He wants blood.
You still negotiating with Mntze?
Not after the attack you pulled.
Tim is as good as dead.
But your Jews are saved ...
Ellis, no. I am responsible. No one else.
I am turning myself in.
Only I shall face the firing squad.
I will be beside you, Hans.
I carry most of the guilt.
- I will join too.
- Then we all go.
Stop it, this is ridiculous!
You're all drunk!
Before you know it, all of the resistance
will give up because of gin.
- Turning yourselves in is not a solution.
- Then what is?
Rescue them.
You won't get out alive of the SD basement.
The building plans of the SD office, when it was still a bank.
Got it from a friend.
Here I am.
I thought, "she's not coming back".
I lost track of time at home.
And then it was curfew and I had to sneak my way in.
What do we have here?
How dumb do you think I am?
Suddenly a beautiful woman comes into my life.
Later she comes to my headquarters...
Then she accidentally has the stamps I'm looking for.
Then she coincidentally appears to be Jewish.
And as soon as she comes to work here,
Franken's best undercover man gets killed.
Quite a coincedence, don't you think?
Choice: Be silent,
and I will hand you to Franken tomorrow.
Or, you tell me everything now
Only if you put away that gun
and kiss me now.
I kissed you, now tell me.
Put away your jackets and get to work.
Call all prisons and ask
How many hostages they have.
You can stop at 40 pieces, delivery today.
Executions will be tomorrow morning at 06:00.
Those calls will not be necessary.
Lieutenant, open your safe.
Of course. What document
are you looking for?
None. You are under the suspicion of
robbing and killing rich Jews.
There's nothing against that,
but you are accused of keeping their treasure to yourself.
By not handing over Jewish property to the empire,
you risk court martial and the death penalty.
Open your safe.
At your order, General.
Empty it quickly.
And here?
Open it, please.
From '39, when we started our campaign
Saved it for our victory.
Your Informant seems to have been mistaken.
This person is always well informed.
Not this time.
My apologies, Franken.
This is not the end of this discussion.
General ...
Mntze is negotiating with terrorists.
He promised them no more retaliation.
Even not for the murder of van Gein.
You negotiate?
With terrorists?
The resistance is willing to stop and give in their weapons.
If we stop retaliating.
This is in violation of a Fhrer order of the 4th of September.
- Which stays in force!
- Why shed more blood?
Russians in Berlin -- that Champagne will never be drunk.
That is defeatism.
And negotiating with enemy is high treason.
Police, arrest this man.
This means the death penalty, Mntze.
And I will lead the firing squad.
Ready.
Hans, the papers to get inside.
And the keys?
Duplicates from a contractor for Zutfenaar.
They built the cells.
I let him choose: A bullet now, or a medal after the war.
He gave them gladly.
Gerben, what are you up to?
I will not let you go alone.
- I decide that. You stay here.
- I can't stay here and do nothing.
I'm going to liberate forty men.
It's your job to get them safely out of here.
Everybody has a job, that one is yours.
The keys.
Gerben.
You will get Tim back.
On my word of honour.
- Why aren't you at your station?
- Mntze got arrested.
- Yes, we heard.
- Good, so the krauts are killing themselves.
- Get Mntze out.
- Over my dead body.
Get Mntze out, or I'm out.
That leaves us no choice.
- You really think this highly of this dick?
- Yes, I do.
Good. Take him.
- Hi.
- Hey
Nice, a party.
Mntze being arrested doesn't do you anything?
- Where there is life, there is hope.
- What hope do we have left?
That the Tommys will arrive.
Ellis, we're finished.
We've worked for the krauts.
The families of the poor bastards that
Franken tortured will come here.
- Or the resistance will kill us.
- The resistance won't kill anyone.
- Like you know.
- Yes, I do.
So you know those guys?
Ellis ... what?
You're a spy.
Jesus. I had never thought you would.
That's like Mata Hari, with Greta Garbo
Ladies, you are expected.
You go ahead, I'll join.
That Garbo though ... she died.
Show me your papers.
Hostages and terrorists from Utrecht.
Hostages.
Right.
Move along.
Open up.
You turn the van around.
Follow me.
Guus.
Ellis!
# ja, das ist meine Melodie
nach der ich singen muss
# nach der ich pfeifen muss
und tanzen muss, und springen muss
# die man beim ersten Ton versteht
weil sie jedem in die Beine geht
# ja, das ist eine Melodie
die mich so selig macht
# wenn ich sie hre,
hab ich immer an das GIck gedacht
# ach bitte sagt mir, liebt ihr sie
meine kleine Lieblingsmelodie
Go.
- Mntze too?
- We promised Ellis.
Siem.
Hi, come on.
It's me, Maarten.
Maarten.
Hi Tim old boy.
# ich tanze mit dir in den Himmel hinein
# in den siebenten Himmel der Liebe
# die Erde versinkt,
und wir zwei sind allein
# in dem siebenten Himmel der Liebe
All together. Chorus.
# ich tanze mit dir in den
# HimmeI hinein
- Boys hurry up.
What's going on down there?
Nothing we can't handle.
Guards.
Tim!
- Go!
- Joop.
- What happened?
-Go, now.
Easy.
Hit it.
Ronnie, you help Kutner.
Ellis, come with me to write a report.
And?
A trap. Complete failure.
And Tim?
Oh God.
Have a seat.
Ellis you did a great job. I am
very satisfied.
Well of course, one does
what one can for the Fhrer.
Yes, but the result is above all expectations.
- It can't be true?
- God damn
They've been beautifully set up with that coal hatch.
Like rats in cage.
You earned your money fair and square.
The bitch tricked us.
What a dirty Jewish trick.
- See, you can't trust them.
- Silence.
Himmler can come down now.
You may do that dear.
We won't be needing this english toy now anymore.
My dear Kuipers, Lieutenant Kuipers,
is saying goodbye to you now.
Ellis, one last word?
She laughs.
That bitch laughs.
Good night and good watch.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Never bite more than you can chew, darling.
Tomorrow, firing squad, along side with your Mntze.
Even if it's the last thing I can do: that girl dies.
How can she do that as a Jew?
- Who knows how much pressure she was under.
- Still ...
What if you had to chose between a bullet or treason.
An explanation is not an excuse.
We kill the girl, no matter what.
Wherever, whenever.
Move along.
Empty, empty.
Here, come here.
Oh, no my beautiful dress.
Quick, a hanky.
That tickles.
Sshhh ...
Come.
Give me the gun.
Franken will never catch us alive. Never.
Move along
Come, hurry up.
Everything in order again, Siegfried?
Move along.
- Make way!
- Not very friendly today are we?
Very diligent.
I'd never have thought.
Here you lazy, dry these.
Cosy, huh?
I wish it could stay like this forever.
It can, if we stay together.
Forever.
But not here in Holland.
They'll think I am a traitor.
They will look for me.
We'll have to straighten that out.
We know what the treason was like.
Optimist. Do you really think they'll
let you finish your talk as an SD officer?
We have no other choice.
We interrupt this program for the following announcement:
[Radio]: The German command has agreed to surrender ...
... of all german armed forces in Holland, the
north west of Germany and Denmark...
... to the commander in chief of the 21st army.
The war is over, my love.
The war is gone.
[Radio]: This includes all the marine vessels.
For us it is merely starting.
I'd never thought to be afraid of liberation.
Lieutenant Franken.
Lieutenant
Ropes away.
- Did you set course?
- Yes.
- In six hours, we'll be in Hamburg.
- Very good
Have a look down below.
Joseph, what's wrong.
Joseph?
Did your really think we'd let you get away?
- What are you doing here?
- You. And your treasure.
Ellis.
Ellis. Here, on the jeep.
- Ronnie.
- Hi, Ellis. Join us.
- How did you get here?
- Just stand in front.
A bit of laughing and pushing around.
Look, my new boyfriend. He has everything a girl wants.
Nylons, and stockings, and chocolate, and whiskey.
Oh, I love him!
- Come ride with me.
- No, I don't have time.
Ok, see you soon.
Bye. Bye.
[Sign]: Traitor
[Sign]: Whore
One moment, we're coming.
Come, Wim. The Canadians are here.
No. You're still alive?
Yes, strange huh, with all those people trying to kill us.
I thought Franken had shot you ...
Surely he told you we got away?
Franken?
Tell me? Me?
We've been in hiding for weeks.
We just got home half an hour ago.
- Who says you are not trying to leave?
- What do you mean child?
I am about to be picked up by Canadian field security
Good, then we'll join you.
- We'll wait in your office.
- Ludwig, what's wrong with you?
Go inside!
Sit down.
So you think I'm guilty for the disastrous attack?
Yes and for the eradication of your Jewish clients.
How dare you! Most of them knew him for years.
They were friends.
What would be my gain?
By stealing of what they entrusted you with.
You and Franken.
You betrayed him where the microphone was.
The hold up was your idea.
You let Hans and his men get slaughtered.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I wasn't the only one.
Kuipers knew all this as well.
But nobody would have his own son killed
Every man has unknown deapths.
May I show you something?
While we were in hiding, my wife and I
tried to put things in perspective.
I examined my agenda.
And we came to a radical conclusion,
didn't we darling?
And that is?
You'll have to join us by going to the Canadian police.
Just tell me.
As a lawyer, I can't.
I have to keep you unprejudiced.
That will be the Canadians.
Every suspect deserves a fair trial.
Even the biggest bastard?
Even those.
- We're coming.
- You?
Wim?
Stay here.
- Look!
- Goddamn, that's Mntze! Get him!
Mntze, we've got Mntze!
We have Mntze!
Yes!
Goddamn. There's Ellis de Vries.
Come with me.
Ellis de Vries.
Over here.
I've got you, bitch.
Attention.
Aim.
Fire.
Get up, you're going to church.
Come on, bring your shit buckets.
- Go on, move.
- Church is up stairs.
Come on.
Hey bitch, shit is over there.
- Move along.
- You pull it up. Hurry up.
Listen ot the voice of God.
Maybe you can change your ways.
Look ahead.
# 't scheepke onder Jezus' hoede
# met zijn kruisvlag hoog in top
# neemt aIs arke der verlossing
# aIIen die in nood zijn op
Hey, silence.
Silence.
We come to see traitors.
Heads up, let me see your faces.
- Look at them.
- Dirty rotten heads.
- Maybe the rest has some to offer.
- Take off your clothes.
- Guys take off your pants.
- Bare ass.
All women naked on top, I wanna see some tits.
Yes.
This too.
Take it off.
She sang for the Krauts.
She'll certainly sing for us.
- Sing for you? Never.
- Of course you do. Everybody sings.
Sing.
Are you mocking me?
Do you want me to lose face?
No way. Dirty Kraut bitch.
Dirty whore.
Hit her. Hit her.
Take cover, move away from the girl.
Damn, it stinks.
Who's got some perfume?
Stinky slut. Dirty stinky slut.
Make way for the fireman.
Stay away from my hose.
- Roll it up.
- Soldiers have no say down here.
I'm the boss here.
I am Commander Akkermans of the Prince's staff.
This is a godforesaken scandal!
Dirty fascists, you'll be out of here within
And you punks up there, get out of here now!
Ellis it's over. Come.
It's over. Come.
I want to leave.
Come honey. It's over.
Just a moment, Mrs. de Vries.
Your personal belongings.
Could you check?
van Smaal?
There goes the doctor.
That's doctor Akkermans.
He was in the resistance.
Long live the doctor!
Chocolate. Chocolate.
Here, don't give it all.
Supplies are still scarce.
# oranje boven, oranje boven
leve de koningin
I want to show you something.
- How did you get it?
- Franken tried to get away with it.
Everything he robbed from the murdered Jews.
I got this from my father, for my first performance.
That bastard Franken tried to make you into an accomplice, huh?
I'll talk to Kuipers about that.
Or higher up with the Prince.
I'll explain.
They'll never believe you.
Everything will be alright.
A happy end. A drink?
One more thing: Mntze got caught. I want to see him.
- Haven't you heard?
- What?
- It's too insane for words.
- What happened?
A Canadian dick allowed ...
... the Krauts to carry out the death sentence.
Doesn't it ever stop?
Ellis?
This will calm you down.
Come, lie down.
Feeling better?
Doctor, Doctor!
Insulin. Too much insulin.
That will put you to sleep. Forever.
Doctor Akkermans, Doctor Akkermans!
The 'hero' has to show himself.
Stay there. Soon you'll see your family again.
And who knows, maybe Mntze, too.
Doctor, Doctor!
(Anthem:)# Wilhelmus van Nassouwe
ben ik van Duitsen bloed
# den vaderland getrouwe
# blijf ik tot in den dood
# een prinse van Oranje
# ben ik vrij onverveerd.
# de koning van Hispanje
# heb ik aItijd geerd
Stop her.
She's a patient, she's ill.
Ellis. Ellis.
Out of my way.
Stop her. She's dangerous.
Let me go.
Let me go!
Goddamnit, let me go!
I'll get you, you whore!
Let me go, bastards, let me go!
Golden ring, number 23.
We found him.
Gerben, I think you'd better go.
Can our own people do this?
I don't want the Krauts to touch him.
You, stop.
Guys take over, it's for Gerben.
Mr. Kuipers? A lady wants to speak to you.
Ellis de Vries?
Wait Mr Kuipers.
Calm down please, Mr Kuipers.
She has information, names.
About these dead people, including your son.
Will you listen to her?
Yes.
Ellis?
Do you know who this is?
- What do you have to say about it?
- This.
This says it all.
From '42 onwards Hans and his friends
helped Jews to find shelter.
Usually his own patients.
And clients of Maarten, the banker.
And Kees, who was a lawyer.
Hans knew how much money they had
and where they were hiding.
Lookat the names Smaal wrote down:
Weiszman, Goud, van Witsen.
All those men came to him with their
money in order to flea to Belgium.
Lured to the Biesbosch and then murdered and robbed.
- Here, my parents.
- Were they patients of Hans?
No, but my brother got an acute appendix problem.
They asked Smaal for help,
who sent in Doc Hans.
It says here: "Dr. A. visits Stein."
Then he called Franken and turned them in.
Franken had van Gein turn up and two days later they were dead.
I don't understand. Hans ...
- Did you know he got arrested last year?
- No?
Dr. A. got out due to lack of proof.
The bastard.
- He had his own people killed.
- Kees, Maarten, everyone.
So no one could ask where their Jewish clients were.
Gerben?
Yes.
Captain ... I'll stay with Gerben.
# oranje boven
oranje boven, leve de koningin
Look. That's Hans' Jeep.
The hearse is gone.
- He's trying to sneak away.
- Where can he go?
Belgium, I think. But the Captain said
they're checking all the road blocks.
You drive.
I'll call Field Security.
A hearse has been seen near a blockade
in the direction of Hollands Diep.
Here, turn right.
- Papers.
- But I've just been checked.
Let go.
Willi?
- Quick, to the back.
- Willi, what's happening?
What's happening, goddammit?
Who are you? Ellis?
Ellis, is that you?
Don't do it. Goddammit.
Goddammit, let me out. Ellis?
Ellis, please don't. Ellis.
Let me out, Ellis, please.
We can talk about this.
Ellis, look.
All for you. Jewelry. I've got more. Jewels, gold.
American dollars. Take them.
Just open the coffin, Ellis.
What are you doing?
Ellis? Goddammit.
Ellis, what are you doing?
What are you doing? Ellis?
Ellis? Don't goddammit, Ellis.
Don't. I have nothing to do with this.
Open it. Goddammit.
Let me out. Goddammit!
I want to ... don't ... Don't!
Goddammit!
Goddammit.
Ellis? Don't
Don't Ellis!
Let me explain, honey.
Let me...
Goddammit. You dirty whore.
I'm going to get you, bitch.
Dirty Kraut whore.
I'm going to get you!
You're going to die!
We should be opening his coffin by now.
Yeah, we should.
What do we do with the money?
- It's not ours.
- It's nobody's.
It belongs to the dead.
He's silent now. At last.
Seemed like an eternity.
Mummy!
Hi, sweethearts.
- Where were you?
- I was here.
- What were you thinking about?
- About the past ...