- Children, look at this map, the black
mark of which, must be erased.
You hide it with your little fingers and you mark it with red.
Then, whatever it may happen, promise to go and find...
...the children of Alsace who are spreading their hands to us.
Let the green branch of hope to blosom in our beloved France.
Blossom from you, dear child.
Grow up! France is waiting for you!
- To rip the map of every trace of Germany and of The Hun...
...we must exterminate that race, we must not leave a single one...
Heed not, their children's cries They slay all now, the woman too...
Or else some day they will rise which
if they're dead, they cannot do.
- We have one and only enemy, who is digging the Germany's grave.
With a heart full of hate, gall and envy...
We have one and only enemy, who raises his murderous hand.
You know the enemy's name. It's England.
This is it!
War has been declared!
Well little brother, are you gonna spend repainting statues?
I put you down to that list too!
In two days, we're all leaving for basic training in Glascow.
At last something's happening in our lives.
Well? Are you coming?
Two minutes yet mr. Sprink.
- I have been ordered...
...to read this message from our beloved Kaiser.
This is a dark hour for Germany.
Our land is besieged.
And we must brandish the sword.
I hope...
...that God will give us strength to use it well...
...so we can resheathe it with dignity.
- Two minutes yet, lieutenant!
- We're going out.
The german trenches are 100 meters away.
We're bombing their machine-guns for more than an hour.
That's good for us.
We pass their first line and then the farm which is behind.
The 134th will replace us tonight.
So we can get some rest.
The Scots will cover us from the left.
You'll recognize them from their black caps.
Don't worry about them, you'll only pay attention to what I say!
I'm like you! I want to go back to my home as well!
So let's do what we have to do, and in one
week we'll be back home for Christmas.
Let's do what has to be done!
Prepare your bayonets!
Load your rifles!
Let's go!
- Don't stay here.
Someone of us survives. Don't stay here.
No William... No William! Come on! Come on William!
I abandoned him...
Like a coward... I abandoned him...
I let him die... all alone...
- You had no other choice.
And now we must pray for him and for all the other casualties.
- The reinforcements arrived... We're leaving Dale...
- You stay here with the rest of the
wounded... I'll see you back in base...
- I know you're in the trenches Father...
It's Andrew Duncan... I'm not far.
Father, I'm eight feet away.
The others... the others are too far away but me...
Father, you've got to come over to help...
That's it. Just walk, straight ahead and you'll get on top of me...
I knew... I knew I could count on you Father.
- What the hell are you doing? This is a suicide!
Don't run! Don't run off like that, darn you!
- Come back... Come back here! - Cease Fire!
- He was the stretcher-bearer! - What?
- You shot the stretcher-bearer! - How do you know that?
- Why did you shoot first?
- It was a Scotts marauder, sir. I Think I got him!
- Good. Stay put. With the slightest move, sound the alert! - Yes sir
Sprink... Come with me.
- Yes, lieutenant!
- Attention every one. Leave the
enemies weapons in the main trench!
- Go help them. - Allright.
- We have to rebuild it.
- Don't worry. None saw me.
Did you get hurt?
What happened?
You were for barely 15 minutes in
the trench. Reinforcements didn't...
- Their machine-guns annihilated us.
I lost a third of my men in 5 minutes.
- You saw the Scots retreat on your left and you left the farm.
- Did you learn anything new?
- I tried the Red Cross but nothing...
Impossible to get news from the enemy zone.
Information say, the Germans are treating the civilians good.
Your wife must be at her parents... with the baby...
During the bombing, one of our cannons exploded.
5 of our men and an officer died instantly.
I asked for you to replace him in that unit.
Artillery is good. You'll move up fast.
- No. I don't want the artillery. I'll stay here with my men.
Find another lieutenant. There are many.
- I am the Major General here and I
rule according to what I feel right.
You'll do what I tell you to.
You'll make Christmas in your unit.
Then you'll go to Poitiers for training. That's an order.
- If you want your visit to remain secret, you better leave.
My orderly is coming soon.
- You'll stay here for 3 days. Then you'll
move in first line to the Delsaux farm.
That sector should be quiet for Christmas.
Get some rest. I'll see you before you leave for Poitiers.
- Goodnight. - Goodnight, General.
- Lieutenant, I found you some blankets for tonight.
What's wrong lieutenant?
- My wallet... I lost my wallet...
- The wallet with the photo you showed me the other day? - Yes.
- What a shame...
But you don't need photos to remember your wife.
I had a mishap as well. Take a look, lieutenant...
2 centimeters higher, and I'd be dead!
It's still ringing!
Unstoppable, like me! Right lieutenant?
- In the briefing it says we put one every 5 meters.
- Every five meters?
- So, how many?
- About 100.000.
Or 20 trips with train for Lille via Brussels.
- Incredible! Christmas trees!
It will take longer to send these trees in front...
...than it would take to send our cannons.
Let miss Sorensen in.
- How is he?
- He's fine.
His regiment got attacked four days ago...
...but they pushed back the enemy.
Now, about your proposal...
I'm afraid... I can't accept it.
I feel that, as a Dane, you can't
understand how serious the situation is.
For 5 months now, 2 million of our men are fighting without pause.
We have neither the time nor the urge to organise a recital.
- It took me a while to understand...
...that I approached the wrong person.
The Heir, who saw me, was delighted with the idea to have...
a recital at his headquarters on Christmas Eve.
I was told, you are responsible for the cannons and the convoys...
...and also the soldiers.
So if you would kindly sign here, next to the Heir...
...before you inform your men.
- You'll only see him for a night. What's the point of that?
- It will be much more than one night.
Our minutes are longer than yours.
Mother, William and I got your package and your letter...
Thanks for the mittens and the mufflers.
It's so cold here, they're most welcome.
The thought of you at home nice and warm, keeps us good.
Thanks for the cake too.
I hope we'll have some left for Christmas Eve...
Your two sons... who love you.
- Good morning Father. - Three cases of whiskey.
- That's a lot of ammunition. - I presume I'm invited?
- My men are completely exhausted.
- We're all tired Gordon... Every single one of us.
I can bring you no relief before three days.
And if the Germans do attack tonight or
tommorow as its suggested they would.
- We'lljust have have to deal with them. - Yes sir!
- Our valiant stretcher-bearer!
You're the one who nearly got one of
his own men killed in no man's land.
The stretcher-bearer is supposed to save lives. Not endanger 'em.
I gave orders. Very clear orders...
...that it's forbidden to leave these trenches
in case of a German counter attack!
- Yes sir, but the situation... - But, you don't give a damn!
Now I suggest you drop the St. Bernard act in future...
...and never forget, something called military discipline!
Is that understood? Do you understand?
Perhars you wanna tell me what you're doing here
in the front line in the absence of any combat.
- I was visiting a friend...
- What? A friend? Where do you think you are? Your local parish?
Now you'll return with me immediately to the back line.
Come on man! Make yourself usefull for once.
Sir. This way's shorter.
We move up here, we take a right through the clergy area...
This way? Get me out of here, will you?
I'm sorry we have to go through the clergy sir...
Christ!
What a bloody fucking mess. Just get me out of here will ya?
- Yes sir. Absolutely sir! Shut up, will you?
As a priest im used to the silence.
- That's enough.
- What's going on? - Nothing.
Just a rifle shot. It's dead calm.
Good. Be carefull, they won't stop even on Christmas Eve.
Follow me.
- Do you know who's brilliant idea that was? - No.
- That's for you lieutenant.
- Sprink... You'll be leaving us... for a night.
- To go where?
- Home, in a way, where you'll be better.
- Why do you dislike me Lieutenant?
- After your regiment was disbanded, I had to take you.
But I prefer masons, bakers, farmers.
Artists like you arejust a waste, nothing but a millstone.
Now go. The officer will take you.
Come on, get moving! 10 o' clock and nothing is done yet.
Take it easy there. Isn't that too short?
- I told you lieutenant, I'm the best barber in Lens.
Even the may or was coming to my store.
- And Henri Hennebicque? Was he your customer too?
- Hennebicque? Doesn't sound familiar...
- He was my father-in-law.
Deputy may or. Lives at 21 Cypress street.
- You never told me sir. I know Cypress Alley well.
I went there several times to get my bike fixed.
At Narcisse Denoyelle, number 43.
- I can see it right now, a little blue gate.
- I think I can tell you now...
Sometimes, at nights, I'm heading to the road towards the farm.
Slowly, so I won't get killed...
and I sit there... and I look...
I know the Delsaux farm pretty well.
I was going there with my bike to get eggs and milk.
Just bey ond the farm is the road to Lens.
Straight to Lens.
On foot, I'd be back home in less than an hour.
With no rush... one hour...
My mother would wait for me at the door...
with a cup filled with hot coffee, just like before...
I'm done lieutenant. I think I'm done. Well?
There's no mirror in front?
Christ how stupid am I?
But I got you a great haircut sir, you're ready for the party tonight.
If you say so...
- Welcome miss. - My pleasure.
- Miss Sorensen, its a pleasure.
I will not tolerate mistakes! Clean it up right now!
- Where is Nikolaus Sprink? I think he arrived an hour ago.
- Sprink? The tenor?
- Miss, we owned this house for 300 years now...
...but its no longer our home since September 23rd.
Ask somewhere else, if you can.
- If they have any taste, they will put him in my room...
...on the top floor.
- You poor thing...
Good taste... Prussians?
You shouldn't even talk to these people!
- No... I have lice...
- We'll sing together again, just like before.
- I'm not like before, Anna.
- Sing for me. Sing for us.
- Your Highness.
- I'm glad to see the war didn't affect you.
Your volunteer as a private...
...impressed me.
- I am not a volunteer your Highness. I was called like every one else.
- I congratulate you for your initiative, miss.
You reminded us, that despite the war, it's Christmas.
- Thanks to you and your voices...
...tonight I'll feel like I am in Berlin.
...where I hope to return as soon as possible.
- Perhars next spring... if everything goes according to plan.
- Next spring!
- Do you smoke?
- Every one smokes in the trenches.
- You have to kill your time in any way possible.
- It's five years today, since the day we met...
- In Oslo...
...Five years passed already?
- You have to flirt with death to realize how time flies away.
That's a terrible thing.
All these fat and sated men, parading and drinking champange.
I have to return to the front...
to sing for my comrades, tonight, more than any other time.
- For months I was trying to make this true, and you want to go?
- I don't want to leave you... but I must go and sing for them.
- I'll return after that. - I'll come with you.
- No way! It's too dangerous. You can't imagine how much.
- Since the time you left, not even a single second passed...
...without me wondering if you're still alive.
You are alive. And I am with you. Nothing else matters.
I was waiting this night for very long.
I don't want to lose a single moment.
And without my pass from the Kaiser you'll not go that far...
- You got a pass from Kaiser?
- The Major general places his trust on you.
- Couldn't they leave us quiet on Christmas Eve?
- We always have to do the dirty work. - I volunteer to go.
I don't want trouble, Gueusselin.
Go there, approach their lines, locate theur
machineguns and return. Understood?
- And if they see me with this moonlight, can I return fire?
- Go, be discreet and come back fast if you want a hot meal.
- Hey lads. Where did you get the pipes?
From the guys of the 92nd, they learnt we're doing Christmas here.
- Any spare seat there?
Froggy Land.
- Come on Father, give us a song.
Play "I dream of my home".
Rosbif Land.
Looks like they're having fun there.
Would you like us to have fun as well?
- This is Anna Sorensen. - Good Evening.
- Are you crazy, and you brought a lady here?
- Lieutenant, I convinced the Heir...
...that a little music wouldn't do any harm.
- Good. You can start.
- Lieutenant!
Come and see. Something weird is happening.
- I don't like this lieutenant.
Could be a diversion for some dirty trick.
- Get down every one!
- Good Evening, Englishmen! - Good Evening Germans...
...but we're not English, we're Scottish.
- It was very nice, but that's enough.
This is not Berlin Opera.
- You're right. It's even better than Berlin.
- Look at that. A meeting and we're not invited!
- Shut up Ponchel. What the hell is going on here?
- Good evening. Do you speak English?
- Yes... A little. - Wonderfull!
- We were talkin about a... a cease fire...
...for Christmas Eve. What do you think?
The outcome of this war won't be decided tonight.
I don't think any one will criticise us for
leaving down our riffles on Christmas Eve.
Don't worry. It's just for tonight.
- What the hell are they doing?
- Maybe the Germans are fed up and want to surrender.
- I would be surprised...
- Ponchel, give me a bottle of champagne and my beaker.
- Merry Christmas.
- Who's the idiot who did that?
- Good Evening. I'm Anna.
- You first.
- Felix. Where have you been?
- His name is not Felix. It's Nestor.
- He's Nestor, the cat from the Delsaux farm.
- I know him better than you.
- Nestor's is going to the French side.
- My wife.
- She's a pretty girl. - Very.
- This is my wife.
- Montparnasse.
- It's my wife's favourite part in Paris. The Luxemburg gardens.
- By the way, you didn't show us a picture of your wife.
- Uhm, like you I had a photo of her but... I lost it.
I've draw her face but... that's not really the same.
- Do you live... on Rue Vavin? - Yes...?
- I think I...
I found your wallet in the trench.
I kept it because of the address.
A little hotel on Rue Vavin.
- I spent a week there with my wife, two years ago.
It was our honeymoon.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
- Hold on, thats Gueusselin's bottle.
- Who cares. He went to sleep. - I would be
surprised if he did. - Thank you... very much... sirs...
- It's good!
- How many month's pregnant was she on that photo?
- Five months.
She was in Lens, at her parents, last July.
She had complications and had to stay in bed...
I asked to stay with her, but I couldn't.
I was called to go to war, and had to leave her there.
- But... don't you write each other? How is she?
- I had no letter from her since September. They never make it here.
I don't even know if it's a boy or a girl.
Hey Scottsman. You know what I got here?
- The French gave me some champagne. Do you want to drink?
- Sing for us.
Sing for them.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- You were wonderfull.
- I'm Jewish. Christmas means nothing to me.
- But I'll never forget this night. - Thank you.
- So what will happen with the young
lady? - Yes, I wanted to ask you.
Could she spend the night in your shelter?
I mean, when is she leaving?
- Tommorow morning. - Fine.
Unfortunately, you can't stay in my shelter. I'm not alone.
There's a big rat, for 3 days now, but I'll get him in the end.
- We'll find a solution. Goodnight lieutenant.
- Don't worry miss, I'll find you a safe place. - Thanks Jorg.
- What did you put in your report to the HQ?
- Well I wrote 24th of December 1914.
- No hostilities on the german side tonight.
- Well, that's the truth.
Tonight...
these men were drawn to that altar like
it was a fire in the middle of winter.
Even those who don't believe came to warm themselves.
...maybejust to be together...
...maybe to forget about the war.
- Maybe...
...but the war won't forget us.
- No more flairs.
- Merry Christmas.
- Listen. Someone is digging out there. - Mines!
- Those damn Scotts are digging a mine sap.
- They'll fill it with explosives and blow us up.
- No, they're not digging any sap. - They do, listen to me.
- You just became too friendly with them last night.
- Yeah? Look who's talking. - Look!
- Jonathan, Jonathan come with me.
- What the hell you think you're doing? The truce is over!
Any moment now the Germans will start
shooting at you. Get back in the trench! Now!
- Get down. Down!
- Good morning lieutenant. - Good morning.
- Is it possible that we officers, talk about the dead?
- Ponchel. Bring your coffee.
- Thank you Ponchel. You can leave now.
- My men will remove the bodies of the men killed last week...
...so that you can burry them.
- And we will return the remains of your
men who fell in our land last November.
- That makes sense.
- Burrying the dead the day Christ was born. Makes sense.
- Oh. I'm fast.
- Sorry but... why do you have an alarm
go off every morning at 10 o'clock.
Is it for the changing of the guard?
- Oh no. No, it's just that lieutenant...
...who used to make coffee every day at 10 for his mother.
He is worried he'll forget all about that with the war.
We'rejust used to it.
- So are we.
- Do you need help?
- In a few days, their families, their wives...
...will receive the bad news...
It would be better not to think about it.
For them, nothing will ever be the same as it used to be.
And you too...
...one day they'll cover you and dump you in a hole.
Lets go, while there is time.
I have the pass. Holland is not that far.
- They have peace there, we can live. - I can't do that, I'll be a deserter.
- No it's not. We'll be together.
- I'm just a soldier... Like every one else...
I have duties, like every one here.
Holland is not that far. They'll get us.
Even your pass won't save us.
- There is another way.
The French borders are 100 meters
away. We only have to cross them.
- I made tea. Perhaps you'd like some.
- Come... come...
- The others asked me to give you these letters...
...they don't trust the military post.
...and as you're going back to Berlin,
...we thought... - Sure.
Come on, Moralek! Go for it!
- I heard about your wife last night...
...If you want...
...I can pass a letter to her.
- Why would you do that? If you get caught...
A letter won't stop us from winning this war!
And when we take over Paris, and everything has finished...
...you can call us for a drink in Rue Vavin.
- You don't have to invade Paris to come by for a drink.
- How many cartridges you have to shoot every day? How many?
- Eight. - Ah. Eight? And you?
- Seven. - Seven and eight. - Us, five! Doesn't surprise me!
- Yesterday, William managed to bag two Gerries...
...who'd been sniping at us for hours.
If he keeps this up, he'll qualifies the best shot in the whole platoon.
All our mates have their eyes on your cake...
...but William and I are guarding it closely.
Lots of love, from both of us.
- Still here? Why didn't they send a vehicle?
- We were waiting, but none came to get her.
- I guess the party dragged up till morning in
the headquarters and they're not awake yet.
- They called me from the HQ five minutes ago.
They told me you dissapeared.
They thought you deserted Sprink.
I told them you came with miss Sorensen...
...to sing for your comrades.
That really impressed them!
They told me to keep an eye on you till they arrive.
Miss Sorensen will return to Berlin...
...and you'll be under arrest... for two weeks...
For disobedience on the front.
- Disobedience on the front?
I don't understand lieutenant. What's the plan for tommorow?
A little football match? An aperitif with those across?
Or will you shoot them like rabbits
after you drink your champagne?
Well lieutenant?
Whats the meaning of all that? It will be more odd
if you die tommorow than if you died yesterday.
- That's enough Sprink.
- Any coffee left?
- Is The French lieutenant here? - Yes, he just arrived.
- What are you doing here? Every one back at his camp, we said.
- I know, I know but...
...our artillery will start shelling you in ten minutes.
- So I suggest you come and shelter in my trench.
- If you had been relieved, I wouldn't
have come to warn your successors.
They would have shot you before you take a step in no man's land.
Par for the course.
- Don't say a word Sprink.
- Bullseye... Sorry.
- Damn! We'll have to rebuild that!
- By the way... That letter for my wife...
- We ceased fire.
It's time for you to go back. I hope you both make it for the war.
- I don't think it's over yet. I wouldn't be surprised
if our own artillery open fire after your attack.
- Par for the course.
- This time I think we should seperate.
I'm glad I met you.
Perhars, under other circumstances...
...we could have... - Yes maybe.
Even a drink in Rue Vavin as a tourist.
- That would be..."chouette", isn't that how you call it?
- Yes. Your French are better than my German.
- Ofcourse. But your wife is German.
- Well... Good luck. - You too.
- Goodbye. - Good luck.
- Let's go boys!
- Lieutenant...
...I managed earlier to trace all their machine-guns.
It's all there.
- What are you doing here? Every one left already.
- We came to keep us as prisoners.
- Prisoners? That's impossible!
How am I going to explain your presence to my superiors?
I can't do that!
Go back to your trenches. Play time is over now!
Sir... lf we go back to the German side they will seperate us.
Put us in a prison, but let us be together.
I beg you.
- Take those two to the village.
They are prisoners. Put them in the
school till they go somewhere else.
And stay with them, We'll be there tommorow.
- Lieutenant. Can you give those
letters to the red cross? It's important.
- Where is Ponchel? I've been looking for him an hour now.
- He said he was going to eat something.
- "My dear, I cling to your memory...
...like a climber cling to his rope, so he won't fall".
- "The poor guy died between our lines."
- "Before we understand it, they scored six times!
- They later admitted that most of them
play for a Munich club called Bayern".
- "I will never forget the voice of that woman in the night..."
- "Drink with those bastards? I'd rather die."
- "The Scottish photographer promised
us photos from New year's Eve,"
- "A Bavarian gave me his address,
to visit him when the war is over."
"We'll spend New Year's eve with the germans...
We'll sing the song the Scotts taught us.
And we'll drink to the health of all those bastards
who are sitting at their warm houses, and sent us here to die".
- He's all yours now.
- You're being sent back to your parish in Scotland.
I brought you your marching orders.
- I belong with those who are in pain...
...and who have lost their faith... I belong here.
- I'm very dissapointed from you.
When you requested permission to
accompany the recruits from your parish...
I personally vouched for you.
But then... then I heard what happened...
...I prayed for you.
- I sincerely believe that our Lord Jesus Christ guided me...
...In what was the most important mass in my life.
I tried to be true to His trust...
...and carry His message to all, whoever he may be.
- Those men who listened to you on Christmas Eve...
...will very soon bitterly regret it.
Because in a few days times their regiment has to be disbanded...
...by order of his majesty, the King.
Where will those poor boys end up in the front line now.
And, what will their families think?
- Excuse me Reverence. The boys are ready.
- They're waiting for me, to preach a sermon to the soldiers...
...who are replacing those who went stray with you.
May the Lord Jesus Christ guide your steps back...
...to the straight and narrow path.
- Is that the true path of our Lord?
- You are not asking the right question.
Think about this... Are you really suitable to remain...
...among us in the house of our Lord?
Christ, our Lord, said...
"Think not that I come to bring peace.
I come not to bring peace but a sword"
The Gospel according to St. Matthew.
Well my brethrin, the sword of the Lord, is in your hands.
You are the very defenders of civilization itself.
The forces of good, against the forces of evil.
Because this war, is really...
...a crusade... a Holy war...
...to save the freedom of the world.
In truth I tell you...
...the Germans do not act like us, neither do they think like us...
...cause they are not like us...
...children of God. Are those who shell
cities populated only by civilians...
...the children of God?
Are those who advance armed...
...hiding behind women and children...
The children of God?
With God's help, we must kill the Germans...
...good or bad, young or old...
Kill every one of them...
...so it won't have to be done again.
- May the Lord be with you. - And also with you.
May God Almighty will bless you...
...the Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost. Amen!
- Every one to their posts! - Every man to his post!
- Quickly!
- What are you doing. Shoot the bloody Kraft!
What are you waiting for? Shoot him God damn it! Parties are over!
What the hell you think you playing at? Shoot him! Shoot him!
Stay down to your posts.
Shame on you Gordon... Shame on you...
- It was very stupid to die disguised as a German, right Sir?
- What the hell were you doing?
- I had a German who helped me...
I saw my mother...
We drank coffee together... Just like before...
You have a son...
Henri is his name...
- How did you let yourself...? - lf you came to preach, go now!
- Don't you realise how serious this is?
It's high treason. Punished by death.
But we can't execute 200 men. That's what saves you.
And I'm not counting all the other cases of
fraternization which reported since that.
- If public learn about this... - Noone will say it...
- I hope so... - I mean I think so...
- You think so?
- The men involved in that are not ashamed of what they've done.
If they won't tell it, it's because noone
would believe or understand 'em.
- Unbelievable! Carousing with the enemy
while part of the country is occupied.
- The country? What does the country
know of what we're suffering here?
Of what we're doing without
complaining. Let me tell you something...
...I feel closer to the Germans than to those who cry...
..."Kill the Germans!", while eating their turkey.
- That's nonsense.
- No. It's just that you're not living the same war as me.
- You and your men will rejoin the Verdun sector.
You're right about one thing.
I don't understand this war.
My Weapon was the cavallary.
You'd make a career there, like I told you.
Today, I have to fight a war where the shover outweights the rifle.
A war in which people swap addresses with
the enemy, so they can meet when it's all over.
Plus the cat we found with a note from the Germans...
"Good Luck comrades!"
I was ordered to arrest the cat for high treason...
untill further notice...
- You're a grandfather, dad...
His name is Henri.
- What are you talking about?
How did you find out?
- You wouldn't understand.
- Henri. Not bad.
Henri Audebert.
Let's try and survive this war for him, huh?
- Sit down.
In two days you'll be in East Prussia...
...to take part in an offense against the Russian army,
I hope you'll show pugnacity in the face of the enemy.
The train will cross the fatherland...
...but it won't be possible for you to see your families.
Why? I think you know why...
- Long live Kaiser Wilhelm! - Long live Kaiser!
- They're giving these to almost every one.
The movie is dedicated in the memory of the German, the Brittish...
...and the French soldiers in the front line, Christmas of 1914.