Like most living creatures,
pigeon quickly associate
to press the buton.
But when, the time recycles automatically
every 20 seconds,
the pigeon wonders:
Why did I deserve this?
And starts to move his wings,
continue to see esential
influences what happens.
We call this:
"Pigeon's superstition''
MR. NOBODY
Why did I deserve this?
How you been since
last time?
- Do I know you?
- We see each other every week.
I am Dr. Flite.
- And who are you?
- Nobody. Nemo Nobody.
It's an unusual name, right?
Sometimes people call me Mr. Craft
Craft cant remember
not a damn thing.
What was the first question
I asked you.
- I dont know.
- Can you tell me how old you are?
I am 34
I was born in 1975.
Would you mind looking at your hands?
You dont have to, if you want.
There's a mirror in front of you
What year is this?
I am 34
I was born in february 1975
So I guess it should be
your birthday
The last mortal turns  118
I am 34.
I want to wake up
I'm sick of waking up!
Dont Nemo, it hurts my eyes.
Hey friend
Good morning my little angels
Time to school
Children will go to school
Paul, be calm
- My name is not Paul
Paul?
Papi? Dady... dady...
Paul dont wake your father
- Elis
- It's me, Jean
Am I dead?
- Go go
Who is Elis?
- Dont know anyone by that name
Esras tired I must rest.
I'll go in.
The sun hurts my eyes.
- What?
This is Gigin Marshall,
live from hospital.
Where we see the last episode
of our series, "'The last mortal''
Mr. Nobody has 117 years
and has nothing.
You dont have these adorable
compatible pigs.
Live on the chain,
will last human dies
natural old-age.
Now doctor, is not found
records of identity.
Nothing about his past.
We do not know who is Mr. Nobody
No
memories remain unclear,
is not abnormal for their age
His old memories come
in great detail
let's try something new
I think of an old technique
No promises
Maybe memories
matrices become
Maybe nothing happens
Be willing to try?
This relaxed
Just listen to my voice
her eyelids grow heavy
His arms and legs
grow heavy
I'll count to three
When I say three
Be asleep
One
two
Remember the day I came here
Three
This sleeping
Remember the back
when you say three
One, two three
Remember
I can not remember much
before my birthday
And even were not born
When not born yet
know everything, everything will happen
When you get time
angels of the living
They put a finger in your mouth
That on this
Means you have forgotten everything
But forget my angel
Then you have to find
Mommy and Daddy is not easy to choose
Blond and blue ojoz
is all what I ordered
It would be nice to not be alone
It is normal for babies to choose
for women at least
And not finished yet, dear.
Not that we do not want a child
Is an important experience
I think it would help my husband
if we have a child
No george?
ultimately chose them?
because the woman smells good
and the man said
I can tell you how we met
It was fate
Give heard butterfly effect?
Once upon a time there was a
Mommy and Daddy
then they found a
cute baby
And they called Bebito
the baby came out of there
born this day
and no other
Daddy is the day
and Mommy, 7
Everything exists
We could see
I could see mom's eyes
but could not see my eyes
the baby could see his hands
But there was himself
so really there?
I really exist?
My mother taught me
choose the best
and here these
the mom brushed her hair
and lipstick
It smelled good, had his watch Daddy
put it in your arm
The clock to Tik Tok
if the baby fell
mother applauded
bravo said
Why me? and not another?
and we will have clear skies
throughout the weekend
Hello.
Why could not remember the past
but not the future?
When I preguntba Mommy
I said, stop asking why?
It's complicated
Okay, I'm a journalist
interviews allowed us
I just wanted to make a spreguntas
A friend works here
helped me get
What time is it?
14 and 12
Where can I get that?
- I give the University Museum
Even works
I have nothing to tell you
I am Mr. Nobody
a man who never existed
Remember how the world was
before crossing the immortality?
What?
- What happened
How it was when humans
were mortal?
There were cars and pollution
Smoked cigarettes
we ate lunch
We did everything we could
in this wonderful
Most of the time
nothing happened
As a French film
And sex? before
sex was obsolete?
Everyone always
was pulling
We fell in love
What time is it?
How was before the big bang?
There was before because before
from this
TIMP never existed
time is the result of
expansion of the universe itself
but what about when the Universe
stops expanding?
and the movement is back
what will be the natural time?
If string theory and correct
the universe posse
9-dimensional space
And a temporary dimension
We can imagine that in the beginning
all the universes were mixed
there during the big bang
3 spaces universes
what we know as high, down
and death
and a temporal dimension
time is
The other six remained together
And if we live in a universe
of bound
how to distinguish between
Illusion and reality?
Time as we know it is a
universe in which we experience
only in one direction
but if the universe
not space
but temporarily
If you mix the mashed ppa
and tomato
Really it's forever.
cigar smoke out of Dad
but never re-enter
We can not return
that is why it is difficult
You have to make the right choice
While not choose
anything is a possibility
Hello Nemo
- Hi Anna
- Hi Elis
Hello Nemo
- Hi Jean
We are joining this day
And Jean Lymo
The pronounced husband and wife
Anna is well
we
Then Daddy and Mommy
fought all day
Nemo And you decided?
want to come with me or
want to keep your father?
nemo!
Sorry, I do not understand
stayed with his father
or was it his mother?
Daddy, is it my fault?
- Of course not
That's my fault.
It is a very good deal
Remember
Recalls
Nemo
It is time to wake up honey
It's getting late for school
Nemo, it's me
I hope you have made
your homework
Hurry up and finish
Invite someone to dinner
tell you to stop your mouth!
How about estubo?
- Good
You've seen good departments?
- E seen a couple
Lymo not good
you see people like
Okay, no problem.
- He has the gift of making you feel uncomfortable
It's nothing
What PAOS on Saturday?
was behind his car
was whispering
He saw nothing
and suddenly the train came
the left
And he was going to crash
You're not funny
Lymo think you can predict
the future
I can
- No one can predict
No one know what will happen
- Yo si
Well if you could know that
going to get that
I knew you'd say that
Are you proud?
Why ruin systematically
all I
Do not think I have the right
to live well?
You could stay with your father
if you wanted
All I would like to present please
a new student
Her name is Anna
sit porfavo
Well, turn the page 250
You're going to swim?
We ..
- No
Come swim with my friends
Do not swim with idiots
Imbecile
What the hell did I say
not swim with idiots?
Anna
- Lyme
If
How have you been?
- I'm fine
Yeah, well
- Are your kids?
If
Well, we
See
What the hell did I say
not swim with idiots?''
You're going to swim?
Not
I can not swim
- Sorry
It's all
Please do not tell anyone
You're going to swim?
- No, I will stay here
Ok
Love
I want to introduce someone
Harry
And this is his daughter Anna
he is Lyme
Why do not you shake hands?
I can not believe
see how old they are
Sleep together?
- No
I will not end
a brother
I'd rather die
- Is your mom?
I have no idea
usually drink coffee in the morning
sometimes I can see the future
It seems that it will not happen
anything fun
Still here
The day I left
sometimes do not sleep
I ue asiq
I believe in what was
is all I have left
what she sees when she sees me? an old
you never answer your questions?
that mixes everything?
taking or dealing
milk?
That is not me
I
I have 9 years
running faster than the train
I do not feel more.
I have 15
And I'm in love
I'm in love
Lymo?
No sleeping in the studio?
No, I just saw and not there
Anna has seen your brother?
- It is not my brother
That these
Who is it?
- It's me
It's me, Dad
Your child
Claro, son
Where were you?
- In the shop.
know that work there
after school
A boy your age
should get out more
Please leave me alone, you know
I can only
It is no problem dad
I like being at home
There was a letter from your mother
I know.
I will read it then
Do not want to see her one day?
E not seen in seven years
if she wants to see me
know where to find me
I have everything I need
All is well
After three months,
and six days of travel
was going
directly to cancer
between Mars and Uranus
and five moons
Colonies had more
onboard computer
was evaluating all
Grace
We're leaving, Lymo?
Excuse me?
- Shall we go?
How did you know my name?
- We go to the same school
You never notice me
Have a girlfriend?
You're queer, or why not
have a girlfriend?
No
I do not want a
Tell me about you
Say something, we
The gravity on Mars is 0.38
is three times less
on earth
the ground is covered
waste and dust
You're amazing
Raise your hand and say I swear
- Why?
Promise me that if I die
my ashes will pull on Mars
Then there would vaiajar
months
Say you swear
I swear
We were neighbors of small
Do not you remember? Elis
In the end
I remember you
I do not know and I am not
a good person
Why do you say that?
Elis to wait!
- I'll call you
You do not know my number
What happens when we fall in love?
As a result of certain
stimuli
released several charges
endorphin
but why exactly that
woman or man
pheromone is released
corresponding
there are no physical or
one recognizes
mother's eyes
an odor that stimulates a nice souvenir
is love
part of a plan?
a plan for reproduction
Bacteria and viruses are organisms
asexual
with each cell division
they mutate
and reproduce more
faster than us
against this we respond with
the most powerful weapons
sex
mixing two individuals
their genes
And creating an individual
resisting the best virus
the more similar is
participating agencies are
between a war between
2 play modes?
All is all for today.
Hi sweetie
- Arrive too late
Okay
I love you
- I love you more
- I most
Okay
- Cheating
Well, see ya later
I always liked fish
and thought that someday
also like
This relaxed
your eyelids are heavy
Remember
Already back in an hour
Anna, cover
going to burn
I wish
We also wish
Forever.
Whatever happens
There is no life without you
No life without you
You look like my son
I am your son, Dad
My son is taller than your
Someone entered
if you could go
move my fingers
Or my eyes
Think you could listen?
Who are you?
What am I doing here?
Move your fingers
. I have to leave here
Back before
accident
I believe in one thing.
I think as you say
you love the people we love
I love you
We should not
Perdi
Why?
- You saw him at the party
He does not love me
Y?
- I love him like
I can not help
I'm in love with him
Sorry
I'm getting married Dad
And who is the lucky?
- Not that
I will marry the first
girl to dance with me tonight
Hello
On that day, make a decision
One, never leave anything
again
Two, I'd marry the girl
my bike
Three, I would be rich
four, we would have a house
a big one!
Painted yellow
with a garden
and two children, and Michael Bow
five, would have a convertible
one red
And a swimming pool
six, I will not stop until
succeed
Papi?
Do not wake your father
I, Jean
Who is Alice?
Do not know anyone named
Replay
Lymo you care?
I ask you a question
You did it on purpose?
I found this on the nightstand
Moments in life come
where everything seems blurry
elections have been taken
I can only continue
I know like the back
of my hand
I can predict any reaction
my life is a bit confused
E done everything to reach this
point and now I'm here
I'm fucking bored
The hardest thing is knowing
I'm still alive
It's my handwriting
But I do not remember
Jean?
What did you say?
A strange dream
It is important to understand
in life, things
not always
as planned
Harry and I think
that life is not always what
thought it would be
Are you talking about?
I do not understand
Well, you know
Harry and I are going to separate
Why?
They have no right!
- Please, you did your part!
Not that passes between two units
but I do not know, is sick!
You are brothers, skies
- We are not brothers!
I knew
And do not tell me
A d (onde you go?
In ten days
My father wants us to go
Wait
every Sunday, ok?
Until we meet again
lifelong
You are the first and last person
and loved it
Ten days
That makes 14.2 thousand minutes
I wish that everything now detubiera
we stay like this forever
I feel the slow breathing
time goes slow
and goes well
I remember your smell
each part of your body
Time to go
I love you
Anna!
Anna
You hear me?
You should see the future
It will be good for a new home
have a new life
We will pool
- You hate the water, not even swim
Do not know what you want
- I do not want it
So tell me what's that?
I do not want to be like you
You know nothing of my
I always liked psiscinas
When I get old I want a swimming pool
Anna
I feel that I see on every corner
Sometimes I wonder
maybe you live in the same time I
And do not know.
Maybe you're here
close
Lymo, hear my voice?
Anna
After 90 days, the computer
still keeping the system
the appropriate level
I was always fascinated by the fact
many frogs could pass
completely frozen winter
and when it was the spring
thawed and re-lived
and point
said computer
to hibernation
Welcome to Mars
I hope you have rested and
an awakening refrescamnte
And wait for the landing
will go to the first excursion
red planet
Probably the worst thing
to be on Mars
is that nothing happened there
time seemed won and empty
It seems that there was much to do
I hope there's something
I get the time.
It is time of day
The sun came out
it is different
of this morning
Not the same perfume.
his hands are soft
is Elis?
We must not
I love Stefano
Do not say anything
You're the one I love
Then count on me to Mars
I promise.
want to walk or something?
I want nothing
Nothing
I'm so horrible.
- You're not
I can not stand
- Think
you have the most incredible children
- Do not try to make me feel better
What's wrong with me?
How this mom?
- This little tired
Always tired
- Yes, always
This depressed?
- It has its ups and downs
Not you, but next time
I'll see someone else
And who is this a joke?
some?
Yo si
What is green, small
and goes up and down?
A lemon in the elevator
not funny
You'll be fine?
- Sure, this evil not because she
I can not stand it
That noise
- Something I'm going to take him down
s birthday
What kind of mother am I?
I have to get up
These partying?
puedod ecirte something '
You have to have a good party
Beautiful lights.
but your friends are not
enough dancing
and your mother must
take care!
It was a good day
The best in a long time
Ready?
- Pope Chao
Have fun.
It is not life without you
I have to get used
We talked so much if not
were there, so strange
truly speak
I need time
when we were separated at 15
I said I would never love anyone else
and never would be in contact
I could never throw out anyone
And not done anything alone
I decided that I'm alive prentendera
and this is where i was expecting
all this time
likely to see lives
but alone
with you
But I'm not used
you know
love
I'm afraid to lose you again
afraid to be without you again
I am so terrified
We need to take time
I see you again
Call me at this number
in two days
I'll wait in the cas Ablank reagent
You know why I lost Anna?
because two months before
was warming an egg
he created something in the room
are as different temperatures
and a shower two months after
other side of the world
the Brazilian did not put out his egg
I was boiling
had lost his job
factory
For six months before
boot jeans prices
As the Chinese proverb says
A single ball of snow
can clean the bamboo
Jeans production
occurs in other countries
I lost all trace of Anna
Wait for it
every day
Anna
Lymo
I'm
Everything will be fine
I had to make this dream
of a prehistoric time
I could hear the screams
the bear trap
and no longer listened to more by the
when I wake up
No Bear
but still I have fear
I'm not a bear hunter
I am an employer of machinery
Copiers
I do not live
What you do is a disaster
I would love away
the bear
and thus would have no more fear
what feeds our fears'
when we have birds in the hatchery
and put a goose
Simulated flying
newborns
stretch their necks
but if we reverse the direction
changes the focus
the response is immediate babies
put fear
no education
and no fear
to sopervivencia
but in humans
when in danger
the body responds
Turn around Nemo
Recalls
Honey, it's me
at least he died or not?
I do not understand
She says she has children
and then not
Hi dad
I'm coming in a while
Are you hungry?
- I want nothing
what will you do today?
I was thinking of taking the
opportunity to self laavr
do you have with this car?
do you mean?
Why do you care so much that car
when you leave me here alone? v
What is the car?
There will be no more problem
with self
what happens?
Why see me like that?
Why look at me so?
Nemo
I do not know Nemo
I never see
You're always somewhere else
Mr Jones
If
We have your luggage
follow me
I'll take you to the hotel where
can rest a while
the appointment is at 3pm
Daniel
Daniel Jones
Daniel Jones is his name?
Of course not
This is weird
his shoes are size
different
Not seafood
is wrong
is all
Then grew two inches
cuandio went to work
Did not feel the same way
is a different perfume
Another person
Let's begin again
Think skateboard
left
right hand
What happens?
- I dreamed Stefano
I did not care
I loved
I can not see another explanation
to be well
anything else that might be?
I loved
I know I'm crazy.
every time I wake up
I open my eyes and see your face
and begin to mourn
I realize that you
my life goes sideways
how can you be so calm?
You're not human
how can you hear that?
Do not
Not my fault, right?
You're not gonna stop, no?
I can not live without you
I hate them all
I hate you
Children
I can not go
- Is there anything I can do
Let's go swimming
I love you
And leave me
know what they say
everything is at the end
even evil
Hello
Not much at the forefront
How will it be?
$ -9 Please
Here
$ 9 please
- Here
Have a good evening
Why smoke cigarrro
never return to smoking?
Molesculas Why separate?
why never sugar
is reform?
Because the universe enters
a state of dissipation
is the principle
the tendency of the universe
develop another state
in order decresciente
the principle of entropy
is related to
arrow of time
result of the expansion
the universe
gravitational force
or is very weak energy?
at the time the universe
can happen to a contraction phase on (
the big crunch
and in that time again?
everything in reverse?
Nobody knows the answer
Please aprovehce to give
a close look at planet
so are these things?
here is cheaper
has become very expensive
Hello
Nemo I
Anna
taste
What brings you to Mars?
- I measure the distance between Mars
and land
time study
everything fails
at a time
Y?
- The crack happened in 1992
could generate some
And you?
I keep a promise
alarm alert
meteor shower
When I wake up
I wake
I wake up!
The game just
Are you okay?
When I say three
awake
One
Two
Three
Wake
Mother
- I know you?
It's me
- Chemical and want?
Henrry!
My son is here
Do not know
're crazy, go!
Mother
Hello, who is?
- Hey, who speaks?
who speaks?
Stop calling this number
- My name is Nemo Nobody
is this a joke?
- No
Operator
I want to address
from 1230512301
One moment please
12 358 street alagator
Hello Nemo
I'm glad you found me
I know it looks complicated to you
but is simpler than you think
Beware the chair is damaged
You okay?
- If
Debei have told you before
the transcript could not
the transcrpcin?
text
the conversation!
Can you hear me?
- What are you living now
is the past
at least for me
I am your
Oldest 70 years
everything that you say I said
a young man myself
I have only to remember
(on the conversation
Everything is written here
Believe
In this life, do not exist
Not because
Maybe someone knows
architect
The architect?
The child, who
wrote when I was afraid
Maybe your parents never
met
Maybe your father died
in an accident
Maybe you did not get to reach
the egg
Maybe you died in a
pre historic man
so it does not work
Do not exist
If the calculations are correct
need permenecer alive
until 2091
and die within 5 to 50 am
Sorry, did not know
it would record more
I have to submit my story
for tomorrow morning
All that said
is contradictory
It can be in one place
and another at the same time
Then we have options
of all those lives, which ...
correct?
Each of these lives.
Each path is correct
Everything could not have
been nothing but
and would have been so
meaning
Tell him hey were aliens
You're too young for that
There may be dead
and stay here
There may not exist
This life after death?
After the death
How can you be so sure
you exist?
Do not exist
Neither do I.
We only live in imagination
a 9 year old boy
We imagine a 9 year old boy
unafraid
impossible options
Run! Run!
Nemo!
Run!
You're the one I love
in chess
its called suan
when a single motion
is not to move
Come and see.
It's the same.
The child is depriving,
He doesnt need it anymore
before he was unable
to make o choice,
because he didnt want to happen.
Now I knows what was happen.
Is unable to make a choice.
Destiny
here you are.
This is the most beautiful day
of my life.
Anna... Anna...