I sure do love you.
.Good morning.
.Good morning, Mrs. MacNeil.
.How are you today?
.Fine, thank you.
It's okay, I've got it. Thanks.
.Good morning, madam.
.Good morning, Karl.
Oh, Karl, we've got rats in the attic.
You'd better get some traps.
Rats?
I'm afraid so.
But the attic is clean.
All right, then, we've got clean rats.
.No rats.
.I just heard them, Karl.
Maybe plumbing.
Yeah, or maybe rats.
Now, will you just get the traps?
Yes, I go now.
.Don't go now. The stores aren't open yet.
.I'll go see.
They're closed!
In the group over here,
I need a couple of priests, a nun....
That's exactly what we want.
Is this scene really essential? Would you
just consider if we can do without it?
Look at this damn thing.
It just doesn't make sense.
It's plain. You're a teacher of the college.
You don't want the building torn down.
.I can read, for Christ's sake!
.Well, what's wrong?
Well, why are they tearing
the building down?
Shall we summon the writer?
He's in Paris, I believe.
Hiding?
Fucking.
Scene 39: Hotel. Take four.
All right. Hustle back on in.
Is this your campus?
Let's get the Defense Department
off this campus!
It's our school!
They have no right!
I've seen enough killing in my life!
There's no reason for it anymore!
Wait a minute!
We're all concerned with human rights,
for God's sake...
...but the kids who want
to get an education have a right, too!
Don't you understand? It's against
your own principle, for God's sake!
You can't accomplish anything
by shutting kids off from their....
If you want to effect any change,
you have to do it within the system.
Okay, cut! That's a wrap.
I think I'll walk home tonight, Mike.
Here, take that and drop it by my house.
Good night, Tom.
There's not a day in my life
that I don't feel like a fraud.
I mean, priests, doctors, lawyers.
I've talked to them all.
I don't know anyone who hasn't felt that.
Hello?
In here.
.Hi. How did your day go?
.Not too bad.
It was like the Walt Disney version
of the Ho Chi Minh Story.
Other than that, it was terrific.
What have we got, anything exciting?
Also, you got an invitation.
What's this?
Dinner at the White House.
You're kidding!
ls it a big party or something?
I think it's five or six people.
Thursday? All right.
Hi, Mom.
What did you do today?
.Stuff.
.What does "stuff" mean?
Me and Sharon played a game
in the backyard.
And we had a picnic down by the river.
Mom, you should have seen it!
This man came along
on this beautiful gray horse.
Really? What kind?
Was it a mare, a gelding?
I think it was a gelding.
It was gray.
It was so beautiful.
The guy let me ride it
all around and everything.
She rode it for about half an hour.
I loved it! Mom, can't we get a horse?
.Not while we're in Washington, honey.
.Why not, Mom?
We'll see when we get home, okay?
.When could I have one?
.We'll see, Regan. We'll see.
On the party invitations,
I want to write a personal..
Regan, don't! Come back!
.All right, give it up. Give it up!
.No!
You'll be sorry!
Father?
Could you help an old altar boy?
I'm a Catholic.
Mama?
.I'm so glad to see you.
.You look good.
I'm all right.
.How's your leg?
.How about you? You are all right?
I'm fine, Mama.
Your Uncle John...
...passed by to visit me.
Really? When?
Last month.
.Is that too tight?
.No.
You have to stay off it. You can't go
up and down the stairs. Give it a rest.
Okay.
I could take you somewhere where
you'd be safe. You wouldn't be alone.
There would be people around.
You wouldn't be sitting here
listening to the radio.
You understand me?
This is my house
and I'm not going no place.
Dimmy, you worry for something?
.No, Mama.
.You are not happy?
Tell me, what is the matter?
Mama, I'm all right. I'm fine. Really, I am.
Here it comes.
There!
.Look at that!
.Do you like it?
Isn't that funny?
I better put him over here to dry, though.
He's still wet.
Hey, where did this come from?
.I found it.
.Where?
In the closet.
Have you been playing with it?
.Yep.
.Do you know how?
I'll show you.
Wait a minute. You need two.
No, you don't. I do it all the time.
Well, let's both play.
You really don't want me to play?
No, I do! Captain Howdy said no.
.Captain who?
.Captain Howdy.
Who's Captain Howdy?
You know. I make the questions
and he does the answers.
.Captain Howdy. I see.
.He's nice.
I'll bet he is.
Here, I'll show you.
Captain Howdy,
do you think my mom is pretty?
Captain Howdy, that isn't very nice.
.Maybe he's sleeping.
.You think?
Why are you reading that stuff?.
Because I like it.
It's not even a good picture of you.
.You look so mature.
.I wouldn't talk!
You wouldn't talk?
I didn't have my makeup man there.
Let me take an eyelash off your face.
No, I didn't get it.
What are we going to do on your birthday?
lsn't it nice it's on Sunday this year?
No work? What can we do?
I don't know.
What would you like to do? Got any ideas?
Let me think....
We never finished seeing all the sights
in Washington.
We didn't get to the Lee Mansion,
lots of stuff.
Shall we do that? Go sightseeing?
.If it's a nice day?
.Yeah, let's do that.
And tomorrow night,
I'll take you to a movie.
I love you!
I love you, Rags.
We'll have a good day.
You can bring Mr. Dennings, if you like.
Mr. Dennings?
Well, you know, it's okay.
Thank you very much...
...but why would I want to bring Burke
on your birthday?
Well, you like him.
Yeah, I like him. Don't you like him?
What's going on? What is this?
You're going to marry him, aren't you?
You've got to be kidding!
Me marry Burke Dennings?
Don't be silly. Of course not.
Where did you ever get an idea like that?
But you like him.
Of course I like him. I like pizzas too,
but I'm not going to marry one.
You don't like him like Daddy?
Regan, I love your daddy.
I'll always love your daddy, honey.
Burke just comes around here a lot
because...
...well, he's lonely.
He don't got nothing to do!
Well, I heard differently.
Oh, you did? What did you hear?
I don't know. I just thought.
Well, you didn't think so good.
How do you know?
Because Burke and I are just friends.
Okay? Really.
Are you ready for sleep?
Good night, honey.
It's my mother, Tom.
She's alone and I never
should have left her.
At least in New York, I'd be near her.
I'd be close to her.
I could see about a transfer, Damien.
I need reassignment, Tom. I want out
of this job. It's wrong, it's no good.
You're the best we've got.
Am I really?
It's more than psychiatry,
and you know that, Tom.
Some of their problems
come down to their faith...
...their vocation, the meaning of their lives,
and I can't cut it any more.
I need out. I'm unfit.
I think I've lost my faith, Tom.
Hello?
Yes, this is Mrs. MacNeil.
Operator, you have got to be kidding!
I have been on this line for 20 minutes!
Jesus Christ! Can you believe this?
He doesn't even call his daughter
on her birthday!
Maybe the circuit is busy.
Circuit, my ass! He doesn't give a shit!
.Why don't you let me..
.No, I've got it, Sharon. It's all right.
Don't tell me there's no answer.
It's the Hotel Excelsior in Rome!
Would you try it again, please,
and let it ring?
Hello? Yes.
No, Operator,
I've given you the number four times!
Do you take an illiteracy test
to get that job, for Christ's sake?
Don't tell me to be calm, goddamn it!
Hello
You're kidding me!
I thought I just went to bed.
What are we doing, Scene 61?
Just remind Flo about that blue belt.
What are you doing here?
My bed was shaking.
I can't get to sleep.
Goddamn it!
Jesus Christ, Karl, don't do that!
I'm very sorry, but you see? No rats.
No rats. Thanks a lot. That's terrific.
Oh, my God!
The edema affected her brain,
you understand?
She don't let no doctor come near her.
She was all the time screaming,
even talking to the radio.
You should've called me when it happened.
Regular hospital is not going
to put up with that, Dimmy.
We give her a shot and bring her here...
...until the doctors fix up her leg,
then we take her right out.
Two or three months and she's out,
good as new!
We want to see Mrs. Karras.
.Do you have an appointment?
.Yes.
.Are you a relative?
.I am her brother. He is her son.
Just a minute.
You know, it's funny.
If you weren't a priest, you'd be
a famous psychiatrist now on Park Avenue.
Your mother would be living
in a penthouse instead of there.
You go in, Dimmy. I'll wait for you outside.
You'll find Mrs. Karras on the last bed
on the left.hand side.
It's Dimmy, Mama.
Why did you do this to me, Dimmy?
Why?
Come on, I'll take you out of here.
Mama, I'm going to take you home.
Mama, everything's going to be all right.
I'm going to take you home.
.Couldn't you have put her someplace else?
.Like what?
Private hospital?
Who's got the money for that?
You?
There seems to be an alien pubic hair
in my drink.
I beg your pardon?
Never seen it before in my life. Have you?
...compared to the Gemini and Mercury
programs, which were tight for space.
We've got about 210 cubic feet,
so we can move around.
If you ever go up there again,
will you take me along?
What for?
First missionary on Mars!
Tell me, was it public relations you did
for the Gestapo or community relations?
I'm Swiss!
Yes, of course.
And you never went bowling
with Goebbels, either, I suppose.
Nazi bastard!
Over behind the church. You know where
I mean? It's a red brick wing.
What goes on there?
Who's the priest I keep seeing there?
He's there all the time. He has black hair
and he's very intense looking.
.Who's that?
.Damien Karras.
That's his office the back of Saint Mike's.
He's our psychiatric counselor.
He had a pretty rough knock last night,
poor guy. His mother passed away.
She was living by herself, and...
...l guess she was dead a couple of days
before they found her.
Cunting Hun!
Bloody, damned, butchering, Nazi pig!
Stop it! I'll kill you!
What's for dessert?
You sleeping?
Burke, your car's at the curb.
Louie's waiting. It's nice and warm.
Yes, honey. What?
Fuck it.
.Was he acting up!
.Blind is what he was.
Hi, Chris. It's a great party.
Yeah, don't stop. Keep going.
I don't need any encouragement. My idea
of heaven is a solid white nightclub...
...with me as a headliner for all eternity,
and they love me.
"Down on the eastside
of toidy.toid and toid
"That's my home sweet home! "
I think we've got a guest.
You're going to die up there.
Oh, my God, honey.
Honey, what's the matter?
I'm sorry, she's been sick.
She didn't know what she was saying.
What made you say that, Regan?
Do you know, sweetheart?
Mother?
What's wrong with me?
It's just like the doctor said.
It's nerves, and that's all.
You just take your pills
and you'll be fine. Really.
Okay?
Is it coming out, Willie?
Yes, I think so.
Mother!
Where'd you get the money
for the Chivas Regal, the poor box?
That's an insult. I've got a vow of poverty.
Where'd you get it, then?
I stole it.
I believe you.
College presidents shouldn't drink.
Tends to set a bad example.
I figure I saved him from a big temptation.
Oh, Christ!
I should have been there. I wasn't there.
There was nothing you could do.
Lie down.
Give me the butt. Come on.
.Now you think you can sleep?
.Yes.
.Are you going to steal my shoes now?
.No.
I tell fortunes by reading the creases.
Now, shut up and go to sleep.
Good night.
Stealing is a sin.
I don't want it!
Honey, it's to help you.
You fucking bastard!
Remember also, O Lord,
Thy servant, Mary Karras...
...who has gone before us...
...with the sign of faith,
and sleeps the sleep of peace.
"Lord, I am not worthy to receive you.
"But only say the Word
and I shall be healed.
"May the body of Christ bring thee
to everlasting life."
It's a symptom...
...of a type of disturbance in
the chemical.electrical activity of the brain.
In your daughter's case,
in the temporal lobe.
Up here in the lateral part of the brain.
It's rare, but it does cause
bizarre hallucinations...
...and usually just before a convulsion.
A convulsion?
The shaking of the bed.
That's doubtless due to muscular spasms.
No, no, that was no spasm.
I got on the bed.
The whole bed was thumping
and rising off the floor...
...and shaking, the whole thing!
With me on it!
Mrs. MacNeil, the problem
with your daughter is not her bed.
It's her brain.
What causes this?
Lesion in the temporal lobe.
It's a kind of seizure disorder.
Look, Doc, I really don't understand
how her whole personality could change.
In the temporal lobe, it's very common.
It is?
It can last for days, even weeks.
It isn't rare to find destructive...
...even criminal behavior.
Hey, do me a favor, will you?
Tell me something good.
Don't be alarmed. If it's a lesion,
in a way, she's fortunate.
All we have to do is remove the scar.
Regan, can you sit up and scoot over here?
A little more.
Good.
I'm just going to move you down
on the table, okay?
That's just for a short time.
You're doing fine.
Very sticky.
Now, Regan, you're going to feel
something a little cold and wet.
Now you're going to feel a little stick here.
Don't move.
Good.
You're going to feel some pressure here.
Now, don't move.
Hook up!
There's nothing there.
No vascular displacement at all.
Do you want me to run another series?
I don't think so.
I'd like you to see her again.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Chris MacNeil is on the phone.
She says it's urgent.
Have you got some time?
Dr. Klein?
Yes, I'm Dr. Klein. This is Dr. Tanney.
Things have gotten worse since I phoned.
Come upstairs.
.Is she having spasms again?
.Yes, but they're violent.
.You gave her the medication?
.Yes.
.What was that?
.Thorazine.
Before that, it was Ritalin.
Chris, doctors.
Mother, please!
Please, Mother, make him stop!
It's burning! It's burning!
Do something, Doctor. Please, help her!
Make him stop! He's trying to kill me!
Mother!
Keep away!
The sow is mine!
Fuck me!
Stay away from me!
Hold her tight!
Don't let them, Mother, please!
She's heavily sedated.
She'll probably sleep through tomorrow.
What was going on in there?
How could she fly off the bed like that?
Pathological states can induce
abnormal strength...
...accelerated motor performance.
For example...
...say a 90.pound woman sees her child
pinned under the wheel of a truck...
...runs out and lifts the wheels
a half a foot up off the ground.
You've heard the story. Same thing here.
Same principle, I mean.
So what's wrong with her?
We still think that the temporal lobe..
What are you talking about,
for Christ's sake?
Did you see her or not?
She's acting like she's fucking
out of her mind!
Psychotic, like a split personality, or....
There haven't been more
than 100 authentic cases...
...of so.called "split personality,"
Mrs. MacNeil.
Now, I know the temptation is
to leap to psychiatry...
...but any reasonable psychiatrist would
exhaust the somatic possibilities first.
So, what's next?
A pneumoencephalogram,
I would think, to pin down that lesion.
It will involve another spinal.
Oh, Christ!
What we missed in the EEG
and the arteriograms...
...could conceivably turn up there.
At least it would eliminate
certain other possibilities.
Dr. Tanney says the X.rays are negative.
In other words: normal.
Do you keep any drugs in your house?
No, of course not. Nothing like that.
Are you sure?
Of course, I'm sure.
I'd tell you.
Christ, I don't even smoke grass.
Are you planning to be home soon?
I mean to L.A.
No, l....
I'm building a new house.
My old one has been sold.
I was going to take Regan to Europe
for a while after she finished school.
Why do you ask?
I think it's time we started
looking for a psychiatrist.
Hello?
What do you mean going off
and leaving Regan by herself?.
Are you crazy? Her window's wide open!
.Didn't he tell you?
.Didn't who tell me?
What's Burke got to do with it?
Nobody was here.
When I went to get the Thorazine...
...l had him stay with her, and....
.I should have known better.
.I guess you should have!
How were the tests?
We have to start looking for a shrink.
Hi, Chuck. Come on in.
I suppose you heard.
Heard what?
You haven't heard.
Burke is dead.
He must've been drunk.
He fell from the top of the steps outside.
By the time he hit M Street,
he broke his neck.
Oh, God!
Yeah, I know.
When I touch your forehead,
open your eyes.
Are you comfortable, Regan?
Yes.
How old are you?
Twelve.
Is there someone inside you?
Sometimes.
Who is it?
I don't know.
Is it Captain Howdy?
If I ask him to tell me,
will you let him answer?
No.
Why not?
I'm afraid.
If he talks to me, I think he'll leave you.
Do you want him to leave you?
Yes.
I'm speaking to the person
inside of Regan now.
If you are there, you, too, are hypnotized...
...and must answer all my questions.
Come forward...
...and answer me now.
Are you the person inside of Regan?
Who are you?
Father Karras?
Have we met?
No, we haven't met,
but they said I could tell.
That you look like a boxer.
William F. Kinderman. Homicide.
What's this all about?
It's true. You do look like a boxer.
Like John Garfield in Body And Soul.
Exactly. John Garfield.
Do people tell you that, Father?
Do people say you look like Paul Newman?
Always.
You know this director
who was doing the film here...
...Burke Dennings?
I've seen him.
You've seen him.
You're also familiar how last week he died?
Only what I read in the papers.
Father, what do you know
on the subject of witchcraft?
From the witching end, not the hunting.
I once did a paper on it.
Really?
From the psychiatric end.
I know. I read it.
All of this desecration in the church...
...do you think this has anything to do
with witchcraft?
Maybe. Some rituals used
in the Black Mass.
And now Dennings. You read how he died?
In a fall.
Let me tell you how. Please, Father...
...confidential.
Burke Dennings, good Father...
...was found at the bottom of those steps
leading to M street...
...with his head turned completely around...
...facing backwards.
That didn't happen in the fall?
It's possible.
.Possible, however..
.Unlikely.
Exactly.
So, on the one hand,
we've got a witchcraft kind of murder...
...and on the other hand, a Black Mass.type
desecration in the church.
You think the killer
and the desecrator are the same?
Maybe somebody crazy...
...somebody with a spite
against the Church.
Some unconscious rebellion.
A sick priest, is that it?
Look, Father, this is hard for you.
Please, I understand...
...but for priests on the campus here,
you're the psychiatrist.
You'd know who was sick at the time,
who wasn't.
I mean, this kind of sickness,
you'd know that.
I don't know anyone
who fits that description.
Doctor's ethics.
If you knew, you wouldn't tell?
No, I probably wouldn't.
Not to bother you with trivia,
but a psychiatrist...
...in sunny California, no less...
...was put in jail for not telling the police
what he knew about a patient.
Is that a threat?
No, I mention it only in passing.
Incidentally, I mention it only in passing...
...l could always tell the judge
it was a matter of confession.
Father, wait a minute!
.Do you like movies?
.Very much.
Well, I get passes
to the best shows in town.
Mrs. K, you know,
she gets tired, never likes to go.
That's too bad.
I hate to go alone.
I love to talk film...
...discuss, to critique.
You want to see a film with me?
I've got passes to the Crest. It's Othello.
Who's in it?
Debbie Reynolds: Desdemona and Othello:
Groucho Marx. Are you happy?
I've seen it.
One last time. Can you think
of some priest who fits the bill?
Come on!
No, answer the question, Father Paranoia.
All right.
You know who I think really did it?
Who?
The Dominicans. Go pick on them.
I could have you deported, you know that?
I lied.
You look like Sal Mineo.
It looks like a type of disorder
that's rarely ever seen anymore...
...except in primitive cultures.
We call it "somnambular.form possession. "
Quite frankly, we really don't know
much about it at all, except that...
...it starts with a conflict or a guilt...
...and it leads to the patient's delusions
that his body has been invaded...
...by some alien intelligence:
A spirit, if you will.
Look, I'm telling you again,
and you'd better believe me...
...l am not going to lock her up
in some goddamn asylum!
And I don't care what you call it.
I'm not putting her away!
I'm sorry.
You're sorry? Jesus Christ!
88 doctors and all you can tell me,
with all your bullshit is....
Of course, there is one outside chance
for a cure.
I think of it as a shock treatment.
As I said, it's a very outside chance.
Would you just name it, for God's sake?
What is it?
.Do you have any religious beliefs?
.No.
What about your daughter?
No.
Why?
Have you ever heard of exorcism?
Well, it's a stylized ritual in which the...
...rabbi or the priest try to drive out
the so.called invading spirit.
It's been discarded these days...
...except by the Catholics, who keep it
in the closet as a sort of embarrassment.
But it has worked...
...in fact, although,
not for the reasons they think.
It's purely force of suggestion.
The victim's belief in possession...
...is what helped cause it,
so in that same way...
...the belief in the power of exorcism
can make it disappear.
You're telling me I should take
my daughter to a witch doctor.
Is that it?
Did you put this in Regan's bedroom?
She's going to be well?
Karl, if you put this in Regan's bedroom,
I want you to tell me. Now, did you?
No, not me.
I didn't.
This was under Regan's pillow.
Did you put it there?
Of course, I didn't.
I didn't put it.
Excuse me, madam.
What?
.A man to see you.
.What man?
Might your daughter remember, perhaps...
...if Mr. Dennings was in her room
that night?
Why do you ask?
Might she remember?
No, she was heavily sedated.
It's serious?
Yes, I'm afraid it is.
May I ask...?
We still don't know.
Watch out for drafts.
A draft in the fall,
when the house is hot, is...
...a magic carpet for bacteria.
Excuse me, madam. Anything else?
No, Karl, we're fine. Thank you.
It's all right.
Why are you asking all this?
It's strange.
The deceased comes to visit,
stays only 20 minutes...
...and leaves all alone a very sick girl.
And speaking plainly, Mrs. MacNeil...
...it isn't likely he would fall
from a window.
Besides, a fall wouldn't do to his neck
what we found.
Except maybe one chance in a thousand.
No. My hunch....
My opinion...
...he was killed by a very powerful man:
point one.
And the fracturing of his skull: point two...
...plus the various other things
we mentioned...
...would make it very probable...
...probable, not certain...
...that the deceased was killed and then
pushed from your daughter's window.
But nobody was in the room
except your daughter, so how can this be?
It could be one way.
If someone came calling
between the time Miss Spencer left...
...and the time you returned.
Judas Priest, just a second.
The servants? They have visitors?
Not at all.
You were expecting a package that day,
some delivery?
Not that I know of.
Groceries, cleaning...a package?
I really wouldn't know.
Karl takes care of all that.
I see.
Would you like to ask him?
No, never mind, it's...
...it's very remote.
No, never mind.
Would you like some more coffee?
Please.
That's cute.
Your daughter, she's the artist?
Thank you.
Incidentally...
...you might ask your daughter...
...if she remembers seeing Mr. Dennings
in her room that night.
Look, he wouldn't have any reason
in the world to go up to her room.
I know, I realize, but...
...if certain British doctors never asked,
"What is this fungus?"...
...we wouldn't today have penicillin.
Correct?
When she's better, I'll ask her.
It couldn't hurt.
In the meantime....
That's okay.
I really hate to ask you this, but...
...for my daughter,
could you please give an autograph?
Of course. Where's a pencil?
Right here.
She'd love it!
What's her name?
I lied. It's for me.
The spelling is on the back: Kinderman.
You know that film you made, Angel?.
I saw that six times!
Really?
It was beautiful.
Thank you.
You're a very nice lady.
.Thank you.
.You're a nice man.
I'll come back when she's feeling better.
.'Bye.
Please, no!
.Do it!
.Please, don't!
You bitch! Do it!
Please, no!
Let Jesus fuck you!
Give it! Give it to me!
Lick me! Lick me!
Mrs. MacNeil, open the door!
Do you know what she did,
your cunting daughter?
Chris MacNeil?
Please go away.
I'm Father Karras.
I'm very sorry. Hello.
I should have told you
I wouldn't be in uniform.
Yeah, that would have helped.
Have you got a cigarette, Father?
Thanks.
Cold.
How did a shrink ever get to be a priest?
It's the other way around. The Society
sent me through medical school.
Where?
Harvard, Bellevue...
...Johns Hopkins. Places like that.
.You're a friend of Father Dyer's, right?
.Yes, I am.
.Pretty close?
.Pretty close.
Did he talk to you about my party?
He sure did.
About my daughter?
No, I didn't know you had one.
.He didn't mention her?
.No.
He didn't tell you what she did?
He didn't mention her.
Priests are pretty tight.mouthed then?
That depends.
.On what?
.The priest.
I mean, what if a person...
...came to you, you know, that was
a murderer or a criminal of some kind...
...and they wanted some kind of help?
Would you have to turn them in?
Well, if he came to me for spiritual advice,
I'd say no.
.You wouldn't?
.No, I wouldn't.
But I would try to convince him
to turn himself in.
And, how do you go about
getting an exorcism?
I beg your pardon?
If a person's, you know,
possessed by a demon, or something...
...how do they get an exorcism?
First, I'd have to get them
into a time machine...
...and get them back to the 16th century.
I didn't get you.
It just doesn't happen anymore,
Mrs. MacNeil.
Oh, yes? Since when?
Since we learned about mental illness,
paranoia, schizophrenia.
All those things they taught me at Harvard.
Mrs. MacNeil,
since the day I joined the Jesuits...
...l've never met one priest
who has performed an exorcism. Not one.
Yeah, well...
...it just so happens
that somebody very close to me...
...is probably possessed.
And needs an exorcist.
Father Karras, it's my little girl.
Then that's all the more reason
to forget about exorcism.
Why? I don't understand.
To begin with, it could make things worse.
How?
Secondly, the Church,
before it approves an exorcism...
...conducts an investigation
to see if it's warranted.
That takes time.
.You could do it yourself.
.No, I couldn't.
I'd need Church approval,
and that's rarely given.
Could you see her?
Yes, I could.
I could see her as a psychiatrist..
Not a psychiatrist! She needs a priest!
She's seen every fucking psychiatrist
in the world...
...and they sent me to you!
Are you gonna send me back to them?
Jesus Christ, won't somebody help me?
You don't understand..
Can't you help her? Just help her!
It wants no straps.
Hello, Regan.
I'm a friend of your mother's.
I'd like to help you.
You might loosen these straps, then.
I'm afraid you might hurt yourself, Regan.
I'm not Regan.
I see.
Well, then, let's introduce ourselves.
I'm Damien Karras.
And I am the devil.
Now kindly undo these straps.
If you're the devil,
why not make the straps disappear?
That's much too vulgar
a display ofpower, Karras.
Where's Regan?
In here, with us.
Show me Regan
and I'll loosen one of the straps.
Could you help an old altar boy, Father?
Your mother is in here with us, Karras.
Would you like to leave a message?
I'll see that she gets it.
If that's true...
...then you must know
my mother's maiden name.
What is it?
Thank you.
Look, I'm only against the possibility
of doing her more harm than good.
Nothing you could do
could make it any worse.
I can't do it.
I need evidence that the Church
would accept as signs of possession.
Like what?
Her speaking in a language
she's never known or studied.
What else?
I don't know. I'd have to look it up.
I thought you were supposed
to be an expert.
There are no experts.
You probably know as much
about possession as most priests.
Your daughter doesn't say she's a demon.
She says she's the devil himself.
If you've seen as many psychotics
as I have, you'd realize...
...that's the same as saying
you're Napoleon Bonaparte.
You asked me what I think
is best for your daughter.
Six months under observation...
...in the best hospital you can find.
You show me Regan's double...
...same face, same voice, everything...
...and I'd know it wasn't Regan.
I'd know in my gut.
I'm telling you that that thing upstairs
isn't my daughter.
I want you to tell me
that you know for a fact...
...there's nothing wrong with my daughter
except in her mind!
Tell me you know for a fact
that an exorcism wouldn't do any good!
You tell me that!
Did Regan know a priest was coming over?
No.
Did you know my mother died recently?
Yes, I did. I'm very sorry.
Is Regan aware of it?
Not at all.
Why do you ask?
It's not important. Good night.
"He broke the bread,
and gave it to his disciples and said:
"'Take this, all of you, and eat it.
"'For this is my body.'
"When the supper was ended,
he took the cup.
"Again he gave you thanks and praise.
"He gave the cup to his disciples and said:
'Take this...
"'...all of you, and drink from it.
"'This is the cup of my blood.
"'The blood of the new and everlasting
Covenant, the mystery of faith."'
What an excellent day for an exorcism.
You'd like that?
Intensely.
But wouldn't that drive you out of Regan?
It would bring us together.
You and Regan?
You and us.
Did you do that?
Do it again.
In time.
No, now.
Mirabile dictu, don't you agree?
You speak Latin?
Ego te absolvo.
Quod nomen mihi est?
Bonjour!
La plume de ma tante.
How long are you planning
to stay in Regan?
Until she rots
and lies stinking in the earth.
What's that?
Holy water.
You keep it away!
It burns!
Oh, it burns!
Who are you?
You know, I'm like in seclusion.
No, I'm just exhausted from work.
She's, she's all right.
I don't want to talk about it, okay?
Okay, I'll talk to you.
I'll call as soon as it's over, all right?
No, I just, I'm going through something
and I just have to....
No, no....
There's nothing.
Hey, thanks a lot.
.Want a drink?
.Please.
What do you drink?
Scotch.
Ice and water.
No ice. I'll get some from the kitchen.
That's all right. I'll take it straight.
Please sit.
Where's her father?
In Europe.
.Have you told him what's happening?
.No.
Well, I think you should.
I told Regan that was holy water.
I sprinkled it on her
and she reacted very violently.
It's tap water.
What's the difference?
Holy water is blessed. And that doesn't
help support a case for possession.
She killed Burke Dennings.
What?
She pushed him out her window.
No one.
Who are you?
No one!
It's a language, all right. It's English.
What do you mean?
It's English in reverse. Listen.
Give us time.
Let her die.
I am no one. I am no one.
Fear the priest.
Merrin!
I am no one.
Merrin! Fear the priest!
Merrin!
Yeah?
I'll be right there.
I don't want Chris to see this.
What's wrong? What is it?
You're convinced that it's genuine?
I don't know.
No, not really, I suppose.
But I have made...
...a prudent judgement that it meets
the conditions set down in The Ritual.
You would want to do
the exorcism yourself?.
Yes.
It might be best to have a man
with experience.
Someone who's spent time
in the foreign missions.
I understand, Your Excellency.
Let's see who's around.
In the meantime,
I'll call you as soon as I know.
Thank you, Your Excellency.
Well, he does know the background.
I doubt there's any danger
in just having him assist.
There should be
a psychiatrist present, anyway.
What about the exorcist?
Have you any ideas?
How about Lankester Merrin?
I had a notion he was in lraq.
I read he was working
on a dig near Nineveh.
You're right, but he's finished.
He came back three or four months ago.
He's at Woodstock now.
What's he doing there, teaching?
He's working on another book.
Don't you think he's too old, Tom?
How's his health?
He must be all right.
He's still running around digging up tombs.
.Besides, he's had experience.
.I didn't know that.
Ten, 12 years ago, I think, in Africa.
The exorcism supposedly lasted months.
I heard it damn near killed him.
Father?
.You're Mrs. MacNeil?
.Yes.
I'm Father Merrin.
Come in.
Thank you.
.Is Father Karras here?
.Yes. He's here already.
It's an honor to meet you, Father.
.Are you very tired?
.No.
I'd like you to go quickly
across to the Residence...
...and gather up a cassock for myself...
...two surplices, a purple stole,
and some holy water...
...and...
...your copy of The Roman Ritual.
The large one.
I believe we should begin.
Do you want to hear the background
of the case first, Father?
Why?
Especially important is the warning
to avoid conversations with the demon.
We may ask what is relevant,
but anything beyond that is dangerous.
He's a liar. The demon is a liar.
He will lie to confuse us.
But he will also mix lies with the truth...
...to attack us.
The attack is psychological, Damien.
And powerful.
So don't listen.
Remember that. Do not listen!
It might be helpful
if I gave you some background...
...on the different personalities
Regan has manifested.
So far, I'd say there seem to be three.
.She's convinced that..
.There is only one.
Stick your cock up her ass,
you mother.fucking worthless cock sucker!
Be silent!
"Our Father, who art in Heaven...
"...Hallowed be Thy name.
"Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done...
"...on earth as it is in Heaven.
"Give us this day our daily bread.
"Forgive us our trespasses...
"...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
"And lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from the evil one."
"Save me, O God, by Thy name.
By Thy might, defend my cause.
"Proud men have risen up against me,
and men of violence seek my life...
"...but God is my helper
and the Lord sustains my life.
"In every need He has delivered me.
"Glory be to the Father, to the Son
and to the Holy Spirit.
"As it was in the beginning, is now
and ever shall be, world without end."
."Save your servant...
."...who places her trust in Thee.
"Be unto her, O Lord, a fortified tower.
"In the face of the enemy...
"...let the enemy have no power over her.
"And the Son of lniquity
be powerless to harm her."
Your mother sucks cocks in Hell, Karras!
You faithless slime!
"The Lord be with you.
."And also with you.
."Let us pray.
"Holy Lord, Almighty Father,
Everlasting God...
"...and Father of our Lord, Jesus Christ...
"...who, once and for all, consigned
that fallen tyrant to the flames of Hell...
"...who sent your only begotten Son
into the world to crush that roaring lion...
"...hasten to our call for help...
"...and snatch from ruination...
"...and from the clutches
of the Noon.Day Devil...
"...this human being,
made in Your image and likeness.
"Strike terror, Lord, into the beast...
"...now laying waste to your vineyard.
"Let Your mighty hand cast him out
of Your servant, Regan Teresa MacNeil...
"...so he may no longer hold captive
this person...
"...whom it pleased You
to make in Your image...
"...and to redeem through Your Son,
who lives and reigns with You...
"...in the Unity of the Holy Spirit,
God, forever and ever.
."Amen.
."O Lord, hear my prayer."
Father Karras.
Damien.
The response, please, Damien!
"And let my cry come unto Thee."
"Almighty Lord, Word of God the Father,
Jesus Christ...
"...God and Lord of all creation...
"...who gave to your holy apostles...
"...the power to tramp underfoot
serpents and scorpions.
"Grant me...
"...Your unworthy servant...
"...pardon for all my sins...
"...and the power to confront
this cruel demon."
"See the cross of the Lord.
Be gone, you hostile power.
"O Lord, hear my prayer.
."The Lord be with you.
."And also with you.
"I cast you out, unclean spirit! "
.Shove it up your ass, you faggot!
."In the name of our Lord, Jesus Christ!
"It is He who commands you!
"He who flung you from the heights
of Heaven to the depths of Hell! "
.Fuck him!
."Be gone...
"...from this creature of God!
"Be gone!
"In the name of the Father,
and of the Son...
"...and of the Holy Spirit.
"By this sign of the Holy Cross,
of our Lord Jesus Christ...
"...who lives and reigns
with the Father and the Holy Spirit."
Damien!
"Amen.
"God, Defender of the human race...
"...look down in pity.."
You killed your mother!
You left her alone to die!
Shut up!
She'll never forgive you!
"I command you...
"...by the Judge of the Living
and the Dead...
"...to depart from this servant of God!
"It's the power...."
Holy water!
"It's the power of Christ that compels you!
"The power of Christ compels you!
"He brought you low
by his blood.stained cross!
"Do not despise my command
because you know me to be a sinner.
"It is God himself who commands you!
"The majestic Christ who commands you!
"God, the Father, commands you!
"God, the Son, who commands you!
"God, the Holy Spirit, who commands you!
"The mystery of the Cross commands you!
"The blood of the martyrs commands you!
"Give way to Christ,
you Prince of Murderers!
"You're guilty before Almighty God.
"Guilty before His Son.
"Guilty before the whole human race.
"It is the Lord who expels you...
"...He, who is coming to judge
both the Living and the Dead...
"...and the world, by fire."
Are you tired?
Let's rest before we start again.
Will you excuse me, Damien?
Dimmy, why do you do this to me?
Please, Dimmy. I'm afraid.
You're not my mother.
Dimmy, please!
What is it?
Her heart.
Can you give her something?
She'll go into a coma.
You're not my mother!
Don't listen.
Why, Dimmy?
Damien!
Dimmy, please!
Get out.
"Our Father...
"...who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name...."
Is it over?
Is she going to die?
No.
You son of a bitch!
Take me!
Come in to me!
Goddamn you, take me!
Take me!
No!
Mother.
Did somebody fall?
He fell from the steps here!
Rags?
Do you want to make your confession?
Are you sorry...
...are you sorry for having offended God
and for all the sins of your past life?
"Ego te absolvo in nomine Patris...
"...et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti. Amen. "
Where do you want this?
.What is it?
.Phonograph.
Storage.
That's everything.
I'm going to miss you.
Same here.
Sure you won't change your mind?
I found this in her room.
You better hurry.
Come on, honey, we have to get going.
She doesn't remember any of it.
That's good.
.All done.
.Okay.
Honey, this is Father Dyer.
.Hi, Father.
.Hello.
Ready, missus.
.Good.bye, Father.
.Good.bye.
I'll call you.
'Bye, Father.
.I hope I see you again.
.I hope so, too.
Father Dyer?
I thought you'd like to keep this.
Fixed By Geniuses Group
ir_guitar@yahoo.com