But it is an ingenious solution
And a final one
No
Ali, his cousin, laid there to die for him?
Who are we fighting?
They cannot go far, all the tracks are watched
We must take to the desert
Bakka will give 100 camels to the man
who brings back Muhammad
or his head
Look for 3 of them
Muhammad, Abu Bakr and Uriqat, the Bidune guide
What is it?
These are drains of camel
Maybe two days, that from the city
Why are you here?
Medina is to the north
They made the tracks, not I
Know much? Traveling West?
I know my art
They say that you can track a bird by smelling the air
we go with him
he may be in that cave over there
Muhammad, if you come out, we will
take you to Mecca alive
Muhammad, come out
they cannot be in there
This web is unbroken
And these pigeons
they would not build
we were wrong to follow them
we should have gone north
Let's move then
we still have time to head them off
A few threads of a spider's web
was all that was then
between Muhammad and murder
But he was a man not to be killed
The Bidune guide led him
and his companion Abu Bakr in their escape
through untracked spaces of the desert
and the heat of the June days
At Medina, his followers waited with their welcome ready
but in great fear for his journey
anything? No nothing
this shows that he is only a man
no man can survive that heat
There! I see them! Look!
Run and hide! I might be obliged
to free you as a gesture
Welcome to the city of Medina, the blessed,
your city, the messenger of god
You will stay with me, messenger of god,
I have the best house in Medina
you'll give me the honor of keeping you
Stay with me!
Please! Please! Please! How can the Prophet
choose between so many welcomes?
Where God guides his camel to stop,
there he will build his house
All agreed
We turn Quaswa, his camel loose
and where Quaswa sits, the Prophet stays
Clever man!
A choice made by camel
can offend no one
Here we will build the house of the Prophet
And our first meeting place,
a prayer house
the first mosque of Islam, here!
God is great!
What's got the prophet to start doing it?
carrying bricks?
Give me that Look, you are doing too much,
please go and sit down we will do it
Look! He went for more
"Work is a worship" he says
he's 53 years old
How old are you?
There is something missing.
Maybe a bell to call people in
the Christians use a bell
what about a horn, like the Jews?
A drum?
There's too much blood in a drum
Why not the human voice
as in Omar bin Kattab's vision?
The Prophet agrees?
he means you, Bilal
me?
You have a good voice, use it!
climb up there!
Brothers, today a man of Medina
will embrace a man of Mecca
Each will share half and half,
reach out, embrace your neighbor and brother
I'm tired of the politics of kissing slaves
Read this
The prophet should concern himself with the after-world
What is my son?
Praying like a horse
does it burn your hands?
It's not upon us to burn down the house
he's making laws like a king.
He's declared that loyalty to Islam
is more than loyalty to tribal family
What?
All muslims are next of kin to one-another?
Don't be mislead by that...
They must change the nature of the tribes before that
The danger is here, the quality:
a man's neighbour is as good as himself
The Lunatic means it
Jews and Christians
have equal rights with Muslims,
the Jews who attach themselves to a common wealth
will be protected
Women have rights of inheritance... Rights
Next, he will be giving the camel rights
He has! the lunatic has!
You can't overload them
he's remaking a city, my city...
damn him..
He's taken our sons from us, he took the children, our future from us.
His rights are wrongs
no more...
This time there will not be any regret
it will take everything of value they left in Mecca
their rugs, their houses, their silver
and with it, large of caravans to Damascus
My friends, listen to me!
I have news from Mecca
everything you have left behind is gone
the Thieves! Abu Bakr's shops,
the prophet's house... sold
Every cup or piece of cloth,
every rag or bone
you ever owned is thrown on the market
You are a people of nothing.
Don't you even fight for what you own?
Who talks of the fight?
What other way is there, Hamza?
When the Prophet says Fight!,
we fight, now he says Peace!
Exactly
you are a peace loving people
up to your necks and fore bearers
go back to work!
We have to defend ourselves.
You are the Messenger of god.
Yet, they mock, abuse and plunder us and we do nothing
In the pathage of war, we are pathetic
But they are led by greed, we are
led by god and you
I know how you hate the sword, but
we have to fight
they've stolen our property, they are taking it to Damascus
right past our own door our door.
I say, by God turn back
I'm sorry I got carried away
Its pounding in my head
Please, fight them!
But look at the sun!
It's not the time of prayer
It is newly revealed by god to his messenger
Fight, but fight in the way of god
against those who fight against you
Drive them out of the places from where they drove you out,
for persecution is worse than slaughter
Fight them until persecution is no more
and religion is God,
but if they stop, let there be no more war
for god never loves the slaughters of wars
so, fight in the way of god
against those who fight against you
God is great!
These are the disciplines that the Prophet
puts upon you
you may not harm a woman, a child or any old person!
you may not harm cripples
you may not harm the man that works in the field
You may not cut down trees
Strike only at those who have expelled you
who have stolen your rights and
riched themselves with your possession!
now, to the wells of Badr
News from Medina!
Arms... Arm yourself... Arm yourself...
defend your wealth
Muhammad has come out of Medina to attack the great caravan
- How many men?
-300 Two horses
- We have more than 100 horses
How many camels?
- 17
- We will bring 117
- And wine,
20 of mine with wine..
we will make a feast of it
That is a war I'd like to fight
a war we can not lose!
ride to Abu Sufian's caravan.
tell him to turn towards Badr
We will join forces tomorrow
near sources of Beder
Wells of Badr... here
Muhammad's march... here
my charge of the caravan.... here
One day's march...
meet them at the wells
I don't like it
There is too much of Mecca on my caravan to be risked
put out the fires...
hold the camels...
We are turning west, away from the wells
away?
you can't...
You must meet them at Badr
we can bring them down like raw eggs
- If I run all night, I'll be out of
Muhammad's reach by morning
Where is your honor, Abu Sufian?
Honor?
- My honor's on the backs of my camels
Yes, I run...
Muhammad has occupied the wells
- he has moved directly into our line of march
- Abu Sufian has broken camp
He's moving west, away from Badr
- The Caravan is safe
So, there is no need to fight
not fight?
- If we fight, we will start blood feuds between brothers
between father and son, you mean
Hudaifa, your own son is with them.
He should have been with....
Mecca is greater than your family
Walid, your second son.
he is your true blood
I say: Fight! We stand in the present
and the future will look after itself
Utbah is not a coward
we will finish them tomorrow.
We fight! we fight!
are you finished?
All right! Take your positions!
Each man to his own place
Go back to your columns
move it. move back
So Muhammad's filled the wells
Now everyone will have to fight for this
we fight
Brothers! we hold the wells
we stand in the name of god and his messenger.
we wait
BATTLE OF BADR......
Send us your champions
Who are you?
we expect our peers and our equals
Come back!
my brother, Shaiba
my son Walid
and myself
Not you! Ubaida and I and Ali
Are we your equals?
There is only one God and
Muhammad is His messenger
Archers! Advance!
Archers!
Still! stretch!
stretch
Archers!
Archers back...
they are regrouping
forward!
ready
Lancers!
God is great!
Attack! God is great!
Umaya!
Bilal!
God is great!
The Prophet is seeing you!
You are not to rob or try to perish this
And if a rogue does, cut him loose.
I said, cut them loose
and give them water
and share your food, equal mouth-fulls.
And if they walk, walk beside them
Any prisoner who can teach 10 Muslims
to read will go free
Why don't they go away?
Because, they blame me Hind,
whatever it is, good or bad
I should have joined them
and drown in the wells of bitter with them
But, I saved the caravan and our future with it
The sing at me?
Why sing my father and my brother is not with me?
Do you think I need you to remind me?
Muhammad, Ali, Hamza!
With my nails, Hamza,
I will give you mesher and mesher, with my nails...
killer, cut throater, butcher
murdering beast, you slaughtered my father
Hamza! I will hunt, like a lion
I will make Hamza, my lion, my prey.
And when you are dead Hamza,
I will cut your heart out,
taste the blood, cut in pieces
I forbit this weiling.
this cannot go on
What we should do, we will do
we will call in our allies,
lead the new one against them
This time, we will prepare it.
We'll plan it
Hamza!
come to prayer...
come to victory...
God is great
There is no god only God
Is it a plague?
what kind of an upside down town have we come in to?
You could fill your pockets very nicely here
No merchant is minding his shop
God is minding the shop
where do you come from?
Yemen
did you stop in Mecca?
It is on the road
you didn't answer my question
did you stop in Mecca?
long enough to rest my camels
Camels rest better in Mecca
than anywhere in the world
Yes What is the word on the desert?
Oh... It is bad for you
they are gathering..
Each young man with a sword is on his way to Mecca
Our strength is here
Do not underestimate them.
they are summoning up their courage.
In Mecca there is music in every house
Abbisinian slave, watch him, he is good, vicious, watch him
I'll free you. give you your weight in silver,
and your height in silk
for one throw like this
So they've come at last
We'll know how many soon enough
It's a big army
3,000 men, hundreds of horses
I bet them at Badr
That was a year ago
They've come to revenge Badr
Go and get your swords!
Soldiers of Mecca!
Blood master blood
avenge the dead of Badr