Let's see what you got.
I need more runners.
I can't write the business fast enough.
You've got to see Granger.
8720. Yeah.
Yeah. Hold it a minute. Beat it, Mottola!
Mr. Granger? Chicago's on the line.
This is Combs. Why haven't you called?
Everyone else is in.
We had problems
with the law this morning.
The mayor promised
to get tough on the rackets.
He shut everybody down
for two hours to make it look good.
Nothing serious. It just puts us behind.
Been making your payoffs?
Yes! He does this every year.
There's nothing to worry about.
Finish your count and get it up here.
I don't want to be here all night.
The man's going to be real happy.
We cleared over $10,000 this week.
- We cleared $22,000 here.
- You got the whole Chicago South Side.
How do you expect my eight lousy spots
to compete with that?
They did $14,000 in Evanston,
$16,500 in Gary and $20,000 in Cicero.
Looks like you're bringing up the rear.
I just got the count.
I'll put the take on the 4:15.
We'll be waiting.
Mottola!
Take this up to Chicago on the 4:15.
They'll be waiting for it
at the clearinghouse.
And don't stop for any entertainment.
Get a cab over on Seventh.
Cut it out!
8720.
Hey, you there! Stop!
Hey, you! Stop that man!
Stop him! He's got my wallet!
Stop him! Stop that man!
He's got all of my money!
Stop him!
Goddamn nigger-lover!
I'll get you someday for this! Sucker egg!
Don't let him get away!
He's got my wallet!
He's got all my money!
- My wallet! He's got my wallet!
- We got it!
What happened?
Did he get you with the knife?
- You need a doctor. I'll call a cop.
- No, no! No cops!
- You wanted by the law?
- No, it's okay.
Are you nuts, carrying a wad like that
in this neighborhood?
Thanks. I'm obliged to you.
I've got to get going.
You ain't going nowhere on this leg.
I've got to. Got to run some slots
in West Bend for a mob here.
I got a little behind in the payoffs.
They think I've been holding out on them.
They gave me until 4:00
to come up with the cash.
If they don't get it, I'm dead.
It don't look good, Gramps.
It's almost 4:00 now.
I'll give you and your friend $100
to deliver it for me.
I don't know.
The mug that hit you is mad at me.
What if he's waiting around the corner?
He won't know you're carrying it.
You've got to help me.
I'm sorry. I'll help you get to a doctor, but
I ain't about to walk into no knife for you.
How about you? All you got to do
is put it in the door slot.
- I'll give you the whole $100.
- What makes you think you can trust him?
Butt out! I gave him back the wallet.
How far is this place?
1811 Mason. Put it in box 3-C.
You won't have no trouble.
There's $5,000 there...
...and here's $100 for you.
Okay, I'll make your drop for you.
And don't worry, you can trust me.
If those goons search you,
you won't get far carrying it there.
- What'll we do?
- You got a bag or something?
How about a handkerchief?
- Here's a handkerchief!
- Give it to me.
- Give me the money.
- Just hurry, will you?
You got any more? Better give it all to me
if you want to keep it.
They think I've been holding out.
My wife got sick and I had to pay the bill.
Stuff it down your pants here.
Like that. Got it?
Hurry, will you?
Ain't a tough guy in the world
that will frisk you there.
Thanks.
Where to?
- Which way is Mason?
- Twenty blocks south.
- Go north, Joliet Station, fast!
- Right.
What's so funny?
I just made the world's easiest $5,000!
- Come on, Luther! Come on!
- Hold on, man!
Hustle!
In here!
Man, was that beautiful!
I thought for sure he was on to us.
No, you had him all the way. All the way!
Good God! We're millionaires.
- Did you know he was that loaded?
- Hell, no!
I just cut into him. I would've settled
for pawning one of them shoes.
Oh, God!
Let's get out of here.
We'll split it up tonight.
Hiya, Marge!
- Hi, kid.
- Hi, Hooker. She's on stage.
Hi, Hooker. Getting married or something?
Get used to it, Leonard.
I'm going to look this good from now on.
- What do you say, Ed?
- Hi, Hooker.
Are you getting married or something?
For Christ's sake, did you hear that?
Harry drops four beats
in the middle of my goddamn routine!
- How long do I have to put up with that?
- Leonard, you're on.
You want to get out of here tonight?
I got some dough.
I can't. I got a 10:00 show. I need the $5.
I'll spend $50 on you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Okay.
...opens up his pants,
the duck sticks his head out.
One lady says to the other,
"See what I see?"
She says, "So what?
You've seen one, you've seen them all."
She says, "Yes, but this one
is eating my popcorn."
You see that guy Harry, he can't keep time.
Supposing there's
some Hollywood movie agent out there.
All those years of training
right down the drain.
Ain't seen you in months.
Thought you took a fall.
Just a little hard times.
Everything's jake now.
How about a ten spot on the line?
There's a lot of action there on 28th Street.
Pay you $35.
$3,000 on the red.
- $3,000?
- Are you nuts?
No, I feel lucky.
Hooker, I can't accept that.
It's too big a bet.
- There's a house limit.
- Take it.
- But Hooker here...
- Take it!
Twenty-two, black.
Tough luck, kid.
Lucky for me it came up black.
A fella could get in trouble here,
losing a bet like that.
Listen, Jimmy, can't we do it again?
Don't worry about it. There's always more
where that came from.
"Don't worry about it," he says. $3,000!
Thanks, Hooker.
Comes in here with $50
he's going to spend on me!
- Thanks for the evening.
- It's not over yet.
Next time you want to spend $50
on me, mail it.
They found Mottola drunk in a dive
in Joliet. He never got on the train.
I don't want to hear about his day.
What happened to the money?
He lost it to a couple of con artists
on his way out of the spot.
- How much?
- $11,000.
I better get on the phone to New York...
...see what the big mick
wants to do about it.
I have a pretty good idea, though.
- Doyle, can I talk to you?
- I'm busy, Floyd.
It's important. We had a little trouble
in Chicago today.
One of our runners got hit for $11,000.
What makes you think
he just didn't pocket it?
We checked his story with a tipster.
He was cleaned by two grifters.
They working for anybody?
I don't know. Could be.
We're running that down now.
Have some local people take care of them.
Nothing fancy.
We've got to discourage this kind of thing.
You follow?
Johnny Hooker!
- If you ain't a sharper in them linens!
- 'Evening, Louise.
Hey, Ma!
If I didn't know you better,
I'd swear you had some class.
Luther said you was something
to see today!
I don't know, Alva.
I got to get faster tying that bundle.
I still give them too much time to think.
Bushwah! I used to make that switch
with slower hands than you got.
'Course, the Up and Down Broadway
was my best game.
Me and Luther didn't make much on it,
but it wasn't so touchy.
Them marks can beat you up bad
when they catch you making that switch.
Come on, Leroy. We'll be late for church.
Ma, they were closing in
on Machine Gun Kelly!
Who you rooting for anyhow?
- Hey, Hooker!
- Can't help you, Leroy.
- You can't beat the house.
- Nuts!
- Since when do you go to church at night?
- Since they started late bingo.
I'll ask the Lord for some of that cash
while He's still paying off.
Luther, look in on the baby
from time to time, will you?
- You too, Louise?
- Child, yeah, got to go pray. See you.
Hey, Erie.
- Gimme! Gimme, gimme!
- There's your cut.
Guy turned out to be an oil well.
- Which way'd he go?
- Due north. He was gonna take it all.
The bastard.
He can blow his nose all the way.
There you go, Luther. Six G's.
- You're late. Where have you been?
- I had a couple of appointments.
How much did you lose?
- All of it.
- In one goddamn night?
Why are you spraying money
around like that?
- You could've been nailed!
- There were no dicks there.
But you're a con man,
and you blew it like a pimp!
- Didn't I teach you to be no pimp.
- What's eating you?
I've blown money before.
- No class grifter would've done it.
- You think my play is bad?
I think you're the best.
I wouldn't be getting out, otherwise.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm getting too old for this racket.
You hang on too long
and you start embarrassing yourself.
We just took off on the biggest score ever.
It's nothing compared to what
you could make on the big con.
But you played the big con.
You told me yourself it was some
dumb game for mama's boys and flakes.
Hell, I never played no big con.
I hung around and picked up a few things.
Ain't no rich boys gonna trust
a hungry nigger enough to be conned.
But I'll tell you...
...I've been looking for this one
all my life, Johnny.
Now I have a chance
to step out when I'm ahead.
Come on!
What would you do with yourself?
I have a brother in K.C.,
runs a freight outlet.
I can go halfsies with him.
It ain't too exciting, but it's mostly legal.
I got an old friend in Chicago
named Henry Gondorff.
I want you to look him up.
There ain't a better inside man alive.
- He'll teach you all you got to know.
- To hell with that.
I want to work with you.
I'm out, Johnny.
Yeah, sure. If that's the way you want it.
That's the way I want it.
How do you like that Coleman?
After five years.
- He knew he was holding you back.
- Yeah, but we were partners.
If it weren't for Luther,
I'd still be hustling pinball.
I don't need more than what I got.
You won't have anything
if you don't lay off the games of chance.
- There's a depression on.
- There's always a depression on.
If you saved a little,
you wouldn't have to grift.
- I like grifting.
- You could buy yourself some things.
- What?
- New clothes, a car.
I got clothes,
and I don't know how to drive.
What else do you got to sell?
Hey, Hooker! Come on, you son of a...
Hi there, Snyder.
What's the matter? Things a little slow
down at the bunco department?
Somebody lose at dominoes?
You scored blood money today,
and you need a friend.
Go find yourself a shoplifter to roll.
You got the wrong guy, pal.
I've been home with the flu all day.
- Stake out my toilet if you want.
- Keep talking!
I'll tell you what you did, smart boy.
You tied into a loaded mark
on 47th across from Maxie's.
You and Coleman played the switch
for him and blew him off to a cab on 49th.
If he hadn't been a numbers runner for
Doyle Lonnegan, it would've been perfect.
You're crazy.
I ain't stupid enough
to play for no racket's money.
Not intentionally, maybe.
That don't cut no ice with Lonnegan.
- He'll swat you like a fly.
- Yeah, well...
...I'll square it with the fixer.
Nobody can buy you a prayer
if I put the finger on you.
Now, I figure your end of the score
was at least three G's.
- I want two, no matter what it was.
- My take was only one.
Then you'll have to come up
with another $1,000 somewhere.
All right.
You're a smart egg, Hooker.
No sense getting dead over $2,000.
Relax, Erie. I'll bill you.
- I thought you blew all your money.
- I did.
I gave him counterfeit. They'll spot it
the first place he tries to spend it.
Are you crazy,
giving him counterfeit money?
Wait up! Where you going?
What the hell are you gonna do
if Snyder puts the finger on you?
- You're committing suicide, kid.
- What's the difference?
If Snyder knows, so does everybody else.
He never gets anything first.
Hey, listen to me.
Don't go back to your place tonight.
Don't go anyplace you usually go.
You hear me?
Damn! There's no answer at Luther's.
Look, you better get out of town
or something.
Lady, let go!
- Ma'am! Ma'am!
- I want my nickel back for that telephone!
No, sir. Nobody here did.
1521 North Bryant.
- Is he dead?
- I don't know. There was a big fight.
I don't know.
Somebody must've pushed him.
- Jesus!
- Luther!
God! No!
Luther!
What happened?
Who would do such a thing to you, Luther?
Come on! Let's get out of here.
Come on! If Snyder catches you here,
you're dead!
- Get out of here!
- Out of the way.
Help me! Help me!
Excuse me.
I'm looking for a guy
named Henry Gondorff.
- Do you know him?
- No.
You sure?
Beat it.
Luther Coleman sent me.
- Are you Hooker?
- Yeah.
Why didn't you say so?
We heard about Luther last night.
Come on.
I thought maybe you were a cop
or something.
It's the room in the back.
He wasn't expecting you so soon, though.
Thanks.
The great Henry Gondorff.
Turn it off!
Are you sober?
Turn it off, will you?
Glad to meet you, kid.
You're a real horse's ass.
Luther said I could learn
something from you.
I already know how to drink.
Sorry about Luther.
He was the best street worker I ever saw.
He had you down as a big-timer.
What happened?
I conned a senator from Florida
on a stock deal.
A real lop-ear. Thought he was gonna
take over General Electric.
Some chanteuse woke him, though,
and he put the feds on me.
You mean you blew it.
Luther didn't tell me you had a big mouth.
He didn't tell me you was a screw-up either.
You played any big cons since then?
I lammed around a bunch of bohunk towns,
one kick ahead of the G-men.
Would be still,
if Billie hadn't set me up here.
Don't kid yourself, friend. I still know how.
Are you going to stay for breakfast,
or do you already know how to eat?
I picked something up along the way.
Is Lonnegan after you too?
I don't know. I ain't seen anybody.
You never do, kid.
Doyle?
Yeah.
We just talked to Chicago.
They got one of the grifters last night.
A nigger.
- How about the other one?
- They're still looking for him.
- Who did Combs put on it?
- He gave it to Riley and Cole.
They staked out the other guy's place
last night, but he never showed.
They figure maybe he skipped town.
Do you want to keep after him?
You see that fella in the red sweater?
His name's Danny McCoy.
Works a few of the protection rackets
when he's waiting for something better.
Danny and I have known each other
since we were six.
Take a good look at that face, Floyd.
Because if he ever finds out
I can be beat by one lousy grifter...
...I'll have to kill him and every hood...
...who wants to muscle in
on my Chicago operation.
- You follow?
- Yes, sir.
Good lad.
You feeling all right this morning, Henry?
Yeah, fine.
You mind opening up the round
a little early today?
We got some business
coming in before hours.
- Sure.
- Check the main gearing, will you?
Man O' War started rattling yesterday
and threw a kid on its head.
Great little countess, that Billie.
She runs a spiffy house up there too.
You plan to spend
the rest of your life here?
I could do a lot worse.
Listen, am I gonna learn to play
the big con or not?
- What's your hurry?
- I want to play for Lonnegan.
You know anything about the guy?
Yeah, he croaked Luther.
Anything else I got to know?
All right.
He runs a numbers racket on the South
Side, owns a packinghouse, a few banks...
Yeah, and half the politicians
in New York and Chicago.
Not a fix in this world will cool him out
if he blows on you.
- I'll get him anyway.
- Why?
'Cause I don't know enough
about killing to kill him.
You can't do it alone, you know.
It takes some guys and money
to make them look good.
- I know lots of guys.
- It's not like playing winos.
- You can't outrun Lonnegan.
- I don't play for winos.
You've got to keep his con
after you take his money.
- He can't know you took him.
- You're scared of him.
Right down to my socks, buster.
This guy would kill a grifter...
...over a chunk of money that
wouldn't support him for two days.
You're going to go for him.
I don't want a hothead looking to get even,
coming back saying...
..."It ain't enough."
'Cause it's all we're gonna get.
Can you get a mob together?
After what happened to Luther,
I can't get more than 300 guys.
Luther said you learn fast.
I hope he's right.
Lonnegan gets most of his income
from the numbers...
...but he's putting more money
in his savings-and-loan business.
- Think he's moving out of the racket?
- No.
He owns most of the stock and it's traded.
My guess is he's just trying
to build himself a respectable image.
He came out of Five Points...
...but he's telling everybody
he was born in Forest Hills.
He knows the market, though.
I don't think we can take him
on a stocks deal.
What about the numbers?
It's run out of a packinghouse on 14th
by a guy named Combs.
Lonnegan comes out every three weeks
to check on it, but...
...he stays away from the day-to-day stuff
in case it's raided.
These are two of Combs'
favorite torpedoes: Riley and Cole.
You ever seen them?
- No.
- They're the ones who hit Luther.
They also got the numbers runner
you conned.
A guy named Mottola. Found him
in a quarry with a knife in his eye.
Lonnegan's had seven or eight people
rubbed on his way up.
His pattern is to get close to a racket boss,
learn the operation, then move in on it.
He's done it to Gorman,
O'Donnell, Buchalman.
He took the numbers from Sharkey.
All four of these guys are dead.
He's vindictive as hell, Henry.
Kills for pride. Doesn't add up
he'd let Hooker get away from him.
You see anything, kid, you let us know.
If they put you on the spot,
we got to fold the con. You got that?
Yeah. You sure it's got to be
one of these two guys?
No. They're just the only ones we know of.
Time.
Set me up five more beers,
will you, Danny?
- You the owner here?
- That's right.
Lt. Snyder, Bunco.
That's a Joliet badge, Snyder.
Don't cut much up here.
Looking for a guy on the lam
for counterfeiting.
- Thought he might be here.
- Don't think so.
I know everyone in the place.
I bounce the lamsters.
All right if I look around in here?
No, but you're welcome
to a free beer before you go.
I don't really need your permission.
I don't know what to do with this guy.
He's an Irishman who doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke and doesn't chase dames.
He's a grand knight
in the Knights of Columbus.
He only goes out to play faro.
Sometimes plays 20 hours at a time.
Just him against the house.
- Roulette, craps?
- He won't touch them.
The croupier at Gilman's says
he never plays anything he can't win.
Sports?
He likes to be seen with fighters,
but doesn't go to the fights or bet on them.
Jesus. Does he do anything
where he's not alone?
Just poker.
And he cheats.
Pretty good at it, too.
Where does he play?
The porters say he runs a braced game
on the Century Limited...
...when he comes here from New York.
$100 minimum, straight poker.
A lot of high rollers ride that train
just to play him.
That sounds good, J.J.
Which way are the rooms?
Who told you this guy was in here?
Nobody. I just know
what kind of woman he likes.
I'm gonna check all the joy houses
till I find him.
Maybe I could help you
if you tell me his name.
I doubt it. Which way are the rooms?
Right through there.
But I wouldn't go in there if I were you.
- What are you gonna do, call the cops?
- I don't have to.
You'd be busting in
on the chief of police just up the hall.
We'll play it out here.
A huge duke is too simple.
With no fix, we'll need a con
with a sure-fire blow-off.
I think we ought to play this guy
on the payoff.
It's the tightest game we got.
It's not all over the papers yet.
Lonnegan is a fast egg. He's not going
to sit still for a standard play.
What does that leave us?
We can't con the payoff to a banker.
We'll use the wire.
Haven't known a player
didn't wanna beat the ponies.
- The wire's been out of date for ten years.
- That's why he won't know it.
I'm not sure I know it.
It'll take two of us working the inside.
Any objections to Hooker as second man?
All right. We'll give Lonnegan the hook
on the train and play him here.
Do you think I can get in that poker game?
Just show up with a lot of money
and look like a sucker.
I also gotta win.
By the way, any of you guys
been passing bad money lately?
If he comes again,
stall him so I can get a look at him.
Fella named Stenner had this place
until about six months ago...
...but he had to give it up.
It doesn't look so good,
but maybe you can fix it up a little bit.
Watch your step when you come in.
There's a dip down to the left.
- How does it look, Eddie?
- It looks all right, Kid.
- It's big enough, and it's off the street.
- I don't know.
It's kind of short notice. I'm not sure
we can get it done by Saturday.
Got to. Gondorff's riding the mark down
from New York on the Century.
We'll take it. Do you manage that building
at the end of the alley?
- For 15 years.
- I'll need a corner room facing this way.
- How much a week?
- Only rents by the month.
$250 for the two of them.
- Last time I expect to see you down here.
- Never heard of the place.
It's been a while
since I stocked the wire store.
Not many mobs playing that anymore.
All we'll need is the bookie setup for now.
I'll rent you everything
I got in the warehouse for $2,000.
That'll give you phones, cages,
blackboards and ticker gear.
If you want a counter and bar,
that's another $1,000.
- That's pretty steep, Benny.
- Gondorff's still a hot item.
- Where would I be if he gets hit?
- Just give us what you can.
We'll send a truck.
How do you want to work this?
Flat rate or percentage?
- Who's the mark?
- Doyle Lonnegan.
Flat rate.
The guy in the black hat with the gimp.
He's not as tough as he thinks.
Neither are we.
- Mr. Shaw?
- Right.
You wanted to see me?
I hear there's a friendly poker game
on this train. Know about it?
- A little.
- Thank you, sir.
- Can you get me in that game?
- I don't know.
There's usually a waiting list.
That'll get you first alternate, sir.
I'll see what I can do.
Twist!
- Patty, me boy! How are you?
- How are you, Twist?
Champ, you're looking like a million!
Good to see you!
Goldie, you old son of a gun.
I saw the Kid in Denver.
He says to say hello to you.
Joiner, are you still working those shapes?
Any number you want, Twist!
- Good to see you again.
- Okay, Lacey. Good to see you.
- It's good to see you.
- Dukey, how are you?
Come on in.
- When did you get back in town?
- A couple of days ago.
You heard about Luther Coleman,
didn't you?
Yes. The boys were passing the hat
for Alva and the kids.
- I never seen the guys so worked up.
- Don't worry about it, Dukey.
We're gonna send
a little calling card of our own.
Gondorff is setting up a wire store.
I'll need a 20-man boost right away.
I got plenty of talent out there tonight.
Take your pick. Lace!
This is a tough one.
These boys have got to be the quill.
Get me the sheet. Let's see who's in town.
Patty, give me the sheet.
Sure.
Gondorff's already on...
Twist, you know this guy?
No, I never saw him before.
He's a dick, though.
Hello, Snyder.
- What are you doing up here?
- I'm on vacation.
You seen that friend of yours lately?
No, no. He packed it in.
Enrolled in detective school.
If you see him...
...you tell him he better pay up
before I get to him.
That son of a bitch.
Thanks, Lace.
Let's see what we got here.
Horse Face Lee, Slim Miller...
...Suitcase Murphy and the Big Alabama
are in from New Orleans.
Crying Jonesy and the Boone Kid
from Denver.
Dippy Burke and Limehouse Chappie
from New York.
These and the guys outside should
give you 30 or more to choose from.
Good, Dukey.
Have them down at Stenner's
old pool hall before 6:00.
- We'll run the route tonight.
- Okay, Twist, but...
...if this thing blows up, remember,
I can't do you no good downtown.
Gondorff is federal.
Dukey, if this thing blows up...
...the feds will be the least
of our problems.
Yeah?
- You in?
- Yeah, I think so.
I gave the kayducer a C-note.
Did you find out the deck?
He usually plays with a Tallyho Fan
or a Tallyho Circle.
I got you one of each.
He likes to cold-deck low, eights or nines.
That's nice work, J.J. Here.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't mention it, ma'am.
She picked him clean. He never missed it.
My God, it looks like
he's expecting a big night.
Must be $15,000-$20,000 here.
- He's waiting for you in the card room.
- Let him wait.
Just worry about your end, kid.
If we ever get to it.
Excuse me.
You sure you checked this guy out?
He seemed like a pleasant man,
a lot of cash on him.
$200 suit, expensive luggage.
I'll vouch for him.
- Why isn't he here then?
- Don't worry. He'll be here.
All right.
What're you doing?
Always drink gin with a mark, kid.
He can't tell if you cut it.
- $2,000 for you, Mr. Clayton.
- Thank you.
All right, gentlemen.
Should we not wait for him?
- Let's go.
- I think that's a good idea.
Mr. Clemens, give me the cards.
Sorry I'm late, guys. I was taking a crap.
The name's Shaw.
Mr. Shaw, meet Mr. Jameson
from Chicago.
Mr. Lombard from Philadelphia.
- And Mr. Lonnegan from New York.
- Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Clayton, Pittsburgh.
Any of you guys want to make a little book
in Chicago, I'm the guy to see.
Game is straight poker...
...$100 minimum, table stakes.
Mr. Shaw, this is a gentleman's game.
We assume you're all good for your debts.
- How much would you like, Mr. Shaw?
- I'll start with $5,000.
We usually require a tie at this table.
If you don't have one, we can get you one.
Hey, that'd be real nice of you,
Mr. Lonneman.
Lonnegan.
Name's Curly Jackson.
Worked for Gad Bryan out of Baldwin.
Jackson?
Jackson, Jackson. Oh, yeah.
Ever play the wire, Curly?
Roped for it long ago. I can shill,
mark board, anything you want.
I don't run with riffraff,
and I only drink on weekends.
Me specialty's an Englishman.
We got a rack of suits over there.
Pick yourself a nice tweed one.
That's all right. I've got all my own stuff.
Doyle?
One.
Bill?
I'll take one.
- Shaw?
- Three.
And the dealer will take one.
Bet $500.
I'll call.
Call and raise.
- $300.
- I'm out.
Fold.
Your three...
...and raise...
...$500.
That's eight to me.
Call.
Jacks on top.
Beats me.
Three tens.
Tough luck, Lonnihan.
That's what you get for playing
with your head up your ass.
Couple more like that
and we can all go to bed early.
The name's Lonnegan. Doyle Lonnegan.
You'll remember that,
or you'll get yourself another game.
You follow?
Bring it right up here!
Eddie, we brought you a tap
into Moe Anenberg's wire.
You'll get race results, odds,
scratches, pole positions, everything.
And just as fast
as Western Union gets them.
- Does J.J. know how to use that thing?
- All he's got to do is read.
The name is Joe Erie.
Joe Erie.
- You played for any particular mobs?
- No.
- You ever play the wire before, Erie?
I never played no big con before, but...
...Luther Coleman was a friend of mine,
and I thought maybe...
...there'd be something I could do.
You got that nose
in Duke Boudreau's tonight?
Yeah.
You got moxie, Erie. Get yourself a suit.
Thanks.
I'll bet three.
Call and raise $200.
Call.
- No.
- I'm out.
Call.
Aces over.
Three cowboys.
All red, queen high.
- Well, that finishes me.
- Don't worry about it, pal.
They wouldn't have let you in
if you weren't a chump!
Lombard'll be joining you in a few minutes.
I've had enough of this game
and quite enough of this company.
Check me out, Clemens.
I guess that just leaves the three of us.
Yes, Mr. Shaw. That just leaves us three.
Mr. Clayton, I think we should
take a break for five minutes.
Tempers seem to be running a little high.
Come on, Linneman,
I was just starting to do good.
- Stack me a cooler.
- We'll be in the station in an hour.
The others are the losers.
You're still okay.
Fix me a deck. Threes and nines.
I'll cut it in on Clayton's deal.
What do you want Clayton to get?
Nothing. I want him out of there early.
I'll bust that bastard bookie in one play.
$400 to you, Mr. Jameson. You're even.
It just wasn't my night.
I need it.
- You know what time we get in?
- No, I don't.
Hey, where's your ante?
Every time I had anything,
he stayed in front of me.
$500.
Your five. $1,000.
I'll fold.
I'll play.
Cards?
Two.
Three.
$500.
Your $500 and $1,000.
Your $1,000. I'll raise you $2,000.
Your $2,000.
Mr. Clemens...
...give me $10,000 more.
I'll call.
Four nines.
Four jacks.
You owe me $15,000, pal.
Must've left my wallet in my room.
Don't hand me any of that crap!
When you come to a game,
you bring your money!
How do I know you won't take a powder?
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll send a boy to your room
in five minutes.
Better have the money or it'll be
all around Chicago that you welched.
You won't be able to get a game of jacks!
Cash me in for the rest of these bums.
You're on, kid.
But I tell you, it's a hard act to follow.
- How did it go?
- We got working money.
- He's steaming.
- Yeah.
Watch yourself.
Doyle, I know I gave him four threes!
He had to make a switch!
We can't let him get away with it.
What was I supposed to do?
Call him for cheating better than me?
Name's Kelly. Shaw sent me.
Your boss is quite a card player, Mr. Kelly.
How does he do it?
He cheats.
In that case, I'll keep my money,
and we'll have another game.
You don't have any to keep.
Here's your wallet.
He hired a dame to take it from you.
He's been planning
to beat your game for months.
He's been waiting for you to cheat him
so he could clip you.
Who do you think you're talking to?
Nobody sets me up!
Take him back to the baggage room!
Put one in his ear!
There were four witnesses at that table!
Then get that other son of a bitch
and dump them in the first tunnel.
We'll be in the station in a few minutes!
It ain't gonna look too good
killing a guy you owe money to.
There's better ways of taking him down.
What do you think Shaw would do to me
if he knew I was telling you this?
Okay.
Why the rat?
I want to take over his operation,
and I need you to help me break him.
- Where's my money?
- Shaw's got it.
How the hell could I ask him for it back?
We're pulling in.
I'm giving you a lift home.
- I was supposed to go with Shaw.
- Explain it to him somehow.
- But he's expecting me.
- I'm giving you a lift home.
You follow?
Yeah, sure. Sure thing.
- Why do you think you can beat him?
- I've been planning this for two years.
I know his organization
backwards and forwards.
I need somebody who's respectable
but not legit.
I'm a banker. That's legit in this state.
Just put down a bet for me
at Shaw's place.
I'll do the rest. I'll supply the money.
I'll supply the information.
What about the money
you come to collect?
I'll tell him you paid it.
I keep his books. He trusts me.
If you help me, I'll pay back the money
he stole out of my own pocket.
- It's worth that much to you?
- Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Maybe a couple of million.
Where do you come from, Kelly?
From the east side of New York.
A place called Five Points.
- But I got out of there.
- Out and up, huh?
I'll have to keep you away from this guy.
You're liable to get ideas.
I'll be at Klein's Drug Store...
...660 South Marshall at 1:30,
if you're interested.
If I'm not there by 1:45, I'm not coming.
Hey, Hooker, how did it go?
Jake.
- Everything go okay?
- Yeah, sure. Hell, easy.
- No sign of trouble?
- No.
- What about Lonnegan?
- I gave him the breakdown.
- And?
- He's good. He threatened to kill me.
If they don't do that,
you know you're not getting to them.
Hello, Doyle.
All right, Riley, what the hell happened?
We missed him.
Whoever he is, he made a fool out of you.
There was no way he could've known
we was in that room.
- Somebody must've wised him up.
- What does Cole say about that?
- I don't know. He took it hard.
- Get out of here, Riley.
Put Salino onto it.
Salino? Why waste our best people
on a small-time job?
This is a nickel-and-dime grifter
we're after.
- They'll get him.
- They had their chance.
All they did was shoot up a neighborhood,
wake up a few cops.
- But that was...
- I told you to put Salino onto it.
It may take a little more time,
but there won't be any holes.
Tell Cole I wanna see him
when he comes in.
He won't be coming in,
not to get bounced off a job, anyway.
This is Salino's job, Vince.
Cole wants to muscle in,
that's his business.
He's breaking the rules
and Salino won't like it.
Now, get me the books.
Those odds on the third race are wrong.
Just a minute. I'll get them.
Don't worry so much.
You're gonna be all right.
Just stay to the back the first time around.
Put a little of this on your nose.
Kelly?
You should always look to the back, kid.
I was afraid you wouldn't show.
We don't have much time.
Get on with it, then.
Sometime after 2:00...
...a guy's gonna call on that phone
and give you the name of a horse.
All you got to do
is take this $2,000 across the street...
...to Shaw's place, and bet it on that pony.
There's nothing to it.
Don't take too much time. We've only got
four minutes after you get the call.
You'll not break him with a $2,000 bet.
This is just a test.
The big one comes later.
Be careful with that. That's all I got.
You were gonna pay me back
out of your own pocket?
I am.
After the race.
I got to get back before Shaw misses me.
Good luck.
Yeah? Go ahead.
The horse is Blue Note to win.
- Fourth race at Narragansett.
- Got it.
Yeah?
Blue Note to win in the fourth race
at Narragansett.
Turning for home,
it's Lady Scout by a length.
Speed Queen a half,
Lady Trust and Miss Petrina.
Into the stretch, it's Lady Scout ahead,
Speed Queen a half.
And at the wire,
it's Speed Queen the winner!
Lady Scout placed
and Miss Petrina showed.
Post numbers two, five and one.
Taking off at 23.
Look at that.
He's got his apes with him.
We'll have to do something about that.
Bubblesome is 10, Beefsteak, 7...
...Vote Boy, 6, Kerry Patch, 12.
Blue Note is 7-1.
This is your last call
for the third race at Lincoln Fields.
They're going to the post.
- You may still wager if you hurry.
- There he goes.
At Detroit, the winner,
Speed Queen, paid $7.20...
...$4.60 and $3.40.
Lady Scout, $7 and $4.20.
Miss Petrina paid $4.
Last flash at Narragansett.
Lady Higloss, 6-5.
I'd think you'd get tired of losing, Harrigan.
Thank you, Mr. Williams.
Blue Note, $2,000 to win fourth race,
Narragansett.
Make sure you see the cash, Eddie.
He's got a name for betting money
he doesn't have.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Arnold Rowe,
your caller for the fourth race.
The mile and one-sixteenth handicap
at Narragansett Park, Rhode Island.
$13,000 added for 3-year-olds and up.
The flag is up, and they're off and running.
It's Bubblesome going to the front,
followed by Lady Higloss...
...Vote Boy, Chancing,
Beefsteak, Kerry Patch...
...and Blue Note trails the field.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Bubblesome ahead...
...Chancing a half, Lady Higloss by one...
...followed by Vote Boy, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Into the second turn,
it's Chancing by a length.
Lady Higloss driving
on the rail and Vote Boy.
Then Bubblesome, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Come on, Chancing!
Lady Higloss a half, Vote Boy by one.
Lady Higloss is a hell of a finisher.
Chancing's gonna have to open up.
Know anything about a horse
named Blue Note?
He never done much. Probably in there
just to round out the field.
Chancing's where you
want to have your money.
- Great tip you handed me, kid.
- Just give him time.
Chancing by one.
And here's Blue Note,
driving on the outside!
- Nice work, Erie. He loves you.
- He's third!
Chancing is shortening stride,
and now it's Lady Higloss and Blue Note.
They're head to head.
They're neck to neck.
It's Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
And Blue Note wins it by a nose!
Lady Higloss is second by three,
and Chancing is third by one.
Who in the blazes is Blue Note?
The winner, Blue Note,
paid $16, $9.40 and $6.
So you want to have your money
on Chancing?
Chancing paid $3.80.
Time for the mile and one-sixteenth.
They're going to the gate at Belmont.
And here are the late odds.
Those garbage men belong to you?
Get them out of here and don't
bring them back. This is a class joint.
Hey, you!
- Kelly!
- Yes, sir?
Run those bums out of here.
- Mr. Shaw, could I...
- Don't give me any of your lip, kid.
Now, run them out of here.
Time for the three-quarter mile: 1:11.4.
The winner, Panic Relief,
paid $12.40, $8.20 and $5.
Barbara A, $6.20 and $4.
Wilder paid $4.
They're at the post at Belmont at 38.
We're waiting on one.
I'll call Belmont next.
That's it, fellas!
- I want to repeat that...
- All right, J.J.
What do you say, pal?
Yeah?
He's on his way.
Hi, Mutt.
Say, Jeff.
- What'd I tell you?
- You got lucky once. That's not enough.
Lucky, hell. I can do it every time.
- Why don't you then?
- It's better to do it all at once.
We're gonna put down $400,000 next week.
At 5-1 odds, that's $2 million.
- Twenty percent is yours.
- Got a system, Kelly?
No. You can still lose with a system.
You're past-posting, aren't you?
Could be.
How?
You're gonna stay in?
Not until I get some answers.
I got a partner downtown.
He runs the central office
of the Western Union.
Race results from
all over the country come in...
...and go across his desk to the bookies.
All he does is hold them up until he can
call us to get a bet down on the winner.
Then he releases the results
to the bookies.
We clean up on a race
that's already been run. You can't miss.
Unless the Western Union dicks
get ahold of it.
You got the $400,000 yet?
No, not yet, but...
- There's only $1,000 here.
- Make another bet tomorrow.
Where's my money?
- I got $16,000 coming.
- You owe me $15,000 already.
If your setup's as good as you say,
there's plenty more to come.
- I decide when to place the bets!
- Not if you want me to keep making them.
I must talk to my partner.
We can't afford to expose too much.
- I'll talk to him myself.
- No!
You've been waiting a long time for this.
Don't ruin it for yourself.
I'll pick you up tomorrow at 3:00.
You follow?
I told him the tale, but he didn't go for it.
He wants to see my partner
tomorrow at 3:00.
- 3:00?
- Yeah.
We can't get a telegraph store set up.
Can we talk him out of it?
No. I would've stalled him,
but I didn't have any help.
We'll have to play him on the fly.
I'll put Eddie to work.
- Let me know when you got something.
- Sure thing, tootsie.
All right, Hooker!
Stop him!
Hooker! Hooker!
I'll get you, you rat!
Why didn't you tell me
about Snyder before?
- I thought I'd lost him.
- You found him again.
We'll have to do something about it.
- What else haven't you been telling me?
- Nothing. That's all.
Hold still.
Why did you move out of your room?
It was too noisy.
You can't play your friends like marks.
You know how easy it would be
for Lonnegan's guys to get you?
All we need is a couple of days...
...and we can nail the son of a bitch.
You just won't learn, will you?
I come in here, teach you stuff
that maybe five guys in the world know.
Stuff most grifters couldn't do.
- All you want to do is run down a bullet.
- I'm asking a couple of days.
I can stay clear that long!
Christ, they'll probably miss you
and hit me.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What will you have?
- Give me the blue plate special.
- One blue plate special.
- You're done?
- Yeah.
- Guess I should've had the meat loaf.
- It isn't any better.
- Hey, where's June?
- She quit.
I'm filling in for her a couple of days
until I can get a train out of here.
Yeah? Where are you going?
I don't know.
Depends on what train I get on.
- Keep it.
- Thanks.
Let's go.
Excuse me, ma'am,
but we're looking for Mr...
Mr. Harmont's office.
- Mr. Harmon?
- Yeah.
Got a work order for a painting job.
- For Mr. Harmon's office?
- That's right.
Well, hold on. Just a second.
- Where to?
- 110 South Wabash.
110 South Wabash. Get going.
What happened to your face?
Got into a fight with a raggle
down on 13th.
Cut me with her ring.
You ought to lay off the skirts.
You don't find any of my boys
messing around with that kind of trash.
Brigham signed it, all right.
I can't understand why he didn't tell me.
He's like all them supervisors.
They think they're too good
for regular people.
He says he was here
and the place was a mess.
We'll hurry so we don't keep you
out too long.
Why can't I work with you in here?
We got to cover the floor and the furniture,
so we don't spill.
If you want to sit in here with a tarp
over your head, go ahead.
How long will you be?
An hour or two at the most.
It's a small job.
We'll go in the side door here.
Hiya, Les.
Les, this is Doyle Lonnegan.
- Mr. Lonnegan, this is Les Harmon.
- How do you do?
What did you bring him here for?
I thought that he should see the operation.
I'm having the place painted.
We can't talk in here now.
We'll have to find someplace else.
Excuse me, Mr. Lonnegan.
Miss Barnes, I'm going home a little early.
If there are any calls, tell them
they can reach me here tomorrow morning.
Mr. Lonnegan?
I want to see it one more time.
I can't do it.
We got telegraph inspectors everywhere.
One more time won't make a difference.
We got $400,000
coming in from the coast next week.
You gonna risk that on a lousy 15 G's?
If it works again tomorrow,
I'll finance the whole thing.
$500,000. 60-40, we split.
We've already got a guy.
He's gonna give us half.
- What am I supposed to say to him?
- Say to him what you want.
Knowing your operation, if I were you...
...I'd be worried about making me happy.
Your guy says a week.
How do we know it won't be a month?
Lonnegan's a banker. He can get
the money without any questions.
We can't keep going into Shaw's
and cleaning up on long shots.
- He's bound to get wise.
- All right. We'll go for short odds.
You follow?
Are you Lt. William Snyder?
I don't know. What's up?
FBI.
Special Agent Polk would like
a few words with you.
You got a couple of minutes?
Yeah, sure.
No. It's got to be south of the river.
Probably this section in here.
31st, 39th, Morgan and Halsted.
Now, that's this section here.
Now, let's break it
into two sections along 35th.
What the hell is this? I got work to do.
Sit down and shut up, will you?
Try not to live up to all my expectations.
Take two men along. Work your way south
from 31st to 35th, Morgan and Halsted.
Go into every place
and let me know what you find.
We've been told, you know a hustle artist
named Johnny Hooker.
- Do you know him?
- Yeah, but I don't know where he is.
Well, we do. He's chumming around
with a big C named Henry Gondorff.
Ring any bells?
Every bunco man in the country
knows Gondorff.
Well, there's word he's gonna run a con
on the South Side here.
We've got a Florida warrant on him,
but it's a thin beef.
He can beat it in court
unless we catch him cold.
All we want you to do
is pick up Hooker for us.
Why don't you pick him up yourself?
If word gets out the feds are in on it,
Gondorff will fold up the whole thing.
Wouldn't that be too bad?
Then you'd have to move out
of this nice office you've got here.
Don't crack wise with me, flatfoot.
I spent too much time in dumps like this
eating Gondorff's dust...
...while you guys in the bunco squads
get rich tipping him off!
That's not gonna happen this time.
We're not gonna tell the police we're here.
You keep your mouth shut and do a job,
there'll be reward bucks in it for you.
And you better take it, 'cause
I can make you work for us without it.
What the hell good is Hooker to you?
He's gonna set up Gondorff for us.
- He'll never do it.
- I think he will.
He's there. Let's get on it.
What's the line on Exponent?
5-1.
- How's it going?
- Nothing yet.
I had a good one on the lead
at Lincoln Fields, but he faded.
Best we had the last hour was Love Potion
at Rockingham and she was 5-1.
All the long shots coming in today.
Take 4-1 if you have to.
Okay.
You can forget the boodle, Eddie.
He could hit us for $15,000 at 4-1.
We can't handle that.
- Give him the shutout.
- Okay.
Okay, Billie, here we go.
At the wire, it's Wrecking Crew,
the winner by five.
Black Mischief, second. Whichaway, third.
Wrecking Crew was 3-1. That's our boy.
Henry?
Here we go. We got a 3-1 at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew.
- Yeah?
- In the sixth race at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew to win,
Black Mischief to place...
...Whichaway to show.
Wait here.
The winner, Time to Go, paid $7...
...$5.40 and $3.80.
Joy Flag, $6 and $4.20.
Readily paid $3.80 to show.
The weather's threatening, but the track
is fast in Salem, New Hampshire.
Here's a late jockey change
there in the fifth at Rockingham.
R.C. Stark will ride Itsie-Bitsie.
$5,000 on Black Mischief, across the board.
The sixth at Belmont.
Would you hurry up there, please?
Wrecking Crew is 3-1, Vale of Tears, 4...
...Black Mischief, 5, Whichaway, 6...
...Chief Yeoman, 12, Peerless Pal is 20...
...and Mariato is 40.
And here we go for the sixth at Belmont.
It's five and a half furlongs.
They're at the post.
- Now.
- The flag is up.
- They're off!
- Belmont, $15,000.
Excuse me, sir. We can't take any bets
once the race is started.
You can bet on another race if you care to.
Going into the backstretch,
it's Wrecking Crew by two.
Whichaway a half, Black Mischief
and Vale of Tears riding on the outside.
- Nothing, thank you.
- What happened?
I didn't get the bet down in time.
Jesus!
Heading for home, it's Wrecking Crew
all alone by six lengths...
...Whichaway a length, and Vale of Tears.
It's Wrecking Crew,
Whichaway and Black Mischief.
And at the wire,
Wrecking Crew wins it by six lengths.
Black Mischief is second by a head...
...Whichaway is third,
followed by Vale of Tears.
You should've had your money
on Wrecking Crew.
It's raining and the track is sloppy
at Riverside Park.
There's a late scratch there.
Transmutate is scratched
in the fifth at Riverside.
At Belmont, the winner, Wrecking Crew...
...paid $6, $4.20 and $2.80.
Black Mischief, $4.60 and $3.20.
I'll have $500,000 here
by post time tomorrow.
Lay it on a race
where the odds are 4-1 or better.
- Make sure I get to the window.
- How am I gonna do that?
I don't know.
Figure it out for yourself, Kelly.
Finished?
Yeah. Meat loaf, apple pie
and a cup of coffee.
- Say, what time you get off work here?
- 2:00 a.m.
- Yeah? Doing anything tonight?
- Yeah. Sleeping.
Eighty-five.
- Is there a back door?
- What's wrong with the front?
There's a guy out there I don't need to see.
Don't look around.
- What does he want?
- He'd like to kill me.
Do me a favor. Go into the bathroom,
open the window and wait there.
Do what I tell you,
and everything will be jake.
Please.
Thanks. Good night.
It's taken.
Thanks. See you.
Shit.
Salino. Hey, I wasn't...
Hey! Got you, Hooker!
- Hey there, Snyder. Long time no see.
- Get going!
Chuck...
...get this to the Department right away.
- Yes, sir.
Hello, Hooker. Take them off.
Special Agent Polk, FBI.
Have a chair.
- You want a drink or something?
- No.
We want to talk to you
about Henry Gondorff.
Yeah? I don't think I know him.
Give yourself a couple of seconds.
You wouldn't want to lie to me.
Lt. Snyder says you've done
lots of confidence work in his town.
Oh, yeah? Lt. Snyder doesn't know shit.
- You ain't got nothing on me.
- Yeah?
How about counterfeiting?
We've got a tip that Gondorff
is gonna run a con on the South Side here.
All you've got to do is tell us
when he's gonna play his chump.
We come in at the sting,
make the pinch, and...
...you walk out free as a bird.
No.
You want to spend the next 20 years
in a federal penitentiary, starting tonight?
I'll make parole.
Like hell. You won't even get a review.
I'll chance it.
Okay. If that's the way you want it.
We might provide you with
a little company on your way up the river.
That wife of Luther Coleman's.
What was her name?
- Alva.
That's it. Alva Coleman.
Pretty fair grifter in her time.
Snyder's given us quite a folder on her.
Nothing major by itself, but...
...put them all together,
it could add up to a lot of years.
- You stink, mister.
- Don't be a sap.
It's not her I want.
If you're too dumb to save yourself, there's
no sense dragging her down with you.
It's over, Hooker.
You can save me a lot of trouble.
But I'm gonna get Henry Gondorff
whether you help me out or not.
- You'll wait till the chump is played?
- Hell, yes.
We don't care about the mark.
He deserves it.
I mean completely played. You come in
before we beat him, and I'll kill him.
All right, Hooker.
But you try to take it on the lam,
and we'll shoot you down on sight.
As long as I get to finish the play.
What is it, kid? You're not saying much.
- Just got the jumps.
- Come in.
Things are a little slow.
I want to open the round for the girls.
Sure.
Take it easy.
We're not gonna lose him now.
We had him ten years ago
when he decided to be somebody.
Believe me,
I've seen enough to know. Ten.
- Twenty.
- Thirty.
- Go.
- Thirty-one.
How many guys you conned
in your life, Henry?
I don't know, 200, 300.
Sometimes we played two a day
when I was with O'Shea's mob.
Of course, Chicago was a rigged town.
The fix was in.
The dicks took their end without a beef.
We had it down to a business.
And it really stunk, kid.
No sense in being a grifter
if it's the same thing as being a citizen.
I got packing to do. I'm gonna be
a hot number again after tomorrow.
I wouldn't ask you to do this
if it weren't for Luther.
Nothin's gonna make up for Luther.
Revenge is for suckers.
I've been grifting 30 years. I never got any.
Then why're you doing it?
It seems worthwhile, doesn't it?
See you.
Looks like he missed you.
Yeah. This time, anyway.
Good night, Mrs. Hillard.
I was wondering if you might want
to come out for a while...
...maybe have a drink or something.
You move right along, don't you?
Hey, I don't mean nothing by it.
I just don't know many regular girls, is all.
And you expect me
to come out just like that?
If I expected something,
I wouldn't still be standing here in the hall.
I don't even know you.
You know me. I'm just like you.
It's 2:00 a.m., and I don't know nobody.
Come on, Henry. Knock off.
You've done everything you can.
- Yeah? Polk.
- Polk, this is Hooker.
- Ready?
- Yeah, go ahead.
Everything's set.
There'll be a guy at the door.
Nobody's got heaters.
You won't have any trouble.
Okay. See you there.
She was gonna kill you, kid.
Her name's Loretta Salino.
Lonnegan's people set her up in the diner.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
She could have killed me last night.
Too many people could have seen you.
She was a real professional.
Used to work in the Dutch Schultz mob.
Who are you?
Gondorff asked me to look after you.
We just got a tip that Gondorff's mark
is some big New York wheel.
As soon as we're inside,
you get him out of there fast...
...before the reporters show up.
I don't want any big shots around
to mess this up for me.
All right, let's go!
Let's go, guys!
The flag is up, kid.
- Anytime, J.J.
- I'm working on it.
We got one, Billie. Here we go.
- Yeah?
- Place it on Lucky Dan...
...third race at Riverside Park.
...One minute 11 and three-fifths seconds.
They were off at 21.
Last call on the third at Riverside Park.
They're at the post.
At Havre De Grace,
the winner, Light Chatter...
...paid $5.40, $3.80...
...and $2.40. Blacksod...
$500,000 to win.
Lucky Dan, third race at Riverside.
You heard me.
Hold on, sir. I'll get the manager.
...in the fourth at Belmont.
Jay Stout will ride Flying Cross.
See that guy over there?
He just bet $500,000 on Lucky Dan.
The winner at Rockingham Park...
...Enfin, paid $6. 10...
...$4.30 and $2.50.
What's your problem?
I'm putting $500,000 on Lucky Dan
to win the third race at Riverside.
Can't lay that off in time.
A bet like that could break us.
Not only are you a cheat...
...you're a gutless cheat as well.
- What are the odds?
- 4-1.
Take all of it.
This is Arnold Rowe...
...calling the third race at Riverside.
This is a claiming race for $1,500
for 3-year-olds and up.
It's been raining, and the track is muddy.
The flag is up and they're off and running.
Dr. Twink is going to the front...
...followed by Lucky Dan,
Ima Dreamer, Orkin...
...Josie G., Chi Chi and Little Star.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Lucky Dan ahead...
...Dr. Twink a length, Orkin a half...
...followed by Ima Dreamer,
Josie G., Chi Chi and Little Star.
Into the backstretch...
...it's Lucky Dan a length, Dr. Twink a half...
...Orkin a head, Ima Dreamer by one.
Sorry, I couldn't wait.
Everything going all right?
You got nothing to worry about.
I put it all on Lucky Dan.
$500,000 to win.
To win?
I said place! Place it on Lucky...
That horse is gonna run second!
Ima Dreamer a half, Dr. Twink a half
and Orkin by two, followed by Little Star.
It's a driving finish!
There's been a mistake.
Give me my money back!
I tell you there's been a mistake!
Give me my goddamn money back!
All right, FBI! Don't anybody try to leave.
Stand on your feet, put your hands
over your head and move nice and slow.
Snyder!
Get them up against the wall.
Make sure they're not carrying anything.
Hello, Henry. It's been a long time.
But it's over.
Okay, kid, you can go.
All right, I said hands up. Keep them up!
Come on. Move them back! Put them up!
Get him out. Get him out!
Come on! Got to get you out of here!
- Come on!
- But my money's in there!
There's some dead guys too.
You can't get mixed up.
You don't understand.
There's $500,000 in there!
He's gone.
Okay, Henry, all clear.
Can you believe it? We pulled it off.
It's a nice con, Hickey. I thought you were
the feds myself when you came in.
No trouble, Henry.
Snyder went for it all the way.
You should've seen the rag
he lit under Lonnegan!
Well, kid, you beat him.
You're right, Henry. It's not enough.
But it's close.
Okay, guys, let's take this place apart fast.
You can pick up your splits from Eddie
at Boudreau's tonight.
Nice going, J.J.
Oh, Henry!
You're not gonna stick around
for your share?
Nah. I'd only blow it.