Keep it goin'!
All right. Shake it out. Keep movin'.
You're late.
Hey, you.
Shake it out!
- Hey.
- You talkin' to me?
Here!
Me and my brother-
It just used to be me and my brother.
We used to do things together.
We used to have fun.
We used to roam the streets.
There was people sufferin'
of pain and hunger.
Some people, their tongues
were hangin' out of their mouth.
Just gotta get fixed up first.
Things aren't always
gonna be this way.
You know that, don't you?
He used to juggle apples.
He- He used to amuse us.
He used to entertain us.
What else do I get to do today?
In fact, all three of us been goin'places...
Looking for things,
searching for things...
goin' on adventures.
They told everybody
they were brother and sister.
My brother didn't want nobody to know.
You know how people are.
You tell 'em somethin',
they start talkin'.
I met this guy named Ding Dong.
He told me the whole earth
is goin' up in flames.
Flames will come out
of here and there...
and they'll just rise up.
The mountains are gonna go up
in big flames.
The water's gonna rise in flames.
There's gonna be creatures
runnin' every which way...
some of them burned,
half their wings burnin'.
People are gonna be screamin'
and hollerin' for help.
See, the people that have been good,
they're gonna go to heaven...
and escape all that fire.
Sackers! I need sackers!
But if you've
been bad, God don't even hear you.
He don't even hear you talkin'.
A man can earn three dollars a day
if he wants to work.
Sackers! I need sackers!
You ever sack before?
- Sure.
- When was that?
- Last year.
- Get on.
Whose place is that?
The owner's. Don't any of you
go up around there either.
- Silver tongue.
- Hey!
- You all right?
- Sure, I am.
- You live around here?
- No, kid.
No, I don't.
- Where do you live?
- In Chicago.
Oh, yeah?
- What's that in your hair?
- In my hair?
- This.
- In my ear?
- Yeah.
- That's what you call a makins.
- What's a makins?
- A cigarette.
- Oh.
- I-It's tobacco in a bag.
- And you put it - roll it up.
- Oh.
- But I'm not gonna - I'm gonna save it.
- You like it out here?
- Yeah.
- It's nice.
I lo - I know. I love it out here.
I like the wheat fields and -
- You have any brothers or sisters?
- No.
- I have a brother.
- What's his name?
- Bill.
- Where?
He's somewhere - I don't know -
over there. I don't know.
I got one.
Let me see.
Don't lose him. There he goes.
Look, look. Look. Oh, you lost him.
I don't think they like us.
Abby's it!
Abby's too slow.
You didn't get me.
"For a thousand years in thy sight
are but as yesterday when it is past...
"and as a watch in the night.
As soon as thou scatters
them that are evil"-
Amen.
Ho!
Stop straggling. Come on. Come on. Come on.
Get that rake over there.
Come on!
Line 'em up.
This farmer,
he didn't know when he first saw her...
or what it was about her
that caught his eye.
Maybe it was the way the wind
blew through her hair.
- What are you smokin' for?
- Why do you wear a black hat?
Let me see your hands.
Why don't you get some spoons,
and I'll meet you over there?
Okay? Over in the field here.
Your sister keep you warm
at night, does she?
- What did you say?
- You heard me.
Hmm.
Come on!
Let me go!
- Relax.
- Okay!
Too bad you ain't got any real food left.
I'm kinda hungry.
I got a little potato here.
You know anything about that woman
out there, the one with the black hair?
You haven't heard anything about her?
Where she's from?
You want me to find out?
You wasted more than 12 bushels
in this row.
I'm docking you three dollars.
Hey, what are you talkin' about?
That's not fair!
Then leave. You're fired.
- Wait a minute.
- Forget it. Don't fight about it.
You want to stay?
Then shut up and get back to work.
They treat you like shit out here.
Don't worry about it.
I seen a doctor comin' by.
I'll see if I can get him
to give you somethin' for that.
Right?
Okay.
Ooh!
Hey!
I appreciate you coming out, Doc.
That's all right.
I'll be checking on you
as time goes on.
You never think it's gonna happen to you.
Yup.
How long would you reckon I have?
You know, you can tell me.
A year. Maybe a year.
He knew he was gonna die.
He knew there was nothin'
that could be done.
Catch it.
Goosey.
You're only on this Earth once.
And I- to my opinion,
as long as you're around...
you should have it nice.
Here we go. Here we go.
Excuse me.
I forgot where I was.
Don't worry.
- Where are you from?
- Chicago.
Wait a minute.
Where do you go from here?
All over.
Wyoming.
You think I'll like it?
- I saved your life today.
- Nah.
Yeah, I killed a shit-eating dog.
Thanks.
I'm always lookin' out for you.
You deserve a medal.
Whoa. Hey.
Are you cold?
It's only for a while.
Then we'll go to New York.
And then what?
Then we're there.
Then we get fixed up.
All right. I want to see everybody working.
Everybody out here,
movin' it along.
Shake it! Come on. Let's go!
Let's go! Go now!
There we go!
From the time
the sun went up till it went down...
theys were workin' all the time.
No- Nonstop.
Just keep going.
Up with it. Come on. Let's go!
You didn't work,
they'd ship you right out of there.
All right. Let's go! Shake it out!
They don't need you.
They can always get somebody else.
That's at a profit of $4.75 an acre.
Multiply that by 20,000.
You're talkin' over six figures.
- Big year.
- Your biggest ever.
Should make you the richest man
in the panhandle.
You oughta get out
while you're this far ahead.
You have nothing to gain by staying.
Hey, get off of there!
No!
You fall in, I gotta clean up.
This farmer, he had a big spread...
and a lot of money.
Whoever was sittin' in the chair
when he'd come around...
why, they'd stand up
and give it to him.
Wasn't no harm in him.
You'd give him a flower,
he'd keep it forever.
He was headed for the boneyard
any minute...
but he wasn't really goin' around
squawkin' about it...
like some people.
In one way, I felt sorry for him...
'cause he had nobody
to stand out for him...
be by his side...
hold his hand
when he needs attention or somethin'.
That's touchin'.
We'll probably be all done
by tomorrow.
You still plan on goin' north?
Mm-hmm.
The reason I ask is, uh...
maybe you'd like to stay on here.
Well, it'd be easier than it is now.
There's not that much work after the harvest.
Pay's just as good.
It's an idea. You could think about it
and let me know later.
I gotta run.
Who's that?
My brother.
He's stuck on ya.
- Hmm. Legs.
- There are people around.
- There's nobody around.
- Yes, there are.
- Look at that.
- Stop it.
He doesn't have any family either.
Why don't you tell him you'll stay?
What for?
I don't know.
Somethin' might happen.
What's your mouth hangin' open for?
Don't tell me. I already know.
On account of your unhappy life -
all that shit.
Well, I'm tellin' you,
we gotta do something about it.
Can't expect anybody else to.
Last load! Comin' down!
Hup! Shut her down!
Are we gonna stay?
If she wants to.
You'd rather go?
I'd rather be the king of Siam.
You put aspirin in this?
- Ninety dollars.
- Thank you, sir.
Hey!
- Want a bite?
- Thank you very much, sir.
Eighty-seven dollars.
Did he ever buy you anything?
Lots of things.
He'll come back, I'm sure.
I don't think so.
Why not?
'Cause if he wanted me to be with him,
he would have took me.
Oh, that's not true.
I don't know. Maybe I wasn't
pretty enough or somethin'.
Somethin' stupid like that.
What happened to your ear?
My dog bit me when I was little.
We were playin'.
Can I have a puff?
He was tired of livin' like
the rest of them-
nosin' around like a pig in a gutter.
He wasn't in the mood no more.
He figured there must be
somethin' wrong with 'em-
the way they always got no luck-
and they oughta get it
straightened out.
He figured some people need
more than they got...
other people got more
than they need.
Just a matter of gettin' us
all together.
Chicago!
Well, go ahead!
Weren't even dancing shoes.
You got on regular shoes.
You never used to be like this.
As long as I can remember, people been giving
me a hard time about one thing or another.
- Don't you start in too.
- Oh.
Big federal case.
We don't have to decide
anything final now.
Just if we're gonna stay.
Hey-yee!
Whoo!
Yeah, I could stay, sure. I gotta keep
my brother and sister with me though.
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
Hey! Yea!
I'll try and come back.
I'll try and come back 'cause I...
I really liked staying with you.
You were so much fun.
I love you, okay?
I want you to be really good.
And I don't want you to do anything wrong.
If you do anything wrong,
I'll come back and I'll get ya. All right?
I love you,
and don't do nothin' wrong!
All right?
I've been thinkin' what to do
with my future.
I could be a mud doctor...
checkin' out the earth underneath.
Why are you doing this?
When I was your age,
I was all by myself in the world.
I used to sit and wrap cigars...
until after dark.
My skin was as white as paper.
I never saw the daylight.
This is not so bad.
Don't make me laugh.
What about this then?
Wait a minute.
- Where are you people from?
- Chicago.
- Yeah? What'd you do there?
- Nothing.
Your brother, I mean.
He worked in a factory.
I can remember
the first time I ever saw you.
Hmm?
Never seen hair as black as yours.
Skin so pretty.
Scared I'd never see you again.
- Run!
- Come on.
Safe!
So, I went to work in the mill.
Couldn't wait to get in there.
Begin at 7:00.
Got to have a smile on your face.
And one day you wake up...
you find you're not
the smartest guy in the world.
Never gonna come up
with the big score.
When I was growin' up,
I thought I really would.
- Where'd you learn that?
- From watching the girls at Baker Hall.
Actually,
I could have been a dancer.
I think I love you.
What a nice thing to say.
Never thought he'd have the guts.
- Who'd know but you and me?
- Nobody.
That's all that matters, isn't it?
You talk like it was all right.
He'll never have a chance
to enjoy his money anyway.
What makes you think we're talkin'
about just a couple of months?
The man's got one foot on a banana peel,
the other on a roller skate.
It'll all be gone in a couple of years.
Who's gonna care
that we acted perfect?
I held out a long time.
I had rich men
pay me compliments.
Have I ever said anything to you
that would make you think-
You don't have to.
I mean, I hate it,
to see you stooped over out there.
Them looking at your ass
like you're a whore.
I hate it.
As you will answer
at the dreadful day ofjudgment.
The secrets in all hearts
shall be disclosed.
And if either of you know
any impediment -
For richer and for poorer...
for better, for worse...
in sickness and in health...
to love and to cherish...
till death us do part.
Bless, O Lord, this ring
that he who gives it...
and she who wears it
may abide by peace.
Thank you.
You're like an angel.
I wish I was.
Does all this seem strange to you?
Why don't you move your things in here,
into the house, while we're gone?
All right.
Bye.
Did you see this?
There's more right up there too.
You've never been in love before?
Why's that?
We never been this rich, all right?
I mean, we were just,
all of a sudden...
livin' like kings.
Just nothin' to do all day
but crack jokes, lay around.
- Help!
- We didn't have to work.
I'm tellin' you,
the rich got it figured out.
This.
Soft tickle.
- Oh, Linda!
- Hey, don't. Please, go away.
- Can you do anything?
- No.
That's not so. Show 'em that.
What? With potatoes?
Uh-huh.
So this is what you do all day.
- Hey! That's mine.
- Now it's for the dogs.
I got to like this farm.
Do anything I want.
Roll in the fields...
talk to the wheat patches.
When I was sleepin',
they'd talk to me.
They'd go in my dreams.
What's the matter with you?
- I get lonely by myself.
- Shh!
You see this bottle?
I want to break it.
- You're crazy.
- That sound dumb?
What do you think?
- You hear that?
- Yeah.
It scares me doing this,
you know?
Dropped my glass.
Doesn't matter.
I never wanted
to fall in love with you.
Nobody asked you to.
A minute ago you said
I was irresistible.
I still am.
Your hair's still the same.
Abby?
Where you been?
I've been looking all over for you.
I couldn't sleep well.
I went out for a walk.
- You should've woke me up.
- I didn't want to.
Nobody sent us letters.
We didn't receive no cards.
Sometimes I'd feel very old...
like my whole life's over...
like I'm not around no more.
Bet he likes looking at you in that.
This?
I thought you liked it.
You don't like them, do ya?
You never have.
I don't think they're honest people.
As a matter of fact,
I think they're a pair of con artists.
You know, maybe you'd be better off
taking over the north end till spring.
I mean, we've been together a long time
and I've always felt close to you.
Just might work out better is all.
Less friction.
You're talkin' about my wife.
Maybe I'd better pack.
I know what you're doing.
That boy's like a son to me.
You know what I thought
when I first saw you?
I thought, "If only I could touch her,
then everything'd be all right. "
You make me feel like I've come
back to life. Isn't that funny?
I always thought that being alone was
just something that a man had to put up with.
It was like I just got used to it.
Sometimes it's like...
you're right inside of me,
you know...
like I can hear your voice
and feel your breath and everything.
Why are you so uneasy with me?
I'm sorry.
I don't blame you.
Did I make it sound like that?
You have a right to.
It's just that it seems
like I don't know you.
Did you see him wave?
- Here he is!
- There he goes!
- That's the president of the whole country.
- Ohh!
Will you help me up?
Instead of gettin'sicker...
he just stayed the same.
He didn't get sicker,
he didn't get better.
They were kindhearted.
They thought he was going out
on his own steam.
I don't know. The doc musta come over
or somethin' and gave him somethin'.
Probably some kind of medicine
or somethin'.
I coulda just took it,
put it in a ditch...
like they do to a horse.
They shoot 'im right away.
Buster, fetch.
Whoa. Easy.
Whoa, pup.
Sally.
Sally, Sally.
Whoa, pup.
Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa.
You seem jumpy today.
I'm sick of these stinkin' birds.
- What's the matter?
- You don't wanna know about it.
Just when things were
about to blow, this flyin' circus come in.
After six months on this wheat patch,
I needed a breath of fresh air.
They were screamin' and yellin'
and boppin' each other.
He- The big one
pushed the little one and said...
"Come on.
I start it, you start. "
The little one just started in.
If they couldn't think of a good one
to come back with, they'd start fightin'.
The little one said:
"No, I didn't do this."
The big one said:
"Yes, you did do this."
You couldn't sort it out.
I wanna give 'em a hand for this.
Hey! Bong!
Mmm. Watch out.
Watch out, watch out.
The devil just sittin' there, laughin'.
He's glad when people does bad.
Then he sends 'em to the snake house.
He just sits there and laughs and watch
while you're sittin' there all tied up...
and snakes are eatin' your eyes out.
They go down your throat
and eat all your systems out.
You're confusing me, you know.
Drivin' me crazy.
I don't know if I'm comin' or goin'.
You never did.
I think the devil was on the farm.
What's going on?
What's the matter?
You know what I mean.
Why do you let him
touch you like that?
What are you talking about?
I don't know how brothers and sisters act
where you come from -
Did you ever have a sister?
Well, then who are you to judge?
Ah, buongiorno, signorina-
Did you say anything to him?
Never seen him act like this before.
- He must think we're awful.
- What do you care what he thinks?
You're in love with him, aren't you?
Are you leavin'?
- Yeah.
- What for?
I got some business to take care of.
They're giving me a lift.
- Just like that, huh?
- Guess so.
He seen how it all was.
She loves the farmer.
He taught me keys on the pianos
and notes.
He taught me about
the parts of a globe.
Ohh!
And the mast here.
Then another great big one straight up here.
So here would be the - the front,
and then the bow.
- Bill!
- Hey, sprinkle!
- I missed you so much. Did you miss me?
- Yeah!
- How much?
- A lot!
- Hey. You look just the same.
- How you doin'?
We been readin' about you.
- What do you mean?
- Oh, about Chicago.
You come all that way by motorcycle?
I'm sorry.
You didn't do nothin' to me.
I didn't know what I had with you.
I think about it -
the things I said to you...
how I pushed you into this.
Got nobody to blame but myself.
I oughta get goin'...
before it gets too late.
Smoke 'em out!
Swat 'em out!
That way! Let's go! Come on!
What's this?
What are you doin'?
What do you care?
Are you crazy?
Catch 'em!
Let it burn!
Get tractors! Blankets!
Catch that mare!
Get back!
He doesn't understand me.
What are we gonna do?
We gotta get out of here.
He knows.
- Do somethin'!
- Fire! Fire!
- Up this way!
- Come here!
Don't stir them up!
Help me get this ground -
- Comin' through here!
- Comin' this way!
Out of my way!
What did you want from me?
Wait!
You're a liar!
Pull it out?
Look, I'll tell you
the whole story later.
Nothing we can do about it now.
Well, you're skinnin' me alive, but-
And the Victrola.
- Even up?
- Yeah.
Nobody's perfect.
There was never
a perfect person around.
You just got half devil
and half angel in you.
She promised herself
she'd lead a good life from now on.
She blamed it all on herself.
It's good. I like it.
She didn't care if she was happy or not.
She just wanted to make up
for what she did wrong.
Got about a three-pound carp.
The sun looks ghostly when there's a mist
on a river and everything's quiet.
I never knowed it before.
You could see people on the shore...
but it was far off and you couldn't see
what they were doin'.
They were probably
callin' for help or somethin'...
or they were tryin'
to bury somebody or somethin'.
We seen trees
that the leaves are shakin'...
and it looks like
shadows of guys comin' at you and stuff.
We heard owls squawkin' away,
hootin'away.
We didn't know where we were goin',
what we were gonna do.
I've never been on a boat before.
That was the first time.
Have you seen her?
Where?
Some sights that I saw was really spooky...
that it gave me goose pimples.
I felt like cold hands...
touchin' the back of my neck and-
And it could be the dead
comin' for me or somethin'.
I remember this guy-
his name was Black Jack.
He died.
He only had one leg, and he died.
And I think that was Black Jack
makin' those noises.
Got 'er wedged in there.
- Grab it.
- Hold on, Randy.
There!
Move over this way!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa!
Check out those trees!
Steady.
Gotta be in here somewhere.
- What's going on?
- Keep down!
- Just stay here.
- Wait a minute -
There!
- I'm gonna come around back that way.
- Don't let him get back to the river.
- Move over. Down this stretch!
- Check out those trees!
Watch it! He's going around
the other side of that bank!
The other's goin' the other way!
Come on!
- Buck!
- Back over there!
You!
You go over there!
I'm gonna go this way. You go over there!
He's in here somewhere!
- Hey, Linder!
- Check it there! Check it there!
Over there! There!
It'll work out. Right?
- Mmm.
- You'll make lots of friends.
You'll be all right.
Now turn around and go inside.
Oranges.
Oranges. Oranges.
- Big barrel of coal.
- Yeah, I saw! I saw!
Keep safe, boys.
Hey, come look!
Come on! Come on!
Don't worry about all that stuff.
I got a new boyfriend. He's in the army.
Maybe he'll get killed or somethin'.
I don't know. Anyway, he said I'm pretty.
And maybe I am.
Look at this!
Come on. Come on.
Hey, what'd you do at that school anyway?
Ballet!
Yeah, I got it!
Get in the alley! Hurry up!
I don't wait two hours for nobody.
Maybe he don't have a watch.
Yeah. If I believe that,
he'll tell me another.
His name was Edward.
He was nice. I liked him.
I don't know.
He said he was gonna buy me a fur.
I always wanted a fur.
- Where ya goin'?
- For a walk.
I don't know where, but -
Go - Go beat the heck
out of some tree or somethin'.
Take it out on them.
You comin' with me or what?
This girl,
she didn't know where she was goin'...
or what she was gonna do.
She didn't have no money on her.
Maybe she'd meet up with a character.
I was hopin'
things would work out for her.
She was a good friend of mine.