Darling, come here.
Do you like it?
Justice...
There will be a trial...
a great trial before a powerful magistrate.
And you, you will be guilty.
Beware! Beware the heat of the fire!
Comrade Chan Gong has come from Beijing.
Welcome her, please.
Comrades, students, revolutionary
companions-in-arms...
I give you my proletarian salute.
I congratulate you on today's grand festival...
for which you have worked so hard.
Your cultural unit has done exceptional work.
I would also like to commend you
on the children's presentation.
It made my heart rejoice.
The story of The Three Heroic Girls...
was a vivid lesson.
It galvanized our historic crusade!
But unfortunately, some efforts
are less successful.
Sometimes the teacher must learn
from his students.
Give it to me.
Capitalist exploitation survived
for centuries...
yet its "classics" are pitiful.
Foreign music is meaningless and empty.
What do they mean by "symphony", "concerto"...
"No 1", "No 2", 'No 3"?
This is empty formalism.
It speaks nothing to the people.
What good is making music... except
to teach and inspire the people?
Long live Chairman Mao!
Overthrow the cultural establishment!
Chou Yuan?
Present.
Why do you teach this instrument?
Comrade Chan Gong, what you say is true...
Louder, please.
Comrade Chan Gong, you are right.
Much of Western music is unrefined, worthless.
This is a fact.
Everything you said is true.
But the music I teach...
Go on!
The music I teach is revolutionary music.
Beethoven, Prokofiev.
Do you think so?
In his speech, Comrade Li said...
Comrade Li was purged and humiliated.
Do you still wish to quote him?
I didn't know.
I have taught for many years.
That is apparent.
We believe in the rule of many voices.
What should we do here?
Throw away that old junk!
Chou Yuan, you must admit your guilt.
Let's challenge degenerate Western art!
Comrade, may I say a few words?
Of course.
Students, comrades, revolutionary Red Guards...
I'm not an authority on foreign music.
I have not studied like Comrade Chan Gong.
But in my opinion, there's nothing
as beautiful as our traditional music.
Chou Yuan also teaches the hu chin.
Could he not focus on that?
Comrade Xiang has shown her wisdom.
Put this down with the other "great olds"!
To every problem there is a solution!
I'm sure you can discover the problems.
And I'm sure you can solve them.
Who is it? Who's there?
Ming!
You scared me. I didn't hear you.
It's a mess. I was tidying up.
What's that?
This is a violin.
A musical instrument from Europe.
From Europe?
Is it a bad thing?
No, a violin itself is a good thing.
Here, take a look
We have to study foreign music
so we can move on...
as Chairman Mao said.
Dad asked if you're coming.
He's waiting.
Yes. Tell him I'll come to see him right away.
As soon as I finish my work.
- Ming?
- Yes?
What you see here, don't tell anyone.
I want you to listen.
This will be our secret, all right?
Go!
Ming!
- Was she home?
- Yes.
Is she coming?
No, she said she'd meet you.
What? Is she coming or not?
I can't say why.
Why what?
I promised her to keep it secret.
What are you saying?
I'm your father. You must tell me everything.
- Xiang Pei!
- Papa, don't!
Open up, it's me.
Where's the key?
Go!
Quiet!
Where is she?
Water! Water!
She's gone.
Is this her?
Look at the date: 1937. It must be her mother.
Chou Yuan!
- What do you want?
- Please let me in.
I've done nothing.
Let me inside.
This is for you.
I don't want it.
It's for you. Take it.
It's a violin. A violin.
I remember.
Do you want it or not?
I'm an old man, but I'm not a fool.
Where are your comrades?
Are they waiting outside?
This isn't a trap.
I've changed.
I don't need it now. I speak from my heart.
Enough!
And I don't need this.
It's from another time.
If you want it, you can have it,
or else no one will.
Do you want it or not?
I've no time!
No more arguments.
Take it! I am a cadre in the Party.
Do you understand?
I can't keep it.
I love the people. Do you understand?
Xiang Pei!
I will keep it safe.
Let's go eat, I'm starving.
Go ahead. I'll wait here.
I'm sure she'll be back.
The last card.
Oh, my God!
Courage, madame... Upside down.
At this point in the spread...
it might be good news.
I feel... I feel the fast air
sweeping around you...
carrying you... furious wind...
and then stopping.
Your journey will end. No question. I see it.
One way or another, your travels are over.
And there is trouble in this like always.
But you... you are strong by now...
strong like a tree in the forest.
Where is he?
Upstairs.
You are not alone.
A crowd of forces, friends and family...
enemies, lovers...
You will attract many admirers...
fighting to win your hand.
And money... lots of money.
No, madame. Don't be afraid.
N this card, I see a rebirth.
This is Mr. Morritz. You know...
So you're the expert?
From New York.
Do you know what you're doing?
316-2799
"With all my heart"
RED VIOLIN UNEARTHED
Ladies and gentlemen
Duval's would like to welcome you
to this eagerly awaited event.
Our thanks to the government of China...
for entrusting us with this
marvelous collection.
Thanks too to Madame Leroux who
organized and made possible this auction.
Let me remind you that the conditions
of sale are listed in the catalog.
Wait!
The tag!
I put the tag on myself.
Too late.
Call security.
Madame? Are you all right?
Is everything all right?
Yes, I'm sorry.
You have the visions.
No. I'd better go now.
My husband...
Of course, go to your husband.
Thanks, Cesca.