[Squeaking]
[Whooshing]
[ Rocket Firing ]
[ Hydraulics Whooshing ]
[BreathingApparatus Hissing]
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
All signs point to this planet
as the location of Zurg's fortress,
but there seems to be no sign
of intelligent lif e anywhere.
[ Electronic Whirring ]
[ All Whirring ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Laser Buzzing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Electronic Whirring ]
- [Electronic Beeping]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Gasping ]
- [ Beeping ]
- [Laughing Evilly]
Come to me, myprey.
[ Continues Gasping ]
[ Grunts ]
[Electronic Buzzing]
[ Screaming ]
To infinity and beyond!
[ Electronic Whirring ]
So, we meet again,
Buzz Lightyear, for the last time.
Not today, Zurg!
- [ Cries Out ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Laughing Maniacally]
- ** [ GameTheme]
- Oh, no! No!
- No, no, no, no.
- Oh, you almost had him.
- I'm never gonna defeat Zurg!
- Sure, you will, Rex.
- In fact,
you're a better Buzz than I am.
- But look at my little arms!
I can't press the "fire" button
and jump at the same time!
Where is it?
- Uh, Woody?
- Huh? [ Grunts ]
- [ Continues Grunting ]
- [ Both ] Ooh.
Hang on, cowboy!
- Woody, are you all right?
- [ Grunts ] Oh. Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine, Buzz. Okay. Here's you r
list of things to do while I'm gone.
Batteries need to be changed.
Toys in the bottom of the chest
need to be rotated.
Oh, and make sure everyone
attends Mr. Spell's seminar...
on what to do
if you or a part of you is swallowed.
- Okay? Okay. Good. Okay.
- Woody, you haven't found
you r hat yet, have you ?
No! And Andy's leaving
for cowboy camp any minute,
and I can't find it anywhere!
Don't worry, Woody.
In just a few hours,
you'll be sitting around a campfire with
Andy making delicious, hot "sch'moes."
- They're called s'mores, Buzz.
- Right. Right. of course.
Has anyone found Woody's hat yet?
[ Sergeant ] Keep looking, men.
Dig deeper! Negatory. Still searching.
The lawn gnome next door says it's not
in theyard, but he'll keep lookin'.
[ Sheep Bleating ]
It's not in Molly's room.
We've looked everywhere.
- I found it.
- you found my hat?
you r hat? No.
The missus lost her earring.
- Oh, my little sweet potato!
- Oh, you found it!
Oh, it's so nice...
to have a big, strong spud
around the house.
- Ooh! [ Giggles ]
- Oh, great. That's just great.
This'll be the firstyear I miss cowboy
camp, all because of my stupid hat!
- Woody, look underyou r boot.
- Don't be silly.
- My hat is not under my boot.
- Would you just look?
[ Groans ] you see? No hat.
Just the word "Andy."
Uh-huh. And the boywho
wrote that would takeyou to
camp with orwithoutyou r hat.
I'm sorry, Bo.
It's just that I've been
lookin' forward to this all year.
- It's my one time
with just me and Andy. [ Gasps ]
- you're cute when you care.
- Bo, not in front of Buzz.
- [ Purrs ] Let him look.
- [ Bleating ]
- Miss Peep, you r sheep!
- [ Whistles ]
- [ Rex Screams, Grunts ]
- This is Al from Al's Toy Barn,
and I'm sittin' on good deals.
- Whoa!
Ow! I think I'm feeling
a deal hatching right now.
Whoa! Let's see what we got. We got
boats for a buck, Beanies for a buck--
-Rex, turn it of f!. Someone's gonna hear!
-Which one is of f?
Buck-buck-buck! And that's
cheap-cheap-cheap! So hurry on down--
For cryin' out loud, it's this one.
- I despise that chicken.
- Fellas! Fellas!
- Okay, I got some good news,
and I got some bad news.
- What news?
The good news is
I found you r hat, Woody.
My hat! Slink, thankyou .
Thankyou , thankyou , thankyou .
- Where'd you find it?
- Well, that's the bad news.
- [Dog Barking]
- Oh, it's Buster!
[ Sergeant ] Canine alert! Man you r
battle stations! Let's move, move, move!
- [Buster Growling]
- Woody! Hide! Quick!
- [ Woody Gasps ]
[ Barking ]
[ Continues Barking ]
[ Beeping Electronically]
[ Snif fing ]
[ Continues Barking ]
[ Growling ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Sputtering ] Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay! you found me!
Buster, all right. [ Groans ]
Hey, how did he do, Hamm?
- Looks like a new record.
- Okay, boy. Sit.
- Reach for the sky.
- [ Whimpering ]
- Gotcha!
- [ Shrieks ]
[ Chuckles ]
Great job, boy.
Who's gonna miss me
while I'm gone, huh?
- Who's gonna miss me?
Who's gonna miss me?
- [ Panting ]
[Woman]
Andy,you got allyou rstuff?
-Have a good weekend, everybody.
I'll seeyou Sunday night.
-It's in myroom.
- [ Barking ]
- Stick'em up.
I guess we'll work on that later.
Hey, Woody.
Ready to go to cowboy camp?
Andy, honey, come on.
Five minutes, and we're leavin'.
Five minutes. Hmm.
Help, help!
Somebody help me!
Let her go, evil Dr. Pork Chop!
[Andy, Evil Voice ] Never!
you must choose, Sherif fWoody.
Howshall she die?
Shark, or death by monkeys?
[ Imitates Monkey Chittering ]
- Choose!
- [Andy Imitating Woody ]
I choose Buzz Lightyear!
- What? That's not a choice!
- [Andy Imitating Buzz ]
To infinity and beyond!
- I'l I save you , Miss Peep.
- My hero. [ I m itates Kissing ]
- [ Andy As Woody ] Thanks, Buzz.
- [ Andy As Buzz ] No problem, buddy.
you should never tangle
with the unstoppable duo
of Woody and Buzz Lightyear!
Oh, no.
Andy, let's go!
Molly's already in her car seat.
- But, Mom, Woody's arm wrecked.
- Oh, no.
- Maybe we can fix him on the way.
- No, just leave him.
I'm sorry, honey,
but you know toys don't last forever.
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
- What happened?
- Woody's been shelved.
[Rex Gasps ]
Andy!
-[ Slinky] Woody?
-[ Bo Peep ] Woody? Honey, are you okay?
[ Andy] Yee-hah!
Ride'em, cowboy! [ Whoops ]
He's back? Hey, everybody! Andy's back!
He's back early from cowboy camp!
- Places, everybody! Andy's coming!
- [ All Gasping, Chattering ]
Yeah!
** [Humming Lone Ranger Theme Song]
Hey, Woody!
Did you miss me?
Giddyap, giddyap, giddyap.
Ride'em, cowboy!
Ohh. I forgot.
you're broken.
I don't wanna playwith you anymore.
[ Gasping ]
No, Andy!
No. No, Andy! No!
[ Choking ]
Andy. Andy. [ Garbled ]
[ Voice Echoing ]
Bye, Woody.
No! No! Andy!
[ Screaming, Gasping ]
[ Grunts, Coughs ]
[ Coughing]
- [ Continues Coughing ]
- [Woody] Wheezy, is thatyou ?
- Hey, Woody.
- What are you doing up here?
I thought Mom tookyou
to get you r squeaker fixed months ago.
- Andywas so upset.
- Nah. She just told him that
to calm him down...
and then put me on the shelf.
- Why didn'tyou yell for help?
- Well, I tried squeakin'.
But I'm still broken.
No one could hear me. [Wheezes ]
[ Coughs ] Besides, the dust
aggravates my condition.
[ Wheezes, Coughs ]
What's the point in
prolonging the inevitable?
We're all just one stitch away
from here to there.
Yardsale? Yardsale!
Yard sale! Guys, wake up, wake up!
There's a yard sale outside!
- Yard sale?
- Sarge, emergency roll call!
Sir, yes, sir!
Red alert!
All civilians fall in position now!
Single file! Let's move, move, move!
- Hamm? Potato Head, Mr. and Mrs.?
- Here.
- [ Both ] Here.
- Troikas. Check,
check, check, check, check.
- I hate yard sales!
[ Yelps ]
Someone's coming!
[ Gasps ]
Okay. Let's see what's up here.
[ Puzzle Pieces Rattling ]
Bye, Woody.
Wheezy! Think, think, Woody.
Think, think, think.
Ooh-- [ Blows Raspberry,
Sputters, Whistles ]
- [ Barking ]
- Hey. Here, boy. Here, Buster!
Up here!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Okay, boy.
To the yard sale! Hyah!
- [Potato Head]
What's goin'on? He's nuts.
- His arm ain't that bad.
Don't do it, Woody!
We love you !
[ Woody] Careful on the steps, now.
[ Grunting ]
[ Buster Pants ]
[ Child Laughing]
Okay, boy. Let's go.
And keep it casual.
[ Woody] Not that casual.
[ Child Babbling ]
- [ Hamm ] Piggy bank
coming through, coming through.
- [ Rex ] Is he out there?
[Buzz] There he is.
- [ Woody Grunts ]
- **[Man Whistling]
- [Rex] He's in the box!
- [ Hamm ] He's sellin' himself
for 25 cents!
- you're worth more than that.
- [Buzz] Hold on. Hold on.
He's gotsomething.
- It's Wheezy!
- [ All ] Wheezy?
Hey, it's not suicide.
It's a rescue.
- [ Woody Grunts ]
- [ Wheezy Squeaking ]
Good boy, Buster. Hold still.
There. There you go, pal.
- Bless you , Woody.
- All right, now.
Back to Andy's room. Hyah!
- [Toys Laughing]
- [Buzz] Way to go, cowboy.
- [ Slinky] Golly bob howdy!
- Woody, I'm slipping!
[ Yells, Grunts ]
[ Child Laughing]
Mommy-- Mommy, look! Look at this!
- Mommy, look! It's a cowboy dolly!
- Hey, that's not her toy!
[Slinky] What's that little gal
think she's doin'?
- Mommy, Mommy, can we get it?
Please? Mommy, please?
- Oh, honey.
you don't want that toy.
It's broken.
- [ Mechanical Voice ]
There's a snake in my boot.
- [ Man Gasping ]
Original hand-painted face.
Natural-dye, blanket-stitched vest!
Little rip. Fixable. Oh, if onlyyou had
you r hand-stitched, polyvinyl--
[ Gasps, Laughs Hysterically] A hat!
I found him! I found him! I found him!
- [ Continues Laughing ]
- [Andy's Mother] Buster! Quiet down!
- Excuse me. Can I help you ?
- Yes. you can help
take his paws of f my pal.
I'll give you , uh,
50 cents for all this junk.
- Oh, now, how did this get down here?
- [Buzz] Handher the sherif f.
Nice and easy.
- Five dollars.
- I'm sorry. It's an old family toy.
- [ Groans ] Wait!
- Nowjust walk away. The other way.
- I'll give you 50 bucks for it.
- Fif ty bucks ain't bad.
- [Mother] It's not forsale.
- Everything's for sale.
- We'll trade. you like mywatch?
- Sorry.
- He's safe. Way to go!
- She showed him!
- Molly, don't touch that, sweetie.
- [ Sputtering, Groaning ]
[Potato Head]
Yeah. Go home, Mr. Fancy Car.
- [Buzz] Hold on.
- [Hamm ] What's up?
[Rex ] What is it, Buzz?
- [ Crash ]
- [ Toys ] What's happening?
What's he doing?
I can't watch!
Can someone cover my eyes?
- [ Buzz ] He's stealin' Woody!
- [ Rex ] What?
He can't take Woody. It's illegal.
- Where's he goi ng?
- Do something.
- Buzz!
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Potato Head ] Get him, Buzz.
Where's the red jacket?
[ Gasping, Grunting ]
[Engine Revving]
[ Grunting ]
[ Cries Out, Grunts ]
Whywould someone steal Woody?
[ Grunts, Gasps ]
[ Gasping, Grunting ]
All right.
Let's review this one more time.
At precisely 8:32-ish,
Exhibit "A," Woody, was kidnapped.
Exhibit " B,"
a composite sketch of the kidnapper.
- He didn't have a beard like that.
- Fine. Etch, give him a shave.
[Slinky]
The kidnapper was bigger than that.
- Oh, picky, picky, picky.
- Let's just go straight to Exhibit " F."
The kidnapper's vehicle.
Now, the vehicle fled the scene
in this direction.
- you r eyes are in backwards.
It went the otherway.
- Hey. Put a cork in it.
- How doyou spell " F.B.I."?
- My crime scene!
Oh, why don'tyou watch
where you're going, "Godspilla"?
- I didn't know there was a crime scene.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- A little quiet, please. Thankyou .
- Huh?
[Mr. Spell]
Lazytoybrain.
- Lousy try, Brian.
- What are you doing, Buzz?
It's some sort of message
encoded on that vehicle's I.D. tag.
- Liz try bran.
- It's just a license plate.
It's just a jumble of letters.
Yeah, and there are about
3.5 million registered cars
in the tri-county area alone.
- Lou's thigh burn.
- [ Buzz Groaning ]
Oh, this can't help.
Let's leave Buzz to playwith his toys.
Toy. Toy. Toy.
Hold on!
[Mr. Spell Beeping Electronically]
- Al's Toy Barn.
- Al's Toy Barn!
Etch, draw that man
in a chicken suit.
- [ All Gasping ]
- It's the chicken man!
- [Buzz] That's our guy.
- I knew there was something
I didn't like about that chicken.
Yeah,yeah,yeah.
I'll be right there.
And we're gonna do this commercial
in one take, do you hear me,
because I am in the middle
of something really important.
- [ Phone Beeps of f]
- [ Chuckling Maniacally]
you , my little cowboy friend,
are gonna make me big buck-buck-bucks.
[ Gasping, Straining ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasping, Grunting ]
- [Siren Blaring]
- [ Gasps ]
Andy!
I can't believe I have to drive
all the way to work on a Saturday.
- All the way to work!
- [ Horns Honking ]
[ Grunting ]
What? Whoa!
[ Screaming ]
Hey! Stop! Horsey, stop!
Stop! Sit, boy!
Stop it!
[ Screams ] Sit, I said!
Whoa! Whoa.
[ Grunts ]
- Yee-hah!
- [ Cries Out ]
It's you ! It's you !
It's you ! It's you ! It's you !
- It's reallyyou !
- What's me?
- Whoo-whee!
- [ Mechanical Voice ]
There's a snake in my boot.
- Ha! It is you !
- Please stop saying that.
Prospector said somedayyou'd come.
Sweet mother of Abraham Lincoln!
The Prospector!
He'll wanna meetya! [ Whistles ]
Say "hello" to the Prospector!
- It-- It's a box.
- He's mint in the box.
Never been opened.
[Pete ] Turn me around,
Bullseye, so I can see.
Why, the prodigal son has returned.
Yee-hah!
It's you ! It's you !
you're here! It's you !
Okay. I'm of ficially freaked-out now.
Oh, we've waited countless years
for this day.
- It's good to seeyou , Woody.
- Listen. I don't know wh--
- Hey, how do you know my name?
- Everyone knows you r name, Wood-y.
Why, you don't know
who you are, do you ? Bullseye?
[ Gasps ]
That's me.
[ Gasping ]
Wow.
Holy cow.
** [Western-style Theme Song]
[ Announcer]
Cowboy Crunchies, the cereal that's
sugar-frosted and dipped in chocolate...
proudly presents:
[ Chorus ] * Woody's Roundup
Come on, it's time to play *
-*There's Jessie the yodeling cowgirl *
-*Yodel-ay-hee-hoo *
- ** [ Chorus Yodeling ]
- Look it! That's me!
- * Bullseye, he's Woody's horse *
-* He's a smart one*
-* Meet the old Prospector *
- Has anyone seen my pick?
* And the man himself
of course, it's time for Sheriff Woody *
* He's the very best
He's the rootin'-est
tootin'-est cowboy *
* I n the wild, wild west *
* Woody's Roundup **
I can't find it! It doesn't seem
to be on any of these stations.
- Keep looking.
- you're going too slow.
Let me take the wheel.
- [Jumbled Audio ]
- [ Rex ] It's too fast.
- How can you even tell what's on?
- I can tell.
- [AlSquawks ]
- [ All ] Stop! Back, back, back!
Too late. I'm in the 40s.
Got to go'round the horn. It's faster.
- [ All ] Back, back! Stop!
- And look for the giant chicken!
Now, Etch!
That's where I need to go.
you can't go, Buzz.
you'll never make it there.
Woody once risked his lif e to save me.
I couldn't call myselfhis friend
if l weren't willing to do the same.
So who's with me?
I'm packing you an extra pair of shoes
and you r angry eyes just in case.
This is forWoodywhen you find him.
[ Clears Throat ]
All right, but I don't think
it'll mean the same coming from me.
Mr. Buzz Light year,
you just gotta save mypal Woody.
- [ Coughing, Wheezing ]
- I'll do my best, son.
Okay, fellas.
Let's roll.
Geronimo!
you'd thinkwith
all myvideo game experience,
I'd be feeling more prepared.
[ Screaming ]
The idea is to let go.
We'll be back before Andy gets home.
Don't talk to any toyyou don't know!
To Al's Toy Barn and beyond!
[ TVJessie ] They don't
call this the old abandoned mine
for nothin', Prospector.
I reckon we oughta
get outta here.
[TVPete ] Where's mygold?
Hold on. I'll light me a candle.
[TV Pete ] Where's my gold?
This sure is a fast-burnin' wick.
Blast us to smithereens!
That there's dynamite!
- Holy tarnation.
- I'll call for help.
*Yodel-ay-hee-hoo *
Hey, critters, go get Sherif fWoody.
Now scurry!
[ TVWoody] Good job,
Bullseye. I reckon the new
schoolhouse is finally done.
- [ Critters Chittering ]
- What's that?
Jessie and Prospector are trapped
in the old abandoned mine,
and Prospectorjust lit a stick
of dynamite thinkin' it was a candle,
and now they're about
to be blown to smithereens?
- [ Rabbit ] Mm-hmm.
- Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
you're fannin' the flames,Jessie!
It takes brains to put out that fire.
Yow! My biscuits are burnin'!
[ Announcer]
Will Woody and Bullseye land to safety?
Can theyreachJessie
andStinky Pete in time?
Tune in next week for the exciting
conclusion: "Woody's Finest Hour."
All right! All right! Next tape!
Hey, w-wait.
What happened? What happens next?
- Come on! Let's see the next episode!
- [Pete ] That's it.
- What?
- The show was canceled after that.
Wait. What about the gold mine and the
cute little critters and the dynamite?
That was a great show!
I mean, why cancel it?
Two words: Sput-nik.
Once the astronauts went up, children
onlywanted to playwith space toys.
I know how that feels.
But still, my own show.
- I mean, look at all this stuff!.
- [Jessie ] Didn'tyou know?
Why, you're valuable property!
I wish the guys could see this.
Hey-howdy-hey. That's me.
I'm on a yo-yo.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, hey. Nice teeth.
And yet, still a good-lookin' guy.
Oh, it's a bank! Cool.
Wh-What do you do?
you push the hat, and out co--
Oh, out come bubbles. Clever.
Oh, wow. Hey, what's this thing do?
[ Laughing ] I get it.
"There's a snake in my boot."
Oh, hey, Bullseye.
Go long! Go long! Whoo!
- ** [ Distorted Instrumental ]
- A recordplayer!
- I haven't seen one of these in ages.
- ** [ Fast-speed Yodeling ]
- ** [ Singing Slows ]
- Okay, now. Slow.
- ** [ Extra-slow Singing ]
- Oh, that's funny, Bullseye.
Hop on, cowgirl! Think fast!
[Jessie Gasps ] Oh.
- Not bad.
- * It's time for Woody's Roundup *
- Whee!
- [Distorted]* He's the verybest*
[Fast-speed]* He's the rootin'-est
tootin'-est cowboy--**
Look at us!
We're a complete set!
- Now it's on to the museum.
- Museum?
- [ Record Scratching ]
- [Jessie Screaming ]
- What museum?
- The museum.
We're being sold
to the Konishi Toy Museum in Tokyo.
- That's in Japan!
-Japan? No, no, no, no, no.
I can't go toJapan.
[ Chuckles ]
What doyou mean?
I got to get back home to
my owner, Andy. Hey, look, look. See?
- [ Gasps ] He still has an owner.
- Oh, my goodness.
[ Hyperventilating ] No. Can't go.
-I can't do storage again. I just can't!
-Jessie.Jessie.
- I won't go back in the dark!
- What's the matter?
What's wrong with her?
- Well, we've been in storage
for a long time waiting foryou .
- [ Continues Hyperventilating ]
- Why me?
- The museum's only interested
in the collection...
if you're in it, Woody.
Withoutyou , we go back into storage.
- It's that simple.
- It's not fair!
How can you do this to us?
Hey, look. I'm sorry,
but this is all a big mistake.
- you see, I was in this yard sale--
- Yard sale?
Why were you in a yard sale
if you have an owner?
Well, I wasn't supposed to be there.
I was trying to save another toywhen--
Was it becauseyou're damaged?
Hmm? Did this Andy breakyou ?
Yeah, but-- No, no, no, no, no!
It was-- It was an accident.
- I mean--
- Sounds like he really loves you .
It's not like that, okay?
And I'm not going to any museum!
- Well, I'm not going back into storage!
- [Door Opening]
- [ Gasps ]
- [Pete ]Al's coming!
- Go! Go on,Jessie.Jessie, look at me.
- Oh, oh, oh.
I promiseyou'll come out of the box.
Now go! Go!
** [Al Humming]
It's show time!
[ Chuckles ] Oh, money, baby.
Money, money, money.
[ Laughs Evilly] And now,
the main attraction.
** [ Resumes Humming ]
[ Gasps, Screams ]
No! His arm! Where's his arm?
Oh... no. No, no, no, no!
What am I gonna do?
I know. I know.
[ Muttering ] Come on! Come on!
Come on! Pick up the phone!
- [ Man ] Hello?
- It's me. It's Al.
I got an emergency here.
- Well, I'm busy.
- Yes, we're all busy.
Look. It has to be tonight.
- [ Man Responds, Indistinct ]
- All right. All right.
But first thing in the morning.
[ Screams ] It's gone!
I can't believe it!
- My arm is completely gone!
- All right. Come here. Let me see that.
- [ Gasping ]
- Oh, it's just a popped seam,
easily repaired.
- you should consider yourself lucky.
- Lucky?
are you shrink-wrapped?
I am missing my arm!
Big deal.
Let him go.
I'm sure his precious Andy...
is dying to playwith
a one-armed cowboy doll.
Why,Jessie, you know he wouldn't last
an hour on the streets in his condition.
It's a dangerous world
out there for a toy.
[ Owl Hooting]
[ Gasping ]
[ Chuckles ]
All right.
Nobody look till I get my cork back in.
- Good work, men.
Two blocks down and only 1 9 more to go.
- What?
- [ All ] Nineteen?
- Are we gonna do this all night?
- My parts are killing me.
- Come on, fellas.
Did Woody give up
when Sid had me strapped to a rocket?
- [ All ] No.
- No.
And did he give up when you threw him
out of the back of that moving van?
- Oh, you had to bring that up.
- No, he didn't!
We have a friend in need, and we will
not rest until he's safe in Andy's room!
- **["Star-Spangled Banner"]
- Now let's move out!
[ Announcer]
And that concludes our broadcast day.
[ Static ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Snorting ]
[ Crunching]
- [ Crunching]
- [ Gasps ]
Bullseye. Bullseye, go, go, go, go.
Oh, tsk. Come on. you don't wanna
help me. I'm the bad guy.
you're gonna go back in storage
because of me, remember? Just go.
Bullseye-- [ Sputtering ]
All right. All right.
Butyou have got
to keep quiet. Come on.
Over here. Attaboy.
Okay, Bullseye. Upsy-daisy.
[ Continues Snoring ]
[ Muffled Grunting ]
[ Chuckling ]
Psst. Bullseye. Cut it out.
Stop it. Psst.
Stop it, Bullseye. Stop it. Stop it.
Stop it.
[Rumbling]
- [ Burping ]
- [ Groaning ]
[ Gagging ]
[ Exhaling ]
[ Snorting ]
- Phew.
- [Remote Clicks ]
- * Woody's Roundup
Come on, it's time to play *
- [ Gasping ]
No, of ficer! I swear.
[ Muttering ] What? [ Gasps ]
[ Gasping, Muttering]
Uh-- Oh.
Get in there.
There you go. Cheap case.
- Where is the remote?
- ** [Theme Song Continues ]
Where is the remote?
[ Grunting]
Why don't I put it in the same place
every ti-- Oh, here it is.
[ Yawning ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Door Closing ]
What is you r problem? Look, I'm sorry
I can't help you guys out.
Really, I am. But you didn't have
to go and pull a stunt like that.
What? you think I did that?
Oh, right, right.
The TV just happened to turn on,
and the remote magically ended up
in front of you !
- you calling me a liar?
- Well, if the boot fits--
Say that again.
[ Enunciating ]
if the boot fits.
Okay, cowboy.
- Yah!
- [ Grunting ]
How doyou like that?
Take it back! Take it back!
Don't thinkjust'cause you're a girl,
I'm gonna take it easy on you .
- [ Screams ]
-Jessie, Woody, you stop this at once.
- [ Cries Out ]
- [ Gasps ]
I don't know
howthat television turned on,
but fighting about it
isn't helping anything.
- if I had both my arms--
- The fact is, you don't, Woody,
so I suggest
you just wait until morning.
- The cleanerwill come, fixyou r arm--
- And then I'm outta here!
Oh, no, no.
Bullseye, don't take it that way.
- It's just that Andy--
- Andy, Andy, Andy.
That's all he ever talks about.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Buzz, can we slow down?
May I remind you that some of us are
carrying over six dollars in change?
Losing health units.
Must rest.
- Is everyone present and accounted for?
- Not quite everyone.
- Who's behind?
- Mine.
Hey, guys.
Why do the toys cross the road?
- Not now, Hamm.
- Oh, I love riddles. Why?
To get to the chicken
on the other side! [ Laughs ]
- [All Whooping]
- [ Rex ] The chicken!
- Oh, well. We tried.
- We'll have to cross.
- What the-- you're not
turning me into a mashed potato.
- [ All Gasping ]
I may not be a smart dog,
but I know what roadkill is.
There must be a safe way.
[Buzz] Okay.
Here's our chance. Ready. Set. Go.
[ Whimpering ]
Drop!
- [ Air Hissing ]
- [Horns Honking]
[ Buzz ] Go!
[ Buzz ] Drop! I said "drop"!
- [ Horns Honking ]
- [ Buzz ] Go!
[ Mumbling ]
[ Buzz ] Drop.
[ Horn Honking, Tires Squealing ]
[Buzz] Go.
That went well.
[ Horns Honking ]
Good job, troops.
We're that much closer to Woody.
[Honking Continues ]
- [ Ringing ]
- Oh, thank goodness you're here.
Is the specimen ready for cleaning?
So, uh, how long is this gonna take?
you can't rush art.
[Bellowing]
[Wheels Squeaking]
[Slinky] Oh, no. It's closed.
We're not preschool toys, Slinky.
We can read.
- [ Doors Mooing ]
- [Man ] Hey,Joe,you're late.
- We've got
a ton of toys to unload in the back.
- All right. All right.
- I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
- All right. Let's go.
[ Rex ] But the sign says it's closed.
No, no, no, no. All together. Now!
- [ All Grunting ]
- [ Doors Mooing ]
[ Giggling ]
Whoa, Nelly! How are we going to
find Woody in this place?
Look for Al. We find Al,
we find Woody. Now move out!
- Woody?
- Woody.
[ Motor Pumping ]
[ Air Hissing ]
Thereyou go.
[ Chuckles ]
He's for display only.
you handle him too much,
he's not gonna last.
It's amazing. you're a genius.
He's just like new.
[ Gasps ]
Wow.
[Whistles ]
I could use one of those.
you know, they make it soyou can't
defeat Zurg unless you buy this book.
It's extortion.
That's what it is.
Hey, I always thought
the golden sectorwas the only--
- [ Screams ]
- [ Hamm ] I thought
we could search in style.
Nice going there, Hamm. So how about
letting a toywith fingers drive?
Am I really that fat?
[Whistles ]
- [ Grunting ]
- Ow!
- What are you doing?
- you're in direct violation
of Code 6404.5,
stating all space rangers
are to be in hyper-sleep...
until awakened by authorized personnel.
- Oh, no.
- [ Grunts ]
you're breakin' ranks, ranger.
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
- I've got an AWOL space ranger.
- Tell me I wasn't this deluded.
No back talk!
I have a laser, and I will use it.
-you mean the laser that's a light bulb?
-[ Laser Humming ]
[ Gasps ] Has you r mind been melded?
you could've killed me, space ranger.
Or should I say "traitor"?
- I don't have time for this.
- Halt!
I orderyou to halt!
[ Both Grunting ]
Listen to me.
Listen. Wait.
- We've been down this aisle already.
- We've never been down this aisle.
- It's pink.
- Face it. We're lost.
- [ Hamm ] Back it up. Back it up.
- [ All Giggling ]
- **[Beach]
- What a great party!
Howlow canyou go?
[ Giggling Continues ]
Excuse me, ladies. Does anyone
know where we might find the Al
of Al's Toy Barn?
I can help.
I'm Tour Guide Barbie.
Please keepyou r hands, arms
and accessories inside the car,
and no flash photography.
-Thankyou .
-I'm a married spud. I'm a married spud.
- I'm a married spud.
- Then make room for the single fellas.
[ Barbie ] To our right is
the HotWheels aisle. Developed in 1 967,
the original series had 1 6 cars,
including the Corvette.
I beg you r pardon, ma'am,
butwhere's Al's of fice?
Please hold all questions
until the end of the tour. Thankyou .
[ Screams ]
It says howyou defeat Zurg! Look!
-Hey, get this outta here, "geek-osaur."
-Excuse me, sir. [ Gasps ]
- [Potato Head] Look out!
- Stop, stop, stop!
[ All Yelling ]
- [ Rex Whimpering ]
- [ Hamm ] Turn into the spin, Barbie!
[ Screams ]
My source of power!
No! Come back![Yells ] Hey!
Wait up! Hey!
Come on! Slow down!
Dinosaur overboard!
Slow down! [ Cries Out ]
Remain seated, please.
[ Recites In Spanish ]
Ow! Listen to me. Listen to me.
you're not really a space ranger.
you're a toy.
We're all toys. Doyou hear me?
- Well, that should hold you
till the court martial.
- Let me go!
you don't realize whatyou're doing!
And this is the Buzz Lightyear aisle.
Back in 1 995, shortsighted retailers did
not order enough dolls to meet demand.
- Hey, Buzz!
- Halt! Who goes there?
Quit clownin' around and get in the car!
Buzz, Buzz, I know how to defeat Zurg!
- you do?
- Come on. I'll tellyou on the way.
No, no, guys! you've got the wrong Buzz!
you've got the wrong Buzz!
Say, where'd you
get the cool belt, Buzz?
Well, slotted pig,
they're standard issue.
No!
[Flash Popping]
- [ Al Chuckling ]
It's like printing my own money.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Yeah? What?
- [ Man Speaking, Indistinct ]
Oh, oh. Mr. Konishi.
Yes, uh, I have the pictures right here.
In fact, I'm in the car right now on
myway to the of fice to fax them toyou .
I'm going through a tunnel!
I'm breakin' up!
Oh, wow! Will you look at me?
It's like I'm fresh out of the box!
Look at this stitching! Andy's gonna
have a hard time rippin' this! Hello!
H-Hi! Hello!
Great. Nowyou can go.
Well, what a good idea.
[Pete]
Woody, don't be madatJessie.
She's been through more than
you know. Why not make amends
before you leave, huh?
It's the leastyou can do.
[ Groans ] All right.
But I don't know what good it'll do.
Hey. Whatcha doin' way up here?
Thought I'd get one last look at
the sun before I get packed away again.
Look,Jessie.
I knowyou hate me for leaving,
but I have to go back.
I'm still Andy's toy.
Well, if you knew him, you'd understand.
See, Andy's a real--
Let me guess.
Andy's a real special kid.
And to him, you're his buddy,
his best friend.
And whenAndyplays withyou ,
it's like even thoughyou're not moving,
you feel like you're alive,
because that's how he sees you .
How did you know that?
Because Emily was just the same.
She was mywhole world.
[Woman ]
* When somebodylovedme*
* Everything was beautif ul*
* Every hour we spent together *
* Lives within my heart*
* And when she was sad*
* I was there to dry her tears *
* And when she was happy so was I *
* When she loved me *
* Through the summer and the fall *
* We had each other
That was all *
*Just she and I together *
* Like it was meant to be *
* And when she was lonely *
* I was there to comfort her *
* And I knew that *
* She loved me *
[ Both Giggling ]
* So the years went by *
* I stayed the same *
* But she began to drif t away *
* I was left alone *
* Still I waited for the day *
* When she'd say *
* I will always love you *
* Lonely and forgotten *
* I never thought she'd look my way *
* She smiled at me and held me *
*Just like she used to do *
* Like she loved me *
* When she loved me *
* When somebody loved me *
* Everything was beautif ul *
* Every hour we spent together *
* Lives within my heart *
* When she loved me **
you never forget kids
I i ke Em i ly or Andy.
[ Whisperi ng ]
But they forget you .
-J essie, I -I didn't know.
-J ust go.
How long will it last, Woody?
Doyou really think...
Andy is gonna take you
to college or on his honeymoon?
Andy's growing up,
and there's nothingyou can do about it.
It's you r choice, Woody.
you can go back, oryou can stay
with us and last forever.
you'll be adored
by children for generations.
Who am I to break up the Roundup gang?
- Hey, Woody, are you in here?
- Nah. This one's empty too.
- Woody! Woody!
- Woody!
Pardon me, gentlemen, but have either of
you seen a cowboy doll with a bad arm?
- Why, no, I haven't.
- Hey! He was talkin' to me!
- No! He was talkin' to me!
- Why, you --
- [ Both Grunting ]
- you see, all along,
we thought the way into Zurg's fortress
was through the main gate,
but in fact, the secret entrance
is to the left, hidden in the shadows.
-To the left and in the shadows. Got it.
-[Al SpeakingJapanese ]
- Someone's coming.
- Everyone take cover.
It was a big pileup, but I don't want
to boreyou with the details.
Yes. Now, let me
confirm you r fax number.
- [ Man ] 01 1 -- [ Continues ]
- 01 1. Wait.
That's a lot of numbers. No. I got it.
- It's him.
- The chicken man.
- Funny, he doesn't look like poultry.
- [ Slinky]
That's the kidnapper, all right.
A kidnapper!
An agent of Zurg if l ever saw one.
[ Grunting ]
And the pice de rsistance!
I promise the collection will be
the crown jewel of you r museum.
- It's Woody!
- Nowthat I haveyou rattention,
- imagine we added
another zero to the price, huh?
- [ Man Speaking, Indistinct ]
- I'll pay anything you want.
- Yes! Yes!
you got a deal!
I'll be on the next flight toJapan!
Quick.
Into the poultry man's cargo unit.
He'll lead us toZurg.
Move, move, move!
[ Sputtering ] Don't touch my moustache!
[ Scatting Happily]
[ Grunts ]
[AlSpeaking, Indistinct]
Rich, rich, rich, rich!
[ Laughing Maniacally]
- [ Gasps ]
- ** [ Humming Happily]
[ Grunts ]
** [ Continues Humming ]
[ Groans ]
Huh?
[ Grunts ]
[ Doors Mooing ]
[ Radar Buzzing ]
[ Growls ] Destroy Buzz Lightyear.
Destroy Buzz Lightyear.
- [ Rex ] Ha! He didn't take the bag!
- No time to lose!
[ Grunting ]
He's ascending
in the vertical transporter.
All right, everyone. Hang on.
We're gonna blast through the roof .
- Uh, Buzz?
- To infinity and beyond!
What are you ? Insane? We're
wasting time. Stand still, Godzilla.
- [ Grunting ]
- I don't understand.
Somehow, my fuel cells have gone dry.
- [ Screams ]
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Laser Buzzing ]
[ Laser Stops ]
- [ Bell Dings ]
- Blast. He's on level 23.
How are we gonna get up there?
Maybe if we find some balloons,
we could float to the top.
are you kidding?
I say we stack ourselves up,
push the intercom
and pretend we're delivering a pizza.
How about a ham sandwich...
with fries and a hot dog?
- What about me?
- you can be the toy
that comes with the meal.
Troops! Overhere. [ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
Just like you said, lizard man.
"In the shadows to the left."
Okay. Let's move!
Mission log. Have infiltrated
enemy territorywithout detection...
and are making ourway
through the bowels of Zurg's fortress.
you know, I think that Buzz aisle
went to his head.
[ Slinky] Oh, no.
Which way do we go?
-This way!
-[ Potato Head ] What makes you so sure?
- I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
- [Motor Whirring]
We've been detected. The walls!
They're closing in! Quick!
- Help me prop up vegetable man,
orwe're done for.
- Hey! Put me down, you moron!
Guys, look! It's not the walls!
It's the elevator!
Come on. We've got no time to lose.
Everyone grab hold!
- [ Hamm ] What?
- [ Slinky] Huh?
[ Hamm ] Uh, Buzz,
why not just take the elevator?
They'll be expecting that.
[Rex] Hey, Buzz!Stop!
Slow down!
To overnight six packages
to Japan is how much?
- [ Woman Speaking, Indistinct ]
- What? That's in yen, right?
Dollars? [ Groans ]
you are deliberately taking advantage...
of people in a hurry, you know that?
All right. [ Sputtering ]
I'll do it! All right. Fine.
I'll have the stuff
waiting in the lobby, and you'd
better be here in 1 5 minutes,
- because I have a plane
to catch, doyou hear me?
- [Door Closing]
Whoo-hoo!
We're finally going.
Can you believe it?
[ Laughs ]
That's custom-fitted foam insulation
you'll be riding in, Bullseye.
First class all the way!
you know what?
I'm actually excited about this.
I mean it.
I really am!
- And why shouldn'tyou be?
- Yee-hah!
- Whoa!
- * Swing you r partner do-si-do *
- Look atyou , dancing cowboy!
- Look! I'm doin' the box step!
[ Woody Laughs ]
[ Grunting ]
Uh-oh. Hey, heads up down there!
- Whoa! Pork bellies are fallin'.
- Hey, how much farther, Buzz?
[ Grunting ]
Halfway there.
[ Groaning ]
My arms can't hold on much longer!
[ Toys Crying Out ]
[ Grunting ]
Too... heavy.
- Oh! What was I thinking?
My antigravity servos!
- [ Hydraulic Whirring ]
Hang tight, everyone.
I'm going to let go of the wall.
- What?
- He wouldn't.
- One--
- He would.
- Two--
- [ All Protest ]
- Three!
- [ Toys Screaming ]
[Toys Landing, Grunting]
To infinity and beyond!
- Approaching destination.
Reengaging gravity.
- [ Hydraulic Whirring ]
[ Laser Buzzing ]
- Area secure. It's okay, troops.
- [ All Moaning ]
The antigravity sickness will wear of f
momentarily. Now let's move!
Remind me to glue his helmet shut
when we get back.
How'bout givin' me
a little intro there,Jessie?
Introducing the high-ridin'-est
cowboy around--
- you forgot "rootin'-tootin'-est"!
- [ Giggles ]
The high-ridin'-est, rootin'-tootin'-est
cowboy hero of all time,
Sherif fWoody!
- Say, little missy, you notice
any trouble around these parts?
- [ Snorts Laughter]
Nary a bit,
not with Sherif fWoody around.
Wait-wait-wait-wait-wait! I got it!
I got it! This is great! Okay!
The bandits got the critters
tied up in the burning barn,
and now for the best part!
Help us!
The barn's on fire!
I've gotya, critters.
No need to worry.
Woody saves the day again!
- Yee-hah!
- Now, where's my trustysteed Bullseye?
I have to ride of f
into the sunset-- Oh!
Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans, Chuckles ]
[ Giggling ] W-W-Watch it.
Wait. I'm ticklish, okay?
- Oh, you are?
- No, no, no. Cut it out.
Stop it. Stop it.
- No, please. No, no. Stop! Stop!
- [ Laughing ]
[ Laser Buzzing ]
Mission log. Have reached
Zurg's command deck, but no sign
of him or his wooden captive.
- [Woody] Please, no!
- That's Woody!
- [ Howling ]
- This way!
[Woody] Please, please, no!
[Potato Head] Buzz, canyou see?
What's going on?
[ Tickling, Protests Continue ]
- [Jessie ] Take that!
- [ Potato Head ]
T o the left. No, you r left.
- Take it up higher.
- [ Buzz ] What's happening?
Oh, it-it's horrible.
They-they're torturing him.
- [ Gasps ] What are we gonna do, Buzz?
- Use you r head!
But I don't wanna use my head!
[ All Screaming ]
- [ All Moaning ]
- What's going on here?
Buzz, guys!
Hey, how did you find me?
- Watch you rself!.
- [ Slinky]
We're here to spring ya, Woody!
- [ Yelling ]
- you heard of kung fu?
Well, get ready for pork chop.
Prepare to meet Mr. Angry Eyes!
[ Snarling ]
Holdit, now! Hey,you don't understand!
These are myfriends!
- Yeah, we're his friends!
- No, Rex, I mean they're my friends!
- [ Growling ]
- Hey, stop it!
Leave him alone, springy dog! Hey!
- Grab Woody, and let's go!
- Fellas, hold it! Buzz, put me down!
- Quick! To the vent!
- They're stealing him.
- [Pete ] No!
- [ WoodyYelling ]
- Hold it right there!
- Buzz?
- you again?
-Woody! Thank goodness you're all right.
-Buzz, what is going on?
Hold on. I am Buzz Lightyear,
and I'm in charge of this detachment.
- No, I'm Buzz Lightyear.
I'm Buzz Lightyear!
- I am Buzz Lightyear!
So, who's the real Buzz?
-I am!
-I am! Don't let this impostor fool you !
He's been trained byZurg himself
to mimic my every move.
[ Gasps, Chokes ]
- [ Continues Gasping]
- [ All ] Buzz!
I had a feelin' it was you ,
Buzz. My front end just had
to catch up with my back end.
Will somebody please
explain what's going on?
It's all right, space ranger.
It's a code 546.
- [ Gasps ] you mean it's a--
- Yes.
- And he's a-- [ Gasps ]
- Oh, yeah.
- you r Majesty.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Woody, you're in danger here.
We need to leave now.
- Al's selling you to a museum--
- in Japan!
- [ Chuckling ] I know. It's okay, Buzz.
- I actually wanna go.
- What?
- are you crazy?
Look, the thing is,
I'm a rare Sherif fWoody doll,
and these guys are my Roundup gang.
- What are you talking about?
- What am I talking about?
Woody's Roundup!
- What are you talking about?
- What am I talking about?
Woody's Roundup!
Oh, it's this great old TV show,
and I was the star. See? Now look.
Look! Look at me!
See? That's me!
- This is weirdin' me out.
- Buzz, it was a national phenomenon.
There was all this merchandise
that just got packed up.
Oh, you should have seen it.
There was a record player and a yo-yo--
Buzz, I was a yo-yo!
- "Was"?
-Woody, stop this nonsense and let's go.
Nah, Buzz.
[ Sighs ]
I can't go.
I can't abandon these guys.
They need me to get into this museum.
Without me, they'll go back
into storage-- maybe forever!
Woody, you're not a collector's item.
you're a child's plaything.
you are a toy!
For how much longer?
One more rip, and Andy's done with me.
And what do I do then, Buzz?
Huh? you tell me.
Somewhere in that pad of stuffing
is a toywho taught me...
that lif e's onlyworth living
if you're bein' loved by a kid.
And I traveled all this way
to rescue that toy...
because I believed him.
Well, you wasted you r time.
- Let's go, everyone.
- What about Woody?
He's not coming with us.
But-But Andy's coming home tonight.
Then we'd better make sure
we're there waiting for him.
I don't have a choice, Buzz.
This is my only chance.
To do what, Woody? Watch kids from
behind glass and never be loved again?
Some lif e.
- [TV Woody] Is everybody okay?
- [TVJessie ]Sherif fWoody!
- I knewyou'd make it!
- Now, remember, deputies,
the real treasures are
you r friends and family.
Before I go, kids, I want to share
somethin'special with you ,
- for the times I'm not around.
- Good goi ng, Woody!
I thought they'd never leave.
[ TV Woody Singing ]
* you've got a friend in me *
- Woody?
- * you've got troubles *
* Well, I've got'em too *
* There isn't anything I wouldn't do *
- * We stick together and
see it through'cause *
- [ Sighs ]
* you got a friend in me *
* Some other folks might be
a little bit smarter than I am *
* Bigger andstronger too *
Maybe.
* But none of them will ever love you *
* The way I do
It's me andyou , boy *
* Andas theyears go by *
* Our friendship will never die *
- [ Sighs ] What am I doing?
- * you're gonna see it's our destiny **
- Buzz! Wait! Wait!
- Woody, where are you going?
you're right, Prospector.
I can't stop Andy growing up.
But I wouldn't miss it for the world.
- No!
- Buzz!
- Yes?
- I'm coming with you !
[ Gasps ] Wait! Wait-wait-wait-wait.
I'll be back in just a second.
Way to go, cowboy!
- Hey, you guys-- Come with me.
- What?
Andywill playwith all of us.
I know it!
Woody, I-I--
I don't know. I--
Wouldn'tyou give anything
just to have one more daywith Emily?
Come on,Jessie. This is what it's
all about: to make a child happy.
And you know it.
Bullseye, are you with me?
[ Chuckling ]
Okay, good boy.
Prospector, how'bout you ?
- [Metallic Thud]
- [ Gasps ]
- [Jessie ] Prospector?
- you're outta you r box!
I tried reasoning with you , Woody,
but you keep forcing me
to take extreme measures.
Wait a minute. you turned on the TV
last night, notJessie.
Look, we have an eternity
to spend together in the museum.
Let's not start of f
by pointing fingers, shall we?
- you reallyare Stinky Pete, aren'tyou ?
-Prospector, this isn't fair.
" Fair"? I'll tell you what's not fair:
spending a lif etime on a dime-store
shelfwatching every other toy be sold.
Well, finally mywaiting
has paid of f,
and no hand-me-down cowboy doll
is gonna mess it up for me now!
Buzz. Help, Buzz! Guys!
It's too late, Woody. That silly
Buzz Lightweight can't helpyou .
His name is Buzz Lightyear.
Whatever. I've always hated
those upstart space toys.
[ Grunting ]
It's stuck! What do we do?
- Should I use my head?
- [ Grunts, Gasps ]
- [Rumbling]
- It's Al!
[ Gasps ]
Look at the time.
I'm gonna be late!
Oh, figures. I can't miss this flight!
I've gotta pack.
All right. Let's see.
Uh, wallet, keys, tickets,
uh, passport, beefjerky--
very expensive over there.
Shower! [ Snif fs ]
Oh, I can skip the shower.
Ijust gotta get outta here now!
[ Mutters Indistinctly ]
Quick! T o the elevator!
- [ Buzzing ]
- Hurry. I can hear it coming.
[ Gasps ]
So, we meet again, Buzz Lightyear--
for the last time.
Aah! It's Zurg! Watch out!
He's got an ion blaster!
[ Moans ]
[ Bell Dings ]
Quick! Get on!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Whimpers ]
The emergency hatch!
Come on!
[ Whimpers, Yells, Moans ]
[ Groans ]
Huh?
- Come on! Hurry!
- [ Whimpers ] But Buzz is in peril!
[ Recording, Repeating ] Buzz-- Buzz--
Buzz-- Lightyear to the rescue!
[ Muttering ]
Surrender, Buzz Lightyear.
I have won.
I'll never give in.
you killed my father!
No, Buzz.
I am you r father.
Noooo!
[Sighs Impatiently]
Come on! Come on! Come on!
[ Whimpers ] Buzz, you could have
defeated Zurg all along!
you just need to believe in you rself!.
[ Gasps ]
- Prepare to die!
- [ Whimpers ] I can't look!
Wh-Wh-Whoa!
[ Yelling ]
I did it.
I finally defeated Zurg!
Father.
[ Gasps, Grunts ]
- [ Bell Dings ]
- Ah, finally!
[ Toys Grunt ]
[ Door Slams, Engine Starts ]
- [ Horns Honking ]
- How are we gonna get him now?
Pizza, anyone?
- Go, go, go! [ Grunts ]
- I got it!
- Buzz, are you coming?
- No, I have a lot of
catching up to do with my dad.
Good throw, son.
That's my boy. Go long, Buzzy!
- Oh, you're a great dad. Yippee!
- Farewell.
- Does anyone know how to drive?
- Slink, take the pedals.
Rex, you navigate.
Hamm and Potato,
operate the levers and knobs.
Whoa.
Ohh.
- Strangers.
- From the outside.
- Oh, no.
- He's at a red light! We can catch him!
- Maximum power, Slink!
- [ Engine Revs ]
Whaa! It turned green! Hurry!
- Whywon't it go?
- Use the Wand of Power.
- [ Gears Grinding ]
- [ Tires Squealing ]
- [ Screams ]
- Ooh! Ow! Ooh!
- Rex, which way?
- Left! No, no! I mean right!
That's right! No, I mean left!
Left is right!
Buzz, he's turning left!
He's turning left!
- Oh, oh, boy!
- [ Gasps ]
Whoa-oa-oa-oa!
Oh, I seriously doubt
he's gettin' this kind of mileage.
Go right! To the right!
Right-right-right-right!
- Whoa!
- [ Gasps, Groans ]
- you have saved our lives.
We are eternally grateful.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Whatever.
[Woman Over P.A. ] The white zone is
for immediate loading and unloading--
No parking.
Guys, we can't park here!
I t's a white zone!
you have saved our lives.
We are eternally grateful.
- Final boarding call
for Far EastAirlines...
- There he is!
flight 451 to Tokyo; all confirmed
passengers must board at this time.
[ Man Over P.A. ] Passenger Twitch,
passenger Leon Twitch, please pick up--
- you have saved our lives.
We are eternally grateful.
- Will you just leave me alone?
- [ Rex ] Oh! Someone's coming!
- [ Girl ] Ooh, a puppy!
Uh, bark-bark-bark-bark.
Bark-bark-bark-bark-bark.
Listen, flyboy. The contents
of that case are worth more
than you make in a year!
- you got that, sport! you be careful!
- I understand, sir.
- Doyou have
a "fragile"sticker or something?
- Don't worry, sir.
I had a box of cookies once
that came back as crumbs!
- The Mystic Portal!
- Oooh.
Once we go through,
we just need to find that case.
[ Gasps ]
[ Toys Screaming]
[ All Groaning ]
- Ow! There's the case!
- No, there's the case!
you take that one!
We'll take this one!
[ All Grunt ]
Whoa-oa! Buzz!
Buzz, my back end's
goin' to Baton Rouge!
- Slinky!
- [ Panting ]
Here we come, Woody!
Woody, here we come! Woody!
- [ All Groan ]
- Nice flash though.
[ Panting ]
Okay, Woody, let's go!
- [ Grunts, Groans ]
- Take that, space toy.
Hey! No one does that
to my friend! [ Grunts ]
- [ Yells ]
- you r choice, Woody.
you can go to Japan
together or in pieces.
if he fixed ya once,
he can fix ya again. Now get in the box!
- Never!
- Fine!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Yells ]
[ All Shout ]
- No! Aaah!
- Gotcha!
Idiots!
Children destroy toys!
you'll all be ruined, forgotten!
Spending eternity
rotting in some landfill!
Well, Stinky Pete, I think it's timeyou
learned the true meaning of playtime.
- Right over there, guys!
- [Whimpering ] No. No! No!
[Woman OverP.A.]
AtlanticAirflight eight...
is nowarriving--
[ Girl ] Look, Barbie.
A big ugly man doll.
Ooh, he needs a makeover.
- [ Whimpering ]
- Hi! you'll like Amy.
- [ Gasps ]
- She's an artist!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Mother]
Come on, hon!
Happy trails, Prospector.
- Buzz! Woody!
- Help us out here!
- [ Gasping ]
- Hurry!
- Oh, no.Jessie! Come on!
- Oh, Woody!
[Jessie Screaming ]
Jessie!
[ Whistles ]
[ Grunts ]
Come on, Buzz.
- Yah!
- Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
Hey-howdy-hey!
Giddyap!
[ Buzz ] Come on, Bullseye! Yah!
Buzz, give me a boost!
[ Grunting, Panting ]
- Oh! Ohh! Oohhh!
- Woody!
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
- Here's the rest!
- [ Panting ] Ah!
[ Glass Tinkling, Shattering]
[ Panting, Grunting ]
Excuse me, ma'am, but I believe
you're on the wrong flight.
- Woody!
- Come on,Jess.
It's time to take you home.
- But... what if Andy doesn't like me?
- Nonsense!
Andy'll loveyou ! Besides,
- he's got a little sister.
- He does?
- Why didn'tyou say so? Let's go!
- Whoa!
[Man ] Holdit! There's a couple
more bags coming from the terminal!
Okay. On three.
- One, two--
- Too late!
Put'em on the next flight!
- This is bad.
- How are we gonna get outta here?
- [Latch Clicks ]
- Over there! Come on!
[ Grunting ]
- you sure about this?
- No! Let's go!
[ Both Gasp ]
- [ Yelling ]
- Hold on, Woody!
- [ Ripping Sound ]
- [ Yelling ]
- What's a cowboywithout his hat?
- Buzz!
- [ Engines Accelerating ]
- [ Whimpering ]
Buzz! Buzz, get behind the tires!
[ Panting, Grunting ]
Jessie, let go of the plane!
- What? are you crazy?
-Just pretend it's
the final episode of Woody's Roundup.
But it was canceled!
We never saw if you made it!
Well, then, let's find out together!
[ Both Screaming ]
Oh-oh-oh.
- We did it! We did it! We did it!
- [ Laughing ]
- Nice ropin', cowboy.
- That was definitely
Woody's finest hour!
- [ Laughing ]
- you r hat, partner.
- Hoo-hoo!
- [ Engines Roaring ]
Let's... go home.
Yee-hah!
[ Panting ]
** [ Hums Lone Ranger Theme ]
Hey, Woody! Woody?
Oh, wow! New toys!
Cool! Thanks, Mom!
It's Bazooka Jane and herjet-propelled
horse! [ Makes Jet Sounds ]
Woody, Buzz, that polecat Zurg
has stolen my space cows!
[ Continues, Indistinct]
Andy, come on, hon.
Time to go.
- Hey, you fixed Woody!
- Yeah.
Glad I decided not to take him to camp.
His whole arm might have come of f.
Well, what do you know?
Yee-hah! Oh, Bullseye,
we're part of a family again!
Hmm?
Uh, m-ma'am, I, uh--
[ Clears Throat ]
Well, I just wanted to say
you're a brightyou ng woman
with a beautif ul "yarnful" of hair.
Uh, "hairful" of yarn.
It's, uh-- Whoo-- Uh--
- [ Clears Throat ] I must go.
- Well, aren't you
the sweetest space toy I ever met?
[Barking]
- What's that? Bark-bark?
- [ Barking ]
This fella says he needs to go out
for a little private time.
That critter needs help!
*Yodel-ay-hee-hoo *
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Barks ]
Ooh, ooh, oh-- Hey, Rex,
I could use a hand over here, buddy.
I don't need to play--
I've lived it!
- No-no-no-no! Oh, nuts!
- [ Clicks Channel ]
[ Weeping ]
Welcome to Al's Toy Barn.
We've got the lowest prices in town.
Everything for a buck-buck-buck.
[ Sobbing ]
Well, I guess crime doesn't pay.
Oh, Andy did a great job, huh?
Nice and strong!
- I like it. Makes you look... tough.
- [ Giggles ]
- [ Smooching ]
- [ Laughing ]
- you have saved our lives.
We are eternally grateful.
- [ Groans ]
you saved their lives?
Oh, my hero!
- And they're so adorable!
Let's adopt them!
- Daddy!
- Oh, no.
- [ Squeaking ]
Wheezy, you're fixed!
Oh, yeah. Mr. Shark looked in the
toy box and found me an extra squeaker.
- And... how do you feel?
- Oh, I feel swell.
In fact, I think I feel
a song comin' on.
** [ Big Band ]
[ Robert Goulet's Voice ]
*you've got a friend in me *
*you just remember
whatyou r old pal said *
-* Babe,you've got a friendin me*
- [Barking]
- [ Giggling]
-* Yeah,you've got a friendin me *
Come on over.
Oh,you are such a big girl.
Andy, you think she's ready
to drive the caryet?
- Yeah, and I can teach her.
- [ Barking ]
- you still worried?
- About Andy?
- Nah. It'll be fun while it lasts.
- I'm proud of you , cowboy.
Besides, when it all ends, I'll have
old Buzz Lightyear to keep me company...
for infinity and beyond.
*you're gonna see it's our destiny *
- *you got a friend in me *
- *Yes, you do *
- * you've got a friendin me*
- * That's the truth*
* you've got a friend*
* In me **
Yeah!
*WOODY'S ROUNDUP
RIGHTHERE EVERY DAY *
* WOODY'S ROUNDUP
COME ON, IT'S TIME TO PLAY *
* THERE'SJESSIE
THE YODELING COWGIRL *
** [ Chorus Yodeling]
* BULLSEYE
HE'S WOODY'S HORSE*
HE'S A SMART ONE.
* MEET THE OLD PROSPECTOR *
* AND WOODY THE MAN HIMSELF *
* OF COURSE, IT'S TIME
FOR WOODY'S ROUND UP *
* HE'S THE VERY BEST
HE'S THE ROOTIN'-EST
TOOTIN'-EST COWBOY *
* IN THE WILD, WILD WEST *
* WOODY'S ROU N DU P
COME ON AND GA THER'ROUND *
WHERE NOBODY WEARS A FROWN *
* BAD GUYS GO RUNNIN'
WHENEVER HE'S IN TOWN *
* HE'S THE ROOTIN'-EST
TOOTIN'-EST, SHOOTIN'-EST
HOOTIN'-EST COWBOY AROUND *
* WOODY'S ROUND UP **
* YOU'VE GOT A FRIEND IN ME *
* WHEN THE ROAD
L OOKS ROUGH AHEAD *
* AND YOU'RE MILES AND MILES
FROM YOU R NICE, WARM BED *
* YOU JUST REMEMBER
WHA T YOU R OLD PAL SAID *
* SON, YOU'VE GOT
A FRIEND IN ME *
* YEAH, YOU'VE GOT
* YOU'VE GOT A FRIEND IN ME *
* YOU GOT TROUBLES
THEN I GOT'EM TOO *
* THERE ISN'T ANYTHING
I WOULDN'T DO *
* WE STICK TOGETHER
WE CAN SEE IT THROUGH *
*'CAUSE YOU'VE GOT
A FRIEND IN ME *
* YES, YOU DO *
* YEAH, YOU'VE GOT
A FRIEND IN ME *
* SOME OTHER FOLKS MIGHT BE
A LITTLE SMARTER THAN I AM *
* BIGGER AND STRONGER TOO *
* MA YBE *
* BUT NONE OF THEM
WILL EVER LOVE YOU *
* THE WAY I DO
JUST ME AND YOU , BABE *
* AND AS THE YEARS GO BY *
* OUR FRIENDSHIP
WILL NEVER DIE *
* YOU'RE GONNA SEE
IT'S OUR DESTINY *
* YOU'VE GOT A FRIEND IN ME *
* YOU JUST REMEMBER
WHA T YOU R OLD PAL SAID *
* SON, YOU'VE GOT
A FRIEND IN ME *
* AND AS THE YEARS GO BY *
* GO BY *
* OUR FRIENDSHIP
WILL NEVER DIE *
* DIE *
* YOU'RE GONNA SEE
IT'S OUR DESTINY *
* YOU'VE GOT A FRIEND IN ME *
* YES, YOU DO *
* YEAH **