Created by Alireza SK
alireza_salehi68@yahoo.com
You still smoke?
No, it's because of getting old
Here you are
Look at your bag...
Have you got a car?
No, I borrowed it
What's this?
It's too cold
Yeah
What's up?
My wrist hurts
Leave it to me..
You have become old, too
Look over there see if I can pass
Yeah, there is enough space
Stop...Stop
What are you doing?
The past
Do the girls know that I've arrived?
No
Didn't you tell them?
I was afraid that you couldn't come
like the last time
Put it in fourth gear
Now I'm here, you can tell them
I want to see them
We're going to see them
Where?
We'll pick up Luci from school then we get home
Didn't you book the hotel?
No
You were supposed to...
I wasn't sure you would come.
What't than supposed to mean?
I Was not SURE
Look, last time I got so busy...
Two days before my flight...
Forget it...
If you want to explain, it takes the whole time you're here
Because I had to cancel my flight?
No
For many things
Children will be happy if you come home.
I didn't mean any trouble for you.
You don't.
Anyway, you had to come home to take your suitcase.
At least you can change your clothes not to get cold.
She was going to fine you, I had to move the car.
What happend?
She is gone.
Did you tell her we would pick her up?
Let's go.
Maybe we're late then she has gone home.
It's not her first time.
Last time she got home at 11.
It's because of their age, It's normal.
No it's not normal.
What has happened to her?
She has been irritating me
for silly things for two months.
Can you talk to her?
Maybe you can get what is wrong with her.
If she remembers me, after this long time.
She loves you very much.
Yet?
Don't go that way...where are you going?...
This way.
Sorry
you forgot everything.
I got distracted.
Marie, don't put them in the car it's dangerous.
Is Luci back?
No
Fouad, you broke it.
Pull it firm.
I can't... it's cutting my hand.
No, no...Not this way.
First, one side should be set then the othe side.
Let me show you.
This one...
We set it in this way...
Alright
It needs some oil, do you know where it is?
We used to put it on that shelf in the store
Ahmad
Lea, Are you ok?
You have really grown up..!
Hello Sir
Your friend is a bit stuck-up!!
What's his name?
My name is Fouad
Hello Fouad.
Are you alright?
Ahmad, Come in
Fouad, come to your room and take your things, come on
It was not in the store
So, it must have been moved when I was not here.
My father has some in his car.
What happend to bookcase that was there?
The old one, it was wooden.
We threw it out.
Really? some of my books were in that bookcase.
We gathered all of your stuff and put them in the store.
Fouad, take your your stuff.
I don't like to sleep upstairs.
What?
I do not like to sleep up.
Do what I said.
Be careful not to be painted.
Wasn't the last colour better?
It isn't done yet, my wrist didn't keep up
I couldn't finish it up
You should have waited for me
I would have painted it myself.
It would've kept me busy here.
You were going to go to hotel.
Give it to me.
Ouch..! keep it back
I got burned.
Sorry
That's enough, thank you.
It's ok.
I put the car keys here.
Thanks.
I put you some clothes upstairs
change them not to get cold.
What are you doing here?
Come on... you sleep up
and Luci sleeps down.
Luci, call me pleaase, I have got a good news for you.
Just till Ahmad is here.
Go please...
She drives me crazy.
Is that your father's car in front of the door?
Yes
Do you live here?
With your father?
Yes
How long?
Since the school began.
You don't need to make this bed,
come down go to your own bed.
Go up... Get down.
What?
One says go up, one says get down.
I'm sorry.
Why did you come down?
He told me.
Ask himself
such beard he has.
There isn't enough bed for three of them down there.
Do you live with someone here?
Yeah
You didn't tell me.
I didn'tell you?
I wrote you in one of my E-mails.
What E-mail?
I can't remember, I told you in one of them.
I didn't recieve such an E-mail.
So, why did you want to go to hotel?
I didn't want to make you uncomfortable.
Anyway, I had told you.
But  I didn't recieve such an E-mail.
So what did you think I told you come to court to get divorced for?
Does he know that I'm here?
Yes
So I leave.
He doesn't come till you are here.
If he does, he will let us know.
When did you send me that e-mail?
I don't know.
So it must be in your E-mails now, yeah?
Yes, I suppose.
Do you want me to show you?
You were supposed to book me a hotel.
Last time I did, But you didn't come.
I had to cancel it.
How much did you pay for canceling?
When should I be in the court tomorrow?
You said you would talk to Luci.
When does she come?
I don't know.
I'll see her tomorrow.
I hoped you would keep your promise
just for once in your life.
I didn't make you any promise.
Yeah, you're right. I'm sorry.
Fouad, Is it hard for you to look where you step on?
Why do I clean here?
that you make it dirty!!
Look at me.
We went to bring this.
I don't care what you went to bring.
Fouad, Get back here.
I told you get back here.
Told you come here.
Leave me alone.
Leave me.
Stop it.
Fouad, Come here.
Leave me.
Come down, I'm tired of you.
Leave me alone.
Stop it.
Stop it Foaud.
Leave me.
Look what you've done here.
Stop it.
Go...Get in.
I told you leave me...leave me.
Please...sorry...sorry
Let go of me, I want to go my own home.
Sorry
Get out.
You drive me crazy, Fouad
Put an end to this Fouad.
I want to go to our own home.
You stay here Fouad.
Open it.
Open the door.
I want to go to our own home.
You should go, you're running late.
I'm cleaning
I'll do it
No, I'll do it myself
Don't do that with your injured wrist.
Give it to me
You wanted to go?
I'll wait for Luci to come
You should go
Lea, give me my shoes please, come on
Do you keep an eye on them?
Yes, you can go
Thank you
Open the door...
Open it...
Foaud, come down
Stay back, I want to open the door
What?
hmm?
Where are you going?
Stop
Leave me
Ok, come down
Let go of my hands
Come down Fouad, first tell me where you wanna go
Take it easy Fouad
What are you doing?
I want to go
Where?
Our home
Where is it?
Paris, it's too far
he can't go there
Shut up, no one asked you anything
Don't talk like that here..
Got it?
You go, I want to talk to Fouad
What's up Fouad?
What has happened?
I want to go to our own home
Do you want make a call there?
No one is there
What is bothering you here?
Becuase she had a fight with you? yeah?
You were not a good kid either
You splashed the paints over the floor
Didn't you?
That's not because of the paints
So why?
Because I'm here? yeah?
Do you want me to leave?
Hello Madam
Hello
You ok?
Not bad
His flight had a delay
Has he arrived?
Yeah
Here you are
Where did you park it?
Over there
Where?
There
Don't put them in the car, it's dangerous
Did you go to the hospital today?
yes
So how is she?
As usual
Didn't you bring Fouad?
What for?
He called me to pick him up
He said he doesn't want to be ther any more
I had a fight with him, with both of them
I'll pick him up tonight,
I take him to my place tonight
Why are you so tough about it?
It's the first time that he says so
Because it's the first time I had an argument with him
I promised him
Ok, I shouldn't have got angry
I make it up to him tonight
If you wanna come, let me know before
Such a great popcorn (speaking persian)
Fouad, Don't do that
Take it to him...be careful
Take it
I don't want it
You cut your hand
No I didn't, it has been before
It's bleeding
Ahmad, he cut himself
Luci
Ahmad?
How did you get it's me?
I knew you would come today
Little Luci
What do you eat Luci?
I don't, Tanks
Come on..please
You won't find such A great Qorme Sabzi (Persian Food) anywhere else
Unless you marry two cool iranian men
You should marry a persian woman too
How is it?
You want more?
No
What does a persian woman look like?
A persian woman...like me but a womanly type
See...like this
Did you like that?
Always like this...does she have a beard?
Do you like to go to Iran with Ahmad?
How are they?
Do you always get home late?
Just for sleep
Really?
Because I have no other place to sleep in
Why don't you want to stay here?
Like yourself...
So you move to your friend's home tomorrow
This is not my home
But your frind's home is?
I'm not comfortable here
Neither am I
Your case is different
It's hard for me to see someone everyday
who wants to marry my ex-wife
She is just your ex-wife now?
yeah
It's ridiculous
What?
You lived with her for several years
Now she is just your ex-wife
Now everything is different
We seprated
Give me a hand
I think you're old enough to understand
Old enough not to be advised by everyone
I didn't come here to advise you
Your mother asked me to have a word with you
to see what's wrong with you
I don't know why she thinks you're more comfortable with me than her
She knows what I'm angry about
I don't want to be here when that bastard comes
Luci
Come, take sit here for a moment
Isn't he a good man?
I don't know...I barely know him
So why do you call him a "bastard"?
What has he done?
Nothing
He has nothing to do here
Look, your mother is going to marry him
She has the right to marry everyone she wants
Everyone?
Even someone who has a child and his wife is in coma
Fouad's mother?
What if she was going to marry someone else?
Was it ok with you?
It makes no difference
So that guy is not your problem?
She has married three men since I was born
We had always this issue
This one also stays a couple of years and then will leave us
Can you talk to her?
What should I say to her?
Talk her out of it
Kids, are you still awake?
Fouad, get up and go to sleep
Just two mintues more...please
Just two minutes
Hi
Goog night (In Persian)
Luci
Would you sleep downstairs tonight?
Fouad and Ahmad go up
I made dinner, if you didn't have
Thanks
Do you want me to warm it up?
No thanks
Where did you get vegetables?
I went shopping with kids
You're still a good cook
Just a good cook...nothing more
What time should we be there tomorrow?
You don't eat Qorme Sabzi with fork
Did you forget it?
Take this
Did you talk to her?
Yes
So what?
As you guess
She doesn't like you marring again
She is afraid that he leaves you after a while
Make her sure that he doesn't
I think I'm not the right person to make her understand
That she should be happy about your marriage
I didn't say she should be happy
I just wanted to know what's her problem
What she want
She wants you don't marry
Yes, I laughed too
Try to convince her before you make youe decision
I've already made my decision
Fouad
Yes
If you aren't comfortable, we can change our bed
No, I'm ok
I need to pee
Ok, get up...
Come on
Did you talk to her doctor?
No, just her nurse
What did she say?
What do you mean?
The scratches on her stomache
She said she did that to herself after I paied her a visit again
Maybe it has nothing to do with you visiting her
Maybe it was unintentional
Do you like it to be unintentional?
I'm sorry
You know waht you're saying?
You can't say whatever you want and then make an apology
Why are you here?
It's dark, I fear to go up
Why do you want to go up?
I told him to go up with Ahmad
The girls sleep downstairs
Maybe he doesn't feel comfortable to sleep next to a stranger
Go, get dressed
I want to go to bed, I feel sleepy
Didn't you tell me to pick you up?
I want to saty here
Get in, sleep next to me
Ahmad, It's running late
It's clogged
Put it for later, we must be there at 9
Kids, shake a leg
Is it delicious?
How are you?
Hello kids
Hi
Samir
Sorry, my hands are dirty
It's blocked again?
No, I fixed it, I just need to fasten it
Would you please give me the tea?
Get ready, we give you a ride
I go myself
Ahmad, we're running late
It's done
Come on kids, get ready
It's still dripping
It was dripping before
I had told you that it needs a washer
Let me fix it
Please go over there
Have you had your breakfast?
Not yet
Can I see you somewhere?
Don't you go to school?
Ahmad
I'm coming
I can skip the school today
When are you off?
At one
Are you looking for something?
No
Wait
I'm attacking...
Isn't the school Luci used to go?
Yeah, it is
Get off
Goodbye kids
Goodbye
Bye mom
Bye dear
Hold on
You can go, bye
Where did you meet each other?
In pharmacy
He used to come and get medicine for his wife
What was wrong with his wife?
She had depression
What's up?
What?
Hmm....What does that mean?
In our culture it means laugh
But here it means mocking
Was it funny?
Have you missed fighting?
Here it means making fun of...was it funny
Is her depression funny?
If you get on my nerve, I'll stop here and go to Tehran right away
- I dont divorce you and your plans will be cancelled
- You haven't changed a bit
Should I pull over?
We're late
Should I stop?
Now...What do you really think about him?
You first tell me how serious it is...the I'll tell you
If it wasn't serious, I wouldn't get pregnant
Miss, come please
Were you kiding?
No
The terms of both side would be considered
Ms. Brisson you no longer use your husband's name
And you're called with your own last name
It needs to be mentioned that Ms.Brisson keeps her house
Your divorce will be registered on Oct 19, 2012 which means today
Both sides keep their own possessions...
Sorry
Turn it off please!
Both sides keep their own possessions and common properties
will be divided by your own agreement
you both should pay the tax
and the cost of divorce is divided between you two
This document explains the agreements of your divorce
If you approve what I read, let the divorce proceed
Are you sure about this madam?
Yes
What about you sir?
Your divorce will be registered here today
and I attach the terms I read to finish off everything
Please turn it off
Marie, It's me. They brought the suitcase from the airport
but it's handle is broken, I don't know if somethong is missed
Take it...what else can I do?!!
Give me a call
Ok?
What if something is missed?
Does it have insurance?
I don't know.
What should I do? Do you get it or should I take it back to airport?
Please sign here
You ok? youre yes?
I'm allergic to paints
So you should find another job
Luci
How are you?
Sorry Sir!  Where can I get the bus to Tajrish?!! (In Persian)
What the hell are you doing here?!!
When did you get here?
Yesterday
Do you know her?
She is really grown up.
How are you?
Have you had lunch?
So what do you think I came here for?
Such a beautiful lady! you remember how litte you were!
He used to bring you here with his bicycle
Shahryar...hat was her sister, she's Luci
Really...Excuse me
You always used to confuse them
Go and take a sit
Where is Valeria?
I call her
Valeria, your friend is here
Who?
Ahmad?...Ahmad !
Hello dear Valeria, How are you?
- Hello...How are you?
- ...You ok?
- I'm alright
- I missed you a lot
Oh...little Luci
Not that much little
How beautiful you are!
Are you two still together?
There's still something in common between us in order to not get seprated
The color of our flags
What are you saying again?
What is your husban saying?
He talks a lot
How is your mom?
She is ok
Did you go ot court?
Yeah
Is it done?
It was done long time ago
Do you still like Ravioli (Italian food)?
What?
I think this guy is not that much bad that you hate him.
Also he isn't in a good situation,
Put yourself in his place
His wife, his kid
How is she going to marry someone who has a wife?
You said his wife is in coma
Not dead yet
Maybe she never dies
well, this is their own problem
You know why his wife is in coma?
No
How should I know?
Didn't mom tell you?
No
She commited a suicide
Because of depression?
Luci, What's wrong?
Luci
Look at me
Let's get some fresh air
What happened?
We want to get some fresh air
Ahmad...Take her back room there
You know why she doesn't tell anyone that his wife has commited a suicide?
Come down then we talk
Because she doesn't want anyone to know
What?
That she attempted suicide because of their relationship
You shouldn't talk about it with such certainty
Especially at your age
That woman told me I grew up, but you think I didn't
Sorry
Ahmad, I don't want them to be together
You think it's in my hands or yours
I can do nothing
If they get married, I never get back to that home
Your mother is pregnant with his baby
That's not right!!
Hold on
Hold on I told you
You know why she went to went to that filthy man?
Because he was like you
Get the keys out of my pocket
The other side
Hi
You're all wet
Yeah
It suddenly got heavy
You want some coffee
No, I just came to take my suitcase
I have to get back
Look, It's over there
Wait the rain stop
I don't suppose it stop soon
Is Luci back?
No, watch out not to be painted
It's handle was broken when they delivered it
Have you called her friends?
No, I can't call them anymore
Did you talk to her today?
Yes
Have got some sort of rope to tie it up with?
There're some in a suitcase in the store
You can take them.
Are the kids asleep?
No
Would you turn it on?
Would you call the kids to give them their souvenirs
What about Fouad?
Yes, sure
You didn't have any plan for him
I've found somethig for him now
May I ask you don't do that
Why?
He has done something bad that should be punished for
Both of them are responsible for that,
And both of them should be punished
I speak on behalf of my own child
What has he done?
Without permission they took the present out of your suitcase
But the present is here now
I put it back
I don't want him to think that the problem is solved
The suitcase was open, they got temptated
I ask them to make an apology
This way they learn to get away by making an apology
I told them that I brought them some gifts
I can't ignore that
Would you stop it?
I punished them enough today
I just said if that's possible
Hello
Hi kids
No..no, at first they should make an apology
Both of them
I'm sorry
YOU?
I didn't take anything
But you were there, weren't you?
But I didn't take anything
It's not important who did
You both were there, you should've told her not to do that
Say you are sorry
Apologize
I apologize
Say I'm sorry
I'm sorry
Look at him
Apologize
I'm sorry
Ok, Come and take your presents
Come on
You spoke in a way as if I took it
I just said I took nothing
So I did it
Yes You took it
No
You told me that the suitcase is open
You didn't have to listen to me
I know why you're upset
Because he gave a helicopter but gave you coloured pencils
Shut up
Crazy
You crazy sick
I took your size four years ago
It hasn't changed
I've got something for Luci, I give it to her tomorrow
Thank you Ahmad
You smoke alot
She hasn't been late this much before
I go after her
Where?
I don't know...subway, street
Give me the car keys
They're with youself
Is it ok if I come?
Ok, If you want
Maybe she won't get back with him
Why did she cry in the restaurant?
Who told you?
I called Shahryar he told me she burst to tears
She hasn't been late this much before
What did you tell her?
Hadn't you told her that you're pregnant?
Did you tell her?
I thought she would back off
That's why she isn't back
You shouldn't have told her
I didn't know
You couldn't hide it forever
Not in this situation
Her problem isn't your preanancy
What is it so?
What is her problem? hmm?
She knows everything
She knows what?
I can't find car keys
Search for them yourself
we talk later
What did you mean she knows evetything?
I don't get it
She thinks his wife has committed suicide because of your relationship
She killed herself because of...
I'll call you tomorrow
Keys are not here
I found them
So what are you doing here?
What do you mean?
Does anyone have a problem with me being here?
I mean...
Enough
Wait for me please
Ahmad
His wife had been depressed long time ago
every time I took my clothes to his dry cleaning...
he didn't feel well
Why didn't he feel well?
What do you mean why?
Forget it
Yoy can say nothing but When you do
you have to make it clear
Look, you say he got a bad feeling whenever you saw him
I didn't say he got, I said he had
He didn't feel well
Forget it, it's getting worse
You want to hear that I'm guilty
I don't want to hear anything
You asked me talk to your daughter to see what's her problem
Now I'm telling you what she thinks
She is making a mistake
I'll tell her, if he comes
What are you going to tell her?
You think she believes you!?
You don't believe it too
You have to do something to make me believe it
She believes it
Why don't you believe it, what's odd about it?
I don'think a a mother with a five years old kid
may kill herself because of depression
You are saying that!!!
Don't you remember yourself??
A mother with a nine months old baby killed herself,
Was that because of me?
when we were together...
She had depression when she delivered her baby
You know what kind of medicine he used to get for his wife?
How long are you going to stay in Paris?
I haven't bought my ticket back yet, I don't know
Couldn't you get a lawyer instead of coming here yourself?
I prefered to come here myself to visit the girls and Marie
To end everything in a good way
Seemingly everrything isn't finished yet
Somethings are left
No
Why do you think so?
When two people see each other after four years and make a fight
It means that somethings are left
Our argument was about Luci
I'm her problem, yeah?
No
It's a misunderstanding
About what?
Something personal that I shouldn't know about?
No, It's not personal
So tell me
I don't know if you're aware of that or not, she is pregnant
All the time stress, smoking and fight
I'm worried about her, too
She didn't smoke before
I don't let that girl
to spoil everything
she should talk to me if she
has any problem with me
She dosen't have any problem, it's just a misunderstanding
What kind of misunderstanding is that has ruined my life
Let Marie tell you
Don't involve her, ok?
She thinks something else about your wife suicide
That she has killed herself because of our relationship
You know it yourself
I heard you saying that to Marie
Really?
She did that to herself over a silly fight with a client
I've been told that sha had depression
She wouldn't have done it, if she hadn't
A silly fight
What sould I do that
Luci doesn't believe it?
Tomorrow I send my worker to
talk to her who was there
Call the police and give them her characteristic
Has it happend before?
No, it's her first time
Maybe he is with his father
Brussels?
Isn't her father in Paris?
He has gone back to Brussels
Is it possible that she goes there?
No
She doesn't have a good relationship with her father
Do you want me to call him?
Let Ahmad do that
I don't think she has gone to Brussels
I call him myself
Ok, give me his number
Shahryar called, he wants you to call him back
Where is the phone?
In the kitchen
Why does she think so?
About what?
About Cline suicide
I don't know
Here it is
Her father's number
Don't make him worried
She is with Shahryar
She went to his restaurant then he took her to his home
He called here twice,
why didn't he tell me anything
He knew how much worried I was
Let me explain
Why didn't he tell me she was there
I was about to die, why he told me nothing?
Ok, I explain
What are you going to explain? hmm?
What do you want to explain?
What happened?
Nothing
I told you once in the car,
if anything happens you tell me not her
And I tell you don't shout at me
Why didn't he tell me Luci was there?
Luci made him promise
Whose house?
She had agreed to stay there
on the condition that he tell no one
He made a promise to hide a sixteen years old girl,
why did he take her to his home?
What do you mean hiding her?
he took pity on her
He cares about her not her mother
Where are the keys?
What for?
She has to get back, sit there and talk to me
Now
Right now
She thinks we don't know where she is
I don't care
She needs to see what a mess she has made.
her suicide has nothing to do with us
She doesn't get back with you.
I call the police if she doesn't
I really call the police
Police can get her back tonight.
What about the other nights
She stays here or goes to Brussels to her father
She won't get back till I'm here
Come in...
Why are you so late?
Don't you have an umbrella?
No
Put it here
How did you get here?
Subway
You'd better take a taxi
I couldn't find one
You've put yourself in trouble.
Is she awake?
She fell asleep
When did she come to you?
That was late...
I thought she was waiting for you
You should've informed us at once
Her was about to die...
How?...You don't have cellphone!
I called her home to find you
But you were not there either
I feard if I tell her mother, she would leave
What has happened?
Some illusions...
Sorry to wake you up.
She wanted to come herself, but I asked her not
Let's go
Where is your coat?
No, I don't go there.
I don't want to get back tonight.
Ok, I call her talk to her yourself
Allo Marie?
She wants to talk to you
Yeah
I saty here tonight.
Why did you hang it up?
She put the phone down.
Let's go.
No.
Get up.
I want to talk to you.
I want you to listen to me carefully.
I don't know how well you can remember
the last months that I was with your mother
You remember anything?
You remember how bad my situation was?
Yeah.
I didn't feel well at all.
I didn't work. I didn't get out.
I just wanted not to exist anymore.
That's why when your mother
says that woman committed suicide
bacause of depression
I completely understand.
Even if she had a little kid.
Did you think about suicide much?
Yes, sometimes.
Like drinking laundry liquid in front of us.
What?
No.
You think when a woman drinks
laundry liquid and tries to kills herself,
when his husband is enjoying himself,
she only wants to die?
Why not taking pills on her bed?
We can sit here and make up thousands of these stories.
But they're only a guess.
Tomorrow we're going to meet Samir's worker.
She has something to tell you.
Tell her I'm gone.
She can get back now.
We would better not be here for a while.
Fouad...get off
Get up.
Leave me.
I told you get up.
Come on. Stop it.
Thanks.
What are you doing?
When I tell you get off, you have to do it.
Look at me. When I'm talking listen to me.
Leave me.
What did you say?
Don't do that again to me.
Why is that?
Look at me. What is it?
Take your pillow.
No.
What's wrong with you?
Fouad, Speak up.
I want to get back to Marie home.
We have to get back to our own home for a while.
you said we live there no more.
Forever.
Yeah. But now is different.
Because that man came?
No.
Because I was naughty yesterday?
Why does Luci hate you?
Because she thinks I want to take her mothar away from her.
She doesn't like her mother too.
Of course she does. Like all the kids.
Like you.. Didn't you miss your mom?
Mom is not home.
Do you want to see her?
Do you want me to take to her?
No.
Why?
I'm afraid
Of mom?
Of that man.
Why do you say that Fouad?
If he hadn't been there they wouldn't
have kept her in the hospital
and unplugged the wires.
Does she die if they unplug the wires?
Why don't they do that?
Because they don't know if she wants to live with that wires or not
She wants to die.
How do you know?
When someone commits suicide
it means that he wants to die.
Sorry dad.
Here it is. That stain.
Did his wife work there?
A couple of days. Samir asked her to come...
for a change of mood.
That day Cline went on a fight with one of the clients.
"Cline" his wife?
Yes his wife.
She had a fight because that client insisted
that her clothes were stained here.
But Cline told her that they had been stained before.
That's all?
Yeah. Then I said we wash her clothes again she can take them tomorrow.
Then Cline got angry with me and said no one asked
you anything I'm the one makes decision here.
She said these clothes were stained before and it has
nothing to do with us and then threw it out of the store.
And that client called the police.
I wanted to get out of the store.
Are you a illegal worker here?
Yes I am.
Cline asked me to stay and tell the police
that her clothes were stained before.
I didn't know waht to do. Then I quietly called Samir to come.
When he came he made an apology to her
and accepted to pay for the damage caused
That client agreed on the condition that
Cline make an apology
Cline said no and then started fighting with me for calling Samir.
When I gathered up my stuff to go Samir caught my hand
and told me to saty and asked his wife to leave.
He fired her in front of me and that client and I stayed.
How many days later she atempted suicide?
About four or five.
Can I go?
Merci.
That's the way depression is.
You kill yourself for nothing.
One day before Cline suicide I sent her all the
love affair E-mails between Samir and my mother.
What are you gonna do now?
I go to Brussels.
That's nonsense, you don't stay with your father
even for two days, you have to get back to your mother.
I can't stand to see someone everyday who I caused
his wife kill herselef. I can't look at her kid.
Take a sit.
Do you want me to help you?
You don't want to talk to my mom, do you?
Listen.
I don't.
I told you take a sit.
Sit down.
I shouldn't have told you.
Listen.
You have two choices,
you can keep it secret and be in torment forever
or tell your mom everything
What's the difference?
It may have an impact on her getting married.
She won't change her decision. She's pregnant.
Imagine she learns when she has his baby,
It's too late then.
If I'd wanted I could've told her during the last months.
It doesn't matter what you want, You should see
if it's important for your mothar to know or not
She deserves to know.
Hi mom.
You ok? Would you open the door for me?
Did you get me potato crisp?
Yes I did.
You're here!!
I was upstairs with Luci.
Are you ok?
How was your meeting?
What meeting?
With Samir's worker.
Yeah...not bad.
Well?
You didn't tell Luci that I was coming?
No.
So how did she know it?
Did she know it?
How?
I don't know.
Maybe she checks your E-mails.
Where do you put it?
Something happend?
Are you in the mood of taking a walk?
No I'm tired?
What's wrong Ahmad?
You want to live with father?
If you go I'll come with you.
You need to saty with mom.
I want to be with you.
Don't think about these matters.
Father's wife is strange, isn't she?
It's ok.
Is he right?
Why did you do that to me?
Why did you do that to me? What did I do to deserve this?
you piece of shit
What did I do to you?
Let her go Marie
Come down...Come down
Take it easy.
Let go of my hand...Let go of my hand
Don't do this...Didn't you promise?
Get out of this house.
Go out for a moment.
Leave me alone.
She is in a difficult situation herself
I asked her to tell you.
She could keep it hidden.
Was it better?
You don'talk.
Why are you still here? Get out of this house.
Get lost.
I don't want to see you anymore.
Stop it.
Go to your room.
Go dear.
Keep it in your mind that it was you who
wrote them She just re-send them.
I don't want to listen to you...Go
I hate it when you make as if you're a good man
and want to give me lessions.
I don't want to give you lessions.
You told me to come here and talk to Luci.
It wasn't for Luci that I asked you to come,
It was for that fucking divorce paper
Listen
Not to see you after four years...forever
Why didn't you tell me to come last year?
Why you told me come in this shit?
Shame on you.
You wanted to get married without telling me.
Go check your e-mails...
You didn't book any hotel.
Don't talk rubbish.
You made me to sleep with his kid in one room, why?
I sent you that e-mail.
You brought me here to avenge.
Yeah, You're right. You happy now?
Then you tell me you're pregnant in court.
Why?
Don't you want to go?
Go for God's sake...Go
Just go...
She's leaving...
Luci, Where're you going? Get back
Who are you to tell me what to do?
Please Luci...Don't make it worse.
Why did you tell her?
you allow it.
You made me.
I didn't want you to be in torment for the rest of your life.
I'm not now?
Is everything ok now?
Wait...
Have you got some money?
Hold on...I come with you.
Hold on...
I go myself
Ahmad
Can I ask you something?
What?
What was in those e-mails?
I don't know.
Get back home
Ahamd
Ahamd...look at me
If you stretch it anymore, you're done...
Cut
You remember me and Mitra?
This word can go on without me and you !!
Sometimes I think if I hadn't gone for years ago...
If you hadn't gone four years ago
you'd gone the next year
Not one year after...two years after
You didn't belong here...
What did I tell you the frist day?
You have to chose to be here or there...
You wanna tell him?
You can tell him nothing.
Go to sleep.
Turn the lights off.
Is Samir here?
Yeah..Upstairs
Hello.
Hello Fouad
You ok?
Yes
Do you have a minute?
Yeah
Come in.
What are they?
Her perfumes.
I take them to hospital for test.
Her nurse said sense of smell is the last step
This one is yours.
She liked it.
What's up?
Nothing
Why don't you come in?
I have to go.
I don't like to hide your happiness from me.
I'm not hiding anything.
You mean you're not happy!!
It's a good news that she reacts to something.
What do you like me to answer you?
You stuck between me and her.
Did you come to this conclusion at one night?
No.
It's been a long time.
When?
What do you mean when?
Because you didn't speak like that till the last week.
I didn't dare to...
Maybe I wasn't sure
Sure about what?
I feel I'm only going to fill her empty place.
Whose empty place am I going to fill?
No one
You sure?
That I'm not a compensation for your unrequited love?
If it was so, I wouldn't get pregnant.
It was something unwanted.
I could abort him.
You kept him to forget that man.
Believe me this relationship has come to an end !!!
You wouldn't beleive it. Otherwise you let him go to hotel.
You think I don't know why you feel bad?
I don't know you anymore.
I feel bad because I know why your wife committed suicide.
Do not involve her, Ok?
Your wife knew it.
Don't repeat the nonsense that your daughter says.
Finally she would've told me, if she had known it.
She never asked you anything about me?
Like what?
Don't know, Why you go out and come back that much!
No, You were like the other clients.
What about you? Wasn't she suspicious about you?
No.
I wish she were.
I wish she were worried that I'm with someone or not.
Thus I knew I was important to her.
Luci sent her our e-mails.
How did she get her e-mail?
Your wife gave her.
Had she met her?
Luci calls the dry cleaning and tells your wife that
she has some of our e-mails that wants to send her.
And your wife told her to send them.
When did she call her?
The day before her suicied.
Nama come here.
After that fight that I told my wife to leave here...
ok
Did she used to come when I wasn't here?
No.
When she wanted to go up
The last days I didn't see her to go up.
Didn't she never come down?
Yeah. Just the last day.
How about before?
No, Why?
I've been told that someone has
called here and talked to my wife.
You can go.
Thanks.
Take it.
I get back.
Sorry mom.
Just don't lie to me again.
What did I lie you about?
That you send those e-mails.
Do you promise me?
Ok?
Why do you think that I lied to you?
Because she wasn't in dry cleaning the day before her suicide.
But I talked to her.
No.
Yes I did.
She had an accent.
His wife is french.
Hello.
Why did you do that?
What?
Why did you introduced yourself instead of my wife and
give that girl her e-mail address?
I'm sorry.
I don't want you to say sorry, Just tell me why.
Speak up.
She didn't like me.
She didn't like you? why?
Had you done something?
No.
So why didn't she like you?
She believed there is something between me and you.
She believed so?
Why? Why did she think so?
Because you let me work here without any paper.
she was supicious of me.
Did she tell you anything?
No.
So what are these bullshits?
I think she always wanted to get rid of me.
You think?
Out.
She never asked me to fire you.
But she always...
She always used to do something that you fire me.
Like waht? hmm?
Ha? I asked you like waht?
Many things.
Like waht?
Sorry
The day that client called the police she didn't let me go.
She said I had to saty.
It doesn't have any relationship.
She wanted the police know that I'm not allowed to work here.
Just this?
That's why she is in coma now?
Get lost!
I washed, ironed and put in cover the clothes we had a fight about.
Get out.
I'm sure there was no stain on them.
She did it herself on purpose.
I'm here for one year, No clothes is stained like that before.
How much of your payment is left?
That's what I do everydaY
There was no stain on those clothes.
I swear to God those clothes weren't stained.
She did that on purpose.
Get lost.
Get out.
I just wanted her to know that there is nothing between me and you.
You were always in a bad mood and thinking about someone else.
But she thought it's because of me.
That day when you took my hand and didn't let me go
insted, you booted her out of, I looked upon her eyes
I know what she was thinking.
You know what you did...mother of a eight years
old boy is in the hospital like a piece of meat.
I didn't do anything.
You gave that girl her e-mail address.
If she had read the e-mails
she would have understood everything.
She wouldn't have come in front of me to drink laundry liquid
She would've gone to that pharmacy in front of taht woman to do that
Or up there in front of you.
Why before me?
Doesn't she come here anymore?
Who?
Nama
No
Why?
She had done something bad.
She said she is sorry.
Somethings couldn't be forgiven.
Like what?
What has happened to your finger?
Nothing.
I want to get back to Lea
Currently we cant
Till when?
Until your mother's situation becomes clear.
When it becomes clear?
I dont know.
I get bored here.
Why don't you come down with me?
I don't like it down there.
Hello
Go up for a moment Fouad.
How are you?
Can I go with Marie then?
Go and get your stuff.
Go.
Would you draw something for mom?
Ok.
Sit down.
You think she read those e-mails?
I don't know.
If she had read them...
She would've told you something about it.
We didn't talk to each other after that fight.
She went into a sulk with me.
Even if she had read them...
it wasn't impportant for her
Was it important?
Maybe
I don't know...Now I want to talk about the present
The past is gone
What I know now is that you're pregnant
We have to forget it
Could we?
We have to
What if we don't?
Is your hand better?
It still hurts a little.
Didn't you go to doctor?
Lack of calcium, The baby takes it all.
How many months?
About three
I thought your wrist hurt because of painting.
Don't know.
Maybe.
There's something I want to tell you before I go.
About what?
When I left...
It's not important
I wanted to make it clear
No.
I don't want to get back to the past
Forget it.
So I go.
What about your stuff in store?
I don't want them
Take them.
What are you doing?
My helicopter got stuck
You broke it!
No, It just stuck
Did you reach it?
Wait...Wait
Be careful
You're going?
Yeah I'm going
Bye Fouad
Bye
Unfortunately she has no reaction.
Nothing?
I saw nothing.
You mean both time that she
clawed at her stomach were involuntary
Maybe, this test doesn't help us
to know how much conscience she is
But she had never clawed at her stomach before.
I can't tell, Maybe it has happened when
the nurse was trying to move her
Their skin is so sensitive.
Sorry doctor
How can I make sure that she has not clawed herself?
Through next tests. However, If they're
negative there will be still some doubts
In this situation every cetainty is dobious
I put the perfumes next to her bed.
Sorry, Did you test all of them?
No just one or two.
Bye.
If you can smell it Cline, squeeze my finger.
Translation and synchronization By
Alireza Salehi
alireza_salehi68@yahoo.com