Slave in the magic mirror,
come from the farthest space,
...through wind and darkness
I summon thee.
Speak!
Let me see thy face.
What wouldst thou know,
my Queen?
Magic mirror on the wall,
who is the fairest one of all?
Famed is thy beauty, Majesty.
But hold, a lovely maid I see.
Rags cannot hide her gentle grace.
Alas, she is more fair than thee.
Alas for her!
Reveal her name.
Lips red as the rose.
Hair black as ebony.
Skin white as snow.
Snow White!
Want to know a secret?
Promise not to tell?
We are standing by
a wishing well
Make a wish into the well
That's all you have to do
And if you hear it echoing
Your wish will soon come true
-I'm wishing
For the one I love to find me
To find me
-Today
-I'm hoping
-And I'm dreaming of
the nice things
-The nice things
-He'll say
-Ah-ah-ah-ah-ahh
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ahh
-I'm wishing
For the one I love
-To find me
-Today
-Oh!
-Hello.
-Oh.
-Did I frighten you?
Wait. Wait, please.
Don't run away.
Now that I've found you
Hear what I have to say
One song
I have but one song
One song only for you
One heart tenderly beating
Ever entreating
One love
That has possessed me
Thrilling me through
One song
My heart keeps singing
Of one love
Only for you
Take her far into the forest.
Find some secluded glade
where she can pick wildflowers.
Yes, Your Majesty.
And there,
my faithful Huntsman,
you will kill her!
But, Your Majesty,
the little Princess!
Silence!
You know the penalty
if you fail.
Yes, Your Majesty.
But to make doubly sure...
you do not fail,
bring back her heart...
in this.
One song
I have but one song
Hello there.
What's the matter?
Where's your mama and papa?
Why, I believe you're lost.
Oh, please, don't cry.
Come on. Perk up.
Won't you smile for me?
That's better.
Your mama and papa can't be far.
There they are.
Can you fly?
I can't! I can't do it!
Forgive me. I beg
of Your Highness, forgive me.
-I don't understand.
-She's mad! Jealous of you!
She'll stop at nothin'!
-But-- But who?
-The Queen!
-The Queen?
-Now, quick, child, run!
Run away, hide!
In the woods! Anywhere!
Never come back!
Now, go! Go!
Go! Run! Run! Hide!
Oh!
Please, don't run away.
I won't hurt you.
I'm awfully sorry.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
But you don't know
what I've been through.
And all because
I was afraid.
I'm so ashamed of the fuss I've made.
What do you do
when things go wrong?
Oh!
You sing a song!
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ahh
With a smile and a song
Life is just like
a bright, sunny day
Your cares fade away
And your heart is young
With a smile and a song
All the world
seems to waken anew
Rejoicing with you
as the song is sung
There's no use in grumbling
When raindrops come tumbling
Remember you're the one
Who can fill the world
with sunshine
When you smile and you sing
Everything is in tune
and it's spring
And life flows along
With a smile and a song
I really feel quite happy now.
I'm sure I'll get along somehow.
Everything's going
to be all right.
But I do need
a place to sleep at night.
I can't sleep
in the ground like you.
Or in a tree,
the way you do.
And I'm sure no nest could
possibly be big enough for me.
Maybe you know
where I can stay.
In the woods somewhere?
You do?
Will you take me there?
Oh, it's adorable.
Just like a doll's house.
I like it here.
It's dark inside.
Guess there's no one home.
Hello?
May I come in?
Shh.
Oh!
What a cute little chair.
Why, there's seven little chairs.
Must be seven little children.
And from the look of this table,
seven untidy little children.
A pickax.
A stocking too.
And a shoe.
And just look at that fireplace.
It's covered with dust.
And look, cobwebs everywhere.
My, my, my!
What a pile of dirty dishes.
And just look at that broom.
Tsk, tsk, tsk!
Why, they've never
swept this room.
You'd think their mother would--
Maybe they have no mother.
Then, they're orphans.
That's too bad.
I know. We'll clean the house
and surprise them.
Then, maybe they'll let me stay.
Now, you wash the dishes.
You tidy up the room.
You clean the fireplace.
And I'll use the broom.
Just whistle
while you work
And cheerfully together
we can tidy up the place
So hum a merry tune
It won't take long
when there's a song
to help you set the pace
And as you sweep the room
Imagine that the broom
is someone that you love
And soon you'll find
you're dancing to the tune
Oh, no, no, no, no!
Put them in the tub.
When hearts are high
the time will fly
So whistle
while you work
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
Not under the rug.
So whistle
while you work
We dig, dig, dig, dig
dig, dig, dig
In our mine
the whole day through
To dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig
is what we like to do
It ain't no trick
to get rich quick
If ya dig, dig, dig
with a shovel or a pick
-In a mine
-Where a million diamonds
-Shine
We dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig
From early morn 'til night
We dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig
Dig up everything in sight
We dig diamonds
by the score
A thousand rubies
Sometimes more
Though we don't know what
we dig 'em for
We dig, dig, dig-a-dig, dig
Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho-hum
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Let's see what's upstairs.
Oh, what adorable little beds.
And look, they have
their names carved on them.
Doc, Happy,
Sneezy, Dopey--
What funny names for children.
Grumpy, Bashful and Sleepy.
I'm a little sleepy myself.
Oh, oh.
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
-Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh--
-Look!
Our house! The lit's light--
Uh, the light's lit.
Jiminy Crickets.
-The door is open.
-The chimney's smokin'.
-Something's in there.
-Maybe a ghost.
-Or a goblin.
-A demon.
-Or a dragon.
Mark my words,
there's trouble a-brewin'.
Felt it coming' all day.
My corns hurt.
-Gosh.
-That's a bad sign.
-What'll we do?
-Let's sneak it up on it.
Yes. Ahem,
we'll, uh, squeak up--
Sneak up. Come on, hen--
Uh, men. Follow me.
Psst.
Shh!
Careful, men.
Search every cook and nanny--
Uh, hook and granny--
Uh, crooked fan--
Uh, search everywhere.
Shh! Quiet.
Look! The floor!
It's been swept!
Hah! Chair's been dusted.
Our window's been washed.
Gosh, our cobwebs are missin'.
Why, why, why--
Why, the whole place is clean!
There's dirty work afoot.
Sink's empty.
Hey, someone stole our dishes!
They ain't stole. They're hid in the cupboard.
My cup's been washed.
Sugar's gone.
Something's cookin'.
Smells good.
Don't touch it, you fools!
Might be poison.
See?
It's witch's brew.
Look what's happened
to our stable--uh, table.
Flowers!
-Huh?
-Look, goldenrod.
Don't do it.
Take them away. My nose!
My hay fever!
You know I can't stand it.
I can't--
I can't--I-- Oh!
Ah-- Ahhh--
Thanks.
Ah-chooooo!
Hey!
Shh!
Ya crazy fool!
Fine time ya picked to sneeze!
I couldn't help it.
I can't tell.
When you gotta, you gotta.
I--I-- I gotta.
I-It's comin'.
Ah-- Ah--
- Don't let him.
- Stop him.
Oh, ah-- Ah-- Ah--
-Don't let go.
-Hold him tight.
-I'll tie it.
-Make a hard knot.
There, that'll hold him.
-Thanks!
-Shh!
Quiet, you fool.
Want to get us all killed?
-Wha-- What's that?
-That's it.
Sounded close.
It's in this room right now.
It's up there.
Yeah, in the bedroom.
One of us has got to go down...
and chase it up.
Uh, uh, uh, up, down.
Here, take it.
Don't be nervous.
Don't be afraid.
We're right behind you.
Yes, right behind ya.
Here it comes!
-It's after us!
-Don't let it out!
-Hold it shut!
-Here it comes.
-Now's our chance.
Hit it, now.
-Give it to 'im.
-Don't let him get away!
Take that, and that, and that!
Hold on there,
i-it's only Dopey.
-Did you see it?
-How big is it?
-Was it a dragon?
-Has it got horns?
-Was it breathing fire?
-Was it droolin'?
What was it doin'?
He's says it's...a monster...
asleep in our beds!
-Let's attack.
-While it's sleeping.
-Yeah, while it's sleeping.
-Hurry, men, it's now or never.
-Off with its head.
-Break its bones.
-Chop it to pieces.
We'll kill it dead.
-Jiminy Crickets.
-Gosh!
-Gee, what a monster.
-Covers three beds.
-Let's kill it before it wakes up.
-Which end do we kill?
-Shh!
-Well, uh, uh--
-What is it?
Why, i-it's a girl!
She's mighty pretty.
She's beautiful.
Just like a angel.
Angel, hah!
She's a female!
And all females is poison!
They're full of wicked wiles!
What are "wicked wiles"?
I don't know,
but I'm "agin" 'em.
Shh! Not so loud.
You'll wake her up.
Aw, let her wake up!
She don't belong here nohow!
Look out. She's movin'.
-She's wakin' up.
-What do we do?
Hide!
Oh, dear!
I wonder if the children are--
Oh!
Why--Why, you're little men.
How do you do?
I said, "How do you do"?
How do ya do what?
Oh, you can talk.
I'm so glad.
Now, don't tell me who you are.
Let me guess.
I know, you're Doc.
Why-- Why--
Why, yes! Yes! That's true.
And you're--
You're Bashful.
Oh, gosh!
And, you? You're Sleepy.
How'd you guess?
-And you?
-Ah--
Ah-- Ah-- Ah--
You're Sneezy.
Ah-choo!
-Yes, and you must be--
-Happy, ma'am. That's me.
And this is Dopey.
He don't talk none.
-You mean he can't talk?
-He don't know. He never tried.
Oh, that's too bad.
Oh, you must be Grumpy.
Oh, yeah.
Hah!
We know who we are.
Ask her who she is
and what she's a-doin' here!
Hmph! Yes! What are you
and who are you doin'?
Uh, uh, what are you--
Uh, who are you, my dear?
Oh, how silly of me.
I'm Snow White.
-Snow White? The Princess?
-Yes.
Well, my dear Quincess--
Uh, Princess. We're, uh--
We're honored. Yes, we're--
-Mad as hornets!
-"Mad as hornets!"
No, no, we're not!
We're bad as cornets--
No, no, as bad as--
What was I sayin'?
Nothin'! Just standin' there
sputterin' like a doodlebug!
Who's butterin' like
a spoodledug? Who's uh, uh--
Aw, shut up!
And tell her to git out!
Please, don't send me away.
If you do, she'll kill me.
-Kill you?
-Who will?
-Yes, who?
-My stepmother, the Queen.
-The Queen!
-She's wicked.
-She's bad.
-She's mighty mean.
-She's an old witch! I'm warnin' ya!
If the Queen finds her here,
she'll swoop down...
and wreak
her vengeance on us!
But she doesn't
know where I am.
She don't, huh?
She knows everything.
She's full of black magic.
She can even make
herself invisible. Pfft!
Might be in this room right now.
Oh, she'll never find me here.
And if you let me stay,
I'll keep house for you.
I'll wash, I'll cook...
Can ya make dapple lumpkins--
Uh, lumple dapplins--
Apple dumplings!
Ah, yes!
Crapple dumpkins.
Yes, and plum pudding
and gooseberry pie--
Gooseberry pie?
Hurray! She stays!
Ah! Soup!
Hurray!
Uh, uh, uh, just a minute.
Supper's not quite ready.
You'll just have time to wash.
Wash?
Hah! Knew there's a catch to it!
-Why wash?
-What for? We ain't goin' nowhere.
'Tain't New Year.
Oh, perhaps
you have washed.
Perhaps we--
But when?
When? Uh, when?
Uh, you said, "When?"
Why, last week-- uh, month--
year-- Why, recently.
Yes, recently.
Let me see your hands.
Why, Doc, I'm surprised.
Oh, Bashful, my, my, my!
And you? Tsk, tsk, tsk!
Worse than I thought.
Oh!
How shocking.
Tsk, tsk, tsk!
Goodness me, this will never do.
March straight outside and wash,
or you'll not get a bite to eat.
Hah!
Well, aren't you going to wash?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Oh, did you hurt yourself?
Hmph!
Hah, women!
Courage, men, courage!
Don't be nervous.
Gosh, it's wet.
It's cold too!
We ain't gonna do it, are we?
Well, i-it'll please the Princess.
-I'll take a chance for her.
-Me too!
Hah! Her wiles
are beginnin' to work.
But I'm warnin' ya, you give 'em
an inch, and they'll walk all over ya!
Don't listen to that old warthog.
Come on now, men.
-How hard do ya scrub?
-Will our whiskers shrink?
-Do ya get in the tub?
-Do ya have to wash where it doesn't show?
Now, now, now, don't get excited.
Here we go.
Step up to the tub
'Tain't no disgrace
Just pull up your sleeves
and get 'em in place
Then scoop up the water
and rub it on your face
And go--
Pick up the soap
Now, don't try to bluff
Work up a lather
and when you got enough
Get your hands full of water
and you snort and you snuff
And go--
You douse and you souse
Rub and ya scrub
You sputter and splash
all over the tub
You may be cold and wet
when you're done
But ya gotta admit
it's good and clean fun
So splash all ya like
'Tain't any trick
As soon as you're through
you'll feel mighty slick
Bunch of old nanny goats
Ya make me sick
Going--
Hah!
Next thing ya know...
she'll be tyin' your beards up
in pink ribbons...
and smellin' ya up with that
stuff called, uh, "perfoom."
Hah!
A fine bunch of water lilies
you turned out to be.
I'd like to see anybody
make me wash, if I didn't wanna.
Ahem.
Get him!
Hey! Let go of me!
Get him over to the tub.
Let me loose, you fools!
Let me loose!
Get 'im up on the tub.
Get 'im up! Hang onto 'im!
Get him up on the tub.
The tub, the tub!
Don't get excited!
Don't get--
Get the soap!
Oh! Steady, men!
We'll get him there.
Now scrub good and hard
It can't be denied
That he'll look mighty cute
as soon as he's dried
Well, it's good for the soul
and it's good for the hide
To go--
-Ain't he sweet?
-Smells like a petunia.
He sure is cute.
You'll pay dearly for this!
Supper!
-Supper!
-Food! Hurray!
Hah!
Magic mirror on the wall,
who now is
the fairest one of all?
Over the seven jewelled hills,
beyond the seventh fall,
in the cottage
of the Seven Dwarfs,
dwells Snow White,
fairest one of all.
Snow White lies dead
in the forest.
The Huntsman has brought me proof.
Behold, her heart.
Snow White still lives,
the fairest in the land.
'Tis the heart of a pig
you hold in your hand.
The heart of a pig!
Then I've been tricked!
The blundering fool!
I'll go myself
to the dwarfs' cottage...
in a disguise so complete
no one will ever suspect.
Now, a formula to transform
my beauty into ugliness.
Change my queenly raiment
to a peddler's cloak.
"Mummy Dust" to make me old.
To shroud my clothes, the black of night.
To age my voice,
an old hag's cackle.
To whiten my hair,
a scream of fright.
A blast of wind...
to fan my hate!
A thunderbolt...
to mix it well.
Now...
begin thy magic spell.
Look! My hands!
My voice!
A perfect disguise.
And now, a special...
sort of death for one so fair.
What shall it be?
Ah! A poisoned apple!
"Sleeping Death."
"One taste
of the Poisoned Apple...
"and the victim's eyes
will close forever...
in the Sleeping Death."
Ahem!
I'd like to dance and tap my feet
but they don't keep in rhythm
You see, I washed 'em both today
and I can't do nothin' with 'em
Ho-hum, the tune is dumb
The words don't mean a thing
Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing
Oh, g-gosh!
I chased a polecat up a tree
Way out upon a limb
And when he got the best of me
I got the worst of him
Ho-hum, the tune is dumb
The words don't mean a thing
Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing
Ahhh
Be careful.
Watch out.
Be-- Be care--
Watch it! Watch it!
Watch--
Watch-- Ah--
Thanks.
Hey! Hey!
Ah-ch-- Ah-ch--
Ah-- Ah--
Ah-ch--
Ah-ch-- Ah-ch--
Ah-- Ah--
Ah-chooooo!
That was fun.
-Now, you do somethin'.
-Well, what shall I do?
-Tell us a story.
-Yes! Tell us a story!
-A true story.
-A love story.
Well, once there was a princess.
Was the princess you?
-And she fell in love.
-Was it hard to do?
Oh, it was very easy.
Anyone could see that the prince was charming.
-The only one for me.
-Was he, uh, strong and handsome?
Was he big and tall?
There's nobody like him...
anywhere at all.
-Did he say he loved ya?
-Did he steal a kiss?
He was so romantic
I could not resist
Some day
my Prince will come
Some day we'll meet again
And away to his castle
We'll go
To be happy forever
I know
Hah! Mush.
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true
Oh, my goodness,
it's past bedtime.
Go right upstairs to bed.
Wait! Hold on there, men.
The, uh, Princess will
sleep in our beds upstairs.
-But... where will you sleep?
- Oh, we'll be quite
comfortable down here..
- in, uh, in, uh--
- In a pig's eye!
"In a pig's eye--"
Sty-- No! No! I mean--
We'll be comfortable,
won't we, men?
Oh, yes, mighty comfortable.
Now, don't you
worry about us.
-We'll be all right.
-Go right up now,
uh, uh, my dear.
Well, if you insist.
Good night.
Good night, Princess.
You're sure
you'll be comfortable?
Oh, yes,
very comfortable.
Well, pleasant dreams.
Pleasant dreams.
-Let go!
-Now, men, don't get excited. Remember...
share and share alike.
Look out, it'll rip!
Bless the seven little men...
who have been so kind to me.
And may my dreams come true.
Amen.
Oh, yes, and please make
Grumpy like me.
Hah!
Women!
A fine kettle of fish.
Dip the apple in the brew.
Let the sleeping death seep through.
Look! On the skin!
The symbol of what lies within.
Now, turn red
to tempt Snow White.
To make her hunger for a bite.
Have a bite?
It's not for you!
It's for Snow White.
When she breaks the tender peel
to taste the apple in my hand,
her breath will still,
her blood congeal.
Then I'll be the fairest in the land.
But wait!
There may be an antidote.
Nothing must be overlooked.
Ah! Here it is!
"The Victim
of the Sleeping Death...
can be revived only
by Love's First Kiss."
"Love's First Kiss"!
Bah! No fear of that.
The dwarfs
will think she's dead.
She'll be buried alive!
Buried alive!
Thirsty?
Have a drink!
Now, don't forget, my dear.
Th-The old Queen's a sly one.
Full of witchcraft.
So beware of strangers.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
-See you tonight.
-Oh, oh, yes.
Well, uh, come on, men.
Be awful careful, 'cuse
if anything would happen to you,
-I-- I--
-Good-bye.
Oh, gosh!
Hah! Disgustin'!
And be sure to watch out--
To wa-- To wa--
To wa--
Watch out!
Thanks.
Ah-ch-- Ah-ch-ch--
Ah-ch--
Ah-chooooo!
Well... all right.
But that's the last--
Oh!
Go on. Run along.
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
Heigh-ho
Good-bye. Good-bye!
Now, I'm warnin' ya. Don't let
nobody or nothin' in the house.
Why, Grumpy, you do care.
Huh!
Good-bye, Grumpy!
The little men will be away...
and she'll be alone...
with a harmless
old peddler woman.
A harmless old peddler woman.
Some day my Prince will come
Some day we'll meet again
And away to his castle we'll go
To be happy forever I know
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true
All alone, my pet?
Why-- Why, yes, I am, but--
The... little men are not here?
No, they're not, but--
Mm-hmm.
Makin' pies?
Yes, gooseberry pie.
It's apple pies that make
the menfolks' mouths water.
Pies made from apples like these.
-Oh, they do look delicious.
-Yes!
But wait 'til you taste one, dearie.
Like to try one?
Hmm?
Go on.
Go on, have a bite.
Ah! Ah!
Stop it, stop it.
Go away, go away.
Shame on you, frightening
a poor old lady.
Oh, I thought I lost it.
There, there.
I'm sorry.
Oh! My heart!
Oh, my--
My poor heart.
Take me into the house
and let me rest.
A drink of water, please.
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Hey, look!
Stop that. Get away!
Get away! Go on, shoo!
Go on, get outta here!
What ails these crazy birds?
Th-They've gone plumb daffy.
Yeah, they've gone--
Ah-- Ah--
Ah-chooooo!
And because you've been
so good to poor old Granny.
I'll share a secret with you.
This is no ordinary apple.
It's a magic wishing apple.
-A wishing apple?
-Yes!
One bite and all
your dreams will come true.
-Really?
-Yes, girlie!
Now, make a wish and take a bite.
Go on, git! These pesky critters
won't stop!
'Taint natural.
There's something wrong!
They ain't actin' this way
for nothin'!
Maybe the old Queen's
got Snow White.
-The Queen!
-Snow White!
The Queen will kill her!
We gotta save her!
Yes, yes,
we-we gotta save her!
-S-She'll kill her!
-What'll we do?
-Yes, w-what'll we do?
Come on!
Giddap!
Wait for me!
Wait--
There must be something
your little heart desires.
Perhaps there's someone you love.
Well, there is someone.
I thought so.
Old Granny knows
a young girl's heart.
Now, take the apple, dearie,
and make a wish.
I wish--
That's it.
Go on. Go on.
..and that he will
carry me away to his castle...
where we will live
happily ever after.
Fine! Fine!
Now, take a bite.
Don't let the wish grow cold!
Oh! I feel strange.
-Her breath will still.
-Oh.
-Her blood congeal.
Now I'll be fairest in the land!
Hurry, hurry!
There she goes!
After her!
I'm trapped.
What will I do?
The meddling little fools!
I'll fix ya!
I'll crush your bones!
Look out!
-One song
-One song only for you
One heart tenderly beating
-Ever entreating
Constant and true
So true
-One love
That has possessed me
-Thrilling me through
-So true
-One song
-My heart keeps singing
-Keeps singing
-Of one love
-One love
Only for you
And away to his castle
You'll go
To be happy forever
We know
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Grumpy.
Oh, Dopey.
Good-bye!
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true
Subtitles provider:
Lopov