We didn't lie to you, folks.
We told you we had living,
breathing monstrosities.
You laughed at them, shuddered at them...
and yet, but for the accident of birth...
you might be even as they are.
They did not ask
to be brought into the world...
but into the world they came.
Their code is a law unto themselves.
Offend one...
and you offend them all.
And now, folks,
if you'll just step this way...
you are about to witness
the most amazing...
the most astounding living monstrosity...
of all time.
Friends...
she was once a beautiful woman.
A royal prince shot himself for love of her.
She was known as the peacock of the air.
She's the most beautiful big woman
l have ever seen.
Why, Hans, how you talk.
l should be jealous pretty soon.
-Don't be silly.
-Don't be silly?
l've seen these women
making eyes at my Hans.
Of course, l ain't jealous.
Frieda, my dear...
l have eyes for only one woman...
the woman l asked to be my wife.
Frulein Frieda?
Are you laughing at me?
-Why, no, monsieur.
-Thanks. l'm glad.
-Why should l laugh at you?
-Most big people do.
They don't realize l'm a man
with the same feelings they have.
Thank you.
You are so kind, monsieur.
-Nice.
-Don't.
You must come to see me sometime,
and we'll have a little wine together.
Thank you, Frulein Cleo.
You're getting old, Jean.
Probably, last night you had too heavy
a dinner, and now your imagination is--
But, Monsieur Duval,
at first l could not believe my own eyes.
A lot of horrible, twisted things,
you know, crawling, whining, laughing--
Be done, Jean.
What were you drinking last night?
Nothing, monsieur, l assure you.
Monsieur, there must be a law in France
to smother such things at birth...
-or lock them up.
-All right, Jean.
lf there's anything like you say
on my grounds, we'll have it removed.
-Come on, let's go.
-All of you! Tout de suite!
Go away, all of you!
Don't you know trespassing
is the same as stealing?
l'm sorry, monsieur.
l am Madame Tetrallini.
These children are in my circus.
Children? They're monsters.
Your circus. l understand.
So you see, monsieur,
when l get a chance...
l like to take them into the sunshine...
and let them play like...children.
That is what most of them are.
Children.
Please forget what was said, madame.
You are welcome to remain.
Au revoir. Come, Jean.
Thanks a thousand, monsieur.
A thousand thanks, monsieur.
Shame!
How many times have l told you
not to be frightened?
Have l not told you...
God looks after all his children?
-Good evening, Madame Tetrallini.
-How are you, Madame Tetrallini?
Big crowd tonight.
There she goes,
taking them out to exercise.
Nurse to a lot of mangy freaks.
" Just as they are represented
on the banners...
" you will see them on the inside.
" Living, breathing monstrosities.
" Josephine Joseph,
half-woman, half-man."
Have a cigar, Joseph.
You dropped your lipstick, Josephine.
Don't get her sore,
or he'll bust you in the nose.
Come on. Hurry up. That's a boy.
You're all wrong. l didn't do it.
What are you trying to do, be funny?
You just don't understand.
A Roman lady....
Getting off the bull
and scratching yourself.
Can't a Roman lady itch?
-Why don't you take a bath?
-l did, but it's the bull that needs the bath.
l think she likes you...
but he don't.
Those flowers you sent to me,
they were beautiful.
But not much beautiful as you.
Thank you.
And Hans, l don't like to ask...
but may l have the loan
of another 1,000 francs...
until my money from Paris arrives?
-With pleasure, Frulein.
-Thank you.
l'll bring it to your wagon tonight.
Forget it.
-Maybe l was just fooling.
-Fooling?
" Come, little girl,
l want to take care of you."
And l fell for that.
Forget it.
So, you're quitting.
ls that it?
Maybe l'm only fooling.
You are not quitting me!
Because l'm kicking you out!
No, you don't. l gave you this.
Why, you cheap....
Don't you come around crying tonight,
trying to get back in.
l'm through wasting my time and money...
on things like you.
Yes. Your time, but my money.
Ungrateful little tramp.
That is fine.
What are you staring at?
Didn't you ever see a lady move before?
l guess you've been listening
to every word he said.
That's it.
Go ahead and laugh. lt's funny, ain't it?
Yeah. Women are funny, ain't they?
They're all tramps, ain't they?
Yeah. Except when you can
get money from them.
l'll be....
Who do you think you are,
shooting off your head?
This is Phroso you're talking to.
Not any of those thugs
you've been chasing around with.
-Now, you listen to me.
-l didn't mean you.
-l had to take it out on somebody.
-Yeah, you dames are all alike.
You're sharpshooting, you're cheap...
and how you squeal when you get
what's coming to you.
Easy, kid. Cut it!
lt's my own fault.
What gets me
so cockeyed sore at myself...
is that l fell for that big hunk of beef.
So you finally got wise
to yourself, did you?
The funny thing about you women is
most of you don't get wise soon enough.
You wait until you're so old,
nobody wants you.
Nobody does, most of the time.
You ought to be tickled to death
you're washed-up with him.
You're not so hard to look at.
Give yourself a tumble.
You'll make the grade.
-Your breaks is coming.
-Coming? Gone, you mean.
Now you'll sit there
feeling sorry for yourself.
No, l ain't.
Don't you ever accuse me of that.
All right.
But one thing, don't go out filling your
hide with booze, celebrating...
'cause fun what's got that way
never done no one no good.
Get me?
l got you.
You're a pretty good kid.
You're darn right l am. You should have
caught me before my operation.
-Hello, Phroso.
-Well, well, well.
-Tomorrow night's the big night, Daisy?
-Yes, the sister's getting married.
-And l'm thrilled to death.
-She thrills at anything.
-Roscoe's a good kid.
-She's only joking.
She'll like him lots
after she knows him better.
That reminds me.
Close your eyes, Violet.
Go ahead, close them.
-What did l do?
-Pinched Daisy's arm.
What do you know about that?
Her master's voice is calling.
Getting fresh?
l don't like it one....
Come on, you'll have to hurry.
We haven't much time.
So you were flirting
with that cheap clown, were you?
-No, l wasn't.
-He was doing a trick with me.
You shut up.
l'm marrying your sister, not you.
-l saw him getting familiar with you.
-Come on, Daisy.
No, you don't.
She's going to stay right here.
No, she isn't. l got to go.
You're always using that for an....
For an alibi.
Where are you going?
You don't look at others so much, do you?
Yes, l have seen you.
So that's how it is.
You got to be caught.
Well?
Come on in.
Help yourself to a drink.
That is fine.
Feel like eating something?
Always.
Prosit.
How many?
l'm not very hungry. About six.
How do you like them?
Not bad.
But you are strong.
You are squeezing me to death.
And you'll like it.
You are taking my breath away.
You....
Now, here's something for your eye.
But, Hans, my Liebchen,
you have not been listening...
to a word l have been saying.
-Hans.
-Yes, Frieda?
-You have not been listening to me.
-Yes, l have, Frieda. l have.
Then what was l saying?
You were saying.... What were you saying?
l was saying, tonight
you must not smoke such a big cigar.
Your voice was very bad
at tonight's show.
Please, Frieda, don't tell me what l do.
When l want a cigar, l smoke a cigar.
l want no orders from a woman.
This is the first time
since we have been engaged...
you have spoken to me so.
Why is it?
Friedchen, l'm sorry. l....
-Here's our coffee.
-There it is.
-Five lumps of sugar in each.
-What? Five lumps?
The little ape sent to Paris for this?
Yes, Paris. We're doing very well.
But l don't like fruit.
You should eat a lot. lt's good for you.
Next time, l tell him l like champagne.
-Who is it?
-lt's Hans.
-Who?
My darling, your basket of fruit was lovely.
But l am...taking a bath now.
-Can't you come back later?
-Yes, Frulein.
Thank you, dear.
You'll spoil everything if he hears you.
What's the matter?
You ain't singing as usual.
This morning
l have such a big washing to do.
How's Hans?
l said, how's Hans?
Hans is fine. Danke, he's fine.
Frieda, something's wrong. What is it?
Nothing. Only....
That Cleopatra woman.... My Hans....
-l cannot tell it.
-She's still after Hans, ain't she?
Yeah. Always she's smiling by him.
Well, if she smiles by somebody l know...
she'll have to buy herself
a new set of teeth.
Why is it we women
always has got to worry?
lt's always been that way.
l guess it always will be.
Yeah. And, by me, she has no shame.
Always, when l can hear it,
she says to him:
" Many thanks, my darling, for the flowers.
" Thanks, my darling," for this...
and " Thanks, my darling," for that.
Always something he has given her.
Don't you worry, Frieda.
He doesn't love her.
That big horse.
Yes, but she keeps after him.
That's why l worry.
Why not pink tights?
You know. With spangles all around.
lt will show her figure off more.
Nein. No tights.
Without tights.
You know, that soft, flimsy,
what-you-call-it stuff.
Where the figure shows through.
Why not like Lady Godiva?
Ja, that's it. And l'll hire her
to ride the back of my bull.
Dummkopf! What have you
on your shoulder for heads?
Swiss cheese?
-What's the matter, Cleo?
-l think l strained my shoulder last night.
Give a rub, will you?
Farther.
Down.
Over.
lt's so good to be rubbed.
-Our cards, lady.
-What for?
A couple of rubbers from Berlin.
That reminds me. l had a swell dream
about you last night.
-You did?
-Yeah.
You were standing in a bathing suit
on a rock. You know, like a statue.
The wind was blowing through your hair,
the waves were washing around you.
And your figure. How it stood out.
lt looked great.
Say, you have got a good figure.
Do you think so?
-Sure.
-Phroso.
Did you try that gag l told you about?
Yeah, l did, and it was a wow.
Get up here, Johnny. l'll show it to you.
l did what you told me,
and it laid them right in the sawdust.
Watch this, Venus.
-Hello, Venus.
-Hello, Johnny.
Phroso, what else did you dream?
Then the dream changed. We was in Paris.
-Paris?
-Yeah, at the opera, right in the front box.
-We were all dressed up.
-What did l have on?
And did l look swell.
Everybody was pointing at me.
They were saying,
"That's Phroso, the clown."
And was l embarrassed.
-Did they say anything about me?
-Sure.
-What did they say?
-Hit me.
Go ahead. Hit me.
On the head. Hit me.
That's how it is. You don't think it's funny.
lt's sad, is it? lt will just panic them,
that's how sad it is.
No.
When? Come on!
Come on, Venus.
The bearded lady's baby's born!
-Ain't it cute? What is it?
-A girl.
Oh, boy, that's great.
And it's going to have a beard.
-How's the proud father?
-Fine.
-What was it?
-A girl.
Better luck next time.
You may get a couple of Smith Brothers.
l'm trying.
Please, Violet, don't quarrel
with him anymore.
lf he's going to say anything,
let him say it.
Don't let him " p-p-p" for an hour.
You're going to do as l say.
l'm the boss of my home.
-Half of it, you mean.
-Please, Violet.
Listen here. l don't want
those tramps you go with...
hanging around my wife.
Be quiet. Hook up our dress.
lf it isn't your dress l'm hooking up,
it's something else.
And another thing. You got to cut out
getting drunk every night, too.
-ls that so?
-Yeah.
l'm not going to have my wife laying
in bed half the day with your hangover.
Daisy, let's get out of here.
No, she don't.
She's going to stay right here.
Come on. l got to go.
You're always using that for an....
For an alibi.
Cleopatra ain't one of us.
Why, we're just filthy things to her.
She'd spit on Hans
if he wasn't giving her presents.
Let her try it.
Let her try doing anything to one of us.
You're right.
She don't know us, but she'll find out.
There you are.
l peeked out of the corner of my eye...
and caught Madame Tetrallini
giving us the once-over.
l guess she knows she's got a good act.
One of the best in the business.
lt isn't only our act that gets them.
We've got personality.
We know how to sell the stuff.
Same way in the last town.
Never heard such applause in your life.
Let me tell you something
that everybody around here don't know.
We're only killing time with this circus.
We've got bigger time to follow,
and we can do it, too.
Catch our act tomorrow night.
We got something new.
Yeah? Can you do anything
with your eyebrow?
Schlitze, what a pretty dress.
How beautiful you look tonight.
You're just a man's woman.
You know what l mean? You.
lf you're a good girl,
when l get to Paris l'll buy you a big hat...
with a long, beautiful feather on it.
-Hello, Elvira.
-Hi.
Hello, Jennie Lee. Look.
Hasn't Schlitze got a beautiful dress?
lsn't that pretty?
When l get to Paris, l'm going to buy her
a big hat with a long feather on it.
And if you're good girls, l'll buy you a hat
with a bigger feather on it.
Why, Schlitze, what's the matter?
l'm sorry, Schlitze.
Did you see him?
He was out there again tonight.
He followed you from the last town.
l know it, and if Eddie sees it,
there'll be a fight.
-lt ain't your fault.
-There you are, Frances.
-Thought you'd gone to bed.
-Hello, Rollo.
Hear that crowd out there again tonight?
l bet you thought the tent was on fire.
Well, it wasn't.
Just the Rollo Brothers
panicking them again.
But then, we do it in every town.
We're so used to it,
it's getting monotonous.
You want to take a look
at our act tomorrow night.
Careful. Don't waste any of it.
-Look how it sparkles.
-Like your eyes.
Dancing, gay, like bubbles.
lt's delicious.
Nice.
lt comes by the finest vineyards of France.
And you sent for it especially for me?
For the most beautiful woman
in all the world.
Darling.
Hello there, baby.
Where have you been so long?
You're a funny guy, Phroso.
-Sometimes, you panic me.
-Don't l know it?
l panic the world because l use my noodle.
l think up funny gags.
l make the world laugh.
With me, clowning is an art.
Why the hat? The head cold?
-Thought you and me had a date to go out.
-l forgot all about it.
Well, l'm into this now.
l've got to go through with it.
Make it snappy, will you?
l'm all dolled up for the occasion.
Sorry, kid. Can't do it now.
We'll make it some other time.
Don't feel that way about it.
l just got this idea all of a sudden.
l've got to finish it.
-Funny gag, isn't it?
-Yeah, l'm laughing myself sick.
Come on.
Honey, come on.
Now, now.
That's much better.
That's the first time you've ever done that.
-Ain't the first time l felt like doing it.
-Yeah?
l don't mind telling you
l've wanted to do this for a long time.
-We're all set now, Venus?
-Yeah.
-All set now.
Please do.
Don't you want to make me happy?
-Yes, but l don't know what to say.
-Just say yes, dear.
Will you?
-Yes.
-Violet.
What are your kicking about?
You've got a good wife. You're happy.
lt's that sister-in-law of mine.
She wants to sit up half the night, reading.
-That's tough.
-Tough? You....
-Good night, darling.
-Good night, Frulein.
Cleo's gone on a diet.
-lt's awfully sweet of you to say that.
-And l know Violet will be happy.
Here's Roscoe.
-Hello.
-Roscoe, this is Mr. Rogers.
Glad to meet you.
-Violet and he are engaged to be married.
-Yeah?
Yes, and you must come
to see us sometime.
Thanks.
You must come to visit....
Come to see us sometime, too.
l certainly will. Thanks.
Who is it?
lt's Frieda, Hans.
May l come in?
Yes, Frieda.
Now that l'm here,
l don't know how to say it...
how to make you understand.
lf you knew how l feel, Hans...
to come to you about her.
Frieda, l'm so sorry.
l don't want to hurt you,
but ich kann es nicht helfen.
lf you could be happy, Hans...
l would not care.
But l am happy, Frieda.
Never in my life was l so happy.
No, Hans. You think it only.
For you, she cannot bring happiness.
Frieda, you don't know.
But l do, Hans.
You think because she's so beautiful
and l'm just--
Don't, Hans. Please.
To me, you're a man.
But to her,
you're only something to laugh at.
The whole circus.
They make fun by you and her.
Let them laugh. The swine.
l love her. They can't hurt me.
But they hurt me.
Frieda, l have been a coward.
l should have come to you
in the beginning.
Please forgive me.
Yes, Hans, l forgive you.
lt is only that you should be happy l want.
You won't worry now, will you?
No, l won't worry.
Nice. Very nice.
lt's platinum.
Say, where do you think
that little polliwog is getting his money?
Listen at him. Getting so particular.
What do you care
where the money comes from?
How much it's worth?
We got $500 for the bracelet,
but this looks like thousands.
l think next time l'll take a fur coat.
Say, that little ape's got ideas about you.
-Jealous?
-Me?
l'd squish him like a bug.
That's his knock.
l'll get rid of him. Go quickly.
Come in.
What do you want?
lt's about Hans.
Well? l'm listening.
lt's behind his back.
Everybody's laughing
because he's in love with you.
Go on.
l know you just make fun...
but Hans, he does not know this.
lf he finds out...
never again will he be happy.
What makes you think
that l am just making fun?
You're big. So beautiful--
And Hans is so little...
so cute.
Well, maybe l'm going to marry him.
lf you marry,
it will be at you they laugh and stare.
That's good. Nothing like being different.
Cleopatra...
queen of the air, married to a dwarp.
-A dwarf.
-A dwarp!
Then it's not for Hans you care.
-lt's the money.
-Money?
You little mind reader.
He has told you
of the fortune he has inherited.
Always he swear to me...
to tell no one
until after we leave the circus.
A fortune?
And fancy you knowing about it, too.
Well, l can't be angry at him for that.
No. You cannot do this.
You wait and see.
Please. You can't.
A fortune.
l bet the little ape's worth billions!
A fortune. Can you beat that?
A fortune. And l have him like that.
Shrewd little Hans.
He knew enough to keep his mouth shut.
l could marry him.
Yes, he would marry me.
Midgets are not strong.
He could get sick.
How?
lt could be done.
Done. l know it.
Come on, my little precious.
Come on, let's drink.
Big, happy drink. Come on.
Quiet! Please be quiet.
Hey, Koo Koo,
give somebody else a chance.
All right!
All right, professor.
A waltz, please.
Show him up, volcano. Burn him up.
Our wedding night.
What a thrill.
Never before did l think
l should be so lucky.
Lucky?
l am the lucky one.
My little Hans.
My Cleo's happy.
-Happy.
-Happy?
l am so happy.
l even could kiss you,
you big, homely brute.
My little green-eyed monster.
My husband is jealous.
He loves me.
Come, my little lover.
Drink to the happiness of your loving wife.
Attention!
We'll make her one of us.
A loving cup.
We accept her, one of us
We accept her
One of us
They're going to make you one of them.
My, big luck.
We accept her!
One of us!
They're going to make you one of them,
my dear.
You dirty...
slimy freaks!
Get out of here!
You! Out!
Get out! You heard her! Get out!
You filth!
Make me one of you, will you?
Well, what are you going to do?
What are you, a man or a baby?
Please. You make me ashamed.
Ashamed. You?
Holy jumping Christmas!
What must l do?
Must l play games with you?
Must mama take you horsy-back ride?
That's it. Horsy-back ride.
Come, my little flyspeck.
Mama is going to take you
horsy-back ride.
-Come on.
-Giddyap.
Forget it, Hans.
She is sorry. l'm sorry.
Didn't l told you she was drunk?
Didn't l told you
we was only having a little fun?
Please.
l understand.
-Everything.
-No, you don't.
l tell you,
there's nothing between me and Cleo.
Be quiet.
Haven't you done
enough damage for one night?
Don't you realize
what l'm being accused of?
l ain't going to be blamed
for something l have not done.
l don't blame you, Cleo.
l don't blame Hercules.
Only me.
Myself.
Now you're talking.
-Talking like a man.
-You fool.
Always l should have known...
you would only laugh at me.
My sweet, l'd rather fall from the trapeze
and break my neck...
than hurt your feelings.
Do you understand now? lt was only joke.
Our wedding...
a joke?
Now l know how funny it is.
Hans the midget.
Hans...the fool!
Tell the divorce court. They'll laugh.
Everywhere, they're laughing.
-You give him too much.
-No, l haven't.
l know what l am doing.
Come on, pick him up.
Doctor, what is it?
What caused it?
Poison.
A very bad case of ptomaine poisoning.
Doctor, did l do wrong, then?
Giving him mustard water?
No. Probably saved his life.
Never before did he drink like that...
but she kept making him,
and making him.
Drink?
You better get Cleo to tell the doctor
what she put in that wine last night.
-What you're talking about?
-The stuff she put in the wine.
You're crazy.
You can't get away with it.
l'll tell the coppers.
So, tell on your own people?
My people are decent circus folks.
Not dirty rats what would kill a freak
to get his money.
You dirty little....
Your imagination's getting the best of you.
Yeah, maybe it is.
But coppers don't have imaginations,
so l've been told.
Don't make me have to go to them.
-Cleo.
-Yes?
lt has been a week tonight...
since we have been married.
A week, since l have said...
-all those things to you.
-Don't!
Never can l forgive myself
for what l've said.
l've forgotten it.
Nothing matters except for you to be well.
So good you are by me, Cleo.
l must fix your medicine, or l'll be late.
l'll be soon back, my little.
Don't be lonely.
l'll never forget
what you are doing for me, Cleo.
But it's what l want to do, my darling.
Now l must hurry.
-Cleo.
-Yes?
Will you leave the door open, please?
Yes, my darling.
-Tonight.
-They will be ready.
All right. You come to my wagon.
" l must hurry now
and fix your medicine, my darling...
" or l will be late."
" Dirty...
" slimy freaks."
-He's waiting.
-Fine.
Soon we go.
-You're imagining things.
-No.
Then l hear Hercules tell Cleo:
"Venus knows too much."
-Hercules? Venus?
-Yes.
Thanks, Frieda.
My little, you must go to sleep.
Your friends better go now.
-l like them here.
-No, Hans.
They can come back tomorrow.
l will give you your medicine
and get you off to sleep.
Go on, all of you. Quick.
-What's this?
-Give me that little black bottle.
Bottle.
You got this bottle of poison...to kill.
Phroso!
Get out, Venus!
Do l have to bust you in the jaw
to make you get out?
Get out, Venus!
Help me!
Mrs. T!
Help! Please, help!
How she got that way
will never be known.
Some say a jealous lover. Others...
that it was the code of the freaks.
Others, the storm.
Believe it or not, there she is.
But, sir, they insist on seeing you.
ln all these years, l've seen no one.
Have l not told you that?
-Send them away.
-Very good, sir.
-l can't see no one.
-Excuse me, sir. You can't come in.
-No, sir. l have my orders.
-Who's going to stop me? l'm in, ain't l?
Yes, you can, Hansie, old boy.
There's someone you've just got to see.
Why did you come here?
Please, Hans. Don't be angry.
Venus and Phroso have been
so kind by me.
Please go away.
l can see no one.
But, Hans, you tried to stop them.
lt was only the poison you wanted.
lt wasn't your fault.
Don't cry, Hans.
Come to me, my Liebchen.
Don't cry.
Don't, Hans.
l love you.
English