Do you ever look atsomeone and wonder.
What is going on inside their head?
Well, I know.
Well, I know Riley's head.
And there she was.
Hello.
- Riley.Whoa. Look at you.
Aren't you a little bundle of joy.
Whoa.
It was amazing.Just Riley and me
forever.
Or for
33 seconds.
I'm Sadness.
Oh, hello.I'm Joy. So.
Can I just, if you could...
I don't know, let me fix that.
Thanks.
And that was just the beginning.
Headquarters only got
more crowded from there.
Very nice. Okay.
Looks like you got this.
Very good.
Oh. Sharp! Sharp!
No,Look Out!
That's Fear.
He's really good at keeping Riley safe.
Easy.
Fall back!
Oh, we're good.
We're good.
- Woo. Good job. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And.
We're back.
Whoa.
Here we go, alright.
Open.
- Hm. This looks new.
- Think it's safe?
- What is it?
- Ah...
Okay, caution.
There is a dangerous smell people.
Hold on.
What is that?
This is Disgust.
She basically keeps Riley from being
poison, physically and socially.
That is not brightly colored.
Or shaped like a dinosaur.
Hold on guys.
It's broccoli!
Blah!
Yuck!
Well. I just saved our lives.
Yeah.
You're welcome.
Riley, if you don't eat your dinner,
you're not going to get any dessert.
Wait. Did he just say
we couldn't have dessert?
That's Anger.
He...
cares very deeply about
things being fair.
So, that's how you
want to play it, old man.
No dessert? Oh, sure.
We'll eat our dinner.
Right after you
eat this!
Arh!
Riley, Riley.
Here comes an airplane.
Oh, airplane.
We got an airplane, everybody.
- Oh.
And.you met Sadness.
She.Well, she.
I'm not actually sure what she does.
And I've checked, There's
no place for her to go. So.
She's good. We're good.
It's all great.
Anyway.
These are Riley's memories.
And they are mostly happy if you notice,
not to brag.
But the really important
ones are over here.
I don't want to get too technical
but these are called
core memories.
Each one came from a super
important time in Riley's life.
Like when she first scored a goal.
It was so amazing.
Hey-hey! Would you look at that.
Very nice.
- Woo-hoo!
- Yeah!
And each core memory powers
a different aspect of Riley's personality.
Like.
Hockey Island.
Goofball Island
is my personal favorite.
Come back here,
you little monkey!
Yup.
Goofball is the best.
Friendship Island is pretty good too.
Oh.
I love Honesty Island.
And that's the truth.
And of course,
Family Island is amazing.
The point is. The islands are personality
are what make Riley, Riley.
Look out,
Blue face.
Lava!
Hoo!
- Who's your friend who likes to play?
- Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
Hey, very nice.
- Agh.
- Brain freeze!
- Agh!
- Awh!
Aw.
- Yeah!
- Yeh!
- Good night, kiddo.
- Good night, Dad.
And...
We're out.
That's what I'm talking about.
Woo! Another perfect day.
Nice job everybody.
Let's get those memories
down to long term.
Alright.
We did not die today.
I call that an
unqualified success.
And, that's it.
We love our girl.
She's got great friends
and a great house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all.
Riley is 11 now.
What could happen?
Sold
- What?
- Aw!
- Hnh!
Okay.
Not what I had in mind.
Aw!
Hey, look. The Golden Gate Bridge,
isn't that great?
It's not made up of solid gold like we thought,
which is kind of disappointed.
But still...
I sure am glad you told me
earthquakes are a myth, Joy.
- Otherwise I be terrified right now.
- ... Yeah.
These are my kind of people.
Alright, just a few more blocks.
- We're almost to our new house.
- Step on it, Daddy.
Why can't we just live in the smelly car.
We're already been in it forever.
Which...
actually was really lucky.
Because that gave us plenty of time to think
about what our new house is going to look like.
What? Let's review
the top 5 daydreams.
- Woo, that looks safe.
- That looks nice.
Oh. This will be great for Riley.
Oh! No, no, no... this one.
Joy for the last time.
She cannot live in a cookie.
That's the one.
It comes with a dragon.
Are we getting close?
I can feel it.
Here it is.
Here's our new house.
And...
Maybe, it's nice on the inside.
- We're suppose to live here?
- Do we have to?
I'm telling you, it smells
that something died in here.
- Can you die from moving?
- Guys, you are overreacting.
- Nobody is dieing.
- A dead mouse!
- Great.
- I'm gonna be sick.
It's a house of the dead.
What're we gonna do?
- We're gonna get rabies.
- Get off from me!
Hey, hey, hey.
All through the drive,
Dad talked about how cool
our new room is.
- Let's go check it out.
- It's gonna be great.
Yes, yes, yes...
- No, no, no...
- I'm starting to envy the dead mouse.
Get out the rubber ball.
We're in solitary confinement.
- Riley can't live here.
- She's right.
- Really bad.
- It's absolutely the worst.
- This house stinks.
- It's the worst place
- ... I've been in my entire life.
- Oh, yeah.
Hey, it's nothing our
butterfly curtains couldn't fix.
I read somewhere that an
empty room is an opportunity.
- Where did you read that? - It doesn't
matter. I read it and it's great.
We'll put the bed there.
And the desk over there.
The hock lamp goes there.
- Put the chair there.
- Oh, the trophy collections.
- There...
- Stars!
- I like that.
- Now, we're talking.
Let's go get our stuff
from the moving van.
Alright. Goodbye.
Well, guess what?
The moving van won't
be here till next Thursday.
Your kidding.
Our van is lost?
It's the worst day ever.
- You said it would be here yesterday.
- And I know that's what I said.
- That's what they told me.
- Mom and Dad are stress out.
- They are stress out. - Arguing.
- What're we going to do.
I've got a great idea.
Did you even read the contract?
Anderson makes her move.
She's closing in.
Hey.
Oh no, you're not.
- She's running for the shot.
- Coming behind you, watch out.
And she scores!
Yeah!
- Woo-hoo.
- Yo-ho.
Come on.
Grandma.
Ha.
Grandma?
Oh-oh, she put her hair up.
We're in for it.
Heyyy.
Put me down.
- Eh-heh-heh.
- Ha-ha.
Sorry, hold on.
- Hello.
- Wait. What.
You're kidding.
Alright. Stall for me,
I'll be right there.
The investors are suppose to
show up on Thursday, not today.
- I got to go.
- It's okay, we get it.
You're the best. Thanks hon.
See you, sweetie.
Dad just left us.
Oh, he doesn't love us anymore.
That's sad.
I should drive, right?
Joy.
What are you doing?
Just you.
give me 1 second.
You know what I've realised.
Riley hasn't had lunch. Remember?
Hey, I saw a pizza place down the street.
Maybe we can try that.
- Pizza sounds delicious.
- Pizza.
- Yeah, pizza.
- Pizza. Great idea. Let's get it.
- What the heck is that?
- Who puts broccoli on pizza.
That's it. I'm done.
Congratulation San Francisco.
You ruined pizza.
First the Hawaiians.
And now you.
What kind of a pizza place
only serves 1 kind of pizza.
Must be a San Francisco thing.
Still, it's not as bad as the soup
at that diner in Nebraska.
Oh, yeah. The spoon stood up
in the soup by itself.
We're good.
Family's running.
The drive out was pretty fun.
What was your favorite part?
Spitting out of the car window.
- Definitely not when Dad was singing.
- Wearing the sit belt.
Oh. What about the time
with the dinosaur.
- Oh, that's the one.
- That was great.
Say cheese.
- Dad. Dad. Dad
- Honey.
Dad, look at the car.
Just look behind you.
No-no-no...
No!
Aw.
Nice one, Joy.
I like that time with the dinosaur.
That was pretty funny.
Wait, what.
What happened?
She did something to the memory.
- What did you do?
- I- I just touched it.
- That shouldn't make it change.
- Oh. Change it back, Joy.
- I'm trying.
- You can't change it back?
- No. I guess I can't.
- Good going, Sadness.
Now when Riley thinks of that moment
with Dad, she's gonna feel sad. Bravo.
I'm sorry, Joy. I don't really know.
I thought maybe if you, if you, I mean...
Joy.
We got a stairway coming up.
Just don't touch any other memories
until we figured out what's going on.
- Okay.
- Alright.
Get ready. This is the monster railing
and we are riding it all the way down.
Wait, what.
What happened?
- A core memory!
- Oh no.
- Sadness, what're you doing?
- It looked like one was crooked
So I opened it and it fell out.
I.
Woo-hoo!
It's just that. I want to,
maybe. hold one.
- Joy!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Sadness. You nearly
touch a core memory.
And when you touch them,
we can't change them back.
Oh, I know. I'm sorry.
Something's wrong with me.
I... It's like
I'm having a break down.
You're not having a break down.
It's stress.
I keep making mistakes like that.
I'm awful.
- Oh, you're not.
- And annoying.
They, well...
You know what.
You can't focus on
what's going wrong.
There's always a way
to turn things around
To find the fun.
Yeah, find the fun.
I don't know how to do that.
Okay, well.
Try to think of something funny.
Oh. Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies?
Oh, yeah.
That's not...
What about that time, with Mag.
When Riley laughed so hard,
milk came out of her nose.
Come on.
Yeah, that hurts.
It felt like fire.
- It was awf...
- Okay, okay.
Don't think of that.
Let's try something else.
- What're your favorite things to do.
- My favorite?
Well, I like it
when we're outside.
That's good! Like, there's
the beach and sunshine.
Oh. Like the time we buried
Dad in the sand up to his neck.
I was thinking more like rain.
Rain
Rain is my favorite too!
We can stomp around the puddles
You know.
There's cool umbrellas, lightning storms.
More like when the rain went south and bad,
that makes our shoe soggy.
And we get all cold, shivery and
everything starts feeling droopy.
Oh. Hey, hey, hey.
Easy.
Why are you crying?
It's... It's really the opposite
of what we're going for here.
Crying helps me slow down and not
obsessive worried of life's problems.
You know what?
Let's think about something else.
How about we read some mind manuals.
Sounds fun.
I've read most of them.
Well. Have you read this one.
This seem interesting.
Long term memory retrieval.
Volume 47.
- No.
- Woo. A real page turner.
Long term memory data selection
via channel sober be.
See. Fun already.
Oh, you lucky dog.
You're reading these cool things,
I got to go work. Life is so unfair.
Ugh.
What can we do. We only got
capital that'll last a month maybe two.
If we can't find investors by then,
we're gonna have to lay people off.
Mom. Dad.
Come kiss me good night.
- I know. I know. We got to land
this, okay. - Be right there.
Did you hear Dad?
He sounded really upset.
What was that? Was it a bear?
It's a bear!
There are no bears
in San Francisco.
I saw a really hairy guy.
He looked like a bear.
Oh. I'm so jumpy, my
nerves are shocked.
Ew. I don't wanna
hear about your nerves.
I'll tell you what it is.
This move has been a bust.
That's what I've been
telling you guys.
There're at least 37 things for
Riley to be scared of right now.
This smell alone is enough
to make her gag.
I can't believe Mom and
Dad moved us here.
Look. I get it.
You guys have concerns.
But we've been through worst.
Tell you what. Let's make a list of all
the things Riley should be happy about.
Fine. Let's see.
This house stinks. Our room stinks.
- Pizza is weird here.
- Our friends are back home.
And all our stuff
is in the missing van.
Oh, come on.
It could be worse.
Yeah, Joy. We could be lying
on a dirty floor. In a bag.
Okay, I admit it.
We had a rough start.
- But think of all the good things that...
- No, Joy.
There is absolutely no reason
for Riley to be happy right now.
Let us handle this.
I say we skip school tomorrow and
lock ourselves in the bedroom.
We have no clean clothes
And we could cry until we can't breathe.
We should lock the door and
scream the curse word we know.
- It's a good one.
- Now, hold on.
Look. We all have our off days.
You know...
Hi honey.
The Mom bad news Train is pulling in.
Toot-toot.
Still no moving van.
Uh-huh.
Now they're saying it won't be here
till Tuesday. Can you believe it.
Toot-toot-toot.
- Where's Dad?
- On the phone.
This new adventure is
keeping him pretty busy.
I
rest my case.
Now, for a few well place
withering scowls.
I guess all I really
want to say is
thank you.
You know.
Through all these confusion you stayed...
Well,
you stayed our happy girl.
Your Dad is under
a lot of pressure.
But, if you and I can keep smiling,
it would be a big help.
We can do that for him.
Right?
Whoa.
Well.
Yeah.
Sure.
What did we do
to deserve you.
- Sweet dreams.
- Good night.
Well.
You can't argue with Mom.
- Happy it is.
- Can't argue with Mom, that's true.
- Team Happy. Sounds great.
- Totally behind you, Joy.
Looks like we're
going into R E M.
I've got dream duty so I'll take care
of sending these to long term.
Great day today, guys.
All is well, team Happy.
Alright.
What's on tonight, dream production?
Now. This is it.
The new place.
Come live with me, Riley.
- Somebody ordered a broccoli pizza.
- Eat me, I'm organic.
Now. Who is in charge of
programming down there?
I know I'm not suppose to do this.
But.
We are not going to
end the day like this.
Don't you worry.
I'm going to make sure that
tomorrow is another great day.
I promise.
Carame- Corn-Curls
- Hello. Did I wake you?
- Do you have to play that?
Well, I have to practice.
And I don't think of it as playing
so much as hugging
Okay. First day of school.
Very, very exciting.
I was up late last night figuring out
a new plan. Here it is.
- Fear. I need a list
- What?
of all the possible negative outcomes
on the first day at a new school.
Way ahead of you there.
They won't notice no meteor.
Disgust.
Make sure Riley stands out today.
But, also blends in.
When I'm through, Riley will
look so good,
the other kids will look at
their own outfits and fart.
Joy! Yes, Joy.
You'll be in charge of the console.
Keeping Riley happy
all day long.
And may I add, I love your dress,
it's adorable.
Oh, this old thing. Thank you so much.
I love the way it twirls.
Train of Thought,
right on schedule.
Anger.
Unload the daydreams.
I ordered extra,
in case things get slow in class.
Might come in handy. If this new school
is full of boring, useless classes.
Which it probably will be.
Oh, Sadness. I've a super
important job just for you.
- Really.
- Uh-heh. Follow me.
- What are you doing?
- And there. Perfect.
This is the circle of sadness.
Your job is to make sure that
all the sadness stays inside of it.
So, you want me
just to stand here?
Hey, it's not my place to
tell you how to do your job.
Just make sure that
all... the sadness
stays in the circle.
See. You're a pro at this.
Isn't this fun?
- No.
- Atta girl.
Alright everyone, fresh start.
We're going to have a good day
which will turn into a good week,
which will turn into a good year,
which will turn into a good life!
So, big day.
New school. New friends.
I know. I'm kind of nervous
but I'm mostly excited.
- How do I look? Do you like my quote?
- Very cute.
You gonna be okay.
You want us to walk with you?
Mom and Dad, with us in public.
No, thank you.
Yup, I'm on it.
Nope, I'm fine.
Bye Mom. Bye Dad.
Have a good day in school, monkey.
- Woo-woo... - Woo-woot...
- Woo... Woo...
Have a great day, sweetheart.
- Are you sure we want to do this?
- In we go.
Okay, going in.
Yes.
Okay. We've got a group of
cool girls at 2 o'clock.
- How do you know?
- Double ears pierce. Infinity scarf.
- Whoa. Is she wearing eye shadow?
- Yeah. We want to be friends with them.
- Let's go talk to them.
- Are you kidding.
We're not talking to them.
We want them to like us.
Oh... yeah.
Wait.  What?
Almost finished with
the potential disasters.
Worst scenario is either quicksands,
spontaneous combustion
or getting called on by the teacher.
As long as none of those happens...
Okay, everybody.
We have a new student in class today.
Are you kidding me! Out of the days!
This is not happening!
Riley, would you like to tell us
something about yourself?
No!
Pretend we can't speak English.
Don't worry.
I got this.
Okay.
My name is Riley Anderson.
I'm from Minnesota
and now I live here.
And how about Minnesota?
Can you tell us something about it?
Well you certainly get
a lot more snow than we do.
Ha-ha-ha.
She's hilarious.
Yeah, it get's pretty cold.
The lake freezes over.
And that’s when we play hockey.
I'm on a great team.
We're called the Prairie dogs.
My friend, Mag, plays forward
and my dad's the coach.
Pretty much everyone in my family skates.
It's kind of a family tradition.
We go out on the lake
almost every weekend.
Or, we did.
Till...
I moved away.
- Hey. What gives?
- What?
Hey, Sadness.
You touched a memory.
- We talked about this.
- Oh yeah, I know. But I...
Get back in your circle.
Ah.
What's going on?
- Get it out of there, Joy.
- Eject.
We used to play tag and stuff.
Cool kids whispering at 3 o'clock.
Did you see that look?
They're judging us.
Somebody help grab that thing.
Everybody put in...
But, everything is different now.
Since we moved.
Oh no.
We're crying and sloth.
What?
Sadness, what are you doing!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm, oh.
- It's a core memory.
- But, it's blue.
No!
Wait!
Stop it.
No.
Joy.
- That's a core memory.
- Hey!
- Stop it.  Let go.
- Don't.  Wait.
The core memories!
Aw!
No-no-no...
- Aw!
Thank you, Riley.
I know it can be tough
moving to a new place.
But we are happy
to have you here.
Alright everyone.
Get out you history books.
And turn to chapter 7.
Can I say that curse word now?
- Eh.
- Aw!
Awww!
Awwwww...!
Awwwwww...
Oh no.
1, 2, 3, okay.
Not enough.
What?
What a nice pass, over to Reed.
Constance cross the line.
Uh-oh.
She's looking at us.
- What did she say?
- What?
Oh, sorry sir.
No one was listening.
Isn't it garbage night?
We let the toilet seat up.
What? What is it, woman?
What?
- He's making that stupid face again.
- I could strangle him right now.
Signal him again.
Ah.
So.
Riley, how was school?
- Aw. Waste of time.
- You got to be kidding me. - Seriously?
For this, we gave up that
Brazilian helicopter pilot?
Move!
I'll be joy.
School was great.
Alright.
Riley.
Is everything okay?
Sir,
she just rolled her eyes at us.
What is her deal?
Alright, make a show of force.
I don't want to have to put the foot down.
No.
Not the foot.
Riley,
I do not like this new attitude.
Oh.
I'll show you attitude, old man.
No-no-no-no.
Stay happy.
What is your problem?
Just leave me alone.
Sir.
Reporting high level of sass.
Take it to DEFCON 2.
Your heard that gentlemen.
DEFCON 2.
Listen, young lady. I don't know where
this disrespectful attitude came from.
You want a piece of this, pops.
Come and get it!
Yeah.  Well.
Well.
Here it comes.
Prepare the foot.
Keys, to exec position.
Ready to launch
on your command, sir.
Awwww!
Just, shut up!
Fire.
That's it.
Go to your room.
Now.
Foot is down.
The foot is down.
Good job, gentlemen.
That could've been a disaster.
Well, that was a disaster.
Come.
Fly with me, criancinha
- Ah.
- Ahh.
We're gonna walk
out there, on that?
It's the quickest way back.
But it's right over the Memory Dump.
If we fall, we'll be forgotten forever.
We have to do this for Riley.
Just follow my footsteps.
Not that high.
It's totally,  ah.
Wooah.
Hey.
So...
Things got a little out
of hand downstairs.
You wanna talk about it?
Come on.
Where's my happy girl?
Monkey.
Woo-hoo.
Whoa!
He's trying to start up Goofball.
Come on.
Hoo-Haa.
Sadness!
Turn right back!
What the?
I get it.
You need some alone time.
And we'll talk later.
- We have a major problem.
- Oh, Joy. Where are you?
We lost Goofball Island.
That means she can lose Friendship
and Hockey and Honesty and Family.
You can fixed this.
Right, Joy?
- I-I don't know.
-Oh.
But we have to try.
Okay, come on.
- Riley's gone to sleep.
- Oh.
Which is a good thing
If... When you think about it.
Because nothing else bad
can happen when she's asleep.
We'll be back to Headquarters
before she wakes up.
We'll just go across
Friendship Island.
- Oh, we'll never make it.
- No-no-no...
Don't obsess over the
way of life's problems
Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies.
Oh Sadness.
We don't have time for this.
We'll just have to go around.
Take the scenic route.
Wait.
Joy, you can get lost in there.
- Think positive.
- Okay.
I'm positive you will
get lost in there.
That's long term memory.
An endless swarm of corridors and shelves.
I read about it in the manuals.
The manuals?
The manuals.
- You read the manuals.
- Yeah.
So you know the way back
to headquarters.
- I guess.
- Woo-Hnn!
You are my map.
Let's go.
Lead on, my map.
Show me where we're going.
Okay, only.
I'm too sad to walk.
Just give me a few hours to...
- Which way, left?
- Right.
No, I mean go left.
I said left was right like correct.
Okay.
This actually feels kind of nice.
Okay, here we go.
We'll be back to Headquarters before morning.
We can do it.
This will be easy!
This is working.
This is not working.
- Are we getting close?
- Yeah. Just another right.
And a left.
And then another left.
Are you sure you know
where we're going?
'Cause we seem to be
walking away from Headquarters.
Oh.
Riley's awake.
Oh. uh.
Don't.
Don't touch, remember?
If you touch them,
they stay sad.
Oh. Sorry.
I... I won't.
- Starting now.
- I can't take much more of this.
Forget them!
- Mind workers.
- But, Joy, we're almost oh.
Phone numbers.
We don't need all these.
They're in her phone.
- Just forget all that, please.
- Excuse me. Hi.
Forget it.
- I need to find Friendship Island.
- Look at this. 4 years of piano lessons.
Yeah.
It looks pretty faded.
You know what. Save Chopsticks and
Heart and Soul, get rid of the rest.
- Are you.
- US presidents. What do you think?
Just keep Washington,
Lincoln and the fat one.
- Forget them!
- Hey!
You can't throw those away.
Those are perfectly good memories.
The names of every
Cutiepie princess doll?
Yes.
That is critical information.
- Glitter storm, Honey pants...
- Forget them.
- Hey! Bring those back.
- They're in the Dump.
- Nothing comes back from the Dump.
- Yeah. Look, lady. This is our job, okay.
When Riley doesn't care
about a memory, it fades.
- Fades?
- Happens to the best of them.
Except for this bad boy.
This one will never fade
The song from the
gum commercial?
You know. Sometimes we send that one
up to Headquarters for no reason.
It just plays in Rileys head over
and over again like a million times.
Let's watch it again.
Yeah, I know. We all know the song.
Okay, real catchy.
- Hey. What do you think, should we do it?
- Yeah.
Okay. Here we go!
Ha-ha-ha.
What the?
This again?
Ha.
Great.
Wait! Do you know how to
get to Friendship Island!
Do you like it there?
Did you feel any earthquakes?
Is the bridge cool?
Yes. Good.
What happened with the playoffs.
We won the first game. Coach says we
might actually go to the finals this year.
Oh, and we got this new girl
on the team. She's so cool.
- Uh. She did not just say that.
- A new girl?
Mag has a new friend already?
Hey-hey.
Stay happy.
We do not want to lose
anymore islands here, guys.
We can pass the puck to each other
without even looking.
It's like mind reading.
You like to read minds, Mag.
- I got something for you to read.
- Anger. What?
- Right here! - Wait-wait-wait.
Let's just be calm for 1 second.
Aw!.
- I got to got.
- What?
I got to go.
Wait. Could you just please
tell me which way is.
Oh no.
Friendship Island.
What?
Not Friendship.
Oh, Riley love that one.
And now it's gone.
Goodbye Friendship
Hello Loneliness.
We'll just have to go the long way.
Yeah.
The long long long... way.
I'm ready.
There's got to be a better way.
- Woo. Well look at you.
- Huh?
I will take you
but not you.
Ah! Who am I kidding.
I can't leave you.
Hello!
- Aw.
- Wait. Hey, wait.
No, wait.
Stop.
- Excuse me.
- Aw!
Oh.
I was, I was looking for
- diversion!
- What?
Ha ha!
So long, sucker.
Ou.
I'm hurt all over.
Wait, I know you.
No, you don't.
I get that a lot.
- I look like a lot of people.
- No no no... I do.
Bing Bong,
Riley's imaginary friend.
- You really do know me?
- Of course.
Riley loved playings with you.
You two were best friends.
Oh, oh.
You wouldn't know.
- We're trying to get back to Headquarters.
- Headquarters?
- You guys are from Headquarters?
- Well, yeah.
I'm Joy.
This is Sadness.
- You're Joy, the Joy?
- Uh-huh.
What the heck
are you doing out here?
That's a good question.
You want to answer that, Sadness?
Without you,
I won't ever be happy.
We can't have that.
We got to get you back.
I'll tell you what.
Follow me.
Thank you. It is
so great to see you again.
I got to tell you.
I'm such a huge fan of your work.
Do you remember when
you and Riley were in a band?
Ha-ha-ha.
I went to all of your concerts.
Yeah.
I blow a mean nose.
- Watching you play tag was such a treat.
- 2 time room champ.
- Oh, and remember your rockets.
- Of course, it runs on song power.
That's right.
Your theme song.
- Who's your friend who likes to play?
- Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
- His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
What exactly are you
suppose to be?
You know what's unclear?
I'm mostly cotton candy. But.
Shape wise. I'm part cat,
part elephant, part dolphin.
Dolphin?
You got to remember. When Riley
was 3, animals were all her age.
The cow goes moo.
The horse goes neigh.
It's all the people
talked back then.
Yeah, yeah.
I guess that true.
- What are you doing out here?
- Well.
There's not much call for
imaginary friends lately.
So, I.
You know...
Yeah, yeah,
Don't be sad.
Tell you what.
When I get back up to Headquarters.
I'll make sure Riley remembers you.
- You will?
- Of course. She loved that.
Ha-ha!
This is the greatest day of my life.
Aw aw aw...
- Are you okay?
- Hey, what's going on?
I cry candy.
- Try the caramel, it's delicious.
- Woo.
- Whoa!
- Here use this.
- Thanks.
Oh, hold on.
Wait a second.
It always get stuck
at the bottom.
Here.
What?
It's imaginary.
Thanks. This will make it a lot easier
to walk back to Headquarters.
Walk?
We're not walking.
We're taking the Train of Thought.
The Train.
Of course.
That is so much fast.
But how do we catch it.
Well, it kind of go all over the place
but there is a station in Imagination Land.
I know a shortcut.
Come on, this way.
Oh. I'm so glad
we ran into you.
The station is right in here.
After you.
- Joy.
- What?
Well. I read about this place in the
manual. We shouldn't go in there.
Bing Bong says it's the
quickest way to Headquarters.
No. But Joy,
this is abstract thought.
What are you talking about?
I go in here all the time.
It's a shortcut.
You see.
(DANGER - Keep Out!)
I'll prove it to you.
Look at me.
I'm crossing into the station.
'Cause I'm taking the shortcut.
Let's. Let's go around.
This way.
Almost there.
If you want to walk
the long way, go for it.
But Riley needs to be happy.
I'm not missing that Train.
Bing Bong knows what he is doing.
He's part dolphin, they're very smart.
Well, I guess.
Okay. What abstract concept are we
trying to comprehend today.
- Loneliness.
- Hm.
I think there is
something in there.
I'm going to turn it on for a minute
and burn out the dumb thoughts.
What did I tell ya.
You'll be in Headquarters in no time.
Hey, will you look at that?
- Whoa. What's happening?
- Oh no, they turned it on.
Oh.
Never seen this before.
My face. My beautiful face.
Whoa!
- What is going on?
- We're abstracting.
There are 4 stages.
This is the first.
Nonobjective fragmentation.
Alright, do not panic. What's
important is that we all stay together.
- Oh.
- Aw.
We're in the second stage.
We’re deconstructing.
Run!
Aw.
I can't feel my legs.
- Oh, there they are.
- Come here, me.
We got to get out of here.
Before we're not even shape and color
We'll get stuck here forever
Bong.
Why did we come in here?
I told you.
It's a shortcut.
The Train.
Oh no. We're 2 dimensional.
That's stage 3.
- We're getting no where.
- Death. Unlucky death.
Come on.
We can't fit.
Oh no, we're not figurative
This is the last stage.
We're not gonna make it.
Wait, we're 2 dimensional.
Fall on your face.
Stop.
Stop!
No.
You said that was a shortcut.
I did. But wow,
we should not had gone in there.
That was dangerous.
They should really put up a sign.
- How long till the next Train?
- Who knows?
But don’t worry.
There's another station. That way.
The Train always stops there,
right before it goes to Headquarters.
If we hurry,
we can catch it.
This isn't another one
of your shortcuts, is it?
Ha-ha-ha.
Yeah.
- Is there really another station?
- Uh-huh. Through there.
- Welcome to Imagination Land.
- Imagination Land?
Sure. I come here all the time.
I'm practically the mayor.
Hey, you guys hungry?
There's French Fries Forest.
No way!
Ha-ha-ha.
Check it out.
Trophy Town.
Medals,  Ribbons.
Everyone's a winner.
I won first prize.
- Me too!
- Oh. Participation award.
Wait, is that?
Is that a? Look.
It's Cloud Town.
That's my favorite.
Hoo-hoo-hoo.
- Oh, it's so soft.
- Oh oh oh. Let me try.
Hey!
What the big idea?
You better fix that wall or else
you're in big trouble.
Oh no, lava.
Woo. Whoa.
Imagination Land is the best.
Oh, is it all going
to be so interactive.
Hey look!
The House of Cards.
Woo wait.
Hang on just a minute.
- Your rocket.
- Yeah.
I stashed it in there
for safekeeping.
And now I'm all set
to take Riley to the moon!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Great.
- Whoa. I love Imagination Land.
- Isn't it great?
And there's always
something new like...
- Who the heck is that?
- Imaginary boyfriend.
- I would die for Riley.
- Whoa.
- I've never seen him before.
- I live in Canada.
Anyway. Through Preschool World.
We're nearly to the train.
Riley, here we come.
Woo-Hoo. Ha-ha-ha.
This should be fun.
New team. New friends.
There kids looked pretty good.
Considering they're from
San Francisco. Heh-heh-heh.
- Got to go.
- Okay. Good luck, sweetie.
Look, kissing isn't going to help us now.If she
tries to use Hockey Island. It's going down.
Which is why, I recalled
every hockey memory I can think of.
One of these is got to work
in place of a core memory.
- She's about to play.
- Hurry.
Ha ha. We did it gang.
It's working.
Oh.
Hahaha.
No-no-no... Aw!
It's like we don't learn anything.
- That's it.
- No no no.
Free on your happy place.
Aw!
- Riley, what's wrong?
- Let's go.
- You're not going to finish try outs?
- What's the point?
Hey.
It will be alright.
- Let's just go back.
- Stop saying everything will be alright.
Hockey!
Oh no no.
She loves hockey.
She can't give up hockey.
Bing Bong,
we have to get to that station.
Sure thing. This way,
just past Grand Cracker Castle.
Hey.
That's weird.
Grand Cracker Castle used to be right here.
I wonder why they moved it.
I would have sworn
Sparkle Pointy Mountain was right here.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Yeah yeah. I don't know.
- We'll have to come back.
- Princess Dreamworld
Oh,
The Stuffed Animal Hall of Fame.
My rocket?
Wait.
Riley and I were still using that rocket.
It still has some song power left.
Who's your friend
who likes to play?
No!
No no.
You can't take my rocket to the Dump.
Riley and I are going to the moon.
Riley can't be done with me?
Hey, it's going to be okay.
We can fix this.
We just need to get back to Headquarters.
Which way to the Train station?
I had a whole trip
planned for us.
Hey, who's ticklish.
Here comes the tickle monster.
Hey.
Bing Bong, look at this.
Oh, here's a fun game.
You point to the Train station
and we all go there.
Won't that be fun?
Come on,
let's go to the Train station.
I'm sorry they took your rocket.
They took something that you loved.
It's gone, forever.
- Sadness, don't make him feel worse.
- Sorry.
It's all I had left with Riley.
I bet you and Riley
had great adventures.
Oh, they were wonderful.
Once, we flew back in time.
We had breakfast twice that day.
- Sadness.
- It sounds amazing. I bet Riley liked it.
Oh, she did.
We were best friends.
Yeah.
What?
I'm okay now.
Come on.
The Train station is this way.
- How did you do that?
- Oh, I don't know.
- I feel sad so I listen to what...
- Hey!
There's the Train.
Oh, we made it. We're
finally going to get home.
Oh no.
These facts and opinions look so similar.
Don't worry about it.
Happens all the time.
On a scale of 1 to 10.
I give this day an 'F'.
Well, why don't we quit standing
around and do something.
- Like what, genius?
- Like quitting. That's what I'm doing.
Sure. It's the coward's way out.
But this coward is gonna survive.
Emotions can't quit, genius.
Ewg. I thought we're
suppose to keep Riley happy
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute!
Uh-huh!
H0 ho ho...
- What is it?
- Oh nothing.
- Just the best idea ever.
- What?
All the good core memories
were made in Minnesota.
Ergo, we go back to Minnesota
and make more.
- Ta-dah.
- Wait wait wait.
You're say we
run away?
Well, I wouldn't call it that.
I call it the 'Happy core
memory development program'.
- You can't be serious.
- Hey, our life was perfect.
Until Mon and Dad decided to
move to San Fran stincko.
But, I mean.
It's just so drastic.
Need I remind you of how
great things were there.
Our room. Our backyard.
Our friends.
Did I ask for the gum commercial?
Anyway, it was better.
That's my point.
- Yeah, Riley was happier in Minnesota.
- Wait. Hold on.
Should we just sleep
on this or something?
Fine, let's sleep on it.
But, hey. I'm sure joyly fun-filled
times are just around the corner.
Huh?
Hey hey.
Why aren't we moving?
Riley's gone to sleep.
We're all on break.
You mean we're stuck
here until morning?
Yeah. The Train of Thought
doesn't run while she's asleep.
- Oh, we can't wait that long.
- How about we wake her up.
Sadness, that's ridiculous.
How can we possibly...
- How about we wake her up.
- Great idea Joy.
Thanks, come on.
Production of
Dreams
Whoa. This place is huge.
It looks so much smaller
than I expected.
Wow, I can fly.
I love that one.
Rainbow Unicorn.
She's right there.
My friend says you're famous.
- She wants your autograph.
- No no, Sadness.
Don't bother Miss. Unicorn, okay?
Sorry she's from out of town.
It's so embarrassing, right?
I love you in Fairy Dream Adventure part 7.
Okay bye. I love you.
[No Entry When
The Light Is On]
Huh! Wonder what that means?
Oh well, let's go in.
Set up the classroom set.
Today's memories are in.
We've got a lot to work with here.
Riley dumped her best friend, had a
miserable day at school and quit hockey.
The writers had put
together a killer script.
Just because Joy and Sadness are gone,
I have the stupid dream duty.
Okay. How are we
going to wake her up?
Well. She wakes up sometimes
when she has a scary dream.
- We could scare her.
- Scare her?
- No no. She's been though enough already.
- But, Joy.
Sadness, you may know your
way around down here.
But I know Riley.
We're gonna make her so happy,
she'll wake up with exhilaration
- We'll excite her awake.
- That's never happen before.
Woo, Riley loves dogs.
Put this on.
I don't think that will work.
- Bing Bong.
- Yeah.
- Don't let anything happen to these.
- Got it.
Uh-huh.
Add the reality distortion filter.
Love it. Remember, play
to the camera everyone.
Riley is the camera.
Make them get out of there.
We are on in
5 4 3...
Hello class.
Before we begin today’s pop quiz...
And she is one bad actress
I want to introduce our new student.
Riley. Would you like
to stand up and introduce
- Camera.
- ... yourself.
And, to Riley.
My name is Riley Anderson.
I'm from Minnesota
and now I live here.
Ew. Look, her teeth
are falling out.
Ew, gross.
Teeth falling out.
Yeah, I'm used to that one.
Let me guess.
We've no pants on.
Hey, look. She came to
school with no pants on.
Called it!
- Ready? I don't think this
happy thing is going to work.
- But if we scare her.
- Just follow my lead.
Here we go.
Aruu.
Bark-bark-bark.
- Who is that?
- What's going on?
Psst, you're on.
Go.
Woo. Let's party.
Let's dance. Woo.
Hey.
A party.
Bark-bark-bark.
Joy, this is not working.
No.
Huh.
Huh.  Sadness, what are you doing?
Come back here.
It's just a dream. It's just a dream.
It's just a dream.
They're trying to wake her up.
Call security.
- Hi Riley, it's me.
- Bing Bong?
Sadness.
You are ruining this dream.
- You're scaring her.
- But look. It's working.
Whoa.
They're not part of this dream.
Get them.
Stop right there!
Pan away.
Boo.
Peek and Poke line.
Aw, careful.
You can't do this.
I know people in Headquarters.
No-no-no...
There go the core memories.
Come on.
- What is this place?
- The subconscious.
That's where they take
all the troublemakers.
My hat feels loose.
How do we get in?
- Is that your hat?
- Yeah, it's my hat.
You sure, I don't know.
Look at the label.
Yeah, it says my hat.
- Wait. It says my hat?
- My hat, it says.
- That's what I wrote in my hat.
- What are you talking about?
- Look. You got my hat on.
- Okay, it's my hat.
- Hey you.
- Oh, you caught us.
Get back in there.
No escaping.
Oh.
I don't like it here. It's where
they keep Riley's darkest fears.
It's broccoli.
The stairs to the biggest smite.
Grandma's vacuum cleaner.
Aw!
Okay, come on.
- Would you walk quieter.
- I'm trying.
What is going...
Candy wrappers.
- Bing Bong.
- Joy?
- There you are.
- Shh.
Who's the person...
- Do you have the core memories?
- Yeah.
All he cared about
was the candy.
Shh.
We're outta here.
Let's get to that Train.
Wait. The Train is not running.
We still have to wake up Riley.
But how?
Oh no.
Hey Sadness. Did you hear
about the party they were having.
Yeah, yes Joy.
Isn't it a bir-bir-birthday party?
Did you say birthday?
- And there's going to be cake and presents.
- And games and balloons.
A Birthday!
Okay.
Follow us.
Nothing like a good scare
to wake you up, right?
- Okay, it's my hand writing.
- No, it isn't.
- It's my hat. I wrote that.
- No, this one's my hat.
- Who's the birthday girl?
- Aw!
- Woo-hoo.
- Come on, let's go.
- Ha ha. We made it.
- Ha ha.
- Guess who's on their way to Headquarters.
- We are.
- What is going on?
- He did it again.
We were at school. And we were naked.
And there was a dog.
The back half was...
It was- It was chasing it, I mean.
- There was a Bing Bong.
- You idiot. It was a dream.
This is ridiculous. We can't even
get a good night sleep anymore.
Time to take action.
Stupid Mon and Dad.
If they hadn't move us
none of this would have happen.
Who's with me?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
She took it.
There's no turning back.
So. How are we going to
get to Minnesota from here.
Well. Why don't we go down to the
elephant lot and rent an elephant.
Hey, that sounds nice.
We're taking the bus, nitwit!
There is a bus leaving
tomorrow, perfect.
A ticket cost money.
How do we get money?
- Mom's purse.
- Oh. You wouldn't.
Oh, but I would.
Where was it we saw it last?
- No!
- Aw!
It's downstairs somewhere.
Mom and Dad got us into this mess.
They can pay to get us out.
How about this...
Isn't this nice?
You can see everything
from up here.
Look. There's Inductive Reasoning.
There's Deja Vu.
There's Language Processing.
There's Critical Thinking.
There's Deja Vu.
And look at this guy's memories.
Hey.
That was a good idea.
About scaring Riley awake.
- You're not so bad.
- Really?
Nice work.
I can't wait to get
the old Riley back.
As soon as we get there,
I'm going to fix this whole mess.
Whoa.
Is this Riley?
She's so big now.
She won't fit in my rocket.
How're we gonna
get to the moon.
Oh. It's that time in the
Twistee Treat, remember?
The hockey team showed up and
Mon and Dad were there cheering.
Look at her.
Having fun and laughing.
- I love this one.
- I love that one too.
- Atta girl. Now you're getting it.
- Yeah.
It was the day the Prairie dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful, she wanted to quit.
Sorry.
I went sad again, didn't I?
I'll tell you what. We can keep working
on that when we get back, okay?
Okay.
I just don't understand.
Why did our moving van
even go to Texas?
Multiple customer.
Well, we were promised
delivery on the 5th.
Uh-huh.
Excuse me. Isn't there any way
you think you can even rush it.
Honesty Island?
Look out!
Aw!
Come on!
Hold on!
- Hurry up.
- Join over here.
- Go-go-go.
- I got it.
- Pull.
That was our way home.
We lost another island.
What is happening?
Haven't you heard?
Riley is running away.
What?
Wait wait.
Hang on, guys.
Are we really doing this?
This is serious.
Look.
We have no core memories.
You want Riley to be happy?
Let's go back to Minnesota
and make more.
Joy. If we hurry,
we can still stop her.
Family Island.
Let's go.
Joy.
Joy. It's too dangerous.
We won't make it in time.
But, that's our only way back.
A recall tube.
We can get recall.
Have a great day, sweetheart.
- See you after school, monkey.
- We love you.
Go, run run!
Go!
Whoa whoa,
Sadness.
Stop.
- You're hurting Riley.
- No no no. I did it again.
If you get in here,
these core memories will get sad.
I'm sorry.
- Riley needs to be happy.
- Joy?
Aww!
Joy.
Aw!
Joy!
Joy?
Joy. Joy, what're you doing?
Would you stop it, please.
Don't you get it, Joy.
We're stuck down here.
We're forgotten.
Do you remember, how she used to stick
her tongue out when she was coloring.
I could listen to
her stories all day
I just wanted
Riley to be happy.
It was the day the Prairie dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful.
She wanted to quit.
Sadness.
Mom and Dad.
The team.
They came to help
because of sadness.
We have to
get back up there.
Joy, we're stuck down here.
We might as well be
on another planet.
Another planet.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way,
and wants to sing this song to say.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Hop in.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
Who's the best in every way,
and wants to sing this song to say.
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
Who's the best in every way,
and wants to sing this song to say...
Aww!
Come on!
Aw!
Aw.
Come on Joy, one more time.
I got a feeling on this one.
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
Who's the best in every way,
and wants to sing this song to say.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
Louder! Louder!
Joy, sing louder!
We're gonna make it.
Woo-hoo.
Bing Bong,
we did it!
We...
Bing Bong?
Bing Bong!
Ha ha! You made it!
Ha ha!
Go! Go save Riley.
Ha ha ha.
Take her to the moon for me.
Okay?
Oh.
I'll try, Bing Bong.
I promise.
We're home!
Riley?
I'll call her cell.
Oh, this is terrible.
Wait. Is that someone
walking towards us?
Look.
Let's cross the street.
It's Mom.
She's on to us.
- What do we do? - Where's my bag?
- Riley needs to get core memories.
We keep going.
Sadness!
Sadness?
Come on, Sadness.
Where are you?
Okay. If I were Sadness,
where would I be?
Oh. Everything is awful
and my legs don't work.
And you have to drag me around
while I touch all the...
Oh no. It's Mom again.
What do we do?
Uh.
This is madness.
She shouldn't run away.
Let's get this idea
out of her head.
Sadness?
- Sadness.
- Joy?
Wait.
Sadness.
Just let me go. Riley is
better of without me.
Come back!
You're saying your husband was
blown away by an elephant.
- Was he with anyone?
- Yes. And there she is!
Hey!
Come back here!
Forget it Jake.
It's cloud talk.
Sadness.
- I only make everything worse.
- Wait.
Sadness, we got to
get you back to...
- It's stuck.
- Oh, great. - What?
- What do you mean it's stuck?
- Now what?
No-no-no.
What is this?
- How do we stop it?
- I got it.
Make her feel scared.
That will change her mind.
- Brilliant.
- I know it's brilliant. Do it.
Nothings working.
Why isn't it working?
- Let me try.
- Wait. You broke it. - No.
- Move. Move.
- Let me do it. Get out of here.
No.
Guys. We can't make
Riley feel anything.
What have we done?
Hey. Hey, look at me.
Did you mean what you said before.
I would die for Riley.
Yeah yeah. Okay, haircut.
Time to prove it.
I would die for Riley.
That's it.
I fold.
Whao...
- Whoa.
Whoa.
Okay. Whoa.
- Woo-woo-woo.
- Whoa.
This is crazy.
No no no.
Joy, be positive.
I'm positive this is crazy.
Now!
For Riley...
- Joy?
- Hang on.
Oh, I wished Joy was here.
Stand back.
Yah!
- That work.
- Well, what would you do if you're so smart.
I'll tell you.
But you're too dumb to understand.
- What!
- Of course your tiny brain is confuse.
Guess I'll just have to dumb it
down to your level.
Sorry I don't speak moron
as well as you. But let me try.
Duh.
Awwww!
Oh.
Thank goodness you're back.
- Things are really messed up.
- We-we-we found this idea.
Oh no.
Joy, you got to fix this.
Get out there.
- Sadness, it's up to you.
- Me?
- Sadness? - Sadness? - Sadness?
- I can't, Joy.
- Yes you can.
Riley, needs you.
Okay.
Wait. Stop.
I want to get off.
Alright.
Thank you, we will.
- Her teacher hasn't even seen Riley all day.
- What?
What was she wearing last?
- Can't believe this.
- Do you even remember what...
- Riley.
- Hey. There you are.
- Thank goodness.
- Oh, we were worried sick.
- Where have you been? It's so late.
- Oh.
Riley, what happened?
Are you alright.
I know you don't want me to.
But.
I missed home.
I missed Minnesota.
You need me to be happy.
But.
I want my old friends
and hockey team
I want to go home.
Please don't be mad.
- Oh, sweetie.
- We're not mad.
You know what?
I missed Minnesota too.
I missed the woods
that we took hikes.
And the backyard where
you used to play.
Spring lake.
Where you learned to skate.
Come here.
Hey.
I'm liking this new view.
Friendship Island has expanded.
Glad they finally opened that
friendly argument section.
I like
Tragic Vampire Romance Island.
Fashion Island.
Everyone shut up.
Boy Band Island?
That's just a phase.
Say what you want.
I think it's all beautiful.
Alright.
Here you go.
Your new expanded console
is up and running.
- Whoa.
- Wow.
- Cool. Upgrade.
- Woo.
Aye, ho ho.
Whoops, did I just do that?
Okay.
Guys, what is 'PUBERTY'.
I don't know.
It's probably not important.
Whoa. I have access to the
entire curse word library.
This new console is the
...
Sorry. I did it again.
My bad.
They're getting to the rink.
Now, when you get out there.
You be aggressive.
- I know Dad.
- Not too aggressive.
You know. You guys don't have
to come to every game.
Are you kidding?
I'm not missing one!
- Go Fog Horns!
- Go Riley!
- Fog.. Horns...
- Okay okay. - Fog Horns
- I got to go.
- the best...
- Oh.
- They love us.
Yeah. Mom and Dad
are pretty cool.
Guys, of course they are.
But we can't show it.
Yeh.
She loved the face painting.
Ha.
Told you it was a great idea.
- Best idea he's had in a while.
- He's a really good guy.
- Ah.
- Oh.
Just in case.
Oh.
Sorry.
- Aww!
- GIRL! GIRL!
- Oh oh.
- GIRL!
Okay.
Bye.
Hey Riley.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Alright.
Let's play some hockey.
- Alright, Anger. Take over.
- Give us that puck or you're dead meat!
On her left.
On her left!
Let's just try not to get
all smelly this time.
Oh. Mom and Dad
are watching us fail.
Not for long!
We've been through a lot
lately that's for sure.
But we sill love our girl.
She has great new friends
and great new house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all, Riley is 12 now.
What could happen?
And who can tell me what year
San Francisco was founded.
Anyone?
- Jordan.
- Uh.
How much more of this?
5 months 2 weeks and 4 days
until summer vacation.
Then it's off to the Bahamas
with you know who.
Come.
Fly with me, criancinha
- Ah.
Have a nice day.
What are we mad about?
I don't know.
Whatever Troy is mad about.
What's Troy mad about?
- I don't know.
I know, I told her that.
We are a total fraud.
Do you think they can see through us.
Of course not.
We're wearing eye shadow.
Being cool is so exhausting.
Who's the birthday girl?
Huh.
Hey.
Hello?
6 years of drama school
for this.
- What?
- Let's move.
Look. This is okay.
This is fine.
We just need to go
to our happy place.
- Aw!
- Aww!
It smells good.
it will be good.
It is good.