Copy boy!
- Make it snappy.
- Where's the rest of this story?
Morning Post.
City desk? Just a moment.
If anybody asks,
I'm at the courthouse.
- Elevator!
- Going down.
- Hello, Hildy.
- Hi, Skinny.
Hello, Ruth, Maisie.
- Is the lord of the universe in?
- Yes, in a bad humour.
Somebody stole
the crown jewels.
- Shall we announce you?
- I'll blow my own horn.
Bruce, wait.
I'll be back in ten.
Ten minutes is a long time
to be away from you.
What did you say?
Go on.
Well, go ahead.
Even ten minutes is a long time
to be away from you.
I like it. That's why I asked
you to say it again.
I like being spoiled. The man
I'm going to see did very little of it.
I'd like to spoil him.
Want me to go with you?
- I can handle it.
- If it gets rough, I'm here.
I'll come running, partner.
- Hello, Jim.
- Hello, Hildy!
- How are you?
- Welcome back.
Hello, Hildy, how have you been?
Beatrice, how's
"Advice to the Lovelorn"?
- Fine. My cat had kittens again.
- Your fault.
Glad to see you. Hi, Jim.
Mildred, you still around?
A little more around the chin, boss.
- What do you want?
- Your ex-wife is here.
Hello, Hildy.
- Hello, Walter.
- Hi.
Hi, Louie.
How's the slot-machine king?
I ain't doing that no more.
I'm retired. Know what I mean?
- Walter.
- I'm busy!
The governor didn't sign
that reprieve.
Tomorrow, Earl Williams dies
and makes a sucker out of us.
What are you gonna do?
- Phone the governor.
- I can't.
- Why not?
- He's out fishing.
- How many places to fish are there?
- Two. Atlantic and Pacific.
That simplifies it.
- Get him.
- And say what?
Quiet, Duffy. He's thinking.
If he reprieves Williams,
we'll support him for senator.
Tell him the Morning Post
will back him.
- You can't.
- Why?
We're a democratic paper.
After we get the reprieve,
we'll be democratic again.
Get going. The Morning Post
expects every editor to do his duty.
You too, Louie.
Get out of here.
Walter, I see you're still at it.
First time I cheated a governor.
What can I do for you?
Would you mind if I sat down?
There's a lamp burning in the
window for you. Here.
I jumped out of that window
a long time ago, Walter.
May I have one of those?
Thank you.
And a match?
- How long is it?
- How long is what?
You know what.
How long is it since
we've seen each other?
Well, let's see.
I spent six weeks in Reno,
then Bermuda. About four months.
Seems like yesterday.
Maybe it was yesterday, Hildy.
Been seeing me in your dreams?
Mama doesn't dream about you.
You wouldn't know her now.
Yes, I would.
I'd know you anytime.
"Anyplace, anywhere."
You're repeating yourself.
You said that when you proposed.
You still remember it.
If I didn't remember it,
I wouldn't have divorced you.
I sort of wish you hadn't.
- What?
- Divorced me.
It makes a fellow lose faith. It gives
him a feeling he wasn't wanted.
That's what divorces are for.
Nonsense, you've got an old-fashioned
idea divorces last forever.
"Till death do us part."
Divorce doesn't mean anything.
Just a few words mumbled by a judge.
We've got something
nothing can change.
- I suppose you're right, in a way.
- Sure.
- I am fond of you, you know.
- Thattagirl!
I often wish you weren't
such a stinker.
You must meet my mother.
She'd like that.
Why'd you promise not to fight
the divorce and then gum up the works?
I meant to let you go, but...
...you never miss the water
till the well runs dry.
A big lummox like you,
hiring an airplane to write:
"Hildy, don't be hasty.
Remember my dimple. Walter."
It delayed our divorce
while the judge watched it.
I've still got the dimple,
and in the same place.
I acted like a husband who didn't
want his home broken.
- What home?
- Remember the home I promised you?
Sure I do. That was the one we were
to have right after the honeymoon.
That honeymoon!
Was it my fault? Did I know that
coal mine would have a cave-in?
I intended to be with you
on our honeymoon.
Instead of two weeks in Atlantic City
with my bridegroom...
...I spent two weeks in a mine
with John Kruptzky.
You deny it?
We beat the whole country
on that story!
That isn't what I got married for!
Oh, what is the good?
Look, Walter.
I came to tell you to stop
phoning me a dozen times a day...
...sending me 20 telegrams...
- I write a beautiful telegram.
- Are you gonna listen?
What's the use of fighting?
I'll tell you what you do.
Come back to work on the paper,
and if we can't get along...
...we'll get married again.
- What?
- I haven't any hard feelings.
Walter, you're wonderful,
in a loathsome sort of way.
- Be quiet so I can say what I have to.
- Tell me over lunch.
I have a lunch date.
- Break it.
- I can't.
Hands off!
Are you playing osteopath?
Temper, temper.
You are no longer my husband
and no longer my boss.
And you won't be my boss.
- What does that mean?
- Just what I say.
You're not coming back to work?
You're right for
the first time today.
- Got a better offer?
- You bet.
Go on, work for somebody else!
That's the gratitude I get.
Stop hamming.
Five years ago, you were a college girl.
I took a doll-faced hick!
You wouldn't have
if I wasn't doll-faced.
It was a novelty to have a face
to look at without shuddering.
I made you a great reporter.
You won't be as good on another paper.
We're a team.
The paper needs both of us!
Sold American!
- All right, go ahead.
- Listen, Walter, please.
The paper's gonna have to get along
without me. So will you.
It didn't work out.
It would have if you'd been
satisfied as editor and reporter.
But you had to marry me.
I wasn't satisfied?
I suppose I proposed to you!
Practically!
Making eyes at me until I broke down.
"Oh, Walter!"
I was tight when I proposed to you.
If you'd been a gentleman,
you'd have forgotten it.
You used to pitch better than that.
Hello. What?
Sweeney? What can I do for you?
What?
I'm not Sweeney. I'm Duffy.
You can't do that.
Not today, of all days!
What's the matter with you?
Are you loony?
Now, listen, Sweeney.
This is no time...
All right, I suppose so.
If you have to, you have to.
- He had to.
- Everything happens to me.
365 days in a year,
and this has to be the day.
What's wrong?
- Sweeney.
- Dead?
He might as well be.
He picks today to have a baby!
Not on purpose?
He's supposed to cover the
Earl Williams case, and where is he?
Walking around a hospital.
Is there no honour?
Haven't you got anybody else?
Nobody else on the paper can write.
This'll break me. Unless...
Hildy.
- You can help me.
- Not a chance.
- Get out, Duffy!
- Save your breath.
- This'll bring us together again.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
This is bigger than anything.
Do it for the paper.
Scram, Svengali.
If not for love, how about money?
I'll raise you $25 a week.
Listen to me, you baboon...
- I'll make it $35 and not a cent more.
- Listen!
- How much will the other paper pay?
- There's no other paper.
The raise is off.
You get your old salary.
Trying to blackjack me.
- I'm busy.
- Look at it.
Do you know what it is?
It's an engagement ring.
Engagement ring?
I tried to tell you right away,
but you would start reminiscing.
I'm getting married and as far away
from newspapers as I can get.
- What?
- I'm through.
- You can get married, you can't quit.
- No? Why not?
I know what it would do.
- What?
- It would kill you.
- You can't sell me that.
- You're a newspaperman.
I wanna go where I can be a woman.
- You mean a traitor.
- Traitor to what?
To journalism.
You're a journalist!
A journalist?
What does that mean?
Peeking through keyholes,
chasing fire engines...
...waking people up
to ask them questions...
...stealing pictures off old ladies?
I know about reporters.
Buttinskies running around
with no money, and why?
So a million people will know
what's going on. Why, I...
What's the use?
You wouldn't know
what it means...
...to want to be respectable and
live a halfway normal life.
The point is, I'm through.
- Where did you meet this man?
- Bermuda.
Rich?
He's not what you'd call rich.
He makes $5000 a year.
- What's his line?
- He's in the insurance business.
- Insurance business?
- That's a good, honest business, right?
Sure, it's honest.
It's also adventurous.
I can't picture you
being surrounded by policies...
I can, and I like it, what's more.
He forgets the office
when he's with me.
He doesn't treat me like an
errand boy, but like a woman.
How did I treat you?
Like a water buffalo?
I don't know from buffaloes.
I know about him.
He's kind, sweet
and considerate.
He wants a home and children.
Sounds like a guy I should marry.
His name?
Baldwin. Bruce Baldwin.
I knew a Baldwin once, a horse thief.
Couldn't be the same fella, could it?
You're not talking about the man
I'm marrying tomorrow.
Tomorrow? As soon as that?
At last, I got out what
I came up here to tell you.
Guess there isn't any more
to the story.
So long, Walter.
So long, Hildy.
Better luck next time.
Thanks.
Well, you kind of took
the wind out of my sail.
I just want to wish you
everything I couldn't give you.
This other fellow. I'm sorry
I didn't get a chance to see him.
I'm particular about
whom my wife marries.
Where is he?
He's right on the job,
waiting for me out there.
Do you mind if I meet him?
- It wouldn't do any good.
- You're not afraid?
Of course not.
Let's see this paragon.
Is he as good as you say?
He's better.
- What does he want with you?
- You got me.
Back in an hour, Mildred.
I am sorry.
I suppose Bruce... What's his name?
- I suppose he opens doors for you?
- And with a lady, he takes his hat off.
I am sorry.
When he walks with a lady,
he waits for her.
In that case...
Allow me.
I can see my wife picked out
the right husband for herself.
There must be a mistake.
I'm already married.
Already married?
You should have told me.
Congratulations again.
- No, my name...
- Mr. Burns.
I'm busy.
What did you say, Mr. Baldwin?
- Mr. Burns.
- My name is...
I'm busy with Mr. Baldwin.
I didn't hear you.
- My name is...
- Mr. Burns...
- What is it?
- I'm Bruce Baldwin.
Can't you see I'm...?
You're Bruce Baldwin!
Who is he?
Who are you?
My name's Pete Davis.
Mr. Davis, is this
any concern of yours?
From now on, keep your nose
out of my affairs.
Don't let it happen again.
I'm terribly sorry about this mistake.
This is indeed a pleasure.
That's wrong, isn't it? Bruce...
Do you mind if I call you Bruce?
- We're almost related.
- No, not at all.
You see, my wife...
That is, your wife.
Hildy, you led me to expect you
were marrying a much older man.
What did I say?
Don't worry. I realize
you didn't mean old in years.
- You always carry an umbrella?
- It looked cloudy.
That's right.
Rubbers too, I hope.
Thattaboy!
A man ought to be prepared.
We'd better run along.
- We'd better go.
- Where?
To lunch.
Didn't you tell him?
No, she didn't.
I guess she just wanted
to surprise you, Bruce.
After you, Hildy.
You're wasting your time.
No, I'm glad to do it.
Hello, Gus.
It's Hildy!
- None other. How are things?
- Can't complain.
I can. I'm hungry.
A roast beef sandwich...
- Sorry.
...on white bread.
Over there, Bruce.
- And you, Hildy?
- I'll have the same.
- You, sir?
- That's all right for me.
Bring some mustard too, Gus.
So you two are gonna get married?
- How does it feel, Bruce?
- Awful good.
- You're getting a great girl.
- I realize that.
Things have been different
since I met Hildy.
I've never met anyone like her.
Everybody else I've known...
...you could tell ahead of time
what they'd say or do.
But Hildy's not like that.
You can't tell that about her.
That's nice.
You're getting a great
newspaperman too.
No orchids, Walter.
One of the best I ever knew.
Sorry to see her go.
- I'd like to believe you.
- I mean it.
- If you ever want to come back...
- Which I won't.
In spite of it all,
there's only one man I'd work for.
I'd kill you if you
worked for anybody else.
- Hear that? That's my diploma.
- It must be quite a business...
- Are you sure you wanna quit?
- What do you mean?
If there is any doubt
or if there's anything...
No, this is your chance to have
a home and to be a human being.
I'll make you take that chance.
Certainly.
Why, I wouldn't let her stay.
She deserves all this happiness.
All the things I couldn't give her.
- All she ever wanted was a home.
- I'll certainly try.
I know you will.
- Where will you live?
- Albany.
- Got a family up there?
- Just my mother.
Your mother.
You'll live with her?
Just for the first year.
That will be nice.
Yes, a home with Mother,
in Albany too.
Nice little town.
It's the state capital.
I know. We were there once.
Remember the night
you brought the governor to the hotel?
You see, I was in taking a bath.
Well, I came walking out without...
She didn't know I was in town.
Bruce, how is business up there?
Any better?
Albany's a good insurance town.
People take it out
pretty early in life.
- I can see why they would.
- Statistics show that most...
I've got a feeling I ought to
have taken out a little insurance.
That really doesn't matter
now that Hildy and I have...
...well, you know, we've...
Does it?
What do you think?
It might have been a good idea
if I had taken out insurance.
I feel that way.
I'm in one business
that really helps people.
Of course, we don't help you much
while you're alive, but afterward.
- That's what counts.
- Sure.
- I don't get it.
- Nice going.
Sorry, Gus.
My foot slipped.
That's all right.
What would you like to drink?
Coffee.
- Shall I put rum in the coffee?
- Sure.
Me too, Gus, please.
- Not for me.
- Go on, Bruce.
I have a lot to do. I have to
buy the tickets, check the baggage...
Do it tomorrow.
We're leaving today at 4:00,
taking the sleeper for Albany.
Oh, you're leaving today at 4:00?
- That's only two hours.
- That's not much time.
I've got a lot to do.
Isn't that silly?
All down over my front.
- That's nothing new. Here.
- I'll get Gus.
Do something
about this, will you?
Call me to the phone when
I sit down.
Thanks, Gus, that's fine.
I'm terribly sorry about that.
That was silly.
Let me get that straight.
I must have misunderstood you.
You're taking the sleeper today,
then marrying tomorrow?
- Well, it's not like that.
- What is it like?
Poor Walter.
He'll toss and turn all night.
Better tell him Mother's coming too.
- Your mother kicked the bucket...
- No, my mother.
Your mother?
That relieves my mind.
It was cruel to let you suffer so.
Isn't Walter sweet?
Always wanting to protect me.
I wasn't much of a husband,
but you can count on me.
I don't think she'll need you much.
I aim to do the protecting.
Mr. Burns, telephone.
For me?
That's strange.
Pardon me.
He's not such a bad guy.
No, he should make
some girl real happy.
Slaphappy.
He's not the man for you,
I can see that.
But I like him.
He's got charm.
He comes by it naturally.
His grandfather was a snake.
Hello? Duffy, listen.
Any way we can stop the 4:00 train
to Albany?
- We might dynamite it.
- Could we?
Maybe we couldn't.
All right, get this.
Send Sweeney out of town on
two weeks' vacation right away.
Keep your shirt on.
Hildy's coming back.
She doesn't know it,
but she's staying.
Tell Louie to stick around.
I may need him. Goodbye.
Thanks, Gus.
- This is bad business.
- What is it?
- The Earl Williams case.
- I read about that.
It's pretty bad.
- What's the lowdown?
- Simple.
Poor dope lost his job,
went berserk and shot a cop.
They'll hang him tomorrow.
- What a shame.
- Your paper has been taking his side.
If he was crazy, why doesn't
the state put him away?
It was a coloured policeman.
You know what that means.
- The coloured vote's important.
- Especially with an election coming.
That mayor would hang his
grandmother to be reelected.
You could show the man
wasn't responsible.
That's not so easy.
Maybe it isn't so hard either.
What do you mean?
Another expert has to examine him
before they hang him, right?
A bird named Egelhoffer's doing it.
He'll say the same thing.
- Suppose he does.
- What's your scheme?
You get the interview
with Earl Williams.
Print Egelhoffer's statement.
Alongside it, run your interview.
Alienist says he's sane.
Interview shows he's goofy.
You could save that poor devil's life.
You could...
- You're going away.
- How long would the interview take?
An hour for the interview.
An hour to write it.
We could take the 6:00 train
if it'd save a life.
No. If you want to save
Earl Williams' life, write it yourself.
I can't write this.
It takes a woman's touch.
Don't get poetic.
Get Sweeney.
He's the best man
for that sob-sister stuff.
Duffy just told me his wife finally
had twins. Isn't that terrible?
Sweeney went out, and we can't find him.
He has twins, and Williams gets hanged.
Now, Walter, look.
Argue with her, or you'll have
blood on your hands.
How can you be happy after that?
You'll remember that
a man went to the gallows...
...because she was too selfish
to wait two hours.
Earl Williams' face will come between
you tonight and the rest of your life.
Stop it, Walter.
The whole place will hear you.
What an act.
I just remembered Sweeney was only
married four months ago.
Hildy, you win. I'm licked.
Then Mrs. Sweeney didn't have twins?
No, indeed.
The twins were Walter's.
It was nothing.
Let's forget it.
We'll start over again.
- I'll offer a business proposition.
- Not interested.
You'll be interested.
Don't listen to him.
I know him from way back.
Excuse me, will you? I'm talking
to him. Now, look, Bruce...
...persuade her and you can
write an insurance policy for me.
I wouldn't use my wife
for business purposes.
Wait a minute, Bruce.
- How big a policy?
- 25,000. 50,000.
What's the commission on
a $100,000 policy?
- $1000, but...
- What's wrong with $1000?
We could use that money.
How long would it take
to get him examined?
I could get a doctor in 20 minutes.
- Get him.
- You keep out of this.
Suppose you have him examined
in his office...
...and see what they'll allow
on his carcass.
- I'm better than ever.
- That's nothing to brag about.
I'll go back and change, and after
you get the check, phone me.
I'll be in the press room
at criminal court.
Walter. I think you better
make that a certified check.
Think I'm a crook?
Yes. No certified check, no story.
It'll be certified.
Want my fingerprints?
- No. I've still got those.
- Gus, how much do I owe you?
Thank you, dear.
- Sorry.
- How much money do you have?
Everything we have, $500.
- Give it to me.
- But the tickets...
I'll buy the tickets.
He'll get you in a crap game.
I don't gamble.
I know people that never did anything
till they met Walter.
Remember, it's everything we have.
I know.
- You got change of ten?
- See what I mean?
I gave everything to Hildy.
I've got...
- Come on.
- Not me. Sign it.
All right.
For the waiter.
Come on, Bruce. Really.
- I'll open for a dime.
- I'm in.
- I'll stay.
- Wilcox 3400.
- How many?
- Two.
Take that, one of you birds.
You ain't doing anything, Ernie.
What's the matter with you guys?
Crippled?
I'll bet 20 cents.
Press room. Wait a minute.
Hello, sarge, McCue talking.
Hold the line, will you? What?
This is the press room
of the criminal courts building.
New lead on the hanging. This alienist
from New York, Dr. Max J. Egelhoffer.
He's interviewing Williams
in the sheriff's office.
Must be the 10th alienist they've had.
If he wasn't crazy, he would be...
...after ten of those babies
psychoanalysed him.
- Is Egelhoffer any good?
- You figure it out.
They sent him to Washington
to interview the Brain Trust.
He said they were sane.
Here's the situation
before the hanging.
I'll pick up a little fudge.
This is Murphy.
More on the hanging.
A double guard is around the jail,
municipal buildings, and terminals...
...to prepare for the expected uprising
of radicals at the hour of execution.
The sheriff's assigned 200 relatives
to guard against the Red Army...
...which is leaving Moscow
in a couple minutes.
When the real Red Menace
shows up...
...the sheriff will still be
crying wolf. What do you got?
- Is that good?
- Looks good from here.
Hildy, when did you get back?
- How are you, Eddie?
- Glad to see you.
Where'd you get the hat?
- I paid 12 bucks for it.
- Coming back to work?
It's a farewell appearance.
I'm going into business for myself.
- What doing?
- I'm getting married tomorrow.
Again? Are we invited to the wedding?
I might use you for a bridesmaid, Roy.
- How are you, Murphy?
- What are you getting married for?
- None of your business.
- You ain't fooling?
Fooling? Look what I've got in here.
Three tickets to Albany
on the 6:00 train tonight.
Three?
For me and my beau and,
hats off, boys, his sweet darling ma.
- That's nice.
- What kind of marriage is that?
I'm settling down. I'm through
with the newspaper business.
Can you picture Hildy singing
lullabies and hanging out didies?
- Swapping lies over the fence?
- Sour grapes.
- She'll get tired of beating rugs.
- I'm not going to beat any rugs.
That's Third and Jefferson.
Where the Central School is.
- No school this time of day.
- Why? You quit.
- You said you were through.
- I thought it might be a good fire.
- What's that?
- Practising for the Williams party.
- You'll miss a nice hanging.
- Not interested.
Tell them to pipe down.
Keep quiet down there! How do you
expect us to get any work done?
Shut up!
Little respect
for the press around here.
- Say, did anybody phone me?
- Not that I know of.
Say, does Walter know
you're getting married?
- Just had lunch with him.
- He knows you're quitting?
- I told him. Any more questions?
- Shall I deal you in?
I haven't got time.
I have to do a yarn on Williams.
Did he know what he was doing?
If you ask us, no. If you ask the
alienist, the answer's yes.
- What's he do?
- He was a bookkeeper.
He starts at $20 a week.
After 14 years...
...he works himself up to $17.50.
- Got more gum?
McClosky Company goes out of
business. Williams loses his job.
Can't get another.
I'm in.
So he hangs around the park listening
to soapbox spellbinders...
...making speeches and believes them.
- Makes some of his own.
- Up a dime.
- I'm in.
- Anything else, doc?
- No, that'll be all.
Everything okay?
Nothing to worry about.
Good, good.
- How are you doing, Bruce?
- Just one more thing.
- Good day, Mr. Baldwin.
- Goodbye, doc. Thanks very much.
Who's the beneficiary?
- Excuse me?
- That is, in case of your death.
- Who do we pay the money to?
- Why, Hildy, of course.
I don't know. That'd make me
feel pretty funny.
Now, why shouldn't I make
Hildy my whatever-it-was?
I should take care of her.
But you will take care of her, Bruce.
If that doctor's right,
I'm good for a long time yet.
Look, Bruce, this is
a debt of honour with me.
I was a bad husband to Hildy.
She could have claimed a lot of
alimony. But she wouldn't take any.
She was too independent.
- I'm independent too, you know.
- I know you are.
But look, you just figure it this way.
I'm good for, we'll say,
at least 25 years yet.
By then, you'll have made enough so
that money won't mean anything to you.
But suppose you haven't made good.
What about Hildy's old age?
Think of Hildy.
I can see her now.
White-haired, lavender and old lace.
- Can't you see her, Bruce?
- Yes, yes, I can.
She's old, isn't she?
Don't you think that Hildy's entitled
to spend her remaining years...
...without worries of money?
Of course you do, Bruce.
Of course, if you put it that way.
And remember, I love her too.
Yes, I'm beginning to realize that.
And the beauty of it is...
...she'll never have to know
until I've passed on.
Maybe she'll think kindly of me...
...after I'm gone.
You make me feel like a heel,
coming between you.
No, no, Bruce.
You didn't come between us.
It was over for her before
you came. For me...
...it'll never be. What do you want?
- Can I see you a minute, please?
Excuse me, Bruce.
Did you get it, you get it?
Where is it? Come on.
- Certified?
- Sure. But, Walter, that's for $2500.
- Here we are, certified and everything.
- Certified.
I'm afraid Hildy'll feel ashamed
to think she hasn't trusted you.
She'll know some day.
You promised to phone her
as soon as you got the check.
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
Get me Hildy Johnson, press room,
criminal courts building.
Sit down, Bruce.
The operator will get her for you.
Excuse me, will you?
Yes, I'll wait, thank you.
Start hollering. Hildegarde.
Thank you.
Hildy Johnson speaking.
Take it easy, will you?
Did you get the check?
Is it certified?
Certified and everything.
I have it right in my pocket.
In your pocket. That's fine.
Wait. Maybe it isn't so fine.
Where are you?
Mr. Burns' office.
Is he there?
Look, Bruce. I don't want you to
carry that check in your pocket.
Well, because...
Yes, yes, I know all that.
But...
There's an old
newspaper superstition...
...your first big check you
put in the lining of your hat.
- In your hat. It brings good luck.
- I never heard that before.
Neither did I. I know it
sounds silly, dear, but do it for me.
Yes, yes, right now.
All right. Just a minute.
There, I've done it.
Anything else?
Oh, yes.
All right.
Yes, I'll tell him. Goodbye.
- Everything all right?
- Hildy said she'll get to work.
- Fine.
- I must be going now.
You don't want to forget this.
It might rain, you know.
You mind if I don't show you out?
I'm so busy in here.
Thanks for everything.
- Excuse me?
- Thanks for everything.
Nonsense. Don't thank me.
I should thank you.
- So long.
Hello, Cooley.
What are you doing here?
I want an interview with Williams.
- No interviews.
- Why?
Sheriff's orders. Besides, a doctor's
coming over. Can't do it.
Say, is this your money?
- No.
- 20 bucks?
- Yeah.
- That's what I thought.
Come on, I'm in a hurry.
Open up here.
- Now, Hildy, don't be...
- I won't be long.
- Hello, Earl.
- Hello.
I'm Johnson.
Mind if I talk to you for a bit?
No, I haven't anything else to do.
I guess that's right.
So I couldn't plead insanity.
I'm just as sane as anybody else.
- You didn't mean to kill the policeman.
- It's against everything I stand for.
They know it was an accident.
I'm not guilty.
It's just the world.
I see what you mean.
Sorry about the lipstick, Earl.
Now, look, after you lost your job...
...what did you do?
I tried to find another job.
How did you spend your time?
I used to sit around in the park,
anyplace. I don't smoke.
When you were in the park,
did you hear any speeches?
You mean those fellows
that talk too much?
I didn't pay any attention...
- Did you hear anything they said?
- Yes.
Is there anything in particular
you remember?
- There was one.
- What did he talk about?
He talked about production for use.
Production for use?
Yes, he said everything
should be made use of.
Makes sense, doesn't it?
Yes, I liked him.
He was a good speaker.
When you found yourself
with that gun...
...and that policeman coming at you,
what did you think?
I don't know exactly.
Could it have been
"production for use"?
- I don't know. I...
- What's a gun for, Earl?
A gun?
Why, to shoot, of course.
Maybe that's why you used it.
- Maybe.
- It seems reasonable.
Yes, yes, it is.
I've never had a gun in my hand before.
And that's what a gun's for, isn't it?
- Maybe that's why...
- Sure, it is.
That's what I thought of. " Production
for use." It's simple, isn't it?
- Very simple.
- There's nothing crazy about that.
- Nothing at all.
- Write about that in your paper.
You bet I will.
Who sent you the roses?
Miss Mollie Malloy.
She's wonderful...
Is that her picture?
- Yes. She's beautiful, isn't she?
- Time's up, Hildy.
All right.
Guess that's all.
I liked talking to you.
Goodbye, Miss Johnson.
Goodbye, Earl.
Good luck.
- Three landladies, boys.
- Did well, didn't you?
What will the Post do without Hildy?
You suppose Burns
will ever let her go?
Remember when Fenton
wanted to go to Hollywood?
- Had him thrown in jail for arson.
- Forgery.
- Was that it?
- Yeah, give me some change.
Hey, Mac.
Hey, Stairway Sam.
Would you mind turning on some lights?
It's so dark, you can't see.
- Who's this guy Hildy's marrying?
- I don't know. Bruce something.
- I give the marriage six months.
- Why?
She can't stay away from the paper.
Did you see her
when that bell went off?
It must be pretty nice to be able
to walk out of a place and quit.
I had a publicity job offer last year.
I should have taken it.
I'd like that,
a job on the side.
A desk and a stenographer.
I wouldn't mind a nice, big blond.
With big brown eyes.
I'll bet you ten to one it don't last
six months.
She's like us, or we wouldn't be
waiting for that guy to dance.
- Miss Mollie Malloy.
- Hello, Mollie. How's tricks?
- I've been looking for you tramps.
- Come to pay a call on Williams?
Nice roses you sent Earl. What do you
want done with them tomorrow?
A lot of wise guys.
You're interrupting.
What do you want?
I came to...
I came to tell you
what I think of you.
Keep your shirt on.
If you was worth breaking my nails,
I'd tear you open.
What are you sore about?
That was a swell story we gave you.
You've been making
a fool out of me long enough.
I never said I loved Earl and wanted
to marry him on the gallows.
You made that up.
And my being his soul mate and
having a love nest with him.
You've been around him
since he got in the death house.
- That's a lie.
- Everybody knows you're his girlfriend.
I met Mr. Williams
just once in my life.
When he was in the rain
without his coat on...
...like a sick dog,
before the shooting.
- Give me one.
- I went up like any human would...
...and asked him what was wrong.
He told me about being fired after
being on the job for 14 years.
- Who bets?
- Bet 20 cents.
I brought him to my room
because it was warm.
Put it on a phonograph.
Listen to me, please.
I tell you he just sat there
talking to me all night.
He never once laid a hand on me.
And in the morning he went away...
...and I never saw him again
till the trial.
- Sure, I was his witness.
- What a witness.
That's why you persecute me.
Because Earl treated me decent,
and not like an animal.
- We're busy.
- Go see your boyfriend.
- He's got a nice room.
- Not for long.
He left a call for 7 a.m.
It's a wonder lightning don't
come down and strike you all dead.
What's that?
They're fixing up a pain in the neck
for your boyfriend.
Shame on you.
Shame on you!
A poor little fellow that never
meant nobody no harm.
Sitting with the Angel of Death,
and you cracking jokes.
- You're gonna get out of here.
- Take your hands off me!
- Let's get out of here.
- They ain't human.
- They're newspapermen.
- All they've done is lie.
All they're doing is writing lies.
Why won't they listen to me?
Who? Hildy Johnson?
Hang on. She'll be back in a minute.
You guys want to play any more cards?
What's the use? I can't win anyway.
Gentlemen of the press.
Hildy.
Phone for you.
What?
Where are you?
You're where?
Well, how did that happen?
Never mind, never mind.
I'll be right down.
I'm sorry, Pete. Sorry.
Hi, sheriff. How you doing?
My shin and my back.
What's going on around here?
- Bruce was in trouble.
- Lioness rushes to defend cub.
Man forgets hankie.
Mama goes to wipe nose.
I still give the marriage
six months.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
What do you want, Pete?
Oh, I got the tickets for
the hanging here, boys.
- Pete?
- What?
Why can't you hang this guy
at 5:00 instead of 7?
It won't hurt you, and
we can make the city edition.
That's kind of raw, Roy, hanging a man
in his sleep to please a newspaper.
But you can reprieve him so he
hangs three days before election.
You can run on a
law-and-order ticket.
I had nothing
to do with those reprieves.
How do we know there won't
be another?
What if Egelhoffer
finds him insane?
He won't find him insane, because
he isn't. He's just as sane as I am.
Saner!
Be serious, boys.
After all, this is a hanging.
It's gonna go
according to schedule.
Seven o'clock in the morning
and not earlier.
There's such a thing as being humane.
Okay, Pinky.
Wait till you want a favour.
- And please don't call me Pinky.
- Why?
Because I got a name, see,
and it's Peter B. Hartwell.
- What's the B for?
- Bull.
I'm innocent. I didn't do it.
I never stole a watch in my life!
I know you didn't.
Mike, let him out.
I can't. He's accused of stealing
a watch they found on him.
- But I never stole...
- Please.
Diamond Louie, a crook, accused him.
- I know. It's no good.
- You gonna let him out or not?
- I never stole...
- Please.
All right, you're not.
Read the Post tomorrow.
I can't imagine who'd do that to me.
- I can't think of an enemy.
- I'm sure you haven't any...
- Have you got the check?
- Yes, I have it right here.
That's a funny superstition
you newspaper people have.
Yes, isn't it?
About being arrested, I thought...
...Walter Burns might have
something to do with it.
But then I realized he couldn't have.
- Why?
- He's a very nice fellow.
Oh, yes, I found that out.
- What's the matter?
- I've lost my wallet.
Yes? Well, Bruce, never mind.
I have the money.
- Better give me the check.
- And that picture of us in Bermuda.
Don't bother, Bruce.
You'll find lots of things missing.
Wait here.
I'm not taking any more chances.
I'll be down in three minutes.
We'll take the next train. Sorry.
"And so into this
little tortured mind...
...came the idea that that gun
had been produced for use.
And use it he did.
But the state has a production-
for-use plan too. It has a gallows.
And at 7 a.m., unless a miracle occurs,
that gallows will be used...
...to separate the soul
of Earl Williams from his body.
And out of Mollie Malloy's life...
...will go the one kindly
soul she ever knew."
That's as far as she got.
- Can that girl write an interview?
- She'll do till somebody comes along.
It's not ethical,
reading other people's stuff.
Where do you get that ethics stuff?
You're the only one who'll swipe it.
I say anybody that can write like that
won't give it up to sew socks...
...for a guy in insurance.
Now I give that marriage 3 months,
and I'm laying 3-to-1.
- Any takers?
- I'll take that bet.
A girl can't leave the room without
being discussed by old ladies.
Hello, Post? Get me Walter Burns,
will you, please?
Don't get sore. We were only saying a
reporter like you wouldn't quit easy.
This is Hildy Johnson. I can quit
all right, without a single quiver.
I'll live like a human,
not like you chumps.
Is that you?
I've got some news for you.
I got the interview, but I've got
some more important news.
Better get a pencil
and take it down.
All ready?
Get this, you double-crossing
chimpanzee.
There won't be an interview
or a story.
Your check leaves with me
in 20 minutes.
I wouldn't cover
the burning of Rome for you.
If I ever lay my eyes
on you again...
...I'll hammer your skull
so it rings like a Chinese gong!
You don't know why I'm angry?
Have Louie tell you about his watch.
And there's just one other
little thing.
Hear that?
That's the story I just wrote.
I know we had a bargain.
I just said I'd write it.
I didn't say I wouldn't tear it up.
It's all in pieces now.
I hope to do the same
for you someday.
That's my farewell
to the newspaper game.
I'll be a woman,
not a news machine.
I'll have babies, give them cod-liver
oil and watch their teeth grow.
If I see one of them
look at a paper, I'll brain him.
Where's my hat?
- Mr. Burns? Yes, she's still here.
- Give me that.
And another thing I want...
Where is my...?
There it is.
- Doctor. Sorry to be late.
- Quite all right.
These boys from the papers
take up my time.
They want me to hang Williams
at their convenience.
- Oh, hello, Earl.
- These newspapers.
What they did to me in Chicago!
- Always want interviews.
- Me too.
I did promise to make
some statement...
...when I finished.
You don't mind?
It's hardly ethical.
All statements come from me.
I see. What do you say to giving
them some sort of joint interview?
I'll discuss the psychological
aspects and you...
We'd have a picture together?
- Shaking hands.
- Splendid idea!
- I don't take a good picture.
- That doesn't matter. Publicity does.
Doctor, I'm getting awful tired.
Can't I go back to jail again?
Sorry. I forgot you were there.
We've some further questions for you.
Sheriff, would you extinguish
the lights?
That will help with what we're
doing here. Now, let me see.
Mr. Williams, you know
that you're going to be executed.
Who do you feel
is responsible for that?
I am innocent. It wasn't my fault.
- Well, Murph.
- Send us a post card.
- Bye.
- Au revoir, Hildegarde.
- When will we see you?
- Next time you see me...
...I'll be in a Rolls-Royce,
giving interviews on success.
So long, you wage slaves.
When you're climbing fire escapes,
getting kicked out front doors...
...and eating in one-armed joints,
don't forget your pal, Hildy Johnson.
And when the road beyond unfolds,
and the...
Look out! It's a jailbreak!
What's the matter? What happened?
Watch where you're aiming,
will you?
- Watch the gate! He'll try the gate!
- Who was it?
- Earl Williams!
- Who did he say?
Earl Williams!
Hello! Hurry up, this is important.
- Earl Williams just escaped.
- Jailbreak!
- Williams went over the wall!
- I don't know anything yet.
Hello, Post? Give me Walter Burns,
quick. Hildy Johnson.
Walter? Walter? Hildy.
Earl Williams just escaped
from the county jail.
Don't worry, I'm on the job.
Hey, Cooley!
Wait!
Hey, wait a minute!
Cooley, I want to talk to you!
This is Endicott. Give me rewrite.
He ain't here.
Hello, Gil?
Here's the situation now.
Ready? Williams was taken to
the sheriff's...
...to be examined by Egelhoffer.
In a few minutes, he shot his way out.
Nobody knows where he got the gun.
He got out through the skylight.
He must have slid down the rainpipe.
No, nobody knows where he got it.
Give me the desk.
The crime commission offers
a $10,000 reward.
No clue yet as to
Williams' whereabouts.
Here's a feature.
An accident about a tear bomb.
Yeah, tear bomb.
Criminals cry for it.
I don't know.
The tear bomb went off
in the hands of the bombing squad.
These deputies
went to the hospital.
- A fine friend you are.
- Wilkerson, the mayor's brother-in-law.
- After all I've done for you.
- Howard Schuster, the sheriff's uncle.
Highlights on Sheriff
Hartwell's manhunt.
William Mansfield, his landlord,
and Lester Winthrop...
...who married the sheriff's niece.
The very homely dame. Call you back.
Mrs. William Rice, scrub lady,
while scrubbing the eighth floor...
...was shot by a deputy.
- Look, I'm not...
- There goes another scrub lady!
It was a flesh wound.
She's in the hospital.
- McCue speaking. Get the desk.
- Any dope on how he escaped?
The sheriff let him out
so he could vote for him.
A man looking like
Earl Williams boarded a southbound...
Call you back.
- I thought you'd gone.
- I thought so too.
Get me Walter Burns, quick!
Walter, listen.
I've got the story on Williams'
escape, and it's exclusive.
That's right, and it's a pip.
It cost me $450
to tear it out of Cooley.
What's the story?
I'll give it to you. First I have
to tell you I gave him money.
And it wasn't mine.
It's Bruce's money,
and I want it back.
Bruce's money?
Sure, you'll get it.
Now, what's the story?
I'll send the money.
I swear it on my mother's grave.
Here's the...
Wait a minute, your mother's alive!
My grandmother's grave.
What's the story?
You get that money down here.
All right, here's your story.
The jailbreak of your dreams.
Dr. Egelhoffer,
the thinker from New York...
...was giving Williams a sanity
test in the sheriff's office.
Sticking a lot of pins in him
so he could get his reflexes.
He decided to reenact the crime
as it had taken place...
...in order to study
Williams' coordination.
I'm coming to it. He had to have a gun
to reenact the crime.
Who do you suppose supplied it?
Peter B. Hartwell. B for brains.
No kidding!
I'm not good enough
to make this one up.
The sheriff gave his gun
to the professor...
...who gave it to Earl, who shot
the professor in the classified ads.
No, ads.
Ain't it perfect?
If he'd unrolled a red carpet
it couldn't have been more ideal.
Who? Oh, no.
Egelhoffer wasn't badly hurt.
He's in the hospital,
where they're afraid he'll recover.
That's great work, Hildy.
Don't worry about the money.
You'll get it in 15 minutes.
I'd better. Bruce is waiting
in a taxi for me, and we're in a hurry.
Hold on a minute.
Vangie, come here.
There's a guy in a taxi in front of
criminal courts. Bruce Baldwin.
- What does he look like?
- That guy in the movies, Ralph Bellamy.
- Oh, him?
- Can you handle it?
I've never flopped
on you yet, have I?
Get going. You only got
about two minutes. Hurry.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
How much was it again?
$450. Well, just a second.
Louie, come here. I need $450
worth of counterfeit money.
- Can't carry that much, boss.
- No, just the $450 counterfeit.
I got that on me.
Quite a coincidence.
Take it to Hildy.
It's coming.
I'm sending it with Louie.
Thanks for your story.
Good luck on your honeymoon.
No, no, never mind the thanks.
Just see that money gets here.
- Hildy, you still here?
- No, I'm in Niagara Falls.
McCue speaking.
Emil, I got a good feature
on the manhunt.
Ready? Mrs. Phoebe DeWolfe, coloured,
gave birth to a pickaninny...
...in a patrol wagon, with Hartwell's
rifle squad acting as nurses.
Phoebe was walking along
the street when... That's right.
So they coaxed her
into the patrol wagon.
When the pickaninny was born,
they checked...
...to see if it was Williams.
They know he's hiding somewhere.
Here's the payoff. They named the kid
Peter Hartwell DeWolfe.
Press room.
Bruce? I thought you were
downstairs in a...
What?
Arrested again? What for this time?
Well, they called it "mashing."
No, I didn't, Hildy!
I was sitting in the taxi
where you left me...
...and the young lady seemed
to have a dizzy spell and I just...
She's kind of...
Yes, she's a blond.
Yes, very blond.
I know how it happened.
Just a minute.
Get me Walter Burns. Hildy Johnson.
Bruce, where are you? 27th Precinct?
Hold on a minute.
Walter, you...
He was there a minute ago.
But I want...
"I'm sorry, I can't locate him."
Why, that double-crossing...
Hello, not you.
Bruce, I can't get there right away.
How about 20 minutes?
I have to wait here for the...
I'll tell you when I see you.
If I ever get my hands
on Walter...
- Anything I can do?
- How much money you got?
- $1.80.
- 64 cents.
- Welcome to it.
- Thanks, you better buy an annuity.
What's that, Emil? No, I can't
give you an official statement.
Wait a minute. Here's the mayor.
How about a statement, mayor?
- Don't pester me now, please.
- His Honour won't say anything.
- You seen Hartwell?
- Hard to tell.
There's so many
cockroaches around...
Wait. How about a statement?
- We go to press in 20 minutes.
- I've nothing to say. Not now.
What do you know
about the escape?
- Where'd he get the gun?
- Not so fast.
- About the election...
- What effect will this have on voters?
None whatsoever.
How can an unavoidable
misfortune like this...
...have any influence on the upright
citizens of our fair city?
Mr. Mayor, please, is there
a Red Menace or ain't there?
How did Williams get out?
Have you picked out somebody
to be responsible?
Is it true that you're
on Stalin's payroll?
The senator claims you
sleep in red underwear.
Forget the jokes.
Don't forget I'm the mayor and...
Hartwell, I want to see you!
- How'd he get away?
- Where'd he get the gun?
Any statement on the
Red Uprising tomorrow?
- Red Uprising?
- There will be no Red Uprising.
The governor says the situation
calls for the militia.
I say anything the governor says
is a tissue of lies.
Here's a red-hot
statement from the governor.
He claims the mayor and
sheriff have shown themselves...
...to be a couple of 8-year-olds
playing with fire.
You can quote him as follows:
"It's lucky that next Tuesday
is Election Day...
...as the citizens will be saved
the expense of impeaching...
...the mayor and the sheriff."
Call you back.
Nice to have seen you, mayor.
- I've got so much to do.
- Wait. Who engineered this getaway?
- Was it the Reds?
- Was it you?
Me? Just a minute.
I've got him located.
- Williams?
- Where?
Out on Center Street. I got a tip.
- Why didn't you say so?
- The rifle squad's going.
You'll catch him if you hurry.
- Please...
- I wanna talk to you.
I've got a lot to do.
- See here, Fred...
- Pete, you're through.
You mean I'm through?
I'm scratching your name off the ticket
and running Sherman in your place.
"Reform the Red with a rope"!
Williams isn't a Red!
There's communistic
sympathizers around, and I thought...
...if I got a slogan
like that I could...
That's got nothing
to do with this case.
There are 200,000 votes at stake.
If he don't hang, we'll lose them.
We're going to hang him.
He can't get away.
What do you mean?
He did get away, didn't he?
What do you want?
- What is it?
- Are you Sheriff Hartwell?
I'm him. What is it?
You're a hard man to find.
I have a message from the governor.
- What?
- It was a reprieve for Earl Williams.
- For who?
- Earl Williams.
You said there wasn't
gonna be a reprieve.
It frightens me to think of what
I'd like to do to you. Who was there?
- Nobody. He was fishing.
- Get the governor.
He's not there.
He's duck shooting.
Blasted nimrod!
Fishing, duck shooting...
A guy who's done nothing
for 40 years...
...gets elected governor,
and thinks he's Tarzan.
Read that. "Insane." He knows
very well Williams isn't insane.
I never met the man.
- Pure politics.
- It's an attempt to ruin us.
- What do we tell the reporters?
- That the party's over because of you.
As an afterthought, tell them
I want your resignation.
Hello. Yes, yes, this is Hartwell.
What? Where?
Holy Moses! Hold the wire!
They've got Williams!
The rifle squad has him
at his house.
- Tell them to hold the phone.
- Hold the wire.
Cover up that transmitter.
Now, listen.
You never arrived.
Yes, I did. I came through there...
- How much do you make?
- I thought he was sheriff...
- What's your salary?
- $40 a week.
How'd you like to make $350 a month?
It's almost $100 a week.
I couldn't afford that. Who? Me?
They need a fellow like you
in the city sealer's office.
- Huh?
- City sealer's.
I should work in the sealer's...
My wife wouldn't like that. She lives
in the country with my family.
That's all right. Bring her in.
We'll pay all the expenses.
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
I got two kids in school. If they
change towns, they'll lose a grade.
No. They'll skip a grade.
I guarantee
they'll graduate with honours.
Hold your horses, Olsen.
Hurry up.
Now, what do you say?
That puts me in a peculiar hole.
No, it doesn't.
You never delivered this.
You got caught in traffic
or something.
- I came...
- Pretend you didn't.
Now get out and don't let
anybody see you.
- How do I know...?
- Come to my office tomorrow.
- What's your name?
- Pettibone.
- Pettibone?
- Not really.
Lay low and keep your mouth shut.
- I'm tired anyhow.
- Go to this address.
Nice homey place.
They'll take care of you.
Say Fred sent you.
- Here's $50 on account.
- I'll tell you in one minute.
You forgot to tell me
what a city sealer does.
- Is it hard?
- Easy. Very easy.
Good, my health isn't...
My wife...
- We'll fix that too.
- My wife?
- Yes, fix anything. Go ahead.
- They're still on the phone.
- Tell them to shoot to kill.
- But the reprieve!
- Go ahead and do as I tell you.
- Olsen.
Shoot to kill. That's the order.
Pass the word.
- $500 reward.
- $500 for the man who does it.
I'll be right over.
Hi, Hildy.
You double-crossing hyena.
What'd you pull on
Mr. Baldwin this time?
- Who, me?
- You and your albino.
- Evangeline's no albino.
- She'll do till one comes along.
She was born in this country.
If she tries anything else,
she'll have to stay in this country.
- Did you bring that money?
- Oh, yeah, $400.
$450.
All right, you can't blame
a guy for trying.
- Give me a receipt.
- I'll give you a scar.
I got plenty of them.
I'll take Mr. Baldwin's wallet too.
- Mr. Baldwin's what?
- His purse. Come on, Louie.
All right, Hildy. I'll do it for you
because I like you.
But tell your financier to be
more careful, know what I mean?
I'll loan him a pair of
your brass knuckles.
Don't talk that way.
I'll take that.
- I'll take it to the station.
- Wait a minute!
Take it to the 27th Precinct
and tell the cops what happened.
I couldn't do that.
Burns would turn me in.
- Not a bad idea.
- Here, catch!
Louie!
Hello, operator. Hildy Johnson.
Will you get me...
Drop that phone!
Never mind.
You're not gonna
tell anybody where I am.
Put that gun down, Earl.
You don't wanna shoot me.
I'm your friend, remember?
I'm writing the story on you
of production for use.
- That's right. Production for use.
- You don't want to hurt me...
Don't move!
Maybe you're my friend, maybe not.
But don't come any nearer.
You can't trust anybody
in this crazy world.
I don't blame you.
I wouldn't trust anybody either.
Don't do that.
Put it back. Put it back.
If you try any tricks, I'll shoot you.
I can do it right from here.
Sure you could, Earl.
But you don't want to do that.
You don't want to kill anybody.
No, you're right.
I don't want to kill anybody.
- That's what I thought.
- Wait a minute. Where are you going?
To close the door
so nobody'd see you.
No, you were going
to get somebody.
I don't want that.
All I want is to be left alone.
I won't get anybody.
You'll get them after me again.
I won't let you do that. I won't...
- Give me that.
- I guess I fired all the shells.
- I'm awful tired.
- That shot. They'll know you're here.
I don't care.
I'm not afraid to die. I told the
guy that when he handed me the gun.
- Quiet!
- Waking me up at night.
Talking about things
they don't understand.
Shut up.
I wish they'd take me back
and hang me.
They will if you don't keep quiet.
I can't survive
another day like this.
You think I could?
Get me Walter Burns, quick.
Tell him I need him.
Bruce, I know I said I'd be down,
but something has happened.
Walter, come right away.
Wait, Bruce, I'll explain.
I've got Williams here,
in the press room.
On the level.
I need you!
Bruce, I've captured Earl Williams.
You know, the murderer.
Stay there, Earl. Wait.
Bruce, I'll be down.
As soon as I hand him
to the paper.
Bruce, I can't.
Don't you realize...?
- Who is it?
- Me, Mollie Malloy. Open the door!
- What do you want, Mollie?
- I got to find...
- Where is everybody?
- They've gone.
Please tell me where.
I don't know.
I'm awfully busy.
They got him surrounded.
They'll shoot him like a dog.
They're looking for you too.
I don't care. Tell me.
I ain't afraid of them.
All right, they're down at
Center Street and Fourth.
- That's where he used to...
- Mollie, don't go.
Come in, Mollie. Draw up a chair.
- Hello.
- How did you get in here?
Down the pipe. I didn't mean to
shoot him. Really, I didn't.
- Be quiet.
- You believe me, don't you?
Sure I believe you.
Thanks for the roses.
They were beautiful.
That's all right, Mr. Williams.
- Don't cry.
- Don't you get hysterical.
I gotta get him out of here.
- You wouldn't get down that hall.
- They'll find him.
I'm trying to think before
those reporters come back.
Let them take me.
What's the difference?
I'll never let them.
Who locked the door?
- Now it's too late.
- Get in this desk.
- Oh, what's the use?
- Come on, get in.
We'll get you out in ten minutes.
Pull yourself together.
All right, here. Sit down.
All right, all right,
I'm coming!
- Don't kick the building down.
- We got phone calls to make.
What's she doing up here?
What's the matter?
Came up here and had hysterics.
- How do you feel, kid?
- Not so good.
Get you some water?
- Do anything for you?
- You don't look so sick.
- Did you bump into Williams?
- Funny!
- Where is he?
- Let me alone.
- Okay. Give me the desk.
- No harm in asking.
Hello, Jim. Yes, false alarm.
They surrounded the house, all right...
...but Williams wasn't there.
The Halloween outside has
the police on its ear.
- I thought you left.
- I'm waiting for Walter's money.
What a chase! Give me Emil.
- Give me the desk.
- Any news, boys?
Yeah, I never been
so tired in my life.
Where?
Melrose Station?
All right, connect me.
Hello, Mollie. How are you?
Hold it a minute.
This looks good.
An old lady claims Williams
is hiding under her piazza.
Tell her to stand up.
- You want to go out on it?
- I'll cover this end.
- I spent $1.40 on taxicabs already.
- No more going out.
- Never mind.
- Who pulled the shades down?
They were throwing lights around.
I've got a hunch Williams...
...ain't where they've been
looking for him.
He might be in this building.
Sure, hanging around
like a duck in a shooting gallery.
From the skylight, but
how did he get down?
- I'm pretending there ain't any Earl.
- He could have jumped to this roof.
Then he could slide
down the drainpipe.
- And come in any of these windows.
- If the story walks in the window...
Masterminds. Why don't you go home?
Maybe Williams will call on you.
It'd be funny if he was
in the building.
Why not search the building?
- I'm not wandering all over.
- Great bunch of reporters you are.
Too lazy to get
the biggest story in years.
You seem pretty anxious
to get rid of us.
- Are you trying to scoop us?
- On my own time?
Maybe Mollie's been giving her
the story on how Williams got the gun.
I didn't do nothing.
- Come clean.
- Let the girl alone. She's...
Well?
Mrs. Baldwin. Mother.
Don't "Mother" me. Playing cat and
mouse and keeping my boy locked up.
Making us miss two trains,
and the wedding tomorrow.
- I'll be with you in five minutes...
- Just give me Bruce's money.
You can stay here forever,
you and that murderer you caught.
- Murderer?
- Which one of these men is it?
- They all look like murderers.
- What murderer?
I never said any such thing.
I'm quoting my son.
He has never lied to me.
Somebody's lying.
- I never said anything like that.
- You did.
I said I was trying
to find the murderer.
- Quit stalling.
- She got it balled up.
Who are you holding out on?
Nobody. Now let me go, will you?
Stop it, stop it!
She don't know where he is.
I'm the only one that knows.
- Where?
- Try and find out.
- Come on, talk.
- Now you want me to talk?
- Talk.
- Ain't that funny?
You wouldn't listen to me before,
and now you want me to talk.
Don't say anything.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Stay out.
- Why didn't you listen to me?
- Cut that out.
- Hands off!
- Where is he?
Why do you wanna know? So you can
write more lies to sell papers?
- Never mind that.
- All right. I'll give you a story.
A wonderful story!
Only this time it'll be true.
You'll never find him now!
Get the ambulance, somebody!
Get an ambulance, somebody!
- She's dead.
- No, she isn't killed, she's moving!
- Did you see that? She jumped.
- I know that.
Where have you got Williams?
Hidden. He's in the desk.
She didn't kill herself.
- How're you doing?
- Let me out.
Quiet. You're sitting pretty.
- What's in there?
- Who are you?
- Bruce's mother.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up!
- You're doing something wrong.
- Mother, please.
- Take her out of here.
- Take the lady to Polack Mike's.
- My name's Louie Peluso.
See that she doesn't talk to anyone.
Tell them it's a case of D.T.'s.
Don't worry, Mother.
It's temporary.
Let go of me.
- Where are you going?
- To get Bruce out of jail.
- Why did you do this to me?
- Get Bruce out of jail?
How can you worry about a man
resting in a police station?
- This is war! You can't desert me.
- Get off that trapeze.
You've got your story.
"Earl Williams captured
by the Morning Post."
I covered your story for you,
now I'm out.
You drooling idiot, there are 365 days
in a year one can get married.
How many times you got a murderer
locked up in a desk?
You got the city
by the seat of the pants.
You've got the brain of a pancake.
This isn't just a story.
It's a revolution.
The greatest yarn since
Livingston discovered Stanley.
- The other way around.
- Don't get technical at such a time.
You've taken a city that's been
graft-ridden for 40 years...
...and given us a chance to have
the kind of government...
...New York has under La Guardia.
If I didn't have your best interest
at heart, I wouldn't argue with you.
You've done something big.
You've stepped up into a new class.
We'll make such monkeys of those
ward heelers, nobody'll vote for them.
- Expose them?
- We'll crucify that mob.
We'll keep Williams undercover
until we break the story...
...then share the glory
with the governor.
- I get it, I get it.
- You'll kick over City Hall.
You got the mayor and Hartwell
backed up against the wall.
This isn't just a newspaper story.
It's a career!
And you bellyache about catching
the 8 or 9:00 train.
- But I never figured it that way.
- Because you're a doll-faced hick.
They'll be naming streets after you.
There'll be statues of you.
The movies will be after you.
There'll be a Hildy cigar.
I can see the billboards:
"Light up with Hildy Johnson"...
- We got a lot to do.
- Now you're talking.
- We can't leave Williams here.
- We'll take him to my private office.
- How are you gonna take him?
- We'll carry the desk over.
It's crawling with cops outside.
We'll lower it out the window with
pulleys. Start pounding out a lead!
- How much of this stuff do you want?
- All the words you got.
- Can I call the mayor a bird of prey?
- Anything you like.
Give him the works. Hello, Duffy?
We got the biggest story in years.
"Earl Williams captured by
the Morning Post. Exclusive!"
Tear out the whole front page.
The whole front page.
Never mind the European war.
We got something bigger than that.
Hildy Johnson's writing the lead.
And get hold of Butch O'Connor.
Tell him to come up here
with his wrestlers.
Yeah, Butch O'Connor. What?
I've got a desk I want moved...
What the deuce do you want?
- Hello, Bruce.
- Hildy.
Never mind the Chinese earthquake.
- I want to ask you...
- How'd you get out of jail?
Not through any help of yours.
I'm not talking to you.
I had to wire Albany for $100
so I could get out on bail.
What will they think in Albany?
The money went to the police.
- We're waiting for that story.
- We'll explain everything to them.
- Where's Mother?
- She left.
I can't hear you.
- Where'd she go?
- Someplace.
- Junk the Polish Corridor!
- Tell me where she was going.
- She couldn't say.
- It's more important.
- Did she get the money?
- She left in a hurry.
- I'll take it.
- In my purse.
I can handle things.
I'll take that certified check too.
I'll give you the tickets.
You'll find your money in the wallet.
My wallet? This is my wallet.
There's something funny going on...
What are you doing?
Just wanted to look at it.
Hildy, I'm taking...
- I'm taking the 9:00 train.
- Sure, sure.
Did you hear what I said?
I'm taking the 9:00...
Oh, Bruce, I put it in here!
Let her alone, will you, buddy?
- Do me a favour...
- Just answer one question.
You don't want to come
with me, do you?
Answer me.
You don't, do you?
No. Take the Miss America
pictures off page six.
Hildy, tell me.
Tell me the truth.
Wait a minute.
Now look here, my good man...
You shut up, Burns.
You're doing all this to her.
She wanted to get away from you.
But you caught her
and changed her mind...
Stick Hitler on the funny page.
Let me ask you...
Will you give up everything
for a man like him?
No, but something's happened.
I'll tell you...
Tell him nothing.
He's a spy, you fool.
- I am not.
- Ridiculous.
You're coming with me right now.
Just a second.
This is the biggest thing in my life.
I see. I'll keep.
I'm like something in the icebox.
You just don't love me.
That isn't true. Just because you
won't listen you say I don't love you.
You never intended to be decent
and live like a human.
All right, if that's what
you want to think.
I'm trying to concentrate.
- You're just like him and all the rest.
- That's what I am.
What? Leave the rooster story alone.
That's human interest.
If you had any sympathy
or understanding...
- I understand, all right...
- Wait.
There's one question I want to know.
The mayor's first wife's name.
The one with the wart on her? Fanny.
What, Duffy?
You never loved me at all.
Never mind.
You don't work for advertising.
If you change your mind,
I'm on the 9:00 train.
If you want me, take me as I am.
Don't try to change me.
I'm no suburban bridge player.
I'm a newspaperman.
That's it. Keep it coming
as fast as you can.
Get back in there, you mock turtle.
Did you tell Butch it's a matter
of life and death?
Good. Butch's on his way. We just
have to hold out for 15 minutes.
- The boys will be back to phone.
- I'll handle them.
Oh, now the moon's out.
Fine. Three taps is me.
Don't forget. Got enough air?
- Not very much.
- That better? You're sitting pretty.
- How's it coming?
- All right. Where's Bruce?
- He went out.
- Is he coming back here?
Certainly. Didn't you hear him?
What have you got?
"While Hartwell's paid gunmen stalked
the city, shooting bystanders...
...spreading terror,
Williams lurked..."
Wait a minute.
Aren't you going to mention the Post?
- Second paragraph.
- Who reads the second paragraph?
How long have I been
telling you how to write?
I'm sorry.
What's the idea of locking this door?
- Who's that?
- Bensinger. That's his desk.
Open the door, will you?
- What's his name?
- Bensinger, of The Tribune.
- The Tribune?
- Who's in there?
Haven't you any better sense...?
Hello. Hello, Mr. Burns. Quite
an honour having you come over here.
- Hello, Bensinger.
- You know my... I just want to get my...
It's quite a coincidence
seeing you tonight, isn't it?
How do you mean?
I was talking to our Mr. Duffy
about you this afternoon.
Really? Nothing detrimental, I hope.
On the contrary. On the contrary.
That was one swell story
you had in the paper today.
Did you care for the
poem, Mr. Burns?
- The poem? The poem was great.
- I liked the ending a lot.
And all is well outside his cell
But in his heart
He hears the hangman calling
And the gallows falling
And his white-haired mother's tears
- Heartbreaking?
- Fine.
Would you like to work for me?
We can use a man like you.
All we got are lowbrows
like Johnson here.
- Are you serious, Mr. Burns?
- Serious? Wait a minute.
Duffy, I'm sending
Mr. Bunsinger over to see you.
- Bensinger.
- Mervyn, isn't it?
- Yeah... No. Roy. Roy V.
- Certainly.
Roy V. Bensinger, the poet.
You wouldn't know. You probably never
heard of Shakespeare either.
Put Mr. Bensinger on staff.
How much you getting on The Tribune?
- $75.
- I'll give you 100 and a byline.
Now you give him everything he wants,
you understand?
Roy, write me a story from the
point of view of the escaped man.
He hides, afraid of every sound,
every light.
He hears footsteps, they're closing in.
- Get the sense of the animal at bay.
- Sort of Jack London style?
- I'll get my rhyming dictionary.
- It doesn't have to rhyme.
I'm deeply grateful, Mr. Burns.
If there's an opening
for a war correspondent...
...I parler a little French.
- I'll keep you in mind.
- Au revoir, mon capitaine.
Bonjour.
"His white-haired mother's tears."
That's the tops.
That fellow Bensinger
is on his way right now.
Handle him with kid gloves.
Have him write poetry.
We don't want him.
Stall him till the extra's out.
Say his poetry smells
and kick him out.
Double-crosser.
He won't quit his paper
without giving notice.
- I mean you.
- Me?
You'd double-cross anybody...
Wait a minute.
Bruce isn't coming back.
He said he was taking the 9:00.
In that case, he's gone.
Don't sit there like a frozen robin.
Get on with the story.
We should be finished
when Butch arrives.
How you have messed up my life.
What am I going to do?
Window's too small.
We'll carry the desk.
I'd be on that train now.
I'm a sap, falling for your line.
- They'll name streets after me...
- Yes, well, get back to work.
I'm not going back to work.
Walter, what...?
- Who is it?
- It's me, boss. It's Louie.
Louie.
- What's wrong?
- Where's Mrs. Baldwin?
What happened?
Down Western Avenue, we was going
65 miles an hour, know what I mean?
Where's the old lady?
We run smack into a police patrol.
Busted it in half.
Was she hurt?
Can you imagine bumping
into a load of cops?
- What did you do with her?
- Search me, when I come to...
You were with her.
You were in the cab.
- The driver got knocked cold.
- Butterfingers!
- You handed her over to the cops.
- What do you mean?
They was on the wrong
side of the street.
Fine. Now she's probably
squawking to the police.
She's not squawking much.
You know?
Don't tell me...
Was she killed?
Was she? Did you notice?
Me with a gun on the hip and
a kidnapped lady...
...I'm gonna ask questions
from cops?
- You know what I mean?
- Dead, dead. This is the end!
It's fate, Hildy.
What will be, will be.
What am I going to say to Bruce?
What can I tell him?
If he loves you, you won't
have to say anything.
Would you rather have had the old
dame drag the police in here?
I killed her. I'm responsible.
What'll I do?
How can I face Bruce again?
- Look at me, Hildy.
- I am looking at you, you murderer.
If it was my own grandmother,
I'd carry on.
- You know I would, for the paper.
- Louie, where'd it happen?
Western and 34th.
- I got to get out of here...
- We can do more here. Be calm.
Listen...
- Hello, hello.
- Maine 4557.
Who? Butch, where are you?
Mission Hospital?
Receiving room.
What are you doing there?
Was a lady brought in
from a smashup?
For H. Sebastian, Butch,
it's a matter of life and death.
- Nobody?
- I can't hear.
- Morningside 2469.
- You got who? Speak up. A what?
You can't stop for a dame now!
I don't care if you've been after her.
Lives are at stake!
You're going to let a woman
come between us?
Was there an old lady brought in
in a smashup?
Butch, I'd put my arm in fire
for you up to here.
You can't double-cross me.
Look around, please.
All right, put her on.
I'll talk to her.
Good evening, madam. Now, listen,
you ten-cent glamour girl...
...you can't keep Butch
from his duty. What?
You say that again,
I'll kick you in the teeth!
Say, what kind of language is that?
Now, look here, you...
She hung up. What did I say?
How do you like that?
Mousing around with some big...
- Will you shut up? I'm trying to hear!
- That's cooperation.
Well, where is Duffy?
Diabetes. I should know better than
to hire a diseased person.
- Give me Olympia 2136, will you?
- Louie!
- Yes, boss.
- Louie, it's up to you.
- Anything you say, boss.
- Get a hold of some guys.
Anybody with hair on his chest,
get them off the street.
We gotta get the desk out.
Is it important?
You're the best friend I got.
- I like you too.
- Don't fail me.
Get enough people to move that desk.
You know me.
Shirt off my back.
Okay, don't bump into anything.
- Dumb immigrant is sure to flop on me.
- Try the hospital again.
If he's not back in five,
we'll carry it out alone.
- Do anything you want.
- There's a million... Could start a fire.
- We'll have the firemen take it out.
- I don't care what you do.
- Come here. See if we can lift it.
- What? Nobody? Never mind.
- Are you gonna help me?
- No!
- I'll strain my back.
- I'll find Mrs. Baldwin.
- Don't open it!
- I'll go to the morgue...
- We want to talk to you a minute.
- Let go. What's the idea?
Get your hands off me!
- Now, look here, Johnson...
- Hey, you!
You mean me?
Yes, you. What do you mean by
breaking in here like this?
I don't care what paper
you're editor of.
Let go of me. Something's
happened to my mother-in-law.
- We know what you are up to.
- She and Mollie were in here talking.
I know nothing,
and there's been an accident.
There's something
very peculiar going on here.
- See here...
- Just a moment, Hartwell.
Make your accusations
in the proper manner.
Or I'll have to ask you to get out.
- Ask me to what?
- Get out.
You will, eh? Don't let anybody
in or out. We'll see about this.
- Give him the third degree.
- Make them talk and you got him.
I'm going to get to the bottom of this.
Are you going to talk?
- What do you want me to say?
- What do you know about Williams?
Now we're getting some...
Take her out.
I got ways to make her talk.
Don't you dare touch me or...
- She's got a gun!
- Grab it!
No, you don't. Walter!
All right, Burns.
I'll take that gun.
- Where did you get this?
- I can carry a gun.
- Not this gun.
- I can explain it.
She was interviewing Williams,
so I gave her a gun to defend herself.
Interesting. But this is the gun
that Williams shot his way out with.
Good man, are you trying
to make me out a liar?
I ought to know my own gun,
oughtn't I...?
- That's where Williams got it.
- She got it from him.
- Where's Williams?
- You're barking up the wrong tree.
Tell me where he is.
At the hospital calling on Professor
Egelhoffer with marshmallows.
- Where is he?
- Ask the mastermind why he's here.
- What do you know about this?
- My dear fellow...
...the Morning Post doesn't obstruct
justice or hide criminals.
- You ought to know that.
- You're under arrest.
- You too.
- Who's under arrest?
Listen, you square-toed,
pimple-headed spy...
...do you realize what you're doing?
I'll show you.
You and the Post
are obstructing justice.
- I'll see that you're fined $10,000.
- You'll see nothing.
I'll begin by impounding the Post's
property. Is this your desk?
What are you afraid of, Hildy?
I dare you to move this desk.
- Go ahead, try it.
- I will.
I warn you, you move this desk out,
I'll put you behind bars.
- He can do it.
- I'll see Roosevelt hears about it.
Tell him. Come on, boys!
- Confiscate it.
- Last chance.
- This is a federal offence.
- We'll take a chance on that.
All right.
Open up this door!
- Mother! I'm glad to see you...
- That's the man that did it. There.
- What's the idea here?
- She claims she's been kidnapped.
They dragged me down all the way
down the stairs and...
Did he do it?
He was in charge.
He told them to kidnap me.
Excuse me, madam.
Are you referring to me?
You know you did.
What about this? Kidnapping, huh?
Trying to frame me, huh?
I never saw her before in my life.
What a thing to say!
I was here when that girl
jumped out the window.
Get the mayor here.
Madam, be honest.
If you were out joyriding...
...plastered, or in a scrape,
why not admit it instead of...
...accusing innocent people?
You ruffian! How dare you talk
like that to me!
He's crazy, Mother.
I'll tell you more.
I could tell you why they did it.
They were hiding some
kind of murderer in here...
Hiding him? In here?
Madam, you're a cockeyed liar...
...and you know it!
- What's that?
- He's in there!
- Give me the desk.
- What a break!
- Stand back.
- He might shoot.
- Guns out.
- He's harmless.
- Don't take any chances.
- You've got his gun.
Go on, you grey-haired old weasel.
Let me out of here!
Mother! I was looking
all over for you. What happened?
- Jake, hang on.
- Hildy, call Duffy.
- No!
- You want to see us scooped?
- Aim right for the centre.
- That's murder.
Okay, one of you get
on each end.
- It's coming up.
- You're covered.
- In a minute.
- Don't move.
- Any time.
- On three.
- It's hot.
- Ready?
- Any second now.
- Three. I got you, Williams.
- Go ahead, shoot me.
- Come out.
Earl Williams just captured
in the criminal courts building.
- On your feet.
- Don't try any funny stuff.
Williams was unconscious.
The police overpowered him.
- He offered no resistance.
- His gun wouldn't work.
The Post turned Williams
over to the sheriff.
- Put the cuffs on them.
- More later.
An anonymous note led to
Williams' capture. Hold on.
The sheriff's tracing a call
that gave away Williams' hiding place.
- Where's the old lady?
- She went out.
Call you back.
- Give me the warden's office.
- You'll wish you'd never been born.
Oh, am I?
- Hello, Fred.
- Well, fine work, Pete.
- You delivered the goods.
- Looks natural, don't it?
- Sight for sore eyes.
- Aiding a criminal.
And a little charge of kidnapping...
What's that?
But that's the jail.
Looks like about ten years apiece
for you two birds.
When you think you've licked the Post,
it's time to get out.
Whistling in the dark won't help.
You're through.
Archie Leach said that to me
a week before he cut his throat.
Is that so?
We've been in worse jams than this,
haven't we, Hildy?
You forget the power
that watches over the Post.
- It's not with you now.
- Says you.
I've caught him. Yes, Williams.
Single-handed.
Proceed with the hanging, per schedule.
- You'll be in office two days more.
- We'll pull your nose out of that feedbag.
I tell you what you'll be doing.
Making brooms in the penitentiary.
Joe? This is Hartwell.
Come to my office right away.
I captured some important birds.
Take their confessions.
Get Liebowitz.
- The lawyers won't help you now.
- You're talking to the Morning Post.
The power of the press?
Bigger men than you have found out
what the power of the press is.
Presidents, kings...
- Here's the reprieve.
- Get out.
- You can't bribe me. My wife...
- No, I won't. Here's the reprieve.
- What?
I don't want to be a city sealer.
- Throw him out.
- Out you go.
Wait.
Who's trying to bribe you?
- They wouldn't take it.
- Insane!
What did I say? An unseen power.
What do you mean with a story like that?
He's an impostor.
Trying to hang an innocent man
to win an election?
That's murder.
- I never saw him before.
- If I was to...
- What's your name?
- Pettibone.
- When did you deliver this?
- Who'd you talk to?
- They started to bribe me.
- They?
- Them.
- It's absurd on the face of it.
He's talking like a child.
- Out of the mouths of babes.
- Hi, babe.
He's insane or drunk.
If Williams has been reprieved,
I'm tickled to death. Aren't you?
You'd hang your mother
to be reelected.
That's a horrible thing to say
about anybody.
You're marvellous.
Take a look at that.
- You're an intelligent man.
- Never mind.
Let's have your story.
- Nineteen years ago, I married Mrs...
- Skip that.
She wasn't Mrs. Pettibone then.
She was one of the...
This document is authentic.
Williams has been reprieved.
Our commonwealth has been saved
the necessity of shedding blood.
Get off the soapbox.
Save that for The Tribune.
Take those handcuffs off my friends.
- I'm amazed at you.
- Isn't he awful?
You don't know how badly I feel.
No excuse at all for Pete.
- I was only doing my duty.
- That's all right.
- What'd you say your name was?
- Pettibone.
- Here's a picture of my wife.
- Fine woman.
- You haven't seen her.
- She's all right.
She's good enough for me.
If I was to tell...
I understand perfectly, and
as long as I'm mayor...
Which should be about three hours.
Enough to get out an edition
asking for your recall.
And your arrest. You boys
ought to get about ten years apiece.
Don't make any hasty decisions.
You might run into a libel suit.
- You'll run into the governor.
- We understand each other perfectly.
Yes, and so do I.
So do you what?
And now, Mr. Pettibone...
...we'll deliver this reprieve
to the warden's office. Come along.
- If I was to tell my wife...
- You won't have to.
Wait till they read
the Morning Post tomorrow.
Tight squeeze.
- Give me Duffy.
- That's our worst jam.
What? Where? Get him.
Remember stealing old lady Haggerty's
stomach from the coroner?
Any time you need this guy
he's never there.
We proved she'd been poisoned,
didn't we?
We had to hide out for a week.
Do you remember that?
The Shoreland Hotel.
That's how we happened to...
We could have gone
to jail for that too.
Yes, maybe you're right, Hildy.
It's a bad business.
You'll be better off.
You better get going.
- Where would I go?
- To Bruce, of course.
- You know he's gone. He took a train.
- Send a wire.
He'll be at the station
when you get into Albany.
- Why doesn't he have a phone?
- I don't know. I got us messed up...
- Get going, Hildy.
- What is that with you?
Wait a minute.
Can't you understand?
I'm trying to do something noble.
Get out before I change my mind.
It's tough enough now.
- Just a minute.
- Send him a wire. He'll be waiting.
- Who'll write the story?
- I will. It won't be as good...
It's my story.
I like to think that it...
- At last.
- I get it. The same old act, isn't it?
Try to push me out,
thinking I'll want to stay.
I know I deserve that.
Wait a minute, Duffy.
This time you're wrong.
When you walk out that door,
part of me will go right with you.
But a whole new world
will open up for you.
I made fun of Bruce and Albany.
You know why?
- Why?
- I was jealous.
I was sore because he could offer you
the kind of life I can't give you.
That's what you want, honey.
I could do the story
and take the train...
Forget it. Come on. Come on.
Goodbye, dear, and good luck.
Duffy, now this is how
it goes so far...
Just a minute.
Hello. Who? Hildy Johnson?
- She just left.
- I'm still here. I can take it.
Hang on a minute.
Hildy Johnson speaking.
The 4th Precinct police station?
Put him on.
I thought you were on your
way to Albany... What for?
For having counterfeit money.
Counterfeit money?
Hold on a minute.
Where did you get it?
I gave it to you?
All right.
I'll try and do something about it.
Honey.
Honey, don't cry, please.
I didn't mean to make you cry.
What's wrong? You never cried before.
I thought you were really
sending me away with Bruce.
I didn't know you had him locked up.
I thought you were
on the level, for once.
That you were just standing by
and letting me go off with him...
...and not doing a thing about it.
Come on, honey. What did you
think I was, a chump?
I thought you didn't love me.
What were you thinking with?
I don't know.
What are you standing
there gawking for?
We have to get him out of jail.
Send Louie down
with some honest money...
...and send him back to Albany.
Sure.
Everything's changed.
We're coming over to the office.
Don't worry about the story.
Hildy will write it.
She never intended to quit.
We're getting married.
- Can we go on a honeymoon this time?
- Sure.
Duffy, you can be managing editor.
Not permanently.
Just for the two weeks we're away.
I don't know where.
Where are we going?
Niagara Falls.
- Niagara Falls.
- Two whole weeks?
Sure, you've earned it. What?
What? A strike? What strike?
Where? Albany?
- I know it's on the way, but...
- Okay, we'll honeymoon in Albany.
Okay, Duffy.
Isn't that a coincidence!
I wonder if Bruce can put us up.
Say, why don't you carry that
in your hand?