Mother! Oh mother!!
Hang on... Commander...
Mother!
It's a case of severe appendicitis.
We need to operate immediately.
He is the face of our movement.
We cannot risk going to the hospital.
We will have to
take the risk, Zahoor.
Or tomorrow the press will report...
that Commander Ikhlaq Latif died...
of a terrifying explosion
of his appendix.
I'll arrange an ambulance and
will meet you by the lake in an hour.
Where will you operate?
At home.
- "What is a home?"
"It is brothers and sisters..."
- And sisters.
"And fathers and mothers."
- And mothers.
"It is unselfish acts and kindly sharing."
- Sharing.
"And showing your loved ones
you're always caring..."
- Caring.
"What is a house?"
Doctor, how are you?
- I am fine.
- You got delayed today...
- Another surgery.
Let the doctor go...
Lower the heat a bit...
And the flames within you...
They can burn this house down!
You'll have the
village burnt to ashes.
Doctor...
- Yes.
Do you know what you're doing?
Exactly what a doctor
should be doing.
Which side are you on?
I am for life.
- Move.
Salam Alaikum! This is Gul Khan.
It's a cordon and search operation.
Every man and boy is ordered to assemble
in the school grounds immediately.
Women and children may stay home.
It's a cordon and search operation.
Every man and boy is ordered to assemble
in the school grounds immediately.
Hilaal!
There's a crackdown in our village.
Every man and boy is ordered to assemble
in the school grounds immediately.
- This crackdown may go on all day...
This before meals, this afterwards.
If the pain gets worse, inject this.
Be careful...
If they suspect something...
no one will survive.
Neither you...
nor I...
And Haider?
God is his guardian.
He will take care of him...
- Save me... Oh, Lord!
- I don't know!!
- Ikhlaq Latif...
Surrender yourself...
- Indian law will give you a fair trial.
Lay down your weapons
and come out.
- You don't have a chance.
Surrender or die.
Sir... Ikhlaq Latif is alive...
We have killed the
other two millitants.
Shall we send in reinforcements?
No bloody militant
dead or alive...
is worth my soldier's life...
In the name of Allah
most merciful...
- Load...
Ready...
Fire!
Everybody line up outside
with your IDs and bags.
Where are you going?
Srinagar.
You are coming from?
- Aligarh.
What do you do there?
I'm a student.
College ID?
Subject of research?
Revolutionary poets of British India.
Which town do you belong to?
Islamabad.
- The captain is out at the check post...
Any message for him?
Salam Alaikum!
Come.
- Sir, I want to interview you...
Go ahead... interview me now...
Ah, thanks!
So...
I'll thrash you!
Your love for Kashmir...
is expressed as Islamabad?
What?
Sir, Islamabad is another name
for Anantnag.
I know.
But for us...
there's just one Islamabad.
In Pakistan...
Nice poems
Rather difficult though.
Be careful with such beautiful inspiration.
Okay?
Take this.
Haider, that burrito
wouldn't budge.
I told him that you are a poet,
not a militant.
And we are engaged to be married.
He wanted proof.
I told him to read your diary.
You wrote your poems for me...
since childhood.
Where are we going?
To see your mother.
Where is she?
At your uncle's.
Stop the car.
I have to go home.
Haider...
There isn't much of a home
left in what remains...
Father, wait...
I'm running late...
- Won't take long...
Let the petals fill with colour...
Let the breeze ruffle the spring...
Let the breeze ruffle the spring.
The next verse?
Let the breeze ruffle the spring...
Come along, my love...
Awake the garden to life.
There... the vase has fallen...
That's my bat.
Hold this.
Dad's shoes...
Haider...
- Yes.
Don't fight it...
What?
You can on]...
Where's the shoe brush?
Haider...
You can on]...
Please.
What is Arshee's car doing here?
Slop!
Now that is quite an interview!
Brother...
Of course, you couldn't
drop me at the airport
You don't get it...
Don't say a word!
- Brother...
Listen...
If I ever see you around her...
you will disappear...
just like your father.
You get me? Like your...
Arshee, move aside.
Leave us! Please.
- Come with me.
- Let go of my hand.
Come with me.
- You never heard my caution.
You let her do as she pleases.
And look now.
She won't leave the house.
I will not stop working.
- What did you say?
Look at me.
What did you say?
Alright, calm down.
You have to stop seeing Haider.
Lucky is right about it.
His life won't be the same
after the doctor's arrest.
The families of militants
can neither get passports...
nor government jobs.
You know how it is.
Yes. Very well...
See what I mean?
She is a stubborn one...
Swear by the Koran.
Place your hand on it.
Arshee...
Open the door.
There's another flight
to Bangalore at two.
I don't want to go.
Don't be a fool.
"Don't want to go..."
You don't turn down such a big job.
Don't take it lightly.
She has the mind of a child...
- I'll speak to her.
Here... I swear by the Koran...
Thank you.
Good to see you...
Why are you laughing?
Sorry!
You are so out of tune.
I have been
begging you to teach me
Since college...
Teach me.
Be my master.
And you look away.
I'll have to sing like this now...
Why don't you?
Please.
- No.
Darling sis-in-law.
My angel...
Haider!
You are home!
Not a word of your arrival...
You've lost so much weight...
- Grown a beard too...
Have you...
written your thesis?
Why are you so quiet?
Say something?
My angel...
- These are hard times.
It's a time for patience.
The Koran tells us.
- God is with the patient.
I've filed a petition in court
It will take some time...
God-willing, all will be well soon.
It doesn't look like it though.
What?
The two of you seem quite happy...
with my father's disappearance.
What?
The two of you seem very happy...
with my father's disappearance.
- Haider...
Have you lost it?
What are you saying?
Exactly what I see...
dear uncle...
Has your musical been on for a while?
Or did this romantic production begin..
After father's disappearance?
Sis-in-law...
How dare you!
Is this the way to talk to your mother?
Is this what you learnt in college?
- Sis-in-law...
Let his father return!
He's a boy...
Let it be...
It will affect your health...
Come along...
Sis-in-law...
Haider...
I am sorry.
Haider... I will explain...
Sis-in-law...
My angel...
Haider...
Come back...
It is time for curfew now.
My angel...
The army will grab him too.
Please! Stop him!
He will be fine.
Please get him back.
Sis-in-law...
I'll manage it...
Don't worn].
Hello!
Whom do you want?
Salman?
Just a moment.
Telephone.
Hello!
Whom do you want?
This call is for you.
Hello...
Whom do you want?
Salman or Salman?
Or Salmanl?
Do you mind taking the trouble...
to introduce yourself?
Your daddy!
Superintendent of Police...
Pan/ez Lone
Sir... Sorry sir!
Pan/ez sir...
- Hello sir...
Do we pay you to sing and dance?
I apologise, sir!
Do you know Haider?
Haider Meet.
Yes sir! I know him very well.
We did high school together.
- Find him!
You'll find him around the lake...
Take him home
to keep an eye on him...
Yes, sir!
Have a good day...
You rascal! Didn't I tell you...
to disconnect the phone before
brother Salman's movie.
- No... not that.
- Want some of this?!
Do you want some of this?
Slop!
Where are you going?
What's in the bag?
Check it...
- Yes, sir.
Your identity card?
And raise your hands...
Frisk him...
Hello Captain.
Salman...
and Salman!
Hello Major!
Haider... How are you?
When did you get back?
- You know him?
Know him?!
He's my sweetheart
Come on, let's get out of here
before curfew sets in.
Or some Major will be welcoming us...
in a military camp.
Let me carry the bag.
Haider, come.
Goodbye, Colonel.
Seated?
Let's go.
In Kashmir, God in heaven...
and the army rules the earth.
- And the army has a bible...
AFS PA
The Armed Forces Special Power Act.
Khurram, my son is innocent.
He's been detained
at the Faraz cinema camp.
Please get him out.
Uncle...
I have no authority...
to free your boy.
I can't get him out...
but I can possibly save his life.
We have to shift him from
a camp to a prison.
We need to get him charged...
with a crime.
- Sir.
- It'll be a false charge.
A false charge.
That would get him
a court hearing.
Meaning...
no chances of dissapearance...
- Okay?
C-H-U-T-Z-P-A-H..
Chutzpah...
It is what it is.
Chutzpah?
What is it?
Once a boy was arrested
for the murder of his parents.
In the courtroom he sought...
a lenient sentence from the judge.
Bewildered, the judge asked...
How do you expect mercy...
after killing your own parents?
The boy replied...
Because I am an orphan now.
That my friends is chutzpah.
A Hebrew word.
- It does rhyme a bit with AFSPA...
- And similar in meaning too.
AFSPA...
Chutzpah...
- AFSPA...
- What will you do now?
The same.
Chutzpah!
I'll look for my father.
Where? In camps?
In prisons?
All of Kashmir is a prison.
I will look for him everywhere.
Jhelum, Jhelum, searching a shore
In whose eyes the sun sets
The sun sets in whose eyes
The waters of the river Jhelum
Have turned saline
Jhelum, Jhelum, searching a shore
Who to ask for how much longer
This pain we must continue to bear
Holding the hand of the blinded night
We must walk yet how much longer
Blood, blood, blood,
blood has become the colour of time
Blood, blood, blood
Blood is a moulten ember
- God! Oh God!
- I'm still alive...
- Thank you, Oh Lord! I am still alive!
- Gentlemen
- Delhi has approved Operation Nightingale.
We have complete support to
arm, fund and run...
the counter insurgency force...
- Complete support!
The enemy's foes are our friends...
Any individual or group...
anyone with a grudge against...
the Hizbul Mujahideen and
Pakistan's proxy war...
surrendered militants,
detainees, undenrials...
- will be our primary recruits.
Khwan-m-Mukhbireen
The Army will run the operation
but your support will be crucial...
in recruitment and intelligence.
Let the Nightingale start singing.
It' s catch and kill.
- We need to nourish the Ikhwan
khwan-m-Mukhbireen ..
With arms, money, power...
Isn't that Kaul's house?
- Yes, he's in Jammu,
in a refugee camp.
I think he's moved to Bombay...
How many cases do you have?
About 75-80.
But why would they take up arms
against their own?
For freedom...
A prisoner will exchange
anything for his freedom.
Pan/ez...
What...
What do we get?
Delhi.
Take them away.
A dead militant is worth
a hundred thousand rupees.
Call the media.
- Yes, sir!
Haider...
Hear me out...
Who...
Who are you angn/ with?
And why?
He's not just your father,
but my brother too...
my only brother...
It's been...
Days since your mother
managed a smile.
She's been crying for weeks.
And you accuse us of singing...
and dancing in joy...
secretly?
She is my brother's wife.
My dearest sister-in-law.
Haider...
Here, take a look.
I am contesting the elections.
Do you know why?
Ask me why?
Why?
- For my brother.
What else!
Once I'm in power...
I'll tear open even] prison
and bring him home.
Uncle, you may wait
for the elections.
My battle has already begun.
"Armed Forces Special Powers Act,
Rule 4 of section 5 says -
Any person taken under custody under
this Act shall be handed over...
to the office in charge of the nearest police
station with the least possible delay."
The least possible delay...
It's been twenty days and
there's no word of him.
If everything worked by the book...
do you think Kashmir would
have been the hell it is?
Pandit Nehru promised Kashmiris
a plebiscite with the world as his witness
What happened?
- Let aside plebiscite...
Even the first condition
to plebiscite...
demilitarization...
did not happen.
When two elephants fight...
it is the grass
that is trampled upon.
I agree, uncle...
But I want to file a formal report
Don't mess with the army, son.
If you file a formal report...
the chances of finding him
will become even more bleak.
Rocky is good...
But you are in India...
Watch the Indian action hero...
Salman Khan...
Tell them...
This film was...
chutzpah!
- Yes.
What is Chutzpah?
It's a big film... a big hit.
A blockbuster...
Can I see it?
- Yes, sure.
Salman... Salman Khan.
- This guy?
Are you done shooting?
I'll eat...
- Come...
Yes please...
- Haider...
- Eat some more...
- I can't see a thing...
Salam Alaikum, uncle.
Princess...
Where's your prince?
Mister...
Your mother has been on a
hunger strike for two days now.
She won't even touch water till
she she sees you.
Open the door, sis-in-law!
I present to you
the sparkle of your eyes...
- your little prince.
My angel...
You know, if you go to Delhi...
you'll easily get a job.
Where?
The National School of Drama.
Please do stop your theatrics now!
What do you mean?
Why am I to blame?
Emotional blackmail...
ever since my childhood...
you would stop eating or leave home.
You would cry away
or threaten suicude.
That is how you sent me
away to Aligarh.
Banished me from my home...
away from my father...
If I hadn't pushed you to Aligarh...
you know well, where you
would have ended up!
What is this?
Where did you get this from?
I demand an answer.
It belongs to a friend.
I'll return it tomorrow.
Ah, now you are friends
with militants?
It's a pistol today,
tomorrow it will be a Kalashnikov...
Going for arms training in Pakistan?
Are you?!
Yes, I'll go across.
Sis-in-law...
Are you alright?
- These are dark days.
Birds of prey circle above...
They prey without care...
Kites grab sparrows and
falcons feast on Nightingales...
- Keep him away from it all...
I have a friend
at the university in Aligarh.
Send him there.
- Let him see the other side of India.
A world without imprisoned days
and curfews at nights.
Doctor Sahib won't let him go.
I'll take care of the doctor.
- Make Haider come around.
Alright?
Now cheer up...
Smile, my child!
This house is a ruin
without your laughter.
Father...
A bride for Khurram...
and it will be a happy home.
He doesn't seem to like any girls.
Why Mr. Khurram?
Well!
All the pretty ones...
are already married...
just like you!
You wicked man...
No father wants to see
his son as a militant.
But sending him away
is not a way out either...
It is a grave problem...
and an old one too.
We have lost a few
generations already...
God alone knows when blood
will stop raining on our land.
It's all up to India.
As they say in India, “birth right“.
And we are only claiming our right...
Freedom.
Freedom...
Gandhi won it for India...
not the gun.
The gun only knows how to avenge...
Commander...
revenge does not set you free..
True freedom lies beyond violence..
Remember...
Revenge only begets revenge.
- Don't you understand?
Can't you hear me?
I am not going anywhere.
I am staying here.
With my father.
Jahid.. to the left...
What is it now?
I ask you, one last time...
Will you go or not?
Should I write it down for you?
I will not!
What is this, mother?!
Will you go or not?
Please hear me out...
- Will you go or not?
Put the gun down mother...
Will you go or notl?
Mother, please...
Would you really have
shot yourself that day?
Do you doubt me?
No. I'm sure.
You wouldn't have.
Was there any other reason
for me to live... besides you?
Or is there?
I bore those long
painful years for you...
Don't...There you go again...
You have to listen to me.
Your father never really
cared for me. Our marriage was dead.
Which is why he gambled his life...
our home...
our honor...
your future... risked it all.
Do we have to see everything
through your eyes?
Always?
There are other ways of seeing.
Try sometime...
Either way,
you will always blame me...
I am used to it.
I know you love your father
more than anyone else...
You certainly don't realise...
What I went through
when you were away.
Hilaal had lost himself in
the hospital, a saint saving lives.
I used to wail like a
hollow bamboo in your memory.
I would wait months for you
to return home in the holidays.
It is my fate to long... to wait...
First for you...
Now...
And now?
The wives of disappeared people
are called 'half-widows' here.
We can only wait.
That is all I can do.
Wait.
For father to return?
Yes.
Or for his corpse.
My father is alive!
He's alive!
Do you understand?!
Please tell me mother, he's alive...
He's alive!
Tell me mother...
he's alive...
Please tell me...
Elections are the first step...
on the long road to peace...
It is a difficult journey...
but we can see our destination...
Wherever you come from...
people want the same thing...
Our schools have been turned
into Army camps...
It is not a democracy...
it a suffocating system.
A 'suffo-cracy'!
The town squares are lined with bunkers
and streets with barbed wires.
According to the APDP there are...
over eight thousand people
who are missing since arrest...
- Your numbers are wrong...
What about those three hundred
thousand Kashmiri Pandits...
displaced from their homes,
living as refugees...
Will you not count them
amongst the disappeared?
My brother disappeared months back.
We have to raise our voices
to search for our own.
- What do we want?
- Freedom...
- We'll snatch away...
And for this I am
running for elections...
I would like to remind you
of our neighbor that arms and trains...
misguided Kashmiri youth
to kill innocent people...
In 1948, they had looted Kashmiri's
when they came as tribals...
Raped the women and
killed their children.
It was the Indian army that
shed blood to save Kashmir.
- And if we aren't around,
it'll happen again.
Does the law allow you to torture
people you've arrested?
The Indian army is one of the most...
disciplined armed
forces in the world.
We train our officers to interrogate,
and not torture.
Amidst militant attacks,
today Kashmir goes to vote.
Militant groups have
exploded bombs in...
Srinagar, Barahmulla and Anantnag.
I want you to understand
the ground reality.
Separatists are not demanding
freedom from India...
but enslavement to Pakistan.
- Indian troops coerced reluctant
voters into polling booths.
- India has rubbished these allegations.
- However, the voter turnout
remained very low.
- Koshmar constituency saw
the lowest turn out...
where only 110 votes were registered.
- Congratulations!
You have won by a hundred votes.
Congratulations!
- Congratulations!
These traditional folk entertainers
known as Bhand...
are enacting a play
which speaks of a new Kashmir...
- A peaceful Kashmir...
- will the new regime bring
a brighter future for Kashmir?
Only time will tell.
Nice...
Very nice article.
Thank you.
- Come inside...
Come in...
Why are you standing there?
- Why don't you come inside...
What has possessed you?
What is wrong with him?
I don't know...
These days he just stands
outside the door for hours.
He doesn't come in...
- Frisk him.
Where are you coming from?
Where are you going?
What's in your pockets?
Your identity card?
You may go now.
People have become so used to
body searches...
that unless they are frisked...
they fear entering their own homes.
It's a psychological disorder...
the 'New Disease'...
Are you a doctor?
The doctor's soul.
Why are you following me?
What do you want?
A message.
What?
I have no message for anyone.
But I do...
A message for Haider,
from his father.
What?
A message for Haider shall be
delivered to Haider! Right?
Here is my number.
I will wait for his call.
What is your name?
Rooh...
Roohdaar.
Do we exist or do we not?!
Haider...
I have to tell you something...
Listen to me...
Haider... Listen to me.
There's a message from your father.
Hello...
Who is it?
I am Haider...
Haider who?
Haider Meet.
Whom do you want?
Roohdaar...
Downtown. Zaina Kadal bridge...
Tomorrow, 9 am.
Okay... I...
What's he heading to Downtown for?
Salman...
TO g0?
Or not to go?
Where is my father?
In a faraway place...
Very far...
You said you had
a message from him...
Yes.
What is it?
Revenge.
Vengeance.
Vengeance from whom?
And why?
From a murderer...
for a murder.
You seem to have confused matters.
My father was arrested by the army
and one of these days...
we will find out where
they're holding him.
Let the petals fill with color...
Let the breeze ruffle the spring...
Come along, my love...
Awake the garden to life.
The prison is a sullen ghost...
Ask the breeze for a whiff of hope...
Oh, someone please...
speak of the beauty of my beloved.
- When fatigue would muffle
our screams in the prison...
a sole voice would
rise through the night...
a balm to our agony...
The lights were never turned off...
we craved for the darkness.
Lice roamed on our broken bodies...
and vengeful snakes in our heads.
MAMA-2 was the other name for hell.
Men returned as from there as mere
shadows of themselves.
Officer...
How many Area Commanders
do you have in Anantnag?
Where did you get the RDX from?
- Aren't you from the Binori mosque?
Met Brigadier Badaam?
Twenty children died
in your bomb blasts...
Do you have any children?
No?
You won't father any.
Give me their names!
Sir, I swear I'm a student.
I swear, sir...
I'm not a militant.
Let's hear it all together...
Long live India!
- Long live India!
Since that day doctor
and I were always together...
like body and soul...
We bore our torments together
in the same cell.
We were chained together.
It seems we will be
killed together as well.
You can die doctor, but I won't.
And how is that?
You are the body
and I'm the soul...
You are mortal and I'm immortal!
Are you a Shia or a Sunni?
I am the river and the tree...
The Jhelum and the Chinar...
I'm both..
a temple and a mosque...
A Shia and a Sunni, I'm both.
A Hindu as well.
I always was... I am...
I will always be...
They moved us to other
camps for interrogation.
Strange camps... stranger names...
Bo-Bo land, Hotel 6...
Faraz cinema...
And one day, there was a revelation.
It was Khurram who
betrayed your father.
Khurram had handled
most of the cases of...
militants caught or
surrendered in Kashmir.
With his help Indian Intelligence
played their trump card...
forming a militia
to kill militants...
A counter-insurgency force...
khwan-m-Mukhbireen
The Ikhwans knew
militant sympathisers...
and their modus operandi.
- The terror of Ikhwan surpassed The horrors...
Kashmir has seen before.
- It was Khuram who killed your father.
- The army crackdown in your village
was not a matter of chance.
- Khurram was the army's informer...
- and your mother Ghazala was Khurram's
- It is certain. We shall witness...
The promised day...
the day of the blessed word...
We shall witness...
Roohdaar...
Yes.
If you do make it out alive...
Convey my message.
To whom?
To my son, Haider.
Tell him to avenge my betrayal...
by my brother.
Tell him to aim his bullets at those
cunning, deceiving eyes...
that entrapped his mother...
that made him an orphan.
And his mother?
God will be her judge.
We had become a burden
for everyone...
They handed us over
to the Ikhwan.
It was a miracle!
The rope that bound us
came loose...
The icy water of the Jhelum
stopped my bleeding.
Sand-miners on the
river bank saved me.
A few days later, they found
the doctor's body.
A little ahead of Baramulla, at Boniyar village
there is a graveyard...
where the unknown dead are buried.
They buried your father there...
he rests in grave number 318.
This is the safety lock.
Shoot him at point blank.
And remember...
aim at the eyes
that entrapped your mother.
Those treacherous eyes
that orphaned you.
Father...
Who are you calling
so early in the morning?
I had a nightmare.
What was it about?
Haider?
Two days and no word of him.
Neither Arshee nor
the Salmans know...
My dearest...
He's not a child anymore.
He'll be back.
I bumped into the principal
of your school yesterday.
He wanted to know when
you are returning to teach.
The children miss you very much...
Once I become whole.
What are you now? Half?
I am half-widow and half-bride.
You are half a fool as well.
Roohdaar!
- This is the number he called.
It is a satellite phone.
It can't be traced.
Sir, you had mentioned about
a permanent job for us...
another time perhaps...
Miss, your gift is ready...
- Thank you.
- You are welcome...
Daddy! is this a snowman?
No...
This is your husband.
Do you like his nose?
Or shall I cut it a bit?
What is that?
A surprise.
Oh.
Oh... God.
When did...
When did you weave it?
My sweet child.
Here, have one more.
It took a lot to make this for you.
No daddy. I'm not hungry.
He's not going to return
sooner if you stop eating.
Who brought him the message?
Roohdaar?
Open your mouth.
We'll have to take care of Haider...
Together.
Don't hide anything from me.
What is going on?
A traffic jam at the square...
Hello...
mic testing one, two, three...
Can you hear me?
Hello...
UN council
resolution number 47 of 1948...
article 2 of the Geneva convention
and article 370 of the Indian constitution...
Raises but one question!
Haider...
- What?
Do we exist or do we not?
If we do... then who are we?
If not... then where are we?
Did we exist at all?
Or not?
Chutzpah is our problem.
Do you know what chutzpah means?
Once upon a time a bank was robbed.
Pointing the gun at the cashier...
the burglar threatened...
give me the money or die..
The cashier gave him all the money.
He went to the next counter...
And asked the man to
open an account for him.
That is chutzpah...
Such audacity, such stupidity.
like AFSPA...
You carry on... I'll fetch him...
AFSPA...
Attention!
Armed Forces Special Powers Act,
section 5, rule 4, point A...
Any commissioned officer...
Yes sir!
Warrant officer...
Non-commissioned officer...
Yes sir!
Or any other person of equivalent rank
in the armed forces may, in a disturbed area...
if he is of the opinion that it is necessary
so to do for the maintenance of public order...
after giving such due warning as
he may consider necessary...
fire upon or otherwise use force,
even to the causing of death...
Against anyone acting in
contravention with law or order.
Law and order...
Order order...
- Law and order...
There is no law,
there is no order.
Whose laws? Whose order?
Made on order...
Law and order...
India! Pakistan!
A game on the border.
India clings to us..
Pakistan leeches on...
What of us? What do we want?
Freedom!
Freedom from this side...
- Freedom!
Freedom from that side...
We will be free!
- Freedom!
Haider!
"A world better than the world,
our lndia..."
"We are her children..."
Haider...
Yes?
Mother...
- What?
- Whose?
Yours...
Mine... yes...
Mother...
When did you come?
Why are you crying?
There's good news for you.
Nobody will call
you a half-widow now...
Father is dead.
He is dead.
I found his grave.
No more hidden musicals.
You don't believe me, right?
Hang on...
I have a photograph...
My dead father...
Mother...
Look at this.
I couldn't find my brother.
But I have found his killer.
He shared his cell at MAMA-2.
He goes by the name Roohdaar...
No one knows his real name.
Even] identity of
his is a ghost identity.
He came from Pakistan in 1990.
An ISI agent.
Two years back, he was
arrested in Baramulla.
He cut a deal with the Indian army...
He penetrated Zahoor's group...
A double agent...
My brother got to know that.
Which is why he negotiated...
his release as well.
On the way out...
he...
He... killed him...
and pushed him into
the Jhelum river...
These people have killed my brother.
Until I avenge his death...
I will not rest...
I promise you...
Haider...
Come in, little princess...
Hello.
What an imbecile you are!
You disappear for days!
You don't even tell
me when you are back.
I worn] for you in vain.
You are so haggard...
Why don't you find me a cure!
Everyone doubts you are going mad.
I trust my doubts but...
doubt my trusts.
What do you mean?
I mean...
Is Roohdaar the brave,
beloved witness?
Is Khurram the master of falsehood?
Whose tells a conceited tale?
Whose bears the cross of truth?
To believe or not to believe.
That is the question...
The answer hides
in yet another question.
What is that?
To trust the surging
beats of the head...
Or to heed the caution
of sober mind...
To kill or to die..
To be or not to be.
Where did you get this?
Give it back...
Haider...
You will do no such thing.
Whether it's the truth or a lie...
Swear upon me.
I have Iovvedd you more than my life.
Not Iovvedd, it's loved...
The V and D softly.
Say it... loved.
Low e-d.
Say.. Kicked.
Kick-Keri .
Plucked.
- Pluck-ked.
Sucked...
Suck-Keri ...
Fwwf.
Fu...
'Baster-ed'...
- 'Baster-ed'...
Thank you for being with us
in this time of grief.
Somehow I have gathered myself
to bear this bitter loss but...
the thought of seeing my beloved
sister-in-law live a widow's life...
and my dearest Haider as an orphan...
How do I find the courage
to bear that?
And thus facing these facts,
I seek your permission...
My elders and friends
present here, allow me...
to marry my sister-in-law
Ghazala Meer...
God bless!
- God bless!
Father...
My father-to-be...
Go on.. feed this fellow.
Mother...
- My angel...
What is this?
When will you grow up?
- Never...
What is this?
Remember what you would say
when you were a child?
What?
"When I grow up I'm going
to marn/ my mommy."
You would snuggle between
your father and me.
Even if he touched me,
you would fight with him.
And now his brother touches you...
What should I do now?
Who would want to share
you with the world?
Your beauty is venomous.
They have given him a pistol...
to kill uncle Khurram...
- Ghazala Akhtar...
Do you accept Khurram Hussain Meer
as your lawfully married husband?
I do.
- Do you accept?
- Khurram Hussein Meet...
do you accept Ghazala Akhtar
as your lawfully married wife?
I do.
O nightingale's head,
O wounded bird
Stay away, stay away,
don't meet the flower
O nightingale's head,
O wounded bird
Stay away, stay away,
don't meet the flower
A head in conflict is in
difficulty indeed
If the head is pounding,
the head is pounding
Then a pounding head
can be wicked too
The flower's scent
is filled with poison
Stay away, stay away,
don't meet the flower
O nightingale's head
Stay away, stay away,
don't meet the flower
O nightingale's head
Listen, O world,
I want to speak
Your story again
I wish to repeat
O nightingale's head,
O wounded bird
There was a pair of birds,
A male and female
The female was innocent,
The male was simple
There was a pair of birds,
A male and female
The female was innocent,
The male was simple
When the mountains
Were covered with snow
A falcon of bad intention
Flew above the trees and forest
Death lurked within its folded wings
Searching to find
A palace's destination
It found a home in
the nightingale's dreams
And stung them with lethal venom
Put poison in the scented flowers
Send to the nightingale in question.
And stung them with lethal venom
It found a home in
the nightingale's dreams
Send to the nightingale in question.
And stung them with lethal venom
He sprinkled gun powder in the valley
Below the lake put snares in sway
Dangling daggers against the male
Cut the bird's wings away
O head, my head, my head,
Only cowards lie
O nightingale's head,
O wounded bird
He had the injured man imprisoned
And tied him up like a slave
Took him to the Jhelum bridge
And threw him to a watery grave
Jhelum, Jhelum...
Red, your amour is red
But the river's of Kashmir
Have their unique essence
The chains broke,
As did destiny's tide
He's alive, he will be living
The criminal now cannot hide
Come to your senses,
lover's nightingale
The flower's scent
is filled with poison
Come to your senses,
lover's nightingale
Such a brilliant stow!
- Who wrote This play?
Zahoor Hussain?
Or was it Roohdaar?
Didn't they give you a gun too?
To kill me?
What shall we do Ghazala?
Die by his bullet?
Or have him treated?
In an asylum.
Don't let him get away...
- Haider...
Catch him...
- Follow him... come on...
It's Post Traumatic
Stress Disorder...
- PTSD.
He needs psychiatric care.
I've had a word at the hospital.
We'll admit him in the
morning after curfew.
If he wakes up,
he'll make a run for it.
I have sedated him well.
He won't wake up for hours.
There's a curfew out there,
I'll drop you in my car.
Okay, thank you.
- Come on.
Arshee...
Open the door...
You misunderstand me.
No!
You have betrayed me.
You took advantage of my trust.
You used me...
You don't care for Haider's life...
You want to use him to
catch those people...
who exposed Khurram.
You don't care if Haider has to die.
Open the door and let me explain...
Try to see my point
I don't want to get your point.
I don't want to see you... ever!
Haider...
Avenge me...
of my brother.
Aim bullets at those
cunning, deceiving eyes...
that entrapped your mother...
Don't forget...
My Lord...
my crime, my sin stinks...
- I'm drowning in guilt.
- My soul reeks of my brother's blood...
Wash me clean...
with the rain of your mercy, My Lord!
Bereave me of all you bestowed...
All the wealth, all the power,
all the fame...
Everything ...
- Let The rain of your mercy...
cleanse me, my Lord!
Haider...
What are you doing?
- Haider...
Give me the pistol...
Do as I say...
- Haider...
Grab him...
Hold his hands...
Show me your hands...
What are you doing?
- Let go of him...
We caught him in time...
or he might have...
I didn't kill you for
you were in prayer...
Even a ghastly sinner would enter
heaven if killed in prayer.
Haider...
you have really gone insane!
Take him away...
I will kill you...
when you are in sin...
not when you are in prayer...
I'll aim my bullets at
your treacherous eyes, Khurram...
those deceitful eyes that
entrapped my mother.
I will aim my bullets
at your treacherous eyes...
those deceitful eyes that
entrapped my mother...
Move it...
Step inside.
Shoot from a distance...
And shoot him on the back.
Wake-up!
Wake-up?
Wake-up you idiot!
Take out your gun!
Watch out!
Haider don't!
We'll do as you say...
Free my hands.
Okay.
It is not my fault...
He told them everything...
He's lying!
It is not my fault...
It was all his fault...
Why are you lying?!
Darn!
Grab the gun... Quick!
Want some of this?
Chutzpah!
Run...
Run Salman, run!
Up... Salman!
Watch out!
Salman!
- Hello...
- Khurram is still alive.
- But I've killed three cops.
I heard...
Where are you now?
On the Pampore highway.
Stay on the line.
It's the doctor's son...
Send him across the border...
You'll need go across
the border for training.
Get to the graveyard
where we met first.
- We'll get in touch...
Alright.
Bye.
Hello.
Hello...
Hello Haider...
Where are you?
In the hospital?
- Haider...
There were other ways to pan...
Why did you have
to get my father killed?
God!
This is not true!
I swear upon God...
this is not true!
I'm going mother.
Where?
You're crossing the border?
It is a fatal trek..
I won't bear losing you..
At least, meet me once...
I won't stop you this time.
I promise...
- Meet me once.
Meet me once.
- My two-faced mother.
Such innocence in one face;
such deceit in the other...
We are not to be blamed
for the doctor's death
Oh! How sad to see a mother lie...
The flowers on father's grave
were still fresh...
and you rushed into
Khurram's marital bed.
The world knows you and Khurram
conspired to murder my father.
These are utter lies...
Mother...
Ikhlaq was hiding in our
house that fateful day...
only you knew that.
Khurram was an informant
for the army...
and you were his informer.
Hello.
You're home?
Then what's that shining in the sky?
I'm scared Khurram.
What happened?
Hilaal's brought Ikhlaq home today.
Ikhlaq Latif!
I had no idea that
Khurram was an informant.
I never wanted to harm
your father.
I did not hate him.
And Khurram?
How did you feel for Khurram?
Wait...
Stop the jeep...
I'll wait eagerly...
For you to be a widow again.
My angel, will you do me
one last favor?
I am tired of my wretched life...
End my agony!
Your life is your punishment.
Differentiation is
the unique element...
It is important to be unique
at something that is...
valuable to your customers...
Lakshmi, I told you not to put
any calls through...
Who?
Yes, put him through...
Hello...
You're equally responsible
for this death...
Despite everything ...
you went to see him...
without telling me...
Your son has crossed over
to the other side...
He's become a bloodthirsty animal.
Yes... but at least
he's not a snake in the grass.
Where is Haider?
- Liyaqat... calm down.
Where is he?
Wherever he is...
he will not survive.
I won't stop till
I put him in a coffin.
Both of them had
guns in their hands...
If Haider wouldn't
have fired first...
Pan/ez would have.
Everyone wants to kill him.
I know he won't make it
The doctor's wife on the line.
Roohdaar...
- Who is this?
Ghazala...
Ghazala Meer...
Oh, why don't you come...
My dearly departed ...
Where you are now...
Sleep.
Oh, why don't you come...
My tired one...
My life...
Just sleep.
Not twilight or sunset...
Just darkness, only darkness...
A nest for your soul...
So rest, just sleep.
Oh, why don't you come...
No one is deep or shallow...
No giants or dwan/es here...
In the nests of a grave...
Only the deep sleep exists...
No beds, no breakfast...
No bags, no baggage...
Only an angel's lullaby...
So sleep...
Oh, why don't you come...
Come home...
Haider...
Where have you been?
We have been waiting for you.
Dig a grave and rest...
Grandpa, Why do skulls
keep grinning?
Your skull will surely
be a brooding one.
Shut up and eat.
The dead know they never lived fully.
And it never stops with death...
Got it?
The body turns into soil...
the soil is,
turned into pots and toys...
You maybe Alexander or Akbar...
Hitler or Gandhi...
all that remains is dust.
Who knows... this flask your grandpa
is sewing tea from...
might be made of some dust
from Alexander's body...
He may have conquered the world...
but today he's sewing
tea in a graveyard.
Whose funeral is it?
A dead person's...
Will you have some tea?
Is it a woman's?
How does it matter?
Let's go and eat...
Come along, son...
Come along.
- Haider, come now...
- Haider!
Arshee...
- Haider...
Haider!
Haider...
Stop Haider... don't go there...
Listen to me...
Haider... don't go there...
They will kill you...
Haider...
Arshee...
Arshee!
- Control yourself...
- Come what may...
- the boy should live...
Get out of there now.
We have too many
weapons Zahoor...
they won't fit in the car.
Take whatever you can. Leave!
NOW!
- Zahoor... it is too late.
- Liyaqat...
Muzamil!
There's a whole battalion inside...
You said he was alone...
I didn't know, sir...
Throw a grenade...
- Brother...
- Bring the rocket launcher here!
- Rocket launcher loaded!
Fire...
Fire!
You were to fire in the middle!
- Muzamil...
Take the whole darn house down...
Yes, sir!
Load up...
Loaded, sir!
What are you doing here?
Please spare my son.
I'll get him to surrender...
If you truly love me,
give me one chance.
- My angel!
My angel!
If you got so much as
a scratch as a child...
I'd tear apart the world...
You are now covered in blood and...
I can't do a thing.
Mother... I won't surrender.
Don't you want to see me
as a widow again?
Angel...
There's no greater pain...
than to see the corpse
of your child.
There is...
To die without avenging
the murder of one's father.
Revenge begets revenge...
Revenge does not set us free...
Freedom lies beyond revenge.
True freedom.
I beg you drop your weapons,
surrender... or else...
Or else?
You won't live through it?
- Mother!
Mother!
"Haider..."
"Avenge me of my brother."
"Aim bullets at those
cunning, deceiving eyes..."
"that entrapped your mother..."
"Revenge only begets revenge..."
"Avenge me..."
"Revenge does not set you free..."
"Freedom lies beyond revenge..."
Haider!
Haider! Finish me off...
Take your revenge...
Ghazala...
Brother...