Translated by 8thSin
http://fansub.d-addicts.com/User:8thSin
Winters didn't feel this cold...
when I was a child.
It's almost two weeks since I returned to Yamagata from Tokyo.
Now that I think of it, I've lead such an unremarkable life.
Please, this way.
Coming in.
My condolences.
We are here to assist you with encoffining.
May I light up the incense?
Yes.
Thank you for coming.
Looks like she's still alive.
Probably charcoal-burning suicide.
How can you tell?
The body is undamaged.
This is what happens when someone is discovered immediately after death in a cold car.
What a waste, she's beautiful.
Do you want to try?
Yes.
For the deceased's peaceful departure,
I will now commence the rite of encoffinment.
Everyone, please see her off from up close.
I will now begin the cleansing.
It has the thing.
What thing?
The thing.
You know, the thing...
Err... May I have a word with you?
Yes, what is it?
After the cleansing,
we apply makeup on the deceased...
We have different makeups for male and female...
Oh... please wait.
Yes.
Sis, which makeup do you want for Tomeo?
Men's or girl's?
Come on, which one?
If I gave birth to a girl from the start,
this would've never happened...
But thanks to someone's seed...
Girl's is fine then?
Yep.
Female's, please.
Yes.
Tomeo...
"Okuribito"
DEPARTURES
Not many in the audience again today.
Yeah, they should put more effort into advertising.
I know!
Let's make a homepage for the orchestra.
My wife's a web designer.
I'll make her do it for free.
What do you think?
More importantly, are you going to be fine?
About what?
Next, the next.
Next what?
You spent so much money on that, gotta start looking for the next one.
Good performance again, everyone.
Good work everyone.
Although the seats were empty...
I think your performances were great.
Um... actually...
today...
the owner of this orchestra, Mr. Sonezaki...
has something to tell you,
so please give him your attention.
You're... disbanded.
See ya.
I finally became an orchestra member.
But it became a past memory in a flash.
This cello is innocent.
Only because it was bought by a loser like me,
it lost its job.
In many ways...
this cello was too heavy for me.
Thank you very much.
Please cook it immediately.
Yes.
Good bye.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
She gave me an octopus.
I just happened to see our neighbor.
They just caught it this morning.
What's wrong?
Disbanded.
What is?
My orchestra.
I see...
You just have to find the next one.
There won't be a next one.
Someone with my skill level can only go so far...
and there's the debt for this cello.
How much?
Don't worry, if it's just around $10,000...
I can pay it back with my job.
$180,000.
$1... $180,000?
Pros all spend that much...
it's relatively cheap.
Why did you hide it from me?
I knew you'd be against it.
Why didn't you tell me...
about something so important?
I'm sorry.
I'll make dinner.
"All the cities around the world are our new homes.
Let's live together on a musical tour."
Those were the words of my marriage proposal.
But the reality is harsh.
No, I should've realized the limit to my talent a lot sooner.
What happened?
This octopus is alive!
You're right. It's alive.
Hey, Dai...
what should we do?
Don't get caught again.
Huh?
I think I'll quit.
Quit what?
Cello.
What will you do then?
Go back to the countryside... in Yamagata.
I vote yes!
Huh?
You don't mind?
Well, the house your mom left you...
we don't need to pay rent, right?
But you really don't mind?
Yes.
This is a wonderful instrument.
I thought it was the greatest turning point of my life,
but for some reason, I felt relieved the instant I let go of the cello.
As if I was suddenly released
from being tied up.
What I believed to be my dream...
was probably not my real dream.
The only thing my mother left me,
when she died two years ago.
I've been told my father ran the cafe at first,
but I have almost no recollection of it.
After he left home for another woman,
my mother ran this small cafe,
and raised me alone.
Meal's ready.
Okay.
I thought you would hate the countryside more.
No, it's kind of refreshing.
I don't know if it's because of the water here, but the rice tastes better too.
Really?
Oh, maybe I'll start a shop.
What will you sell?
This is it!
This, this one!
No age limit, high salary?
In addition, short actual working time?
As a full-time employee!
"NK Agent"? What kind of company is that?
"A job that helps out journeys."
A travel agency?
Oh, maybe tour guide?
It says "no experience necessary".
I'll go ask for details.
Yeah.
This is it.
Excuse me.
Is this "NK Agent"?
Yes...
I'm Kobayashi, I called earlier.
Oh, you're here for the interview!
The boss will be back soon, sit here.
Yes, thank you.
I...
was against it when the boss wanted to post the ad in the newspaper.
Oh...
It's extremely hard to attract people into this industry.
Um... what does this company do?
What? You came without knowing anything?
It said to help out with journeys...
Uh... that's not what you do?
Boss, he's here for the interview.
Nice to meet you, I'm Kobayashi.
I called you this morning.
Oh, it's you.
You seem more energetic than on the phone.
Thank you.
See? It was a good idea.
Pour some tea.
Yes.
I brought my resume just in case.
Okay, sit down.
Thank you.
Can you put in lots of hours here?
Huh? Uh... yes.
You're hired.
Eh?
What's your name again?
It's Kobayashi Daigo.
Order his business cards right away.
Got it.
W... wait...
We haven't discussed anything... salaries and other things...
Oh, right.
Let's start with one hand.
"One hand"?
$500?
$5000.
$5000?!
Too little?
Not at all, I can get that much?
I don't mind paying you in cash, daily.
No, wait, what kind of work will I...?
Let's see...
As my assistant at first.
Exactly what...?
To be exact...
encoffining.
Encoffining?
A job that places the corpse into the coffin.
It's starting to bloom!
Corpse as in dead people?
You ask funny questions.
No, uh, um...
The job posting said helping out journeys.
I assumed it was a travel agency...
Oh, this is a misprint.
Misprint?
Not "helping out journeys", it's...
"Helping out peaceful departure".
Departure?
So "NK" stands for "NouKan" (Encoffining).
Anyway, it must be some kind of fate.
Just give it a try.
You can quit if it doesn't suit you.
This is for today.
No, I can't...
Don't worry!
No...
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Here.
Where did you get this?
You said you wanted to eat sukiyaki from here, right?
Yonezawa-beef?
The highest-grade sirloin.
Wow! Was it expensive?
I got paid in advance.
You got the job?
Kind of, yes.
Great! Let's celebrate today.
Sure.
So, what kind of job was it?
Tour guide after all?
Not really...
Sales?
What's the matter?
It wasn't a travel agency.
Oh? What was it?
Ceremonial event-related...
Like a wedding hall?
Yeah.
They might make you play the cello again!
I'll make sukiyaki right away.
Okay.
This is great! Looks tasty.
I don't think I'll come back that late.
Get going.
Bye.
Morning.
Hello.
Use the boss' table until the new one arrives.
Your business cards are ready.
No misprints.
Are these that uncommon?
This is my first time seeing a real one.
First time?
Yes.
My grandparents passed away before I've grown up,
and my mother passed away while I was abroad.
She was already in her grave when I got back.
What about your father?
He left home for another woman when I was 6.
Your mother must have been lonely.
But...
I wonder if someone like me who has never even seen a dead body before...
can really do this job?
You'll get used to it!
To dead bodies?
Yeah.
The weather is nice lately, so we're not very busy...
but change of season...
Do you need help?
...will be very busy for us.
Where does work come from?
Funeral homes.
Funeral homes?
Yes. Encoffining...
used to be done by family members.
Eventually it was passed to funeral homes,
then companies like ours appeared.
In short, it's a super-niche industry.
It's pretty heavy.
There are many kinds of coffins.
$500, $1000, $3000.
They differ by that much?
The left one is plywood, the next one has metal fittings and carvings on both sides.
And the most expensive one is solid cypress wood.
Oh, the difference is in material and decoration.
Yes, they all burn the same way.
Same ashes.
The last shopping of your life is done by others.
Kind of ironic.
Right.
Yes, this is NK Agent.
Yes, he's here.
Yes, Minato Theater?
Immediately? Okay.
Is that the boss?
A job.
A job?
Are you from NK?
Yes.
He's here.
Oh, there he is.
He's a newcomer to our company...
Kobayashi.
...his name is Kobayashi, the model for today.
Good luck everyone.
Model?
We're going to film right after you finish changing.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Get changed and makeup over there.
Makeup?
Yes.
Boss...
Don't worry. Go ahead.
Okay.
[ Encoffining Manual ]
...first apply cotton stuffing and cleansing.
Followed by...
The model is coming out!
Not bad.
Um... who's going to see this video?
Don't worry,
it's a corporate DVD, so nobody will see it.
In encoffining,
we first perform cotton stuffing and cleansing.
Cleansing symbolizes the ridding of this world's fatigue, pain, and lust...
and also symbolizes the first bath for a new birth.
Traditionally, a washtub was used for cleansing,
but for sanitary reasons,
nowadays, we use sterilized cloths...
to wipe...
the body.
Clothing ritual is performed to maintain the dignity of the deceased.
Making sure the deceased's skin cannot be seen by the relatives...
we perform it with utmost care.
After the preparation,
we shave the face before applying makeup.
Males in particular experience shrinking of muscle and dry skin,
it seems as if they have a long mustache,
so we shave them thoroughly.
The skin of the dead gets damaged easier than you might think.
Sometimes the skin peels off just by touch.
Therefore,
we perform it with caution and care...
Ow!
What the...
Ow, ow!!
Uh, oh.
Ow, it hurts, it hurts!
Uh, oh...
Ow, ow!
Don't worry, don't worry.
It's not so bad.
Welcome home.
I'm home.
What is it?
What happened to your face?
My boss pushed me while I was shaving.
You were shaving at work?
Yeah.
You only use electric shavers at home...
I had no choice, the boss ordered me to do it.
Don't worry, it's not so bad.
Weird company.
No kidding.
Weird...
weird company.
The first job came without a warning.
Um...
what should I do?
For today...
you just have to watch.
Okay.
But man...
we hit a bad one.
Huh? What do you mean?
Never mind.
Well, you'll see.
Don't scare me like that!
Thank you for waiting.
Thanks for coming.
Where is the body?
An old lady living by herself... dead for two weeks.
The body is badly deteriorated. Be careful.
See you later.
Who is he?
From the funeral home.
Our employer.
Let's get started.
It stinks!
Ugh.
This way.
Eh?
Help out a little.
Yes.
Hold her feet.
Her feet!
Yes.
You said I only have to watch...
Slowly... gently...
Come on, hold them!
Yes.
Wait, wait...
You can go home for today.
It was a bit too intense for the first job.
Really? Let's go today.
- Yeah sure!
Hey, did you eat something weird?
No.
Something smells.
Must be your scarf!
No way!
That guy wearing black, he smells!
Ah! It's still here!
Leave it over there.
Yes.
$3.
Okay. Thanks.
Towels for $1.
Okay.
You can get a lot of money for this place right now.
I refuse to quit.
Leave already.
I just want the best for you.
You talk just like a civil servant!
I'm not so old that you need to worry about me!
Right? Shiori?
Can I come for the big bath again?
Yes, of course!
For you,
grandma will work hard!
Daigo...
Yamashita.
When did you come back? You could've at least contacted me!
Sorry, I've been busy.
Oh! You're Dai from Kobayashi's cafe.
Yes, it's been a long time.
It sure has been!
I hear you have an amazing job!
Huh? Well... yes...
What is that instrument called?
Cello, that monster-sized violin.
Right, cello!
He's a great man.
He plays an instrument called cello in Tokyo!
Wow!
If only my son was as talented as he is!
Mom...
Sorry, we're having a little argument here.
Next time...
Sure, next time.
Bring your wife here next time.
You're married, right?
Yes.
This place is very peaceful without this fool.
Which fool gave birth to this fool?
Anyway, I have no intention of selling this place!
Oh, I got it!
Did you figure it out?
Yes, I finally figured it out.
Something happen at work?
No.
Let's eat!
Yeah.
Let's eat...
Our neighbor gave it to me.
Oh.
It was just slaughtered this morning, so it's really fresh!
She said we can even eat it raw!
Maybe we should wait a little longer.
Hey...
Are you ok?
Are you alright?
What's wrong?
Dai, you're acting strange...
Hey, come on, Dai...
Hey, you're embarrassing me.
Not here...
Dai?
Hey, wait...
Mika...
What exactly...
am I being tested for?
Is this my punishment for not seeing my mother off?
What will happen to me?
Strangely, thinking about it made me want to play the cello.
I simply wanted to play the cello while reminiscing my past.
It's so small...
Salmons?
Ah, yes.
They're right by the rocks... over there.
Oh! Go for it!
It's kind of sad... to climb only to die.
Why work so hard if you're going to die anyway?
I'm sure they want to go back...
to their birthplace.
Let's go for lunch. Lunch.
It's an order from your boss.
Is this a coincidence?
Huh?
That you happened to pass through here.
It's fate.
There's no such thing...
This is your god-given job.
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm sorry, sorry, I apologize.
They're angry!
Come on, Mr. Sasaki!
Sorry.
You're late.
It's 5 minutes past already!
I apologize.
You people make a living from the dead.
Brother...
Hurry up, damn it.
I sincerely apologize.
Is there a lipstick your wife liked to use?
What?
To revive a cold body,
and grant eternal beauty.
It was calm and precise.
And more than anything, it was filled with affection.
To be present at the last farewell, and send off the deceased.
It was tranquil, and every action seemed elegant.
Thank you very much.
Please allow me to close the lid.
Naomi...
Excuse me...
I'm sorry about earlier today.
No, it's our fault.
Please take these.
Thank you.
That was...
the most beautiful she's ever been.
Thank you so much.
It's nothing.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Ah! Don't tell me...
Yes, she's my wife.
Wow!
Nice to meet you.
You've caught a pretty one!
It's not a big deal!
Take your time and warm up.
Yes, thank you.
Good evening.
Oh, hello.
Do you always come here?
I've been coming here for more than 50 years.
Oh! Maybe I've seen you before...
Hot baths like this are pretty nice too.
They use groundwater heated by firewood.
The water feels soft.
That's why it doesn't sting even though it's hot.
I see.
It's the best bath house in Japan!
Right.
See you again, Tsuyako.
Thank you, come again.
Would you like me to help?
It's bad karma to get help from the customer!
You do everything by yourself?
Yes, my husband died a long time ago.
My son who works at a government office
tells me I should sell this place so they can build a condo here...
but my current customers would be in a fix.
As long as I'm still healthy...
Come on, you're still young.
Give him your support.
What?
Dai is too kind.
He keeps everything to himself.
When his parents split up too...
He never cried in front of his mother.
He cried when he was alone in the bath.
So hard his shoulders shook from crying.
He's like that sometimes. Please be understanding.
Yes.
How's the water today?
Hmm... so-so.
Oh, shush!
That's great. It looks good on you.
It's all white!
It's going to get cold starting tomorrow!
Give it to me.
Thanks.
Hey, wanna go for a drink?
Oh, right! I know a nice bar.
Really? Let's go!
(With dialect) "Let's go".
Let's go?
Let's go.
Let's go!
It's good!
It's been a long time since we've drunk together like this.
It's like a scene from an enka (traditional Japanese song).
Your mother listened to this kind of music?
They must all be my father's.
Oh, right.
It started out as your father's cafe.
I don't even want to think about him.
Actually, I don't even remember his face.
Don't you want to see him?
Nope.
But... if I did...
If you met him?
I'd knock him out.
It's my father's favorite.
I think...
your mom loved your dad the whole time.
No way.
Otherwise she would've thrown out all the records.
She wouldn't have sorted them.
Yes?
I want you to go right away.
What? Now?
Yes, someone hung himself in the Star Hotel by the station.
What about the boss?
He just left for another client.
Please go by yourself today.
Okay?
Okay.
Have a good day.
Thanks.
Good morning.
Morning. Thanks for last night.
The police officer was impressed.
Because of your young age.
I gave it everything I've got.
I see.
It's really cold today.
Yeah.
Here.
Thank you.
Bloodyshot eyes! Didn't get any sleep?
This job is mentally draining.
How did you end up in this job, Ms. Uemura?
Thanks for the tea.
A lot happened when I was young.
I couldn't stay over there...
Where?
Hokkaido.
None of my past jobs lasted.
I just happened to end up in a cafe in this town.
But the owner had a cerebral hemorrhage...
and died all of a sudden!
Then, our boss came...
That was when I witnessed encoffining for the first time.
Made me think...
when I die, I want this person to do it for me.
He's completely different from others.
That's how I ended up here.
Fate plays funny tricks on people.
Never know what'll happen.
You're right.
Tastes great.
Hey, Yamashita.
Is he a friend of yours?
Good afternoon.
You don't have to greet him.
Honey...
Go on. I'll catch up.
There's a rumor going around.
About what?
It's none of my business, but find a proper job!
Let's go. Come.
I'm home.
Mika?
Mika...
What's wrong?
...make sure the relatives cannot see the cotton stuffing taking place...
At times, we may need to stuff the anus as well.
Roll up the cotton like this, and...
push in all the way inside the anus to prevent an outflow of body fluid.
What's this?
You looked through my desk without my permission?
That's not the issue.
I just happened to be a model for this...
I found out about your job too.
So... what?
Why didn't you tell me?
You would've been against it...
Of course! Doing this kind of job...
aren't you ashamed of it?
Why should I be?
Because I touch dead people everyday?
I just want you to have a normal job.
What's normal?
Everyone dies.
I'll eventually die, and so will you.
Death itself is normal.
I don't care about the philosophy of it!
Just quit the job now.
Please.
I've never complained until now.
When you wanted to quit the cello...
and when you said you wanted to come back to the countryside...
I followed you with a smile.
Of course, I was actually sad.
But...
because I love you...
So please...
just this once,
do what I ask.
And if I said no?
Can you work in this job for rest of your life?
I'm going back to my parent's home.
Come and get me after you quit your job.
Mika...
Don't touch me!
Filthy!
It's wrong.
Huh?
My daughter didn't look like this.
Her hair color is wrong...
it's all wrong!
That's how she look like!
What are you doing?!
It's all wrong.
Redo it.
Yes.
Why are you saying this now?
This only happened...
because you didn't raise her properly!
You don't have to say it like that.
What did you say?
You also never paid any attention to her.
Who the hell do you think you are?
You got her on the damn bike,
and you ended up surviving!
Aren't you ashamed?
Stop.
Stop, stop.
It's you!
Leave.
It doesn't change the fact that it's your fault Miyuki died.
Can you make up for it?
Huh?
Can you take that guy's job for rest of your life and make up for it?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
The boss will be sad to hear that.
What?
He really liked you.
He did?
Yeah! You're our first ever employee!
The interview was very simple despite that.
He always acts on his instincts!
He said he felt something in you.
But still...
Sorry, but please talk to him in person if you want to quit.
He's upstairs.
Excuse me.
Come on in.
Okay.
What have you been eating?
What?
Your wife hasn't come back yet, right?
Yes...
Eat here.
It's probably better than your wife's cooking.
Let's eat.
What's this?
Blowfish milt.
It's best grilled, with salt.
That's my wife.
Passed away 9 years ago.
All married couples are eventually separated by a death,
but it's tough being the one left behind.
I dressed her up, and sent her away.
My very first client.
I've been working in this business ever since.
This too...
This is a corpse too.
The living eat the living to live.
Right?
These plants are an exception.
You have to eat if you don't want to die.
If you're going to eat, might as well taste good.
Tasty, isn't it?
It sure is.
Yeah it is... sadly.
It's almost two weeks since I returned to Yamagata from Tokyo.
Now that I think of it, I've lead such an unremarkable life.
Will I really be able to make a living with this job?
Do you want to try?
Yes.
Slowly, lower from the head.
Tomeo...
Good bye.
Thank you.
We've been doing nothing but argue since Tomeo started dressing up like that...
I haven't looked straight into his face for a long time.
But... seeing him smile made me think...
ah... he really is my child.
Even if he looks like a girl...
he really is my child!
Thank you so much!
Tastes great!
Is it tasty?
...Sadly.
Did you bring the cello?
Really? I want to hear!
I'll play a little bit.
It's my first time listening to a cello live.
You were in an orchestra too, right?
Yes, but it went out of business right away.
How long have you been playing?
Ever since I was in kindergarten.
Wow, for that long?
This is also a children's cello...
my father forced me to learn to play this.
Your father had a fine taste.
He's the worst father ever.
He ran a small cafe,
but he ran away with a waitress, never came back.
He really was the worst father ever.
I wonder what he's doing now.
Who knows, probably already dead.
Well, what should I play?
Let's see...
something Christmassy.
Yeah.
Uh... will different religions bother you?
Don't worry.
Buddhism, Christian, Islam, Hindu...
we handle all religions here.
Then,
for the Holy Night...
Yes, this is NK Agent.
Thank you always for your business.
Yes, tomorrow.
The name of the deceased is...
I will now prepare for her last journey.
Gently cover her toes...
Um...
My grandma said she wanted to wear loose socks.
Okay.
Grandma,
bye-bye.
Thank you for everything, grandma.
...in the name of Jesus Christ...
Amen.
Boss has aged a lot!
Thank you, honey.
Mika!
You haven't been cleaning this place?
Occasionally.
You're lying, you haven't even cleaned once.
I cleaned twice.
That's not "occasionally".
You're a mess without me, as I thought.
I have something to report too.
What is it?
I'm pregnant.
Wow...
I'm going to be a father?
So please start getting your life together.
Can you proudly tell your child about your job?
I'm sure it'll lead to bullying.
I don't care about money. Let's just live happily together.
Yes, hello?
What? Now?
What?!
Okay. I'll be there right away.
You're going to work at a time like this?
Lady at the bath house...
passed away.
She's my wife, Mika.
She collapsed while carrying firewood...
and passed away.
She was working 'til the very end.
It'll be lonely around here,
without this bath house.
Please wipe her face one by one,
and bid her farewell one last time.
Mom...
Mother...
Shiori.
This is good-bye to your grandma.
Mother...
Thank you for everything.
This is where you work?
Everyone, please see her off with a prayer.
Please allow me to close the 'window'.
Thank you...
see you again.
Can I witness the last moment of my mother?
Thank you.
I guess people get a hunch about these things.
Last winter, the two of us had a little Christmas party.
I didn't expect her to celebrate it at this age.
But...
she said she wanted to have one no matter what.
We bought a small cake, lit up the candles...
and celebrated together.
Then, out of the blue...
she asked me to help her with the firewood.
This must have been what she meant.
I'm good at burning things.
Working here for a long time makes me think...
that death... is a gateway.
Death doesn't mean the end,
but leaving the present, heading for the next stage.
Truly a gateway.
As a gatekeeper,
I've seen off many people.
"Have a nice trip,
see you again", I would say...
Mom...
I'm sorry, mom...
I'm sorry, mom.
I'm sorry.
Mom...
I'm sorry, mom.
What are you doing?
This is it!
Here.
What?
Stone-letter.
"Stone-letter"?
In the ancient times,
before humans invented writing...
they searched for the stone that resembled their feelings,
and gave it to another person.
The person who received the stone,
read the other person's feelings by the weight and texture.
For example, smooth texture symbolizing a peaceful mind,
and rough texture symbolizing a concern for others.
Thank you.
What did you feel?
It's a secret.
That's a wonderful story.
Who did you hear it from?
My old man.
Does that mean... that big stone too?
Yes, I got it from my father.
I never knew.
"Let's give each other stone-letters every year", he said...
yet that was the only time.
Such a lousy father!
Can you play everyday for the unborn baby?
Sure.
What a nice weather.
Good afternoon.
Is this the Kobayashi residence?
Yes.
A telegram for Ms. Kazuko.
What...?
Is she no longer here?
No, uh... my mother-in-law passed away two years ago.
Really? Oh...
Excuse me, can I see it?
You're not supposed to...
[ Kobayashi Hideki. Time of death: 7:30 of the 18th,
please come and collect his body... ]
I'm back, sorry for taking so long.
Daigo, you forgot to take your cell phone.
What? Oh... it's back home.
Sorry.
Father passed away.
Whose?
Yours.
What do you mean?
... is what they told me when I called the Yurahama Fishing Association.
Our address was in his belongings.
But I don't even know him...
I haven't seen him in more than 30 years!
And the person he ran away with can take care of him.
It seems he was alone the whole time.
He'll be cremated tomorrow morning.
It seems his body is in their assembly hall.
Anyway, we're no longer legally related...
tell them I can't sign the documents.
Thanks.
Dai...
Please go for him.
Don't worry about it.
Please, I'm begging you.
I...
abandoned my son in Hokkaido.
He was 6 years old.
I fell in love with someone...
"Mommy, mommy"...
he cried, but...
I shook off his small arm, and left home.
Your son...
Of course I want to see him, but... I can't.
Why not?
Just go see him if you want to.
Do all parents who've abandoned their child act like that?
Then you're all too irresponsible!
Please, go for him.
Go and see his last appearance.
Dai...
Boss...
Hey...
Take one you like.
Go ahead.
He was already dead when I showed up this morning.
I was surprised.
I don't know where he came from,
but he came to this town by himself.
He worked very hard at the port.
So I let him live in this shack.
I see...
He was a quiet man...
I'm glad someone from his family showed up.
People from the funeral home will be here soon.
Okay.
He's your father.
I'm ashamed to admit...
I don't recognize...
his face.
That he looked like this...
It doesn't even ring a bell.
What was this man's life?
He lived for 70-odd years...
Only to leave a cardboard box behind.
He's here.
Thanks.
Excuse us.
Can I take him now?
Let's just toss him in.
Yeah.
Um...
Yes?
May I?
No, we can do it.
Just give him a drink after we place him into the coffin.
Ready...
What are you doing?
My husband is...
an encoffiner.
Father...
He's my father.
Translated by 8thSin
http://fansub.d-addicts.com/User:8thSin
Motoki Masahiro as Kobayashi Daigo
Hirosue Ryouko as Kobayashi Mika
Yamazaki Tsutomu as Sasaki Ikuhei
Yo Kimiko as Kamimura Yuriko
Yoshiyuki Kazuko as Yamashita Tsuyako
Sasano Takashi as Hirata Shoukichi
Scriptwriter: Koyama Kundou
Music: Joe Hisaishi
Beauty Director: Tsugei Sao
Cello performer, director: Kashiwagi Hiroki
Director: Takita Youjirou