CELL 211
Valuable objects
are checked in here.
It avoids stealing
among inmates.
They must also turn in cell phones,
belts, blades, razors...
Anything the guard considers
dangerous is removed.
- Shoelaces too?
- Yeah.
You wouldn't believe
what they do with shoelaces.
Scary?
Don't worry,
you'll get used to it fast.
You'd better. These bastards
end up getting out,
but you have to spend
your whole fucking life here.
You can see it's in fucking shambles.
All they do is patch it up.
We have to wait until
they finish the new center.
The yard is obligatory
from 9 AM until lunchtime.
They have a blast out there.
Playing soccer,
dealing stuff...
They've got it made.
In any case,
these are the calmer ones.
We keep the big shots apart.
We call this patio the strip.
The only air a DSS ever breathes.
"Designated for Special
Surveillance."
Murderers, jail breakers,
psychopaths...
The best of every home.
We used to mix them with
the others in the cell block,
but they'd go berserk over nothing.
They run the show in here.
Many have AIDS and years left to
serve, so they don't give a fuck.
Nothing will happen to them
if they cut you, so why hold back?
It gives them status
with the other inmates.
Julian, this is Juan, the new guy.
He starts tomorrow.
Nice to meet you.
Why is he here?
He was bored
so I'm showing him around.
- Don't scare him too much.
- No.
- Bye.
- They're artists.
What is it?
Worse than a musket.
It'll blow a hole right through you.
A piece of pipe
and a spring to fire it.
- Can they get powder?
- They can get anything.
If you've got the dough,
you can have sushi delivered.
How do they get it in?
Family members
during personal visits,
other stuff we get for them...
To find out what's going on,
get in good with one of these boys.
That's how we came across
the musket.
A Colombian named Apache
gave it to us. You'll meet him.
We let him do his thing
and he tells us what's up.
Listen, Juan.
Never trust any of them.
Never forget where you are,
and look them in the eye.
Never let them see you're scared.
In the eye, but watch their hands.
They're like magicians.
Nothing here, nothing there...
and presto.
A nice little spoon.
- Holy shit!
- Damn!
Fuck!
It broke through the net.
- You all right down there?
- We're fine!
Just a close shave!
Kid, are you okay?
- What's wrong?
- Shit, you're bleeding.
Let's take him to the infirmary.
No, let's take him to cell 211.
It's empty.
Why didn't we take him
straight to the infirmary?
I don't know.
Who could have imagined
what was going to happen?
Hey, Malamadre!
Stroll's over!
Everything okay down there?
We're fine!
Just a close shave!
German, get the doctor.
Juan, stay calm.
Look at me. Juan.
Look at me, kid.
Come on.
Look at me, Juan.
Look at me.
Juan...
Juan, look at me.
Don't close your eyes.
Don't close your eyes!
They're taking the block!
We have to go!
Juan!
They'll kill us, come on!
We can't leave him!
Come on, let's go!
Please!
- Is the block sealed?
- Completely.
Even the security area
is locked down.
Did everyone get out?
Except Julian,
he was watching the strip.
Okay, we screwed up.
We have to locate Malamadre.
I'll bet anything he's behind this.
And he has a hostage.
He has 2.
Where did you come from?
Fucking shitty prison guards!
I'll slit your throats and rip off
your balls, you bastards!
Pincho!
Pincho, where's Malamadre?
Downstairs in the shop
with Tachuela and Apache.
Watch cell 211 for me.
Make sure nobody goes in or out.
Nobody!
His name is Juan Oliver.
He's 30 years old, married...
He starts work on the first.
- That's tomorrow. What's he doing here?
- He wanted to see how things work.
This will give him an idea.
How could he get left inside?
That's what I'd like to know.
Come on,
let's go.
They're waiting for you.
Who?
Fuck you!
Get outside!
Out!
Go on!
Get out there!
Fucking move it!
He's with Pincho and Releches.
Trouble.
Those 2 do anything
Malamadre says.
Come on, damn it!
And the cameras in the basement?
They've smashed them all.
We have to go in.
We can't. We have to wait
for the SWAT team.
And get them killed,
like Medina 2 years ago?
We have weapons
for emergencies.
They're only for self- defense.
Or that of a co- worker.
I'm sorry,
but it's either them
- or us.
- What if they take a gun off us?
Armando's right.
We have to wait.
Malamadre, here's the guy
I told you about.
Where did you come from?
From 211.
That cell was empty.
Not anymore.
Why are you bleeding?
I got roughed up.
So, the guards beat you up
your first day.
You must have pissed them off.
Well...
I do my best.
Hear that,
Tachuela?
- He did his best.
- They wasted no time.
Besides ball- busting,
what are you in for?
First degree homicide.
- How much they give you?
- 19 years.
- You're probably innocent.
- No.
I killed him and I'd do it again.
I don't buy it.
Why not?
Because you don't look like a
killer. You wouldn't hurt a fly.
So you're the prison shrink.
He's pushing his luck.
Though I wouldn't mind spending all day
in a white robe handing out valium.
One for you, one for me!
Utrilla probably had
a lot of fun with him!
Put it out and strip down.
What?
Take off your clothes.
What for?
Mostly because I fucking said so.
Lose the shirt!
Don't be shy!
Go on!
Cutie pie!
Gorgeous!
He's got nothing on!
Nothing?
Look at that thing!
You're gonna love it here!
Hey, Bubba!
You've got competition!
Turn around, let them see you.
Somebody's gonna get quite
a mouthful!
How many have you strangled,
Superman?
Okay, that's enough.
You've all had a little fun.
Back to your business.
Everybody out.
You'd better watch out. You could win
a beauty contest in here with that.
Who would ever undress
in front of all these fags?
Apache.
Listen up.
Have your men get rid of
the surveillance cameras.
- They've seen enough.
- Right.
- Where is my clean underwear?
- Did you check the second drawer?
I only see the ones
you gave me.
So?
I can't wear these to work.
Why not?
You said you loved them.
I do, but they're personal.
So the gentleman wants to dress fancy
for his first day of work at the prison.
Don't make fun of me.
I just think it's funny you're
worried about your underwear.
I want to make a good impression.
Then don't wear anything.
You should leave a camera.
So they can see you later on,
when you want to negotiate.
Cover it up. That way you control
what they see and what they don't.
Not bad.
You just earned yourself
some underwear.
Get this man
a clean pair of shorts. He can't go
around with his balls hanging out.
Give him yours, jerk- off.
Move!
I'd leave that one.
Which one...
Calzones?
That one.
It's Juan and he's with Malamadre.
What's he doing?
- Why's he covering the camera?
- Clever bastard!
What is it?
He's tricking them.
They think he's an inmate.
He's trying to tell us
he's fine and he's tricked them.
Okay, let's everybody
get this clear.
Nobody outside this room must know
that Juan Oliver isn't an inmate.
If word gets out and they hear
something, he's fucked.
The SWAT team is here.
I hope this kid's a good liar.
Recognize this bastard?
Look closely.
Is he the son of a bitch
who beat you up this morning?
No, it's not him.
How about that, Julian?
Today is your lucky day.
You were in for
some real punishment.
But I bet you remember
Mueco here.
Mueco sure remembers you
and your friends.
Went a little far, didn't you?
Look at him.
Look at his face,
he's a zombie.
He wasn't pretty before,
but now he looks like shit.
Wouldn't you say?
Yes.
Yes, what?
Yes, he looks like shit.
See? You insult him and
he doesn't even blink.
How many of you
were in there letting him have it?
4? 5?
You hardly fit in there.
Then 20 days in the hole.
Okay, come on.
No hard feelings.
What's done is done.
We'll just leave you two alone
for a little while
so you can talk it over.
Talking about it always helps.
Right, Julian?
Be careful.
If something happens to me,
you get nothing.
What do you think I'd get for you?
A plate of spaghetti?
They don't give a shit about you.
Don't worry, Julian.
I promise you'll have a great time
in the infirmary tonight.
Malamadre's Word.
Let's go.
Hey, Calzones.
How are you at literature?
How did you hear about it?
What did they say?
Relax, if something were up,
I'd tell you.
Okay, bye.
Shit. They talked about
the prison riot on the radio.
How do these people
find out about everything?
Some idiot always tells
his family about it.
How easy things look
from an office
in Madrid. They've decided
to teach them a lesson.
They're afraid they'll riot
once a week,
like 10 years ago.
What about Julian
and the other guy?
Nobody to negotiate?
They won't negotiate.
The order is to go in
as soon as the SWAT team
sees an opening.
Then we should warn them
about the situation.
What situation?
The inmates in cell block 4.
It's empty. They were moved
to other prisons
for remodeling.
Not all of them.
Jon Arteaga. Alias: Potolo.
Ex- member of cell in San Sebastian.
Sentenced to 1,200 years in prison
for 7 murders
and a thwarted kidnapping attempt.
Antxon Elorza, "the professor. "
Native of Renteria,
112-year-sentence.
Asier Urriticoechea.
Alias: Txiqui. 30 years old.
Sentenced to 8 years
for throwing a Molotov cocktail,
causing severe burns
to a member of the Basque police...
I'm not accusing anyone.
What I'm saying is the ETA story
wasn't us, you understand?
Hey, cut it out!
Trying to comb your way
out of here?
What should I do,
sit around waiting to get killed?
Nobody's going to get killed.
Hey, knock it off.
Quit speaking Basque.
We don't want any secrets.
Gentlemen, everybody out.
Move it!
What's he saying?
That he has 3 hostages
better than any guard.
He wants us to know
he's calling the shots.
Ernesto Almansa,
federal envoy sent to negotiate.
Jose Roca, I'm the warden.
We gave them a walkie-talkie
but they still haven't tried
to contact us.
Staging all this with the ETA
members in the middle...
He's trying to win over
his audience.
How long have we complained
to anyone who'd listen?
For years! To judges,
the district attorney, newspapers...
And what did we get?
Nothing but bullshit!
A bunch of crap!
But now, with our friends
from the north,
they're going to listen to us.
But for real.
Because this time we've got them
by the balls!
By the balls!
This was 10 years ago,
in Puerto de Santa Maria.
They should have fried
the son of a bitch.
He has nothing to lose.
He knows he'll never get out.
So he won't be easy to reason with.
The ETA members were transferred to
that cell block yesterday, the same day
they were supposed to leave.
This is no coincidence.
- What do you mean?
- They must have had
this information. And if they had
it, it had to come from somewhere.
This isn't the time
to look for those responsible.
We're about to play a game of poker
with a murderer.
We'll mark the cards, of course.
I'd like to make sure he won't know
my next move beforehand.
Conejo.
Conejo was in the cell
next to Malamadre.
Conejo's in the infirmary.
He was having cramps.
Let me talk to him.
I'll find out who tipped them off.
In this situation,
we have no choice but to try.
Utrilla.
The cure better not be worse
than the illness.
By the way,
has Juan's wife been notified?
- Hi.
One kilo of tomatoes, please.
"Demands."
See that, Tachuela?
Very good.
Did you see his handwriting?
He writes better than my last lawyer,
I never understood a word he wrote.
Right, since you can't read...
I read fucking great.
Writing is the problem.
It's like everything,
you have to do it every day...
Right, that must be it.
I can tell you're great at it.
You must work in a bank
or an office or something.
I was studying to be
a civil servant.
What kind? A cop?
Post office.
Right.
And suddenly you kill some fucker
and it all goes to hell.
- All those letters and telegrams...
- Come on, Malamadre.
Get to it.
First of all, that supervisor.
What's that fucker's name?
Benigno.
No, Maligno.
His name is Maligno.
Get rid of him.
We're sick of him giving his blessing
to all the crap they do to us.
You can't keep a man isolated
for 20 days straight
in a fucking hole with no light,
nobody to talk to...
You're even grateful
when they come and beat on you.
At least you can yell at somebody.
Personal visits.
Every 2 weeks,
not whenever they feel like it.
They pull the plug on you here
and nobody says a damn thing.
You wanna keep giving it
to your wife, don't you?
Or don't you feel like it
anymore?
What happened, you catch her
with someone and lose your head?
You must have been hot.
Otherwise I can't picture you
using a knife.
It wasn't a knife.
And it had nothing to do
with my wife.
The doctor.
No more treating people
through bars. No wonder
they mistake cancer for diarrhea.
Like Morao.
Guy was screaming all day long
his head
was bursting,
his head was bursting...
In the end he had a tumor
the size of a kiwi.
They took it out
after he was already dead.
They found him at your place,
cell 211.
Sitting there with his veins open
because nobody gave a fuck.
Morao...
This is Ernesto Almansa, the national
envoy sent to negotiate. Who is this?
Felipe Gonzalez.
You know the drill. No bullshit,
let's get this over with.
That's what we want. The sooner this
is over, the easier for everyone.
Can we speak in person?
You know where to find us.
We should meet
in the security zone.
No, no. None of that crap.
You wanna talk, come on in.
All right.
But uncover the camera
so they can see me from outside.
What, don't you trust us?
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
We know what respect means.
Sorry, but without the camera
there's no way.
Okay, you want the camera,
you got it.
How about in 15 minutes?
Fine by me.
I wasn't going anywhere.
Turn it towards the block.
That's Apache.
He controls the Colombians.
The other one is Tachuela,
Malamadre's right hand.
If he's watching that door,
there's a reason.
The hostages must be in there,
but we have to confirm it.
What a bastard.
You're head over heels.
She's got you by the balls.
What's her name?
Elena. Her name is Elena.
Elena. Is she hot?
I'm just asking,
a friend's wife is sacred to me.
She's pregnant.
We're having a kid.
Damn, that sucks!
I mean getting put in jail,
not having a kid.
We have to be careful.
You sure the new guy
can be trusted?
Can anybody?
People we know.
You guys, us...
He only just got here.
He was a dealer.
The guy I killed.
He gave my brother
some bad shit
and it did him in.
And you went after him.
That takes guts.
Fucking drugs.
When someone new comes along,
you have to keep an eye on him.
That's why Malamadre
is always with him.
He writes good.
That's great.
He can write letters
to old ladies for us.
If you want,
I can take a little stroll
and have him checked out.
Not a bad idea.
Okay.
It's showtime.
Come on.
Okay, Calzones. Frisk the gentleman
and let's get to it.
You've heard by now
this isn't my first riot,
so let's skip the bullshit,
okay?
Fine with me.
They're in the bathroom.
He's clean.
Hey, Daddy!
They couldn't send
anybody smaller?
How about it, Calzones?
He's like that song.
I married a dwarf
for a laugh...
Would you rather talk
to somebody else?
I was only joking, little man.
What are your demands?
Give him the paper.
It's all there,
in pretty handwriting.
I'll have to talk to the Ministry.
Go ahead, talk to whoever you want.
Keep the list, it's for you.
I have to see the hostages
to make sure they're okay.
Sorry, but they're taking a nap
and I'm not waking them up.
Don't worry,
we're treating them great.
- But...
- What did I say?
Didn't we agree no bullshit?
Take the list, turn around
and don't come back without
something nice to say.
Okay?
Scram.
Hold on a second.
I have a couple errands for you.
You like seafood?
We want shrimp for everybody.
Bring sandwiches, fruit
and 40 kilos of shrimp.
And 100 grams of coke and another 100
grams of speed, to keep everyone awake.
I can tell by your face
we're gonna be here for a while.
I'll see what I can do.
"I'll see what I can do."
You see, Calzones? They always say
that. "I'll see what I can do."
They never talk straight,
and then people get hurt.
You want someone to get hurt?
Certainly not.
Hey, half- pint.
Before anything,
I want this man to talk to his wife.
To his wife?
Yeah, she's pregnant
and he's worried.
Do you have to talk
to the Ministry for that?
Don't look at me like that.
It's what you wanted.
He can come with me
and use the phone.
Okay.
But if anything happens to
my friend,
we'll let the bulls run loose.
Don't worry,
nothing will happen to him.
Let's go.
He's leaving with him.
He did it.
Open the door.
Fuck!
- Fuck!
- Something happened in the block.
Close the door.
Close the door!
Turn the camera.
We can't lose sight of them.
Do it, damn it!
Go see what the fuck is going on.
Move it!
If this is a trick...
Follow him.
Son of a bitch.
You have my word
we're not behind this.
- What's going on?
- How should I know?
It's okay!
What are they looking at?
They're looking up.
Raise it.
- That stupid Elvis killed Sebas.
- So what?
I warned him!
Fucker!
Busting my balls all the time.
He asked for it.
That guy looks dead.
Yeah, he's dead.
Is he one of the hostages?
Get him inside!
Don't let them see him!
Get him inside, damn it!
Get him inside!
Is that him?
It could be.
We have to go in.
Attention all units,
we're going in.
What the fuck are they doing?
We have to get them out there!
Malamadre's the only one
who gives orders around here!
Who the fuck do you think
told me to?
4 and we go in.
4...
- They're coming in!
- Put them in front of the camera!
The SWAT team!
3...
- Move!
- The SWAT team's coming in!
2...
- 1...
- There they are.
The hostages are in the block!
Abort, abort!
Remain calm.
The operation has been aborted.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Remain calm.
They're not coming in!
Let's go! Let's go!
Calzones!
It worked out this time, but act
alone again and I'll crush you.
We've received conflicting reports,
but the deceased could be
one of the ETA members
being held hostage since this
morning. The news has sparked
an immediate reaction
in several prisons
where members of the terrorist group
are more numerous.
Of course you can quote me.
The 3 hostages are alive.
I don't know
where you heard that,
but it's completely false.
... the Basque government
has expressed concern.
More and more family members
and onlookers have gathered outside
the prison to confirm reports
that one inmate has died and several
others have been injured.
The only new information we have is
an ambulance entered 5 minutes ago
but that's all we know.
You son of a bitch!
You're trying to kill me!
How did Malamadre find out about
the members of ETA? Who told him?
Who?
He locked himself
in there with him.
- How long ago?
- Half an hour, but he's in bad shape.
He wouldn't let me give him
anything for the pain.
There's an ambulance
waiting outside.
Don't worry,
I'll talk to him.
If he goes too far...
Give me something!
I can't take it anymore!
I'm dying!
I don't care if you burst
right here!
Tell me or we'll wait
until you're pissing rocks!
That's enough,
you're going to kill him.
We can hear him outside.
Besides, this is no way
to treat a human being.
What?
It isn't?
Now that you came in playing good
cop, it'll be twice as hard
to make him talk.
Twice as hard, you hear me?
Talk, motherfucker!
Talk!
Borrego.
Borrego told him.
The barber?
Yeah.
He hears about everything.
He cuts everybody's hair.
Give him an aspirin,
he earned it.
You should know I'm reporting this.
I'm sorry,
- but I can't cover it up.
- You can't?
Then why didn't you stop me?
I told you to stop.
Did that make you feel better?
Nice having me around when someone
has to stand up to these fuckers.
Armando.
A call for you in the warden's
office. It's urgent.
Go on, don't keep them waiting.
Elena?
- Yes.
- This is Armando,
I work with your husband.
Well, we met this morning.
I'm sorry, but Juan can't talk
right now. He's in another block.
I just saw the news. They say
there's a riot and people have died.
Don't believe the TV,
they always exaggerate.
There was trouble, but only in one
block and it's completely isolated.
By the way,
Juan said you're pregnant.
How far along?
6 months.
Listen, he's not answering
his cell phone.
He must have checked it in.
They don't allow cell phones
for safety reasons.
Tell her to go home.
Look, I have an idea.
Why don't you go home and when I see
Juan I'll tell him to meet you there.
- That you're worried. Okay?
- Yeah, okay.
Juan said you're getting
the apartment ready. That's great.
Anyway, take care. And don't worry,
not every day is like this.
- Talk to you later.
- Okay, bye.
Good. Very good.
When she gets home the police
will notify her. It's for the best.
See? I was right.
They love you guys.
And I thought they'd take
the shrimp thing as a joke...
If you want to laugh,
go laugh with the txakurras.
Nobody laughs at me.
Relax, we all know
you're the big murderer here.
Compared to you,
we're all amateurs.
Though you always kill
from a distance.
Boom and that's that.
I bet you're pretty courageous.
I have balls enough
to gut you right here.
If any one of you
lays a finger on us,
kiss your whole family goodbye.
You might be doing me a favor.
My only family is my cousin in
La Corua and he's a fucking prick.
Let's take it easy.
This will be over in a few hours
and we can go our own ways.
You fight your war
and we'll fight ours.
What if they don't meet
your demands?
I don't know.
What would you do
if you were me?
Stay with me. You don't have
to go in until tomorrow.
I already told you.
I want to make an impression.
Show them someone responsible,
with his home, his wife,
his child...
Well, almost.
Well.
Too bad.
- What are you doing?
- Me? Nothing.
Weren't you leaving?
Yeah.
But I can go in later.
I don't have to clock in.
PRISON
Fucking Tachuela!
Always the same.
The one from the trial,
when we busted out...
Remember how hot she was?
She was amazing.
She had huge tits,
in the middle of the courtroom,
his knife to her throat...
"Oh, no! I'm going to faint!"
And this homo says,
"If you faint,
I'll cut you!"
And she says,
"No, no, I won't faint!"
I looked over and thought,
"He's feeling her up!"
He was more worried about
feeling her tits
than escaping from prison.
Fucking lawyer!
What a son of a bitch.
God damn it.
6 months of vacation
we had there.
You had longer,
they didn't catch you
for a year.
11 months and 3 days.
Know what I remember most
about those 6 months?
Drinking a beer on the beach
at La Victoria, in Cadiz.
The place was nothing special.
More crowded than Japan.
But just sitting there,
so relaxed,
with my beer...
and the sea...
- How are things down here?
- Fine.
Living it up, Malamadre.
- You've never been better.
- That's right.
The shrimp was a great idea.
Here you go.
Eat. I don't want you
to go without.
You're kidding, right?
I didn't say talk,
I said eat.
Know the joke about the 2 guys from
Bilbao who went looking for mushrooms?
No.
One of them says,
"Look, Txomin. I found a Rolex."
The other one says, "Are we looking
for Rolexes or mushrooms?"
Just like this fucking idiot
killing Sebas during the riot.
What's your fucking problem?
You think we set all this up so you
could do whatever you fucking wanted?
I should fucking kill you!
You almost screwed this up
for everybody, you dumbshit!
That's enough,
he got the point.
You think so?
He's pretty damn stupid.
Did you get the point
or you want dessert?
I got it.
I'm glad.
They're talking about us
in English!
It's Juan.
Juan Oliver, you hear me?
Check it out!
Zamora.
They're talking in English.
What are they saying?
That they're the first terrorists
ever taken hostage in Spain.
You were right, Malamadre.
We sure fucked them good!
What are they saying?
What?
Apparently they've had riots
in other prisons.
Malamadre,
I'm gonna take the TV outside.
Break the lock.
Somebody answer,
I don't have time for this.
The hostages are in 219,
you hear me? In 219,
but I don't know for how long.
They're moving them constantly.
- This is Almansa.
- Finally!
Come on.
Be careful,
it's glass!
Be careful!
Over there, in the corner.
Have you talked to Elena?
Did you tell her not to worry,
I'm okay?
Yeah, she's fine.
She's proud of what you're doing.
What are they saying?
They're talking about all the people
killed by ETA.
LIVE FROM ZAMORA
That's my sister!
That's Maria, my sister!
- That's Susi!
- Give me the remote.
Something's gonna happen.
People are nervous.
What about the injured people?
They won't tell us anything.
This will be a bloodbath if you
come in. What are you going to do?
I can't tell you that.
My life is at stake
and you can't tell me?
We're not allowed
to endanger the ETA members.
That's the agreement
with the Basque government.
Let's burn it down!
Where's the walkie?
They're preparing an entry, but only
if the ETA members are in danger.
What about me?
Why not just meet their demands
and get it over with?
It's not that easy, Juan.
If we give in now, tomorrow
this could happen everywhere.
But I'm in here today!
Can't you just give them
something
and get me the fuck out of here?
- Well?
- It's not there.
Son of a bitch!
If one of these bastards took it,
I'll fucking kill him.
Be careful,
someone will steal it.
You left it on the table.
Yes?
I'm looking for Juan Oliver.
Who?
Juan Oliver.
- Is he an inmate?
- No, he works here.
Actually he starts tomorrow
but he came in today.
- I talked to somebody named Armando.
- Armando Nieto?
- I don't know his last name.
- Hold on a minute.
Who died?
On TV they said somebody
got killed!
What's his name?
- We need to know!
- Where's my brother?
Malamadre has us all
in trouble again.
See if the motherfucker
gets us all killed. Son of a bitch!
Who did that to you?
Nobody.
Was it Utrilla?
Yes, it was him.
Would you shut up?
Don't worry, I'm not like him.
You can trust me.
I don't think I said anything.
I didn't even remember
it was him.
When did I cut Utrilla's hair?
Over 8 days ago.
Almansa.
It was Utrilla.
The barber who cuts their hair
also does guards.
He mentioned the transfer of the ETA
members and Malamadre heard about it.
Not bad.
Saving himself 10 euros on a haircut
has killed 3 people.
3?
2 more deaths in Nanclares de la Oca,
a guard and an ETA prisoner.
Emilio Dominguez Arriola
is the name of the guard
whose death has been confirmed
in the riots at
Nanclares de la Oca.
With 15 years of service, he was
transferred here 3 months ago.
As of this moment, ETA- related
prisoners have been isolated
in all prisons
as a security precaution.
You can't stay here!
You must leave the premises!
Walk in an orderly fashion
to the exit.
Hey, an ambulance is leaving!
Have Lorenzo and Matias meet me
in the stockroom.
On the double!
Step away from the ambulance!
Fuck!
What the hell are you doing
out there?
I don't know what you mean.
People are getting fucking
brutalized out there!
The riot police probably
had no choice. Don't worry.
Nothing will happen,
you have my word.
Your word isn't worth shit!
You better watch out.
Somebody asked me to find out
if you could be trusted.
And?
You can't be.
There's plenty weird about you.
Why are you telling me this?
Malamadre is over there.
I always give a man
a chance to defend himself.
Or to offer something
in exchange.
Elena!
Elena's out there!
Give me the walkie- talkie!
Give it to me, Elena's out there!
Give it to me!
Elena is out there!
Get her out of there!
What?
What the fuck are you doing?
Stop the riot police,
Juan's wife is out there.
- What's she doing there?
- I don't give a damn.
He saw her on TV.
We have to cut the signal.
Get back!
What's happening?
Can you imagine if we could be
like this forever?
I wouldn't mind.
But the baby will have
to go to school someday.
Do you realize you worry more
about the baby than I do?
You know what they say.
Children change your life.
Yeah, they say that.
But I don't want
our life to change.
Promise me it won't change, that
you'll love me and fuck me the same.
Almansa, what the fuck happened
to the TV?
A demonstrator threw a Molotov cocktail
and the antenna caught fire.
We're trying to get
the signal back.
You'd better fix it. And I want
a list of the people injured.
All right, but I'll need time.
You have half an hour.
What about Calzones's wife?
You found her, right?
Yeah, she's fine.
In any case, tell Calzones
we had her taken to the hospital
to make sure everything's okay.
Hold on, tell him yourself.
I want to talk to Elena.
I'll see what I can do.
But I don't think the doctors
want to upset her right now.
You said she was fine.
Yes, she is.
But apparently they took her in
as a precaution.
I have to see her.
I think that's the best idea.
I can have you taken to the
hospital, you'll be back in an hour.
I have to go.
No, I'm sorry, Calzones.
Not now.
You're not the only one
with people out there.
And if you hurt anybody out there,
I'll go berserk.
It's the only fucking thing
you people understand.
Don't bother.
They put up inhibitors.
One on each side of the roof,
jamming the frequency.
The fuckers are going
out of their way.
They don't want us to find out.
Something big must have happened.
Why don't you ask them?
Just take the walkie- talkie again.
Have you thought about
our conversation?
I have nothing to offer you.
What did they promise you,
faggot?
Second degree murder?
What about me?
What do I get for keeping quiet?
What?
Nothing?
I might as well
just talk to Malamadre.
Too bad for you.
Your credit has run out.
Wait.
Wait, maybe there is something.
A piece of paper.
"Weapon,
sink, cell 233."
In your handwriting.
Sound familiar?
I don't know.
Show it to me.
If you want,
we can show it to Malamadre,
see what he thinks.
Let me out.
You and me are gonna
make a deal.
Find out what really
happened out there,
and I'll give you that paper.
So you can wipe your ass with it.
These graphic images recorded
earlier have caused an uproar.
Was the police response
too severe?
Elena Vazquez Guardiola,
from Santander,
remains hospitalized in Zamora
under supervision
due to her injuries.
How was I supposed to know
she was out there?
You're the one who shouldn't
have been out there.
You're suspended from service.
And you can pack your bags.
When this gets out,
you'll never set foot
in a prison again.
If you play your cards right,
you're out in 7 years.
I'll take the wrap for this.
Just say you were
scared shitless,
that you went along.
That's what half these guys
will say.
At age 7,
a kid wouldn't even realize.
If I were you,
I'd tell Elena
never to bring him here.
The less to remind you
of the outside, the better.
I have a kid somewhere.
His mother was from Murcia.
Really feisty broad.
She had no idea
I was an escaped fugitive.
Does he look like you?
I don't know.
I hope not.
He must be 8 by now.
But I've never seen him.
"Out of sight..."
The list.
Only 4?
They were clubbing people
left and right!
Fucking bastards.
Almansa really fucked up this time.
What are you doing?
If you kill him, they'll come in.
That's all they care about.
They'll shoot their way in!
It'll be a massacre!
Tell him to leave.
If he comes in here I'll kill him!
- Calm down, Tachuela.
- Calm down my ass!
You want to be remembered as the
madman who led them to slaughter?
I don't give a shit! I told him
he'd pay if he fucked with us.
That's how it is.
Hold him.
Cut off his ear!
That'll show them we mean business.
They won't risk coming in over an ear.
Wait.
- What for?
- I'm thinking, damn it!
Fuck this shit!
Come here. Come here!
You're gonna cut off his ear.
Here.
Cut off his ear.
Cut off his ear! Cut it off!
It's the list of people injured.
Malamadre wants to see you.
What for?
Malamadre.
What faces...
What, did somebody die?
Apache found out about
the riot outside.
At least 20 people were injured
and 7 are hospitalized.
Some of them serious.
Among them, Elena.
Show him.
She shows up here.
It's poor quality,
copied from the news.
They said her name is
Elena Vazquez Guardiola.
That's Elena, right?
That's a guard, Utrilla.
They call him the Old Bitch.
The Old Bitch!
He always liked hitting people.
I want him to see him.
Utrilla!
Call from upstairs.
They want to see you.
All I've done is string them along.
They don't trust me anymore.
They can't send someone else
to negotiate?
Malamadre said no. He asked for you.
He prefers somebody he knows.
Armando should go.
He's the new chief, right?
They should see
nothing has changed.
If you don't want to do it,
you don't have to.
Officially you've been suspended.
We'll talk about that later.
Happy with yourself, asshole?
Nice mess you've made.
Like my friend says,
"I do my best."
Utrilla sure has balls!
Don't move, motherfucker.
Open your mouth
and I'll kill you.
Now you and me are gonna
walk down those stairs, got it?
Where is he going?
Stay there!
They're going downstairs.
Where?
Downstairs to the basement.
Check the block.
Turn the camera!
- Turn it.
- Quickly.
Turn it, turn it, hurry up.
They're gone.
Shit, it's empty. It's a trap.
It's a fucking trap!
We have to get Utrilla
out of there.
I'm calling the Ministry.
We need authorization.
No, no.
There's no time for that.
Say the word and I'll go in.
I'm sorry,
I can't make that decision.
Maintain your position.
- What was that?
- Maintain your position.
The Old Bitch.
His wife is the one
you beat up out there.
- I didn't see her coming.
- A pregnant woman?
I didn't have time to react.
It was an accident.
Leaving her there
was an accident?
You clubbed her
and left her there.
See it?
Now do you see it?
Piece of shit!
Take it easy, damn it.
- What happened to Elena?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
They took her to the hospital,
that's all I know.
You didn't even ask about her?
Bullshit! Look at me.
Look at me! Look at me.
Tell me the truth
or you're dead.
If she'd been badly hurt,
I would be suspended at home.
I want to talk to her.
I need her to tell me she's okay.
Here.
Tell him if Elena
doesn't pick up the phone,
we'll kill him.
That'll get their attention.
I want to talk to Elena!
Juan, this is Armando.
Do you remember me?
Yeah, I remember you.
Listen to me, Juan.
Elena can't talk to you
right now.
She's been sedated.
You're lying to me, damn it.
You're lying to me too!
Calm down, let me explain...
She can't be sedated,
she's pregnant!
Unless she lost the baby.
Is that it?
Did she lose the baby?
If she lost it,
tell me already.
That's it, right?
You're afraid to tell me. That's
why you've been lying all along!
Look, Juan.
You'd better come out.
Tell Malamadre
to let you come see Elena.
I already asked him
and he said no.
Yeah, but now it's different.
Why?
She isn't dead, is she?
Elena isn't dead...
I'm sorry, Juan.
I truly am.
We just got the news.
We wanted to wait until
all this was over with
to explain what happened to you.
Get the fuck off me!
He's a guard!
Calzones is a guard!
Get off him! Get off him!
Get off him!
Calzones is a guard!
Look me in the eye, damn it!
He's not an inmate!
He tricked you!
He lied to you all!
He's a guard, damn it!
Tell them, Calzones!
Tell them who you are! See if they
still feel sorry for you!
Tell them, damn it!
Tell them!
Tell them...
A smart girl like you,
so pretty, and me...
You being so ugly and dumb...
First a slaughterhouse,
now a prison.
It's not like I'm an engineer.
You could have anybody.
Somebody who could
give you stuff.
I don't want stuff.
I want you.
MY FUCKING HEAD HURTS
SICK, SICK, SICK...
MORAO'S HEADACHE
KILLED HIM HERE
CAR BOMB IN MADRID
ETA RESPONDS TO RIOT IN ZAMORA
What about what Utrilla said?
- I don't give a fuck what he said.
- What if it's true?
- What about this?
- Leave it there for now.
- What did Apache say?
- He didn't find anything.
He had the guts
to kill that fucker.
He's up to his neck in shit
just like everybody else.
Hello.
Ernesto Dueas.
I've been sent directly by the
President to find a solution.
A bit late, no?
Excuse me?
If they'd been on the ball
we might not still be here.
You're probably right.
This situation should have been
handled differently.
I have full authority
to make a deal.
We studied your requests
before coming
and we're in a position
to concede in most cases.
We'd have to discuss
certain details.
It's Utrilla.
A prison guard.
I'm responsible for his death.
You're Juan.
My name is Juan Oliver
and this is only the beginning.
Meet our demands or
we'll kill all 3 hostages.
They'll be dead before the SWAT team
can get to them, just like him.
He says they'll meet our demands.
We just need to work out
a few details.
And what will happen after that?
Your conditions will improve.
For how long?
I don't understand.
How long before you go back to doing
whatever you want with us?
All they want
is to stop this and lock us up
before anyone notices.
We're trash,
and what you do with trash
is take it out
so it doesn't stink.
He might not be the right person
to be negotiating...
Why?
Because they killed Elena?
I might as well hang myself in
my cell and get out of the way.
I wouldn't be the first.
Do you know how the guy in cell 211
before me died?
No, I don't.
We can't trust him.
They can't be trusted!
There's only one way.
They have to commit in public.
So they can't break their word.
Make them say on TV
they'll end the DSS program.
To hell with solitary confinement!
Abolish DSS
and publicly acknowledge
all the people who have died here.
You have one hour.
We want to see the minister
on TV in one hour
saying this shit is over,
you got that?
Maybe I'd better give you
a little while to talk over
the situation.
There's nothing to discuss.
We're all behind him.
Shut down DSS
or you'll be hosing blood
off the walls!
You're a fucking dead man!
Nobody shows me up!
You know I'm right.
What did I tell you?
What?
That if you acted alone
I would gut you.
You also said this was
the chance of a lifetime.
Don't bullshit me!
You can't trick me!
You're just trying to get back at
them. Am I right?
Things are getting out of hand.
They're scared.
Why do you think they sent
a government official?
This is bigger than we imagined.
What will happen
if the hostages die?
I'll be remembered as the madman
who led everyone to slaughter.
Ring a bell?
Things have changed.
Yeah, now you don't care
if they kill us all.
You just said
in front of everyone
we're going all the way.
Are you gonna keep your word?
Are you?
Malamadre always keeps his word.
Take the hostages
up to cell 225.
Tell Releches not to let anyone in
unless I say so.
- What are you gonna do?
- Just do as I say, damn it!
- Malamadre.
- What?
We have to talk.
Almansa? I have nothing
to say to you.
We have something important
to tell you.
You know what we want to hear.
And you know it's madness.
We have to find a way out.
This better not be a trap
so you can shoot me.
If you thought it was a trap, you
wouldn't have come. Pick up the file.
It was a trick all along.
Juan isn't an inmate,
he's a guard.
He was supposed to start today,
but he got caught by the riot.
I don't believe it.
This is a trick, you bastard.
This is just paper and a photo.
What Utrilla said was true.
How the fuck do you know
what Utrilla said?
Juan isn't our only insider.
He was helping us
until his wife got hurt.
Now he's on his own. He doesn't give
a shit about anything and you know it.
Why the fuck are you
giving me this now?
What for?
So I'll kill him?
The government's offer stands.
You could be on the street
in a year, maybe less.
He tricked us.
Malamadre, he tricked us.
All of us.
That bastard tricked us all.
And now those fuckers are in trouble
and they want us to kill him.
Not even the filthiest rat in here
would betray someone like that.
That guy is the fucking rat,
Malamadre.
He lied to us
and he has to pay for it.
The problem is the others
are behind him now.
We tell everyone he's a guard,
period!
What he asked for is crazy.
They'll never do it.
These people will never
admit defeat on TV.
When they give you something,
they do it quietly, in secret.
Have they ever given you
anything?
Have they ever really
given us anything?
He's a son of a bitch, but he's
right. They're scared.
We have to go all the way.
Open up, open up!
What?
I already told you!
He's losing blood!
You have to get him out of here!
- It's almost time.
- Open up, damn it!
Fuck!
It's time.
They have 10 minutes.
They might still call.
You're right.
A lot can happen in 10 minutes.
They're here.
Alpha and Bravo distract them,
Xavi drops down from the roof
and heads for cell 225.
They might have time
to kill them.
No, there'll be no resistance
when we reach the cell.
I have to quit smoking.
Ever seen what it does
to your lungs?
All black and disgusting.
I don't think it will be
what kills you.
You're a real jerk, Calzones.
You know that, right?
I do my best.
Your best and more.
It takes a lot of balls
to do what you did.
Standing up there and telling
everyone you were an inmate.
Though things got screwed up
in the end with Elena.
Sometimes life fucks you up
and you don't even realize.
They asked me to kill you.
What did you tell them?
To go to fucking hell.
Now you and me
are going out that door
and we're gonna do
what we said we'd do.
And when the shit hits the fan,
you'd better hope they kill me quick
because if they don't,
I swear I'm gonna skin you alive.
Get that straight.
Nobody makes a fool of Malamadre.
Whatever happens,
you're not leaving here alive.
That's what you wanted, right?
If those bastards don't tell me,
you will, right?
There's no way to ever be sure.
The TV's back on!
Hey, look!
... the Ministry of the Interior related
to the violence that began yesterday
at the prison in Zamora...
It's the end of DSS!
They're coming in!
Kill the hostages!
Do it now!
There's no time!
Bullshit!
That way!
Throw them outside, damn it!
Come on, damn it!
Calzones!
God damn it!
Calzones.
Calzones, look at me.
Look at me. You're okay.
You're okay. Look at me.
Look at me!
Look at me.
Stay here, with me.
- Damn it!
- They killed Malamadre!
They killed Malamadre and Calzones!
They wish they could.
But not yet, right, Calzones?
We'll get those bastards.
We'll get those bastards good!
Motherfucker!
Yeah, that's him.
That's Juan Oliver.
The resolution of a crisis
of this sort
is never completely satisfying,
but I think, as a whole,
the final outcome
can be considered
a success.
This one's still alive!
Given the risks
and the limited
options at our disposal,
the appearance of an alternative to
a possible collaboration with Malamadre
made all the difference.
You could say
the wall had more cracks
than we at first imagined
and we were able
to exploit them in time.
On the negative side,
we mustn't forget that we were unable
to get Juan Oliver out of there alive.
Personally,
I must say I'll never
forgive myself for that.
MORAO'S HEADACHE
KILLED HIM HERE
CALZONES DIED HERE
Any more questions?