...and the "Beast of the Middle East":
"the Ayatollah"
And the Ayatollah will not let go...
...he's punishing away. Oh my goodness!
How much can this man take...?
Will he defeat him or a draw
the horns are out... Here it comes...
Ram Jam! He's done it!
One! Two! Three! It's over!
This is one for the ages: April 6, 1989.
This event will go down
in professional wrestling history...
Great show, "Ram".
Really put them over.
Here you go.
Sorry, I was sure
the gated be bigger.
But don't forget: two months,
Raw Way, legends signing.
I need you, man.
Yo, "Ram".
- Think you could,... sign this for me?
- Sure.
My first match ever was you versus
Davey Diamond at the Spectrum.
- Oh yeah.
- 1985.
- That was good.
- Yes
You were awesome.
- Appreciate it, man.
- Thanks, man.
Oh, shit.
Lenny.
Come on, Lenny.
Open up.
Goddamn, Lenny.
Ram.
Ram, wake up.
Wake up.
Who woke me up?
Come on, man.
I'll see you maniacs
in a little while.
Alright. I'll be back.
I'll be back.
I ain't going anyplace.
- Lenny.
- Yes?
Lenny, why are you doing this to me?
Youll get in when I get my money.
Oh, c'mon, Lenny, you know
Im always good for it.
Yes, you're always good for it,
that is why this happens.
Come on, brother, my back went out.
Just let me at least get my icepack.
- I cannot help you.
- Oh come on, man!
Oh, God.
Hey, Wayne, you got a second?
Not really, why?
I was wondering if you could throw me
some more hours.
What's the matter?
Did they raise the price of tights?
Funny.
Let's see what we've got.
Weekdays, I'm busy
on the weekends.
- Hi, boys!
- Hey, what's up?
- Well you're good looking, you diesel man.
- How are you?
Go to change.
Hi guys, listen up!
Where is OG?
- You are first against TDS.
- Thank you.
Second we've got Harvey Concordbey
vs. Billy the Kid and Lex Lethal.
Third, Sadie versus Daddy More.
Fourth, in Judas the Traitor
versus Rod Beckos.
Intermission.
Fifth, Kevin Mathews
versus Inferno.
Sixth, we have Suga and DJ Hyde
versus the Funky Samoans
Seven, Paul Enormous and Andy Anderson
versus Jim Powers and Papa Don.
And last but not least, for the strap,
we got Tommy Rotten versus Randy The Ram.
- All you guys got it?
- Yep. Got it.
Alright, let's do this.
Have a good time.
- Hey, Ram.
- Hey there.
- How're you doing, man?
- Hey.
I'm Tommy, we're gonna be working tonight.
I know you're Tommy, I saw you at
Pennsylvania a couple of months ago.
- Allentown.
- It was really good, you really brought it.
Thank you.
Keep working, man, you know.
People who drive the Cadillacs,
want you to politics, they run the show,
they're about abilities. You just hang in there.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
- Right?
But as far as tonight, I dunno
what you wanna do.
It had a few ideas.
I was thinking, you know,...
maybe just for the heat, I'll give you
a low blow, followed up by a bulldog.
Just bring the cheap heap, bro...
You guys can heat on us right away.
Keep the heat on us, beat the shit
out of us. Bum, bum, bum, bum.
We'll come up, we get on the ropes.
- You guys bring us both in the hard way.
- OK.
Then we got up, double-drop you,
quick patter out again.
So we're gonna really milk it tonight.
- We're gonna milk it, nice and
slow, old-school, easy. - Awesome.
Don't work his leg, man. That's,...
Everybody does that.
- Work his neck. Work his neck.
- Yo, yo, we will be working the neck.
- You will?
- Good. Oh, you work your leg?
Maybe you can make your
come-back right off there.
A splay off the ropes, then
super-kick...
and ram-jam
and we go and have a beer.
It sounds good, doesn't it?
You hang in there; you got a lot of ability.
- Alright.
- OK?
- Thank you.
- Pleasure.
And now for you, Randy "The Ram"
Come on.
Randy "The Ram"!
Be friends, alright?
Want to stop?
Do you want me to stop it?
Are you sure?
Come on!
Ram!
Use the post.
Come on, you fat piece of crap!
Get off to the rest of your likes...
And I'll beat the hell out of
each and every one of you...
You don't wanna see what it means?
I will destroy you too!
Shut the hell up!
Get up, old man.
Ram! Ram!
Ram!
Ram Jam! Ram Jam! Ram Jam!...
One, two, three.
Ladies and gentlemen, here is your winner
Randy "The Ram" Robinson.
- Randy, you popped that crowd.
- Yeah.
- Let's clean of this stuff, okay?
- Yes.
Hey, Ram. You got a sec?
Right here.
Do you realize whats coming up?
- Huh?
- On April 6.
The 20th anniversary of you and
Ayatollah at the Garden.
Yeah, well, that was long time ago.
Time fucking flies, right?
Here's what I'm thinking.
Two words:
Re Match.
Hey, man, you're all set.
Im doing this big Fanfest thing down
in Nevada that weekend.
...and I want to main-event it
with you two guys:
"Ram - Ayatollah, II"
Hey, I heard Bob's doing really good with
his used car line out in Arizona.
- I just don't see how he...?
- For this...?
Bob is going to dust off
the old turban
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, let's bring it.
Come on, guys, let's all go
take a shower together.
What's up, Ram?
How are you doing?
- What's up Big Chris? What's shaking?
- I'm alright.
Yo, man, you still have that hook-up
with that crack at your gym?
- What do you need?
- My back is killing me, Vicodin,...
whatever he's got.
- Drop by at the mansion...
in a couple of days and I'll hook you up
- You're the man, Ram!
- Hello, Ruby, how you doing, baby?
- Hey, Ram, how's it going?
Give me a cold one.
Here you go.
- Cassidy around?
- I think shes working a VIP.
I'm sorry, sweetie, we said
the other girl.
Yeah, the blondie with the belly chain.
- Yes, I know, but she's not as great...
I'm sorry, but we really
don't want you.
- How old are you anyway?
- Oh, you're like my mom, dude.
I do things your little fiances
never even dreamed of...
Yes, like graduate in 1985.
Hey, hey, hey, you are being
a little rude to the lady.
- How about an apology, huh?
- Who the fuck are you, man?
You don't talk to a lady like that.
I talk to her like that
when I wanna talk like that.
- No, no, It's okay.
- No, don't need to be talked to like that.
It's cool. It's cool.
I got it. I got it.
It's alright, guys...
Let me tell you something.
I guarantee you this lady's
100 times hotter than
any skank ass pussy
youre gonna be marrying.
- What are you...?
- What the fuck...?
Are you kidding me?!
- Fucker!
- Easy.
200 fucking bucks just walked out.
Just trying to help.
Shit, they're punks
Easy!
I'm sorry.
I'm better looking than them anyway.
I didn't mean to piss you off...
OK.
It's good to see you back.
Good to see you too.
I have not seen in a while.
How have you been?
I'm telling you, it was one
of the historic matches in history.
There's 20,000 people
and another millionand half sitting
at home watching on pay-per-view.
We're slamming the piss out of each other,
I mean, for god knows how long...
...we're both gashing... You ask any
wrestling fan, they've heard about that one.
- Million and a half?
- Yeah, it was big.
In a rematch, it could be
history all over again.
Damn, look at you! You are
really smokin baby!
Let me make an honest woman out of you.
Who knows? I'm in pretty good
shape right now.
You know, with a little luck,
this could be my ticket back on top.
You never know whos in that crowd.
That would be a dream.
Oh, Jesus, you're bleeding.
Yes, I got cut tonight.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, it's nothing.
- And they say wrestlings fake, huh?
- Fake? I'll show you fake. Look at this...
1986, Denver Coliseum
Billy BobBanjo hit me with a two-by-four.
He had a loose nail
...and it split my biceps.
Cut it the hell open...
It's better with it now.
Look at this one here.
1988 Orlando, Civic Center
Mr. Magnificent threw me
over the top ropes,
landed on my shoulder,
cracked my clavicle way in half.
Oh, God. Did it hurt?
I hurts you when I breathe, but, I mean,
you get the roar of the crowd,...
you just, you just,
put it through, you know...
"He was pierced for our transgressions,
He was crushed for our iniquities.
The punishment that brought
us peace was upon Him,
and by His wounds we were healed. "
- What was that one?
- "The Passion of the Christ. "
You have the same hair.
You never seen it?
Dude, you gotta! Its amazing.
They throw everything at him:
Whips, arrows, rocks...
Just beat the
living fuck out of Him for the whole two hours.
And He just takes it.
Tough dude.
A sacrificial ram.
Next on the main stage will be Cassidy.
Harmony on the small stage.
Oh, well, fuck.
- Gotta go.
- Where're you going?
- How much do I owe you?
- That's 60.
Keep the change.
Thank you.
On stage, the lovely Cassidy.
A bottle Andrilon, 250.
Vali Q, 75 bucks.
Two bottles of Trans, $25 each.
The box 50.
Bio-insulin, 100 bucks.
You've got four boxes of Sustanon,
it's three amps to the box...
30 for a box, 1 buck 20,
Dianabol, 100 bucks.
With this, I've got you a bottle extra,
200 bucks. Altogether 995.
If you've only got 400, give me the 400
then we're good for the rest.
Got any GH?
I've got Chinese and I've got Serostim.
I don't want any of that Chinese stuff.
My poor Ram,
I'll help you out, alright?
Fuck you.
You've got to take the
bacteriostatic water with it too.
Makes your growth last longer.
Anything else?
Painkillers, spikes, barbs?
No, I'm tabbed.
- Sure?
- Those will dope me.
- Viagra.
- No.
Things to blow?
Got it all man, whatever you need.
Some kind of pharmacy, brother.
- Well man, I look out for you.
- Yeah, sure.
You take your shoots
and you're alright then, right?
- I'm just gonna get big and strong.
- Yes, you sure are my friend.
- You're looking good, brother.
- I'm trying, baby, I'm trying...
- Show me what you've got.
- Oh, come on, come on...
- Show me.
- Come on...
Little something,
there's not much there, baby...
Come on, bring it up.
Look at that motherfucker...!
Now, right up there,
stay right up there.
- Do you see it right up there?
- Aha.
I don't need these curls on too long,
because last time they broke off
I think they got too fried.
So how's the old man doing these days?
- Work, work, work...
- Work, work, work, huh?
We still have a job, right?
- Hey, Gloria, how're you doin'?
- Hey babe, how's everything?
Here we go.
Lay it on, brother. Lay it on.
There you go...
You're supposed to fall to your knees.
- So where's the bug spray in here?
- Row 6 at the right side bottom.
Right side. Bug spray.
Come on, once more.
- Give it to me, brother.
- Okay, man.
Fuck.
- A couple of mouse traps?
- Load them, set them in the ring and body slam them.
Good.
How're you doin', sir?
- How you doing?
Now what do you think?
What do you think about this? Huh?
- That'll work.
- OK.
Come here.
Hey, I don't look good, but I feel good.
My knees, my back, anything
you need me to do, sir,
just, maybe, keep the running
to a minimum.
Like, maybe I could hit the ropes once,
take a bump for you...
But like no criss-crossing, please.
That hardcore stuff is not for me.
Talk to me about what you wanna do tonight.
- Are you cool with staples?
- Staples?
- Staple gun.
- What dya mean?
- Like staple gun...
- Staple gun?
- You never did it before?
- No. Does that hurt?
It is a silly question.
Man, they're not so bad going in.
Kinduv scary.
You got a big metal thing up against you...
Pull them out, they're gonna leave
a couple of holes, little bit of blood loss there.
- Rock 'n roll!
- Thank you, sir.
- Take it easy with the stapler, though.
- No problem, sir.
One, two, three.
Ladies and gentlemen, the winner:
the one and only Randy "The Ram" Robinson.
Good job.
Helluva mess up there, man,
helluva mess.
(?), man... Good work, properly done.
Fucking insane, Ram!
Wow, say Ram, let's get some glue...
Crazy shit, man, crazy...
- You were OK with the table hit?
- I'll live, sir. I'll live.
Ant & Roach Killer
Oh, shit.
You have a lot of staples, gonna pick them out.
Alright, take it easy, doctor.
Hold still.
Damn.
Time to eat.
Aaaah. Goddammit!
Kill him.
Use this leg!
Ram.
Fuck you.
OK, let me get you this out of you.
Doesn't look very good, man
Almost done.
OK, Ram, you can go and take a shower.
Nice work, man.
I think we achieved what we wanted.
Relax.
Try to relax.
Molly, get some help in here, please.
Keep your hands down.
Try to relax.
Come on.
Relax.
Ok, and again, touch;
there we go.
Thank you, Marilyn. OK.
Mr. Ramsemsky.
- Call me Randy
- Randy, I'm Dr. Wade Disadale.
So, how is it all looking?
Much better than before the bypass.
So, we're in the clear.
We're all good.
Well, it's your heart. You need to start
taking better care of it.
- How will I do?
- Well, for starters, you're gonna be under a slew of medications...
And the stuff that you're putting
in your body, you need to cut it out.
I know, I know.
I can live without that.
When can I get back in the gym and huh...
and start working out?
- As far as the exercise goes...
it's still okay, as long
as it is moderate.
- Doc, I am a professional wrestler.
- That's not a good idea.
What do you mean?
Your heart has been through a lot and
won't be able to handle this strain of activity.
Well, I can slow my routine down.
I can just pace myself.
- Mr. Ramsemsky.
- Randy, call me Randy.
Randy, you almost died.
Next time
you might not be so lucky.
Well, hey doc, thanks for all
the good news.
This copy is for you.
Someone left this here,
said he was your promoter.
You earned it, dude! You're a warrior!
rest up, feel better. - Jerry Difusco
P.S. If you're up by the 23rd,
I got something in Yonkers
Robert Ramsemsky, come to the pharmacy,
your prescription is ready.
- Robert Ramsemsky?
- Randy.
Sign here, please.
Thank you.
There you go.
My money.
Welcome home.
Adam.
- Want to play Nintendo?
- Alright.
OK, let's see what you've got there.
Alright, here comes the Ayatollah.
Here we go. Come on.
Say, did you hear about
"Call of Duty IV"?
- What?
- "Call of Duty IV".
- "Call it Duty IV"?
- "Call of Duty IV"
- "Call of Duty IV"?
- Yes
- Very cool actually.
- Really?
This is so old...
- And what is about?
- It's a war game.
Most of the other Call of
Duties are like based...
on World War II,
but this one is with Iraq.
- Yeah?
- You switch off between a Marine,...
and an SAS British Special Operatives.
It's pretty cool.
Wow! Hold on. Alright, alright,
there we go.
Alright, There, there is it: Ram Jam!
- You're finished, OK. One more.
- I gotta go.
- I just gave you an ass whipping...
- Don't you wanna get even?
- No, that's OK.
- Really?
- I'll catch you later, right?
Do your push-ups, brother.
Hey!
Hey.
Ram Man!
Been a while.
Yeah, I was in the neighborhood...
I thought that maybe we could go
grab a hamburger.
- I'm working.
- OK. Maybe later.
Are you okay?
- Can we talk for a second?
- Sure, yeah. What's up?
Someplace more quiet.
Randy...
Randy, I cant leave with a customer.
Listen, I had a heart attack.
- Where are you parked?
- Out in the back.
Great. Go to your car. Ill meet you out
there in 15 minutes.
You know what? I wanna go on a break.
I need a cigarette, I can't quit.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
That's OK.
When was it?
A couple of weeks ago.
How are you feeling?
I don't feel like Hercules.
What happened?
I was walking in the dresser room
and the guys told me
I just dropped like a brick.
I don't remember nothing.
And now the doctors tell me
that I can't wrestle no more.
What you gonna do?
You know, I just don't feel right.
And that's why...
that's why I wanted to talk to you.
Cos I don't wanna be alone.
Oh, Randy.
You should be with your family now.
Don't you have a daughter?
Where's your daughter?
- My daughter, she don't like me very much.
- I don't blame her.
Everyone needs a father and, trust me, this
kind of thing brings people together.
You should call her.
I should go back in.
You gonna be okay huh?
- I'll be okay.
- OK
Stephanie.
Hi, we're not in,
leave a message.
Uh, is Stephanie home?
Who can I say it is?
Tell her it's her father.
Hey, Stephanie, where're you going?
- What do you want?
- Well, I just have to talk to you.
Can't really talk right now.
- I really need to talk to you.
- I have school.
- You're going to school?
- Yeah.
That's great!
Listen, I had a heart attack
and I just thought I needed to tell you.
You're such an asshole.
What do you want from me?
What do you want?
I've just been alone and you're my daughter
and I love you. And I just...
- ... just needed to see you.
- It's bullshit.
- You want me to take care of you.
- No.
Yes. Well, I'm not gonna do that.
Where the fuck were you when I
I needed you to take care of me?
You know, on all my birthdays
which you never been even to one.
You probably don't even know when it is...
So you may want to know: I don't care
if you had a heart attack. Fuck you!
Hi Ram, I didn't think I'd see you here.
- Why not?
- Hiya
Heard you collapsed
at the DiFusco show.
Ah, man I just overheated
and blacked out, that's all.
Really?
I was out of the hospital in less than an hour.
- So you're fine?
- Bruno, I'm good to go!
That's excellent, I was just
gonna cancel the minivan.
- What minivan?
- The rented one for FanFest.
Me and the whole gang is driving down,
Terry C, Casiano, Fat Bag...
I am so fuckin psyched.
Volpe gave me an assload of flyers...
There...
It's gonna be epic.
Volpe said the scout
from the show is gonna be there.
- 20 years in the making.
- It's gonna be something.
Come on, I've got you settled down here.
- Hey bro.
- Hey, what's going on, bro?
Ya, you've got a pretty good crowd today.
- Great, I'll loosen up.
- Alright.
Hey, my man, how're you doing, big guy?
Good to see you.
- I've been a big fan of yours for years.
- How are you doing, brother?
- It's really great to meet you.
- Alright.
- I've got a Polaroid?
- Absolutely.
Here it goes.
- What's your name again?
- Evan.
- E-V...?
- E-V-A-N
One, two...
Ram!
- That's 8. There you go, Matthew.
- OK, here you go.
- Hi, I'm Cassidy.
- Henry.
Nice to meet you.
Where you from?
Hartfield.
Yes?
How are you doing tonight?
OK.
How about a private dance
to make you feel better?
- No, not tonight.
- No, Henry?
- No.
- No?
Okay.
No.
On the main stage
The Exotic...
Hey.
- Hey, when did you get here?
- I just moved in.
You did?
- How are you feeling?
- I'm feeling good.
- I'm better.
- Good.
And I took your advice, so I went
and saw my daughter.
Yeah? How did that go?
Huh... It didn't go very well...
She sort of... cut me a new asshole.
Oh, sorry to hear that...
Well hey, what're you gonna do?
Maybe if we went out,
did something special? Or a present?
That's a really great idea.
What's she into?
I don't know really.
- What kind of music does she like?
- I really don't know.
Is she into something else like
cooking, or books or something like that?
- I don't know.
- OK... well
You should get her clothes,
some kind of clothes...
- ... all girls dig that.
- Yeah?
Yes
Hey, I know the right place.
It's this kickass little
vintage shop in Elizabeth.
I think on Elisabeth Avenue;
you should go on a Saturday,
that's when they get all the best shit.
Thanks, thanks a lot.
Wanna dance?
I don't think I am quite ready for that yet.
Okay.
That was fast.
Listen, why don't I meet
you there on Saturday
and help you pick something out?
I'd like that a lot.
- One?
- Yeah.
Alright.
Alright. One.
Hey, hello.
Did you forget how to knock? We'll
try that again. Right? I am serious.
- What do you want?
- I was wondering if I could get some...
more work, something huh,...
you know, steady, full time.
All I've got is weekends.
That works...
Isn't that when you sit
on other dudes' faces?
- So what've you got?
- Deli counter.
Deli counter...
- Dealing with the customers and stuff?
- Yeah.
A parade of hot horny housewives
begging for your meat.
You got anything else?
No, I do not. Interested?
Yeah, sure.
- Hey.
Goddamn, I almost didn't
recognize you. You look...
...you look clean.
Clean?
I mean you look lovely.
Okay, thanks.
Listen, should I call you Pam or Cassidy?
- Pam.
Don't get used to it.
What is she? Goth, punk, hippie?
- Preppy?
- I ain't got a clue.
Hey, Pam.
- Pam.
- Yeah?
Thank you. I really appreciate this.
You're welcome.
Listen, I think Stephanie is...
...a lesbian.
...Does that make a difference with the...?
No. Nope.
Maybe it's all in my head, I don't know.
Oh, wow! What about this?
See this, it's got an'S' on it,
it's perfect.
Good.
I mean, it's winter, so maybe
you want something warmer, like a peacoat.
You got a point there.
- It is her size.
- That looks pretty cool.
I don't know, man, this is
pretty Rock'n Roll.
What do you think?
Should go with your gut, man.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You know, so look so goddamn
pretty in the daytime.
Hey, have a beer with me?
I gotta get going.
One beer.
I really...
I got a kid.
You have a kid?
Well...
What do you have, a boy or a girl?
Boy.
Jameson.
- How old...?
- Nine.
Oh, hmm, who would figure, huh?
Well, its not something I usually tell
the customers. It's not exactly...
...it's not a turn-on.
Hold on. Wait a second.
I want you to give this
to your little guy, it's...
it's a Randy the Ram action figure.
Tell him not to lose it,
it's a $ 300 collector's item.
Really?
No.
Come on, hey.
One beer.
Okay.
Its a 'great looking kid you got there.
I think so.
I want to see where
he gets his good looks from.
He sure doesnt get it from his father.
What is that?
Just this condo thing, down by Trenton
Are you thinking about moving there?
- Working on it, yeah
- Yeah?
The schools are really awesome,
that neighborhood...
...it's cheaper.
What about your gig over at The Chicks?
Done. Quitting.
Wow, hell yeah, alright!
Come on now, baby. Dance with me.
- Here?
- Yeah, right here.
- Ive danced to this plenty.
- OK, I'll dance for you then.
Where did you get this?
Hey, man, I need a job.
Oooh, it's a lap dance I'm getting.
I knew right from the beginning
That you would end up winning
I knew right from the start
You'd put an arrow thru my heart
Goddamn, they dont
make em like they used to.
Fuckin eighties, man. Best shit ever.
Bet your ass, man.
Guns n 'Roses fucking rule.
Cre...
- Def Lep,
- And that Cobain pussy had to come around
... and ruined it all, ya know.
Like there's something wrong
with having a good time?
Lemme tell you something,
I hated the fucking 90's.
What's the matter?
No contact with customers.
I gotta go.
Hey, you said one beer.
- I did?
- Yeah.
One beer.
There you go.
Hey, bro, this is supposed
to say Randy.
I guess they got it off
your W-4 or something.
Shall I really gotta
wear one of these things?
No, you're special.
Can you change it?
Just wear the fuckin' thing, alright?
Oh, shit.
Take your baloney, pal.
Are they all on sale
or just the regular one?
- The Hudson Acres, huh...
- Well it wasn't very clear.
- Let me check.
- Okay.
Wayne, to the deli counter.
Itll just be a minute.
So, which in your opinion
is the best smoked ham?
The best what?
Smoked ham.
Which?
If you wanna take my guess,
the Mapple Glaze is not bad.
Breast. Thighs.
Small pieces.
Lock it up.
Push 'Start. '
Yes.
What would you like?
Could I have half a pound
of pesto pasta salad?
Coming up.
Half a pound of pesto pasta on the button.
- Need anything else?
- No, that's all.
You have a lovely day, darling.
Thanks. You too.
Give me 8 pieces of chicken.
- What kind of chicken do you want?
- I want 8 pieces.
Two breasts, two big breasts.
Two big breasts, coming up.
That's what I want,
Big breasts, or something with a brain.
And 2 wings.
Stay away from them thighs.
A lotta chicken flying out the door.
There you go, honey, have a good day.
- Who's next?
- Me.
- What're having, good looking?
- Have a pound of egg salad.
Have a pound of egg salad, coming up.
- Here we go.
- Fresh?
Fresh? Fresh as monkey's bread, brother.
This is the good stuff.
Coming up.
Down and out, come on.
The 4th corner, come on, come on...
It's 12 seconds left, go, down and out.
Both hands.
Hey, Touchdown. goddamn,
How 'bout that, cowboy?
What're having, spring chicken?
Hi.
Hey, Meg, how're doing?
Yeah, it's the Ram.
Yeah, sure, yeah...
Listen,
You're gonna have to count me out for Utica.
I'm retiring.
Hey, Frank, how're you doin'?
I'm good man, I'm good.
Listen.
Come on, sorry, Volpe.
You know Id kill to do it.
No, I realize. I understand.
No, no more, I'm done. I am retired.
Stephanie.
What, are you stalking me?
No, I...
...I brought you a present.
Come on, open it.
The S stands for Stephanie.
Oh, yeah.
You like it?
It is shiny.
That's not really the present.
I've got you something else.
This is your real present.
- A peacoat.
- Oh?
Wintertime, and...
I want you to keep warm.
Thank you.
Anything for you, sweetheart...
So, what are you doing right now?
What am I doing?
Yes, I thought that maybe we could,
you know, stop by our old favorite place.
We have no favorite place.
You'll recognize it when you see it.
Now is not really the best time,
I've got some stuff that I gotta do.
What kind of stuff?
Stuff.
Come on, I'm not gonna like...
...I'm not gonna take a bite
out of you or anything.
I just want to hang out for a little while.
I haven't been here in ages.
You remember the fun house?
It's there, it used to be the Monster Motel.
- Kinduv.
- Oh, you loved it,...
we used to go in there and they have
this spooky-ass squeleton pop out of...
a coffin and youd get so scared,
youd cry and you would run out and...
then you begged to get back in again.
Always was a glutton for punishment.
Yes, you wouldn't go in unless you could sit
on my foot
and wrap your arms around my leg.
We'd walk you the whole way
through like that.
Ah, I don't even remember that.
I do.
I just wanna tell you
I'm the one who is supposed
to take care of everything.
I who is supposed to
make everything okay for everybody.
It just didn't
work out like that.
And I left.
I left you.
You never did anything wrong.
You know?
I used to try to, huh,... forget about you.
I used to try to pretend that
you didn't exist.
But I can't.
You're my girl.
You're my little,...
my little girl.
And now
I am an old broken-down piece of meat.
And I'm alone.
And I deserve to be all alone.
I just don't want you to hate me.
Okay?
Oh, man, we can't go in there...
Oh God.
This should have been a bar or something.
Hey, here we go.
What is that?
That is my bow to you.
Am I supposed to bow back?
You can lead, you're not bad.
Thank you.
Hold on.
Wait, let me get the door.
I hope that wasn't
too painful for you.
It was okay.
Yeah, well.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Maybe we can go out to dinner sometime.
Dinner?
On Friday or something.
Whatever works for you.
Saturday will be better.
Saturday?
Yeah.
You got it.
Hey, you there.
Come on, open it.
Ill do it later when its quiet.
Oh, come on, I wanna watch
your face when you read it.
Thank you, that's very sweet.
Hey, thank you. I mean,
come on, baby, you saved my ass.
What?
- I can't do this.
- Can't do what?
This.
I thought we had
a little something going on here.
No, I think you're awesome.
Like, youre a great guy.
So, what is the problem?
You think that I'm a stripper and I'm not.
I am a mom...
I have responsibilities,
I have a son...
Anyway, you dont want
that fuckin' mugging stuff.
What if I do?
I can't go there.
- What about the other day?
- It was a mistake.
It didn't feel like a mistake to me.
The club and the real world they don't mix.
Well, I'd say I think
that's a lot of bullshit because
I think you still feel something.
You are a customer, OK?
You're a fuckin'customer...
I don't go out with customers.
You got it.
Yeah, I got it... Hey can I have
some tequila over here, please?
Sure.
Tell you what...
Here.
- What's that?
- I want a dance.
Stop that.
What's the matter, are you going
to refuse a paying customer?
- I want a goddamn dance, sweetheart.
- Fuck you.
Come on, get up there, move your ass,
squeeze your titties together,
shake your fuckin' ass...
Fuck you!
- ... you're telling you like me...
Gimme a goddamn dance!
- Get the fuck outta here!
- Ram! Let's take it outside.
- You wanna drink, my man?
- No, I'm alright.
Oh, no...
- Hey there.
- What's happening?
What're you doing here?
I thought you were retired.
I just came to see the show.
Come in, come on,
man, of course.
Hey, what's up here? I haven't seen
you for long. All good?
- Hey, you guys look great tonight.
- Did you like it?
Yeah, a helluva show.
You were right.
- Look at this guy, man...
- You look good!
Hey, what's important, they liked you.
So how've you been, man?
- Well, hanging and swinging, brother.
- Keep hitting.
We're gonna drink?
You buy it?
I'll buy it.
Fifteen.
Thank you...
I know who you are.
My brother used to have
your poster on his door.
Well, your brother's got good taste.
Yeah, a pretty hot picture...
So, what're you doing here?
We did a show.
Fascinating. How do you still wrestle?
I'm still jumping off the top rope.
Do you wanna party?
Party? What do you call party?
Party like a fireman party.
Oh shit, that's pretty cool.
Go get a fucking room.
Shit!
Damn!
Hey, is Stephanie home?
...so, you dont have to go out there. You
dont owe him shit.
I know him, he is stressed out,
and wants you to be stressed out
Hey.
- Who said you could come in?
- What the fuck are you doing here?
- I'm sorry, Stephanie.
- Now get the fuck out.
I'm gonna handle this. OK, I can handle this.
Obviously not.
I can handle this.
Come on, I'm sorry,
I screwed this up.
- I'm so sorry...
- Wait...
I'm just...
You don't have to leave.
Fuck!
You know, I waited in that restaurant
for two hours.
Two fucking hours I was telling
myself "Maybe something happened,
maybe he's stuck in traffic...",
but no, you keep doing the
same shit to me over and over again.
I apologize, I got a lot of stuff
swimming around in my head
and I went out and had a drink...
and another drink...
That is such shit!
My God, I do not know why I do this.
Because you are a fuck-up.
You're a living, breathing fuck-up.
and I cannot fucking do it anymore...
I can't stand it, I can't
fucking cry for you,...
I can't fucking do it anymore...
Fuck you.
You're an asshole!
a fucking asshole!
- Get off me!
- Calm down.
I'm sorry, I know, I know you hate me.
I know, I know you do.
I know you hate me...
Calm down, listen.
No, I don't care!
I don't hate you.
I don't love you.
I don't even like you.
And it was stupid
to think that you could change.
- I can.
- I don't care.
Come on.
There's no more fixing this.
It's broke, permanently.
And I don't care about that,
it's better.
Sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I don't ever want to see you again.
Look at me.
I don't want to see you...
I don't want to hear you...
And done. You understand?
Done!
Get out.
A pound of German potato salad.
A little less.
Less...
- A little more.
- A little more...
I see.
A little more.
A little less.
At last.
What's with the line? Lets pick
things up, right? It's rush hour.
Come on people, Lets pick
it up...
Have a nice day, lady.
- 31.
- 31. Here, you take it.
Do not know you from somewhere else?
No.
You look so damn familiar.
- You're teamsters?
- What're you having?
Half a pound of Virginia ham,
half pound of the yoghurt spread
I know I know you from some place.
You play softball?
No.
You're not one of Mikey's Bicycles, right?
- Never heard of the guy.
- Wait a second.
- Randy the Ram?
- No.
The wrestler from the 80s?
Ram Jam!
That's freaky. You look just
like each other. Just older.
Goddamn.
Randy, Randy,
the customers...
You little prick, you're gonna talk
to me the way you do?
Fuck you!
I quit! I quit!
Want some fucking cheese, lady?
Get your own fucking cheese.
Are you crazy?
I'm out of here.
Robin, Robin...
Man, it's Randy.
Listen, I wanna do it.
I want back in, FanFest.
Just tell him it's back on.
Hey man, I don't give a shit.
I just wanna wrestle.
Okay. You got it, brother.
- I want him in bed by eleven.
- Eleven, OK.
I don't want him to bargain.
Bye monkey.
One, two, three...
yeah, you're up.
Hi.
Hey.
How did you find me?
- Big Chris.
- Big Chris?
The big bouncer.
Big Chris, yeah.
I know I came off like a bitch
the other day and I'm really sorry,
I didn't mean all those things that I said.
Youre not just another customer.
But, you know, at the same time
I have this line...
I can't cross it...
No, I understand that,
that's okay.
I gotta go.
- Where you going?
- I got a match.
Match?
It is in Welminton, come by.
When is it?
Phoenix is out of the question, I'm
taking over Arizona, do you hear me?
- Ram-A-Lam...
- Hey, Bob.
Hey, Nigel, how're you doing, brother?
Long time...
- Are you okay?
- Yes, well...
- Good to see you, bro.
- Yeah, look at you...
- You know what? Didnt think
we were gonna do this.
Yeah,... you and everybody else.
Sunday night, you know, I get a call
and they say, "He's back in, it's on again. "
Im like "What?"
Listen, when you get setled in,
you wanna go over some of the things?
What things?
The spots.
Okay, how's this right here?
I am the heel and you're the face... done.
Hey Bob.
I am glad to see that
things haven't changed.
Yeah, I love you too.
Cassidy, come on Cassidy
get back up there...
You left your shoes.
Cassidy?
Hey Cass?
Man...
Three more miles.
You ready to do this thing?
I think so.
See you outside.
...the Beast Of The Middle East...
The Ayaaa-to-laaaah!...
- How much?
- $ 20.
Where is the dressing room?
The dressing room?
Randy.
- What are you doing here?
- What are you fucking doing?
I'm doing my thing.
I'm going to work.
But... your heart.
My heart...
My heart's still taken...
- Yeah, but the doctors say...
- I know what I'm doing.
the only place where I get hurt
is out there.
The world don't give
a shit about me.
I'm here.
I'm really here.
What do you call that?
And his opponent...
From Elizabeth, New Jersey,
Hey,
...do you hear that?
This is my call.
- I'm going in.
- Randy The Ram Robinnnnsonnnnn!
Randy? Randy?
I just wanted to say...
You're all very...
I'm very grateful to be here...
A lotta people told me that
I'd never wrestle again.
and that's all I do,
You know, if you live hard
and you play hard...
and you burn the candle at both ends...
...you pay the price for it.
In this life you can
lose everything you love,
everything that loves you...
Now I don't hear as good
as I used to... and I forget stuff,
and I'm not as pretty as I used to be,
but goddamn, I'm still
standing here and I'm the Ram!
As time goes by...
as time goes by, they'll say:
"He's gonna stop...
he's finished, he's a loser...
he's all through...
You know what? The only
ones who're gonna tell me
when I'm through doing my thing...
is you people here.
You people here...
You people here,
are the ones,
who are worth doing this for,
because you are my family.
I love you!
Thank you so much.
Yeah, pick it up!
Go easy on me for chrissake!
What're you doing?
This is my move!
It's still my move, Randy!
This is how you do it.
- Don't push me!
- Don't tell me what to do.
I forgot how much fun this was, Ram!
Bring it, Bob!
Asshole!
You're going down!
I will take you out as well....!
Ram, are you alright?
Are you okay, Ram?
Ram?
I'm gonna touch over to you.
Hit me, come on, Ram, hit me.
We didn't enough.
Are you okay?
You're alright?
It's okay, Ram,
take it home.
One, two, three, four...
Subtitles by KV
on Subtitle Workshop - 2009