What?
I said I just wanted to talk.
What the hell?
What's with the way you
fucking talk?
Who the fuck are you?
My...
name is...
Oh Daesu.
Why are you picking on
someone else's girlfriend?
Hold on.
Mister Daesu!
- Am I picking on you?
Okay, I got it!
Oh Daesu,
please sit down.
Oh boy,
must have drunk a lot.
Hold on, let me piss first!
I didn't do anything!
You son o f a bitch!
We have to do something about him.
- Asshole!
- Sit down!
I'm very sorry.
Fuck, I gotta piss bad.
- Cute, huh?
- Yeah, I saw it. Now go sit down.
Today's my daughter's birthday.
I got her a present
for her birthday.
Snatches o f clouds floating
in the sky
A pleasure boat
floats in the river
My name, Oh Daesu, means...
"Getting along with people"
That's why I'm Oh Daesu.
But, shit...
Why can't I get along today?
Set me free!
- Shut the hell up!
- Set me free!
Let go o f me, damn it!
That son o f a bitch really
needs some prison time.
- Get away from me!
- Hey, get him!
I'll make sure he doesn't get drunk
and cause more trouble.
- Have a nice day, o fficer.
- He's usually a nice guy.
Let's go.
- I'll visit you soon.
- We don't want you to come back.
That's up to me, assholes.
Hey!
My sweet pea, it's daddy.
Daddy got my sweet pea a present.
I'll be home soon with your gift,
so wait a bit longer.
- Let me talk to her.
- Good girl, good.
Give me the phone.
Yeun hee, Joo hwan
wants to talk to you.
You know Joo hwan, right?
Hold on.
Hello, hi, Yeun hee.
It's me, Joo hwan.
So today's your birthday?
Happ y birthday.
I'll treat you to something
nice tomorrow.
Hello? Hi, Ja hyun. I'm sorry.
I know it's very late.
Daesu is on his way now.
I'm sorry.
Yes? Hold on.
Daesu, it's your wife.
Daesu!
Hey, Daesu!
Couldn't you hurry up a bit.
Hey, stop fooling around
and let's go.
Daesu!
Sir, wait. Come here.
Wait, talk to me.
I won't tell you to let me go.
Just tell me why I'm here, okay?
I should know the reason at least.
Shit, I've been locked up here
for two months already.
Sir, wait, come here.
What place is this?
Sir, just tell me how long
I have to stay in here.
Sir! Fuck you!
Come here, you asshole!
I saw your face, asshole.
You're dead if I get out.
Come here, asshole.
I'm sorry, I won't curse.
Just tell me.
One month, two, or three?
Hey, where are you going?
Just tell me how long,
you son o f a bitch!
You asshole!
You son o f a bitch!
If they had told me
it w as going to be 15 y ears
could it have been easier to endure?
0 r could it have not?
"Laugh, and the world laughs
with you. Cry, and you cry alone."
When the melody turns on
gas comes out.
When the gas comes
I fall aslee p.
I found out later that it's the s ame
Valium-gas Russian soldiers used
on the C hec hen terrorists.
When I w ake u p
my hair has been c ut.
I don't like my sty le really.
But they c hange my c lothes
and c lean the place u p.
Grateful bastards.
0 ne!
Tw o!
Three!
It's too spicy.
I don't want spinach.
You eat it.
I won't eat spinach.
I don't want to eat it.
Kim Jahy un's body w as found
dee ply stabbed in the nec k.
Seeing that it w as a cold
blooded murder
w ith nothing v aluable stolen
police sus pect that
the motive w as out of hatred.
Her husband w ho dis appeared
a y ear ago is a prime sus pect.
According to w itnesses, her
husband, 0 h Daesu,
drank often
c ausing trouble w ith his w ife.
Neighbours s ay they
fou ght frequently.
Blood s amples found at the scene
matc hed 0 h Daesu's.
Fingerprints found on a c u p
also matc hed 0 h Daesu's.
It w as confirmed by sources that
0 h Daesu visited his w ife recently.
The stolen family album
also bac ks their theories.
After three y ears
many w rinkles
have formed on his face.
If y ou stand aimlessly
at the phone booth
on a rainy day
and meet a man w hose face is
covered by a violet umbrella
I'd su ggest
that y ou get c lose to the TV.
The TV is both a c loc k
and c alendar.
It's y our sc hool, home,
c hurc h, friend
and lover.
But...
my lover's song
is too short.
This morning around 7:30
the to p 50m of
the Sungsoo Bridge in Seoul
suddenly collapsed in the middle.
I w rote dow n all the peo ple
w hom I fou ght w ith,
bothered, and hurt.
This w as both
my prison journal
and autobio graphy of
my evil deeds.
I thou ght I have lived
an average life
but I've sinned too muc h.
All I thou ght about
at that moment
w as that the guy ne xt door
probably ate w ith one c ho pstic k.
But.
But...
Who w ould've imprisoned me?
Was it Yoo Heung s am?
Lee So y oung or Kang C hangsuk?
Whoever it w as, just w ait.
Wait a bit more.
I'll rip y our w hole
body apart
and no one w ill be able to
find y our body any w here.
Bec ause I'm going to
c hew it all dow n.
0 ne line for one y ear.
I have to sew six lines.
I guess the ne xt y ear w ill be easier.
The more the tattoos
the shorter the c ho pstic k.
The shorter the c ho pstic k
the bigger the w all's hole gets.
Any w ay
time passes w ell.
9 y ears.
10 y ears.
11 y ears.
Enforcement of an arrest w arrant
Handover of Hong Kong
Yesterday's convention center
Death of Princess Diana
Funeral for Princess Diana
Westminister Monastery
IMF, Financ ial su pport
offic ially approved
12 y ears.
Artillery Salute
Arriv al of President
Kim Dae Jung in Py ungy ang
Underdo g Korea!
Mirac ulous Q uarterfinals!
13 y ears.
Noh Moo Hy un elected. 49%
14 y ears.
I'll be out in a month.
I'll be free in a month.
I'll be out. After a month.
I'll be out in a month.
I'll be out.
In e xactly one month.
I'll need money w hen I get out,
so w hat should I do?
Should I steal or rob?
What shall I eat first?
Anything w ill be fine
e xce pt for fried dumplings.
Where am I any w ay?
With all c ars honking
it must be the c ity.
The most important thing is
w hat floor I'm on.
What if I pierce throu gh the w all
and it's the 52nd floor?
Even if I fall to my death
I'm still getting out.
I'm getting out.
In one month.
Right now
you're ly ing on a plain.
When you hear the bell
you will turn your head
and look down.
You will see
an endless field o f green grass.
The sun is shining bright
and there's a cool breeze.
It's a human being.
Don't stop me!
Mister.
Even though
I'm no worst than a beast
don't I have the right to live?
Mister.
Even though
I'm no worst than a beast
don't I have right to live?
Yes.
That phone booth alley
w as just there.
Now there's an apartment building
So he throw s me on the roof.
What a numskull.
I want to tell you my story.
Delay your death.
What?
I see.
Of course.
Now I'll tell you my story.
The reason why I want to die.
Hey!
It's a w oman being.
That lunatic... Hurry!
Hey! Come over here!
Lau gh and the w orld
lau ghs w ith y ou.
Wee p and y ou w ee p alone.
My home is gone.
I c an't c all either
my friends or relatives
since I'm the one
w ho murdered my w ife.
Since I'm a fu gitive.
You dickshit!
Dic kshit.
Never heard of it
since the TV
doesn't teac h y ou c urse w ords.
C an imaginary training
for 15 y ears
be put to use?
It c an.
0 ple gnathus fasc iatus.
Lives in the w arm w aters
of coastal reefs.
Has w eak refle xes, but c an resist
uny ieldingly once c au ght in a hook.
In Ky uns ang Province
its offs pring...
What's this smell?
Don't even think about asking
me any questions.
I don't know a thing.
Yes?
I said I want something alive.
Oh, right.
Long time no see.
This is my first time.
Maybe not?
But she looks familiar.
You look very familiar.
Have I seen you somewhere?
"Searching for the best che f"
"On channel 11
every Thursday at 6:30"
"The youngest female che f o f
Japanese food"
Oh that...
They said the ratings are low
but I guess it's popular.
Women's hands are usually warm
so they can't make sushi.
Wow, you sure know a lot!
Who are you?
Do y ou like y our c lothes?
Why...
- Why did you imprison me?
- Who do y ou think I am?
- Yoo Heungsam? - Wrong.
- Did Lee Soyoung hire you?
- No, w rong again.
Lee Jongyong?
Kang Changsuk?
Hwang Jooyeun?
Kim Nasung? Park Ji woo?
Lm Duksoon? Lee Jaep yung?
Kuk Suran? Who the hell are you?
Me?
I'm sort of a sc holar.
And my ma jor is y ou.
A sc holar study ing 0 h Daesu.
An e xpert on 0 h Daesu.
Who I am isn't important.
Why is important.
Think it over.
Review y our w hole lifetime.
Since y our sc hool is over it's time
for y our homew ork. Right?
Kee p this in mind
"Be it a grain of s and or roc k,
in w ater they sink as the s ame"
Let me ask you one thing.
You hypnotized me in there
didn't you?
What did you do to me?
I miss y ou.
Hurry, and come to me.
Here you are.
It's alive, right?
I'll slice it up now.
I must be a different breed o f
women. My hands are very cold.
What's w ith her?
Sir.
Wake up, sir!
Kee p this in mind.
Be it a grain of s and or roc k,
in w ater they sink as the s ame.
Are you awake?
Is this true?
That fever remedy
really works.
Why'd you faint
if you trained so much?
A lack o f needed sunlight
depletes you o f vitamins A and E.
So I'm not immune to influenza.
Do you usually talk that way?
That bathroom door
is broken and doesn't lock.
Don't get any bright ideas
or I'll slice you like sushi.
- What's this? - Suppositories.
How else could I feed you
medicine if you fainted?
C an imaginary training
for 15 y ears be put to use?
It c an't.
That was very bad o f me.
After bringing you here
and rejecting you,
I understand why you're mad.
I do.
I brought you here
because I like you, too.
But.
You don't even know my name.
I'm Mido.
You see.
Later,
when I'm really ready,
I swear on my life that I will
give my self to you.
That song, "The Face I miss"
in your diary that's the sign.
When I sing it,
then you get yourself ready.
When it actually happens.
I could resist again
at the heat o f the moment.
But no matter what
don't ever back out.
Just give it to me!
Give it... to me?
The ants.
Do you still see them?
Do you still feel that way?
Yeah, if you're alone
you see the ants.
Very lonely people
that I met
they all hallucinated ants
at one time.
After I thought about it.
Ants move around in groups.
So I guess very lonely people
keep thinking about ants.
Even though I never did.
She called from overseas
five or six years ago
asking if her dad
showed up.
She doesn't even know
that he killed her mother.
Since she has few
relatives she calls us.
Her Korean has gotten bad.
I think her foster parents
are both doctors.
Anyhow, Miss Reporter
Daesu really hasn't been caught yet?
Your daughter's address
is on the front
and on the back is a map
to your wife's grave.
Ev a. Stoc kholm.
Ev a.
Do you want to call her?
Want me to call her?
Wanna go to the grave together?
No, a fter I kill that bastard first.
"Blue Dragon"
Is it right?
I haven't c hew ed it y et.
Blue Dragon, so?
Is that the taste?
Be it 10 or 100 restaurants,
it doesn't matter.
I c an never forget that taste
for 15 y ears, Blue Dragon.
Want me to make you
an ID to log in?
Do you have a favorite
movie or song?
I talked to him.
The Count o f Monte Cristo?
There's no one
by that name here.
How's life in a bigger prison,
0 h Daesu?
Who are you?
The lonely prince in the high tow er.
Don't forget me.
Who's this bastard?
I don't know him.
I just chat with him sometimes.
Where are you going?
- Where are you going?
- I can't trust you.
Magic Blue Dragon!
What could that mean?
Why the hell did they order
from a restaurant this far aw ay?
I've gone by five
C hinese restaurants already.
My lungs feel like e xploding.
Tell your cooks to put
less scallions in the dumplings.
Sure.
- Set it down and go. - Okay.
We don't work on anyone
being protected by body guards.
There are other people
who specialize in that.
You can hire them.
We work just on the small fries.
If it's over six months
transportation fee is free.
Yes, o f course.
Why'd you lock me up, you...
Dickshit.
In our 7,5 floor business our
client's info is top secret.
I'm going to pay
you back for all 15 year.
Each one I y ank out
will make you age one year.
Stay still.
Ready to talk?
I don't know.
I didn't see his face.
I recorded it.
"Oh Daesu"
AB blood type raise your hand.
Go, he lost a lot o f blood.
As e xpected,
I c an't get along today either.
I've now become a monster.
When my vengeance is over,
c an I return as the old Daesu?
Mister, are you alright?
Look at all this blood!
Mister, what happened to you?
Saewoon Apartments in Eung am,
building 8.
Please take care o f him.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
Farewell, Oh Daesu.
Farew ell, 0 h Daesu.
0 h Daesu.
Farew ell.
Any bastard y ou hate,
but c an't dare to kill,
any bitc h y ou detest,
but w ant more than kill,
w e are at y our service.
Wouldn't he go c razy if
he's loc ked u p for a long time?
Well, if y ou prefer he doesn't,
w e c an mix dru gs into his drink
Ris detal Solution
It's a w ell trusted dru g
used to treat sc hizo phrenia.
The duration time is important,
so how long time w ill he...
15 y ears.
- Too long?
- What did he do?
0 h Daesu, y ou see,
talks too muc h.
Go to sleep.
Time to visit Joo hwan
at the Internet ca f tomorrow.
Sit wherever you like.
Joo hwan.
0 h Daesu, y ou see,
talks too muc h.
Have you heard this voice be fore?
Is there anyone,
who hates me this much?
I don't know all the 260 names
o f your women's husbands.
- Who's Mido?
- This girl cries over nothing.
Joo hwan.
Did I really talk too much?
My friend,
I'd like for you
to find that criminal
among people you're close to.
"Search: Evergreen"
"Evergreen
invites you to conversation"
"Congratulations, your case was
automatically dismissed yesterday."
But remember this
by all means
Open quote:
Like a gazelle from the hand
o f the hunter.
Like a bird
from the snare o f the fowler.
Free yourself.
Close quote.
- Who are you?
- And you, you rotten bastard?
I made u p my mind
w hen I w as imprisoned,
I w ouldn't trust any one any more.
If there's any one
w ho I find sus pic ious
then I'll c reate a sec ret
that person and I w ill only know.
That ID, monster, is a trap
that I made to catch you.
You lead a stranger to your place.
Who the hell are you?
Who's Evergreen?
I trac ked dow n that Evergreen ID
and found the ow ner's name.
- Ready to jot it dow n?
- Go ahead.
It's Su Daeoh. That's
a strange rare surname. - Address?
In Eungam, Saew oon apartments.
Building 7, room 407.
I'm not doing fine
w ithin life in a bigger prison.
"Evergreen"
"Who are you?"
You meant to ask this, right?
You can find out on your own.
Come on, it's a game.
First, "who?"
Then, "why?"
If you figure it out,
come see me anytime.
I'll raise your score.
You have until July 5th.
Oh no, only five day s le ft.
Too short?
Hang in there. If you succeed
I'll kill my self and not Mido.
That's right, Mido.
I'm going to kill every woman
you love until you die.
Well, you're notorious for
not protecting your women.
Wow, you're strong,
Mr. Monster.
Yes, you're the very
monster I created.
But you won't find out the "Why"
if you do this.
15 years o f being curious to waste.
So is that okay with you?
Sit down there.
Oh, the famous teeth torture.
You won't have enough
time to torture me.
Since I have a weak heart
I have a pacemaker in my chest.
When it was put in
know what I asked the doctor?
Doctor Hopkins, give me a remote
control to turn the motor o ff.
Pardon? Why?
So that I can kill my self
easily at anytime.
I'll give you $ 100, 000 more.
Oh, what will you do?
You want to kill me right away,
but you won't find out "Why".
You want to torture me
but I say I'll my self first.
Do you seek revenge
or do you find the truth?
Oh, you're in a though spot.
I've been watching over you
for 15 years.
I faired well thanks to you.
I wasn't bored or lonely.
Seeking revenge is the best cure
for someone who got hurt.
Try it.
The loss o f 15 years,
the pain o f losing
your wife and child.
You can forget all this.
Once again
revenge is good for your health.
But... What happens a fter
you've revenged yourself?
I bet that hidden pain
will probably come back again.
Are you there, Daesu?
Daesu,
long time no see.
Hasn't she been tied up
for too long?
I think you also
le ft the door open.
Please save me.
But I could die first.
This dentist is really good.
Don't move.
Stay still.
What's with you?
Now.
Here we go.
You see, they say that people
shrivel up because
they have imagination.
So do not imagine.
You'll become brave as hell.
Now, here comes the real thing.
Yes?
You know I'm glad
you told me about this place
but I haven't even started.
What?
Let's go.
Let's really go.
Let's fight.
- What a roughneck.
- Your hand.
I'm going to chop o ff
your hand.
You touched Mido's breasts.
Then what about my tongue?
You still don't trust me,
bastard!
It looks hard to accomplish.
I looked into it
and the reason why the bank
re fused to pay $ 270 million
isn't because our building
has any irregularities.
They have an internal
problem at their bank.
So I think there
won't be any problems
although Chairman Choi's
equity share is at 25 per cent.
- Daesu.
- Yeah?
- Did he really say that he'll kill me?
- Yeah.
Because you love me?
- Daesu.
- What?
I wonder where my love is
The night is getting lonelier
The words we spoke
through our eyes
C an be felt throu gh
the hands
So many nights
have passed
Yet my feelings are constant
tow ards y ou
Tears flood out from my eyes
But there is a face that I miss
They packed their stuff
and le ft in a rental car.
Mido called the restaurant
and quit.
Let's go a fter this is done.
You should get some rest today.
I can't even sleep.
Since I'm forlorn.
Mr. Han,
do you really think
Mido has fallen in love
with Daesu?
Already?
Daesu, it really hurts.
But I'm enduring it.
You must know this.
How'd you hold out?
For 15 years?
There's alway s a way.
Do you like it?
You really like it, right?
I want to be good to you.
Do not w orry about the future.
Don't imagine anything.
I feel like thanking
all those y ears in that prison.
If I w asn't in there
could Mido have liked me?
He could only know that I w anted
to c ho p off Mr. Park's hand
by putting a bu g on us.
And he knew our w hereabouts
by tailing us.
"I've been bugged.
Please find it."
You know
may be he freed y ou
bec ause he has fun
w atc hing y ou seeking revenge.
And never tell y ou w hy, so he
c an toy w ith y ou forever.
You think that's w hy?
Evergreen Press,
an online printing s y stem.
Evergreen Pasta and Pizza.
Evergreen Services specializing
in security, parking, cleaning.
Evergreen Tree Garden.
Evergreen Old Boy s,
Sangnok High Schoolin
alumni homepage.
Evergreen Secret Diary,
Jung Sang rok's personal site.
Norwegian Food, Evergreen.
"Welcome to Evergreen Old Boy s"
But it's time to close up.
Can't I look at the records
o f Class -79?
It's dark,
so turn on the lights.
Take your time.
Joo hwan?
Let me ask you something.
Do you know
Lee Woojin o f Class -79?
I think he went to America to study.
Lee Woo jin?
Don't know him.
So is that the bastard's name?
How'd find him?
I looked through all the school's
albums and found his face.
I don't know w ho someone is
just w ith a name.
Got anything else?
Why don't y ou look for
the sc hool records or something?
Do you know Lee Soo ah?
She was in the same grade.
Lee Soo ah?
- She died.
- What class was she in?
Homeroom tw o of our senior y ear.
She w as in my room, ne xt to y ours.
What about her?
Why is there no photo?
Ah, she died so that's why.
How did Soo ah die?
Yeah, y ou w ouldn't know,
she died after y ou transferred.
She w ent alone to the Habc hun
an fell into the river.
She c roaked like a dead fish.
A w eek later they found
her bloated body in the w ater.
- What was she like?
- Her?
She was a total slut.
On the outside
she acted like a prude
but she was a filthy whore
on the inside.
Rumours had it that
that slut fucked everyone at school.
I should've gotten in there.
I also heard that her family
was really rich.
Her grades were good, too.
But the bad thing
was that she was a slut.
Man, this is such an old story.
It's been a long time.
But that Soo ah, you see...
Hey, w hat's going on? Hey!
Joo hw an!
What's w ith y ou?
Oh Daesu
My sister wasn't a slut.
You must accept this.
Since you got rid o f your bug
I had to come all the way here
to eavesdrop.
So that's why Joo hwan died.
Because o f you.
I'm going to kill y ou!
You son of a bitc h!
You motherfucking cocksucker!
We're not open yet.
Please come back in an hour.
Someone who got six gold teeth
recommended this place.
Mr. Park?
I had to move because o f you.
As an commemoration
I installed a new TV.
Do you like it?
There are so many channels.
Great, huh?
There are even some
who pre fer to stay here.
You lived in a place like this
for 15 years?
It felt like home
a fter 11 years though.
Come on.
I don't need money.
An enemy's enemy is a friend.
We threw away the hand
'cause it rotted.
Damn sons o f bitches.
I'll kick their asses.
So why'd you bring me here?
If I don't return a fter July 5th
then let her go.
While I was locked up here
I remember someone visiting me.
What did that person do?
Was it three times?
I put a hypnosis inducing
drug on your water.
Sodium Barbiturate?
TV man knows it all.
That's nonsense.
Even though it was a
Catholic school
she wouldn't die because o f
a couple o f rumours.
There's probably another reason.
Could she have been pregnant?
I really don't think
Soo ah was like that.
She was such a pure girl.
She didn't sleep with anyone.
But she did go out
with someone back then.
So who was that guy?
I have no idea.
Choon shim?
You knew Lee Soo ah, right?
Who was her boyfriend?
Don't know?
Shut up! What would you know
about friendship!
Shut the crap.
Then who'd know?
Who? Joo hwan?
What?
Yeah, I know him.
But how'd he know?
Yeah? Really?
Okay, hung up.
I'll call you back.
Choon shim said
she heard it from Joo hwan
and that you'd know the best.
Ring, ring, move aside.
You'll get hurt if y ou hesitate.
Oh Daesu! Look at you!
Put it out!
I'm trans ferring today.
To Soeul.
So butt out, Miss Kim.
You good for nothing!
You're Oh Daesu, right?
- And you're Miss...
- You're popular among the girls.
You know how rumours are.
I heard you're really funny.
Say something.
Me being popular
is such a big hassle.
There's this father and son.
They went to the public bath, and...
See you later.
See you later!
Third grade, third grade pals.
- Come on.
- Wait.
- Come here.
- I won't.
- Hurry and come here.
- Okay, okay.
Satis fied?
- Raise this up.
- Come on.
- Raise it.
- I won't.
What?
It tickles.
Give it here.
- What are you doing?
- Let me see.
What are you doing?
- Stop.
Go away.
- Was it really Soo ah?
- I don't know her name.
All I know is that she's in your room
a she rides a red bike.
Have a good trip.
See you in Seoul if I go.
Where are you going?
Going on a date
with Choon shim.
I'll kill you
if you shoot your mouth.
No w ay.
You get loc ked u p for 15 y ears
just for doing that?
Was that suc h a big c rime?
Be it a grain of s and or roc k
in w ater they sink as the s ame.
That's what Lee Woojin believes.
Then,
what does July 5th stand for?
That's the day
Lee Soo ah died.
Now it's over.
Instead o f seeking revenge
you wanted to find out
why you were imprisoned, right?
Now we'll run away where
he can never find us, right?
I can't end it like this.
Seeking revenge
has become a part o f me.
But you don't even know
where he lives.
Like a gazelle
from the hand of the hunter.
Like a bird
from the snare of the fow ler.
Free y ourself.
It's a phrase from
"Jamon" 6, verse 4.
Jamon in English
means Maxim.
And Evergreen s aid
he lives in a high tow er.
So six and four
must be just floors.
Fourth floor.
Sixth floor.
0 r the sixty forth floor?
P?
Please insert the code.
What would you
like me to pray?
Wrong entry.
Please insert again.
Dear Lord
please let me meet
a younger man next time.
Please let Woojin
bow next to Daesu
and make him
beg forgiveness.
You slept with your sister.
Let's go up and talk.
Take him!
Don't be so violent.
Feels great.
- You slept with our sister.
- I feel so re freshing.
And I started the rumours.
That's why your sister died.
Looking through the mirror
reminds me o f that day.
Erasing my memory and telling me
to find the truth was unfair.
I won,
so die like you promised.
You think you forgot that day
because you were hypnotized?
Are you sure?
Do you know the real reason
why you can't remember?
Let me tell you.
You just forgot.
Is that bland?
But it's true
that you just forgot.
Why?
Since it's not your business.
Your rumour
grew so out o f proportion
that Soo ah being pregnant
became a rumour.
My sister got sucked
into that rumour.
And began believing it.
So her period stopped
and her belly began to swell.
Funny, isn't it?
Ever though how'd a girl feel
bearing both her child and nephew?
Understand now?
Your tongue
got my sister pregnant.
It wasn't Lee Woojin's dick
it was Oh Daesu's tongue.
Is that why you killed your sister?
Even though how'd the boy feel
impregnating a child and nephew?
You were probably a fraid.
Afraid that everyone will know
once the baby's born.
When you realized that she
imagined it a fter you killed her.
I understand your hate.
They said Soo ah died alone at the
dam, but who took this photo?
And what about the date July 5th?
This is no fun.
I'll just finish what I was say ing.
Listen care fully. My story is fun.
Ever heard o f
posthypnotic suggestion?
You suggest something
during hypnosis
and then it's acted out
in your wakened state.
Still haven't figured it out?
"You lead a stranger to your place.
Who the hell are you?"
What about y ou, y ou bastard?
We hypnotized both o f you.
One very fortunate thing
was that both o f you were
highly receptive to hypnosis
compared to others.
Isn't this fun?
One word gets you pregnant
one word gets you in love.
But no matter how much you two
are receptive to hypnosis
or no matter how good o f a
hypnotist Mrs. Yoo is
getting people
to fall in love isn't eas y.
So do you know how we did it?
Your first suggestion
was to go to that restaurant
a fter your release.
Next, to react to
the cell phone's melody.
When you heard this
you were to say something.
Who are you?
Do you like your clothes?
And Mido was to react
to the man who were to say this.
When she grabs your hand
your reaction would be...
Your gravest mistake wasn't
failing to find the answer.
You can't find the right answers
if you ask the wrong questions.
It's not
"Why did Woojin imprison me?"
It's
"Why did he release me?"
Once again
Why did Woojin release
Daesu a fter...
15 years?
"Laugh, and the world laughs with
you. Weep, and you will weep alone."
Mr. Han!
Mido.
She doesn't know, right?
Why did you hide her there?
You thought he'd hate me.
Couldn't you figure it out
that it was a trap?
How can you protect your woman
with that brain o f yours?
I've been secretly raising Mido
since she was three.
What's wrong with you?
And Mr. Park's hand?
You moron.
Know that new prison o f his?
He said he had to move
so I bought him that building
for his hand!
Daesu!
A box is here.
It's that same violet box.
- He's telling me to open it.
- No!
Don't open it no matter what!
If you open it
something terrible will happen.
What's in it?
You know, don't you?
Mido,
sweet pea, wait a little longer.
I'll be there very soon.
Can't you come right now?
I'm scared.
My sweet pea,
you can wait for me, right?
- Yes.
- Good.
Good girl.
I'll call you very soon, okay?
I beg you...
Please, don't tell Mido.
What has she done wrong?
You know it was all my fault.
I have...!
I have committed
a terrible sin
to your sister.
And I was very wrong to you.
I'm really sorry.
So please leave Mido alone, okay?
If Mido finds out the truth
you asshole
I'll rip your whole body apart
so no one will be able
to find your body any where.
Why? Because I'm
going to chew it all down.
Woojin!
Woojin, I made a mistake.
Please forget what I said.
Sir! Boss!
Woojin!
We are the
Evergreen Old Boy s, remember?
With the energy
from a green pine tree
the great Sangkok High...
I'll do whatever you want.
I'll do anything.
I beg you.
Woojin, if you want me
to be a dog, I will!
I'm Woojin's Dog from now on!
I'm your pupp y!
Look, I'm wagging my tail.
I'm a dog. I'll guard the house.
I'll be your slave dog.
The box...
Just leave it closed.
Now...
What joy will I live for?
Daesu...
It really hurts.
But I'm enduring it.
You must know this.
My sister and I loved each other
even though we knew everything.
Could it be the same
with you two?
Soo ah.
Woojin.
I know you've been scared
so let go o f me, okay?
Remember me, okay?
I have no regrets.
What about you?
This is the w hole adventure
I w ent throu gh until now.
Thank y ou for listening
to a terrible story till the end.
I ho pe that y ou understand
the reason for sending a letter.
The reason for that is
that I have no tongue.
To be honest
I have no reason to help you.
But you see?
I was touched by
this last sentence.
"Even though I'm worse
than even a beast
Don't I have the right to live?"
The hypnosis could go wrong
and disturb your memories.
Will that be okay?
If you're ready
stare at that tree.
The tree is slowly changing
into a concrete column.
You're now in Woo jin's penthouse.
It's a dreary night.
The sound of y our footste ps
to the w indow permeats the room.
When I ring my bell
y ou'll be s plit into tw o persons.
The one w ho doesn't know
the sec ret is 0 h Daesu.
The one w ho kee ps
the sec ret is the Monster.
When I ring the bell again
the Monster w ill turn around
and be gin w alking.
With eac h ste p
y ou age one y ear.
When the Monster
reac hes seventy he w ill die.
There's no need to w orry.
It w ill be a very peaceful death.
Now, good luc k to y ou.
What's wrong?
Look at you.
Were you with somebody?
I love you, Daesu.