Berlin, Germany.
You didnt wake me.
You were sleeping.
You let me sleep because you cant
bear to have breakfast with me.
Nothing could be further from the
truth. I boiled you an egg. See?
Id hardly have boiled you an egg
if I didnt want to see you.
Tea or coffee?
Does any woman ever stay long
enough to find out
What the hell
goes on in your head?
What are you doing tonight?
Im seeing my daughter.
Your daughter? Youve kept very
quiet about her.
Have I?
Shes been abroad for a year.
Did you say tea?
Im going.
Give my love to your daughter.
Tickets please.
Neustadt, West Germany, 1958
Hey, you!
Your feets!
Hey, kid.
Up.
Its alright
Where do you live?
Its here.
Ill be fine now.
Thank you.
Goodbye
Look after yourself.
Im worried about him.
He looks terrible.
The boys saying he doesnt need a doctor.
- He does.
- I dont need a doctor.
Good then.
- Peter!
Were not going to argue about this.
Remind me, how old are you now?
Michaels fifteen.
Its scarlet fever.
Hell be in bed
for several months. At least.
In completely isolation.
Emily, keep away. Hes contagious.
Emily?
How are you feeling?
Better.
I meant to tell you..
the day I got ill...
a woman helped me.
She helped you?
Yes. She brought me home.
Do you have her address?
Yes?
I brought you these flowers.
To say thank you.
Put them over there.
I would have come earlier, but Ive
been in bed for three months.
Youre better now?
Yes, thank you.
Have you always been weak?
Oh no. Id never been ill before.
Its incredibly boring.
Theres nothing to do.
I couldnt even be
bothered to read.
Well, thank you again.
Wait.
Ill walk with you.
I have to go to work.
Wait in the hall while I change.
There are two more buckets downstairs.
You can fill them and bring them up.
You look ridiculous, look at you, kid.
You cant go home like that.
Take off your clothes.
Ill run you a bath.
Do you always take a bath in
your trousers?
Its all right, I wont look.
I'll get you a towel.
Thats why you came back.
Youre so beautiful
What are you talking about?
Look at me kid.
Slowly.
Youve inconvenienced your mother.
How many more times?
Ive said Im sorry.
You scared her.
- I got lost, thats all.
Thats why I was late.
Can I have some more?
How can anyone get lost in their
own home town?
I meant to head for the castle, I
ended up at the sports-field.
Theyre in opposite directions.
- Its none of your business.
Hes lying.
Hes not lying.
Michael never lies.
Dad, Ive decided, I want to go
back to school tomorrow.
The doctor says you need another
three weeks.
Well Im going.
Peter!
Like this?
That's right!
Not so fast.
It's alright!
Do it again.
What's your name?
What?
Your name?
Why do you want to know?
Ive been here three times.
I want to know your name.
What's wrong was that?
Nothing, kid...
There's nothing wrong with that.
It's Hanna.
It looks so suspicious.
Whats yours, kid?
Michael.
So I'm with Michael.
Hanna.
The notion of secrecy is central to
Western literature.
You may say the
whole idea of character
in fiction is defined by people holding
specific information
which for various reasons.
- Sometimes perverse... Sometimes noble
They are determined not to disclose.
You never tell me what youve been
studying.
Studying?
At school.
Do you learn languages?
Yes.
What languages?
Latin.
Say something in Latin.
Quo, quo scelesti ruitis? Aut cur
dexteris aptantur enses conditi?
Aut cur dexteris aptantur
enses conditi?
Its Horace.
Its wonderful.
Do you want some Greek?
Oi men ippeon stroton oi de pesedon
oi da naon phais epi gan malainan
emmenai kalliston, ego de ken otto
tis eratai.
Its beautiful.
How can you tell?
How do you know
when youve no idea what it means?
What are you studying in German?
I'm studying a play
Well, Im writing a play.
By a writer called Gotthold Ephraim Lessing.
Youve heard of him?
The plays called Emilia Galotti.
You can read it.
Id rather listen to you.
Allright.
Act One.
Scene One.
The setting:
one of the princes chambers.
The Prince:
I'm not very good.
Go On!
"Complaints, nothing but complaints."
For goodness sake, is there anything,
live for work?"
just imagine that people actually envy us.
Youre good at it, arent you?
Good at what?
Reading.
What's funny?
I didnt think I was good
at anything.
What are you doing?
What is it?
Why did you treat me like if you didn't know me?
You didnt want to know me!
You can see I was in the first carriage.
So why did you sit in the second?
What did you think I was doing?
Why the hell do you think I was there?
How should I know.
I need a bath.
You know I've been working.
I'd like to be by myself
Could you please, leave?
I... I didnt mean to upset you.
You dont have the power to upset me.
You dont matter enough to upset me.
I dont know what to say.
Ive never been with a woman before.
Weve been together four weeks
and I cant live without you.
I cant!
Even the thought of it kills me.
Kid, you thought we could make love
in a tram?
kid, myla the e that we will
kocha is the tram?
Is it true what you said?
That I dont matter to you?
Do you forgive me?
Do you love me?
Do you have a book?
Yes, I have.
I took something
with me this morning.
What is it?
"The Odyssey" by Homer.
It's my homework.
Were changing the order we do things.
Read to me first, kid.
Then we make love.
"The Odyssey" by Homer.
Whats an odyssey?
Its a journey.
He sets out on a journey.
Good.
Sing to me of the Man, Muse, the
man of twists and turns...
Driven time and again off course,
once he had plundered
The hallowed heights of Troy.
Come here!
"You press your hand
to his lips."
"She was dead"
"Pass all hed."
"I poked into the place aways and
encountered a little open patch
as big as a bedroom.
All hung around with vines.
and found a man lying there asleep,
and by Jinks,
it was my old Jim..."
"- When you learn it. I'll rec catch up land with shout you...
Lady Chatterley felt his naked
flesh against her as he came into
flesh against her as he came into her.
For a moment he was still
inside her...
This is disgusting.
Where did you get this?
I borrowed it from someone at school.
You should be ashamed.
Go on.
Blistering Barnacles and a
thundering typhoon. It is water.'
But what on earth did you expect
it to be?
Whisky.
Whisky! By thunder, whisky.
Whisky?
Come now captain, you
cant be serious.
Thats enough for today, kid.
I was wondering...
Do you think you could get some time off?
Maybe we could go for a trip.
What sort of trip?
Bicycling holiday.
Just for two days.
Ive got a guide-book.
Ive worked out the route.
Look!
What do you think?
I think you like planning, dont you?
Im not frightened.
Im not frightened of anything.
The more suffering,
the more I love.
Danger will only increase my love,
it will sharpen it,
it will give it spice.
Ill be the only angel you need.
You will leave life even more beautiful
than you entered it.
Heaven will take
you back and look at you and say
Only one thing can make a soul
complete,
and that thing is love.
Excuse me.
Do you know what would you like?
What are you having?
You order.
Ill have what you have.
Two a skip the potato...
Thank you.
I hope your mother was happy.
She enjoyed her meal very much.
Here, let me show you where were going.
Its OK, kid.
I dont want to know.
- What are you doing?
- Im writing a poem. About you.
About you.
Can I hear it?
Its not ready.
Ill read it to you one day.
- Morning Henry.
- Good morning, Mr. Berg.
- Room 306
- Thank you.
- You all right, Michael?
- Im fine.
Youd better hurry.
You know what shes like.
- For now!
- Good luck.
Please, Stand!
Please, sit down.
The defender, please!
- Hello
- Hello.
Good morning, ladies.
Gentlemen, please welcome your
new fellow-students,
treat them with courtesy.
Sit down!
Hello!
My name is Sophie.
Im Michael.
"The Odyssey"
Take off your books.
Everyone believes that Homers
subject is homecoming. In fact,
The Odyssey is a book about a journey.
Home is a place you dream of...
Berg, I dont mean to distract you,
but were meant to studying Homer,
not studying Sophia.
Its wonderful, isnt it?
Wonderful.
Its going to be a great summer.
Why do you leave early?
He always leaves early.
Do you have large for a job?
See you tomorrow.
Im sorry Im late.
I was held up at school.
I have a new book.
"The Lady with the Little Dog."
By Anton Chekhov.
The talk was that a new face had
appeared on the promenade,
a lady with a little dog.
Schmitz!
One moment, please!
I read the reports on you
Every single word.
Excelent!
To work with me in the office.
Were going to promote you.
Congratulations.
Let's get out of here...
Come on! Michael, We're leaving.
Let's Go!
This is a surprise to
your birthday.
What is it?
I'm sorry, really...
We thought youd like it.
We have a beer, will dances.
I promised someone.
Michael? Please!
"Here and there the reflection of stars
and the lights..."
Oh kid, kid. Stop.
What?
Stop.
Whats wrong now?
Nothings wrong.
Its nothing.
You know?
You never ask,
You never bother to
ask how I am.
You never say.
It just happens to be my birthday.
Its my birthday, thats all.
In fact, youve never even asked when it is.
Look if you want a fight, kid?...
No, I dont want a fight.
Whats wrong with you?
What business is it of yours?
Its always on your terms.
Everything!
We do what you want.
Its always what you want.
My friends were giving me a party!
Well then why are you here?
Go back to your party.
Isnt that what you want?
And its always me that has to apologize.
You dont have to apologize.
No-one
has to apologize.
War and Peace, kid.
Now you must go back to your friends.
Michael. You all right?
It's him
Good.
Get the boy something to eat.
I think we all knew youd come back
to us eventually.
Mr Berg. It is eight oclock.
Your daughter.
Thank you.
Julia.
I'll not kept you waiting
I was early.
Welcome back.
So how will you decide?
I dont know.
Im happy back in Berlin, I suppose.
Youve seen your mother?
I wanted to get away, that's all
It was Paris,
but it could have been anywhere.
Away from your parents?
Im aware I was difficult.
I wasnt
always open with you.
Im not open with anyone.
I knew you were distant.
You know?
Id always assumed it was my fault.
Julia.
How wrong can you be?
- See you soon.
- Ill see you soon.
- Good night, Dad.
- Good night, Julia.
Those of you for the special seminar group.
Please stay on in this room.
Professor Rohl will be here in a moment.
Well...
we seem to be quite a small group.
A small group and a select one.
Clearly, this is going to be a
unique seminar.
We're going to start reading this, gentlemen.
- Karl Jaspers.
- And ladies...
"The question of German guilt."
So this is where you are.
Yes.
Come in.
You take work seriously.
Oh I dont know.
Youre rather a serious boy.
Its how I was brought up.
What about you?
Are you serious?
Youre sure you want to work tonight?
But I wont work every night.
See you tomorrow.
We need help.
Why all the police?
Theyre worried about demonstrators.
For or against?
both.
Is a circus.
All photographers are now asked to leave.
The defendants, please..
Please sit down!
The first thing Im going to do is hear motions
from each of the defendants lawyers.
Theyre going to be arguing that
theres no reason
to keep the defendants in jail until the
outcome of the forthcoming trial.
Do you want a pen?
Ive got a pen.
Hanna Schmitz.
Your name is Hanna Schmitz?
Yes.
Can you speak louder please?
My name is Hanna Schmitz.
Thank you.
You were born on October 21st, 1922?
Yes.
At Hermannstadt.
And youre now 43 years old?
Yes.
You joined the SS in 1943?
What was your reason for joining?
You were working at the Siemens
factory at the time?
Yes.
Youd recently been offered a promotion.
Why did you prefer to join the SS?
Objection
Ill re-phrase my question.
Im trying to ascertain if she joined the SS freely.
Of her own free will.
I heard there were jobs
Go on...
I was working at Siemens when I
heard the SS was recruitin
Did you know the kind of work youd
be expected to do?
They were looking for guards.
I applied for a job.
And you worked first at Auschwitz?
Yes.
Until 1944. Then you were moved to
a smaller camp near Cracow?
- Yes.
- Are you OK?
Im fine.
... You then helped move the prisoners west
in the winter of 1944 in the so-called death marches?
- So what did you think?
- I do not know.
It wasnt quite what I expecting.
Wasnt it?
In what way?
What were you expecting?
I thought it was exciting.
Exciting?
Why? Why did you think it exciting?
Because its justice.
Societies think they operate by
something called morality
But they dont.
They operate by something called law.
Youre not guilty of anything merely
by working at Auschwitz.
8,000 people worked at Auschwitz.
Precisely 19 have been
convicted, and only 6 for murder.
To prove murder you have to prove intent.
Thats the law.
The question is never Was it wrong?
but Was it legal?
And not by our laws.
No.
by the laws at the time.
with the law of the times.
But isnt that...
What?
Narrow?
Oh, Yes. The law is narrow.
On the other hand, I suspect people
who kill other people
tend to be aware that its wrong.
Miss Schmitz, youre familiar with this book..
Yes.
Parts of it have already been read
out in court.
Its by a survivor,
a prisoner who survived
Ilana Mather...
She was in the camp, wasnt she,
when she was a child?
She was with her mother.
Yes.
In the book, she describes a
selection process.
At the end of the months labour, every month,
sixty inmates were selected.
They were picked out to be sent from the
satellite camp back to Auschwitz.
Thats right, isnt it?
Yes.
Its right.
And so far, each of your fellow defendants
has specifically denied
being part of that process.
Now Im going to ask you.
Were you part of it?
Yes.
So you helped make the selection?
You admit that?
Then...
tell me, how did that selection happen?
There were six guards,
So we decided wed choose ten people each.
Thats how we did it - every month.
Wed all choose 10.
Are you saying your fellow
defendants took part in the process?
We all did.
Even though theyve denied it?
Youre saying you
took part in the process.
than the "I", true
Ms Schmitz?
Did you not realise...
you were sending these women to their deaths?
Yes, but...
there were new arrivals,
new women were arriving all the time. So...
of course we had to move
some of the old ones on.
Im not sure you understand...
We couldnt keep everyone.
There wasnt room.
No, but what Im saying
let me rephrase: to make room,
you were picking women out and saying
You you and you have to be sent back to be killed?
Well, what would you have done?
Should I never have signed up at Siemens?
Ms. Mather, theyre ready for you now.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Where's Michael?
- I do not know.
In your book you describe the
process of selection...
Yes.
You were made to work and then,
when you were no longer any
use to them,
then they sent you
back to Auschwitz to be killed.
Are there people here today who
made that selection?
Yes.
I need you to identify them
Can you please point them out?
Her
And her.
her.
Thank You!
Please continue.
Each of the guards would choose a
certain number of women.
Hanna Schmitz chose differently.
In what way differently?
She had favourites.
Girls, mostly young.
We all remarked on it,
she gave them food and places to sleep.
In the evening,
she asked them to join her.
We all thought
Well, you can imagine what we thought
And then we found out...
...she was making these women read aloud to her.
They were reading to her.
At first we thought this guard, this guard is...
more sensitive,
she's more human,
she's kinder.
Often she chose the
weak, the sick,
she picked them out,
she seemed to be protecting them almost.
But then she dispatched them.
Is that kinder?
I want to move on now to the march.
As I understand it, you and your
daughter were marched for many months.
Yes. It was the winter of 1944.
Our camp was closed down,
we were told we had to move on.
But the plan kept changing every day.
Women were dying all around us in the snow.
Half of us died on the march.
My daughter says in the book,
less a death march, more a death gallop.
Please tell us about the night in the church.
That night we actually thought we were lucky
because we had a roof
over our heads.
Go on!
Wed arrived in a village, as always,
the guards took the best quarters,
they took the priests house.
But they let us sleep in a church.
There was a bombing raid.
In the middle of the night.
The Church was sit.
At first we could only hear
the fire, it was in the steeple.
Then we could see burning beams,
and they began to crash to the floor.
Everyone rushed,
rushed to the doors.
But the doors had been
locked on the outside.
The church burned down?
Nobody came to open the doors?
Is that right?
Nobody.
Even though you were all burning to death?
How many people were killed?
Everyone was killed.
But you survived?
Thank you.
I want to thank you for
coming to this country
today to testify.
I dont know. I dont know what
were doing any more.
Dont you?
You keep telling us to think like lawyers,
but theres something
disgusting about this.
How so?
This didnt happen to the Germans.
It happened to the Jews.
What are we trying to do?
Were trying to understand.
Six women locked three hundred Jews
in a church,
and let them burn.
What is there to understand?
Tell me, Im asking:
what is there to understand?
I started out believing in this trial.
I thought it was great.
Now I think its just a diversion.
Yes?
Diversion from what?
You choose six women,
You put them on trial,
You say They were the
evil ones, they were the guilty ones.
Because one of the victims happened
to write a book!
Thats why theyre
on trial and nobody else.
Do you know how many camps
there were in Europe?
People go on about how much did
everyone know?
Who knew?
What did they know?
Everyone knew.
Our Parents, Our teachers.
That isnt the question.
The question is
How could you let it happen?
And - better - Why didnt you kill
yourself when you found out?
Thousands! Thats how many.
There were thousands of camps.
Everyone knew.
Look at that woman...
Which woman?
The woman youre always staring at.
Im sorry but you are.
I dont know which woman you mean.
You know what Id do?
Put the gun in my hand,
Id shoot her myself.
Shoot then All.
Why did you not unlock the doors?
Ive asked all of you and Im
getting no answer.
Two of the victims are in this court.
They deserve an answer.
Here, this is the SS report.
You all have copies.
This is the report which was
written, approved and signed by all
of you immediately after the event.
In the written report, you all
claim you didnt even know about
the fire until after it happened.
But that isnt true, is it?
Well? It isnt true.
I dont know what youre asking.
The first thing Im asking is,
why didnt you unlock the doors?
Obviously. For the obvious reason.
- We couldnt.
- Why couldnt you?
We were guards.
Our job was to guard the prisoners.
We couldnt just let them escape.
I see.
And if they escaped, then
youd be blamed, youd be charged,
you might even be executed?
Well then?
If we opened the doors, then there
would have been chaos.
How could we have restored order?
It happened so fast. It was snowing.
The bombs - There were
flames all over the village.
Then the screaming began.
It got worse and worse.
And if theyd all come rushing out,
we couldnt just let them escape.
We couldnt.
We were responsible for them.
So you did know what was happening?
You did know? You made a choice.
You let them die
rather than risk letting them escape.
The other defendants have made an
allegation against you.
Have you heard this allegation?
They say you were in charge.
It isnt true.
I was just one of the guards.
She was in charge
She was!
It was her idea.
Of course she was.
Did you write the report?
No. No.
We all discussed what to say.
We all wrote it together.
She wrote it!
She wrote the report!
Is that true?
Yes you did!
Does it matter who did?
She wrote it!
I need to see a sample of your handwriting.
My handwriting?
Yes.
I need to establish who wrote the report.
Im sorry, but I really dont see how thats appropriate.
Nearly 20 years have gone by.
Take her this piece of paper.
Counsel, approach the bench.
Are you really going to compare
handwriting of twenty years ago,
with handwriting of today?
Counsel, approach the bench.
There is no need.
I wrote the report.
Silence, please.
Order.
Youve been skipping seminars.
I have a piece of information.
Concerning one of the defendants.
Something theyre not admitting.
What information?
You dont need me to tell you.
Its perfectly clear
you have a moral
obligation to disclose it to the court.
It happens this information is
favourable to the defendant.
It can help her case.
It may even affect the outcome,
certainly the sentencing.
So?
Theres a problem.
The defendant herself is determined
to keep this information secret.
A moment, please.
What are her reasons?
Because shes ashamed.
Ashamed of what?
Have you spoken to her?
- Of course not.
Why "of course not"?
I cant.
I cant do that.
I cant talk to her.
What we feel isnt important. Its
utterly unimportant.
The only question is what we do.
If people like you dont learn from
what happened to people like me,
then what the hell is the point of anything?
Schmitz!
You have a visitor.
Quiet Please!
Michael Berg!
Times up.
Are you came in?
Youve taken your time.
What is it?
Where you're going?
Im sorry.
I need to sleep by myself.
Nazi
Silence in the court!
All rise!
The court finds guilty the
defendants Rita Beckhart,
Karolina Steinhof, Regina Kreutz,
Angela Zieber, Andrea Luhmann
jointly aiding and abetting murder in three
hundred cases.
The court finds the defendant
Hanna Schmitz
of murder in three hundred cases.
The court sentences the accused as follows.
Beckhart Rita, Karolina Steinhof,
Regina Kreutz, Angela Zieber
and Andrea Luhmann
you will each serve a total sentence in
prison of four years and three months.
Hanna Schmitz,
in view of your own
admissions and your special role,
you are in a different category.
The court sentences the accused
Schmitz to imprisonment for life.
Where are we going?
I said: Ill tell you when we get there.
You told me you liked surprises.
I like surprises.
Shes grown, hasnt she?
I dont know. Its so long since I
saw her, Michael, how can I tell?
Is my fault.
We shouldnt have come unannounced.
Daddys going to live in his own house.
Mother, Im afraid Ive have some bad news.
Julia knows.
Weve already told her.
Gertrud and I are getting a divorce.
You didnt come for your fathers
funeral, but you come for this?
its not easy for me to
visit this town.
Were you really so unhappy?
- Thats not what Im saying. Its not what I meant.
- Well then?
You mustnt worry about Gertrud.
Im going to look after her.
And anyway, lets face it, shes already
a state prosecutor,
she earns far more than I do.
Michael, Im not worried about Gertrud.
Im worried about you.
Sing to me of the Man, Muse,
the man of twists and turns
Driven time and again
off course, once he had plundered
The hallowed heights of Troy...
215- mail.
217- mail.
121966215.
Number.
open it.
Testing. Testing. 1-2-3.
Testing. Testing.
"The Odyssey." by Homer
Sing to me of the Man, Muse,
the man of twists and turns
Driven time and again
off course, once he had plundered
The hallowed heights of Troy...
The Lady with the Little Dog
by Anton Chekhov.
"Talk of a new face, which
is a display of the prom..."
The Lady with the Little Dog
I want to take out a book.
Which book?
Do you have "The Lady with the Little Dog"?
Whats your name?
Hanna Schmitz.
The Lady with the Little Dog,
42813 The Lady with the Little Dog,
1,2,3,4,5,6.
Thanks for the latest, kid. I really liked it.
- There is no letter?
- No letter.
Sign it.
Please, send more romance
I think schiller need a woman. "
Are you getting my letter?
Write to me kid.
- Mr Michael Berg?
- Yes.
Thank you for calling me.
You got my letter?
I have it here.
As I say, Hanna Schmitz is coming
up for release very soon.
Hanna has been in prison for over
twenty years.
She has no family. She has no friends.
Youre her only contact.
And Im told you dont visit her.
No. I dont.
When she gets out, shes going to need a job.
Shes going to need somewhere to live.
You cant imagine how frightening the modern
world will seem to her.
I have no one else to ask
If you dont take responsibility for her,
then Hanna has no future at all.
Its kind of you.
Thank you for letting me know.
Youre Michael Berg?
I'm Louisa Brenner.
Good Morning!
We were expecting you earlier.
I should warn you: for a long time Hanna
held herself together.
She was very purposeful.
In the last few years
Shes different.
Shes let herself go.
I'm taking you straight to the canteen.
Theyre just finishing lunch.
Before you.
Youve grown up, kid
Ive got a friend whos a tailor,
he makes my suits. Hell give you a job.
And Ive found you somewhere to live.
Its a nice place.
Quite small but nice.
I think youll like it.
- Youll like it.
- Thank you.
There are various social programmes
cultural stuff I can
sign you up for.
And theres a
public library very close.
You read a lot?
I prefer being read to.
Thats over now, isnt it?
Did you get married?
I did. Yes I did.
We have a daughter.
Im not seeing as much of her as I would like.
Id like to see a great deal more of her.
The marriage didnt last.
Have you spent a lot of time
thinking about the past?
You mean, with you??
No. No,
I didnt mean with me.
Before the trial I never thought
about the past.
I never had to.
And now?
What do you feel now?
It doesnt matter what I feel.
It doesnt matter what I think.
The dead are still dead.
I wasnt sure what youd learnt.
I have learnt, kid.
Ive learnt to read.
Ill pick you up next week, OK?
That sounds a good plan.
We can do quietly, or shall we make a
big fuss?
Quietly.
OK. Quietly.
Take care, kid.
- You too.
See you next week.
I have come to collect Hanna Schmitz.
Please, take a sit
She didnt pack.
She never intended to leave.
"The talk was a new face.."
The Lady with the Little Dog
She left me a message,
a sort of will.
Ill read out the bit that
concerns you.
There is money in the old tea tin.
Give it to Michael Berg.
He should send it, alongside the 7,000 marks
in the bank,
to the daughter who survives the fire.
Its for her.
She should decide what to do with it.
And tell Michael I said hello.
- Ms Mather?
- Yes.
- Michael Berg?
Youre Michael Berg.
I was expecting you.
- Please.
- Thank you.
So you must tell me: Exactly
brings you to the United States?
I was already here. I was at a
conference in Boston.
Youre a lawyer?
I was intrigued by your letter
But I cant say I wholly understood it.
You attended the trial?
Yes. Almost twenty years ago.
I was a law student.
I remember you,
I remember your mother very clearly.
My mother died in Israel
- A good many years ago.
I'm sorry.
Go On, please!
Perhaps you heard. Hanna Schmitz
recently died.
She killed herself.
She was a friend of yours?
A kind of friend.
Its as simple as this.
Hanna was illiterate for the
greater part of her life.
Is that an explanation
of her behaviour?
No.
Or an excuse?
No. No. She taught herself to read
when she was in prison.
I sent her tapes.
Shed always liked being read to.
Why dont you start by being
honest with me?
What was the nature of your friendship?
When I was young
I had an affair with Hanna.
Im not sure I can help you, Mr. Berg.
Or rather, even if I could
Im not willing to
I was almost sixteen when
I took up with her.
The affair only lasted a summer. But..
But what?
I see.
And did Hanna Schmitz acknowledge
the effect shed had on your life?
Shed done much worse to other people.
Ive never told anyone.
People ask all the time what I
learned in the camps.
But the camps
werent therapy.
What do you think
these places were? Universities?
We didnt go there to learn.
One becomes very clear about these things.
What are you asking for?
Forgiveness for her?
Or do you just want to feel better yourself?
My advice, go to the theatre,
if you want catharsis, please.
Go to literature.
Don't go to the camps.
Nothing comes out of the camps.
Nothing.
What she wanted...
what she wanted
was to leave you her money.
I have with me.
To do what?
As you think fit.
Here.
When I was a little girl,
I had a tea-tin for my treasures.
Not quite like this.
It had Cyrillic lettering.
I took it with me to the camp,
but it got stolen.
What was in it?
Oh. Sentimental things.
A piece of hair from our dog.
Some tickets to operas my father had taken me to.
It wasnt stolen for its contents.
It was the tin itself
which was valuable,
what you could do with it.
Theres nothing I can do with this money.
If I give it to anything associated with the extermination
of the Jews, then to me it will seem
like absolution and that is something
Im neither willing nor
in a position to grant.
I was thinking maybe an
organization to encourage literacy.
Good.
Do you know if theres a
Jewish organization?
Ill be surprised if there isnt.
Theres a Jewish organisation for everything.
Not that illiteracy is
a very Jewish problem.
Why dont you find out?
Send them the money.
Shall I do it in Hannas name?
As you think fit.
Ill keep the tin.
Thank you.
January 1995
Where are we going?
I thought you liked surprises.
I do. I do like surprises.
Who was she?
Thats what I wanted to tell you.
Thats why were here.
So tell me.
I was 15,
I was coming home from
school,
I was ill...
is a help to me a woman.