Okay.
911 emergency.
I need an ambulance.
I have you at 9212 West Third
Street in Los Angeles.
Yes, room number 2.
What's the emergency?
There's been a suicide.
Who's the victim?
I am.
In seven days,
God created the world.
And in seven seconds...
... I shattered mine.
- I can have four new fillets overnight.
- Oh, no. No, thank you.
What is your name again? Ezra?
Is that right?
Yes, sir. I'll just need
your first and last name...
...so I can call up your account.
- You know what?
Here's what I'm thinking, Ezra. I think
I'm gonna mail you the meat back...
...so you can see firsthand the type
of dog food that you're peddling.
That won't be necessary, sir.
So how about we just start
with your last name?
Thomas.
And don't even get me started
on the pork.
- Have you tried the pork?
- Well, no, sir.
I'm not much of a meat eater myself,
but I hear really great things...
...about the pork.
- Oh, so you don't eat pork at all?
- No, sir.
Are you Jewish?
Is that why you don't eat pork, Ezra?
Well, can we...?
What's your first name, Mr. Thomas?
Ben.
Hold on, what was that voice?
I don't... I don't have an order
for a Ben Thomas.
Ezra, what was that voice?
- What voice?
- Are you blind?
- Excuse me?
- You're kidding me.
A blind beef salesman
who doesn't eat meat.
Now, that... That is rich.
That is rich.
Have you ever had sex, Ezra?
Did Lawrence in Accounting
put you up to this?
Because somehow I can't imagine
the blind, vegan...
... beef salesman having sex.
- Listen, I'm trying to help you, sir.
- You're trying to help me?
The blind beef salesman
is trying to help me?
I'm actually starting to feel
pretty bad for you, Ezra.
Because I look at my life, and it is
surrounded by so much beauty...
... and you can't see shit.
Is that fair?
Does that seem fair to you, Ezra?
Do you even know
what color the ocean is?
Do you?
- It's blue, sir.
- "It's blue, sir."
Say what you wanna say.
React.
Say what you wanna say to me.
Thank you for calling
Cheyenne Meats.
That's not what you wanna say,
you coward. You coward.
You blind, vegan, beef-salesman,
virgin coward!
- Goodbye, Mr. Thomas.
- Say what you wanna say.
Ken Anderson. Nicole Anderson.
Allie Anderson. Ed Rice.
Steven Phillips. Monica Freeman.
Sarah Jensen.
Ken Anderson! Nicole Anderson!
Allie Anderson! Ed Rice!
Steven Phillips! Monica Freeman!
And Sarah Jensen!
Hi, can I help you?
Yes. Hello, I'm looking for Emily.
- You're a friend of hers?
- Yes, ma'am.
- She's not home.
- Oh, goodness.
No, she left this morning.
She had to do some more tests.
She asked me to watch Duke
until she got back.
Okay.
You ever try mixing banana peel
into the soil?
- Really?
- It works, I swear.
Oh, would you by chance
know where I could find her?
Supervisor to 104.
Cardiac wing?
Take the elevator to the fifth floor
then turn left.
Thank you.
Well, that's what I was just saying.
It's absolutely impossible.
Hold the elevator.
Thank you.
Can I help you?
Yes. Good evening.
I'm here to see Emily Posa.
I'm sorry, visiting hours
are from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m.
You know, it is really important
I speak to her for just a moment.
You'll just have to come back
during visiting hours.
Thank you very much.
So if there is one thing
that I have learned...
...and you all should remember
about winning these contracts:
Three steps. First, tell them
what you're gonna tell them.
Step two, you tell them.
Step three,
tell them what you told them.
We are gonna close
by reminding them...
...that old girl has a 3-percent better
impulse from sea level to vacuum...
...and if they pass on that, quite
frankly, they deserve another Sputnik.
Now, if you will excuse me...
...I have a very lovely, very hungry
woman at home waiting for me.
Sarah.
Honey.
Everyone at work kept saying
it was daylight-savings time.
You were supposed
to be here a while ago.
- I kept saying it wasn't.
- This happens all the time. It's work.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- No, I'm angry with you.
I'm gonna be angry all night long.
- I'm angry with you.
- What are you doing?
How about that?
How about I'm angry with you?
- Hello?
- Hey, it's me. It's your brother.
Where are you?
I'm at the beach house.
Are you okay?
Of course.
Listen, why'd you disconnect
the landline?
The phone broke.
I don't need it anymore.
Did I? Did I do something?
No.
Not unless you're smoking again.
No, I've put on 20 pounds.
I'm in the best shape of my life.
Are you eating?
Are you taking care of yourself?
- You sound terrible again and...
- Yeah, I'm fine. Look, I gotta go.
Give Melanie and the kids
a hug and a kiss.
I'll talk to you later.
You take care of yourself.
Hold on. I know it's been a while,
but when you were staying here...
...you didn't take something of mine
by mistake, did you?
I remember giving you something.
You remember that?
Because I remember that very clearly.
Yeah. Yeah.
Just remember I love you.
Hi, my name is Ben Thomas.
I'm here to see Stewart Goodman.
Inez, look at me, please.
Inez. I'm speaking to you.
I understand you refused to take
your meds again. Is that true?
No, no, no.
Let's try using your words
this time, okay, Inez?
I mean, this silent treatment
isn't doing anybody any good.
Inez, how can we help you if...?
Okay, how about I come back
tomorrow...
...and see if you've changed
your mind, okay?
Thattagirl.
I thought I was coming
to your office today.
I was in the neighborhood. I thought
I'd stop by, save you the drive.
Terrific. Well, look, let's go talk
in my office, yeah? Come on.
I take a no-nonsense approach.
I mean, I cut the operating costs
of this place...
...over 17 percent last year alone.
- I'm sure that made them happy.
- Oh, hell, yeah.
Now, if I could only get
my own finances...
...in that kind of shape,
I wouldn't have you sitting here.
No offense.
That your new Beemer out front?
Ben, I mean, when I found out...
...that my bone-marrow transplant
wasn't successful...
I'm well aware of your
ongoing medical condition.
Things aren't looking
very promising for me.
Look...
...I have a bonus coming in January.
I just really need
this six-month extension.
Really, I mean, I am doing the very
best I can here, I promise you.
I'm gonna show myself out.
I'll be in touch.
Well, thank you. I appreciate it.
I mean, this way
everybody wins, right?
Hello.
My name is Ben.
I totally understand
if you don't wanna speak to me either.
But I would really like
to just have a moment of your time.
I'm trying to figure out
what kind of man Stewart Goodman is.
It is within my power to drastically
change his circumstances.
But I don't wanna give that man
a gift that he doesn't deserve.
I need you to tell me
whether or not he is a good person.
"The drug he gives me...
...makes me dizzy.
I want a new one."
Well, that sounds
very reasonable, Inez.
What else?
You can trust me.
What else, Inez?
He's punishing you?
How is he punishing you?
How is he punishing you, Inez?
Ben?
- Hey, Ben, where you going?
- Where's the washroom?
To the right. Is there a problem?
- Give her a bath, right now.
- Absolutely.
Thank you. Thank you.
You have the wrong
impression here.
I'm gonna stop by
from time to time...
...make sure you're showing
these people some respect.
Look, this is
a misunderstanding, okay?
You don't treat people like that.
Let me explain, okay, Ben?
- And I'm not giving you an extension.
- Ben!
I'm not giving you anything.
I almost believed you,
you son of a bitch.
I almost believed.
Okay. Grip and rip.
This time it's gonna be
a lot different.
Hey.
- Hey, Michelle.
- Hey.
- Good to see you.
- You too.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Hey, man.
- Hey. What are you doing here?
Just coming to make sure that she
is still kicking your ass at everything.
And I am.
- Can we have a sec, hon?
- Yeah.
All right.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm good. You said you were
gonna call me on the 15th.
- Today is the 19th.
- I know.
Doctor didn't have the results,
so I had no information to give you.
Still, you should call me.
- Yeah, I know. Yes, I know.
- We're still friends. Right?
Yeah. I'm just...
I'm doing some soul-searching,
you know?
Don't do that.
- We have a plan.
- I know.
- Do what you promised me.
- I will.
You know, they rent clubs
up at the clubhouse.
I'm well aware of that.
I think I'm gonna keep my ass
unkicked today.
Were you looking at him,
or were you looking at me?
Actually, I was just sitting here.
Am I doing it wrong?
I think I saw you
in the elevator the other day.
Oh, yes.
Actually, you are being audited.
My name is Ben Thomas.
I'm with the IRS,
and you owe the government...
...$56, 240.19.
I know.
And now you get me.
Would you have a seat, please,
Miss Posa?
So I've been looking over
the income statements...
...from the last three years.
- 2005...
- Were...?
Were you in my room
the other night?
No, ma'am, I was not
in your room the other night.
That's not exactly IRS protocol.
So I've been looking over
'05, '06 and '07.
There seems to be quite a disparity
between what you claimed and...
Mr. Thomas?
I just got discharged.
So, you know,
unless you're gonna, like...
...haul me off
to some IRS jail or something...
...I'd really like to get home now.
- Oh, sure. No problem.
- Okay.
I'll be in touch.
Welcome to the Travel Inn.
Can I help you?
I need a room.
How many hours?
About two weeks.
Clear it! That's it, that's it!
All right, come on! Vamos, Manny!
All right, all right. That's it, that's it.
Hey!
- What you want?
- Break it up!
- You want some of this?
- Get off! Get off!
Hey, Rico, knock it off!
Somebody wanna remind Rico
where we are?
The sanctuary, coach!
- I can't hear you.
- The sanctuary, coach!
That's right, Rico, in the sanctuary.
Now give me 20 starts and stops.
Hello, this is Emily Posa.
I'm not home right now,
but please leave a message...
... and I'll call you back
as soon as possible. Thank you.
Hi, my name is Susan Nall.
I'm calling because a friend...
... told me you do letterpress
invitations, and I was wondering...
Hello? Hi, this is Emily.
Yep, I do wedding invitations.
I'm not able to take any requests,
though, right now.
I know someone nearby who does it.
She's not as good as I am,
but her prices are very...
Hello?
Duke?
Duke.
We're out here.
Hello, Miss Posa.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I came to see you.
Don't you people ever call ahead?
You people tend to try
to hide things.
Is that meat?
No! No, no.
No. No meat. No.
- Well, he was really enjoying it.
- He eats steamed broccoli and tofu.
- Why?
- He's a vegetarian.
- He is a vegetarian?
- Yes.
Well, that sucks.
Hey, can we talk?
Do you have a moment?
No.
Actually, I have to take Duke
for a walk.
No problem. I'll go with you,
if you don't mind.
- So...
- Hey, hey.
Hey.
So I've been looking over
2005, 2006 and 2007.
Now...
I'm listening.
- Can I get him for you?
- Nope. I got him.
Let me get him. Let me get him.
Let me get him.
- You all right?
- Yes.
Whoa, sorry. Whoa, not these.
- That's okay. Watch...
- No, no. Heel, heel, heel.
Yeah, maybe we shouldn't
feed him meat.
So I've been looking over...
- Yeah, maybe we can do this later.
- Yeah.
So you cook it all
ahead of time, I see.
No, actually. I can't remember
the last time I cooked.
This is my sister's way
of looking out for me from afar.
Do you have any siblings?
Yes, one brother.
He's a... He's a good egg.
Yeah, I just have the one sister too.
Are you receiving income
from any source...
...that the government
is currently unaware of?
Well, lately I've been taking
to diving in local wishing wells, so...
I mean, but it's just occasional dimes
here and there...
...or, once in a while, a quarter.
No, actually...
...I had to refinance this place
to pay my past-due medical bills.
I've been informed that you suffer
from congenital heart failure.
Yes. Did you gather that
while stalking me at the hospital?
No, I...
You're currently Status 2,
which means you're sick enough...
...to be on the national UNOS
waiting list...
...but not sick enough to be admitted
into the hospital...
...and placed on Status 1.
So basically, if your heart starts to fail
quickly and no donor can be located...
...you're screwed.
Is it true that you said...
...that you do not believe
that you even deserve a heart...
...because your life is unremarkable
in every way?
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
Do you have to take any type
of sensitivity training...
...to join the IRS, Mr. Thomas?
- No, not really.
- Yeah.
So you don't consider yourself
a good person?
How would you answer that question
if I asked you the same?
"Unremarkable" would be
an upgrade for me...
...I assure you.
I'm gonna freeze your accounts
as uncollectible until further notice.
I'm sure that'll buy you
five or six months, penalty-free.
Here's my card.
If anyone from the IRS
tries to contact you...
...you call me immediately.
Okay.
Thank you.
- Mr. Thomas?
- Yes.
Why do I get the feeling you're
doing me a really big favor right now?
Because I get the feeling
that you really deserve it.
All right?
You off to?
You off to pollute
someone else's dog now?
No.
Just going home.
Where's that?
Take care, Emily.
You too.
- What is this thing for?
- I told you already.
And why are you bringing a fish
into your room?
Because it's my room.
And I don't want anyone going
into my room, understood?
Well, I don't think you can
keep a fish in your room.
I think I can.
Well, I've never had anybody
who kept a fish in their room.
Now you do.
Who?
Good night.
The first time I ever saw
a box jellyfish...
... I was 12.
Our father took us
to the Monterey Bay Aquarium.
I never forgot when he said...
... that it was the most
deadly creature on earth.
To me it was just...
... the most beautiful thing
I'd ever seen.
I spoke to the doctor again.
He's gonna send over your files
in the morning.
- Is this everything?
- Yeah.
- Any questions?
- Same one.
Well, same answer, then.
You know, I was thinking last night
about when we were 14...
...and we made our big pact.
You remember on the beach
in front of your grandparents' house...
...we agreed that we would never,
never date each other's girls?
I remembered that that night you told
me how much you liked Stacy Miller...
...and that you were gonna
ask her out. And I said:
"Hey, man. You can't.
Her and I already did it."
Which we didn't, but I wanted to...
...but she liked you way more
than she liked me, and...
So I lied to you
because I was so jealous.
And I realized that I've been
carrying around this lie...
...in my heart for the last 25...
Stop it!
Stop it.
Stay focused.
Do what you promised me.
- What, you think I'm...?
- Do what you promised me.
You think I'm gonna
let you down now, don't you?
I've known you my whole damn life!
Okay?
This? This? This is not something
you do every day.
Okay? This is...
This is not easy for me.
I'll make sure everything goes
as planned.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Hello, Holly.
Look at you.
- What are you doing here?
- I came to see you.
- Really?
- You have a minute?
Sure. Come on in.
Here's my desk. Have a seat.
You look great.
- I do?
- Yes.
I feel great.
- How are you?
- I'm really good.
I need a favor.
Whatever you need, just ask me.
I need a name.
Someone in the system.
Someone having
a really hard time...
...that needs help, but may be
too proud to ask for a handout.
What are you doing?
I'm helping.
I need a name.
Okay.
Connie Tepos.
Her boyfriend almost killed her
last year when she tried to leave.
He broke three of her ribs
last month.
She's scared to death
to press charges...
... and we can't do anything.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Connie Tepos?
- Yes?
My name is Ben Thomas.
I'm with the IRS.
IRS? But I always pay my taxes.
Yes, this is more of
a general inquiry.
I don't understand. What...?
May I come in?
Not now. My boyfriend is not here.
It's very important for your family.
For my family?
Beautiful.
Please, have a seat.
What's this all about?
Your case has come to my attention.
And I wanted to get to know you.
You wanted to get to know me?
Why?
Because I'd like to help you.
I don't understand.
I'm aware of your case.
And your boyfriend.
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
No, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Kids, go to your room.
He's coming back?
He's not coming back.
You said you were from the IRS,
but you're lying to me.
- No.
- You're not telling me the truth.
Who sent you here?
Please sit down.
I'm not going to sit down.
- Please, calm down.
- I'm not going to calm down.
You come into my house.
You talking to me
about mi caso y mi boyfriend?
- Who sent you here?
- Nobody.
Nobody?
Get out of my house immediately.
You can trust me.
I trust no one, Mr. Thomas.
I talked to Holly.
I can get you out of here.
To a safe place. A beautiful place.
Why did you talk to Holly?
Your children are in danger here.
Don't talk about my kids,
Mr. Thomas.
- You don't know.
- You don't have to live like this.
Get out of my house now
or I'm gonna call the police.
- Okay, okay.
- Who are you?
- I want you to take my card.
- I don't need help.
I want you to take my card,
and call me...
- I don't need it.
- I'm gonna leave it.
Okay. Thank you. Get out right now.
- You're not helpless.
- Can you leave? This is my house.
Please, just think about it.
I don't need you.
- I can't talk right now.
- I need to talk immediately.
- Where are you?
- I'm nowhere.
I'm gonna meet you at the house.
Look, no. I'm not at the house.
I'm traveling. I'll talk to you next week.
No, no, no. We need to
discuss this right now.
Wouldn't wanna get
on her bad side.
- I'll sign to that.
- Yeah.
How you doing, you two?
I'm good.
Got a big day.
Yep. No more dialysis, George.
See you in the O.R.
Yep.
- I'll see you there as well.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
So I heard you raised
enough money...
...to give a couple of the kids
partial scholarships to college.
It's no big deal.
I just convinced a couple
of bigwig donors...
...that what the world really needs
to see is more Latinos on ice.
You know, Ben,
I keep asking you this...
...but why me?
Because you are a good man.
No, really.
Even when you don't know
that people are watching you.
Hello?
Okay, I can't hear you,
so try back again.
Gonna hang up now.
Bye.
Mr. Thomas?
We're ready for you.
These are beautiful.
Banana peels. Who knew?
Emily?
Can I get a refill?
- Susan?
- Yeah.
How's Ryan?
He's good. He's at his dad's
this weekend.
Will you tell him for me that I'm ready
whenever he is for a free lesson?
Yeah, all right.
Things are kind of crazy right now
with school...
...but maybe when school's out.
Oh, yeah. That's perfect.
How's the pie?
Oh, it's... It's good.
You gonna ask her out?
The waitress.
No.
You never know.
I don't... I don't think she sees me.
Good night, Ezra.
Hello?
Ben?
Hi, I'm sorry to call so late.
Did...? Did someone
from the IRS contact you?
No.
I just...
I was having trouble breathing after
I took Duke for a walk, and I fainted.
An ambulance had to take me
to the hospital.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know why I even
called you. I'm sorry.
It's just that I have your card
with me, and...
Ben?
Are you still there?
Yes.
Do you ever
think about dying, Ben?
Every now and again.
My face is bluish.
It's not exactly a good sign.
You should try to rest. Just...
Why don't you see
if you can get some sleep?
I like talking to you.
I like talking to you too.
Would you tell me a story, please?
Okay.
All right. Once upon a time...
... there was a little boy named...
Oh, lucky me, you just got it
on reserve like that. Okay.
Let me guess. His name was Ben.
No, actually,
this little boy's name is Tim.
I like the name Tim.
Go on.
Tim's little brother
was always pestering Tim...
...to make him paper airplanes,
because he was really good at it.
But Tim had much bigger
dreams than that.
Okay. Then what happened?
One day, Tim went out
to the backyard...
...and he put leaves
and taped branches to his arms...
...and started climbing
the big oak tree.
His little brother said,
"Tim, you can't fly."
And he said,
"Yeah? You just watch."
He got all the way to the top
and jumped.
How tall was this tree?
It was... It was pretty tall.
He broke his arm.
Oh, my God...
This is a horrible story.
Oh, no, no. It gets better.
From that experience,
Tim realized that he wanted to fly.
So he dedicated his life
to making spaceships.
I thought you said
this was a good story.
Oh, well...
Yeah, that is...
...until the dragons showed up.
Oh, okay, see,
now it's getting better.
I like dragons.
Especially dragons in space.
Yes, and these were fire-breathing
space dragons...
... with really bad attitudes.
I see.
I have an idea.
Why don't you try to fall asleep...
... and when you do,
I'll just hang up.
Okay.
Ben?
Yes.
Thank you for listening.
And for talking.
Try to fall asleep.
Good night, Ben.
Good night, Emily.
Emily?
I lied to you.
I think about dying every day.
Dr. King to NICU. Dr. Wesley King,
please report to NICU.
Hey.
- Hey.
When did you get here?
Last night, after we talked.
You slept here?
Good morning. How's our patient?
- Morning. Better.
- Good.
- Hello.
- Hi, Ben. Is that right? IRS?
- Yes, how are you?
- Good, thank you.
- I'll leave you two alone.
- No, no, stay, please. Don't go.
He can... He can stay.
Whatever you want.
You fainted because
your heart was too weak...
...to pump enough blood
to your brain.
It's enlarged
and it's starting to shut down.
How long?
It's entirely up to your heart.
Could be six weeks,
could be a month.
But we've upped you to Status 1 B.
At least I'm on the list.
Not only that,
but we're giving you this pager.
And when it goes off,
it means you have a donor.
The inotrope drug I started you on...
...it's gonna stabilize your
blood pressure within 24 hours.
Then what?
We wait.
- Can I do that at home?
- Once you're stable, you can.
Okay.
I'm gonna run to the cafeteria.
I'm gonna get you something.
If you want something else,
I can get you something else.
Would you stay?
I mean, unless you have
something else to do.
- I'd really like it if you stayed.
- I don't have anything.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
What the hell is that thing?
It's a dog. Just for one night.
No. Hold on, hold on.
I don't give two shits, okay?
We have a dog policy here.
Little dogs only.
Poodles and Shih Tzus.
It's in the contract. It's English
and Spanish for everyone to see.
And besides, that, my friend,
is not a dog.
It's a goddamn horse.
Well, let me know when you add
a horse policy to the contract.
Yes.
Mr. Thomas, it's Connie Tepos.
Hey, Connie.
I don't know why I'm calling you...
...but I'm calling you.
You said you could help us and...
Can you really help us?
This just doesn't make any sense.
- What if he finds us?
- He won't.
- What makes you so sure?
- Stop it.
- You don't know him.
Don't be weak.
- Don't be weak.
- I'm not weak.
I'm strong.
Take this. Take it.
You are gonna start this car...
...and you're gonna go.
This is real,
and this is gonna be your new life.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Look at those babies.
Look how beautiful
those babies are.
I know, I know.
They deserve it.
Okay?
You're headed north up the coast.
Lorena. Lorena.
I've always believed
this place can heal the soul.
Mommy, the ocean.
Yes, the ocean.
I hope that proves true for you.
When you sign your name
on the dotted line of the contract...
... you'll own my house outright.
I only ask that you never mention
how you got the house...
... or try to contact me
for any reason.
And if you're wondering why you,
please stop.
All I ask is for you
to honor my wishes...
... and, of course,
live life abundantly.
Hey. Thanks. Got it.
Hi, Duke.
Hi, baby.
What time does the nurse come?
She should be there
by the time I get home.
- Ben?
- Yes.
I know I'm the girl
with the broken wing.
But who are you?
Who am I?
I am your friendly neighborhood
tax collector.
Ben.
Where the hell did you come from?
I grew up in Oakland.
Literally. Okay.
Where did you go to college?
As far from Oakland as possible.
Massachusetts Institute
of Technology.
How about you?
UCLA.
You went to MIT?
Like, the MIT?
Oh, and now you're wondering how
I wound up as a lowly tax collector.
Absolutely.
- I sort of stumbled into this job.
- That's a big stumble.
What from?
I always wanted to be an engineer.
An engineer?
What kind?
The kind that sent people
to the moon.
Really?
Yes.
I don't wanna talk
about me anymore.
That's too bad,
because you're very interesting.
Have you...?
Have you ever been in love?
Emily, please.
Yes, you have.
Come on, you can tell me.
Yes.
But it ended.
- What happened?
- Stop it.
- No, seriously, you can tell...
You need to get some rest.
I'll call you tomorrow,
or maybe I'll stop by.
No, if I have questions tomorrow,
what then?
That's not a part of the deal.
What the hell does that mean?
Emily, hold on. Hold on.
- Just leave.
- Emily, wait.
Wait!
Thank you for everything you did.
Did you like the eggs?
They were okay, I guess.
I don't like the eggs you buy.
Okay.
You're wearing suit pants.
To weed.
Yeah, I didn't... I didn't have
any other clothes with me.
- You know, I was gonna get to those.
- I saw them the other day.
I figured I would just take the day off
and get this done for you.
Ben?
Yeah?
This is a really ridiculous apology.
Come on.
I wanna show you something.
Oh, no, I gotta finish.
You can finish tomorrow.
Come on.
This is where I used to work.
And these are the artifacts
of said work.
Wow, those are great.
How old are they?
This one is just shy of 120 years.
It's how I put out my line of letterpress
cards, wedding invitations, invites.
What about this one?
That youngster...
...is the Heidelberg Windmill, 1956.
Call it "The Beast."
Well, that seems appropriate.
It pooped out on me
about five years ago, though.
And I can't find anybody to fix it.
It's kind of a dying art.
Defibrillator here works, though.
Luckily. It kept my business afloat.
Wanna see how?
Please.
Okay. Now, true pressmen...
...hate that we modern girls...
...want a deep impression.
See, for a hundred years, they tried
their damnedest just to kiss it...
...so that it didn't leave
an indentation.
Now it's the only way
to prove it's not digital.
I think it feels richer.
You okay?
Yeah.
Look, Ben...
I don't really know anything about you
or where you came from...
...but you keep showing up.
And I'm glad.
Okay.
So Duke needs a walk.
Are you interested?
Yes.
Come on.
Hey, hey.
Right here.
There you go.
He's like a different dog
with you around.
I don't think we ever
properly bonded.
Why would you get such a big dog?
Did you know that Great Danes on
average only live about seven years?
They have heart issues.
I think I got him because...
...I thought he could help me
with my illness.
It'd be something
I could take care of...
...as opposed to being
always taken care of.
You know, just so you know,
I used to be really hot.
Like, unauditably hot.
Is that so?
Yeah.
I haven't felt like this
in a really long time.
There's so many things
that I wanna do.
I wanna go on a plane
for 13 hours...
...and not have to stress
that I can't reach my doctor.
You know, like, just travel.
Go backpacking, have experiences.
See the world.
I just wanna have the time
to figure out who it is that I am.
You know, what I like.
Do things, try things,
get out of my head for once.
I would really like to go running.
I think about that sometimes.
What it would just feel like
to go running.
So...
...see you tomorrow?
Yes.
But if you need anything,
just call and I'll come right back.
Okay.
Bye.
I had a really great time today.
Me too.
Bye.
No anesthetic. You ever
donated bone marrow before?
You're a brave guy.
How long have you
known Nicholas?
What the hell happened to you?
Hey, how much longer
are you gonna stay in my hotel?
Motel.
How much longer?
Actually, I was planning
on dying here.
Well, then you need to pay
in advance.
Hello?
Hey, it's Emily.
Are you sleeping?
Yes. No.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
My sister came over for a couple
of days last week with the kids...
...and it was really great.
I tried calling you a couple times.
How are you doing?
Yeah, I'm good.
Everything's fine. I've been...
I've been traveling a lot, so...
Well, are you busy tonight?
What do you mean?
I don't... Maybe you wanna
come by and say hello?
Around 7?
You don't have to if you don't want to.
I just, you know...
Look, I totally get if you don't wanna
hang out with the dying girl, so...
I can... I can come at 7.
Okay.
Bye.
- Well, how you doing tonight?
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Have fun.
- Hi.
Come in.
I am so glad she's gone.
Are you okay if we eat outside?
Eating?
You didn't eat already, did you?
- No.
- Okay.
No.
Well, it was a surprise...
...but you're on time.
I haven't cooked anybody food
for years, so you better like it.
Or lie to me.
This is for you.
You don't have to say anything.
I just got it... Change in there.
Dinner is ready and you're not.
So hurry up.
Chop-chop.
You look great.
Yeah. It's pink.
It's salmon.
You are so nice.
So are you.
Everything's vegetarian.
I hope you like eggplant Parmesan.
I haven't treated myself very well...
...in the past few years.
Start now.
All right.
What do you think?
It's delicious.
Glad you like it.
Do you wanna hear
my favorite song?
Yes. Are you gonna sing it?
No, I can't sing anymore.
Oh, and a performance.
Oh, no.
Shall we?
You need to relax.
This is relaxed.
I have a surprise for you.
Surprise?
Yes.
For me?
- Keep them closed.
- Okay.
And open.
Okay.
You cleaned The Beast.
Actually, I fixed it.
No, you didn't.
Oh, okay, let's go, then.
Wait. Are you serious?
Try it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Wait right here, okay?
I'll be right back. Wait right here.
One second.
Hey!
Tell me what's going on.
- Now!
- All right.
Ben, you need to go home.
Do you know they keep a full history of
every inquiry a revenue officer makes?
- You understand?
- Keep your voice down.
- Just keep your voice down.
- No. What you are doing is a crime!
You are impersonating
a federal officer. It's a felony!
All right. Listen.
You can't play with people's lives.
Do you understand that?
All right.
All right, there's a coffee shop.
There's a coffee shop
near where I'm staying.
- Tomorrow we'll sit down...
- Where are you staying, Tim?
Tell me, because I don't know
where my brother lives!
A motel. Five blocks from here.
We'll sit down tomorrow morning,
I guarantee it.
Where are my credentials?
Give me my credentials back.
Here it is. Here. Here.
Just go home.
You have a beautiful family.
Go home and enjoy them.
Tim, Tim, Tim,
why are you even here?
Tell me, who is Emily Posa?
I'll explain everything tomorrow.
Look, give me your car keys.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna be right here.
So you remember I love you and...
Tim, don't make me come knock
on the door, okay?
I didn't realize how late it was and...
I have a really long drive,
so I need to go.
I don't wanna keep lying to you.
I don't wanna... Wait, Emily.
Do you wanna play a game?
What game?
The "what if" game.
What if...
...my pager goes off...
...and it's a heart...
...and...
...it works?
And my body doesn't reject it?
And...
...what if I have time?
What if?
What if we have children?
What if we got married?
I love you.
- I love you too.
- I love you.
Hi.
Is Dr. Briar on duty tonight?
She's doing her rounds.
Can you tell her it's Ben Thomas?
It's very important.
- I'll... I'll page her.
- Thank you.
Dr. Briar to the nurses' station.
Hey.
- Is it Emily?
- No, no.
I'm sorry.
It's...
Is there?
I'm sorry.
Do you have any more optimism...
...about Emily...
...than you did the other day?
Ben...
...when you're looking for a donor
with a rare blood type...
...the odds go way down.
To what?
They go down. What's the...?
Give me a percentage.
Give me a number.
Three, 5 percent.
I know. I'm sorry.
I wish the numbers were higher.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- I do.
Hello?
Dan.
It's time.
I love you.
1:38 a.m.
Hello?
Ezra.
My name is Ben Thomas.
I called you a few weeks ago.
You probably don't remember.
I do remember.
I wanna apologize for being
so cruel to you...
...but I had to be certain.
I had to be certain
that you were a decent man. Kind.
- Slow to anger.
- What do you want from me?
I wanna give you a gift.
You're gonna be contacted
by a man named Dan Morris.
You can trust him.
Was that you at the diner?
Goodbye.
911 emergency.
I need an ambulance.
I have you at 9212 West Third Street
in Los Angeles.
Yes, room number 2.
What's the emergency?
There's been a suicide.
Who's the victim?
I am.
You are gonna need to stop
looking at that thing so much.
Why? Is it gonna crack?
Oh, no. I paid extra
for the non-cracking kind.
I bet you did.
- Why don't you just turn that off?
- I know. No more. No more work.
I'm done. Almost done. Almost done.
Tim!
I have procedures.
I understand, but she needs
that heart or she will die.
- Ben?
- One, two, three.
Hey.
How you doing?
About a year after the accident,
I got sick.
I got lung cancer,
and I needed a double-lobe transplant.
Tim could only give me one,
of course.
It must have planted a seed,
because he...
About six months later...
...he donated the right part of his
liver to this woman.
Her name is Holly.
I'm proud of you kids. Very proud.
Good job. Good job.
- Ezra.
- Yeah.
Hi.
Are you a parent?
No.
Have we met?
You okay?
You must be Emily.
Yes.
It's so nice to meet you.
Subtitles by LeapinLar