TOHO COMPANY, LTD. Presents
(The three villains of)
THE HIDDEN FORTRESS
Executive Producers SANEZUMI
FUJIMOTO & AKIRA KUROSAWA
Starring
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
Directed by AKIRA KUROSAWA
Stay away from me!
You stink of dead bodies.
Give it up.
We both smell of corpses.
And it's all your fault!
Your smell makes me want to puke.
Though shitworms can't smell shit.
What?
You're a shitworm.
You make me sick.
And you thought we'd make
a fortune at the war.
What's funny, you idiot!
It's all funny!
First, we arrived late to the war.
Then they mistook us for
the defeated side
and forced us to bury the dead.
We finally escaped and now it's
been 2 days we've only had water.
But the funniest thing is
your foolish cry baby face.
Let's go home.
Don't you have any pride?
We've even been stripped
of the arms we sold our homes for.
We can't go home like this.
Then take it off this dead guy.
Even if I'm desperate,
I'm not a thief.
Do what you want. I'm going!
Go. I'll come home after
I make a buck.
Don't come crying to me then.
Get caught again
and be a gravedigger.
Fool! Go away!
It'll be a blessing to see you go,
you shitworm.
We can't cross the border
from this road.
It's a Yamana check station.
Not even a mouse could pass
through those barricades.
If they find us, we're dead.
What now?
Unless a fog breaks out,
we can't move.
What does it say up there?
It's a notice about a reward
for 10 pieces of gold.
Read it to me.
"Wanted. Princess Yuki of Akizuki."
"A reward of ten ryo
for her capture."
"Three ryo for information
of her whereabouts."
"By order of the Lord of Yamana."
- Move!
- Walk!
I'm not one of them.
I'm thankful for the fog
but I can't see anything.
Which way is Hayakawa?
Shut up and follow me!
Who is it?
Not grave digging again.
Matashichi!
Listen!
There is 200 kan of pure gold
hidden in this castle.
Until you find it, you're no
longer men but moles!
So dig! Dig until you drop, moles!
Matashichi, this is hell.
It's the end!
If we're going to die,
let's die together.
That way!
Thieves! Rice thieves!
What shall we do now?
Find the Princess.
The Princess?
The sole survivor
of the Akizuki clan.
I think the reward on her head
is ten ryo.
Ten pieces of gold?
Informers get three.
Three pieces of gold?
It's no good. That's only a dream.
If we get greedy and get caught,
we're done for.
I guess we'd better go home.
But how will we cross the border?
Bang and we're dead.
Let's eat.
I can't think on an empty stomach.
Not ready.
These don't burn at all.
What's this?
Why, it's gold!
You're right! It's gold!
But... a piece of gold...
inside a stick?
I've heard of a rich man hiding
gold in the pillars of his home, but...
What's this? An insignia!
Looks like a crescent.
The crescent is the Akizuki crest!
That's the reserve gold they were
digging for in the castle.
You made the fire -
where did you get the wood?
Let's split up and look.
I'll go this way.
You go over there to the marsh.
The same piece!
What are you doing?
One's mine!
I found both!
I found the stick first.
I threw it!
I picked up the gold!
Liar! I'm the one who
noticed it was gold.
- Let's go back.
- Back?
There must be more.
If someone else notices it,
we're screwed.
He's following us.
Watch out. Maybe he's a bandit.
He's not a bandit. He has no sword.
You can't be sure.
He may work for one.
He stopped following us.
Let's go back.
No, better be careful.
It's late, anyway.
It won't hurt to wait one night.
It's a big job.
Better safe than sorry.
We haven't seen that guy since,
so maybe we didn't need to worry.
Probably a lumberjack
or a charcoal maker.
So, let's get this straight now.
What?
Don't play dumb.
How to split up the gold.
Let's be fair and divide it equally.
You don't like it?
- But I...
- Then it's settled! All right?
Let's sleep.
Sleep tight, and let's dream
of mountains of gold.
Hey!
Good eve...
Cold, isn't it?
What are you doing here
in the mountain?
How about you?
- Us? We intend to cross the border.
- The border?
- We want to go to Hayakawa.
- Hayakawa?
But beyond the mountains
it's Yamana.
Yes... but you see...
to go to Hayakawa...
This is Hayakawa.
And this is Akizuki
where we are now.
This is... Yamana.
We want to go from Akizuki
to Hayakawa.
But the border is guarded
by Yamana soldiers.
So, we'll cross first to Yamana.
And then slip into Hayakawa.
See...
There's no way that survivors
of the Akizuki clan
would go to Yamana,
the enemy territory.
So the border between Akizuki
and Yamana should be open.
That's right.
The Hayakawa-Yamana border
must be
easier to cross than
the Akizuki-Hayakawa border.
Anyway, we're just peasants.
Even if anything happened,
we'd still make it.
All right. I've made up my mind.
Going through Yamana
is a good idea.
The 200 gold pieces are useless
here, but with three men
and three horses,
we can carry it out.
200 gold pieces?
What are you talking about?
Be honest.
I've got an eye on that place.
- Don't kick the stones.
- You stop grabbing my leg.
What now?
What is he doing?
He's not here.
Where did he go?
That guy can't be trusted.
What is this place?
It's what they call
a hidden fortress.
A hidden fortress?
The Akizuki one.
Look. You can see all of Yamana.
But...
For a fortress,
it's strangely empty.
Someone's here!
What are you doing?
Oh, it's that guy.
Hey. Come down quickly.
How did you get down there?
What are your names?
I'm Matashichi.
I'm Tahei.
Matashichi, put the rice down.
Tahei, you put the rice in the pot.
Hurry up!
Where's the water? I need
a drink before the food.
Me too. I can't even spit anymore.
Hey. What's your name?
Me? I'm Rokurota Makabe.
Rokurota Makabe?
I've heard that name before.
Makabe...
Rokurota Makabe...
Get out of here. Rokurota Makabe
is a legendary Akizuki
samurai general.
You take us for fools.
We shouldn't put up with this.
Hey. Stop fooling around. You're no
general, you're just a bully.
What's with the big attitude?
Don't make fun of us. Damn you.
What?
That wasn't very nice.
You could have told us if
there was a secret passageway.
We've been partners
since last night.
Besides, just because you found
this place first,
doesn't mean you're the boss.
Let's decide now how
we're going to divvy up.
Fair and square, we share it
in three equal parts. Deal?
Here's the water.
Excellent.
This is some fortress that
they have water like this.
Don't bother.
I already went through there.
Just prepare the rice.
Shut up. I can't take it anymore.
You can stuff your orders.
You want to fight?
Don't hold back. Do him in.
Cook the rice.
It's a girl.
Where is she? Who is she?
I don't know. She's really quick
though. She's already gone.
Look. She's mine, OK? I'll kill you
if you go near her.
Cook and then it's work.
What are you doing?
Don't touch me, fool!
It's uncomfortable enough.
It's your face that
makes me uncomfortable.
Leave my face alone.
I hate the way you blink
all the time.
There you go again.
Shut up. Put your filthy teeth away.
Show them to me once more
and I'll bash them in.
I'm quitting! This is idiotic!
I dig and dig and nothing!
It's his fault.
Dammit. Gone again.
He's on his high horse
watching us do all the work.
Right. He's probably running
around looking for that girl.
Maybe he already found a place
and is sleeping with her.
We agreed to split everything in
three. The girl should be the same.
That bully is not just anyone.
I can't figure out what he's up to.
He may already have found the 200
pieces of gold and moved them.
That's very likely. I'm sure of it.
That means he's hiding the gold
right now.
So if he's not in this fortress...
Look!
That spring is fishy.
Pretending like he's already
checked it out... damn.
Where do you live?
Hey, lady, don't be mad.
What are you doing?
Shut up! I told you I'd kill you
if you touched her!
Wait, boss. It's not fair.
Look. The girl dropped this.
Don't go behind our back.
She's worth 10 ryo.
This does not belong
to a country girl.
Maybe you think she's the
Akizuki princess.
You're right.
That comb does belong
to Princess Yuki.
But now it belongs to me.
Give it back.
I took it from the Princess
and gave it to her.
What?
I don't lie.
Then where is Princess Yuki?
I captured her and handed her
over to the Yamana authorities.
Careful. I think he's full of crap.
Here's the reward of 10 ryo.
Still think it's a lie?
Tell me. Where did Matashichi go?
I don't know.
What are you plotting? Tell me!
To... to the town.
To do what?
He went to report.
Report who?
- The princess, of course.
- The princess?
We're not as stupid as you think.
You thought you had fooled us
but we're not that gullible.
I know your game.
Your reward money is just
a part of the hidden gold.
You're greedy on top of it.
You want to capture
the princess yourself
so you can have all the reward.
It won't go so smoothly.
I made a mistake
by relying on scum.
You think you're better, scum?
Matashichi, did you see
the officers?
Fool. Do you think
I'd be back so soon?
It's the talk of town already.
The princess was captured
a while back and
she was beheaded yesterday.
Boss, we're sorry we doubted you.
It's Rokurota Makabe.
Enter.
Any news?
Kofuyu served her duty.
The enemy will relax
their guard now.
Now is our chance to escape.
What happened to Kofuyu?
As a dutiful servant, my sister went
in place of your Highness.
This assures the safety
of your Highness.
Rokurota!
Fool!
What are you saying your Highness?
Kofuyu was 16... I am 16. What
difference is there in our souls?
It is our duty as servants.
Kofuyu was honored...
Lies! If I were Kofuyu,
I would curse this Princess.
Your words are too harsh.
Rokurota has no leg to stand on.
Be quiet!
I don't even want to see your face!
Your nobility that doesn't
even shed a tear
when you've killed your sister.
I hate it!
I don't know what to do with her
Highness. It's the Lord's fault.
Even if he was lacking an heir,
it was cruel to raise her Highness
like a boy.
Say right and she'll go left,
say left and she'll go right.
And though she is a girl,
she has never shown me a tear.
The same
with her present behavior.
Insensitive to your pain of having
sacrificed your sister, she...
She herself does not shed a tear,
but she still criticizes you.
It's too much.
Her Highness is the real sacrifice.
Her suffering of having to rebuild
the Akizuki clan...
The Yamana's are here!
There are horses at the spring.
This is good, to fool the Yamana's
by going through enemy lines.
This was the peasants' idea.
Depending on their answers,
I was ready to kill them.
But hearing their plan to go
through Yamana to Hayakawa,
I was stunned.
Sometimes even moss can be smart...
How long can we rely on them?
We can rely on their greed.
Make them carry gold and
they'll put up with anything.
That takes care of the gold.
But we cannot take a chance
with the Princess.
But staying here is not safe either.
This hidden fortress will soon
be discovered by the Yamana's too.
And our deal with Lord Hayakawa
may not last either.
Understood.
But what shall we do
with the Princess?
We can disguise her looks,
but not her class.
And her speech...
Her Highness
will have to be a mute.
A mute... isn't there any other way?
There isn't.
I don't know if the Princess
would agree.
Leave it to me.
I hadn't ridden in a long time.
She runs fast. She's too good
to be a packhorse.
Just in case you need to ride.
So we finally pass
through enemy lines.
- Speaking of which, could you play mute?
- Mute?
I'm sure you couldn't do it.
To go through Yamana, my greatest
concern is your speech.
We were discussing
you could be a mute...
But I think it's impossible.
I was captured once and
had to pretend to be a mute.
It was agony.
Your Highness couldn't take it.
I'm not biting.
When you say right, I say left.
I'm a handful.
Let me use reverse psychology.
Princess.
All right.
This once I will let you fool me.
Otherwise your plan will be foiled.
Your noble face again.
If you need anything, tell me now.
Once I'm a mute,
I'm not talking until Hayakawa.
We have to tell him.
The bully? Never mind him.
Idiot, shut up. We'll get caught.
Where are you going?
Boss, run! The Yamana soldiers
have found us.
There were horses by the spring.
Idiots. I stole those.
We can't carry 200 pieces
of gold without them.
Gold?
We'll climb down today.
Where is the gold?
Hey. Where is the gold?
Don't hold out on us. Come on.
I knew it!
Don't fool around with us.
You said you had already gone
through there.
Why did you make us dig
at the fortress?
I was testing you.
We'll need a lot of backbone
on the road. You did well.
Lift the gold out of the water
and onto the horses.
The three of us will carry the rest.
Gold!
Leave the gold in the wood.
Dammit.
Where did you hide this?
You're so suspicious.
That's just firewood.
It's a bad idea to take the girl.
She'll slow us down.
What if she blabs...
- She's mute. Don't worry.
- Mute?
This will be an easy border
to cross.
Wait.
Better be cautious.
Don't move 'til I come back.
If we want to get rid of him,
now's our chance.
Don't worry. She's mute.
She's mute but she can hear.
Stupid. A mute can't speak
because she's deaf.
This is where we have to think.
He's sly so we can't trust him even
if we cross into Hayakawa.
He'll cheat us.
Let's run away.
What about his load?
We can't carry it.
We'll take his horse.
There's no time to argue.
Let's tell her we're taking
the horses for a drink.
Fool. They're not drinking sake.
What are you doing?
Where are the horses?
What shall we do?
Princess!
It's frustrating to be a mute.
All I can do is watch.
The two of them?
Out of greed, they took the horses.
Then the enemy spotted them.
Fine allies.
You!
We can't cross that river.
There is a firing squad
on the other side.
I know your game.
Take the gold and get lost.
He's gone.
Boss!
There he is.
Boss, the other side is lined
with Yamana soldiers.
What would you do?
What do I care?
What are you doing?
Wait and see at the fortress?
Shut up. Go away.
Please, take us with you.
We promise to behave.
What's that?
The Yamana's found it!
What will we do?
We're leaving.
Which way?
Straight ahead.
You're joking!
Leave it to me. I have a plan.
Your pass?
Wait!
Boss.
Next!
Your pass. What's your problem?
I picked up something.
What? It's just a piece of wood.
I found it at Mt. Suribachi.
He found this.
The Akizuki crest!
You really found it
at Mt. Suribachi?
Bring me my horse!
That gold is mine. Give it back.
No.
Give me the gold or a reward.
Shut up. Get lost.
Give me a reward. I won't move!
A reward! Give me a reward!
Greedy.
Two or three loaded horses,
several men and a girl.
If you see such a group,
arrest them immediately.
There are signs that Princess
Yuki's party has been here.
But she was beheaded...
Using a double has been
done before.
You also saw the smoke rise
on the mountain across.
That was Akizuki's hidden fortress.
It was guarded by an old soldier
and two others.
They could have escaped. Instead
they burned the fortress
and fought 'til their end.
It appears they wanted to signal
and gain time for others to escape.
The Princess and a few men
escaped with the gold for sure.
There are traces on the road.
Don't slack. Catch them
and you will be rewarded.
Are you ok, boss?
Let's take a back road.
- Stop sneaking around. It invites suspicion.
- But...
What are you doing?
We're staying here tonight.
Here?
You've got to be kidding me.
Let's hurry through the night.
It's a long way. Let's not push it.
Then let's camp out.
Hide a stone among stones
and a man among men.
Where will we hide the gold?
Leave it out in the open.
You're so slow. Get a clue
and bring some water.
Always crying,
but you refuse to take johns.
You were a lousy deal.
Where did you get her?
In Akizuki. Lose a war
and plenty of women go on sale.
How much?
Five silver pieces. Want her?
Idiot. I'm not a dog like you.
- You bluff.
- No, sorry.
Now, look here.
Look.
Average looking, but excellent
body. How about it?
For one silver piece,
she's yours for the night.
What's the use of buying a woman
who won't take customers?
How much is she?
She's a looker!
She's not one of yours?
I'll buy her.
Who does she belong to?
Whose girl is she?
I'll buy her! I'll buy her
for a piece of gold!
Enough!
- She's a mute.
- Mute?
That's too bad. I'll pass.
Who's the owner
of the horse outside?
Is it yours?
Do you want to sell her to me?
I'll give you whatever you want.
But my load...
She's too good for a packhorse. 5
silver pieces. You can buy 5 horses.
Boss. What shall we do?
Two horses are not enough
for everything.
It's hard to find another one.
This sucks.
There is no time for girls.
Buy that girl back.
I cannot.
Why not? I am
the Princess of Akizuki.
I can't bear to see one
of our own in trouble.
No, you're in trouble...
Your kindness will harm you.
Whatever. Buy her back.
- No.
- You cannot make my heart mute too!
A cart was a bad idea.
We're the horses now.
And we've even taken in that girl.
Stop following us. Go away.
Go back to Akizuki.
Don't stop. Continue.
Have you seen four people,
three horses and a girl?
If you do, report them immediately.
It went well. We're lucky.
Who said a cart was a bad idea?
You were grumbling about the girl.
But those men are stupid.
Why not check the wood?
What shall we do now?
Be calm!
Put it down.
Report them!
Run! Wait on the hill!
Why, if it isn't Rokurota Makabe!
Hey, Hyoe Tadokoro!
Stand aside!
You're no match for him!
A rare meeting.
I regret not meeting you on the
battlefields this time around.
I regret it, too.
How about a duel?
With pleasure!
With what? A spear?
Sounds good.
All of them are inferior,
but choose one.
I lost!
Wait!
We'll meet again.
Rokurota!
- Firewood?
- What about firewood?
Apparently gold is hidden
in the wood.
They're hiding here with all that.
Four of them.
One girl with three men.
She's Princess Yuki from Akizuki.
The reward is 200 pieces
of gold for her.
Five pieces just for information.
Don't jump the gun.
It won't be easy.
A strong general, Rokurota Makabe,
is with her.
It's cold!
It's been three days now.
- More rain. More rain.
- What?
We can't move even if it stops.
We go out there
and we'll get beheaded.
You madman.
Are you glad to be beheaded?
Why not?
It's better than putting up
with this.
Then give up the gold and get lost.
Good idea.
I'll leave.
But I'm taking all I can carry.
I'll be set for life.
I'll leave too.
Great. What's left is all mine.
Take what you want and beat it.
But we're not getting anywhere.
Where are you going?
I'm going to find something
to put the gold in.
The one with the shorter one
disappears for a while.
He's late.
I'm sure he'll be back soon.
What's going on?
Everyone is carrying wood...
I know! It's the Fire Festival.
Haven't you heard of the Yamana
Fire Festival where the villagers
dance around a bonfire?
We lucked out!
They're going in our direction.
If we join the crowd...
I don't get it. Why do we have
to patrol a Fire Festival?
Look. There's a lot
of wood at the Festival.
The Akizuki clan may hide here
with their gold hidden in firewood.
What's this?
There is too much wood to check.
We'll inspect the suspicious ones
who stray from the crowd.
Where is everyone?
To the Festival...
Marching with the crowd...
The life of a man
Burn it with the fire
The life of an insect
Throw it into the fire
Ponder and you'll see
The world is dark
And this floating world is a dream
Burn with abandon
Burn it! Throw the cart
into the fire!
No!
- Don't be stingy, fool.
- No!
They're suspicious.
Move. Burn it!
Dance!
That's enough. Let's pack it up.
But, Boss, there's more...
Don't be greedy!
There's no point in taking more
than we can carry.
You two carry 30 kan each.
I carry 40... with the two women,
that's 20...
What? I can carry 40 kan too.
I'll carry 50 kan.
Hurry up!
It's such a shame to leave
that gold.
Go back?
Where are you going?
No more.
What are you looking for?
Boss, help us!
Help!
If you want to live,
pick up your load.
Follow me!
Hurry up! We can cross
the mountain overnight.
It's hard. I'd rather be dead.
Then die.
Boss!
Calm down!
Don't stand up!
Listen! I'll run and distract them.
Escape while you can.
We're done for. Let's run.
Farewell!
Did you say something?
I'm not worth it. Leave me and go.
It's the end.
If we get caught, they'll kill us.
Not if we don't have any gold.
We'll turn them in.
You're right.
Maybe we'll even get a reward.
Idiot! They'll shoot us
if we're not careful.
I'm sure Yamana and Hayakawa
are patrolling their border.
We can report them there.
Your Highness... Hayakawa.
Are you joking? We got them
and their gold long ago.
Go home, fools.
Look carefully! You won't see
200 gold pieces again!
I'd rather see Princess Yuki!
She's a sight for sore eyes.
To think she'll be beheaded
tomorrow...
Stay away!
Just a glance.
Let me through!
Tadokoro here to identify them.
Hyoe Tadokoro!
What happened to you?
Where did you get that scar?
You. You've changed.
Naturally.
Tell me what happened. We're on
opposite sides,
but we're true friends.
Friends? Then why did you let me
survive the shame of my defeat?
To defeat an enemy and to let him
live appears to be a kind act,
but it is cruel.
Look at me!
My Lord shamed me
before everyone.
See the scar left by
the relentless beating?
I curse you!
Fool! Are you the
great Hyoe Tadokoro?
What you make of another's
kindness is up to you.
You and your Lord.
Evidently you're both fools.
To punish you so for losing
to an enemy...
Even I do not dare such a thing.
I'm the Princess. It's me.
Stop.
I appreciate your loyalty,
but this is it.
I want to die with dignity.
Your Highness, this Rokurota
cannot apologize enough.
You endured so much
and it was all in vain.
You're wrong, Rokurota.
I had a good time.
The happiness of these days
I would have
never known living in the castle.
I saw people as they really are...
I saw their beauty and their
ugliness with my own eyes.
Rokurota, I thank you.
- I can now die without regret.
- Your Highness!
Rokurota.
That Fire Festival was fun.
I like that song.
The life of a man
Burn it with the fire
The life of an insect
Throw it into the fire
Ponder and you'll see
The world is dark
And this floating world is a dream
The life of a man
Burn it with the fire
Let's burn it!
Turn the horses!
Turn them, I said!
He's mad! Get them!
Hurry, Rokurota! Take the Princess!
She is a great leader...
serve her well.
Hyoe!
Don't die in vain!
If you wish, follow us!
Come!
Forgive this traitor!
Damn. When I got to Hayakawa
with the gold,
I imagined I'd be so happy.
We're lucky to have our heads.
Let's stay friends.
We risked death together, we'll stay
friends back at the village.
Stray horses.
Gold!
This is all mine.
What? Give me one of them.
I found them first.
You are greedy. You said we
should split everything 50/50.
That was then, this is now.
You shithead.
You. Are you from the Akizuki clan?
No, we're just peasants.
I don't get it.
Peasants with all this gold?
Arrest them!
Let's stay friends in heaven too.
Matashichi! Tahei! Look up!
What? It's me.
No wonder.
Even I didn't recognize you.
Your armor becomes you.
Rokurota Makabe.
You look even more handsome.
You don't recognize
your Princess Yuki?
The mute. The mute girl.
Matashichi. Tahei.
You two went through a lot for us.
However, that gold is an indispensable
fund to restore Akizuki.
Not I, not even the Princess
can take it.
I hope you will be satisfied
with this. Here.
Split it fairly. No fighting.
You keep this.
No you keep it.
But...
Don't worry about it.
The End