Date: 13th Day of May, 1630
Weather: Fair
The heat of day rises hourly
10 am: Hon. Heir Bennosuke
departs bearing fresh river trout
for presentation to the hon. Lord Doi
at His Lordship's mansion
No incidents worthy of note
However,
around midday
an ex-warrior, formerly in the service of
the Lord of Geishu,
appeared at our gate.
HARAKIRI/SEPPUKU
Official residence of Lord Iyi
A former retainer of the Lord of Geishu?
Correct!
And my names is Hanshiro Tsugumo
Tsu as in Ohtsu
Gumo for clouds in the sky
And your errand here?
My lord's downfall came about in 1619
I have since moved to Edo
and have managed to make a meager living
while seeking employed under a new master
But in such times of peace, all was in vain
and my hopes are crushed
The years passed unrewarded
and lacking means of subsistence,
life has become intolerable
Rather than live on in dire poverty and disgrace
He would die honorably by hara-kiri
He begs use of a corner of this mansion
for the ritual
Such is his request
Another one?
Is there no end?
And your wish, sire?
Good! I'll see him
A former retainer of the Lord of Geishu,
I am Hanshiro Tsugumo
I respectfully beg your favors
Clan Elder of the House of Iyi, Kageyu Saito
I am indebted to you for this interview
My purpose here...
I am fully informed
Rather than to live on in dire poverty,
You prefer to die honorably
by hara-kiri
Is that not so?
Correct!
Truly a most worthy turn of mind
I am greatly impressed
You mentioned having served
the former Lord of Geishu
Did You know Motome Chijiiwa?
Chijiiwa?
You don't remember?
He also served the Lord of Geishu
In its day, the Geishu Clan counted
some 12,000 retainers
I regret to say...
Indeed? But that is a minor matter
Early this year... possibly the end of January...
An ex-warrior... a Motome Chijiiwa...
came to this mansion
On a mission identical to yours
He also begged permission to perform hara-kiri
Are you interested in how he fared?
I am listening
A former retainer of the Lord of Geishu?
That is correct! Former retainer of the Clan
And known as Motome Chijiiwa
And... your errand?
Abolition of our Clan led me to
seek humble quarters in Edo
Here I have managed to subsist
while waiting to serve a new master
But in a world of peace there is no hope
I expected this
And... what would you do?
Let me see...
A truly deplorable state...
The Sengoku Clan erred
They set the precedent
No... I don't agree
Why not?
The ex-warrior who entered the
Sengoku mansion was sincere
He intended to die
And touched by his sincerity
the Clan took him in as a back-room retainer
They did not err! They did right
It is the others who copy him,
who cast such shame on us
Far from wishing to die, they merely
seek material aid
They are but common extortioners!
You prefer to die honorably
to die at our door
Offer him a pittance to go his way as
do the other clans
No... that would never do!
Offer coins to one
and others will soon flock to our door
They will pour forth like ants to a mound of
sweet sugar
Following the end of civil war,
the land abounds with ex-warrior
Scrambling for food like animals!
The House of Iyi is blunt-witted
Their reputation for grit and moral fibber
Once sufficed to keep ex-warrior away
But... now?
Even pride in the martial arts is a thing of
the past...
swept away by years of peaceful living
Such would be the rumors circulated
throughout the land
His Lordship absent
and such harmful rumors spreading in
his absence...
It must never be!
Bribery to send him packing has
never crossed my mind
Without the least intention of dying
he dares pretend...
Hon. Elder!
Allow me...
Your pardon...
His Lordship's retainer... Umenosuke Kawabe
Motome Chijiiwa... ex-warrior of Geishu
And now... kindly come with me
To the bath-room
In his Lordship's absence
the hon. Elder reported your plight to our hon.
Heir, Bennosuke
Our young master is deeply moved and
wishes a word with you
I am allowed an interview with the hon.
Heir, Bennosuke?
That is correct
However... those clothes will not do
First you must bathe
Proper dress is being prepared for you
I am in your hands
I am overwhelmed
Incredible! Am I dreaming?
Not only inconceivable... it's...
Your pardon!
Forgive the unexpected delay
You must change now
To death robes
You're shocked?
Was I not to see your hon. Heir?
He has expressed such a desire
Odd! It must be a misunderstanding
It's not!
The hon. Umenosuke Kawabe passed me
the information...
Oh? Hon. Kawabe did?
I begin to understand... yes... it could be possible
Then... you know about it?
Yes, it becomes quite clear
The hon. Elder reported your plight
to our hon. Heir
who was deeply moved by your courage
and wished to make you one of us
However... a samurai resolved to
performing hara-kiri
must be one of unwavering will
As nothing can alter his decision,
allow him his final wish...
I would readily spare the time for
a word with him
but Lord Doi requests my attendance
Extend him all courtesies of my house
and have my men witness the ritual
Let it be a proud example
Such were his words... as told to me
Well? Did you enjoy it?
A most interesting story
A tale befitting the valiant traditions
of the House of Iyi
And... what are your intentions?
Oh... you are referring to this?
Exactly!
Be not concerned...
I came here with this avowed purpose in mind
Most laudable!
I commend you on your unwavering decision
Hon. Tsugumo
Perhaps I should continue my story
about this Motome Chijiiwa
I am listening
Come... time is fleeting!
You must change your robes
All preparations have been completed for
your hara-kiri ritual
I beg a boon!
A boon... allow me a little time!
I won't run!
I promise to return here
Just a few days!
It's too late
It's unjustified!
Was it not at your request
that we made arrangements?
I beg your forgiveness! Just a day or tow...
I will return!
A Samurai's word is sacred. It cannot be!
Our master swordsman,
Hayato Yazaki Young...is eager for action!
One move... you'll be ripped open!
And there are others...
Rather than be chopped up like some dead fish
die in honor...
Come... you must change robes
Heed me, hon. Ancestors!
Forgive the unworthy ex-warrior
which defiles our sacred garden
The family honor is at stake
the future of the Tokugawa Clan and
our sacred Samurai Code
I beg you be witness to my decision!
Both blades?
It's useless!
Such a blade couldn't slash a radish!
A samurai's blade is his soul!
Blade of bamboo...
And his is to die by hara-kiri?
A shameless wretch!
All is now ready
Motome Chijiiwa...
Rather than live in dishonor,
you have chosen to die by hara-kiri
A most commendable wish
An end befitting a true warrior
I am shamed to admit that even this House
with its proud traditions
boasts very few men of such integrity
To witness this most unique rite
all the retainers of this house hold
have been gathered here
Go your way... with heart at peace
A boon, sire!
Oh? What is it?
A day or two of grace... I implore you!
I seek not to escape! I will return
I beg you... implore you!
An odd request, indeed!
I have been informed that Edo abounds
with ex-warrior who disgrace our class
by threatening to perform hara-kiri at one's gate
unless a pittance is offered them
Don't tell me... you...
No... I would never...
Yes... I'm sure you wouldn't
A man of your lofty character would be,
incapable of such disreputable action
Now... feel free to proceed!
This unworthy will be your second
Exponent of the Shindo-Munen School
Though words be unnecessary, I would explain
The rite of hara-kiri has changed with the years
Of late, this sacred ritual
has fallen into idle formalism
The victim no sooner reaches for his blade,
than he is beheaded
No disembowelment is involved
In some cases, a fan is placed on the tray
instead of a blade
Today, however, no shabby imitation
of this sacred rite will be tolerated
All will proceed in traditional form
Understand?
Like this... you will open your bowels crosswise!
Only then will I undertake to execute my duty
I act only when disembowelment is to
our satisfaction
Is that clear?
Proceed!
It is your blade... and you die by it
A samurai's blade is his soul
What blade could be more appropriate?
Well... what keeps you?
Please, proceed
Strike!
Behead me!
Not yet! Slash open your bowels
Why stops? Pull your blade!
To the right!
Yes... even as a final resort...
to bite off one's own tongue...
A praiseworthy...
yet disgraceful act!
And after all... he threatened with
only bearing blades of bamboo
By the way... what are your intentions?
I assume you are referring to this?
The fate of this hapless youth was
exactly as I related it
Hon. Tsugumo... heed my advice and reconsider
No. No! Set your mind at ease on that score
Unlike this youthful Chijiiwa,
neither of my blades are of bamboo
I will perform the ritual
without biting off my tongue
Enough!
Hon. Tsugumo... at your insistence,
I grant you your wish
Attendant!
Hanshiro Tsugumo, ex-warrior of Geishu,
seeks to die by hara-kiri
As his dress is inappropriate,
he is to be supplied with robes...
What is it?
Such considerations are unwanted
My present attire most befits a
destitute ex-warrior
headed for the next world
For the considerate treatment
extended me this day
I am deeply grateful
Hanshiro Tsugumo fails to find words to
thank you
Now... I proceed
Incidentally, hon. Elder... who will be
acting as my second?
Ichiro Shinmen has been selected
You have a preference?
Yes... I would request the services of hon.
Hikokuro Omodake
His fame as a Shindo-Munen School
swordsman precedes him
True! Hikokuro has won wide acclaim
Hikokuro...
Omodaka has absented himself today
He has sent in a formal request for
4 or 5 days of rest
Indeed? Then it cannot be helped
Hon. Tsugumo... as you have just heard,
Omodaka is not present
Any other choice?
Hmm... most disappointing!
I had looked forward to hon.
Omodaka acting as my second
Could I not beg his special attendance?
Yes... perhaps. His fatigue was not
too noticeable yesterday
It couldn't be serious
Attendant!
Go seek out Omodaka and inform him
that I wish his attendance
Go now... hurry!
I am indebted to you for your kind consideration
And now... will you await him here?
Or will you come inside?
To re-enter your mansion
may cause my determination to waver
My pending journey might become distasteful
I will wait here
Your grim determination is awe-inspiring
Hon. Elder
There is nothing to be gained from
tedious waiting
Allow me to relate my life story to
pass the time
Oh? The story of your life?
Yes. The life story of an impoverished
ex-warrior may sound boring
but my fate here today
may be the fate of others tomorrow
Those who heed my tale
may even find
certain gems of wisdom hidden therein
Your fate today... another's tomorrow?
Yes... sounds interesting!
Heed well his final words
The words of a man heading for Eternity
This is no ordinary testament
There is much to be gained from it
Hon. Elder...
The tale you related earlier is complete
with all truths and facts?
It is
The Geishu ex-warrior, Motome Chijiiwa,
was a lad of some slight acquaintance
Motome Chijiiwa...
Yes... a lad of some slight acquaintance
Motome was a handsome youth of 15
And my daughter, Miho, a child of 11
Eleven years ago...
Yet... I close my eyes
and it all comes back to me as if it
were only yesterday
Another round?
Why bother?
Our duty is to rebuild
Archery will not help us
Oh, peace... wonderful peace!
By the way, the 22nd is the 7th anniversary
of my wife's death
Oh? I remember the date...
but the 7th already?
Yes... and I plan a small ceremony at
my residence
But not offerings...
I understand
But I can hardly believe it! Seven years?
And what is more,
a war-scarred veteran like you
bringing up that charming child all by yourself.
You... it's the other way around!
When hon. Yuki died,
I wondered how you'd manage
And yet... look at you...
a perfect kite-hawk combination!
The widowed kite puttering about
bringing up his young one
Only to find his young
grown into a princely hawk!
A fine young hawk!
Nonsense!
He grows up only in body
A far cry from the noble hawks
soaring overhead
You know... I always felt
I'd be of no use off the battlefield
but somehow I've managed
Had life gone on thus,
all would have been well
But not our life!
Our lives are like unto houses
built on foundations of sand
An ill wind means the end
What brought about the downfall of
Milord's vast Geishu domain?
Need I go into details?
You must all be informed
Repairs on Hiroshima Castle were construed
as a threat to the Tokugawa Shogunate
In June of 1619...
Our master's domain was abolished
and 12,000 innocent retainers of his household
were suddenly deprived of means of livelihood
Jinnai!
The Hon. Hanshiro Tsugumo
Final requests to my friend of long standing:
Demise of the hon.
Castle Repairs Commissioner
is expected at any moment
I precede him on this final journey
my attendance alone will suffice
I beg you to refrain
But my son,
Motome is yet a mere child of 15 years
I beg for him your future guidance
Impatient one! Could he not have
waited for me?
Hanshiro... I forbid you!
You are not to join me
it is all so meaningless!
Jinnai is enough!
Be not imprudent!
Jinnai died first to forest all
any attempts by you
He accompanies me on your behalf
And now, Hanshiro,
it is your duty to carry on
To take over for him...
Who else is there to look after his son,
Motome?
Masakatsu now goes to meet Jinnai
Hanshiro... have you no message for
your friend, Jinnai?
No message for Jinnai?
Inform Jinnai... just inform him...
The future and destiny of his son,
Motome Chijiiwa
Are watched over and protected by
Hanshiro... with his life!
Hon. Tsugumo
Well?
How did you fare?
Sire... he seems gravely afflicted
And what malady ails him?
His family reports that he suffers high fever
and much acute pain
I begged to visit his bed-side
but he suffers such great pain
that they would not allow it
I departed upon leaving your message
Then we have no choice
This sultry weather...
it must have afflicted him
Hon. Tsugumo...
you have heard his report
I must ask you to name another as
your second
Ah... most unfortunate! He seems too
indisposed to attend
Then I beg the services of Hayato Yazaki
Hayato? You wish Hayato?
Inaba... has not Yazaki been absent also?
Yes, sire... he applied for leave to
overcome his fatigue
Hon. Tsugumo... I regret to say that
Yazaki is also unavailable
Oh? Hon. Yazaki is also indisposed?
That is most unfortunate!
Then... as I have no choice...
I would request Umenosuke Kawabe
Hon. Elder... could hon. Kawabe also be ailing?
Could such a thing be possible?
Well, well! It seems that he also is indisposed
That all three of them should find
this day unfeasible...
A strange coincidence
How odd indeed!
All is not well...
Hikokuro was most insistent
and forced Motome Chijiiwa to commit Suicide
It was Hayato Yazaki who discovered that
the blade was of bamboo...
No... that was Umenosuke
After all... I warned them against it
It's no use now
Very true!
But how will you cope with him?
He is not one to die meekly
He must be plotting something
Whatever his intentions
I will force his hand and make him
perform hara-kiri
If he refuses,
I will have my men cut him down
without mercy
What happens within these walls
remains an unknown secret herein
The men will attack at my signal
But Hikokuro and the others bother me
I should send someone but under
the circumstances,
I wish you'd go personally
Hon. Tsugumo
Though summer days be long, time is fleeting
I bid you resign yourself
But hon. Elder! There can be no ritual
without a second
Yes... I have just discussed the matter
with my major-dojo
The men you request are not available
So I will pick one for you
Ichiro Shinmen!
You will act as second for the
Geishu ex-warrior, Tsugumo
Fulfill your duty with care
With your permission,
I named three men to serve as my second
I would still insist on one of them
Have you no ears?
All three are indisposed today!
Is that not clear enough... or can't you hear?
Oh? If such be the case,
there is nothing I can do
I fear this ritual must be postponed
Hold your tongue!
Your knavery goes too far!
First you beg a site to perform hara-kiri
Now you quibble over a second
You never intended to die!
Money was your motive!
If I were a common extortioner,
would I be placidly sitting here?
I came prepared to die
But hara-kiri alone
cannot ensure an easy trip to Hades
A second is needed to lop this off
A skilled master swordsman
What is more, I do not die a criminal
I am free to choose a second
You're a disgrace! A fraud!
Hara-kiri was not your motive...
Insolent dog!
Wait!
Restrain yourselves!
I beg a word with all present...
Pray restrain yourselves!
What now? It is too late for words
No... not yet!
I am not yet finished...
With my life story
For any more such lengthy tales, I have no ears!
Hon. Elder
Should you force my hand,
I will do battle like one possessed
Many of your innocent men will sustain injuries
Some may even die!
Would it not be wiser
for all to hear out my tale?
Then I will disembowel myself in good grace
Should hara-kiri be too good for me,
you may turn your men on me
But for now... I entreat you to hear me
out to the end
You will remain true to your word?
I swear it!
On your samurai honor?
Good! But make it short
I have no ears for long, absurd tales
Stand back, men!
Now... where was I?
Oh, yes... my master's house abolished;
the death of Jinnai Chijiiwa
and I had just reached the point
where he entrust me with his son
Following my master's downfall,
I left the land and came to Edo
The end of civil war created hordes of
ex-warriors
In better times, a clan would gladly
have employed
a distinguished ex-warrior
But in times of peace, the honored warrior
is no longer in demand
He eats or fasts as Fate dictates
Yes... it shames me to recall our life
during the past 8-9 years
However... even amidst such misery,
My daughter, Miho, continued to grow
and soon it was her 18th spring...
Hon. Sire...
Should I not return by midday,
your meal is prepared
The finest delicacy loses taste
when one dines alone
I will wait
Then after I receive payment,
I will purchase some dried fish
Your pardon!
Busy? You're going out?
Yes... to see the whole saler
The Hon. Mikawaya?
Good luck!
Experience surpasses training! You're quite
an expert now
Forgive me
For constantly requesting advances
My earrings are so meager
Your frank innocence disarms me
I had intended a few harsh words
By taking the initiative, you tie my hands
I bow to you
By the way... that proposition I put to
you the other day...
Have you given it serious thought?
Yes... my mind is made up
Oh? That's gratifying!
Yes, it takes a great burden off my mind
No... your proposal regarding Miho...
I have definitely decided against it
In short, the adoption of Miho would
merely be a pretext
The Sakakibara family would then make a
concubine of her
Hon. Tsugumo... it's a powerful clan
To be related to them
would assure you a rewarding future
Yes... I am aware of that
However, hon. Seibei never will I sacrifice
my daughter
to further my fortunes
Pride is all right
but should not a parent consider her plight?
A young... and beautiful... girl
without even a festival kimono
Day in and day out...
slaving at her father's side!
Hon. Tsugumo... do not be led a stray by
these times
It's futile to fight the tide
For Miho's sake and your own...
it's all too obvious...
only because she is blessed with
such beauty is such opportunity made possible
Confucius says
Ignorance of one's mission
makes not a Superior Person
Ignorance of etiquette means failure
Ignorance of words means ignorance of men
Class dismissed!
- Thank you, master
Hon.Sire...
Welcome, Sire...
Have some
I took the liberty of preparing us some tea
However, Motome... I have come for
some serious words with you
Honored one... why such formality?
Indeed... the days and months flow past
so swiftly!
Miho is already eighteen
And looking more and more like her mother
It seems unbelievable that she could
be my child
No... if she had taken after me,
such beauty would be impossible
Honored One... why are you talking this way?
You see... Motome...
I want you to take Miho as your wife
I realize that this is all very sudden
But... how about it, Motome?
Surely you are aware of the poverty in
which I live
As tutor for my neighbors children,
I sustain my miserable existence
How could I possibly take a wife?
You dislike Miho?
Do you like her... or don't you?
I do not ask you to marry Miho
merely because it was your sire's wish
No... boorish warrior that I am,
I can feel for you and Miho
Convincing Motome was no simple matter
The lad had a stubborn streak
which I had failed to realize
However... he did love Miho
and Miho certainly had no objections
The crane which lives 1,000 years
Symbolizes the countless happy joys;
The tortoise prevails 10,000 years
Bearing, the crowning triple pleasures
Hay the glistening sands long reflect
The sun of numerous morning to come
Two years passed, brought them their first son
A son who was named Kingo
It was I, of course, who served as the
infant's godfather
Welcome, sire
No... not asleep
Hon. Sire... you are too generous
Nonsense! Amidst your own chores,
you care for me
What is here... now that I am alone,
my wealth becomes a burden
Can't take it with me
Oh, no... it seems I have awakened him!
Yes, my fine rascal dimples
are not for a warrior's son
You little rogue!
Oh? The Matsudaira Clan abolished?
Yes. As with many another provincial warlord
However... this Clan was a link in
Tokugawa power
One outcome is sure... more ex-warriors!
Listen?
You heard how one threatened hara-kiri
at the Sengoku mansion
An ex-warrior from a provincial clan,
one Shume Chi...
Will this wake up the Sengoku?
It doesn't matter
Many ex-warriors force themselves
into various mansions
threatening hara-kiri
To stop these disturbances,
these households reluctantly offer them coins
A most shameful turn of events
Yes... a disgrace!
These happened
No officials' assistance,
things will continues
As you have said,
no report of officials' efforts for
the help of times like these
Live under the poverty... how can one
become so base?
Yes... what is it?
It is time now
It's the time, he wants his milk
Whenever he cries out, you feed him
An evil habit to form
Look... Kingo!
How, look...?
Kingo, like it?
With Kingo, we fear nothing
Life was full of laughter
However... such happy days were not
destined continue forever
The snowing winter,
snow was as thick as the mountain
One day... Miho vomited blood
One had always been a delicate child
and drudgery was too much
Her frail body had been over-worked too often
I can help nothing...
Motme tried hard
The poor boy!
Town Labor Poo
Fifty men, forty yens
Look, samurai!
Stay out! The townsmen need work
A sword-bearing laborer can only
bring me trouble
Twenty men, forty-five yens
Motome's plight was pitiful!
His every effort ended in vain
Miho went from bad to worse
Strange how evil hounds misfortune!
I still recall how we barely survived that year
Then as the spring of this year brought
forth plum blossoms...
What is it?
Motome!
Is it Miho?
It is Miho?
It's... Kingo...
What? Kingo?
He's feverish! He burns with fever
Miho... were you standing idly by
while this child was stricken?
It seemed a fever brought by a cold
But... what did the physician say?
He came... did he not?
You have not called in the physician?
But... why didn't you?
Kingo! Don't give up
This Old One and your parents
have long since sold our valuables
There is nothing... nothing we can
do to save you!
Though we be so helpless
Kingo a good samurai
must not give up the fight!
Kingo, you mustn't lose!
You mustn't!
You mustn't lose... you mustn't!
There is still one final chance
In my absence... look after Kingo
Motome... what is this new idea?
I know a former retainer
who is now a money-lender
But his rates were so high!
And this is no time to be concerned
about details
You are right!
If you know such a person... hurry!
Yes, I go now
I will return by evening at the latest
As Miho is also bed-ridden,
I beg you to look after Kingo
Do not worry, I'll be here
But, Motome, he is seriously ill
The greatest haste is required
Make arrangements and hurry back
Yes... I will return by evening
I go now
We depend on you, Motome
No, let me do it
Kingo... just a while longer...
What delays him?
This will not do!
What is keeping Motome?
What takes him so long?
Getting up now will do no good for
Kingo's fever!
Where can Motome be?
He should have returned by evening
He promised!
What keeps him? Where can he be?
I continued to wait
Each hour seemed as long as autumn day
But we waited in vain
Motome never did return to us
I will return by evening
Look after Kingo...
Those were his words on departing
Such was my final parting with
Motome Chijiiwa
However... later that night at the Hour
of the Dog
Motome did come home
But only by himself
He was accompanied by a gallant escort
of retainers
and underlings of the Iyi Clan
Such was the hon. Chijiiwa's touching request
However, our gateway was unsuitable,
and we cordially accommodated him in
our garden,
where he was able to fulfill his wish
Of late, one hears of mansion frequently
visited by ex-warriors
who extort a pittance
by threatening disembowelment
We understand that the households are
greatly embarrassed thereby
However... advent of
this honorable samurai, Chijiiwa,
who did die by hara-kiri:
And the honored House of Iyi
which did not fail to adopt appropriate
measures;
these two serve as examples to ex-warriors
and to weak-kneed members of
other households
A refreshing breeze
and eye-opener for such disgraceful elements!
Surely a matter for mutual congratulations
Show the blades
A moot point
Will you examine the two swords of
the deceased?
Please note... they are of bamboo
Of bamboo?
Miho!
Note that both blades are of bamboo
We want no claims regarding loss of the blades
Is that quite clear?
You understand?
The... Motome begged the loan of a blade
from one of you?
Such was not the case
He died magnificently... using that blades!
Motome... died by the bamboo blade?
Correct!
We witnessed in detail the ritual performed
with bamboo blade
An unsightly affair!
A samurai needs to die by a true blade
which is a warrior's soul
Now... we take leave
Miho wept...
and wept...
Forgive me!
It was I... who was so thoughtless!
You sold those blades...
You sold them for Miho's sake...
And still... I never realized...
Yet... I never parted with mine
I would never have dared
In my ignorance,
I clung... to these worthless symbols
Useless tokens...
Ravaged by raging fever and in a coma,
Kingo died some two days later
And three days later...
Miho also passed on...
following her child to the next world
Thus was Hanshiro Tsugumo left alone
in this world
Alone and solitary figure...
Hon. Tsugumo...
Does that conclude your tale?
Yes... in a way
No! I wish one final word
I beg all in attendance to listen well
No matter how dire his circumstances,
for a member of the samurai class
to extort aid by threatening hara-kiri
is an abominable act and cannot be forgiven!
On the other hand,
This household's method of coping with Chijiiwa
can justly be said to leave much to be desired
A samurai shaming himself
By begging a few days of grace must
certainly have a reason
Certainly it was not out of place for you to
ask his reason!
Is this asking too much?
Did not one of you now present feel need
for such consideration?
With a wife fatally stricken
and an innocent, ailing child demanding
immediate attention...
He begged this chance to inform me
and to make one final effort
before leaving matters in my hands and
returning to this mansion
Hanshiro Tsuguma!
Enough of your excuses!
Chijiiwa may have been victim of
various circumstances
But he himself want to die!
Though matters did not go as planned,
he sowed his own seeds
It was not for him to resent,
blame or accuse others!
It was for him to forget all else and
die a magnificent death
To go unwavering to one's death is
the way of the true samurai!
But to plead for days of grace!
Signs of a true coward!
No wonder one thought him mad!
Yes, you are right!
Truly, Motome was not in his right mind
But for such state of mind,
I have only praise
Even the famous samurai is a mere
human being
He cannot live on air alone
In a crisis,
even men like Motome will stand by
their family
Yes, and I'm glad!
The bamboo ex-warrior
Not only samurai...
even the townsmen sneer at
Motome's memory
Yes. Let them who would... laugh!
It is impossible to fathom the hearts of all men
The ruthless Shogunate policy of wiping
out the provincial lords,
brings ruin to innocent thousands!
The well fed may never realize this
Some among you
may loathe Motome for his pleas
Put yourself in his position,
what would you have done?
After all... our samurai honor...
merely glosses the surface
Enough nonsense!
You dare suggest that our honor is
merely superficial?
That's right!
Some threaten hara-kiri
and try to evade the consequences
Such wishful thinking can be perilous
Any who ask are allowed to die
In fact... we see to it that they do!
It is the way of our Clan
No half measures for us!
In other words,
you believe that I have no intentions of dying?
That I come, enraged at the way
you dealt with my son-in-law,
merely to give voice to my numerous grudges?
Is that what you believe?
Need you ask me?
You need only ask yourself
Either way... you have no intention of
letting me get away?
That is my choice
I see no reason to ask you to leave
Hon. Elder... suspicious eyes welcome the devil
You recognize the proverb?
My promise to perform hara-kiri is not a fraud
Despite all my efforts... you still...
First of all... even if I do live on,
what is there to look forward to?
Much rather would I hurry to join Motome...
Miho... and Kingo
In the Land beyond where they await
my coming
However... I cannot go to them with
both these hands empty
Is that not true?
Explaining Motome's predicament enables
your men to understand his position...
To reflect on their own hot-blooded approach...
Not all are convinced that they did right
Was it possible that they might have
carried things too far?
Perhaps more appropriate measures could
have been taken...
A single word to this effect would being
satisfaction to Motome
Would this not be most fitting gift I could
take to him?
Such were my plans... but to my regret,
that was not to be
Now we understand each other
Your touching tale is of no use
No... a samurai who claims that honor serves
only to embellish the surface
could never reach our hearts
In short... they are the illogical
grumbling of a senile ex-warrior?
Well... it serves no purpose to lament that now
Forgive my prolonged narrative
Now I go through with the ritual...
Oh... one moment!
Before beginning,
I must return some items entrusted to me
Each bears the name of the original owner
Please, study them
Hon. Hayato Yazaki... hon.
Umenosuke Kawabe... both swordsmen
held in high esteem by the Iyi Clan
for their honored bravery
But, hon. Elder...
and others in attendance... be not concerned!
I accepted only their top-knots
and not their lives
My encounter with hon. Yazaki took place
six days ago...
One moment!
Hon. Kawabe was disposed of five days ago...
on May 8th
But the master swordsmen of the
Shindo-Munen School,
hon. Hikokuro Omodaka was not to be
made light of...
Possibly aware of the fate of his
two companions,
he was never off guard
Yes... to be honest,
I was at a loss as to how to deal with hon.
Omodaka
As you reach out for your blade
I draw... and fell you with one blow!
However... I fear that my blade will be
blocked by this lintel
A sideward blow at your waist is hampered
by this pillar
Forgive my delay
I couldn't find you
Please, make ready
As one cannot duel here,
we will repair to the Plains of Gojin-In
Hovel that it is,
the owner may be annoyed if you fail to return
And someone must come to dispose of
your corpse
I suggest a short note stating that
you proceed to the Plains of Gojin-In
to duel with Hikokuro Omodaka
He wisely took advantage of the winds
But a blade not only cuts... it can stab or
be used to snap others
Swordsmanship untested in battle
is like swimming on land
Be that as it may it was my first fight in
16 years
Since the Summer Siege of Osaka
Taking a man's head is not easy
But to take only his top-knot was harder still!
Irrespective of skill,
to lose one's top-knot is equivalent to
losing one's head
A laxity and dishonor
which even death cannot wipe away!
Yet, they claim illness and hide
until their top-knots grow back, hon. Elder!
You boast of traditions of bravery but
even the code of the House of Iyi seeks
only a false front!
A maniac! Fell the culprit!
Hanshiro Tsugumo has fallen, sire
And our casualties?
The casualties among our men!
Masakatsu Sugita... Sobei Umemura...
Ichiro Shinmen... Uemon Yoshioka...
died in action
Eight others suffer injuries
The ex-warrior from Geishu,
Hanshiro Tsugumo, died of hara-kiri
Our retainers died of illness
No retainer of the Iyi Clan was killed or maimed
by this impoverished ex-warrior!
At his own request,
ex-warrior Hanshiro Tsugumo performed hara-kiri!
Our men died of illness!
There can be no connection!
See that none other dies of illness
The injured must be given treatment
immediately!
Hon. Elder... I return
Omodaka... Hikokuro... died last night at
his residence
The two others, Kawabe and Yazaki,
still claim illness... but...
Foolish one!
Why did you not order them to die?
Go immediately... order them to die by hara-kiri!
And... take some skilled men with you!
Should they refuse,
they are to be slain on the spot! Understand!
Also, these men... Omodaka, too,
are victims of illness... not hara-kiri!
Stupid one!
You know the ways of administration...
You fall to realize the implications?
You idiot!
I go now, sire
Geishu ex-warrior, Hanshiro Tsugumo,
died by hara-kiri in the early evening
His words and actions markedly odd
Many considered him as being out of his mind
Also, disposition of Geishu ex-warrior,
Motome Chijiiwa, who died in January,
was found appropriate
and the fame of the House of Iyi was
greatly enhanced
In this case also,
our stern measures were soon known
throughout the administration
Consequently,
three days later,
during formal session at the Castle,
His Lordship took occasion to laud our hon.
Heir Bennosuke
...in peace as in turbulence...
With this borne in mind
the House of Iyi will prosper
throughout the ages
May 16th, 1630... 7th Year of Kan-Ei