- Joint raided!
- No!
That's just our Raymond,
our lovable Sgt. Shaw.
All right. Let's go, you men.
Come on.
Let's go.
Come on, Sarge.
Gertrude buy you beer.
What's the matter with him?
I'm afraid our Saint Raymond,
he don't approve.
Maybe he's got a girl back home,
or something.
Him? Our Raymond?
Are you kidding?
- Silvers, how about the robe?
- What are you talking? Get out.
Bad here.
- How do you know?
- Chunjin born two miles from here.
So far, every place we've been in Korea,
this joker was born two miles from it.
What's so bad about it?
Tricky. Swamp all around.
Thirty yards up, maybe quicksand.
Nobody said anything about quicksand.
Can't we go around it?
- No, Sergeant.
- What's your personal advice?
All walk in single line,
next 200 yards.
Not tactical to travel forward
in a single line.
Patrol sink.
We go around it.
- No, Sergeant.
- Never mind.
Okay, pass the word.
Ths naton jealously guards
ts hghest award for valor
the Congressonal Medal of Honor.
In the Korean war,
wth 5,720 mllon personnel engaged...
only men were so honored.
One of these men
was Staff Sgt. Raymond Shaw.
Raymond Shaw was returned from combat
and flown drectly to Washngton...
to be decorated personally
by the Presdent of the Unted States.
Ths s why hs presence, or the
presence of any Medal of Honor wnner...
s suffcent to brng generals
to ther feet, salutng.
Congratulations, son.
How do you feel?
Like Capt. Idiot
in Astounding Science Comics.
Hold it, General.
Hold it, General, please. Come on.
Get in there quickly.
Mother, what is this?
What are you doing here?
Sen. Iselin, how does it feel to be
the father of a Medal of Honor winner?
- He is not my father.
- The Senator is Raymond's stepfather.
I can only say that, as one...
who has devoted his life
to the service of his country...
You did this...
You did this, Mother. You organized
this disgusting three-ring circus.
You're a Medal of Honor winner.
Incidentally, congratulations.
I would have written, but we've been
in a frightful mess the last few months.
All right, let him through!
That's enough, now.
Let him through.
Say 'cheese.'
All right, that's enough, now.
Let the poor boy through.
Please, let him through.
What is the matter, Raymond?
We've gone to a lot of trouble to...
- Arrange the parade foryou.
- The parade?
Get that out. Your sick...
Just because your parents
and the entire country...
- are proud of you...
- Who's kidding who, Mother?
Johnny's up for re-election in November.
You've got it all figured out, haven't you?
Johnny Iselin's boy, Medal of Honor winner
That should get you 50,000 votes.
Raymond, I'm your mother.
How can you talk to me this way?
I want nothing for myself.
My entire life is devoted
to helping you and to helping Johnny.
- My boys, my two little boys.
- Mother, stop it.
That is all I have.
On the afternoon of hs arrval
n Washngton...
Raymond Shaw was decorated
at the Whte House...
by the Presdent of
the United States.
Hs ctaton, attested to
by hs commandng offcer...
Capt. Bennett Marco, and the nne
survvng members of hs patrol...
read n part 'Dsplayng valor
above and beyond the call of duty...
dd sngle-handedly save the lves
of nne members of hs patrol...
capturng an enemy machne-gun nest,
and takng out n the process...
a full company of enemy nfantrt.
He then led hs patrol, whch had been
lsted as mssng n acton for three days...
back through the enemy lnes to safety.
A gift from the Citizens For Iselin
Committee for his last birthday.
It absolutely saved our lives
during the campaign.
You see,
this opens up into a double bed.
This is the Press Room.
And this is my private office.
Anything to take the pain
out of campaigning, eh?
That's what I always say.
- May I take this thing off now, Mother?
- Raymond, what is the matter with you?
You look as if your head were going
to come to a point in seconds.
Johnny, fix him a drink or something.
Sit down, Raymond. Relax.
We'll be home in less than
two-and-a-half hours.
I'm not going home with you, Mother.
I'm going to New York.
What?
I've got a job on a newspaper.
Research Assistant
to Mr. Holborn Gaines.
Holborn Gaines, that Communist?
He's not a Communist, Mother.
As a matter of fact, he's a Republican.
But the terrible things he's written
about Johnny...
He came to interview me
at the White House this morning.
Afterwards, I asked him for a job.
He gave it to me.
We discovered that we had
a great deal in common.
What could you possibly have in common
with that dreadful old man?
For one thing, we discovered that we
both loathe and despise you and Johnny.
And that's a beginning.
The war n Korea was over.
Captan, now Major, Bennett Marco
had been reassgned...
to Army Intellgence
n Washngton.
It was, by and large,
a pleasant assgnment...
except for one thng.
Nght after nght, the major was plagued
by the same reoccurrng nghtmare.
Stop it. Stop it.
Another modern discovery,
which we owe to the hydrangea...
concerns the influence of air-drainage
upon plant climate.
Many years ago, when I was traveling
about the country...
I noticed magnificent hydrangeas
on the hills...
where the air-drainage
was perfect...
and very poor specimens, or perhaps
none at all, in the valleys.
Formerly, we used to consider
sheltered valleys...
more favorable to plants
than hilltops...
but the avoidance of late spring
and early autumn frosts...
enjoyed by sites
with good air-drainage...
where the cold air can drain safely
away to lower levels...
gives the hills a decided advantage.
Thus it was the hydrangeas that gave
the first pointer...
in another modern discovery
of horticultural importance.
From this, it might appearthat
the hydrangea is a fairly simple plant.
But there are more complications.
The cultivation of hydrangeas
was evolved from...
a number of varieties
originally found in Japan...
not all of which, of course,
have the same characteristics.
Two of them do not share the quality
of producing...
blue flowers in
mineral-rich soils.
Allow me to introduce
our American visitors.
I must ask you to forgive their
somewhat lackadaisical manners...
but I have conditioned them,
or 'brainwashed' them...
which I understand
is the new American word...
to believe that they are
in the lobby of a hotel in New Jersey...
where a meeting of the Ladies'
Garden Club is in progress.
You will notice that I have told them
they may smoke.
I have allowed my people
to have a little fun...
in the selection
of bizarre tobacco substitutes.
Are you enjoying your cigarette, Ed?
Yes, ma'am.
'Tastes good,
like a cigarette should.'
Now then, comrades...
may I present
the famous Raymond Shaw...
the young man you've flown 80,000 miles
to this dreary spot in Manchuria to see.
Raymond, pull your chair over here
by me, please.
I am sure you've all heard
the old wives' tale...
that no hypnotized
subject may be forced...
to do that which is repellent to his
moral nature, whateverthat may be.
Nonsense, of course.
You note-takers might set down
a reminderto consult Brenman's paper.
Experments n the Hypnotc Producton
of Ant-Socal and Self-lnjurous Behavor.
Or Wells' paper which was titled,
I believe...
Experments n the Hypnotc
Producton of Crme.
Or, of course, Andrew Salter's
remarkable book...
Condtoned Reflex Therapy...
to name only three.
Or if it offends you
that only the West is working...
to manufacture more crime
and better criminals...
against the modern shortages...
I suggest Krasnogorski's...
Primary violence Motivation...
or Serov's The Unilateral Suggestion
to Self-Destruction.
My dear Yen, as you grow older,
you grow more long-winded.
Can't we get to the point?
Has the man ever killed anyone?
Or has he not?
I apologize, my dear Dimitri.
I keep forgetting that you're a young
country and your attention span is limited.
Tell me, Raymond,
have you ever killed anyone?
- No, ma'am.
- Not even in combat?
In combat?
Yes, ma'am, I think so.
Of course you have, Raymond.
Raymond has been a crack shot
since childhood.
Marvelous outlet
for his aggressions.
May I have the bayonet,
please?
Not with the knife.
With the hands.
With the hands?
Here, have him use this.
Raymond, whom do you dislike the least
in your group here today?
- The least?
- That's right.
I guess Capt. Marco, ma'am.
Notice how he is always
drawn to authority?
That won't do, Raymond.
We need the captain
to get you your medal.
Whom else?
- I guess Ed Mavole, ma'am.
- That's better.
Now then, Raymond,
take this scarf...
and strangle Ed Mavole
to death.
Yes, ma'am.
Excuse me, Ben.
Pardon me.
Hey, Sarge, cut it out.
Quiet, Ed, please.
Now, you just sit there quietly
and cooperate.
Yes, ma'am.
Major, to your knowledge...
have any other ex-members of your
patrol had similar dreams?
No, sir, not to my knowledge.
Doesn't it strike
any one as curious...
that Mavole was one of the two men
lost in the action?
Yet, every night in my dream...
he's the one that Raymond...
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
Now look, Maj. Marco...
since you first brought this recurring
dream of yours to our attention...
Raymond Shaw, his life,
his background, his habits...
his friends and associates have been
under scrupulous examination.
The facts speak forthemselves.
His stepfather is
a United States senator.
His mother is head of different
patriotic organizations.
Raymond himself works as confidential
assistant to Holborn Gaines...
the most respected
political journalist in America.
It's inconceivable that anything...
As the consulting
psychiatrist present...
I'd be interested in hearing
your personal feelings about Shaw.
Raymond Shaw is the kindest,
bravest, warmest...
most wonderful human being
I've ever known in my life.
I see.
And this opinion, Major,
was it generally held?
His fellow soldiers, did they feel
the same way toward him?
The men loved him, sir.
Why shouldn't they?
He saved their lives.
It would seem obvious to me...
that Maj. Marco is suffering
a delayed reaction...
to 18 months of continuous
combat in Korea.
I strongly recommend that the matter of
Raymond Shaw be dropped here and now...
and that Maj. Marco
be temporarily reassigned...
to less strenuous and, if I may say so,
less sensitive duties.
I think a few months'
detached service...
to, perhaps, the Public
Relations Corps...
should put the Major right
back in the pink.
Mr. Secretary...
Mr. Secretary, can you explain
the proposed cut in budget?
Since, sir, you've asked
a simple-minded question...
I will give you an equally
simple-minded answer.
Since no great naval power
menaces the free world today...
the Navy's overwhelming preponderance
of surface ships seems to be superfluous.
Hence the cut in budget.
Major, my time is important.
How much longer must we go on
with this nonsense?
If there are no further questions,
I think that about wraps things up.
Mr. Secretary,
I have a question, sir.
Who are you, sir?
I am United States Senator
John Yerkes Iselin.
And I have a question so serious...
that the safety of our nation may well
depend on your answer.
Who?
No evasions, Mr. Secretary,
no evasions, if you please, sir.
Evasions? What the hell
are you talking about?
What kind of foolishness is this?
I'm new at this job, but I don't
think it's good public relations...
to talk that way to a senator,
even if he is an idiot.
I am United States Senator
John Yerkes Iselin...
and I have here a list
of the names of 270 persons...
who are known
by the Secretary of Defense...
as being members of
the Communist Party...
and who are still, nevertheless,
working at shaping the policy...
of the Defense Department!
- Senator who?
- I demand an answer.
There will be no covering up, sir.
- What?
- No covering up.
- You won't get your hands on this list.
- How did you get in here in the first place?
- Major, throw that lunatic out of here.
- And I deeply regret having to say...
- in front of these ladies and gentlemen...
- You claim to be a senator?
...and the radio audience of our great nation
that you no longer have my confidence.
You're an idiot, if you ask me.
You're out of your mind.
This is no longer a matterfor investigation
by the Defense Department.
Get out of here!
- I'm afraid you've lost your chance.
- Get that man out of this room.
This matter is now the responsibility
of the United States Senate.
I will not have him in here,
do you hear me? Not ever!
If I ever catch you in this room again,
I'll throw you out bodily.
What do you want?
Get out of here.
- Hold it.
- Don't you take my picture anymore.
Clearthis room!
Sen. Iselin.
I'd like to verify that number, sir.
How many Communists did you say?
I said there are exactly...
I have proof there are...
104 card-carrying Communists
in the Defense Department.
How many, sir?
275, and that's all I have to say
on the subject at this time.
Major, how many did he say?
Excuse me just a moment.
- Very good, Raymond.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Capt. Marco?
- Yes.
On yourfeet, Captain, please.
Sorry, ma'am.
When you are returned
with your patrol to Korea...
and you make your way
to Command Headquarters...
what will be the first duty
you will undertake?
I will make my report
on the patrol, ma'am.
What will you report?
I will recommend urgently...
that Raymond Shaw be posted
forthe Medal of Honor.
He saved our lives and took out
a complete company of Chinese infantry.
A complete company?
What the hell is this?
We can spare an imaginary company
of infantry forthis particular plan...
- Mikhail Mikhailovich.
- All right.
If we are out to humiliate
our brave Chinese ally...
in the newspapers of the world...
we might as well make it
a full battalion.
We don't object, Comrade,
I assure you of that.
However, Comrade, we thank you for
thinking of the matter in that light.
If we may proceed
with the demonstration...
who is that little fellow
sitting next to the Captain?
That's Bobby Lembeck...
our mascot, I guess you'd call him.
Doesn't look old enough
to be in your army.
I guess he isn't, but there he is, ma'am.
Capt. Marco, will you be good enough
to lend Raymond your pistol, please?
Yes, ma'am.
- Thanks, Ben.
- Sure, kid.
Shoot Bobby, Raymond.
Through the forehead.
Wake up, it's all right.
Everything's all right.
It's all right.
That same dream again?
What makes it so awful...
is to keep dreaming a thing
like that about Sgt. Shaw.
It's been going on for weeks, now.
I must be going crazy.
You ought to write to Sgt. Shaw.
- I tell you, nothing's wrong with me.
- Ask if anyone else is having similar dreams.
Maybe I will.
Maybe I'll do that.
If anybody can help me, he can.
You like him a lot, don't you?
Raymond Shaw is the bravest,
kindest, warmest...
most wonderful human being
I've ever known in my life.
'Dear Sarge, I had to say ths
or wrte ths to someone...
'because I thnk I'm gong nuts.
'Snce you were my best frend n
the army, here goes.
'Sarge, I'm n trouble.
'I'm afrad to go to sleep
because I have terrble dreams.
'I dream about all the guys on the patrol
where you won the medal...
and the dream has
a lot of Chnese people n t...
'and a lot of bg brass
from the Russan Army.
'Well, t's pretty rough,
you have to take my word for that.'
- Raymond Shaw, please.
- This is he.
Raymond, why don't you pass the tme
by playng a lttle soltare?
Can you see the red queen?
Good.
One week from next Saturday,
you wll be called for...
at 11:10 a.m. And taken
to the Tmothy Swardon Santarum...
84 East 61st Street.
We want you there for a checkup.
Is that clear?
You may put the cards away now.
Goodbye, Raymond.
Mr. Gaines, it's Mr. Shaw.
He was run down on the street
by a hit-and-run driver.
It just came overthe AP.
Good heavens.
Find out what hospital he's in,
and call them.
See if there's anything
we can do to help.
You're welcome. Goodbye.
That was Mr. Gaines,
from his newspaper.
He said to tell him to take it easy
and not to worry about a thing.
Which, of course,
we will not tell him...
on the chance it is
some sort of pre-arranged code.
- Comrade zilkov?
- Yes?
Yen Lo. Pavlov Institute.
Doctor...
an honor and a pleasure.
You may go.
When did you arrive?
I was flown in last night
under embassy quota.
Revolting journey.
Raymond, it's nice to see you again.
It's nice to see you again, sir.
We're going through
this elaborate procedure...
simply out of precaution...
in case there are any visitors.
Although I cannot imagine
who will visit Raymond.
- Attractive plant you have here.
- Thank you, Doctor.
It's actually a rest home
for wealthy alcoholics.
We were able to purchase it
three years ago.
Except forthis floor and the floor above it,
which is sealed for security purposes...
the rest functions quite normally.
It is one of the few Soviet
operations in America...
that actually showed a profit
at the end of the last fiscal year.
Profit? Fiscal year?
Beware, my dear zilkov.
The virus of capitalism's highly infectious.
Soon, you'll be lending money out
at interest.
You must try, Comrade zilkov,
to cultivate a sense of humor.
There is nothing like a good laugh
to lighten the burdens o the day.
Tell me, Raymond...
do you remember murdering
Mavole and Lembeck?
I beg your pardon, sir?
Mavole and Lembeck...
the men who were lost
on the patrol.
Do you recall
what happened to them?
It was a very clear action
for a night action.
Capt. Marco sent up
some low flares...
so it was easy to see
what was happening.
Bobby Lembeck got separated
to the left.
Mavole went after him.
By the time he reached him,
the enemy had a fix on the position.
They were killed instantly
by a high mortar shell.
I don't think they ever knew
what hit them.
Do you realize, Comrade...
the implications of the weapon
that has been placed at your disposal?
You may remove
your head bandage, Raymond.
A normally conditioned
American...
who has been trained to kill and then
to have no memory of having killed.
Without memory of his deed,
he cannot possibly feel guilt.
Nor will he, of course, have any
reason to fear being caught.
Having been relieved of those uniquely
American symptoms guilt and fear...
he cannot possibly give himself away.
Our Raymond will remain
an outwardly normal, productive...
sober and respected member
of the community.
And, I should say, if properly used,
entirely police-proof.
His brain has not only been washed,
as they say, it has been dry-cleaned.
Thank you, Raymond,
you may replace your head bandage.
Sealed floors or no, you
will permit him visitors...
to avoid suspicion.
Ateam of my specialists
is being flown in tonight.
It will take about a week,
working between visiting hours...
to check the mechanism out
completely.
It has been two years since
the conditioning took place.
And you want to be sure the linkages
are still functioning correctly...
before he is turned over
to his American operator.
- Comrade, if you will excuse me.
- Where are you going?
Since I can do nothing more
until my specialists arrive...
I had thought to spend
the afternoon at Macy's.
Madame Yen has given me
the most appalling list.
I personally guarantee it. He is ready to be
turned overto his American operator.
And I, being personally responsible
for Soviet Security...
in the entire Eastern Seaboard
of the United States...
refuse to turn him over
to his operator...
until at least one practical test
has been run.
You say the man has been built
as an assassin.
Very well, then.
Let him assassinate someone.
I'm shocked that a security officer
with the responsibility you hold...
would risk a mechanism
as valuable as Raymond...
out of sheer nervousness.
You yourself admit the man has not
killed for overtwo years.
I assure you, Doctor, conditions
offering minimum risk can be arranged.
All right.
If you insist on this foolishness...
have him kill one of your own people
here on a sealed floor.
I would gladly.
But ourtable of organization happens to be
under acceptable strength as it is.
Why can't we be reasonable
about this?
Why can't he kill some
non-productive person on the outside?
Very well, then.
For his own protection, he must be
instructed that if he is ever...
discovered at the scene of an
assignment, this other person...
or persons must also be killed.
All right, doctor.
Whom do you think he should kill?
With humor, my dear zilkov,
always with a little humor.
If kill we must, for a better New York,
why should it not be...
his superior at the newspaper,
Mr. Holborn Gaines?
With Mr. Gaines out of the way...
might he not then be given
that very influential job himself?
Who's there?
It's me, Mr. Gaines.
Raymond.
I'm sorry to disturb you, sir.
Don't get any silly ideas about
this ridiculous-looking bed jacket.
It was my wife's.
It's the warmest thing I have.
Perfect for reading
in bed at night.
I didn't know
you were married, sir.
She died nearly six years ago.
What the devil are you doing here
at 4 a.m.
Anyway, I thought you were
in the hospital.
Don't tell me you've come here at
this ridiculous hourto talk something over.
You're not going to pour out your heart with
the details of a sordid love affair, are you?
As a matter of fact,
they told me you'd be asleep.
- Who told you I'd be asleep?
- They did.
They?
Who are 'they'?
Who's this mysterious 'they'?
Answer me, my boy.
- Colonel.
- Ben.
- May I come in for a minute?
- Please do. Come on in.
May I ask A Is this an official visit?
And B May I mix you a drink?
AYes, it is,
and B You certainly may.
- Scotch all right?
- Fine.
My God, where do you
get all the books?
I got a guy who picks them out for me,
at random.
Water all right?
Fine.
He's in San Francisco.
Got a little bookstore out there...
and he ships them to me
wherever I happen to be stationed.
- You read them all?
- Yeah.
They'd also make great insulation
against an enemy attack.
But the truth of the matter is
that I'm just interested in...
The Prncples of Modern Bankng...
Hstort of Pracy...
Pantngs of Orozco...
Modern French Theater...
The Jursprudental Factor
of Mafa Admnstraton...
Dseases of Horses
and novels of Joyce Cart, and...
Ethnc Choces of the Arabs.
Thngs lke that.
- Ben?
- Yeah.
The army's got a lot of things
wrong with it...
but it does take care of its own people,
which is why I'm here.
As a public relations officer,
you're a disaster.
- I never wanted...
- Apparently, among otherthings...
you permitted the Secretary to make some
unfortunate remarks to that idiot Iselin...
- which started him off on a rampage.
- Mickey, listen to me, please.
For six months, I've been driven nearly mad
by a recurring dream...
The medical officer in charge...
What the hell does the Medical Corps
know about intelligence work, Milt?
I tell you,
there's something phony going on.
There's something phony about me,
Raymond Shaw...
about the whole Medal of Honor
business.
For instance, when the psychiatrist asked
me how I personally felt about Raymond...
and how the whole patrol felt about him,
did you hear what I said?
Did you really hear what I said?
I said, 'Raymond Shaw
is the kindest, warmest...
'bravest, most wonderful human
being I have ever known.'
And even now I feel that way,
this minute.
Yet, somewhere in the back of my mind,
something tells me it's not true.
It's just not true.
It isn't as if Raymond's hard to like.
He's impossible to like!
He's probably one of
the most repulsive human beings...
I've known in all of my life.
Ben, what I came to tell you is
Public Relations has sent you back to me.
And in your present state
there's no possible way I can use you.
As of this moment,
I'm placing you on indefinite sick leave.
Go away, Ben. Find yourself a girl.
Lie in the sun.
I absolutely refuse.
You don't seem to understand.
What I've just told you
is not a suggestion, Major.
It is an order.
Yes, sir.
Good night, Ben.
- Do you mind if I smoke?
- Not at all. Please do.
Maryland's a beautiful state.
- This is Delaware.
- I know.
I was one of the original Chinese workmen
who laid the track on this stretch.
But, nonetheless,
Maryland is a beautiful state.
So is Ohio, forthat matter.
I guess so. Columbus is
a tremendous football town.
- You in the railroad business?
- Not anymore.
However, if you will permit me
to point out...
when you ask that question,
you should say...
'Are you in the railroad line? '
Where's your home?
I'm in the army. I'm a Major.
I've been in the army most of my life.
We move a good deal.
I was born in New Hampshire.
I went to a girls' camp once
on Lake Francis.
That's pretty far north.
- What's your name?
- Euginie.
Pardon?
No kidding, I really mean it.
Crazy French pronunciation
and all.
- It's pretty.
- Thank you.
I guess yourfriends
call you Jennie?
Not yet, they haven't,
for which I am deeply grateful.
But you may call me Jennie.
What do yourfriends call you?
Rosie.
Why?
My full name is Eugenie Rose.
Of the two names,
I've always favored Rosie...
because it smells of brown soap
and beer.
Eugenie is somehow more fragile.
When I asked you what your name was,
you said it was Eugenie.
It's quite possible I was feeling
more or less fragile at that instant.
I could neverfigure out what that
phrase meant 'more or less.'
Are you Arabic?
My name is Ben. It's really Bennett.
I was named after Arnold Bennett.
- The writer?
- No. A lieutenant colonel.
He was my father's commanding officer
at the time.
- What's your last name?
- Marco.
Maj. Marco.
Are you Arabic?
Let me put it another way.
Are you married?
- No. You?
- No.
- What's your last name?
- Cheney.
I'm production assistant
for a man named Justin...
who had two hits last season.
I live on 54th Street...
a few doors from
the Modern Museum of Art...
of which I am a Tea-Privileges Member.
No cream.
I live at 53 West 54th Street.
Apartment 3 B.
Can you rememberthat?
Eldorado 59970.
Are you stationed in New York?
Or is stationed the right word?
I'm not exactly stationed in New York.
I was stationed in Washington.
But I got sick, and now I'm on leave
and I'm going to spend it in New York.
Eldorado 59970.
I'm going to look up an old friend of mine
who's a newspaper man.
We were in Korea together.
Mr. Shaw, there's a gentleman outside
to see you.
- A gentleman?
- An Oriental gentleman, sir.
He said he was in the army with you.
There were no Oriental gentlemen
in the army with me.
He is very insistent, sir.
All right, show him in.
I am Chunjin, Mr. Shaw, sir.
I was interpreter attached
to Charlie Company, 52nd Regiment.
Yes, I rememberyou.
You were the guide and interpreter
to the patrol.
What can I do foryou?
- What are you doing here?
- Yourfather did not say to you?
- My father?
- Yes. Sen. Iselin. I write to...
Sen. Iselin is not my father.
Repeat, he is not my father.
If you learn nothing else on your visit
to this country, memorize that fact.
I write to Sen. Iselin.
I tell him how I interpret
your outfit.
I tell him I want to come to America.
He get me visa.
Now I need job.
Ajob?
Yes, sir, Mr. Shaw.
But, my dearfellow,
we don't need interpreters here.
We all speak the same language.
I am tailor and mender.
I am cook, I drive car.
I am cleaner and scrubber.
I fix anything. I take message.
I sleep at house of my cousin.
I ask for job with you...
because you are a great man
who saved my life.
I could use a valet, I think.
And I would like having a cook.
A good cook, I mean.
Very well,
you can live at your cousin's.
I will pay you $ 60 a week.
You will have every Thursday
and every other Sunday off.
Thank you, Mr. Shaw.
I'm leaving for Washington
in a few minutes.
I'll be back here by 8:10 p.m.
I would like to have dinner waiting.
Yes, sir, Mr. Shaw.
Just like United States Army.
Oh, God, I hope not.
You're going to be marvelous
in there this afternoon, hon...
ljust know you are.
There's just one thing, babe.
I'd be a lot happier if we could just
settle on the number...
of Communists I know there are
in the Defense Department.
I mean, the way you keep changing
the figures on me all the time...
it makes me look like
some kind of a nut, an idiot.
The boys were even starting
to kid me about it.
Just yesterday in the cloakroom,
they said, 'Hey, Johnny'...
You'll look like a fool if you
don't do what you're told.
Who are they writing about all over
this country, and what are they saying?
Are they saying, 'Are there any
Communists in the Defense Department? '
Of course not.
They're saying...
'How many Communists
are there in the Defense Department? '
So stop talking like an expert
all of a sudden...
and get out there and
say what you're supposed to say.
Come on, babe.
I'm sorry, hon.
Would it really make it easierforyou
if we settled on just one number?
Just one real simple number
that will be easy for me to remember.
There are exactly
57 card-carrying members...
of the Communist Party in
the Department of Defense at this time.
Point of order, Mr. Speaker.
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
How did the old ladies
turn into Russians?
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
How did the old ladies turn into Russians?
What was Raymond doing with his hands?
What were you doing there?
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
What were you doing there?
It was original of you to have
the police department call so shyly...
and ask for ourfirst date.
They asked me who
I'd be willing to...
I know, and thank you.
I've got to find Raymond.
Maybe he's home by now.
All right, darling.
Whateveryou want.
But first,
I have something to tell you.
You know what I was doing
when you so cleverly had the police call?
Don't bothertrying to guess,
you're too tired.
I'll tell you what I was doing.
After I dropped you off...
I went straight home,
and when I got upstairs...
- Apartment 3 B.
- That's right. Very good.
Before I even took my coat off,
I telephoned my fianc.
I told you I wasn't married,
I never said I wasn't engaged.
Well, I called up my fianc,
and he came over as soon as he could...
which was instantly...
and I told him
I had just met you...
and I gave him his ring back.
I tried to convey my regrets for
whatever pain I might be causing him.
Just then, you had the police call to invite
me to meet you at the 24th Precinct.
So I grabbed my coat,
kissed my fianc on the cheek...
forthe last time in our lives
we would ever kiss...
and I ran.
At the police station, they told me you had
beaten up a very large Chinese gentleman.
Not Chinese, dear, Korean.
At least, I think he was Korean.
A large Korean gentleman, but that
you were a pretty solid type yourself...
according to Washington,
with whom they had checked.
So I figured...
if they'd botherto get a comment
on you from George Washington...
you must be somebody
very important indeed.
I must say, it was rather sweet of
the general, with you only a major.
I didn't even know you knew him.
If they were the tiniest bit puzzled
about you, they could have asked me.
Yes, indeed, my darling Ben...
they could have asked me...
and I would have told them.
- Hi, kid.
- What in the hell's going on?
They called me in Washington to tell me
you'd broken into my apartment...
and beaten up my houseboy.
Yeah, well, see, Chunjin, when I...
My God, you look terrible.
I've never seen you look so awful.
Raymond...
I want to tell you that I've been
having this terrible nightmare.
I've been in the army 19 years.
First time I've ever seen
one of these.
I've been having this nightmare...
a real swinger
of a nightmare, too.
It has to do with
all kinds of strange people.
Is it about a Russian general
and some Chinese...
and me and the men
who were on the patrol?
How did you know that?
Take your hands off me.
Please, Raymond, tell me,
how did you know?
I don't really know
anything about it.
- But you just started to tell me...
- Do you remember Al Melvin?
- The corporal in the patrol?
- Yes, of course.
I had a letterfrom him
a couple of weeks ago.
Needless to say,
I was very surprised to hearfrom him.
You know how much
the guys in the outfit hated me.
Well, not as much as I hated them,
of course.
But anyway,
the funny thing was...
he said in his letterthat I was
the best friend he had in the army.
I was the best friend
he had in the army.
The poor, simple boob.
Anyway, he wanted to tell me
about his nightmare.
He said he was going out
of his mind.
Tell me what he said
about the nightmare.
He keeps dreaming that the patrol
is sitting in a hotel lobby...
and there are a lot of Chinese brass
and Russian generals...
Anyway, what's nightmarish
about that?
The letter?
Have you got the letter?
No, I don't.
I never keep letters.
That's all he wrote?
That was the end of it?
Why? Is it the same thing
you've been dreaming?
Do something for me, will you?
Call Eldorado 59970.
If a young lady answers...
tell her I've gone to Washington.
The town, not the general.
I'll be n touch wth her
as quckly as I can.
You'll do that, won't you?
Eldorado 59970.
To take some of the mystery out of it,
the photographs you're looking at...
are shots of male models,
Mexican circus performers...
Czech research chemists...
Japanese criminals...
French headwaiters...
Turkish wrestlers,
pastoral psychiatrists...
and, of course, various
officials of the USSR...
the People's Republic of China...
and the Soviet Army.
Hold the one on the right, please.
Hold this one, too.
Exactly one hour ago,
Mr. Alan Melvin, in Alaska...
made the same two photographs.
This one here wore sunglasses,
smelled like a goat.
His moustache was a little thinnerthen.
He had a loud voice, and it grated.
He's about 5-11,
on the heavy side.
Uniformed
as a lieutenant general.
His staff wore civilian clothes.
They looked a little like F.B.I. Men.
His name, incidentally, is Berezovo.
He's a member of
the Central Committee.
This one wore civilian clothes,
but his staff was uniformed...
varying from a full colonel
to a first lieutenant.
They wore political markings.
Lights.
I'm going to recommend setting up
a joint-intelligence, C.I.A. F.B.I. Unit...
based out of New York.
You'll work with them,
representing the army.
- Your assignment's Raymond Shaw.
- Very good, Colonel.
It should be a very pleasant
assignment, Major...
considering that Raymond Shaw
is the kindest, bravest...
warmest, most wonderful human being
you've ever met in your life.
My mother, Ben, is a terrible woman.
Aterrible, terrible woman.
Chunjin.
We would like some more wine.
Oh, I forgot.
Afteryou called,
I gave Chunjin the night off.
Because it was Christmas Eve,
I told him.
He was very reluctant to go.
That's probably because he's a Buddhist,
and he doesn't celebrate Christmas.
I don't think that Chunjin
is a Buddhist.
He smiles all the time.
What a shame.
I thought he was a Buddhist.
Otherwise I would have sent him
a Christmas card.
But I figured...
that if I sent him a card
at this time of the year...
then he would have to send me a card
on the Buddha's birthday.
- To save face, right?
- Right.
And that would have started
a whole big magilla.
Exactly.
You did exactly the right thing.
Twelve Days of Chrstmas.
One day of Christmas is loathsome enough.
What were we saying?
Oh, yes, my mother.
But you don't want to listen to me
talking about...
Of course I do.
I'm interested.
It's rather like listening to Orestes
gripe about Clytemnestra.
- Who?
- A couple of Greeks in a play.
You know, Ben...
it's a terrible thing
to hate your mother.
But I didn't always hate her.
When I was a child,
I only kind of disliked her.
But after what she did to
Jocie and me...
that's when I began to hate her.
Jocie?
Jocie Jordan.
Sen. Jordan's daughter.
That's pretty funny, isn't it?
Thomas Jordan's daughter...
and Johnny Iselin's stepson.
That's her.
Jocie.
- She's lovely.
- I always keep her picture.
Years later, I realized,
Ben, that...
I'm not very lovable.
No, don't contradict me.
I am not lovable.
Some people are lovable,
and other people are not lovable.
I am not lovable.
But I was very lovable
with Jocie.
You cannot believe
how lovable I was.
In a way.
Then, of course,
my motherfixed all that.
Ben, you don't blame me
for hating my mother, do you?
I'm not making excuses...
but I have been even less lovable...
than I was since.
It was the summer just before
I went into the army...
and I was bitten by this snake.
- Are you following me?
- I am.
While I was lying there,
absolutely helpless...
afraid to move, because
you're not supposed to move...
it makes the poison circulate...
when, unexpectedly,
there she was...
with a razorblade in her hand.
My daddy's going to be
so pleased about this.
I mean, he's absolutely scared about
snakes in this part of the country.
I know that sounds terribly Freudian,
but in this case, I don't think it is.
I think he's just simply and uncomplicatedly
afraid of snakes, period...
which is why I happen to be
riding around with a razorblade...
and a bottle of potassium
permanganate solution.
You don't happen to have
a handkerchief, do you?
No, of course, you don't.
I don't either.
I do have a Kleenex.
Seriously, Daddy is going to be
just thrilled about this.
All summer long,
he's been raving about snakes...
and nobody's even seen one,
and now this.
I promise you,
it may be uncomfortable foryou...
but it's going to absolutely
make his summer.
Now you just lie very still.
Don't move.
That's very important.
I'll be right back with the car
in a minute.
You're lucky,
young man, very lucky.
If I were to tell you the statistics
on death by snakebite every year...
But in this case, I think...
There's no swelling above or below.
Normal.
I must say, there's a good chance
you're going to live.
You are not, by any chance,
a mute, are you?
I want to thank you
very much, Miss...
- Jordan.
- Miss Jocelyn Jordan.
- How do you do?
- Hi.
And now, according to
the quaint local custom...
- it's yourturn to tell us what your name is.
- My name is Raymond Shaw, sir.
How do you do, Raymond?
Is your place near here?
Yes, it's that red house
just across the lake.
- The Iselin house?
- My house.
It was my father's.
My father's dead, he left it to me.
We were told that that was
the summer camp of Sen. Iselin.
Johnny stays there sometimes, sir.
When he gets too drunk for my mother
to allow him to be seen in Washington.
My dear, although we've done everything
that modern science recommends...
there's still the traditional folk remedy
against snakebite, which we haven't applied.
So, to be on the safe side...
- Mrs. Iselin is your mother?
- Yes, sir.
I once found it necessary
to sue your mother...
for defamation of character
and slander.
My name is Thomas Jordan.
Sen. Thomas Jordan.
The Communist?
One of your mother's
more endearing traits...
is hertendency to referto anyone
who disagrees with her about anything...
as a Communist.
The last time she so referred to me
on a network radio program...
it cost her $ 65,000
and court costs.
What hurt her more
than the money, I think...
was the fact that I donated it...
to an organization called
the American Civil Liberties Union.
- Sen. Jordan?
- Yes, Raymond.
I would very much like to ask
your permission to marry Jocelyn.
We were together every
minute afterthat.
You just cannot believe, Ben...
how lovable the whole
damn thing was.
All summer long, we were together.
I was lovable...
Jocie was lovable...
the Senator was lovable...
the days were lovable,
the nights were lovable...
and everybody was lovable.
Except, of course...
my mother.
What is it, Mother?
What sort of a greeting
is that at 3:30 a. M?
- It's 2:45 and what do you want?
- I want to talk to you, Raymond.
About what?
- About that Communist tart.
- Shut up with that.
Do you know what Jordan is?
Are you out to crucify me?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm going to bed.
Raymond, sit down.
How would you see her?
They live in New York.
I'm getting a job in New York.
- You have your army service.
- Next spring.
I might be dead by next spring.
Raymond, if we were at war...
and you suddenly became infatuated
with the daughter of a Russian agent...
wouldn't you expect me
to come to you and object...
and beg you to stop the entire thing
before it was too late?
Well, we are at war.
It's a cold war...
but it will get worse, until every
man, woman and child in this country...
will have to stand up
and be counted...
to say whetherthey are
on the side of right and freedom...
or on the side of
the Thomas Jordans of this country.
I will go with you to Washington,
tomorrow, if you like...
and I will show you proof
that this man stands for evil.
That he is evil.
And that his whole life is devoted to
undermining everything that you and I...
and Johnny
and every freedom-minded American...
She won, of course.
She always does.
I could never beat her.
I still can't.
I wrote a letter...
or she wrote it and I signed it,
I can't even remember which.
It was a terrible, vile,
disgusting letter.
The next day,
I enlisted in the army.
I never saw her again.
God knows, Ben...
I'm not lovable.
But I loved her.
I did love her.
I do love her.
Come on, kid.
Time foryou to call it a night.
So this lousy brother-in-law of mine,
I say to him...
'You think you're a poker player?
Well, I got a flash foryou.
You ain't no poker player.'
So I says to him
'My advice to you,
from the bottom of the heart...
don't play poker.
If I was you, I'd get myself
another line of action.
Why don't you pass the time
by playing a little solitaire? '
- So he says...
- Give me a deck of cards, please.
When I got married to my old lady,
I got no idea that this guy...
comes in the same package,
that it's a package deal.
For 11 long years,
I got this crumb tied around my neck.
- Believe me, it's no bargain.
- A beer, please.
Sorry I'm late, kid.
Got held up in traffic.
So I says to him,
'Do me a favor, will you?
'Why don't you go and take yourself
a cab and go up to Central Park...
'and go jump in the lake? '
Get out of there.
What are you doing?
Hi, Ben.
What the hell are you doing?
What's the matter with you?
I don't know.
I was next to you at the bar,
you were playing solitaire.
Then you bolted out of the bar,
took a cab to the park...
and jumped into the water.
I don't remember, Ben.
Ljust don't remember.
Wait a minute, I do.
I remember.
In the dream.
I remember what you were doing
with your hands.
You were... Of course.
Obviously, the solitaire game serves
as some kind of trigger mechanism.
Black 7 on the red 8.
I suggest we discard the various number
systems and concentrate on the face cards.
- Red 6 on the black 7.
- Thanks a lot.
Because of their symbolic
identification with human beings.
Based on Raymond's psychiatric pattern,
we can safely eliminate jacks and kings.
Black 6 on the red 7.
Why don't you try it for a while?
Human fish swimming at the bottom
of the ocean of atmosphere...
develop psychic injuries
as they collide with one another.
Most mortal of all...
are those gotten
from the parent fish.
Queen of Diamonds on the black king.
Hey, what are you doing?
- Cheating is a form of regression.
- I remember.
I remember.
I can see that Chinese cat
standing there smiling like Fu Manchu...
and saying, 'The Queen of Diamonds
is reminiscent in many ways...
'of Raymond's dearly loved
and hated mother... '
'and is the second key
to clearthe mechanism... '
'for any other assignment.'
'... our great republic, repeat, republic... '
'until the peril
of international Communism... '
'is driven from every dark corner
of this great nation.'
Give me a little chucky
underthe chin.
I can't tell you how worried
I am about Raymond.
- Raymond? What Raymond?
- Raymond Shaw. My son. Your stepson.
I've been thinking about him,
and you know what I've decided?
- What?
- I've decided it's time he got married.
May I ask what you find
so amusing?
Who could you possibly find
who would marry Raymond?
I have devoted considerable thought
to the problem.
It has occurred to me
that Tom Jordan's daughterJocelyn...
you remember her, hon...
that mousy little girl Raymond was so
attracted to that summer at the lake?
- That little 'Communist tart'?
- All right!
- I may have been hasty.
- A little in the hairline.
Anyway, times change. I now think
she would make Raymond an excellent wife.
She's been living in Paris
forthe past two years.
I have word she'll be
coming home soon.
When she does, I think we should
give a little party.
But, babe, I thought
that you and Sen. Jordan...
I keep telling you not to think.
You're very, very good
at a great many things...
but thinking, hon,
just simply isn't one of them.
You just keep shouting, 'Point of order,'
into the television cameras...
and I'll handle the rest.
- I think a June wedding would be nice.
- Bourbon, water.
Right before the convention.
I don't know why yours is
the only apartment in New York City...
without an air conditioner.
Sometimes I think you came to us
from another century.
Chu-chin-chow,
or whateveryour name is...
the steaks are to be broiled
for exactly 11 minutes...
no more, no less, on each side
in a preheated grill at 400 degrees.
Yes, ma'am.
Mother, may I ask a question?
Of course.
What are you doing here?
Why are we having our annual meeting?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
When I got your message,
announcing you were coming...
I naturally assumed
you wanted something.
Not at all. This is a purely
social event. However...
The 'however.'
As you may or may not have heard,
Johnny and I are giving an enormous party.
A costume ball, actually,
at the summer house on Long Island.
I wondered if you'd like to attend?
Have you gone out of your mind?
The reason I ask is because we're giving it
in honor of an old friend of yours...
and herfather.
What old friend?
Do you remember a darling girl we met
before you went into the army?
Jocelyn Jordan,
Sen. Jordan's daughter?
She's been living abroad
forthe last several years.
She arrived back in New York
a week or so ago.
And I thought...
considering the rather shabby way
you treated her...
it might be a rather gracious gesture
if I gave her a coming-home party.
Jocie and herfather...
coming to a party of yours?
Of course...
once I explained to her
you would be there.
It's all right,
it's Polish caviar.
Johnny, come over here, hon.
You stand in the middle.
- Thank you. See you later.
- You look marvelous.
- Where is she? Have they come?
- They'll be here any minute.
Are you sure they're coming, Mother?
Absolutely sure?
Raymond, don't be such a jerk.
Go and get yourself a drink
or a tranquilizer or something.
Raymond can certainly be a royal pain.
She's just kidding.
You look great. Just great!
What are you supposed to be,
one of those Dutch skaters?
Raymond, darling...
Why must you always look as if
your head's about to come to a point?
Now just be patient, and she'll be here.
I guarantee it.
Raymond, why don't we just sneak away
for a few minutes...
and sit down somewhere quietly
and have a drink?
Are you absolutely sure
she's coming, Mother?
I told you, she telephoned me
minutes ago from the hotel.
- Mother, how did she sound?
- Like a girl.
Why don't you pass the time
by playing a little solitaire?
Tom boy, so great you could come.
I am here at this fascist rally...
because my daughter has assured me...
that it was important to her happiness
that I come.
There is no other reason.
Good old Tom.
The time has come for us to have
a serious discussion.
We feel... What is it?
It's me, babe, Johnny.
Tom Jordan's here. I need you.
I'll be right out!
- Who's in there with you, anyway?
- Raymond!
Hurry it up, will you?
We've got work to do out here.
I'll take this one with me, dear.
It might be mischief if I leave it.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I've been watching you through the window.
When I saw you, my heart almost
shot out of my body.
I sent Daddy around the front way.
I had to see you alone.
Come on, lover.
Why don't you just take that somewhere
very quietly and drink it?
All right, dear, run along.
The grownups have to talk.
How good of you to come, Tom.
I have explained to your husband
why I am here.
I know you have strong personal
feelings about Johnny and I.
What I would like to find out is
how strong they really are.
To put it as simply as possible...
If Johnny's name were put forward
at the convention next week...
would you attempt to block him?
You're joking, of course.
Mr. Stevenson makes jokes. I do not.
You're seriously trying
forthe nomination forJohnny?
No. We couldn't make it.
But I think he has a good chance
forthe second spot.
I've answered your question,
but you haven't answered mine.
- What question?
- Will you block us?
Will I block you?
I would spend every cent I own
and all I could borrow to block you.
There are people who think of Johnny
as a clown and a buffoon.
But I do not.
I despise John Iselin...
and everything that Iselinism
has come to stand for.
I think if John Iselin
were a paid Soviet agent...
he could not do more to harm this country
than he is doing now.
You asked me a question...
very well,
I'll answeryou.
If you attempt to deal
with the delegates...
or cause Johnny's name
to be brought forward on the ticket...
or if in my canvass of the delegates
I find that you are acting...
I will bring impeachment proceedings
against your husband...
on the floor of the United
States Senate.
And I will hit him, I promise you...
with everything in my
well-documented book.
For $ 1 million, pick a card.
- Card tricks. If I had known that...
- Pick a card.
The Queen of Diamonds.
That's pretty good.
How did you do that?
This is what is known, my dear girl,
as a forced deck.
This deck of cards is often employed
by a professional magician...
to simplify his problem of guessing the card
picked by the little old lady in the third row.
Also employed by
Army Intelligence officers who...
Rosie, let's get married.
- We certainly are in good spirits. -Yes we are.
Tomorrow's the big day.
Lunch with Raymond...
then a nice little game
of solitaire...
and a nice long chat
about the good old days in Korea...
and some old Chinese
and Russian friends of ours.
Then a suggestion ortwo
to rip out all of the wiring...
and then, dear girl, it's over.
All over.
- What's the matter, don't you want to?
- Want to what?
Get married. Why don't you pay
attention to me when I speak to you?
Bennie, I want to marry you more than
I want to go on eating Italian food...
which will give you some idea.
Then why don't we get with it, kiddo?
You know, arranging forthe papers,
forthe blood test, posting the banns...
figure out what we're gonna name the kids,
renting the rice...
- buy the ring, call the folks.
- Folks?
You neither? Orphan?
I used to be convinced that I was the sole
survivor of a spaceship that overshot Mars.
Very sexy stuff. Very, very sexy.
- Ben!
- Hello, Raymond.
Ben, I want you to meet Jocie.
Remember, I told you about her?
This is my friend, Maj. Ben Marco.
- Miss Jordan.
- How do you do, Major?
Only, it's not Miss Jordan anymore.
It's Mrs. Shaw. Mrs. Raymond Shaw.
We flew to Maryland last night.
We got married. We Just got back.
Aren't you going to pop champagne,
or dance in the streets...
- or at least kiss the bride?
- Congratulations.
Ben, isn't she beautiful?
Am I not the luckiest guy
in the whole world?
You don't have to answerthat.
Anyway, I'm the one who's lucky.
Listen, darling, there must be
some beer or champagne...
or penicillin eye-drops
or some anchovies in the ice box.
Crack open whatever it is.
The three of us have got to have a drink.
Come on, bustle.
Make like a housewife.
I'll get out of this idiot suit.
Ben, you should've seen the judge's face.
There we were, the Queen of Diamonds
and me looking like, I don't know...
like Groucho Marx.
Groucho Marx?
Ben, ljust made a joke.
Not a very good joke,
I admit, but a joke.
Have you ever before
heard me make a joke?
Ljust made one.
Groucho Marx.
Big day! Mark that down in your book.
Raymond Shaw got married,
and he made a joke.
Groucho Marx.
'The Queen of Diamonds? '
What did he mean?
My costume. I came to this costume party
as the Queen of Diamonds.
I didn't know what to wear.
Then I saw this big playing card in a shop.
Mrs. Shaw.
Please, Major, Jocie.
You call me Jocie,
I'll call you Ben.
Mrs. Shaw, Jocie...
the reason I came here
this morning...
is to ask Raymond to voluntarily
put himself under arrest.
What?
Maybe not under arrest,
that's pretty strong, but...
to surrender himself
for some questioning.
Questioning?
What kind of questioning?
Raymond is sick, Mrs. Shaw,
in a kind of a special way.
- He doesn't even realize it himself.
- Sick? He's not sick.
He's the healthiest man I've seen
in my whole life.
- You can tell that by just looking at him.
- That's not the kind of sick I mean.
You're wrong, Ben.
He's tied up inside, in a thousand knots,
I know that.
But you can see foryourself
how he is with me.
We were married just six hours ago.
We've been in cars and offices
and airplanes ever since.
What are your plans?
There's an inn, The Bedford House,
near Bedford village...
it's about an hourfrom here.
There's hardly anyone there
this early in the season.
We've already wired for a room.
Ben, you've got to believe me and trust me,
I can make him well.
I'll give you 48 hours. Have him
back here day aftertomorrow.
I'll talk to him then.
Afterthat, we'll see.
Thank you, Ben.
Thank you, and God bless you.
Darling.
What?
Nothing.
Just darling.
My dear girl...
have you noticed the human race is divided
into two distinct and irreconcilable groups?
Those who walk into rooms
and automatically turn television sets on...
and those who walk into rooms
and automatically turn them off.
The problem is they usually
marry each other, which causes...
... elopement of Jocelyn Jordan,
daughter of Sen. Thomas Jordan...
and Korean war hero, Raymond Shaw,
stepson of Sen. John Iseln.
- It appears however...
- My Romeo.
... ths Montague-Capulet note
wll have lttle effect on the feud...
now ragng between
the two party leaders.
From hs campagn headquarters,
Sen. Iseln stepped up hs charges...
aganst the man
attemptng to block hs nomnaton.
I now charge ths man, Thomas Jordan...
wth hgh treason.
And I assure you,
the moment the Senate reconvenes...
I shall move for
ths man Jordan's mpeachment...
and after that a cvl tral.
Come on, get dressed.
We're driving down to New York.
Go straight to yourfather's house.
Convey my personal apologies to him.
I'll join you later.
What are you going to do?
Something I should have done
a long time ago.
I'm going to beat that vile, slandering,
son-of-a-numbskull to a bloody pulp!
Mother!
That vile, slandering husband of yours,
where is he?
Something very important has come up.
There is something you have to do.
Who is it?
It's me, sir.
Raymond, my boy.
Jocie waited up as long as she could.
She turned in about one hour.
She told me the good news.
I want to offer my congratulations
and welcome you to the family.
I've been watching my daughter's face
all evening.
- She's a very happy girl.
- Thank you, sir.
Come with me.
I'll force some good whiskey on you...
to celebrate your wedding,
soothe you after a trying day...
There's some whiskey in that cabinet
beside you. Help yourself.
I only hope you haven't been too much
upset by these idiotic attacks of Iselin's.
Actually, I take the position
that any attack by Iselin is a great honor.
Actually, I haven't had so much supporting
mail in the Senate in the last years.
I'm very glad to hearthat, sir.
What the hell is that in your hand?
It's a pistol, sir.
Is that a silencer?
Why are you carrying a pistol?
What...
Ben, what is it?
Raymond Shaw shot and killed his wife
early this morning.
- But it doesn't say...
- I know.
It wasn't Raymond that really did it.
In a way, it was me.
As you can well understand,
gentlemen...
my wife is prostrate overthe loss
of this dear and wonderful girl...
whom she loved as a daughter.
And your stepson, Senator,
where is he?
My son Raymond's in retreat...
praying for strength
and understanding...
to try and carry on somehow.
Ben, it's foryou.
Maj. Marco speaking.
How could anyone... Jocie.
How could t happen?
Where are you, Raymond?
I think maybe I'm going crazy.
I'm havng terrble dreams
lke you used to have and...
Where are you? We can't talk on
the telephone. Just tell me where you are.
I'm in a hotel room...
across from the Garden.
Eghth Avenue sde.
Room 4.
All right. Listen to me. Wait there.
I'll be there in 10 minutes.
Don't move, just wait right there.
Okay, I'll take him now.
Everything's got to move quite normally.
I want him to feel like he's safe.
Just give me a pack of cards.
They just handed the vice-presidential
nomination to that idiot Iselin.
Hi, kid.
Who killed Jocie, Ben?
Tell me, I've got to know.
How about passing the time
by playing a little solitaire?
Now let's start unlocking a few doors.
Let's begin with the patrol.
You didn't save our lives ortake out
an enemy company or anything like that...
did you, Raymond?
What happened?
The patrol was taken
by a Russian airborne unit...
and flown by helicopter...
across the Manchurian border
to a place called Tunghwa.
We were worked on forthree days...
by a team of specialists
from the Pavlov Institute in Moscow.
They've developed a technique
for descent into the unconscious mind...
- part light-induced and part drug.
- Never mind all that now.
Tell me what else happened at Tunghwa.
We were drilled forthree days.
We were made to memorize
the details of the imaginary action.
What else?
And I strangled Ed Mavole...
and shot Bobby Lembeck.
One red queen works pretty good.
Let's see what we get with two of them.
Keep playing.
Then I killed Mr. Gaines.
It was just a test.
It didn't matter who I killed.
They picked him to see
if the linkages worked...
before they turned me over
to my American operator.
And that business
about jumping in the lake...
it really did happen.
It was an accident.
Something somebody said in the bar
accidentally triggered it.
Keep playing.
Then I killed Sen. Jordan.
And afterthat...
You are to forget everything that
happened at the Senator's house.
Do you understand? You'll only
remember it when I tell you so.
Now, Raymond, now the big one.
Why is all of this being done?
What have they built you to do?
I don't know.
I don't think anybody really
knows except...
Berezovo in Moscow...
and my American operator here.
Whatever it is,
it's supposed to happen soon...
right at the convention.
Maybe...
I don't know.
They can make me do anything, Ben...
can't they?
Anything.
We'll see, kid.
We'll see what they can do,
and we'll see what we can do.
So the red queen is our baby.
Take a look at this, kid.
Fifty-two of them.
Take a good look at them, Raymond.
And while you're looking, listen.
This is me, Marco, talking.
Fifty-two red queens and me are telling you.
You know what we're telling you?
It's over.
The links, their beautifully conditioned
links are smashed.
They're smashed as of now,
because we say so.
We're busting up the joint,
we're tearing out all the wires.
All the queen's horses
and queen's men...
will never put old Raymond
back together again.
You don't work anymore.
That's an order.
Anybody invites you to
a game of solitaire...
you tell them, 'Sorry, buster,
the ballgame is over.'
It's time for my American operator
to give me the plan.
Yes? Yes, I understand, Mother.
She wants me to go.
There's a car waiting
for me downstairs.
The convention reconvenes at 9:00 p.m.
Forthe acceptance speeches.
I don't think anything
will happen until then.
- I'd better go now.
- Here is a number.
I've got 500 people at my disposal,
a thousand if I need them.
You call me at that number.
Try to call me by...
or as soon as you find out
whatever it is they want you to do.
Remember, Raymond,
the wires have been pulled.
They can't touch you anymore.
You're free.
It's been decided that you will be
dressed as a priest...
to help you get away
in the pandemonium afterwards.
Chunjin will give you a two-piece
Soviet Army sniper's rifle...
that fits nicely into a special bag.
There's a spotlight booth
that won't be in use.
It's up underthe roof on the Eighth Avenue
side of the Garden.
You will have absolutely clear,
protected shooting.
You are to shoot the presidential
nominee through the head...
and Johnny will rise gallantly
to his feet...
and lift Ben Arthur's body
in his arms...
and stand in front of the microphones
and begin to speak.
The speech is short...
but it's the most rousing speech
I've ever read.
It's been worked on here and in Russia,
on and off, for over eight years.
I shall force someone
to take the body away from him.
Then Johnny will really hit those
microphones and those cameras...
with blood all over him...
fighting off anyone who tries
to help him...
defending America,
even if it means his own death.
Rallying a nation of television viewers
into hysteria...
to sweep us up into the White House...
with powers that will make martial law
seem like anarchy.
Now this is very important...
I want the nominee to be dead...
about two minutes after
he begins his acceptance speech...
depending on his reading time
under pressure.
You are to hit him right at the point
that he finishes the phrase
'Nor would I ask of any fellow
American... '
'in defense of his freedom... '
'that which I would not
gladly give myself.'
'My life before my liberty.'
Is that absolutely clear?
Would you repeat it for me, Raymond?
'Nor would I ask of any fellow American... '
'in defense of his freedom... '
'that which I would not
gladly give... '
'myself.'
'My life before my liberty.'
I know you will never entirely
comprehend this, Raymond...
but you must believe
I did not know it would be you.
I served them.
I fought forthem.
I'm on the point of
inning forthem...
the greatest foothold
they will ever have in this country.
And they paid me back
by taking your soul away from you.
I told them to build me
n assassin.
I wanted a killerfrom a world
filled with killers, and they chose you...
because they thought it would bind me
closerto them.
But now we have come
almost to the end.
One last step...
and when I take powerthey will be
pulled down and ground into dirt...
for what they did to you...
and what they did in so contemptuously
underestimating me.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
We need the lights. Lights.
Lights out.
Why hasn't he called?
It was a calculated risk, Ben.
You were right to take it.
Even if it's not true,
it's nice of you to say it.
- The Garden's filling up.
- Take it easy.
- 8:44 a.m.
- I know.
If Steinkamp doesn't take off
that stupid hat...
and stop messing around with
those broads, I'll bust him into a PFC.
Easy, Ben.
Okay, Milt, I blew it!
My magic is betterthan your magic.
I should've known better.
Intelligence Officer.
Stupidity Officer is better.
If the Pentagon wants to open up
a stupidity division...
they know who they can get
to lead it.
Raymond was theirs, he is theirs,
and he'll always be theirs.
There's time.
He may still call.
For money?
That's what I figured.
- Let's get the hell out of here.
- All right, Ben, let's go.
You've got to stop this thing.
How can I stop it?
On what evidence?
If there was a bomb here,
oryou got a tip there was, you'd stop it.
You'd empty the White House,
if you had to.
I say there's a time bomb here,
just waiting to go off.
Lades and gentlemen,
our natonal anthem.
Raymond has never missed
with a rifle in his life.
We're in like Flynn, lover.
- Lades and gentlemen...
- Just take it easy.
... I gve you the next
Presdent of the Unted States
Mr. Charman...
delegates, my fellow Amercans...
t s wth great humlty...
albet wth enormous prde...
and wth a sense of the job to be done...
that I most humbly and most gratefully...
accept ths nomnaton
for the hghest offce n our land.
It s wth a full awareness...
that the four years
that le ahead for ths countrt...
are, n a sense, the crucal years...
the years, f I may borrow
Mr. Churchll's phrase...
'the years of decson.'
And, f I may be permtted
a phrase of my own...
the years of strvng.
For t s not what has been done...
n the past...
nor what may be done
aganst the far horzons...
of some dstant future...
but what wll be done now.
Nor would I ask
of any fellow Amercan...
n defense of hs freedom...
that whch I would not gladly gve myself.
My lfe before my lberty.
You couldn't have stopped them, the army
couldn't have stopped them, so I had to.
That's why I didn't call.
Poorfriendless,
friendless Raymond.
He was wearing his medal
when he died.
You should read
some of the citations sometime.
Just read them.
'Taken, eight prisoners,
killing four enemy in the process... '
'while one leg and one arm
were shattered.'
'He could only crawl, because
the other leg had been blown off.'
'Edwards.'
'Wounded five times.'
'Dragged himself across the direct fire
of three enemy machine guns... '
'to pull two of his 71 wounded men
to safety amid dead... '
'and 23 casualties.
'Made to commit acts...
'too unspeakable to be cited here...
'by an enemy who had captured
his mind and his soul.
'He freed himself at last...
'and in the end...
'heroically and unhesitatingly
gave his life...
'to save his country.
'Raymond Shaw.'
Hell!
Ripped from DVD by: IronMan_br