TOHO CO., LTD.
A TOHO-KUROSAWA PRODUCTION
YOJIMBO
Produced by TOMO YUKI TANAKA
and RYUZO KIKUSHIMA
Screenplay by RYUZO KIKUSHIMA
and AKIRA KUROSAWA
Cinematography by
KAZUO MIYAGAWA
Production Design by
YOSHIRO MURAKI
Music by
MASARU SATO
Assistant Director SHIRO MORITANI
Production Manager HIROSHI NEZU
Starring
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
TATSUYA NAKADAI
YOKO TSUKASA, ISUZU YAMADA
DAISUKE KATO, SEIZABURO KAWAZU
TAKASHI SHIMURA
HIROSHI TACHIKAWA
YOSUKE NATSUKI
EIJIRO TONO, KAMATARI FUJIWARA
IKIO SAWAMURA
ATSUSHI WATANABE
SUSUMU FUJITA, KYU SAZANKA
KO NISHIMURA
TAKESHI KATO, AKIRA TANI
TSUNAGORO RASHOMON
YOSHIO TSUCHIYA
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
Stop, you brat!
Let me go, Father!
This battle
is the chance of a lifetime!
Crazy fool!
The chance to get killed!
Why do you want
to be a gambler?
A farmer's place
is in the fields.
A long life eating gruel -
to hell with that!
I want good food
and nice clothes.
I'm gonna live it up
and die young!
Old man.
I'd like some water.
Why the hell didn't you stop him?
How could I?
Kids these days are all mad.
It's not just the kids.
Everyone wants easy money.
It's all thanks to gambling.
A roll of the dice and you're rich.
Can't tell whose money
is whose anymore.
Have you heard
the sake brewer's trading silk now?
Says he'll pay more
than the silk merchant.
Yes, but...
what difference does it make...
with the town the way it is?
We don't even know
when the next silk fair will open.
Hungry dogs come running
when they smell blood.
Let 'em rip each other apart
and dye the silk in their blood.
Then they can have
their stinkin' fair!
SILK MERCHANT
Samurai, wanna make
some dough as a bodyguard?
The going rate has hit the roof.
My commission's one ryo.
Which side will you take?
Seibei Manome runs a brothel.
All the women you want.
But he's going downhill.
I'd bet on Ushitora Shinden.
Look.
The inn at the corner.
That's his place.
Tell him Constable Hansuke
sent you.
I'd take you myself,
but I'm the law around here.
Don't forget, now.
I get one ryo.
Go ahead.
It's a public road.
Even dogs pass freely!
You won't get hired like that.
You gotta act big,
show 'em who's boss.
They only look tough.
Chop off one of their arms
and they'll behave.
Then you'll get hired.
Mind your own business,
you bastard!
Come in.
RESTAURANT
- Sake?
- Food.
There's no business these days,
so I don't have anything.
Even the rice is cold.
I don't mind.
Actually, old man -
I know.
You can't pay.
I'll bust some heads first.
No!
I've seen enough fighting!
The food's on me,
but then get the hell out of town!
Thanks.
There he goes again!
The casket maker.
Only guy in town
making any money.
Can't make coffins fast enough.
It's best not to have
any gamblers at all.
One boss to a town
we can tolerate,
but two is a disaster.
Only the casket maker
profits from that.
Knock it off, you bastard!
Gamblers are
so cold-blooded and greedy,
you wouldn't think
they'd have paternal feelings.
But all this trouble started
when Seibei decided
to give all his territory
to his son.
His right-hand man
wouldn't stand for it.
Ushitora's his name, a real -
Strange name.
His ma began labor
in the year of the cow, Ushi,
but he bounced out
in the new year of the tiger, Tora.
Talk about ringing in
the New Year with a plague.
He left Seibei to start a rival gang,
taking half of Seibei's men with him.
Only swords can settle things now.
They're both fuming, rounding up
drifters and criminals for their gangs.
Instead of buying silk,
they're buying thugs.
How's business, casket man?
How many coffins did you sell
while I was away last night?
Two to your side.
What?
And four to the other side.
Not too bad.
Ushitora's brother, Inokichi.
A wild boar, befitting his name.
He's a half-wit,
but dangerous when mad.
He's returned
with three new recruits.
What a disgrace!
That's our constable.
He's supposed to arrest the riffraff,
but just look at him.
He's not the only one, though.
Have a look.
An imposing facade, but the owner
Tazaemon is worthless.
He's our cowardly mayor,
a silk merchant by trade.
He'd managed to survive
by siding with Seibei,
but when Ushitora rebelled...
Tokuemon, the sake brewer,
sided with Ushitora.
Tokuemon says
he's the new mayor,
and he even started selling silk.
Tazaemon is finished.
He bangs his prayer drum all day,
hoping for Seibei's victory.
Hear that?
Damn them all!
This town is doomed.
Now do you see?
You'll gain nothing
by getting sucked into this evil.
Eat quickly and leave.
I've had enough rice.
Give me some sake.
I like it here.
I'll stay awhile.
Why?
Don't you get it yet?
Yes, I do.
That's why I'm staying.
Listen, old man.
I'll get paid for killing.
And this town is full of men
who deserve to die.
Think about it.
Seibei, Ushitora,
the gamblers and drifters -
with them gone,
the town could have a fresh start.
You're nuts!
Not if you had nine lives!
I won't do it alone.
How then?
Sake.
I'll think while I drink.
Everyone in this town is crazy!
But you're even crazier!
I want to talk to Seibei.
Who the hell are you?
Wanna hire me?
I'll be your bodyguard.
I'll show you what I'm worth.
The two-bit samurai again?
What do you want this time?
- You guys have such cute faces.
- What?
You talk tough but couldn't hurt a fly.
Adorable.
Don't take us for fools.
See this tattoo?
I wasn't in prison for nothing!
I'm a wanted fugitive.
They'll crucify me if I'm caught.
Same here.
They'll stick my head on a pike.
Not to brag, but I've committed
every crime in the book.
So you won't mind
if I kill you?
- What?
- Kill us if you can!
It'll hurt.
We're gamblers.
We ain't afraid of the sword.
There's no cure for fools.
What?
Casket maker. Two coffins.
No, better make that three.
All right, make me an offer.
What'll you pay me
to finish them off?
How about three ryo?
I'm going to Ushitora.
I bet he'll pay more.
Four then!
Five!
Six!
Add a zero to the end.
Ten! I'll pay you ten!
Twenty!
Twenty-five!
Thirty!
All right!
Fifty!
Very well.
Twenty-five in advance,
with room and board.
My men wish
to welcome you.
But first, a drink.
We gotta talk.
Stupid wench has no manners.
You're mad to pay 25 in advance
to a complete stranger.
What if he runs off in the night?
Leave it to me.
He won't have time.
I plan to attack today.
Ushitora's men must be terrified
after he killed three of their gang.
We'll win for sure
with him leading us.
I see.
But then we'll have
to pay him 25 more.
What if we kill him afterwards?
We'd get the whole 50 back.
- That's going too far!
- Quiet!
If you can't even do that,
forget about being the heir.
Honor means nothing
to gamblers.
Your mother's right.
You can't build a fortune unless
you're known as a killer and a thief.
You kill that two-bit samurai.
Treat him nice and he'll let down
his guard. It'll be easy.
The men won't respect you
unless you show you can kill.
But I killed
one of Ushitora's men!
One man!
Don't flatter yourself!
Some son you are.
What are you so afraid of?
Whether you kill one or one hundred,
you only hang once!
Twenty-five ryo exactly.
Master, let's drink
and get acquainted.
My son, Yoichiro.
My wife, Orin.
My four strongest men:
Magotaro, Yahachi,
Matsukichi and Sukeju.
Where's Master Homma?
By the way,
may I ask your name?
Me?
Sanjuro Kuwabatake...
(30-year-old Mulberry Field)
But I'm almost 40.
You must be joking!
As names go,
it's good enough.
I'm a complete stranger, anyway.
Master, why sit over there?
Come sit here.
Here will do.
He gets 50 ryo, and I only get two.
He's in a different class.
Someday I'll show you
my true worth.
Maybe sooner than you think.
How about today?
We raid today at noon!
In plain daylight, boss?
We haven't won until we kill
Ushitora and Inokichi.
They could run away at night.
Don't be afraid!
With Homma and this master leading us,
we're stronger than ever.
Twelve o'clock noon!
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
You're not gonna sneak away
that easily! Get in there!
We paid a lot for you!
Get in!
Master, please come!
Master, please hurry!
Ushitora's men have come out!
All right, follow the master!
You wanna fight?
Do it yourself.
I'm not interested.
Sorry, missus,
but I don't intend
to be killed after your victory.
Here's your 25 ryo.
Son of a bitch!
Chickening out at the last minute!
Where's Homma?
Find him!
- He ran away in broad daylight.
Which one of you is Ushitora?
I am.
What do you want?
Seibei has offended me.
I've cut my ties with him.
That's all.
Why, you -
Watch out!
This fight's gonna be bad!
It's gonna be bad!
What're you waiting for?
You can't back down now!
All right!
An inspector from Edo is coming!
You got lucky this time,
you swine.
You're the lucky one!
Your head is mine when he leaves!
All you fugitives hurry up and hide!
The same goes for all of you!
Tell everyone
to open their doors!
All's quiet around here, got it?
Not even the dogs are fighting.
Open up!
Open shop!
Act as if everything's normal!
Got that?
Old man...
that inspector's a nobody,
but he sure has a swank palanquin.
What's so funny?
His men are drinking tea.
So?
Take a look.
Spiked tea.
Don't be so angry.
If I could've had them
massacre each other,
it would've spared me
a big housecleaning.
Too bad they were interrupted.
- Get out!
You're out of your mind!
You think so?
It's obvious. You think they'll
just overlook what you did?
Ushitora and Seibei
won't stand quietly by.
Sure, they'll come
talk to me eventually.
Question is, who'll show up
with a pile of money first?
All they care about is winning,
so they both want me.
Just wait and see.
Hey, is that your nitwit mayor?
Is that Tokuemon?
Now it makes sense.
No wonder the inspector
has such a nice palanquin.
By the way,
I'd like a drink too.
You've got nerve!
You're stone broke!
You want something?
You're tough.
I like you.
Aren't you angry
I killed three of your men?
They were worthless.
I'm Ushitora's brother -
- Inokichi.
- You know me?
I hear you're strong.
Not that strong.
Master!
Don't be a stranger.
Have a drink with us.
Or are you still angry?
- I should ask that of you.
- Don't be mean.
You took my joking
too seriously, silly man.
Come on, let's go.
No, you don't.
We were gonna have a drink.
Right? Start the sake flowing!
Make it your best.
It's on me.
Never!
My brother'd beat me to a pulp!
And I'd be kicked out of the house!
- Bitch!
- Yeah, what?
Hey, casket maker.
Drowning your sorrows?
The inspector's long visit
must have killed your business.
You've stayed ten days
already yourself.
Don't be like that.
Your shop has flourished
because of me.
Shut up!
This isn't a brothel.
If you want a place to stay,
go to Seibei's.
Bad idea.
Both sides are fighting for me.
I'll stay here
and let them keep hoping.
Everyone but him out.
Come to my place. Now.
What's the rush?
The inspector's leaving tomorrow.
A magistrate was killed
in a town 24 miles from here.
He doesn't seem too concerned.
He won't learn of it until tonight.
You seem to know everything.
Was the magistrate's murder
your doing?
Possibly.
The inspector's presence
is costing me a lot.
So are my hired men.
I see.
Speaking of which,
here's 30 in advance.
Thirty more if we win.
Come right away.
I'd feel bad not giving Seibei
a chance to better your offer.
Ready to exploit any weakness,
aren't you?
Tough luck.
I'll decide my price
after the inspector leaves.
Cheer up.
The inspector's leaving.
Really?
Fantastic!
What did Ushitora want?
Son of a bitch!
The slaughter's gonna start again?
Looks like it.
What's taking them so long?
It's about time one of them
made me an offer.
Some samurai.
All you talk about is money.
This is dangerous and dirty work.
It's only worth it
if the price is right.
You'd only be a bodyguard.
With some bodyguards,
the employers
have to watch their backs.
What's that fool up to?
He's been running back and forth all day.
Gonji, a bottle of sake.
Forget it. I'm not gonna
let you celebrate the butchery!
I'm not! I'm miserable!
They're making peace.
They are?
And I bought
a lot of lumber for coffins.
What do I do now?
I'm sorry for you guys,
but now the town will quiet down.
You idiot!
Gamblers only make peace
to prepare for a bigger fight.
They can't have the silk fair
if they're fighting.
No silk fair means
no gambling rooms
and no income from their territory,
so they make up for a while.
A truce is merely the seed
for an even bloodier battle.
You got that?
There's nothing more dangerous.
Still, they were so determined
to destroy each other.
How'd they manage
to calm down?
I think Unosuke suggested it.
Unosuke?
Ushitora's youngest brother.
He returned last night from his travels.
Evil bastard came back, did he?
He looks as gentle
as the zodiac Rabbit he's named after,
but he's a wolf inside.
A whole year you've been gone.
Even the winds welcome you!
Want to see
something interesting?
What's going on?
Same thing at your place?
Makin' fools of us!
They end their feud, then send us away
with crumbs in our pockets!
Sons of bitches!
We'll show 'em!
Bastards!
What are they moaning about?
Ushitora made us
risk our lives,
and that was just yesterday!
Hachi, quiet!
I'll tell ya, Kuma,
I can't take it anymore!
Let's go report it to the law.
Then that Ushitora's gonna -
That hurt!
Get up!
Let's go!
Why'd you do that?
- Come on!
- No!
Ushitora's a real bastard.
Where the hell
did you come from?
What'd he pay you to kill
that magistrate? One ryo?
Don't we wish!
Just two silver pieces.
That's a raw deal.
But the information
will come in handy.
You're a gold mine.
Now I can blackmail Ushitora,
or even sell you to Seibei.
Get up.
Get up!
It's a bargain.
If you take them and report it,
Ushitora's done for.
But boss,
what about our truce?
Your son and Unosuke are negotiating
at the mayor's place now.
So what?
It'd be perfect if Ushitora
got arrested during the talks.
Ready, ladies?
Haven't had a woman in a while,
have you?
Take your pick and have fun.
It's dangerous around here.
Wait!
Take care of your purchase.
It would be a total loss
if Ushitora got them back.
Lock them up
in the storehouse.
Get me Ushitora.
Who the hell -
Get me Ushitora!
Boss!
What is it?
So it's you, is it?
I don't need a bodyguard
at the moment.
Too bad you turned down
my earlier offer.
Hachi talks too much.
If you're too cheap,
you pay more in the long run.
Two silver pieces -
what an insult.
He and Kuma got drunk
and blurted out everything.
Those bastards!
Where the hell are they?
One of Seibei's men overheard them
and captured them.
I followed. They're locked up
in Seibei's storehouse.
Sons of bitches!
You don't get
information like this for free.
Take as much as you want.
You're my bodyguard
from now on.
This is enough for now.
I'll consider the bodyguard part.
Uno, you don't know him, do you?
This guy's tough as hell.
Ino! Uno! What are you doing?
Get in here now!
What is it?
Don't kill Yoichiro!
Get his sword
and take him to Brother!
Get going!
Seibei!
We have Yoichiro!
Did you hear me?
Listen carefully,
and don't try anything funny.
If you want him back,
bring us Kuma and Hachi!
We'll trade!
Each side will send
three unarmed men
to the guard tower at 2:00 a.m.!
Got that?
- Pretty good.
- It'll get better. Just watch.
Don't forget
to call the hour at 2:00!
Old man,
give me something to eat.
Take what you want
from the pot.
I won't get any business
with all this trouble brewing.
You know, old man,
this town is starting to boil again,
just like this pot.
What have you done?
Did you write
this new little drama?
Half of it.
Unosuke just rewrote
the other half.
It's 2:00 a.m.!
Ready, Ushitora?
We're coming, Seibei!
I'll push them forward,
and you let go of your rope.
Seibei!
That was a dirty trick.
We're even now.
If you love Yoichiro,
shave your head and ask
my brother to take over as heir.
Just as I thought!
Uno, look here!
Hey, Ushitora,
you see this?
I'll be keeping her!
Ask the horny old sake brewer
what he says to that!
That was amusing.
Mommy!
Where's my mommy?
I'll show you.
Don't you want to look?
I can't see her!
You will soon.
Mommy!
Kenbo!
Nui!
Hansuke, hurry up!
Mommy!
Coward! Why didn't you
bite your tongue off and die?
You caused us so much trouble!
Ungrateful bastard!
Hurry up!
Come on!
Seibei!
You'll be hearing from me!
I can't wait!
I've got a few things planned myself!
Don't come any closer.
He cried himself to sleep.
Poor fellow.
His wife was too beautiful.
It all started when he lost
to Ushitora at gambling.
If she were ugly,
he'd only have lost his house.
But old Tokuemon
was drooling all over her.
Ushitora saw a chance
to draw Tokuemon to his side.
He took the wife and house
and dangled them in front of Tokuemon.
This poor fool built a hut
right next to his former house
just so he could watch helplessly
as Tokuemon ravishes his wife every day.
I don't want her anymore!
I gave her up for good!
Then why the heartbroken look?
Going home?
Won't you get beaten up?
Weren't you told not to see her?
I'm used to it.
I don't mind.
Ushitora has his men
watching over her.
She can't even see her son.
Good-bye.
Guys like that make me sick!
I've decided
to be your bodyguard.
You have my gratitude.
I want 30 in advance.
That's a steep price.
I'd refuse if I were you.
But he's so tough!
Tougher than this?
Don't say that, Uno.
If I refuse, he'll go to Seibei.
That would be bad!
Buy him then.
Here. Thirty ryo.
Thirty more when we win.
Of course.
You have my word.
If that's settled, let's drink to it.
To our partnership!
Fine, but is the woman safe?
What woman?
Tokuemon's woman.
If they get her again,
you'll lose for sure.
Don't worry.
I've got six roughnecks on watch.
That's not enough.
You need at least one
as tough as this guy.
Brother, should I go?
I'll go along
and see how they're doing.
Thanks.
It ain't a fun job.
You gotta stand in the cold
when Tokuemon comes around.
He doesn't seem
to be here now.
Is that where the jackass
who lost his wife lives?
I almost forgot!
I gotta beat him up!
Hey, you!
Hanging around
Tokuemon's woman, huh?
How many times
we gotta tell you not to see her?
Ino, there's trouble!
Everyone's dead!
All six men have been killed!
Tell Ushitora, quick!
Who's there?
Get your husband and run!
Idiot!
Mommy!
Nui!
Run for it!
Here's 30 ryo.
I stole it from Ushitora.
Take it.
You idiots!
What are you waiting for?
Stop that!
I hate pathetic weaklings!
Start crying and I'll kill you!
Ushitora's coming!
Get lost!
We'll thank you later.
Idiot! Don't ever come back here!
Thank you.
- What happened?
- Take a look.
What a mess.
Didn't I tell you?
Six men weren't enough.
Must have been
15 or 16 men.
Where's the wench?
Gone, of course.
Seibei's pretty clever.
Brother!
Son of a bitch!
My silk's burning!
Please put out the fire!
I'll give you anything!
Don't move!
Hand over the wench
and we'll save the shop!
What wench?
Don't play dumb!
Give her back or else!
- What are you talking about?
- Shut up!
My sake's pouring out!
Do something!
Stop up the holes!
I'll give you anything!
Help!
This is Seibei's doing!
Come with me, men!
What happened?
Why so glum?
Your business should be booming.
No.
When the fighting gets this bad,
they don't bother with coffins.
Another bottle.
Comin' right up.
You're unusually friendly today.
What's going on?
Gives me the creeps.
Aren't you angry that I became
Ushitora's bodyguard?
Not at all.
You're not a bad guy
after all.
What?
You're not really bad.
You just pretend to be.
He came by last night.
Who?
The man who makes you sick.
He told me everything.
Oh, and another thing.
He said to give you this.
Aren't you going to read it?
Sure, it's just a long,
tedious thank-you note.
But read it.
He risked his life to bring it.
Shut up!
I'm busy drinking!
We need to talk.
About what?
Ino just got back
from a recruiting expedition.
- Get any men?
- No.
No wonder.
None of your former hires
are exactly singing your praises.
But Ino heard an interesting story
from one man.
He saw Tokuemon's woman crossing
the ridge with her husband and little brat.
That was the morning
after our six men were killed.
Which means that
Seibei didn't kidnap her.
It would seem that way.
Then who killed our men?
Ino, before you came running
to tell Brother,
did you see those men dead
with your own eyes?
No. He told me -
By the way, those six
were sliced up real good.
You're the only one around here
that skilled with a sword.
So?
It occurred to me...
that maybe you killed them.
But Uno, he's our bodyguard.
Why would he do that?
That's what I don't get either.
Hold it.
What's this?
"To the honorable samurai
from Kohei and Nui."
You sure it's okay
to leave him untied?
Sure. He's nothing
without his sword.
Where am I?
This is the brewery.
This is the gate to hell.
Watch it!
A pat from you is like
a beating from a normal man.
You want another thrashing?
Where are you going?
That's the shortcut to hell.
You're not supposed to kill him.
Don't worry.
He's still groaning.
Do you know who I am?
Then listen.
Master Tokuemon
wants to talk to you personally.
You must know
where the woman is.
You can't trust him.
He's out to save his own skin.
The master's talking.
You keep quiet.
I dislike long-winded talk.
The quicker we settle this,
the better.
Tell me where the woman is.
In return, I'll let you live.
What's the matter?
It's a generous offer.
You're not going to refuse,
are you?
I won't talk!
What?
- Wait! Don't kill him!
- Don't worry.
Kannuki, teach him a lesson.
How about it?
You gonna talk?
Hell no, you half-wit!
Don't kill him.
Don't get blood
on that storage chest.
Thanks to him,
we have to sleep here now.
I'm gonna beat him up again.
He's getting on my nerves.
Huh? I could've sworn
I locked this door.
The bastard's gone.
What?
Don't scare me like that!
Brother, this isn't funny!
Morons!
No point looking where it's light!
Search where it's dark!
Old man, open up!
It's me.
I know I'm quite a sight,
but could you do your staring later?
Didn't I warn you?
You're too damn reckless.
Save your lecture!
They'll be here soon!
Tell them I went to Seibei's place.
Got that?
Did that two-bit samurai come here?
Lie and you'll be sorry!
Yes, but he went
to Seibei's place.
Don't believe the old fool.
He and Two-Bit are in cahoots.
But Seibei would gladly hide him
to find out where the slut is.
That guy's really something.
He wouldn't stay put
with his head cut off.
Fine. We'll kill
Seibei's entire gang.
I only held back
because of the woman.
Gather some straw
and smoke them out.
Smoke 'em out like raccoons
and kill 'em? Fun!
Pull yourself together.
But what'll you do now?
Go next door
and buy a coffin.
How can you give up like that?
You idiot!
I'm not dying yet.
There's a bunch of guys
I have to kill first.
Is this safe?
What if Ushitora's men check?
They don't have time.
Take a look.
What's Ushitora doing?
Smoking out Seibei
and his men.
Sounds interesting.
Set me down. I wanna watch.
That's crazy!
Set me down!
I can't see from here.
Move further out.
Uno, it's me! Don't shoot!
Idiot!
Don't leave your post!
Kannuki's guarding the back.
Listen, I killed those two guys
who killed three of ours.
You came out to tell me that?
Get back in there!
You won't get away,
you wench!
Come here, you greedy bitch!
Where are Seibei and Yoichiro?
- I don't know!
- Tell us or we'll kill you!
Mommy!
Seibei, come out!
Yoichiro's begging for mercy!
Seibei!
You win! I'm coming out!
Don't kill me or my son!
All right!
All my territory is yours!
You can take over!
You filthy scum!
Only the samurai is left.
Where is he?
- There's nobody in there.
- That can't be.
- See for yourself.
- He can't just vanish.
He's all beaten up.
He can't go far.
Old man, let's get going.
Son of a bitch!
The casket maker ran away!
That's not good.
Anyone else around?
It gets worse.
Inokichi's coming this way!
We have no choice.
Talk him into helping you.
- But -
- Just try it!
- Just in case.
- Thanks.
Hey, whaddaya doin'?
The casket maker and I
were gonna bury this body,
but the bastard got scared
and ran off.
Would you give me a hand?
Are you kidding?
Hell, no!
- Afraid of a dead man?
- What did you say?
You talk big, but fear's
written all over your face.
What?
I'm not afraid of nothin'!
Then hurry up and help.
Couldn't be easier.
You sure? We're going to the cemetery.
I saw ghosts there a while back.
Ghosts?
Hell, I see ghosts
and I feel relieved!
Good. Let's go then.
- Is this far enough?
- Yes, thanks.
Where are the ghosts?
They only appear
to scaredy-cats like me,
not to brave guys like you.
I'd feel bad leaving you here alone.
I'll help you bury him.
That's all right.
Weren't you looking for someone?
You're right!
Brother's gonna beat me!
Are you all right?
That was all very amusing.
Can you walk?
There's a small temple nearby.
I can walk.
You don't look like
one of the living.
I'll come back to life
with a few days' sleep.
It's even worse
when you smile.
You're late, old man.
I'm hungry.
It's me!
Gonji's in trouble!
What happened?
He got caught
on the way here.
The rice and ointment for you
gave him away.
Where'd they take him?
Seibei's place.
Ushitora has moved in there.
You plan to fight with that?
- I'll make sashimi outta them!
- Wait.
Use this. Being a coffin maker
has its advantages.
It's wrong to use a dead man's sword,
but it's the best I had.
Get away while he's fighting
Ushitora and his men.
You told him I got caught?
You stupid meddler!
Hurry!
Don't come any closer!
Mommy!
Children shouldn't play
with swords.
Go home to your mother
and live a long life eating gruel.
You're a nice guy.
I've got a favor to ask.
What?
Without my pistol...
I feel sort of naked.
I can't go
to the other world without it.
Please...
let me hold it.
Don't worry.
I fired it twice.
There's no more bullets.
Thanks.
I can't.
Everything's going dark.
Damn it!
Who's banging
the prayer drum?
I don't need any prayers.
Hey!
Two-Bit! Are you there?
I'm here.
I'll be waiting for you...
at the gates of hell.
Look at him.
He died as recklessly
as he lived.
Hansuke!
What is it?
Go hang yourself.
It'll be quiet in this town now.
Old man.
See ya around.
THE END