THE EXTERMINATING ANGEL
Providence Street
- Where are you going?
- I'm going for a stroll
Now? We have 20 guests for dinner
I forgot that, but I promise
I'll be back soon
- You are going nowhere
- Please let me go
All right, but don't bother
coming back
Lucas has quit.
Has he been arguing with you?
No. He didn't tell us he was leaving
We got on well together.
He's a nice man
If he was not happy,
it's a good thing he's gone
Well, there are plenty more
like Lucas about
Maybe there's a woman involved
Camila, what shall we do?
Please yourself, but I simply
must go out
That's how I feel, but where
can we go at this hour?
And the weather's so awful
One of my friends will put us up
I'm taking a taxi, I could
drop you off
You'll wait for me
The caviar?
Madam wants the main dish
to be served first
- And I've got to do it
- Because you're a clown
Lucas isn't here. Your coats
will be taken upstairs
- Do you hear anything?
- They've gone upstairs
We shouldn't leave like this
You should have thought
of that before
Let's go
No, I've never tried it
Our youngest colonel, yet you
have no taste for heroism?
I dread the noise of guns, Blanca
What of your countrt?
It's a network of rivers
flowing into the sea
- The sea is death
- Death for one's countrt
Alvaro, Edmundo wishes to speak
To the wonderful evening
given to us by Silvia...
...with her magnificent
virgin bride of Lammermoor
Bride, perhaps... but virgin?
- A title more appropriate to "Valkyrie"
- "Valkyrie"?
My name for Leticia.
She's ferocious and a virgin
Are you sure she's virgin?
They say she preserves it -
a perversion, perhaps
To the wonderful evening
given to us by Silvia...
...with her magnificent
virgin bride of Lammermoor
I've taken the liberty
of varting the menu
The hors-d'oeuvre will be a Maltese
dish, which is good for the appetite
It's made of liver, honey, almonds
and a piquant sauce
Delicious! I had it when
I conducted in Capri
Right on cue, just as in the theatre
Wonderful, Lucia!
That was really unexpected!
Lucia has a flair
for such chic surprises!
I'm not in the least bit amused
I'm just in time.
Don't let him loose
Mr Russell doesn't like jokes,
put him in the garden
I think madam is wise.
There are other problems, too
- What's wrong?
- Odd things are happening
If madam will come with me...
- And the sheep, madam?
- Put them in the garden, too
- Where are you going?
- Madam...
Are you leaving, too, Pablo?
I must see my poor sister,
madam
Why? Is she ill?
She felt unwell this morning
Ridiculous! This is an insult
to my guests
Everything is ready to be served,
madam
God, give me patience!
Have you been unhappy here?
On the contrart, a vert happy
five years, madam
- So?
- Forgive me
- And where are you going?
- I'm going with Pablo
- We'll be back in the morning
- Consider yourselves dismissed
I would like to be of service
to madam
Please forgive us.
Excuse me
No doubt they planned this.
Why?
Servants become more impertinent
evert day
Continue serving with the footmen.
I'm relying on you
- What about our things?
- We'll come back for them tomorrow
They won't let us in.
I'm taking my suitcase now
A passing Jew
No, it was "Valkyrie"
A fascinating woman
- What is your name?
- Beatriz. And yours?
Eduardo
- Age?
- Thirty
- Profession?
- Architect
- Single?
- Until Saturday, like you
Five more days
I ate with real appetite tonight,
doctor
Your treatment has transformed me
Not at all.
Your ailments are not serious
- Do you dance?
- I've never tried
A pity. I would love to be
in your arms
I'm flattered that my patient
is so pleased with me
- Transference
- I've long wanted to satisfy that desire
Did you bring your pills?
- What's the matter?
- It's nothing, doctor
With your ulcer you shouldn't
eat so much
May I present an old friend of mine?
- It's a pleasure to meet you
- Likewise
- Will you excuse me?
- Of course
- Blanca is playing for us
- We'll be back in a minute
Why did she kiss you so passionately?
Poor Leonora, how is her cancer?
Any hope?
None. I give her three months
to total baldness
A good skull
- Leandro!
- My dear Cristin
It's so nice to see you.
I thought you were still in New York
- I turn up like a bad penny
- We must get together
We must arrange one of our
special entertainments
Careful, we're not alone
May I present Mr Russell?
Don't bother.
Continue to present each other
Besides, it's all Greek to me.
Excuse me
- That Russell is eccentric
- He must be a man of letters. Too bad!
Shall we go and listen to Blanca?
Bravo! Well done!
- Magnificent!
- An exquisite performance
How superb it would be
with a harpsichord
Now something by Scarlatti, I beg you
Excuse me, but it's late and I'm tired
But it's the most intimate,
agreeable moment of our evening
- You've been wonderful, Blanca
- Was it Paradisi?
Exquisite!
So, the great conductor is one of us
I'm happy to make your acquaintance...
so fraternally
- Which lodge?
- Dawn Twenty-one
Sublime column
Maestro, what do you think
of the pizzicato we've just heard?
Sonata, sir, sonata
May I introduce you? Seor Ugalde,
this is...
- Leandro Gmez
- Nice to meet you
- Will you stay long?
- Will you?
- You first
- No, you
- I live here
- Just as I thought
- Time for the coats
- Yes, sir
Please excuse him. He felt
rejuvenated this evening
He drank a little, and he's tired
One cannot but admire his stamina
on the rostrum
How can he sustain
such demanding activity?
Well, after the concert
he even tried to...
I've nothing to complain about.
I even have to restrain him
Let him sleep. He may trt again here!
My goodness, I don't think
he would do that here
Of course not.
I expressed myself badly
She's a little tired. It's only
natural in her condition
Congratulations. Drowsiness
is a good sign
- Your fourth child?
- I've lost count
- Are you sure you're the father?
- You'd better ask her
Science will decide
I thought you'd gone
Ral is telling us about
the fauna of Romania
The climate, you see...
I really must go now.
Where is my shawl?
Just a second
They won't go. It's nearly four
They'll go soon. Then you
can slip up to my room
Your husband?
If he finds you, I'll say I wanted
to show you my incunabula
Good idea
Thank you so much
It went well, in spite of...
It's late, and your lipstick
is fading
We must look after our friends.
They are feeling cooped-up
I enjoy the spontaneity
of this situation
If you care to spend
the night here...
...we will have rooms prepared
for you
I'm glad to see that the spirit
of improvisation still survives
You are the perfect host, but we
must not abuse your hospitality
I have a rehearsal tomorrow
And I have an appointment...
in only four hours time
Now they're turning out the lights
We must make a decision.
We must leave
If the others are drunk or mad
they can stay
This is outrageous!
If I weren't a guest here...
...I'd teach that lout a lesson
These clothes may suit statues,
but not men at 5am
Isn't that going a bit too far?
Don't forget that he's lived
in the United States
It's warm, and the body
is most exhausted at this hour
They will be ashamed when they
recall their conduct
Certainly, and I wish to spare them
embarrassment
Let us go to their level, to mitigate
their conduct a little
Please, Lucia, sit here
Our first night together
But why are we here?
Why haven't we left?
Because evertone decided to stay
Is that normal?
Life is amusing... and strange
I can hardly keep awake
Come... Let's sleep
- Did you sleep well?
- I didn't wake once
For me it was worse than
the Nice Express derailment
You were in a derailment?
Fascinating!
You should see yourself!
I'm bewildered. What's going on?
How could this happen to us?
It's a bit much
We must offer them breakfast,
then they'll go home
I hope so. I'm relying
on their discretion
I was quite shocked
A third-class carriage was squashed
like a concertina
And inside, what carnage!
The sight didn't upset me.
I must be insensitive
I'm hungrt
Yet you fainted at the bier
of Prince Lourcat
No comparison!
How could one be insensitive
to his grandeur in death?
He had such a noble profile
Don't they eat breakfast here?
I think the lower orders are
insensitive to suffering
Have you ever seen a wounded bull?
It's impassive
I'm going to tidy myself. We look
horrible, but it's amusing
Did you sleep well?
I must look awful. Why stare at me,
dear sister?
You are more interesting than ever -
unkemptness becomes you
I must look awful.
Why are you staring at me?
You are more interesting than ever -
unkemptness becomes you
What sharp ears!
After a bad night,
he lost consciousness at dawn
You should have told me.
He must be put to bed
It's better not move him. We'll do
what we can for him here
- Keep him warm
- I thought he was looking odd at dinner
It may not be anything serious,
it's not the first time
- How is he?
- Almost totally bald
- I don't understand
- He only has a few hours to live
And your prognoses are never wrong
- I don't feel vert well, either
- It's nothing
Julio, do your best to provide
breakfast for our guests
It's vert early,
the tradesmen haven't delivered yet
- Not even the milkman?
- Not even him. It's really odd
Bring the cold meat from dinner
and some hot coffee
Lucia, where could we freshen up
a little?
I should have attended to that
earlier. Come to my room
I bet they won't go
You see? What do you make
of this situation?
I don't know. It's uncommon,
or perhaps only too common
No one seems to behave logically
Why didn't you and your fiance
leave?
I don't know... like evertone else...
and you?
I don't know
That's what bothers me
Not one of us has made
the slightest effort to go home
Why? Was it natural for us
to spend the night here...
...against the elementart rules
of etiquette?
Have we become a gypsy encampment?
I think it's vert original.
I love things out of the ordinart
I don't like it. But I said nothing,
out of politeness
Come, gentlemen, let's not exaggerate
We were enchanted by the music,
the conversation...
It's not a cause for surprise.
My feet are swollen
May I ask our charming Lucia...
...why serve breakfast here,
instead of in the dining room?
Well, doctor, since we're all here
I thought...
The doctor loves to play
Sherlock Holmes, doesn't he?
My husband and children must be
worried. I'm going home
We'll go with you.
This is all so absurd
- Are you coming, Rita?
- Isn't it rather early to go out?
We must see our children off
to school
My children study at home
with their tutor, Abb Samson
I think he is something of a saint.
Even my husband says...
Isn't it true, Cristin?
Madam, this is no time to prattle
about priests... Let's go
Excuse me
What have we got to lose
by drinking coffee?
I can't smoke on an empty stomach
I'd like some, too.
Will you join us, Blanca?
This is excessive
I find this atmosphere
almost hysterical
It's not the first time that
I've breakfasted at a party
Lucia, I'm afraid there are
no sugar spoons
I'm sorrt, the butler has no help
- Julio, the sugar spoons
- Yes, madam
May I get you something, gentlemen?
Some coffee?
No, Julio. Just do as you were told
I think I should attend until
breakfast is completed
Didn't you hear me ask you
to fetch sugar spoons?
- I merely thought...
- Do as I asked
What's the matter?
Do you feel unwell?
Blanca, what's wrong? Can I help you?
What's your opinion of all this?
The butler's strange disobedience
confirms my observations
No matter how we trt,
we cannot leave this room
What's going on?
A man is vert ill!
- How is he, doctor?
- Bluntly, he is in a coma
If only I had some heart stimulants
Cristin, we need to make an effort
and put and end to this apathy
We must get Mr Russell out of here
He urgently needs proper
medical facilities
The doctor is right.
We must make an effort
Who will dare to take him?
Why don't you do it? You know
we'll all follow you
It's useless
We're lost. Why did you
bring me here, dear sister?
Don't be cruel. It was you
who made me come here
Calm down...
There's no water
Isn't there any coffee left?
I'm dying of thirst
Madam must excuse me,
but there's not a drop left
This can't be bad. A squeeze
of lemon will improve the taste
Thank you, Eduardo,
but I'd rather wait
I don't understand,
there must be a solution
Look at me.
We haven't gone mad, have we?
Evertone's forgotten us. We've been
here for 24 hours. We're lost
That's what worries me most
What's the matter?
Why don't people come...
Unless evertone's dead
and we're the only survivors
- Why don't they come for us?
- Calm down
Shut up!
- I'm breaking the window
- Use the door
There's a connection between this
and the servants leaving
Gentlemen, please
Let's not be alarmist. The servants
must have had their reasons
Like rats when they leave
a sinking ship
May I just say...
I think they left for no reason
They were all happy until
shortly before you arrived
In short, there's no explanation.
It's extraordinart
We must keep calm, there's
nothing worse than panic
A situation like this
can't last forever
We're not spellbound, this isn't
a sorcerer's castle
We will only overcome our plight
by cold analysis
I propose...
...that we should all concentrate,
make a supreme effort...
...be determined to get out of here,
to succeed...
Shut up, Nobile.
You're responsible for all this
We're all victims of a joke
that's in vert bad taste
I, my dear friend? Because
I invited you to dinner?
- Because I opened my door?
- Exactly!
You invited each of us
to dine here
"Would you do me the honour... "
et cetera
We'd rather have slept at home,
or in a brothel. Anywhere!
Why did you extend
that strange invitation?
Strange? But you were all delighted
You yourself said
how happy you were
Then I correct myself. One person
caused this degradation - you!
Me? You've lost your wits
Edmundo is right.
You're nothing but a fool
If you weren't a lady...
The water didn't seem to harm
the butler
- I've got a headache
- No, Blanca, don't
Can't these men do anything?
They bicker like tarts
Silvia, find a way for us
to get out of this hole
Don't be offended. He's more
sensitive than a young girl
I'm sure this situation upsets him
more than it does us
Don't make me worse!
I don't want to hear anyone.
I want to be alone
I'm content. I won't see
the extermination
I wouldn't mind dying, but not
among people, like this
I want the chance to be alone
with you
What hope have we got to be alone?
There is a way we can isolate
ourselves from the others
I don't see how
I'll tell you when they're asleep,
if they ever decide to sleep
I lifted the lid and saw a precipice
and a raging torrent
As I sat down an eagle flew by
below me
The wind blew dead leaves
in my face
I'm cold
Consumatum est
Just what we need! It would be better
if we evaporated when we died
This corpse will demoralise them
Why didn't the old man die?
What's one conductor, more or less?
What shall we do?
- Were you seen?
- I don't know. I don't care
- Here it flows into the sea
- I can't reach
Keep descending
Already the horrible, fixed grin
My love
My death.
Oh, my enclosure!
Still nothing
- What do you suggest?
- This can't go on forever
Three days ago the mayor
tried to establish contact
He wanted to give them instructions
by loudspeaker, if any are still alive
But I made him see the absurdity
of the idea
It strikes me as a good idea
But there's a simpler way. Why not
enter the house? No one's done that
Yesterday we ordered a brigade
of sappers to enter
At nightfall they returned
to the barracks defeated
- Did they trt to enter?
- No, that's the worst of it
- Let us go in! We're not animals
- Clear off!
Why is it taking so long?
It's easy
What's wrong?
- Me first. I'm feverish
- Me, too
Wait your turn
You stepped on my foot!
Must you wear shoes?
Why is it taking so long?
Maybe the water has been cut off
You could help them
Excuse me
Move away! Women first!
Get in line. Drink only
one glassful now
It will be dangerous to drink
too much at first
Drink in moderation
- Women first! Didn't you hear?
- Here, drink up
I won't let you brutalise my brother!
How nice and fresh
Hungrt... I'm hungrt
Don't eat! Don't leave me alone!
He's gone two days without speaking.
He's oblivious to evertone, even me
And you say it isn't serious?
It isn't. He's suffering no more
than we are
He may feel the effects more
because of his age
My hands are like dead twigs
We might be better off without water
We'll only prolong our agony
by drinking it
- What are you eating?
- Paper. It helps to stave off hunger
- It's nauseating
- The taste isn't disagreeable
We used to eat it at school.
The lessons bored us
My teachers were Jesuits,
good people
We were bored, like most children
I know that paper is made
from softwood trees
It can't harm you.
Would you care to trt it?
- Julio, come here
- Excuse me
- Put this cloth around it
- Don't go! Don't leave me alone!
Prince! Save me! Our pact!
I can't stand it anymore!
I can't bear the way that harpy
combs her hair! I hate her!
Better hunger and thirst than her!
Why not comb it properly?
Like that, you see!
Comb it right through!
We are fed up with your odd habits
Sorrt to bother your, Beatriz
Have you seen a silver box
containing pills?
A silver box? No, I'm sorrt
They're my husband's pills. We used
to take great care of them but...
...now we're all feeling a bit...
I'll look for them
I'm hungrt
By any chance, is there
a lump of sugar?
I'm sorrt, madam, but there's
been nothing for two days
Are you feeling better? Someone
will find the box, you'll see
Doubtless someone has it,
but wants to see me suffer
Don't say that
You know, I wonder...
I wonder what they're doing.
I think of them all the time
I never forget them, either.
Our poor children
My only consolation is that
the Abb will care for them
The Abb! I'm worried that they're
at the mercy of that hypocrite
- That's unjust
- Admit he chases after you
- I won't say more
- Go on, say more!
Are you interested?
You and your marital problems
mean nothing to me
You're insolent! I thought so
as soon as I saw you!
I don't care. I've nothing
but contempt for you
Gentlemen, we are all
in the same boat
We'll all gain by treating
each other considerately
- You'd better keep quiet
- That's right
It's cynical to give advice
to your victims
My victims? What do you mean?
I'd be relieved to hear
of some good reason...
I'm tired of explaining
Come with me, don't say anymore.
Don't make them more irritable
Sit down
Sit down with me, please
My friend, I'd give my life
to remedy this situation
I am appalled by suffering. I've
always tried to help the needy
How could they possibly believe
that I...
Calm down
Alvaro, I'm so hungrt
Think of a way to get us out
Only a miracle can free us
Why don't we all pray together?
We have made a solemn vow
If Divine Providence frees us
we will offer a Te Deum
That frightful smell. It's unbearable!
We're trting to contain it
Don't go! Don't leave me alone!
I'm so cold
Blanca, remember what I told you
about your hair
Doctor?
What can we do? She's suffering
so much, poor thing
I can't stand it.
Why don't you kill me and end it all?
Don't be silly. You had a good night
We need analgesics as much
as we need food
We haven't even an aspirin
Don't leave me, doctor
I feel better when you're near
If we ever get out of this trap
I'll go to Lourdes
- Promise that you will come with me
- I promise
We'll humble ourselves
at the Virgin's feet...
...for only she can get us out of here
Don't talk so much. It won't help
if you get excited
When we are at Lourdes...
...you must buy me a washable
rubber Virgin
You will, won't you?
Are these yours?
We call this room
"The Paradise of Thebes"
A few friends gather here
to pass unforgettable hours
Why didn't you show me before?
In these circumstances, just imagine
if the others knew
What was for pleasure
can now relieve pain
Laudanum, codeine and morphine
Morphine? Where?
- What is it?
- It's none of your business
What has he got hidden there?
You'll sample it
when evertone is asleep
- I'm hungrt
- Silence
This is too much,
show some respect
- You smell like a hyena!
- What?
Like a hyena, madam!
How dare you? Why insult me?
Shame on you for mentioning what
we have the dignity to ignore
It's the truth. She stinks,
like you, I, and evertone!
We live in a pigsty, like real pigs
You all disgust me. I hate you!
Take no notice, he's hypersensitive
This will end badly, my dear
What I've always hated most -
coarseness, violence and filth
They're now our inseparable
companions
Death is preferable
to this abject promiscuity
Lord Elohim, be with me
The empire of witchcraft
is assembled here
Before I die, divine Lord...
...come! come! come!
What have you done?
Have you lost your mind?
- Tie her hands up
- Take her away at once!
Call an ambulance
She's feverish. Put cold compresses
on her forehead
Don't crt, it's over. They'll take turns
to ensure nothing happens to you
- It's nauseating
- But it will kill the pain
- What day is it?
- What?
We've been here over a month,
haven't we?
Not yet. We'd have died of hunger
before now
I feel we've always been here
I feel the same way
And we'll always be here
Unless...
Unless we escape together,
lose ourselves in the shadows
You don't answer
Where you go, I'll follow
- Look, it's just what we thought
- Yes
What's that?
- What's the problem now?
- Be quiet!
Who stepped on my hand?
- What's the matter?
- I may have dreamt it
I'm not blind, sir!
- What are you talking about?
- You behave like an incubus!
Please, don't be ridiculous
Watch your tongue!
- Calm down, gentlemen
- What's the matter?
The colonel took advantage
of the dark, like a thief!
You swine! Enough of this!
I challenge you to a duel!
- I accept!
- A madhouse! One can't even sleep
Nobile's at the centre of it all,
it's another of his schemes
Don't you see
he's got an upset stomach?
This is madness. Calm down
and talk reasonably
Anything but physical violence!
It's not like us!
Remember your upbringing,
remember who you are
I'd like to know if Nobile
provoked this
We'll show him he can't play with us
I prefer not to answer, gentlemen
There's a limit to our patience
Rita, trt to pacify him
I'll never forget how
you've ridiculed me
- I'd rather have food than fighting
- Leave me alone!
How could you?
Even the strongest
are losing their heads
Have pity on me
Cristin, please,
evert problem has a solution
I beg your pardon,
yours and evertone's
I was out of my mind.
I was not myself
Please forgive me, madam
May I make a suggestion which
I hope you will approve of?
To avoid lamentable brushes
in future...
...ladies should sleep on one side
of the room, men on the other
Remember you are speaking
to gentlemen!
He's a degenerate. He enjoys
insulting us
- Edmundo is right
- I just thought...
Don't trt anymore,
can't you see that...?
Thank you
Remember now, behave yourselves.
Let's go
- Where are you going?
- They're Ugalde's children
We're going to look at the house,
their parents are inside
- Go ahead
- Thank you
I'm sure I can go in and talk to them,
if they're still alive
- Are you sure?
- I'll show you
Won't you let me? Then I'll tell
the Press!
I need to be listened to,
I'm sure I can solve this business!
Another maniac
Go on, Johnny, don't stop
- Why have you stopped?
- Go on, Johnny?
- He must not stop
- Keep going, child!
Why run back?
You can't trust children!
- Come on, trt again!
- No, let's go
So as not to fall into total apathy...
...we must keep the place
clean and tidy
We'll organise cleaning teams
How are you?
- All right, except for my head
- You poor thing
If it weren't for him and Leticia,
they'd act like savages
I'll never forget their defence of you
I had a presentiment before going
to the opera that night
I heard a voice insisting:
"Take the keys, take the keys"
The keys?
In the cabala, a key is anything
which opens the doors of the unknown
Now, Blanca, hold that firmly.
Like this
And you, Silvia, the other one,
like this
Victim!
I can't feel anything,
we need innocent blood
We must await the sacrifice
of the last sheep
- What's the matter?
- Look!
In the cupboard...
Listen evertone...
- What's the matter?
- It's over
Eduardo, Beatriz...
Doctor, in there!
What's going on?
Leandro, Colonel, help me.
Keep evertbody away
Let me see, Alvaro
- How did they do it?
- It doesn't matter. Back off
They slit their wrists
What's so funny?
I was thinking...
...what if I pushed you into
the other room?
I'd kill you
What does that mean?
They've lost whatever reason
they had
It's a Masonic call for help.
They must go to each other's aid
But here... unless, of course,
the bear...
Cristin, the time has come
to speak the unutterable word
C... H... I... H... H... O... H
Shut the windows!
Save yourselves!
They're coming in their millions!
- It's late, my boy. Off to bed
- I'm not sleepy
- So many people!
- He died in mortal sin
My dear child!
I shall never see you again!
Look, at the summit!
Can you see him?
- The Pope!
- Yes, it is
So solemn and majestic,
like a warrior
I'll tuck you in
- Good night, my dear
- Good night, Mum
Nothing! The same as usual,
like a tomb
- Why the quarantine flag?
- It could be an epidemic
- Typhus would be better than this
- Pablo!
What brings you here?
The same as you, to see
if there's any news
- Maybe they're all dead
- You think so?
Sometimes you can smell the stench
from here
Perhaps it's the food rotting
in the kitchen
Don't shoot! No, don't kill it, please!
It's quite tame. I work here
The cook and the maids...
- You told them we were coming?
- I've not said a word
- What are they doing here?
- I don't know
Let's find out.
Perhaps they've heard some news
Ral says we'll be free
if Nobile dies
Dead spiders spin no webs
If he had any dignity he'd know
what to do
He's hiding with Leticia
Stop that! It's the most decent
thing you could do
Speak up, gentlemen. Let's all
hear your plotting
We want to get rid of him
Are you mad? That's completely
irrational
We don't want reason,
we want to get out
- If you're looking for a fight...
- Alvaro, stand aside!
- We've nothing against you two
- We're justified by necessity
- Kill him!
- Better late than never!
- Listen, fools!
- Kill the doctor, too
Why is he trting to stop us?
Think of the terrible consequences
of your actions
This won't be the last vile act
It means the disintegration
of human dignity. It's bestial
Stand aside, or I won't answer
for your safety
Enough of talking!
Get him!
- That's enough, Ral!
- You stay out of this!
Look, it's Nobile!
There's no need for violence. You can
have what you want easily
Thank you, Leticia
Just a moment. Stand still
- What's the matter?
- I don't know
Yes, now I know
It's really extraordinart
How long have we been here?
I've lost track of time
Think how often we've changed
positions during...
...this terrible eternity
It's like a chess game.
We have made thousands of moves
We've even moved the furniture
hundreds of times
Yet now everything is
just as it was then...
...people and furniture...
...the scene as it was that night
Is it another hallucination,
or is it true? Tell me, Alvaro
- Tell me!
- It's true
I was here and you were beside me,
weren't you?
And I was sitting here
We sat here and I held
your hand in mine
- Who remembers?
- After dinner I sat at the piano
- You were there
- It's true!
That's all vert well,
but what's the point?
Can you remember what you played?
Perfectly
The last piece I played
was a Paradisi sonata
Play it again. Just the end.
Go on, play it!
Play it
You stood behind me. Go on, get up
You were clapping
You rose from the piano,
someone came up to you
Who spoke first?
Make an effort!
Trt to remember!
An exquisite performance
Answer. What would you have replied?
Yes, yes
I'm sorrt we have no harpsichord
for you
How superb it would be
with a harpsichord
Now something by Scarlatti,
I beg you
It's late, isn't it?
It's three o'clock
Excuse me, but it's late
and I'm tired
We're all tired and we want
to go home, don't we?
Let's go, then! Come on, follow me!
Follow me!
This way!
- It's good. Brandy from the house?
- My last bottle
Look! There's light!
Camila, come here.
Look, the light's on
- It's them
- My goodness!
- Let's go in
- After you
Why not wait for the faithful
to leave?
- Wait? Why?
- Well...
- Father...
- Yes?
Something's wrong
- Let's wait a moment
- A good idea
I've forgotten my missal
- Why are they not leaving?
- Let me through
I'll explain
- You go first
- I'm in no hurrt
What's going on? Let's go
The End
Subtitles by
International Broadcast Facilities
WWW.clan-sudamerica. com. ar