MOSFILM
Mom, there's a cuckoo over there.
IVAN'S CHILDHOOD
Based upon the story "Ivan"
by V. Bogomolov
Written by Vladimir BOGOMOLOV
and Mikhail PAPAVA
Directed by Andrei TARKOVSKY
Director of Photography
Vadim YUSOV
Production Designer
Ye. CHERNYAYEV
Music by V.OVCHINNIKOV
Sound by E. ZELENTSOVA
Starring
Kolya BURL YAYEV as Ivan
V. ZUBKOV as Kholin
Ye. ZHARIKOV as Galtsev
S. KRYLOV as Katasonov
N. GRINKO as Gryaznov
D. MIL YUTENKO as the Old Man
V. MAL YAVINA as Masha
I. TARKOVSKAYA as Ivan's Mother
Comrade Senior Lieutenant!
What is it?
We detained someone... The lieutenant
told me to bring him to you.
Light the lamp.
He was crouching in the river,
near the bank.
He won't say why,
nor answer any questions.
He says he'll only talk
to the commander.
He must be very weak,
or just pretending.
The second lieutenant's ordered
to bring him here.
Stand by the stove.
Who are you?
First, send him out.
Wait outside. I'll call you.
Well? Say something.
Where are you from?
I'm Bondarev.
Tell number 51 at HQ
that I'm here.
And who's number 51?
What HQ do you mean?
What army?
Code address: VCH-49550.
Come on, strip
and rub yourself down.
Here. Take it, it's dirty, anyway.
Take off your pants, too.
Don't be bashful.
What's that on your back?
Answer me!
None of your business.
And don't shout at me.
You just tell HQ I'm here.
They'll know what to do.
Don'tyou teach me.
You know where you are?
I never heard of you.
You'll stay here until you tell me
who you are and where you are from.
Are you going to speak?
If you want me to report aboutyou,
tell me where you are from.
- I'm from the other bank.
- What?
And how did you get here? Can you
prove thatyou're from the other bank?
I don't have to prove anything.
And stop questioning me!
Or you'll answer for it.
Tell number 51 at HQ
that Bondarev's here. Now!
They'll know what to do.
Number 3?
Comrade Captain, number 8 reporting.
I've got Bondarev here.
- Who?
- Bondarev.
He demands that I notify "Volga".
You mean Major Bondarev?
From the operations unit?
No, he's not a major.
A kid about twelve years old.
Are you kidding? What's the matter
with you? Are you sober?
Well, I thought... Comrade Captain,
he says he came from the other side.
Did he get here on the magic carpet?
He's just snowjobbing you.
Tell him
that if he doesn't notify number 51,
he'll be held responsible.
See? I reported aboutyou
as you have asked me to.
I was told to lock you up.
I asked you to tell number 51 at HQ.
And who'd you ring up?
You expect me to personally
contactArmy HQ?
- Let me do it, then.
- Don'tyou dare!
Who are you going to ring up?
Who d'you know atArmy HQ?
Captain Kholin
and Colonel Gryaznov.
Tell Colonel Gryaznov I'm here. Now.
Or I'll do it myself.
"Baikal",
get me number 51 at "Volga".
Comrade Colonel,
Senior Lieutenant Galtsev reporting.
I got Bondarev here. He demands...
Bondarev? Is he alone?
Galtsev!
Listen carefully, Galtsev.
No questions. No talking.
You got me?
Kholin!
Kholin's already on his way to pick
him up. Meanwhile, be nice to him.
See that he's comfortable.
Mind you, he has a hot temper.
And give him a pencil and paper.
Anything he writes send to me
immediately.
- You got me?
- Yes, sir!
Are you hungry?
I'll eat later.
I won't look.
Get me number 13.
Vassiliev, bring in two pails
of hot water.
What? Yes, I'm going to have
a bath.
Go on, wash up. I'll be back soon.
Thanks.
It's deep!
Of course it is.
If a well is deep,
you can see a star in it
even in the daytime.
Which star?
Any star.
- I see it, mom!
- Yes, there it is.
Why is it shining?
Because it's nighttime for the star.
That's why it's shining.
Is it really nighttime now?
No, it's daytime.
It's daytime for you and me,
but it's nighttime for the star.
Mommy!
Haven't they come yet?
No. Go back to sleep.
I'll wake you up when they come.
Were you here while I was asleep?
Yes. Why?
Did I talk in my sleep?
No. Why?
Never mind.
I never used to talk in my sleep.
Now I don't know.
I've become jittery.
Ivan!
Kholin!
Katasonych is waiting for you
at the hollowtree, and you're here.
The nazis are there.
So I swam.
I had cramps, and nearly drowned.
- You mean you swam across?
- Yes. Don't get angry.
They're patrolling the bank.
I couldn't find our boat in the dark.
They could catch me.
You got so skinny.
Just a bag of bones.
Go and bring the car up close.
Tell the sentry not to let anyone in.
Here, put this on.
Go on.
Stop!
Where have you been?
- Where are you going?
- For kerosene.
What for? We're leaving.
Here's to our meeting!
Kholin, Katasonych is still waiting
for me at the hollowtree.
To his safe return!
Number 2 here.
This is number 51. Malyshev,
remember, you had an argument?
They were right. We should take
the Fyodorovka direction.
But we've already decided...
Save your breath, I've heard it all.
- May I come in, Colonel?
- Yes, come in.
- What?
- I said I've heard it.
I have absolutely reliable,
first-hand information.
Waited all night for nothing, eh,
Katasonych?
Sit down.
Ivan's here.
He couldn't get to the bank
at the hollowtree.
He says there are German patrols
everywhere.
- How did he get here?
- He swam across.
Jesus!
A grown man might've drowned.
Well, that's it.
Enough of a good thing.
Wait, Ivan!
Comrade Colonel, why?
He said I'll be sent to the rear.
To a military school, by your order.
Is that true?
Why did you do it? You deceived me.
An offensive is being planned.
I can still be useful.
You yourself said that reconnaissance
is most important!
That scouts are the soul of the front.
You were trying to trick me!
I'm not going! And if you force me to,
I'll run away.
I'll join the partisans.
Ivan, you're going to a military
school. You got me?
And stop arguing.
I won't discuss it.
But I will!
Kholin, tell him I'll do a good job,
I'll be useful.
I just can't...
You tell him, Katasonych,
I can't go to the rear!
The matter is closed!
All right... Military school,
or a children's home,
it's all the same to me.
Be quiet...
The stove and chimney
will stand forever.
Where is it?
I put it here.
Are you going far?
Yes.
Right.
Everybody's going far nowadays.
But why?
Who knows?
I lost a nail.
Could you help me find it?
You have nothing to do, anyway.
Come in.
The stove and chimney
will never burn down.
Here's a straight nail.
No, it won't do.
Where's your ma? Alive?
A nazi shot my old woman, too.
Where can it be?
I saw it a minute ago.
He was a tall fellow...
He wore glasses.
And had long hair.
- What's your name?
- Ivan.
Pelageya will be back soon...
That's my wife's name.
I'll have the house all ready for her.
Ivan!
Why'd you run away, Vanya?
You think I have nothing better to do
than chasing after you?
I didn't ask you to.
Don't talk back at me. Look at him,
he wants to join the partisans!
Get into the car!
You won't run away again.
Yes, I will.
I said get into the car!
I'll run away
from that military school,
just like I did from the children's
home.
"I ran away from Granny,
And from Granddad, too..."
O Lord,
will this ever end?
Vanya, can'tyou understand, silly,
that war is for grown men?
You promised you won't issue
that order!
Lyakhov and Moroz were killed because
they were big. I can get through.
Besides, I'm all alone.
You know I have no family left.
That's enough, Vanya.
It's been decided.
Nothing is decided!
You're not my dad to decide.
Shut up!
Or I'll spank you.
I'll run away anyway,
if you don't let me go.
I'm my own boss.
Indeed!
You're my pain in the neck.
D'you knowthat there's lice
in Company 5?
The linen isn't disinfected properly.
Do something about it.
Yes, Comrade Senior Lieutenant!
The situation is out of control.
Yes, sir.
There'll be no time for that
when the offensive begins.
Yes, Comrade Senior Lieutenant!
Thank you, Comrade Senior Lieutenant.
- A letter from home?
- Yes.
- Everything all right?
Greetings!
I've been looking for you.
Carry on. I'll wait here.
You're a commander. You must be
strict with your subordinates.
Butyou try to do everything yourself.
There's a lull now, and we have time.
When the offensive starts,
there'll be the wounded.
I don't know what to do aboutyou.
Since you're a commander,
get the medical service in order.
You've got two days. Then report back
to me.
Yes, Comrade Senior Lieutenant.
Don't worry.
Everything'll be... in order.
What's your name, Lieutenant?
- Masha.
- That's a pretty name.
My name's Leonid.
Lennie for short.
Have you ever had a boyfriend
called Lennie?
- No.
- So I'm the first?
Are you from the Ukraine?
- Why?
- You're beautiful and stubborn.
No, I come from near Moscow.
Peredelkino. Twenty minutes by train.
In Siberia, where I come from,
300 km is considered "near".
Surikov, the painter, used to live in
our town. Ever heard of him?
And in our town, writers used to live.
We once saw Alexei Tolstoy.
And Korney Chukovsky.
He's very tall, with a white head.
They were walking in the woods.
- Were you ever wounded?
- Yes, I was.
Why are we so formal?
Let's be on first name basis.
- I find it hard to so quickly.
- And I don't.
I'll start now, and you start
gradually, okay?
- What is it?
- A cobweb!
So what? Aren'tyou a brave soldier!
Some brave commander!
I'm only afraid of spiders.
Nothing else?
Vassiliev!
Have you seen Captain Kholin?
He went that way with the doctor's
assistant.
Walk the trunk! You said
you're not afraid of anything.
Well, I will.
That's enough.
Jump! I'll catch you.
Got scared?
Then why don'tyou?
No special reason.
So you were frightened?
All right, I forgive you.
I don't need your forgiveness.
You don't?
- Let me help you.
- I'll manage.
She'll manage!
Come here, Masha.
What for?
Come on, Masha, come here.
Come here, quick!
Hurry!
Now go away...
Go away, Masha.
You hear me, Masha? Go!
Go away quick, Masha...
Let's go and have a look
atyour troops.
There they are, Lyakhov and Moroz.
Go have a smoke.
- Good morning!
- Hello, Katasonych.
Galtsev, give me the defense line map.
Wait for me in your "underground".
I'll be right back.
Comrade Senior Lieutenant,
the gunners gave me a record.
They say you have a gramophone.
Could we listen to it?
- The gramophone's broken.
- I'll fix it.
Thanks, Katasonych.
This place is best, Captain.
But where will we land?
What d'you say, Katasonych?
In those bushes.
It's a safe place.
Only be sure to tell the gunners
to leave us a corridor.
WELCOME
Damn! Couldn'tyou have dug
a deeper one?
D'you know who's sitting there,
on the other bank?
I know.
Then why can'tyou bring them here?
It'll take but an hour.
- Have you got any boats?
- No.
You're lying.
- What for?
- I need them.
You are not even good at lying.
- They're for the landing party.
- That's what I need them for.
Are you and Katasonych planning
a scouting mission?
No, a picnic
with your gramophone.
Will Ivan go again?
Ivan, Ivan...
I'm not an information bureau.
- What's so funny?
- Nothing.
You've got a pretty doctor's
assistant.
I'm sending her away.
She can't cope with the job.
Aren'tyou severe, Galtsev!
Have a heart.
War is a man's business.
It's not for girls.
All right, go. I don't need you here.
Some man!
Excuse me, are you Masha?
Yes.
Don'tyou remember me?
No, I don't.
We took the college entrance exams
together.
Yes... now I do.
I'm so glad I metyou!
Me, too.
I'm glad I saw you.
Where'd you go after the exams?
I looked everywhere...
Now I've found you, Masha.
I'm coming!
I've found you!
We'll meet again, won't we?
We'll meet again, Masha!
We'll meet again!
WELCOME
Captain!
- That's you, Katasonych!
- We are here.
- Good.
Hello, Kholin!
- Hello, Ivan!
Ivan?
- Hello.
Give us a hand, Galtsev.
- Hello, Katasonov!
- Hello, sir!
Give us something interesting,
Galtsev, some magazines.
With lots of pictures.
Come here.
- Here. This one's about scouts.
- I've read it.
- How about this one?
- This one, too.
- And this one?
- This, too.
- You're lying!
- I'm not.
I was stuck at HQ all this time.
I did nothing but read for 3 days.
I gotyou a spring for the gramophone
at HQ.
Thanks, Katasonych.
It's under the bed.
- What's this, so big?
- An art book. Captured material.
- Any pictures in it?
- It's all pictures.
Give it to me.
You should've listened to him sprechen.
Like a real Fritz.
I wanted to make him an interpreter,
now he's in command of a battalion.
Look!
Are these Germans?
Yes, it's an old engraving.
They're Germans, all the same.
Look at this skinny one on a horse.
I saw one just like him
on a motorcycle.
Look, they're killing the people here,
too.
It's just a painting.
No...
I knowthem.
Who is this? A German?
He's either a German doctor,
or writer.
They have no writers.
I sawthem burning books
on the square.
They poured petrol over them
and set them on fire.
There was soot in the air for a week
after that.
This writer lived
about 400 years ago.
Well, then maybe...
If they spot us,
our gunners will keep them down.
We'll leave Ivan a passage
in the swamp.
I retreat last.
Got it?
What's this?
I think I'd better take
one of Galtsev's boats.
- Will you take me along?
- Where to?
To the other bank.
A volunteer, eh?
Can you swim?
Don'tyou worry. I can swim
this river and back 5 times.
What a hero.
Are you trigger-happy, too?
Stop it.
You see? He's so touchy.
No self-control.
How can I take you across?
- Then you don't get a boat.
- We'll commandeer it.
Or I'll reportyou to the Commander,
and you'll bring it to us on your back.
Come on, stop it.
He'll give us a boat.
Am I right?
All right. Let's go have a look.
You stay here and rest up.
Wow! What a knife!
Listen, Galtsev, would you give it
to me?
I would, Vanya, but...
Don't be a miser. Give it to him.
This is a memento.
It was my buddy's. He was killed.
- Let me have it till tonight.
- All right.
Why should I go with you? You're not
taking me across, right?
Come on. I'll take you,
but not today. After the war.
It's okay now.
We'll listen to it after supper.
I'll getyou a knife just like it.
I'll get one tomorrow.
By all means.
Where're his parents?
- Whose?
- Ivan's.
I don't know. They say
his mother and sister were killed.
His dad was a border guard.
I guess he was killed in action.
Really?
He's been through more
than you can imagine.
He was a partisan, too.
He knocked about the world.
What'll become of him?
The colonel or Katasonych will adopt
him when the war's over.
Why them and notyou?
I would,
but the colonel says
I need some upbringing myself.
Katasonych!
He's really good at stealing boats.
He'll never take a bad one.
Tell us, Galtsev,
how many owners have you ripped off?
- Which one?
- Take this one.
- No.
- What do you mean, no?
He should be sent to the rear.
A war is no place for children.
Stop it, will you?
You see, Lieutenant,
if we don't take him across,
he'll go on his own.
All he can think of...
is vengeance.
Don't waste your breath explaining.
They can't see here beyond their nose.
Didn'tyou say
you wanted to adopt him, and now...
What's the matter with you?
Get lost! We'll manage withoutyou.
That's not the way to do it.
- All right, Kholin.
- Don't Kholin me!
The colonel is right.
You do need upbringing.
Watch out, or I'll reportyou
to the commander.
Well... keep cool.
That's the main thing.
Slowly... carefully.
And remember,
we have to get him alive.
Got it?
THERE ARE 8 OF US.
ALL UNDER 19.
IN AN HOUR FROM NOW
THEY'LL SHOOT US.
AVENGE US.
Hurrah!
Surround the building!
Don't let him out!
Hands up! Come out!
So you're hiding!
You can't hide from me!
Are you shaking?
You'll answer for everything!
I'II...
D'you think I've forgotten?
I'll putyou on trial!
I'II... I'II...
Want some tea,
Comrade Captain.
Damn! It was our best boat!
You're lucky to be alive.
Forget the boat.
Faster! Hurry!
Can you hurry up?
Ivan!
Don't be afraid. It'll be over soon.
What is it, Ivan?
I'm not afraid.
I hear you were a partisan.
- Why'd you leave them?
- We were surrounded in the woods.
They sent me out by plane
to a boarding school.
But I ran away.
They're just wasting food there.
Memorizing names of reptiles.
Yeah, that's not for you. You ought
to go to a military school.
Did Kholin make you say so?
Why Kholin?
He's not the only one with brains.
I think so, too.
You've done your fighting.
Rest up, go back to school.
Whoever's of use
doesn't rest up in wartime.
Right. But war isn't for boys.
Not for boys?
Have you been to Trostyanets?
- Where?
- That's a death camp.
Why are you teaching me?
What do you know?
You're all together in it.
Smoking again?
Go on, smoke.
It'll turn you lungs green.
So what?
Nobody can see them.
- I don't wantyou to smoke.
- Okay, I won't.
We'll start out in an hour and a half.
Let's have supper.
- Where's Katasonych?
- He was summoned to HQ.
Why didn't he stop by
to wish me good luck?
He couldn't. It was an emergency.
Why'd they summon him?
They know how badly we need him.
And they summoned him all the same.
A fine friend! He could've stopped by.
Will it be just the two of us?
The three of us. He'll go, too.
Stop grinning. And don't stare at me.
You volunteered, didn'tyou?
Are you frightened now?
No, I'm not. It's sort of unexpected.
Unexpected...
Everything in life is.
- May I come in?
- Yes.
What's up?
We billeted the new men, Lieutenant.
- Where?
- In Companies Two and Three.
- Very well. You may go.
- Yes, sir.
I wouldn't take you,
but it's an emergency.
Make up your mind.
No complaints afterwards.
What d'you think I am?
All right.
Who'll you leave in command?
I think, Guschin,
of Company 5.
If they learn you crossed the river
without permission...
we'll be in trouble.
Although it won't take more
than two or three hours.
AVENGE US
Wake up, Ivan!
Do you hear? It's time.
Katasonych didn't even stop by.
I told you he couldn't.
You know how he loves you.
Don'tyou?
I know.
But still, he could have...
Here. Get dressed.
- Need any help?
- No.
Let's jump.
To see if anything rattles.
Dump your matches.
Are you crazy?
Crews, take your positions.
Go chat with the sentry
so he won't notice us... Got it?
And no comments!
Got a light?
Who's that?
It was all so stupid...
They brought the boat here
and had a smoke...
The captain was here.
He was over there...
He started climbing out of the trench.
And then he slid back down.
We didn't even hear a shot.
The captain shook him up:
"Katasonych! Katasonych!"
But he was dead.
The captain said to leave him here...
till morning.
Don't discuss it.
Get the oars.
Who's that?
Who's that, Kholin?
That's our men.
Lyakhov and Moroz.
They went across after you.
There's still time.
Wait here. I'll be right back.
- Come over here. It's dryer here.
- Makes no difference now.
MG-34.
- Are you nervous?
- A bit.
I've become jittery lately.
Can't get used to begging.
They should be buried.
- Who?
- Lyakhov and Moroz.
Sure, we'll do it.
Quiet! Everything's tiptop.
Let's go.
This is the place, guys.
- How do you feel?
- Fine.
- Well, I'll be going.
- I'll go a part of the way with you.
No, you're too big. They'll catch on.
Let me go.
The gully's clayey. You'll leave
footprints. I'll carry you over.
I said I'm going alone.
- See you soon.
- See you.
I'll see you.
Be careful.
If the offensive starts,
meet us in Fyodorovka. Got it?
- See you soon.
- Goodbye, Vanya.
What's up?
I want a smoke.
- Wantyour mommy, too?
- Cut it out.
l, for one, really do want my ma.
Won't it be good, eh?
- They'll notice the boat!
- What if they spot Ivan?
Are you a louse, or plain stupid?
Just stupid.
See a doctor aboutyour nerves
when the war's over.
Damn! It's a clayey gully!
What we need now is a good rain
to wash away all footprints.
I think he made it.
Wait here for me.
I'll go for the boat.
When I come back,
call out to me in German.
- Try it.
- Halt!
If I'm caught, swim back.
You said you could swim this river
and back five times.
What if you're wounded?
Don't worry about me.
Halt!
Quiet!
Damn you! Come here!
Hurry up!
Is that them?
Yes.
Them yesterday, us today.
Climb in.
- Are things quiet on the bank?
- Yes.
See? Nothing to fear.
Where are you going?
Why aren't we going back?
It's the first snow of the year.
Kholin!
What if he hasn't passed yet?
He might still be hiding, waiting.
Jump in the water!
Let's drink to...
May I come in,
Comrade Senior Lieutenant?
Masha!
Who were you talking to
on the road the other day?
- Your friend?
- Yes, my friend.
The one... that wore glasses?
He wasn't wearing glasses.
But he was!
He is strange.
No, he isn't.
- What is it, Lieutenant?
- I've come to say goodbye.
I'm transferring her to a hospital.
That's a good idea.
Masha!
How quiet it is, Galtsev.
Isn't it, Masha?
It's so quiet.
The war...
Brothers!
Victory!
IMPERIAL CHANCELLERY
I can take you there.
- Is it far from here?
- No, it's not far.
Come closer.
Can you identify these bodies?
He says he can.
It's Goebbels,
his wife and daughters.
He poisoned his family
with potassium cyanide
and ordered his body to be soaked
with petrol...
and burned.
He can show you the place.
At night he murdered his wife,
children, and himself...
I see. Let's go.
Won't this be the last war on earth?
You're too nervous, Galtsev.
See a doctor aboutyour nerves.
But, Kholin, wait...
You were killed.
And I'm alive.
I must not forget it.
Shot.
Hanged.
The End