Good night, Pat.
Good night.
What happened to the old
bank? It was beautiful.
People kept robbing it.
That's a small price to pay for beauty.
Hit me.
Again.
Bust!
Give me credit, Mr. Macon?
You know my rules, Tom.
Well, it looks like you just about
cleaned everybody out, fella.
You haven't lost a hand
since you got the deal.
What's the secret of your success?
Prayer.
Let's just you and me play.
Hit it.
Bust.
Yeah, you're a hell of
a card player, fella.
I know, 'cause I'm a
hell of a card player,
and I can't even spot
how you're cheating.
The money stays, and you go.
Well, we seem to be
a little short on brotherly love
around here.
If you're with him, you
better get out of here.
We're on our way.
I wasn't cheating.
Come on.
I wasn't cheating!
You can die. You can both die.
You hear that?
If he invites us to stay, then we'll go.
He's got to invite us to stick around.
He'll draw on you.
You don't know how fast he is.
I'm over the hill, but
it can happen to you.
That's just what I want to hear.
Every day you get older. That's a law.
What would you think about
maybe asking us to stick around?
What?
You don't have to mean it or anything.
Just ask us to stick
around. I promise...
I can't help you, Sundance.
I didn't know you were the Sundance Kid
when I said you were cheating.
I draw on you, you'll kill me.
There's that possibility.
You'd be killing yourself.
Why don't you just
invite us to stick around?
You can do it...
and easy.
Come on.
Why don't you stick around?
Thanks, but we got to get going.
Hey, Kid.
Hey, Kid, how good are you?
Like I been telling you...
over the hill.
Boy, you know,
every time I see
Hole-In-The-Wall,
it's like seeing it for the first time.
Every time, I ask myself
the same question...
how can I be so damn
stupid to keep coming back?
What's your idea this time?
Bolivia.
What's Bolivia?
Bolivia... that's a country, stupid.
Central or South America.
One or the other.
Let's go to Mexico instead.
All they got in Mexico is sweat.
There's too much of that here.
If we'd been in business
during the California gold rush,
where would we have
gone? California, right?
When I say Bolivia, you
just think California.
You wouldn't believe
what they're finding
in the ground down there.
They're just falling into it.
Silver mines, gold mines, tin mines.
Payrolls so heavy we'd strain
ourselves stealing them.
You just keep thinking, Butch.
That's what you're good at.
Boy, I got vision,
and the rest of the
world wears bifocals.
Hi, News. What you doing?
Aw, howdy, Butch. Uh, nothing.
Nothing.
Howdy, Sundance.
You sure are. You're
doing something. What?
Just fixing to rob the
Union Pacific Flyer, Butch,
like what we had in mind.
You fellas got everything
I told you all wrong.
Sure, we might hit the Flyer,
but even if we do, it won't be this run.
It'll be the next one, the return.
Sundance and me, we
been checking the banks.
No banks.
What?
The Flyer, Butch.
Fellas, bad as they are,
banks are better than trains.
They don't move. They stay put.
You know the money's in there.
When I left, I gave orders.
New orders been given.
I run things here, Harvey.
Used to you did.
Me now.
This don't concern you.
You tell him to stay out.
Well, he goes his own way, like always.
What's the matter with you guys?
When I came here,
you were nothing. I formed you.
Who says?
Read them a clipping, News.
Which one?
Any of them.
This one here's from Salt Lake Herald.
Butch Cassidy's
Hole-In-The-Wall Gang...
That's me!
You want Harvey to do your planning?
Want him to do your thinking for you?
You want him to run things?
Shut up now, News.
Not till I get to the good part.
Also known to have
participated in the holdup
are Flat Nose Curry and News Carver.
I just love to read my
name in the paper, Butch.
So we just forget
about Logan taking over,
O.K., Flat Nose?
You always said
that any one of us could challenge you.
'Cause I figured no one would do it.
Figured wrong, Butch.
You guys can't want Logan!
At least he's with us.
You been spending a lot of time gone.
Well, that's because
everything's different now.
Guns or knives, Butch?
You got to plan more, prepare more.
Guns or knives?
Neither.
Pick!
I don't want to shoot with you, Harvey.
Anything you say, Butch.
Maybe there's a way to
make a profit in this.
Bet on Logan.
I would, but who'd bet on you?
Sundance...
when we're done and he's dead,
you're welcome to stay.
I don't mean to be a sore loser,
but when it's done,
if I'm dead, kill him.
Love to.
No, no. Not yet.
Not until me and Harvey
get the rules straightened out.
Rules in a knife fight?
No rules.
If there ain't any
rules, let's get started.
Someone count 1, 2, 3, go.
1, 2, 3, go.
I was really rooting for you, Butch.
Well, thank you, Flat Nose.
That's what sustained
me in my time of trouble.
Hey, what's this about the Flyer?
Harvey said we'd hit it
both this run and the return.
Nobody's done that to the Flyer before.
No matter how much we got at first,
they'd figure the return was safe
and load it up with money.
Harvey thought of that?
Yes, sir, he did.
I'll tell you something, fellas.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
Stop it.
Where?
Up ahead there.
Bet that's old Butch himself.
Hold it there.
Just thought I'd watch.
Bring the kids, why don't you?
Stick your heads in.
You're just going to
get yourself blown up
you don't open that door.
I can't do that. I work
for Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific Railroad. He...
Shut up about that E.H. Harriman stuff
and open up.
What's going on?
We got a patriot in there.
That's young Woodcock.
He's awful dedicated.
Woodcock?
Yes, sir.
You know who we are?
You're the Hole-In-The-Wall
Gang, Mr. Cassidy.
I understand that,
but Mr. E.H. Harriman
himself give me this job.
I got to do my best.
Your best don't include
getting yourself killed.
Dynamite's ready.
Mr. E.H. Harriman himself
had the confidence...
Open the door, or that's it.
You think E.H. Harriman
would get himself killed for you,
Woodcock?
I work for Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific Railroad,
and he entrusted me...
Hey, Woodcock.
Woodcock, you all right?
Hey.
Hmm?
Whatever Harriman's
paying you ain't enough.
There ain't what I'd call
a fortune in there, Butch.
Well, just so we come out ahead.
That's the main thing.
The
Hole-In-The-Wall Gang
just robbed the Flyer
right outside of our town,
so that makes it our responsibility
to get out there and get after them.
You'll have to bring your own horses.
How many of you can bring your own guns?
How many of you will want
me to supply you with guns?
Well... come on now.
I think it's up to us to
do something, don't you?
What's the point?
They're probably halfway
to Hole-In-The-Wall
already.
That's exactly why we have got to hurry.
If we mount up right now
and get out there after them,
maybe we can head them off.
If we did that, they'd kill us.
We don't want to let
them get away with this.
Boy, I just eat this up with a spoon.
All right, youse two,
I want you at my party.
What party?
I'm losing my piano player.
He's going off to fight the war.
What war?
The war with the Spanish.
Remember the Maine.
Who can forget it?
I'm giving him a send-off. so come on.
Goodbye, Dolly
I must leave you...
When I was a kid,
I always thought I would grow up
to be a hero.
It's too late now.
Why'd you say something like that?
You didn't have to say
something like that.
You want me to go alone
and fight the
Hole-In-The-Wall Gang?
That's fine with me.
If you want your kids
to know you let me,
that's fine with me,
but I don't think that's what you want.
Is it?
Why don't we enlist,
go fight the Spanish?
You and me in the war.
We got a lot of things going for us...
experience, maturity, leadership.
I'll bet we end up officers.
I'd be Major Parker.
Parker?
Yeah. That's my real name.
Robert Leroy Parker.
No fooling?
No.
Mine's Longbaugh.
No fooling.
Long what?
Harry Longbaugh.
So you'd be Major Longbaugh.
What do you say?
You just keep thinking, Butch.
That's what you're good at.
But you're not frightened.
No, sir.
You have got respect for me,
and I have got respect for you.
That's why you and you and you
are riding with me. Am I right?
Well, what do you say?
I say this.
I say, ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, friends and enemies,
meet the future!
The future what?
The future mode of transportation
for this weary Western world.
Now, I'm not going to make
a lot of extravagant claims.
Sure, it'll change your
whole life for the better,
but that's all.
What the hell do you think you're doing?
You got the crowd together,
so I thought I'd do a little selling.
I'm trying to raise a posse here.
A short presentation.
The horse is dead.
This item sells itself.
Are you going to listen
to him or come with me?
Butch, Fanny says to come into her party
right now.
No oats, no mess, no kicks, no bites,
no running away, no
stepping on your foot.
Well, I think I'll get saddled up
and go looking for a woman.
Good hunting.
Shouldn't take more
than a couple of days.
I'm not picky...
as long as she's smart,
pretty...
sweet...
gentle, and...
tender and refined...
lovely...
carefree.
Aah!
Keep going, teacher lady.
It's O.K. Don't mind me. Keep on going.
Let down your hair.
Shake your head.
Do you know what I wish?
That once you'd get here on time.
You are mine, Etta Place.
Mine.
You hear me?
All mine.
Your soft white flesh is mine.
Soft...
white...
bwhaa!
Meet the future.
Do you know what you're doing?
Theoretically.
Aah!
Don't ever hit your mother with a shovel
It leaves a dull impression on her mind
Raindrops keep fallin' on my head
And just like the guy
Whose feet are too big for his bed
Nothin' seems to fit
Those raindrops are fallin' on my head
They keep fallin'
So I just did me some talkin' to the sun
And I said I didn't like
the way he got things done
Sleepin' on the job
Those raindrops are fallin' on my head
They keep fallin'
But there's one thing
I know
The blues they sent to meet me
Won't defeat me
It won't be long
Till happiness
Steps up to greet me
Raindrops keep fallin' on my head
But that doesn't mean
My eyes will soon be turnin' red
Cryin's not for me
'Cause I'm never gonna stop the rain
By complainin'
Because I'm free
Nothin's worryin' me
Raindrops are fallin' on my head
But that doesn't mean
My eyes will soon be turnin' red
Cryin's not for me
'Cause I'm never gonna stop the rain
By complainin'
Because I'm free
Nothin's worryin' me
You've come to get him for the Flyer?
Would you believe I'm broke already?
Why is there never any money, Butch?
I swear, Etta, I don't know.
I've been working
like a dog all my life,
and I can't get a penny ahead.
Sundance says it's
because you're a soft touch
and always taking expensive vacations,
buying drinks for everyone,
and you're a rotten gambler.
That might have something to do with it.
Butch.
Hmm?
Do you ever wonder if I'd met you first
we'd been the ones to get involved?
We are involved, Etta.
Don't you know that?
You are riding on my bicycle.
In some Arabian countries,
that's the same as being married.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Stealing your woman.
Take her.
Well, you're a romantic bastard.
I'll give you that.
O.K., open up in there.
I work for Mr. E.H. Harriman...
Hey, Woodcock!
Butch?
You O.K.?
Uh, well, sort of.
Hey, that's wonderful.
Let's take a look at you.
Well, now, Butch,
you've got to have more respect for me
than to think I'd fall
for a stunt like that.
You can't want to get blown up again?
Uh, Butch, you know if it were my money,
there's nobody I'd rather have steal it
than you.
But I'm still in the employ
of Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific Railroad.
Start this train!
Get back inside, lady.
I'm not afraid of you.
I'm not afraid of anything.
I'm a grandmother and a female,
and I've got my rights.
We got no time for this.
You can bull the others, but not me.
I've fought whiskey, and
I've fought gambling...
We got no time for this.
What are you doing? Let go!
What are you going to do to her?
Well, leave her alone.
You're after the money,
and the money's in here.
Please! All I want
is for somebody to start this train.
Somebody, please!
Open the door, Woodcock,
or tell her goodbye.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name,
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
What am I going to
tell poor Mr. Harriman?
Woodcock, what'd you have to go and do
something like that for?
Well, Butch, you blew
the last one so easy,
I just had to, um, do something.
Give me that and get some more,
a lot more!
Well, that ought to do it.
Think you used enough
dynamite there, Butch?
Ha ha ha ha.
What the hell is that?
Whatever they're
selling, I don't want it.
Will you leave it?
Come on!
Hyah!
Hey, Butch!
What?
They're very good!
Split up!
How many of'em are following us?
All of'em.
All of'em?
What's the matter with those guys?
Hyah!
I think we lost 'em. Do
you think we lost 'em?
No.
Neither do I. Hyah!
Take our horses out back. Feed 'em good.
Where's Sweetface?
Just inside. Trouble?
Listen, you dirty old man,
I know you're a lying thief
and so do you,
but who'd know it to look at you?
Get yourself out front fast.
You seen us ride through
not five minutes ago.
Do this right,
I'll get you an old dog to kick.
Here, room 9. Top of the stairs.
Hey, you realize you're driving me crazy
staring out the window like that?
I swear, Sweetface can handle it, easy.
He wouldn't dare louse me up.
He's that scared of me.
Hey, kid, how can I give Agnes
the concentration she deserves
with you staring out
the window like that?
Butch, you're really something,
you know that?
Could you be a little more specific
about that, Agnes?
Butch!
O.K., Sweetface, give them a nice smile.
Come on.
That's a nice touch.
I swear, if he told me
I rode out of town 10 minutes ago,
I'd believe him.
And there they go.
No, no.
Don't ask me to stay.
You're the only real man I ever met.
You know that, Butch?
It's not just 'cause of all that money
you got to spend on people. It's you.
The way you're always
looking to see am I happy or not?
A lot of the other girls,
they... they might want you
for when you got lots of money
to spend on people.
Me, I... I don't care about...
clothes and money and jewels...
and furs,
and things like that.
Lots of the other girls do,
but I never did.
I always said, Agnes...
Don't move.
Stand up.
Put your hands up.
Higher.
Now turn around and start...
Get our horses and come on back here.
Hyah!
Get out of here!
Get out!
Go on!
Get out of here, you fat-headed beast!
Come on!
You're the fat-headed
beast. Quit shouting!
Boy, somebody sure trained 'em.
Which way?
Well, it doesn't matter.
I don't know where we've been,
and I've just been there.
They can't follow us. We're safe.
You really think so?
I will if you will.
How long you
figure we've been watching?
Oh, a while.
How long before you figure
they're not after us?
A while longer.
How come you're so talkative?
Just naturally blabby, I guess.
Ohh! I haven't done so much riding
since I quit rustling.
That's a miserable occupation.
Dusk to dawn, no sleep, rotten food.
Hey.
I see it.
Torches you think?
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe lanterns.
They're following our path.
Dead on it.
I couldn't do that. Could you do that?
How can they do that?
Who are those guys?
You sure this'll work?
It'll work.
That's what you said about Sweetface.
This'll work.
Once they divide up,
we take them, no trouble, right?
Maybe.
Boy, for a gunman,
you're one hell of a pessimist.
They ought to get
to where we split up any time.
They're just about there.
How many of them do you
think will come our way?
Oh, I wish we had rifles.
I mean, they got rifles.
But we got surprise on our side, right?
So far, they're doing what we want.
You think we ought to
take them from up here?
Kid, look, you know this
work better than I do.
Is it best here,
or maybe down there,
closer to the trail?
Uh...
Damn it!
They're not going for it.
Who are those guys?
I don't know.
We got to do something and shake them.
Whatever you come up with
is fine with me,
but whatever it is, it better be now!
What are you doing here?
Easy, Ray. Easy.
What the hell do you mean, take it easy?
You promised you'd never
come into my territory.
And we haven't.
Just because we were friendly
doesn't give you the right to break in.
What if we was seen together?
I'm too old to find another job.
At least have the
decency to draw your guns.
Listen, Butch is trying
to tell you something.
All right. What do you want?
A couple of things.
We want to enlist, Ray.
In the army. Right away.
Go fight the Spanish.
Oh, you're crazy. You are crazy.
You are, both of you, crazy!
They'd throw you in jail
for a thousand years each.
Come on, Sundance.
Start trussing my feet.
Here. You seen these before. Come on!
I'm not taking the chance
that someone saw you coming in.
We're serious about this.
You are known outlaws.
We'd quit.
That's the point. Is that on tight?
That's all right.
There's some hankies in the drawer
you can use to gag me.
I swear, this'd work, Ray.
You trust us. The government trusts you.
Anything you tell them
they gotta believe, right?
You've never done a
dishonest thing ever,
and you're pushing 60. We'd quit.
They'd drop the charges against us,
we'd fight till the war is over.
They don't even have
to make us officers.
That's some proposition.
They forget all about the years
of thieving and robbing.
They take you into the army,
which is what you want
in the first place.
There's something out there
that scares you, huh?
But it's too late.
You should've let yourself get killed
while you had the chance.
You may be the biggest
thing to hit this area,
but you're still two-bit outlaws.
I never met a soul more
affable than you, Butch,
or faster than the Kid.
But you're still two-bit outlaws
on the dodge.
It's over! Don't you get that?
Your times is over,
and you're gonna die bloody,
and all you can do is choose where.
I'm sorry,
I'm getting mean in my old age.
Come on. Shut me up, Sundance.
Ah, you're wasting your time.
They can't track us over rock.
Tell them that.
They're beginning to get on my nerves.
Who are those guys?
You remember the time
you, me, and Etta went to Denver
for a vacation?
I'm glad you brought that up, Kid.
That's an important topic,
considering our situation.
The night we went gambling, remember?
We had dinner at the hotel.
Etta had roast beef, and I had chicken.
If I can remember what you had,
I'll die happy.
Look out there.
What?
I got to talking to
some gambler that night.
He told us about an Indian...
full-blooded Indian,
except he used an English name,
Sir... somebody.
Lord Baltimore?
That's right, and he could track anybody
over anything day or night.
So?
The guy on the ground, I think it's him.
No. Baltimore works out of Oklahoma.
He's strictly an Oklahoma man.
I don't know where we are,
but it isn't Oklahoma.
Ah, it couldn't be him.
It couldn't be him.
I guess.
Whoever it is,
it sure the hell is somebody.
Damn it!
Don't they get tired?
Don't they get hungry?
They've gotta be.
Why don't they slow up?
They could even go faster.
At least that'd be a change.
They don't even break formation.
Do something!
Kid.
What?
Who's the best lawman?
Best? How?
You mean toughest or easiest to bribe?
Toughest.
Joe LeFors.
Gotta be.
LeFors never leaves Wyoming. Never.
You know that.
He always wears a white skimmer.
That's how you tell it's Joe LeFors,
'cause he wears a white straw hat.
Look at that guy out front.
Jesus, who are those guys?
Hyah!
Come on now.
Here you go, Kid.
Go on! Get out of here! Go on!
What if they don't follow the horse?
You're the brains, Butch.
You'll think of something.
Damn it!
The way I figure it,
we can either fight or give.
If we give, we go to jail.
I've been there already.
If we fight,
they can stay where they are
and starve us out...
or go for position, shoot us.
Might even get a rock slide started.
What else can they do?
They could surrender to us,
but I wouldn't count on that.
They're going for position, all right.
Better get ready.
Kid, the next time I say
let's go someplace like Bolivia,
let's go someplace like Bolivia.
Next time.
Ready?
No. We'll jump.
Like hell we will.
No. It'll be O.K.
if the water's deep enough
and we don't get squished to death.
They'll never follow us.
How do you know?
Would you jump that
if you didn't have to?
I have to, and I'm not gonna.
We got to. Otherwise we're dead.
Come on.
Just one clear shot...
that's all I want.
I want to fight them!
They'll kill us.
Maybe.
You want to die?
Do you?
All right, I'll jump first.
No.
Then you jump first.
No, I said.
What's the matter?
I can't swim!
Why, you crazy?
The fall will probably kill you.
Oh-oh...
ohhh...
shiiiit!
Hang on to me.
You're drowning me!
I can't help it. I can't swim.
You're choking me!
I can't swim!
I'm telling you, if I drown,
I swear to God I'll kill you.
Never said I was a great swimmer.
Oh! You're choking me!
Oh! I'm choking!
Let go of me.
I'm choking!
Let go of my throat.
The papers said they had you.
Was it LeFors? Did they say?
Joe LeFors?
I think so.
And their tracker?
Tracker?
Was it Lord Baltimore?
I think so.
The paper's inside.
You got enough to feed us?
Don't you know I do?
They said you were dead.
Don't make a big thing out of it.
No. Make a big thing out of it.
Hey.
It was Baltimore and LeFors.
You know who else?
Who?
Jeff Carr, George Hiatt...
Hiatt?
T.T. Kelliher.
We lucked out getting away.
You know that?
Why would these guys join up
and take after us, though?
Forget it. Bunch like that
won't stay together long.
They will...
if Mr. Harriman has his way.
Who?
Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific Railroad.
He resents the way you've
been picking on him,
so he's outfitted a special train
and hired special employees.
You've been avoiding them for two days.
It's really sort of flattering
if you want to think about it that way.
A setup like that costs more
than we ever took.
Apparently he can afford it.
That crazy Harriman.
That's bad business.
How long do you think
I'd stay in operation
if every job cost me money?
If he'd just pay me what he's spending
to make me stop robbing him,
I'd stop robbing him.
You probably inherited
every penny you got!
Inherited guys,
what the hell do they know?
You say they were hired permanent?
No. Just till they kill you.
That means they're
still after us, Butch,
and it's going to be the same thing
all over again.
They'll show up here...
sooner or later.
Hey, Etta.
I'll get you some more.
Butch and me have been
talking it all over.
Wherever the hell Bolivia is,
that's where we're off to.
We'll go down there and play it safe,
maybe keep our hand in a little bit.
Butch speaks some Spanish.
I can wrestle with a menu O.K.
And you speak it good.
And it'd be good cover
going with a woman.
No one expects it.
Then we could travel safer.
What I'm saying is,
if you want to go,
I won't stop you,
but the minute you start to whine
or make a nuisance,
I don't care where we are,
I'm dumping you flat.
Don't sugarcoat it like that, Kid.
Tell her straight.
I'm 26, and I'm single
and a schoolteacher,
and that's the bottom of the pit.
And the only excitement I've known
is here with me now.
So I'll go with you,
and I won't whine,
and I'll sew your socks,
and I'll stitch you when you're wounded,
and I'll do anything you ask of me
except one thing.
I won't watch you die.
I'll miss that scene,
if you don't mind.
The future's all yours,
you lousy bicycles.
Well, you know, it could be worse.
You get a lot more for
your money in Bolivia.
I checked on it.
What could they have here
that you could possibly want to buy?
Jeez, all Bolivia can't look like this.
How do you know?
This might be the garden spot
of the whole country.
People may travel hundreds of miles
just to get to this spot
where we're standing now.
This might be the
Atlantic City, New Jersey,
of all Bolivia for all you know.
I know more about Bolivia
than you know about
Atlantic City, New Jersey,
I can tell you that.
Aha!
You do, huh?
I was born there.
I was born in New Jersey...
brought up there, so...
I didn't know that.
The total tonnage of what you don't know
is enough to shatter...
We're not accomplishing
as much as we might.
Listen, your job is to back me up,
because you'd starve without me.
And you, your job is to shut up.
He'll feel a lot better
after he's robbed a couple of banks.
Ha ha ha ha!
Bolivia.
Hell, it's just a bank
like any other bank.
You got to move in slowly,
check out everything.
The thing to remember...
Don't tell me how to rob a bank.
I know how to rob a bank.
A few dark clouds
appear on your horizon,
and you just go all
to pieces, don't you?
Buenos das, seores.
Les puedo servir en algo?
Ordenen para atenderlos
por favor inmediatamente.
Quieren hacer algn depsito?
Quieren abrir una cuenta?
Bien, el cajero los
atienda inmediatamente.
Los atendemos por todo.
Seor?
Adis.
This is a robbery.
Esto es un robo.
This is supposed to
be a unison recitation.
Why do I have to do any of this?
He's the one
who claimed he knew the language.
Your line of work requires
a specialized vocabulary.
I got nervous. I forgot
the words. Shoot me.
You've had worse ideas lately.
Raise your hands.
Uh... las manos arriba.
Raise them.
Arriba.
All of you back against the wall.
Todos ustedes, um...
arrsmense a la pared.
Give me the money.
This is not going to work,
and we're going to be up all night
until you get this.
Now give me the money.
It's on the tip of my tongue, Etta.
I swear it.
Butch, are you still thinking in there?
What the hell else is there to do?
Try this one.
Where is the safe? Open it.
Dnde es...
Uh, that's a hard one.
Dnde est la caja? brala!
That's very good, Butch.
You're a good teacher. Etta.
Esto es un robo!
Manos a...
Manos, um...
Manos arriba!
They got them up! Skip down!
- Arriba!
- Skip on down!
Todos ustedes arrsmense a la pared.
They're against the wall already!
Dnde es...
Oh, you're so damn smart,
you read it.
A goddamn crib sheet.
You almost blew it.
You sure didn't help much.
You can't do anything
without a crib sheet.
For God's sake, don't drop the money!
I won't drop the money!
Voy a traer el comisario.
S, vamos.
Ay, nombre.
Evarista.
Evarista qu?
Seor comandante,
dos hombres acometen y asaltan el banco.
Dos yanquis y una muchacha
se fueron por la caada.
Se llevaron mi pistola y todo el dinero.
Vmanos!
A caballos!
Isn't that a pretty sight?
Well, we're back in
business, boys and girls,
just like the old days.
Let's stay here and get him
and be done with it.
But what if we lose?
We saw him with two guys.
What if he's got 20?
You don't know for sure it's LeFors.
I'm a hell of a guesser.
He can't arrest you.
It's a foreign country.
He can't take you back.
He's not going to take anybody back.
He's going to wait for us
to pull another job
and then hunt us down.
Let's finish it now, Butch,
one way or the other.
He's got to wait for us
to pull another job.
Well, what if there isn't another job?
He can't arrest us,
and he can't take us out of here.
We'll drive him crazy.
We'll outlast the bastard.
We'll go straight.
So you want jobs.
You're from the U.S. of A.,
and you are seeking after employment.
Well, you couldn't have picked
a more out of the way place
in all of Bolivia,
I'll tell you that.
Gracias, Jess.
Ordinarily you've got to wait
to work for Percy Garrison,
but this ain't ordinarily.
Bingo.
You mean there are jobs.
Yes, there are jobs.
There are lots of jobs.
Don't you want to know why?
Yeah, why?
Damn it.
Because I cannot promise to pay you.
Don't you want to know why?
O.K., why?
On account of the payroll thieves,
fellow citizens.
You see, every mine around
gets its payroll
from La Paz.
And every mine around
gets its payroll held up.
Some say it's the Bolivian Bandits,
and some say
that it's the bandidos yanquis.
Could I see that?
Mm-hmm.
Fairly nice-looking piece.
Can you hit anything?
Sometimes.
Hit that.
No, no, son. No, son.
I just want to know,
can you shoot your piece?
Shoot.
Damn it.
Can I move?
Move?
What the hell you mean, move?
I'm better when I move.
Yeah.
Well, considering that I'm desperate
and you're just what I'm looking for,
on top of which
you stem from the U.S. of A.,
we start tomorrow morning.
You mean we got jobs.
Payroll guard.
Damn.
Vmanos a trabajar!
Hey, Chucho!
Chucho!
Oh, don't you remember
Sweet Betsy from Pike
Crossed the high mountains
With her lover Ike
Two yoke of oxen
And a big yalla dog
Tall Shanghai rooster
And one spotted hog
Toodle-dang
hoodie di-do
Doodle-dang hoodie ay
Toodle-dang
hoodie di-do
Doodle-dang hoodie ay
Shanghai ran off
And the cattle all died
Last piece of bacon...
I think they're in the trees up ahead.
In the bushes on the left.
They're in the trees up ahead.
You take the trees,
I'll take the bushes.
Will you two beginners cut it out?
Well, we're just trying
to spot an ambush.
Morons.
I've got morons on my team.
Nobody is going to rob us
going down the mountain.
We have got no money
When we have got the money
on the way back,
then you can sweat.
Bingo.
Move it out!
Move it!
We hit this place in June, didn't we?
Jones!
Give me a hand over here.
Who am I, Smith or Jones?
Live.
About a half hour more,
and we can start to worry...
as soon as we get
to that pass up there.
We'll be all right till then.
They might try something here.
No. Better cover up there.
You got to relax, you fellas.
You got to get used to Bolivian ways.
You got to go easy.
Damn it!
Like I do.
Of course, you probably think I'm crazy,
but I'm not.
Bingo.
I'm colorful.
That's what happens
when you live 10 years alone in Bolivia.
You get colorful.
Where are they?
I can't see them.
Let's get out of here.
Tell them to leave the money and go.
Dijen el dinoro...
Dinero... and, uh...
y vayanese.
Que dejemos el dinero y nos vayamos?
Tell them we were hired
to take it back. It's our job.
Tell them the money isn't ours.
El dinero...
no es nuestro.
No, ya no es de ustedes.
Ahora es de nosotros.
Claro.
We'll try telling them again.
It's our job. The money isn't ours.
El dinero no es nuestro.
Lo necesitamos.
Tambin nosotros necesitamos.
What do you think?
Not so good.
Can you take the two on the right?
Kid, there's something I
think I ought to tell you.
I never shot anybody before.
One hell of a time to tell me.
Try for the two on the right
dead center.
That way, if you miss a little,
you'll still hit something.
Go.
Please.
Qu?
Por favor.
Por favor?
Aah!
Well, we've gone straight.
What'll we try now?
There are other ways of
going straight, you know.
There are other ways of going straight.
There's farming.
We could buy a place.
I don't know how to farm.
What about a ranch, then?
I don't know.
The last time we tried ranching
was during our rustling days.
Even then,
we weren't much good at it.
It's hard. Hours are brutal.
No, you got to be a kid
to start a ranch.
Hey.
Hmm?
I might go back ahead of you.
You mean home?
I was thinking of it.
Whatever you want, Etta.
Maybe I'll go.
Hey.
Hmm?
Etta's thinking of, uh,
maybe going home ahead of us.
Whatever she wants.
I'll go, then.
Manos arriba!
How much you got?
It's hardly worth it. Alpoca mine.
I tell you, no more jungle work for me.
You're getting to be an old maid.
Keep your old maid remarks to yourself.
I'll work in the city, in the mountains,
but from now on jungle work is out.
Bandidos yanquis?
Mm-hmm.
Tell them to be quiet.
What's the word?
Quietas.
I tell you,
the jungle's a better
cover for payrolls.
Kid, I got a right to my opinion,
and in my opinion,
there are snakes in the jungle.
I don't work around snakes.
What is this place?
I don't know.
San Vincente, I think.
Comer?
Si, Seor.
Pasen. Juan, ven.
Llvate los caballos.
I don't enjoy jungles.
I don't enjoy swamps.
I don't like snakes.
I don't much care for night work.
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
Capitn! Capitn!
Capitn, all en la plaza,
hay una mula de las minas de Alpoca.
Las minas de Alpoca?
S, s. All estn.
Dos hombres la acaban de traer.
Estn comiendo en el
restaurante de mi pap.
El guisado est delicioso.
Para chuparse los dedos.
Si quieren mas, es la
especialidad de la casa,
si quieren mas,
no tengan pena y dganmelo.
Yo estoy aqu para servirles.
Agradezco la visita de tan
distinguidos caballeros.
Muchas gracias.
Para servirles.
S.
The specialty of the house,
and it's still moving.
Well, that settles it.
This place gets no more of my business.
Hey.
What?
What do you think? I
bet it's just one guy.
Don't you get sick of
being right all the time?
Reloading.
That's all I got.
We're going to run out
unless we can get to that
mule and get some more.
I'll go.
This is no time for
bravery. I'll let you.
Loaded.
Hell!
I'm the one that has to go.
Why you?
'Cause I could never give you cover.
You can cover me.
You can see I'm right, can't you?
You go.
Yeah, why am I always so damn smart?
Here.
Go.
O.K.
Ah!
Is... Is that what
you call giving cover?
Is that what you call running?
If I knew you were going to stroll...
You never could shoot,
not from the very beginning.
And you are all mouth.
Jefe, llega el ejrcito.
Mi capitn.
Dnde estn?
All en la plaza.
Cuntos hombres son?
Dos hombres.
Dos hombres?
Mi capitn, por favor...
Dos?
Bandidos yanquis.
Bandidos yanquis, eh?
S, mi capitn.
Hmm.
Sargento Rico,
desmonten 20 hombres
y vayan con el teniente.
I've got a great idea
where we should go next.
I don't want to hear it.
You'll change your mind.
Shut up!
O.K., O.K.
Your ideas got us here.
Forget it!
I never want to hear
another of your ideas.
All right.
O.K.
Australia.
I figured secretly you wanted to know,
so I told you.
Australia.
That's your great idea?
Oh, boy, it's the latest in...
in a long line.
Australia's no better than here.
Aw, that's all you know.
Name me one thing.
They speak English in Australia.
They do?
That's right, smart guy.
So we wouldn't be foreigners.
They got horses in Australia.
They got thousands of
miles we could hide out in.
And a good climate, nice beaches.
You could learn to swim.
No!
Swimming isn't important.
What about the banks?
They're easy.
Easy, ripe, and luscious.
The banks or the women?
Well, once you've got
one, you've got the other.
It's a long way, isn't it?
Aw! Everything's got
to be perfect with you.
I don't want to get there
and find out it stinks.
At least think about it.
All right.
I'll think about it.
Hey.
When we get outside...
and we get to the horses,
just remember one thing.
Hey, wait a minute.
What?
You didn't see LeFors
out there, did you?
LeFors?
No.
Oh, good.
For a moment there,
I thought we were in trouble.
Fuego!