Merry Christmas!
- Whats your name, little boy?
- Eric.
What do you want for Christmas, Eric? Hm?
A Johnny Lightning 500.
- You been good, little boy?
- Yeah.
Good. You like Santa Claus? Huh?
Now, you like Santa Claus, right?
(*jukeboxmusic)
Lets sing a little song. Jingle Bells.
* Jingle bells, jingle bells
* Jingle all the way
* Oh, what fun it is...
Get up.
Get up! And hold em up.
- Hold it!
- Freeze!
Jimmy, watch it. Hes got a knife.
- Hold it, you son of a bitch!
- No, no!
Thats enough. Dont kill him. Thats enough!
- Get up!
- Come on, give me a break!
- l aint done nothin, man.
- Break, your ass.
- Come on.
- Get up!
Will you stop it? Stop it!
- Jimmy.
- Let me bust him. l wanna bust him.
- l wanna bust him.
- Let me talk to him. Let me talk to him!
- You got a friend here. You got a friend.
- You gonna tell us who your man is?
Whens the last time you picked your feet?
Whos your connection, Willie?
- Answer him!
- No, no, man!
ls it Joe the barber?
Thats who it is, isnt it?
Dont give us any shit.
Whats Joes last name?
- l dont know, man!
- Give him a chance. Just give him a chance.
All l know is he lives on 125th Street, man.
Above the barber shop.
What side ofthe street does he live on?
North or south?
- l dont know what youre talking about.
- What side ofthe street does he live on?
- Whens the last time you picked your feet?
- Whats he talkin about?
l got a man in Poughkeepsie wants to talk
to you. You ever been in Poughkeepsie?
- Hey, man, give me a break.
- Come on, say it. Let me hear you say it.
Have you ever been to Poughkeepsie? Youve
been to Poughkeepsie? l wanna hear it!
- Yes, l... lve been to Poughkeepsie.
- You sat on the edge ofthe bed.
You took offyour shoes
and picked your feet, didnt you?
- Now say it!
- Yes.
All right. You put a shiv in my partner.
You know what that means, goddamnit?
All winter l gotta listen to him
gripe about his bowling scores.
lm gonna bust your ass for those three bags,
then lm gonna nail you for picking your feet.
Merci.
Bonjour.
Cestmerveilleux, chri.
Tu me gtes. Je taime.
Cestpour toi, chri.
Merci, chrie.
Need a little help there?
- You dumb guinea.
- How the hell did l know he had a knife?
- Never trust a nigger.
- He couldve been white.
- Never trust anyone. Goin sick?
- No.
- Are you goin sick?
- No!
- What dyou say we go to Chez for a drink?
- Jimmy, lm beat. lm gonna go home.
All right, all right. One drink.
- Drink this.
- Whip it out.
* How many times have l been downhearted
* Looked up and saw him
smiling like a shiny dime
* And hoped that he would stay
and tell me why he was so happy
* lf he had the time
* Oh, l wish there was a way to race him
* Catch a flying horse and chase him
* Everybodys goin to the moon
* Me and you, everybodys goin
* ltll be quite soon
* lts customary in songs like this
* To use a word like spoon
* By the light ofthe silvery
* Well take a flight to the silvery
* Everybodys goin to the moon
* How many times, while looking down
has he heard us singing songs
* And wondered who we were
* Hey!
* Then envied us because
the lady in the moon is gone
* And now he misses her
* And then he wondered to himself
now why is it no one ever pays a visit?
* Everybody gets to go to the moon
* Yeah, yeah, yeah
* Everybody gets to go, itll be quite soon
* Now its customary in songs like this
* To use a word like June
* By the light ofthe silvery
* Well take a flight to the silvery
* You know, everybodys goin to the moon
* Now, isnt it a miracle
* That we are the generation
* Thats gonna touch that shiny bubble
with our own two hands
* And its got to make you glad to be alive
* Yes, its got to make you proud to be a man
l make at least two junk connections
at that far table over in the corner.
The guy in the striped shirt and tie combo,...
..l know him too.
l thought we came here to buy me a drink.
(Jimmy) Who is that clown?
lts a policy guy from Queens.
- (Jimmy) Dig the creep comin to the table.
- (partner) lts Jewish Lucky.
He dont look the same
without numbers across his chest.
That table is definitely wrong.
* lts customary in songs like this
* To use a word like spoon
* By the light ofthe silvery
* Fly to the silvery
* Everybodys goin to the moon
(applause)
More!
What about the last ofthe big-time spenders?
Do you make him?
No. You?
(Jimmy) Hes spreadin it around
like the Russians are in Jersey.
Oh, yes.
What do you say we stick around
and give him a tail?
Come on. Just for fun.
Give who a tail?
The greaser with the blonde.
What for? You wanna play
hide the salami with his old lady?
Yeah.
Miss, can l ask you
about those boots? Theyre...
Monica.
- Who in the hells that?
- Who keeps score?
(Jimmy) Hey.
- (Jimmy) Kissy devil, isnt he? Look at him.
- Well, theyre all cousins. You know that.
Yeah, say goodbye. Come on.
Whats he got now?
- Hudson Terraplane, thats what he got.
- No, no.
- Easy.
- OK.
Go to work.
(Jimmy) Cloudy, lll lay odds
he takes us to dago town.
Well take him, Popeye. Hes nothin.
(Cloudy) Seven oclock in the morning.
l dont believe it.
(Jimmy) Relax. Youre havin fun, aint you?
lfthats not a drop, lll open
a charge for you at Bloomingdales.
Make it Alexanders. l like the toy department.
Hes comin back.
Pass him. Make a left.
Alain.
(Cloudy) Ourfriends name is Boca.
Salvatore Boca. B-O-C-A.
They callhim Sal. Hes a sweetheart.
He was picked up on suspicion
ofarmedrobbery. Nowget this.
Three years ago he tries to hold up Tiffanys
on Fifth Avenue in broad daylight.
He couldve got two anda haifto fiive,
but Tiffanys wouldntprosecute.
Also, downtown theyre prettysure he pulled
offa contract on a guynamedDeMarco.
- (Jimmy) Howabouthis oldlady?
- Hernames Angie. Shes a fastfiilly.
She drewa suspended
forshoplifting a yearago.
Shes onlya kid.
19, according to the marriage licence.
(Jimmy) 19 goin on 50.
- What else?
- Hes had the store a yearanda haif.
Takes in a fastseven granda year.
So whats he doin with two cars
anda tab at the Chez?
The LTDs in his wifes name.
The Cometbelongs to his brotherLou.
Hes a trainee at the garbagemans
school on Wards lsland.
He did time a couple ofyears ago -
assaultandrobbery.
Black Cadillac.
New Jersey plates.
RWN-264. l know that one cat. We saw him
outside the Pike Slip lnn the other day.
l want a blouse like that for my girlfriend,
but you could model it.
Better not let my husband hear that.
l dont care if he hears it.
Will you do it for me?
OK. How much are you gonna pay?
- $50 an hour.
- 50 an hour?!
- lll do it. $200.
- No, cant afford it.
lll call you later. Bye-bye.
Hey, its 1.30. l didnt expect you till two.
- You work around here?
- Across the street.
(Jimmy) Thats the third time
hes come here this week.
- You gotanything on this building?
- Clean. l checked the tenantlist.
RememberDon Ameche, the actor?
He lives here.
Oh, yeah, andsomebody else.
- Does the name Joel Weinstock ring a bell?
- Youre kidding.
No, sir. He lives righthere.
He was the bank on the shipment
out ofMexico three years ago.
Yeah, so lhear.
Hes goin to Wards lsland.
Well be spotted. Whys he doin that?
Maybe hes gonna go down
and see his brother.
Well, maybe its another drop.
Well, he gets a free ride.
(*jukeboxmusic)
(music stops)
All right, Popeyes here!
Get your hands on your heads, get offthe bar
and get on the wall! Come on, move, move!
Come on, move out! Face the wall.
Turn around there. Move!
- Hands outta your pockets.
- Turn around.
Turn around. Get on the wall.
Hey, did you drop that? Pick it up.
- Pick it up! Come on, move!
- (Cloudy) What are you lookin at?
All right, bring it here.
Get your hands outta your pockets.
- Whats my name?
- Doyle.
- What?
- Mr Doyle.
Come here. Dyou pick your feet?
Do you...? Get over there.
Get your hands on your head.
- Hold em up.
- We told you people we were comin back.
Were gonna keep comin back
until you clean this bar up.
Keep your eye on your neighbour.
lf he drops somethin, it belongs to you.
What is this, a fuckin hospital here? Huh?
Turn around there, fella.
What have we got here?
This belong to you? Huh?
Stand up there, noddy.
Get your hands on your fuckin head.
- You wanna take a ride there, fat man?
- Oh, bullshit.
Huh?
Pay attention.
Were gonna ask questions later.
(Cloudy) Turn around.
All right, shut up there. Shut up!
Anybody want a milkshake?
All right, come over here. You and you.
Hey, whiskers! Come over here.
Move ass when l call you! You!
Come on, you, baldie. Come on, move.
All right, put it on the bar.
- Get it on the bar!
- Get the hell in there.
- Put your hands on your head.
- All of it.
Smart ass, you dropped somethin. Pick it up.
You want that hand broken? Get it up there.
What else you got here, huh?
Turn around.
Youre under arrest. That goes for you too.
Get in that phone booth. Move!
Get in there. Face the wall, put your hands
against the wall and lock yourself in.
Hey, you!
Haircut! Where are you going?
- You talkin to me, baby?
- Yeah, lm talkin to you! Come here!
- Whats happening?
- Where you been?
- ln there.
- Can you stand a toss?
- Sure, lm clean.
- You use shit?
No, man. Who are you, Dick Tracy
or somebody? l said l was clean.
- lm not gonna get stuck, am l?
- lm clean!
- lf l do, you know what happens.
- Yeah. l said lm clean.
Get off! lll break your motherfuckin ass!
Give me a nickel.
Give me a nickel. Come on!
l told you lm clean. What the fuck
you wanna come down on me like that for?
This is goddamn full of shit.
- Hows everything?
- Everythings everything, baby.
Theres nothin out there. lts all milk.
- There aint nothin around. Nobodys holdin.
- l got a name for you. Sal Boca. Brooklyn.
- Boca?
- Yeah. B-O-C-A.
- Never heard of him.
- What about his wife Angie?
Doesnt register.
Theres been some talk, though.
- About what?
- A shipment.
Comin in this week, the week after.
Everybodys gonna get well.
- Well, whos bringin it?
- Who knows?
- Where do you want it?
- Huh?
- Oh, shit. This side.
Beat it!
lm gonna check on this address.
lfthey dont know you, its your ass.
- l thought l told you to stand there!
- Get that hair down before Saturday.
Were goin now. Goodbye!
Move ass. Tell everybody
well be back in an hour.
Great, but you belong in
Bedford-Stuyvesant, not Ridgewood.
Why dont you detach us? Give us a shot, at
least till we find out iftheres anything here.
Everybody wants Weinstock. Maybe heres
the lead were looking for. We deserve this.
You couldnt burn a three-time loser
with this garbage.
The man has done absolutely nothin.
Youll wind up in an entrapment rap.
Brooklyn is loaded with guys that own
candy stores, two cars and go to nightclubs.
You put this hustler together with Weinstock
and maybe we got a big score.
Big score, my ass! At best
hes sellin nickel-and-dime bags.
l wouldnt be infringin on your coffee break
if l thought it was a nickel-and-dimer.
Your hunches have backfired before, Doyle,
or have you forgotten about that already?
Jesus Christ, Jimmy,
whats happened to you guys?
Every year you lead the narcotic bureau in
arrests. What was it, over 100 again last year?
Terrific. But who? What did you bring in?
A high-school kid in short pants
that had a twitch?
You grab a bellhop because
hes got three joints in his sock?
Walter, we got the information
theres no shit on the street, right?
lts like a desert full ofjunkies
waiting to get well.
Goddamnit, this could be it. This little
candy-store guy, hes put on a big show...
..in a club with no narcotics connections.
They were all over him.
And after working a day and night,
we tail him to Brooklyn.
And we sat on him for practically a week, and
who do we come up with? Joel Weinstock.
Now you gotta let us have it.
Do you believe all this crap?
l go with my partner.
- Whatll it take?
- A wire.
No, two wires.
One on the store, one on the house.
You know l have to get a court order
for a wire tap, dont you?
- But youll try.
- We know you can do it, Walt.
Popeye, you still picking your feet
in Poughkeepsie?
Jentends parler de a.
Je narrive pas  y croire.
Alorsje vais un peuparlerpourmoi.
Jai tendance ... penser
mes propres problmes, enfiin...
Monsieur Devereaux, is this
your first trip to New York?
- Yes, its my first.
- Why did you choose to come by ship?
The next several weeks
will be very difficult for me,...
..and the ocean is the only place where
the telephone isnt ringing all the time.
Do you agree with the recent survey finding...
..that showed that Mayor Lindsay
was the sexiest man in the world?
(interpreter translates into French)
Tout fait, oui.
Heres the warrants and the court order
for the wire tap. Judge gave you 60 days.
Mulderig and Kleinll sit in for the feds.
Theyll make all the buys.
Make sure you keep em informed
of everything that goes down.
You know Doyle there, dont you?
Yeah, l know Popeye. His brilliant hunches
cost the life of a good cop.
lfthis is the way youre comin in on this,
why not stay home and save us a lot of grief?
- Because thats my opinion.
- Shove it up your ass.
Whatever.
Bill, do me a favour, give them a chance.
He came in with a little basic information.
You worked with him, had some trouble,
but dont get off on the wrong foot.
- You have any problems, come to me.
- Simonson, just keep off my back.
Just try and cool it with him. lfyou have
any problems, come to me. lll handle him.
- lll be happy to work with him.
- Hes a good cop.
- Hes got good hunches once in a while.
- Fine. Just keep him off my back.
(TV) Floridas MackelBrothers
invite you tojoin the great escape.
You can saygoodbye to airpollution,
commuting, high prices, rising taxes...
..and cold, depressing winters.
MackelBrothers willshowyou the way
to Florida andfresh, clean air.
Warm andsunnyyear-round weather
in a home thatyoullbe proud to own.
Call MackelBrothers rightnow...
Popeye.
- What?
- lts me, Cloudy. Open the door.
l cant.
- What do you mean, you cant? You all right?
- Yeah, lm all right.
Let yourself in, will you?
What happened?
(Doyle) That crazy kid.
She locked me up with my own cuffs.
- Wheres the keys?
- Over there.
(woman gasps)
Hi there.
Anybody hurt in this wreck?
l thought l told you to get
plastic folders for this stuff.
Your scrapbook is like you.
- A mess.
- Give me my pants, will you?
Come on.
- Did you get the warrants?
- Yeah.
l also got two feds. Mulderig and Klein.
What do we need those pricks for?
Because our departments got
about 908 bucks to make buys,...
..and they can get all they want
from Uncle Sap. Hello.
These yours, darling?
(whistle)
30 over here for this gentleman. Can l get 35?
- 35 here.
- 35 over here. Can l get 38?
- Yeah, right here.
- 38 over here. How about 40?
- 40.
- 40 over here. l got 40. Can l get 41? 41?
40 once, 40 twice.
Sold to the gentleman for $40.
We come now to the next number: 42399.
- 10 bucks.
- l got $10 over here. Do l hear 12?
- 12.
- 12 over here, 12. Can l get 14?
- 14.
- 14 over here. How about 16? Can l get 16?
- 16.
- 18.
18 over there. How about 20?
- 20.
- $20 over here. How about 22?
- 22.
- l got 22 over here. Can l get 24?
- 24.
- 24 over here. How about 25? 25, anybody?
- 25.
- l got 25. Can l get 26? Can l get 26?
25 once, 25 twice.
Sold to the gentleman for 25.
Every car sold here...
- (Angie) Where are you?
- (Sal) Taking care ofbusiness.
What do you mean, taking care ofbusiness?
lts aftermidnight.
You know... lhad to meet
some people tonight.
Well, fiinish allyourmeetinpeople andget
back here now. Andbring a pizza with you.
Where am lgonna get
a pizza this time ofnight?
Well, try, OK?
l dontknow where lm gonna
fiinda pizzajoint open.
- Sal?
- Yeah.
Dontforget- anchovies.
- (man) Salvatore?
- (Sal) Oh, yes. Yeah, yeah. Hello.
- (Cloudy) Who is it?
- Yeah, this is Sal. Howare you?
- Sounds like a foreigner.
- You meetme Wednesdayat the hotel, OK?
- Sounds French.
- Willl expectyou?
- (Sal) Yeah. What time?
- 12 oclock. Yes?
(Sal) Yeah. Yes.
Strictly small potatoes.
You sure can pick em, Doyle.
Still wearing your gun on your ankle?
Someone told me the reason
why you do that is...
..when you meet a chick
and you rub up against her,...
..she cant tell youre a cop.
l said its bullshit. lts gotta be
a fast-draw gimmick or somethin.
Bill, why dont you knock it off, huh?
Hes gettin too far ahead.
Youre gonna lose him.
(carhorns)
(driver) For Christs sake, move the car!
(Doyle) What the hell is goin on here?
Klein, this is Cloudy. Do you read me?
Klein, this is Cloudy. Do you read me?!
Come in, for Christs sakes!
This is Cloudy. Do you readme?
Listen, we losthim on the bridge.
Right. l got him.
Hes headin north on East River Drive.
- Excuse me.
(Doyle) You take Sal. lll take the beard.
There goes Sal.
- You want the red or the white?
- Pour it in your ear.
- Yes, sir?
- Yeah, guyjust walked in, whats his name?
lm pretty sure that ones a Frog.
He made me, too.
He lives on four, he went up to six.
Hes cute, real cute.
The other guys a Frog. He checked
into the Edison. Had a hooker sent up.
You should have collared him right there.
- Whos on him?
- Klein.
- How about Sal?
- We put him to bed for the night.
Why dont you do the same, Doyle?
You look like shit.
(Cloudy) Come on.
Look, my partner and l
made this case, you know, originally.
- We dont want any feds screwing it up.
- Case? So far you havent shown me a thing.
You keep shootin your mouth off,
lm gonna knock you right into next week.
- (Cloudy) Knock it off.
- Dont tell me to knock it off.
Cut it out, will ya, for Christs sakes!
Theres nothin goin down. Get some sleep.
Blastoff. 180.
200. Good Housekeeping seal of approval.
210. US government certified.
220. Lunar trajectory.
Junk-of-the-month club. Sirloin steak.
230. Grade-A poison.
Absolute dynamite.
89 per cent pure junk. Best lve ever seen.
lfthe rest is like this,
youll be dealin on this load for two years.
- lts worth the half million?
- How many kilos?
- 60.
- 60 kilos...
Eight big ones a kilo, right? This stuffll
take a seven-to-one hit on the street.
By the time it gets down to nickel bags,
itll be 32 million.
Thank you, Howard. Take whats left
there with you and good night.
Uh-uh. Not that one. The little one.
- l guess we got a deal, huh?
- What we got here, Sal, is a test.
A deal for half a million dollars? Maybe.
Maybe?
Come on, the guys in a hurry. He wants
the bread. He wants to go back to France.
This guys not gonna play games. Look, hes
one ofthe shrewdest cats l ever come across.
What am l, a schmuck? Whats the hurry?
He could see a couple of shows,
visit the top ofthe Empire State Building.
Dontjerk me, Weinstock.
l spent a lot oftime settin this one up.
So what do you want, a badge?
This is your first major-league game, Sal.
One thing l learned: move calmly,
move cautiously, youll never be sorry.
Look, lve been damn careful up to now.
This is why your phone lines are tapped and
the feds are crawlin all over you like fleas.
- Hell take the deal somewhere else.
- Let him take it and find out how easy it is...
..to put together a half a million in cash.
Theres no hurry to do this kind of business.
The stuff is here!
We can make the switch in an hour!
Look, lm tellin you,
hell split ifwe dont move.
This guys got em like that.
Hes everything they say he is.
What about you, Sal?
Are you everything they say you are?
That son of a bitch.
Thank you.
- Hello?
- This is Doyle. lm sittin on Frog One.
Yeah, l know that. We got
the Westbury covered like a tent.
The Westbury, my ass! l got him
on the shuttle at Grand Central.
Now what the hells goin on up there?
l make him comin out ofthe hotel.
He was free as a bird.
What the hell are you talkin about?
Yeah, well, uh...
Listen, l dont care how many
bartenders you got that are sick.
No, lm not workin thatjoint.
Thats right. Same to ya, buddy.
Can l get a grape drink?
Watch the closing doors.
Son of a bitch!
Hi. Can l have a round-trip
ticket to Washington?
- Cash or charge?
- Cash.
Cash is $54. Please print your name
on both tickets before you board the plane.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye. Have a nice flight.
- Yes, sir?
- Round trip to Washington.
- So?
- So everythings goin great.
Terrific. Beautiful.
lll need a few more days, though.
The boys think we oughta cool it for a while,
just to make sure theres no heat.
You must take me for an imbecile.
Why do you think l asked you
to meet me in Washington?
l havent spent five minutes in New York City
without the company of a policeman.
Look, lm levellin with you.
l need a little more time.
My people think we oughta find a better time
to make the switch, thats all.
lt has to be by the end ofthis week.
Look, Charnier, you gotta be reasonable.
lts your problem.
Well, its your problem, too.
So nice to have seen you again.
(arguing)
We found a set ofworks
on the kid driving the sports car.
- His girlfriends in the back. Shes dead.
- Give the car a toss.
- l say we keep sittin on Boca.
- Jimmy, give it up. lts all over with.
lfthere was a deal, its gone down by now.
We blew our warrants and we blew our cover.
Listen, l know the deal hasnt gone down.
l know it. l can feel it. lm dead certain.
Last time you were dead certain,
we ended up with a dead cop.
Break it up! Will you two break it up?
Stop it! Hold on to yourself.
Whats the matter with you?
Jimmy, you wasted two months on this.
No collars are comin in...
..while youre runnin around town
jerkin off! Now go back to work!
Youre off special assignment!
(gunshots)
(screaming)
Get down! Get out! Get outta the area!
Leave her alone! Stay away!
Leave her alone. Theres a sniper up there!
(children crying)
(train approaching)
Hey!
Stop that man! Hes wanted by the police!
- Whats the next stop into the city?
- 25th Avenue.
Hold it!
Police emergency. l need your car.
When am l gonna get it back?
For Christs sake!
Hold it! Stop! Halt!
(screaming)
- Dont stop.
- But...
- Dont stop or lll kill you.
- l gotta stop in the next station.
Touch the brakes and lll blow you in half.
(train horn)
- Whats goin on?
- l dont know. Sit down, buddy. Relax.
Coke! Coke, you all right?
Hey, Coke, you all right?
Dont answer.
- Get back.
- Relax.
Keep going.
Youre not gonna get away with this.
Put the gun down.
Get back!
- Come on, now.
- l said get back!
Stop!
Hold it!
(man) Lets get outta here!
Come on, come on. Shake your ass.
Cant seem to find the damn ticket.
- Wheres the guy?
- Hes gettin my car. Hes in the back.
Thank you.
- Can l help you, sir?
- Yeah.
- You got your ticket?
- l must have dropped mine.
What kinda ticket did you have?
Hes in the brown Lincoln. Foreign plates.
Hes walking towards Front Street.
(Klein) Gothim. Angies parked
overhere in the LTD.
(Cloudy) Cute. You stay with her.
Were gonna sit on the Lincoln.
The cars dirty, Cloudy.
Were gonna sit here all night ifwe have to.
What time is it?
Ten after four.
- Huh?
- Ten after four.
Thats the third time
those guys have been around.
All right, lets hit em. Hit em!
Freeze!
Nobody move! Put your hands in the air!
Stay right there. lfyou move,
lll blow your fuckin head off.
- What the hells that?
- What are you doin? Turn around.
Whos the boss here? Whos runnin this
outfit? You are? What are you doin here?
- Just runnin around.
- Who sent you down here? Dont talk back.
- What are you doin here?
- We saw the car.
We was breaking down the tyres.
Thats all it was.
Lock em up.
Come on, come on!
Nothin but a bunch of lousy spic car thieves!
- Nothin there except a New York City map.
- Are you bullshittin me?
That cars dirty.
Take it in and tear it apart.
(Doyle) Tear it out.
Nothin here, Jimmy.
(coughing)
This is all solid.
Theres nobody been under that car
since it came from the factory.
That thing is clean.
l dont buy that, lrv.
The stuff is in that car.
Well, you find it. l cant.
Enfiin on ne va pas passerlajourne ici.
a fait deuxheures quon estl.
Soyez patient.
Look, the car was lost sometime last night.
First they send us to Pier One,
then here. Then what?
Why did you park the car
down by the waterfront?
Youre staying in midtown Manhattan
and you lose the car by the Brooklyn Bridge?
Monsieur Devereaux is scouting locations
for a film for French television.
He probably left the car to look at something.
We were told by the police commissioner
that the car was brought to this garage.
- l demand its immediate return.
- You have to be patient.
We get four or five hundred cars here a day.
Monsieur Devereaux is
an important guest ofthis country.
He is working with the absolute cooperation
and participation ofyour government.
Here are his credentials
from the French consulate.
Unless you wish to see this in his film,
l suggest you locate the car immediately.
Youre in a no-smoking area, sir. Would you
please extinguish your cigarettes?
What was the weight ofthe car
when you got it, lrv?
4795 pounds.
You sure?
Thats what it was.
4795 pounds when it came into the shop.
Owners manual says 4675.
Thats 120 pounds overweight.
And when it was booked
into Marseilles it was 4795.
Thats still 120 pounds overweight.
Jimmys gotta be right.
Listen, l ripped everything outta there
except the rocker panels.
Come on, lrv. What the hell is that?
Shit.
Son of a bitch.
All right.
l got it for you, Randy.
ltjust came in from downtown.
- Whos Devereaux?
- l am Mr Devereaux. Why?
lm sorry, Mr Devereaux, but we get a lot
of cars here and its hard to keep track...
- You mean the car is here now?
- Oh, yeah. lts right outside.
They stole it right
offthe street from you, huh?
Goddamn. Youre gonna have to pay
the towing charge, you know.
l was told these things happen in New York,
but one never expects it.
Yeah, well, thats New York.
ls this your first trip over here?
Yes. Wheres my car, please?
lts right over here.
Youre lucky this time. lts in perfect shape.
Not a scratch. You must lead a charming life.
Henri.
Je vous attendais.
(man) Lets go!
l wouldnt be surprised if ld been followed.
- Listen, lll see you at Pops tonight.
- OK, babe. Take care.
(police sirens)
They got the bridge blocked off!
This is the police. Youre surrounded.
Come out with your hands up!
Give em the gas!
Hold your fire!
Stop!
Theyre comin out! Hold your fire!
Popeye. lts me, its me.
Frog One is in that room.
Drop it!
Mulderig.
You shot Mulderig.
The son of a bitch is here.
l saw him. lm gonna get him.
(gunshot)
Visiontext Subtitles: Sally Lewis
ENGLlSH SDH