My mother died of pneumonia
when I was just a kid.
My father'd kept their wedding
cake frozen for 10 whole years.
After the funeral he gave it to the
yardman. He tried to act happy...
...but he couldn't be consoled by the
little stranger he found in his house.
Then one day, hoping to begin a new
life away from all his memories...
...he moved us from Texas
to Fort Dupree, South Dakota.
I'll give you a dollar
to eat this collie.
I ain't gonna eat him for a dollar.
I don't think he's a collie, either.
Some kind of dog, though.
Watch your head.
Hey, Woody! Give me a cigarette!
Woody wouldn't give me a cigarette.
Ever notice he don't talk much?
Yeah, he's not a talker.
You got that.
Little did I realize that what began
in the alleys and back ways...
... of this quiet town would end
in the badlands of Montana.
-They won't fit.
-How do you know?
-What size are they?
-Your size.
-Give me a dollar.
-Nah.
They cost 20 new.
Why don't you see if they fit you?
This lady don't ever pay her bills.
She's gonna get in trouble
if she doesn't watch out.
I throwed enough trash for today,
Cato. I'll see you in the morning.
-Catch!
-What do you mean?
Hi. I'm Kit. I'm not keeping you
from anything important, am I?
No.
Just thought I'd come over and say
hello to you. I'll try anything once.
-What's your name? I said mine.
-Holly.
Well, Holly, you.... I don't know,
you want to take a walk with me?
-What for?
-Oh, I got some stuff to say.
Guess I'm kind of lucky that way.
Most people don't have anything
on their minds, do they?
Oh, incidentally,
my last name is Carruthers.
-Sounds too much like "druthers," huh?
-It's okay.
Yeah, well, nobody asked me what I
thought. They just hung it on me.
-You still in school?
-No, I got me a job.
Doing what?
Well, I don't mind getting up early
so I got a job throwing garbage.
Holly!
-I'm not in love with it.
-That's my father. I gotta run.
Wait! When will I see you again?
-I know what my daddy's gonna say.
-What?
-Can I be honest?
-Sure.
That I shouldn't be seen with
anybody that collects garbage.
-He'll say that?
-Yeah.
-Now, what's he know about garbage?
-Nothing.
There you go.
I mean, there's nothing
he wants to know. I gotta run.
-Who was that?
-Just some boy.
Is that gonna kill the grass?
You got some on my feet!
What'd he want?
He was just asking if we needed
any yard work done.
I said no.
And for him not to bother us.
Heard the news, Kit?
No.
Been in all the headlines.
What's that?
You've been fired.
Ain't that a helluva note?
Yeah, how about that?
I won't need my keys. I'll leave them
where they'll be nice and handy.
I've got my dog.
Have you ever held another job before?
Yeah, I used to throw trash
for the city.
-And you lost that one?
-Yeah, I wouldn't be here if I hadn't.
-Why did you leave?
-Just felt like it.
What kind of work you think you'd be
qualified for? I just gotta get this.
Well, I can't think of anything
at the moment.
I want you to write me out a slip
though, proving I came down here.
I think we can get you something
working cattle over at the pens.
Yeah, what the hell.
Just hope there's a breeze.
He was handsomer than anybody I'd met.
He looked just like James Dean.
-Hi.
-Well, stop the world.
-Hey, quit my job.
-Great.
Seemed like the right move.
-What you doing?
-Spanish.
How do you say "quit my job"
in Spanish?
Something mi trabajo.
Well, I'm going to work
as a cowboy now. Thinking about it.
It's a routine, like anything.
-What do you think?
-I don't know.
Yeah, well, at least nobody can get on
me about wearing these boots anymore.
You want to go for a ride?
Well, I got homework.
Bring it along.
Somebody dropped a bag
on the sidewalk.
If everybody did that,
the whole town'd be a mess.
Hi.
-You're a redhead.
-I know.
-Anybody ever call you "Red"?
-Yeah, but I don't like it.
-Why not?
-I just don't.
-I got a headache.
-Oh, yeah?
-Can I come see you tomorrow?
-Okay.
Kit went to work in the feedlot
while I carried on with my studies.
Little by little, we fell in love.
As I'd never been popular in school...
...and didn't have much personality, I
was surprised he took a liking to me.
Especially when he could've had any
girl in town if he'd given it a try.
He said that I was grand though,
that he didn't want me for sex...
...and that, coming from him,
this was a compliment.
He'd never met a 15-year-old girl
who behaved more like a grownup.
He didn't care what people thought.
I looked good to him
and whatever I did was okay.
If I didn't have a lot to say,
that was okay too.
What a nice place.
Yeah, the tree makes it nice.
And the flowers.
Let's not pick them. They' re so nice.
It's your play.
Of course I had to keep this a secret
from my dad. He would've had a fit...
...since Kit was 10 years older and
from the wrong side of the tracks.
Our time with each other was limited.
Each lived for the precious hours...
... when they could be with each other,
away from the cares of the world.
My stomach's growling.
There's an old Fudgsicle,
you want it?
No.
-Somebody else is gonna get it.
-I don't care.
Kids eat that kind of stuff in Korea.
In the feedlot, he'd remember
how I'd looked the night before.
How I ran my hand through his hair
and traced his lips with my fingertip.
He wanted to die with me, and I dreamed
of being lost forever in his arms.
The only thing I did wrong was
throwing out my fish when he got sick.
Later I got a new one,
but this incident kept bothering me.
Well, he was sick.
You couldn't do much about that.
-I guess not.
-So?
-Well, it scared me.
-I know....
I didn't mind telling Kit
about this stuff.
Strange things happened to him too.
And some of what he did was strange.
He faked his signature
whenever he used it...
... to keep other people from forging
important papers with his name.
And as he lay in bed
in the middle of the night...
...he heard a noise like somebody
was holding a seashell to his ear.
And sometimes he'd see me
in beautiful white robes...
...and I'd put my cold hand
on his forehead.
Did it go the way it's supposed to?
Yeah.
-Is that all there is to it?
-Yeah.
-What was everybody talking about?
-Don't ask me.
I'm glad it's over. For a while I was
afraid I might die before it happened.
Had a wreck or some deal like that.
See where that tree fell in the water?
Yeah. River must've washed
the roots away.
You don't care about
anything I say, though.
-You know what I think?
-What?
Let's crunch our hands with this stone.
Then we won't forget today.
-But it would hurt.
-Well, that's the point, stupid.
Don't call me stupid.
Okay, but I'm gonna keep it
for a souvenir.
Well, maybe one that's lighter.
Kit vowed he'd always stand beside me
and let nothing come between us.
He wrote this out, put it in a box
with some of our tokens and things...
...and sent it off in a balloon
he'd found on the garbage route.
His heart was filled with longing
as he watched it drift off.
Something must've told him we'd never
live these days of happiness again...
... that they were gone forever.
Then, sure enough, Dad found out I'd
been running around behind his back.
He was madder than I'd ever seen him.
As punishment for deceiving him,
he went and shot my dog.
He made me take extra music
lessons after school...
...and wait till he picked me up.
He said if piano didn't keep me off
the streets, maybe the clarinet would.
Sure is pretty.
What'd you come out here for?
I wasn't aware there was
any law against it.
You know Holly?
Well, she means
an awful lot to me, sir.
Before I met her, nobody could
ask me how I was doing with my girl.
Matter of fact, I didn't have one.
Is that right?
It okay, me leaning on your Willys?
Look, I got a lot of respect
for her too, sir.
It's about as good a one
as I know to tell you.
Well, it's not good enough.
What'd happen to her if she
stuck around with a guy like you, Kit?
She'd get along okay.
And if she didn't, why,
she could just take off.
Just take right on off,
I wouldn't mind.
I'd always tell people I deserved it.
I don't want you hanging around
anymore. I don't wanna see you again.
Understand?
You something.
Takes all kinds, sir.
Hi.
What are you doing?
I got a gun here, sir.
Always a good idea to have one around.
What do you think you're doing?
Go on, get out of here.
I got it all planned.
And I'm taking Holly off with me.
Okay, boy. I'm turning you over
to the authorities.
-What for?
-Coming on my property with a gun.
-No, you're not either.
-Yeah? Why not?
'Cause I can't allow it.
Hey!
Hey, wait a minute!
Suppose I shot you?
How'd that be? Huh?
Wanna hear how it sounds?
-Kit! Kit!
-Hey, where're you going?
Daddy?
This is Holly.
Are you gonna be okay?
I came in the front.
How bad off is he?
I can look and see.
We better call the doctor.
Listen, I'll say how it happened.
The part I saw.
Well, I don't think that'd work.
He don't need a doctor.
-Are you sure?
-Don't believe me, see for yourself.
I found a toaster.
Don't worry, honey, I'll--
Listen, maybe we ought to tell
somebody about this.
You said that once already.
Too late now.
Why?
They're not going to listen to me.
You either. You kidding?
Suppose the neighbors heard the noise?
Wouldn't be funny.
Listen, I'll be back after a while.
Oh, you wanna call the police, that's
fine. Just won't be so hot for me.
My girl, Holly, and I have decided to
kill ourselves. Same way I did her dad.
Big decision, huh?
The reasons are obvious. I don't have
time to go into them right now.
But one thing though,
he was provoking me when I popped him.
That's what it was like. Pop.
Now we're sorry.
I mean, nobody's coming out of this
thing happy, especially not us.
I can't deny we've had fun though.
That's more than I can say for some.
That's the end of the message.
I ran out of things to say.
Thank you.
--Holly and I have decided
to kill ourselves.
Same way I did her dad.
Kit left the record playing over
and over for the D.A. to find.
He was gambling for time.
Kit made me get my books from school
so I wouldn't fall behind.
We'd be starting fresh
and have to change our names.
His would be James, I'd be Priscilla.
We'd hide out somewhere up north...
... where people didn't ask
a lot of questions.
I could've snuck out the back
or hid in the boiler room.
But I sensed that my destiny now lay
with Kit, for better or for worse.
It was better to spend a week
with one who loved me...
... than years of loneliness.
How you doing?
I'm fine. Kind of tired.
Yeah, me too.
We hid out in the wilderness by a river,
in a grove of cottonwoods.
We built our house in the trees...
... with tamarisk walls and willows
laid down to make a floor.
There wasn't a plant in the forest
that didn't come in handy.
We planned tunnels
under the forest floor.
And our first task every morning
was to choose a new daily password.
Sometimes we'd steal
a chicken or a bunch of corn...
... or some melons from a melon patch.
Mostly, we just lay on our backs
and stared at the clouds.
Sometimes it was like being
in a big marble hall...
...how we talked in low voices
and heard the tiniest sound.
They'd found only one set of bones
so we knew they'd be looking for us.
Kit made sure we'd be prepared.
He taught me how a gun works.
How to take it apart and rebuild it...
...in case I had to carry on
without him.
He said that if the devil came at me,
I could shoot him with a gun.
One day I carried 30 pounds of wood
a distance of five miles.
Another day I covered my eyes with
makeup to see how they'd come out.
We had our bad moments
like any couple.
Kit accused me
of only being along for the ride...
... while at times I wished he'd fall in
the river and drown so I could watch.
Take a break, Red.
Life of Riley, huh?
Mostly though, we got along
fine and stayed in love.
One of the chickens died last night.
I almost stepped on him.
"The Kon-Tiki's motion was a little
different from what it usually was.
We had become sensitive
to the log's rhythms.
I thought of suction from the coast and
was always on deck and up the mast. "
He was nervous.
"Time passed. At dawn, just before 6,
Torstein came down from the masthead.
He saw a line of small
palm-clad islands ahead. "
I grew to love the forest. The cooing
of doves and the hum of dragonflies...
...made it lonesome
and like everybody's dead.
When the leaves rustled overhead...
...it was like the spirits whispered
about the things that bothered them.
One day while looking at some
vistas in Dad's stereopticon...
-...it hit me that I'm just a girl...
-Hi.
... whose father was a sign painter,
who had just so many years to live.
Sent a chill down my spine
and I thought...
... where would I be this very moment
if Kit had never met me?
Or killed anybody?
This very moment.
If my mom had never met my dad.
If she had never died.
And what's the man
I'll marry gonna look like?
What's he doing right this minute?
Is he thinking about me now...
...by some coincidence,
even though he doesn't know me?
Does it show on his face?
For days afterwards, I lived in dread.
Sometimes I wished I'd fall asleep...
...and be taken off to some magical
land, but this never happened.
What?
Get out of here! Run!
Somebody's coming!
Hide!
Hey!
Holly!
Get in the car, Red.
We don't need this.
Kit felt bad about shooting
those men in the back.
But he said they'd come in and
would've played it down and dirty.
Besides, he'd overheard them say they
were only interested in the reward.
With lawmen
it would have been different.
They had a job to do and deserved
a chance. But not a bounty hunter.
We went to hide out with Kit's friend
from the days of the garbage route.
-How you doing, Cato?
-Not bad.
Take that son of a bitch.
What you been doing?
Running this place for a guy in town.
Nothing much to speak of.
Well, I don't notice us
hustling trash, either.
-Where'd you get them antlers?
-They come with the house.
Well, Cato,
I want you to meet my girl.
Holly Sargis.
Hi.
This guy at the nut house walked around
naked, except for hat and gloves.
And a nurse said,
"You can't walk around that way. "
And the guy says, "Well,
nobody comes around here anyway. "
The nurse says, "Well, why do
you have on the hat and gloves? "
And the guy says,
"Well, you never know. "
Isn't that funny?
Yeah, I guess.
She plays clarinet too.
-Don't you get bored around here?
-Well, sometimes.
The other day, an old boy plowing
the field there found some old coins.
Some old Spanish coins.
-That's what he told you, huh?
-Nope, no, he showed me one.
-What'd they look like?
-Well, kind of round, like so. Gold.
-Where at?
-Over in that field over there.
I'll show you if you want.
Let me finish my supper.
We're thinking of going to Texas.
Holly wants to visit some people.
But after that, I don't know.
They say Mexico's nice.
-Kit, maybe I better get a shovel.
-Okay.
-I'll catch up with you.
I found a lid.
It was laying on the ground.
Put that down. It's dirty.
-You missed!
-You're a pissant.
Hey, you're throwing big ones!
Cato!
The shovel's in the truck.
Kit never let on why he shot Cato. He
said talking about it could be bad luck.
And that right now we needed
all the luck we could get.
You never told me about her.
Look at all this junk.
How's he doing?
I got him in the stomach.
Is he upset?
He didn't say anything to me about it.
Bunch of junk.
He stole that cage.
I saw him do it.
Why look at that? Can't afford it.
I'm just looking.
Why don't you go in there and
keep him company for a while?
-Hi.
Is that your spider in there?
In that bottle?
Yeah.
What do you feed him?
Oh, flies.
Grasshoppers when I can catch them.
Does he bite?
He never bit me.
Hi.
-Hi.
-Where's Cato?
-Well, he's gone.
-Gone?
-Yeah.
-Where?
-He said not to tell.
-Oh, yeah?
He said for you to give us
a lift into town.
You've got the Studebaker, right?
-I need to pick up something in there.
-I can't allow that.
-What?
-If you go in, I'll have to kill you.
-What's going on?
-Can't take any chances.
Come out of there, young lady.
Let's go out in this field. Come on.
Skip that. I'll keep my eye on you.
-Okay.
-You don't mind?
Hi.
What's gonna happen to Jack and me?
Have to ask Kit. He says frog, I jump.
Okay.
-What's your friend's name?
-Jack.
-You love him?
-I don't know.
I gotta stick by Kit.
He feels trapped.
-Yeah, I can imagine.
-Well, I've felt that way, haven't you?
Come on, you two,
down in the cellar.
Go on.
-Promise to stay there for an hour?
-Yeah.
-You expect me to believe that?
I'm gonna shut the door.
-Think I got them?
-I don't know.
Well, I'm not going
down there and look.
Suddenly I was in shock. Kit was the
most trigger-happy person I'd met.
He claimed if you play for keeps and
the law's coming, it's okay to kill.
You had to take the consequences
though, and not whine about it later.
He'd never seemed violent before,
except for once...
... when he said he'd like
to rub out a couple of guys.
It shows how you can know a person and
not really know him at the same time.
We're in for it now. If they catch us.
What'd you put him in there for?
Just to keep him out of the sun.
I didn't feel shame or fear,
but just kind of blah...
...like when you 're sitting there
and the water's run out of the bathtub.
-You tired?
-Yeah.
Yeah, you look tired.
When this is over, I'll sit down
and buy you a big, thick steak.
I don't want a steak.
Yeah, well, we'll see about that.
Hey, look. They're probably
gonna blame that on me too.
Bastards.
The whole country was looking for us.
Who knew where Kit would strike next?
Sidewalks cleared out.
Stores closed and drew their blinds.
Posses and vigilante groups formed
from Texas to South Dakota.
Children rode to school
under heavy guard.
A famous detective was brought in
from Boston. He could find no clues.
People left their lights
on while they slept.
My clarinet teacher said I wasn't
responsible, but others said I was.
On Thursday, the governor of Oklahoma
sent the National Guard...
... to guard the Federal Reserve Bank
in Tulsa because Kit meant to rob it.
It was like the Russians had invaded.
We needed supplies,
so we went to a rich man's house.
Kit felt it'd be safer
and quicker than shopping.
A maid came.
Hi. I'm here to check your meter.
My tools are in here.
This is Holly, she's from Texas.
Later we found out she was deaf,
and we hadn't even known it.
Excuse me.
-Hi.
-Yes?
-This your place?
-Yes.
Sorry to barge in on you.
Anyone else here besides you two?
No.
Good deal.
Oh, we're on the run. And...
...we'd like to hang out here a while,
couple hours maybe, how'd that be?
Stay as long as you like.
Next time I ring, that means
it's time to clear out.
I left Kit in the parlor
and went for a stroll outside.
The day was quiet and serene
but I didn't notice...
... for I was deep in thought and not
even thinking about how to slip off.
The world was like a faraway planet
to which I could not return.
I thought what a fine place it was,
full of things that people can enjoy.
Listen to your parents and teachers.
They understand things
and aren't the enemy.
There's always an outside chance
you could learn something.
Try to keep an open mind. Try to
understand the viewpoints of others.
Consider the minority opinion...
...but try to get along with the
majority of opinion once it's accepted.
Of course, Holly and I have had fun
even if it has been rushed.
So far, we're doing fine.
Hadn't got caught. Excuse the grammar.
Hi.
Kit's downstairs playing
with the Dictaphone.
Sometimes he acts like there's
something wrong with his bean.
Hope nothing ever
goes wrong with mine.
You think he's crazy, huh?
I don't know, he's kind of odd.
They claim I've got him wrapped
around my finger.
But I never told him to shoot anybody.
-Gosh, I like your house.
-Thank you.
Hi.
-Hi, Mr. Scarborough here?
-Yeah.
The thing about him,
he's down with the flu. He's sick.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I'd invite you in but it's contagious.
Don't want an epidemic.
No, of course not. Only he called
last night and asked if I'd come by.
Well, he didn't have it last night.
-What's that?
-I'd like to leave a message, okay?
Sure.
You have to excuse me now.
I have to go back inside.
Bye.
Hey, Tex, we're out of here!
-Hi! What you doing?
-Just thinking.
Good a way to kill time as any.
She okay?
-Yes.
-Good.
We're gonna take the Cadillac
for a while. How'd that be?
-Fine.
-Don't worry, I won't let her drive.
Oh, here.
A list of what I borrowed. Car too.
Okay, ma'am, let's go. Out that way.
Go on.
You're my friend?
-Yes.
-Okay, no monkey business now.
Groceries.
That guy could sell that list I gave
him as a sample of my handwriting.
-Why you always walking ahead of me?
-Why you always walking behind me?
Don't!
-Anybody ever do that to you?
-No.
-Positive?
-Yes.
Guess there's no way
I'll ever know for sure.
That guy must pay through the nose
to keep this place up.
Lawn. Gas and electric. Bagworms.
Plus the upkeep on the cars.
You get a little money and think
your problems are solved.
Well, let me tell you, they're not.
I'd like to get out of here.
Soon as I start the car.
And fix my hat.
Fearing roadblocks on the highways,
we took off across the Great Plains.
Kit told me to enjoy the scenery
and I did.
" Rumor: Pat Boone's seriously
considering giving up his career...
...so he can return to school
and complete his education.
Fact: Pat told intimates that so long
as things go well for his career...
...it's the education that will
have to wait. "
I don't blame him.
"Rumor: Frank Sinatra and
Rita Hayworth are in love.
Fact: True. But not with each other. "
Yeah.
Through desert and mesa,
across endless miles of open range...
... we made our headlong way...
...steering by the telephone lines
toward the mountains of Montana.
Kit'd sometimes ram a cow
to save ammo, and we'd cook it.
Once we had to eat a bunch of salt
grass. It tasted like cabbage.
For gas we used the leakage from the
valves of pipelines along our way.
"Drip gas " is what it's called
in that part of the country.
Gradually we approached the border.
Kit was glad to leave South Dakota
and cursed its name.
He said that if communists
drop the atomic bomb...
...he wished they'd put it
in the middle of Rapid City.
That's Montana over there.
I never been to Montana.
Acquaintance of mine's been there,
but I hadn't.
Never had any reason to.
State bird's the meadowlark.
We lived in utter loneliness,
neither here nor there.
Kit said that solitude was a better
word, more like what I wanted to say.
Whatever the expression, I told him
we couldn't go on living this way.
Why not? I mean, I'm having fun.
At least I'm not bitchin'.
I feel like an animal living out here.
There's no place to bathe and...
... not any place to get
anything good to eat.
Well, I'll catch you a big trout
soon as we get to the mountains.
Everybody loves trout.
I'm serious.
In the distance, I saw a train
making its way across the plain...
...like the caravan in
The Adventures of Marco Polo.
It was our first taste
of civilization in weeks...
...and I asked Kit if we could
have a closer look.
Before we left, he shot a football
he considered excess baggage.
Then he buried some of our things.
He said nobody else would know where
we'd put them, that we'd come back...
...and they'd still be here,
just the same, but we'd be different.
And if we never got back, somebody
might dig them up years later...
...and they'd wonder.
We should have hopped it.
It was going too fast.
I could have pulled the car
on the tracks to slow it down.
Then we'd be stuck here.
Maybe we ought to be stuck here.
I'm not saying I know.
You're crazy.
Kit spun the bottle, leaving to fate
which direction we should take.
The slope throws it off,
we ought to find a flat place.
How about over here?
It doesn't matter.
If I'm worth a damn,
I'll pick the right direction.
-See what I mean?
-No.
Well, I shouldn't expect
miracles, should I?
We'll keep heading
for that mountain.
Just remember, I said
it wasn't such a hot idea.
We took off at sunset, toward
the mountains of Saskatchewan...
...for Kit, a magical land
beyond the reach of the law.
He needed me more than ever,
but something came between us.
I stopped paying attention to him.
I sat in the car and read a map
and spelled out sentences...
... with my tongue on the roof of my
mouth where nobody could read them.
We moved closer to the border.
Across the prairie,
at the edge of the horizon...
... we saw gas fires
at the Missoula refineries.
To the south, we saw the
lights of Cheyenne...
...a city bigger and grander
than I'd ever seen.
I felt many things
looking at the lights.
Most important, I made up my mind
to never tag around...
... with the hell-bent type,
even if I loved him.
I found the strength
to tell Kit this.
I pointed out that if we got to the
North, he still couldn't make a living.
I can get a job with the Mounties.
Northwest Mounties.
I got all the qualifications.
I can ride and shoot...
...and I don't mind the cold.
I like the cold.
What?
Nothing.
I was just running off
at the mouth as usual.
I'm sorry, I wasn't listening.
Hey, man, don't lip it.
Well...
...they'd ask to see your driver's
license before they'd hire you.
I'm not going to let
that stop me.
-You smoke Pall Mall?
-Yeah.
You haven't seen me when
I'm going after something. Tough.
Hey, don't touch that!
Nat King Cole!
If I could sing like that...
...if I could sing a song
about the way I feel right now....
It would be a hit.
Kit knew the end was coming.
He wondered if they'd
pronounce him dead...
...or if he'd read what the papers
would say from the other side.
He dreaded being shot down alone
without a girl to scream his name.
Then, for an instant, the sight of the
mountains at dawn got his hopes up.
God, what a sight.
Tell me this.
What's a little Texas girl
like you think of that sight?
Love this air.
Morning.
You got any gas?
Maybe.
I'm sorry, but we got
to ask you for it.
We're about out,
been driving all night.
I don't got time to explain.
-What I got I can't spare.
-Just a second now.
That's your truck, isn't it?
You didn't walk here.
It's mine, all right.
Well, listen, I'm gonna
swap you my Cadillac.
Don't worry, you're getting
a fair deal. Hell, ask anybody.
What's the Blue Book value
on this thing, Mildred?
Who are you?
Carruthers. I shoot people
every now and then.
-Not that I deserve a medal.
-Kit.
Okay, friend, start running.
-Give me a chance!
-Go on! Get!
I had a feeling today was the day.
-Helicopter.
-Yeah.
He's not taking us on a ride.
-Let's make a run for the car.
-I don't want to.
Have you got a better idea?
I just don't wanna go.
What?
What is wrong with you?
What is the matter with you?
I don't know what to make
of people like you.
I really don't.
You want a second chance?
Noon, Grand Coulee Dam,
New Year's Day, 1964. Meet me.
Got that?
Hey! Anybody here?
Hi.
You got any shells for a Savage,
.300 Savage?
-Nope.
-I pissed mine away shooting bottles.
You wanna fill her up? Please.
You want any of that junk,
it's yours.
What was going through his head
before they got him?
Why didn't he run while
he had the chance?
Did he figure they'd
catch him the next day?
Was it despair?
Said he had a flat tire,
but the way he carried on...
...I imagine this is false.
Hi.
Hold it right there.
I could've held off an army
in the mountains.
-Oh, yeah?
-Long as my ammo held out.
About there's where you caught me.
We did it, Ray.
-Better not leave the car here.
-Put your hands back of your head.
Now put the other one on yourself.
Hell, he ain't no bigger than I am.
Look at that.
You're gonna give me
a cauliflowered ear.
He should have thought about that
before he got caught.
Shouldn't he?
Think I'll take the juice?
Beats me.
What kind of rifle were
you shooting at me?
Thirty-aught-six.
-You ever opened up like that before?
-Nope.
You boys performed like
a couple of heroes.
Don't think I'm not gonna
pass it around in town.
You tossed my hat out the window.
Wanna sue me?
-No.
-Kit.
Kit, I got a question for you.
-You like people?
-They're okay.
Then why'd you do it?
I don't know.
I wanted to be a criminal.
Just not this big of one.
Takes all kinds, though.
You know who he looks like?
-You know, don't you?
-No.
I'll kiss your ass if you don't
look like James Dean.
How you doing?
Fine as can be expected.
Just locked up, can't move.
-Nice coat you got on.
-You think? It's leather.
Hey, now look here,
here's a real prize.
I had this 10 years.
Who's gonna get it?
-Give me that.
-There.
Where you from?
-South Dakota, where you from?
-Here.
Wanna comb?
-Joni James is from South Dakota.
-She got out too.
-Who's your favorite singer?
-Eddie Fisher. Yours?
-Eddie Fisher.
-Damn! You want a pen?
-Been to Kansas?
-How old are you?
Don't you read the papers?
-Been married?
-No, I haven't.
Hey, Kit. You afraid of death?
I haven't thought about it much.
Say again?
-Did you when you were on the move?
-Yep.
I won't tell you how
to run your show...
...but these cuffs are pinching.
What do you say?
I need to get your signature.
I'll have to read them first.
Could I get a Coke?
Sure thing.
Come on.
-Keep out of trouble.
-Don't worry about us.
Holly's over here
if you want to see her.
Sure.
I gave him the papers.
I don't want him in trouble....
You wanna give me
a little slack here?
Hi.
Don't worry.
I'll get you off the charges.
There are other boys out there waiting
for you. You're gonna have fun.
Boy, we rang the bell, didn't we?
I'll say this though.
That guy with the deaf maid,
he's just lucky he's not dead too.
Of course, too bad about your dad.
Yeah.
We're gonna have to talk
about that sometime.
There you go, Tom.
-Thank you.
-Thank you very much, Chief Sims.
-Sorry.
-You didn't cause me any trouble.
Thanks anyway.
Well....
-Kit.
-Tom.
-Good luck.
-Thanks.
-I mean it.
-I know you do. You too.
-Now we go.
-Okay. Thank you.
Come on, Red.
They took us back to South Dakota.
They kept him in solitary so he
didn't get to know other inmates.
He knew they'd like him,
especially the murderers.
Myself, I got off with probation
and a lot of nasty looks.
Later, I married the son of the lawyer
who defended me.
Kit slept in court
while his confession was read.
He was sentenced to die
in the electric chair.
On a warm spring night,
six months later...
...after donating his body to science,
he did.
-Sir? Where'd you get that hat?
-State.
Boy, I'd like to buy me one of them.
You' re quite an individual, Kit.
Think they'll take that
into consideration?
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]