MOSFILM
Artistic Association of
Writers and Cinema Workers
NATALYA BONDARCHUK
DONATAS BANIONIS
YURI YARVET
VLADISLAV DVORZHETSKY
NIKOLAI GRINKO
ANATOLY SOLONITSYN
in
SOLARIS
Based on the science-fiction novel
by Stanislaw Lem
Screenplay by
F. GORENSHTEIN, A. TARKOVSKY
Directed by
Andrei TARKOVSKY
Director of Photography
Vadim YUSOV
Production Designer
Mikhail ROMADIN
Music by
Eduard ARTEMYEV
Sound by
Semyon LITVINOV
Used in the film
the chorale-prelude in F minor
by J.S. Bach
SOLARIS
Part One
Chris! Come here!
You're just in time.
He takes a walk every morning
for at least an hour.
He has been working too hard,
all night sometimes.
This science of solaristics of his!
He reminds me of a bookkeeper
making up his accounts.
We expected you yesterday.
He wanted to run away
when he saw me.
Hello!
How do you do?
I guess I shouldn't have bothered
you today.
How old we have grown!
I'm only now beginning to realize it.
Everything will depend on his
initial report from the station.
Every message we receive
is confusing or incomprehensible.
If he confirms for us that
the study shouldn't continue,
the station can be taken out
of Solaris's orbit.
I understand.
You promised to talk to him.
I've brought the film.
Yes, of course.
Would you mind keeping
the boy for a few days?
Anna'll be pleased to have him.
She'll have more free time now.
When does he leave?
By this time tomorrow, he'll already
be gone.
It's very pleasant here.
This house looks like my grand-
father's house. I liked it very much.
And so we built this one just like it.
I don't care much for new things.
Well, I better get going.
I've an awful lot to do.
Don't you want to see this?
I've already seen it many times.
Twenty-one days after the launch
of our expedition,
radio biologist Vishnyakov
and physicist Fechner
went on an exploration mission over
the Solaris ocean in an air vehicle.
When they failed to return,
we ordered a search.
The fog was too dense,
and we had to call the search off.
All of the rescue craft
returned to the station
except the helicopter
piloted by Burton.
He came back
only after the dark had set in.
He immediately ran to his quarters,
obviously in a state of shock.
It was so unusual
for a man
who had been flying for 11 years.
He had recovered in a couple of days,
but he would never leave the station.
And he refused to approach
the window overlooking the ocean.
While under medical care in a clinic
he offered to make a statement
of great importance,
one which he felt could affect
the whole future of Project Solaris.
Very well, let's hear his story.
Now is the time
to let Burton talk.
The first time I descended
below a thousand feet,
I had trouble maintaining altitude,
because the wind had come up.
All my efforts were required
in operating the ship.
I wasn't watching outside.
As a result, I entered the fog bank.
Was that an ordinary fog?
It was like nothing I'd ever seen
before.
It seemed to be a colloidal substance,
a gluey mass.
All the windows were coated.
Because of the fog's resistance
I began to lose altitude.
Where I supposed the sun would be,
the fog glowed like fire.
Half an hour later, I emerged
into a large open space.
The patch was round,
about a few hundred meters across.
At that moment I observed
great changes in the ocean.
The water became still,
and the surface looked transparent.
A sort of yellow mucus started
to congeal under it.
When it rose up,
it glistened like glass.
Then it began to boil,
and a frothy crust appeared on top.
The surface was brown
like burned sugar syrup.
This substance solidified into big
lumps,
giving shape to
all sorts of figures.
I was being drawn to
the fog bank,
so I had to struggle
against this force for some time.
When I looked down again,
I saw a sort of garden.
A garden?
Quiet, please.
I could see vegetation, hedges,
acacia trees, narrow paths.
All of this same substance.
And all these trees and plants,
did they have leaves?
Those bushes, acacias?
They looked like they were made of
plastic, but in real-life proportions.
All of a sudden cracks started
to appear.
The boiling began again,
all was in froth.
You'll be able to see it
for yourselves.
Everything I saw
will be on the film.
Then I suggest
we interrupt the hearing
and look at it
with our own eyes.
Yes, show us the film.
It's very interesting.
- Is that all?
- Yes, that's all there is.
But we don't understand.
Your film is nothing but clouds!
That must be the fog
I was talking about.
I'm as surprised
as you are.
All this might be the result of
the bio-magnetic current of
the Solaris ocean acting on Burton's
conscience.
We know these currents to be not
only a gigantic cerebral system,
but also to be capable
of generating thought.
That is a hypothesis
that has not been confirmed.
Weren't you ill on that particular
day?
Oh, this next part is pointless.
We'll pick up here.
...I saw something floating.
I thought that it looked like
Fechner's space suit.
I kept circling the spot to make sure
I wouldn't lose sight of it.
Suddenly I could see the form
rise slightly,
as if treading the waters.
I could see the man, he wasn't
wearing a space suit, and he moved.
You mean it was human?
Yes, human.
You saw his face?
Yes.
What man?
Who was he?
It was an infant.
- Did you recognize it?
- I'd never seen it before.
When I circled nearer,
what I saw was monstrous.
What do you mean?
At first I couldn't make it out,
but then it became clear
that it was incredibly huge.
It was twelve feet tall.
Its eyes were blue,
its hair was dark.
If you're not feeling well,
we can recess the hearing.
I will continue.
It was absolutely naked,
as if new born.
And it was moist, or rather slippery.
Its skin was glistening.
It rose and fell
with the waves,
but it was moving by itself.
The whole thing was repugnant.
Wait a minute,
there isn't very much more.
...Burton's statements
would appear to be
the expression
of a hallucinatory complex,
induced by atmospheric
influences of the planet,
plus obscure symptoms to which
the brain's cortical substance
contributed in some measure through
the excitation of associated zones.
This report in no way reflects
the actual facts.
Or almost in no way.
There's a different opinion
offered by Professor Messenger
who believes
that the information
supplied by Burton
could be true
and needs to be
thoroughly studied.
I saw everything I described
with my own eyes!
I would dare to venture
another opinion.
We are on the verge
of an immense discovery,
and it would be unwise to be
influenced by the fact that we base
our decision upon the observations
of an unqualified layman.
Every explorer may well envy
this pilot,
his presence of mind,
his talents of observation.
Moreover, given
the recent information,
we are bound morally
to press forward with our probes.
I can understand
how Professor Messenger feels,
however let's look back
at the long road we've traveled.
For all our work, the Solaris probes
are back where we began.
Years of effort
have proven useless.
All we know about Solaris
reminds me of a mountain
of separate facts
which we are unable to squeeze
into the framework of any conception.
Well, we're even worse off today,
as regards the essential.
Solaristics is degenerating.
The essential question is far more
serious than just Solaristics.
We're probing the very frontier
of human knowledge.
By artificially establishing
a knowledge frontier,
we limit our concept of
the infinity of man's knowledge.
And if our movement is not forward,
do we not risk moving backward?
What do you mean by saying
that the information supplied by me
is in no way reflects the actual
facts?
I saw all this with my own eyes.
It means
that some real phenomena
could have triggered
your hallucinating.
In windy weather
it's very easy
to mistake a swinging bush
for a living creature.
To say nothing of a strange planet!
There's nothing offending in it
for you.
What action are you going to take
in view of Prof. Messenger's opinion?
Practically none at all.
Our research in this area
will be discontinued.
I have a statement to make.
It's not my reputation but the spirit
of the expedition that you offend...
Well, et cetera...
It's considered to be good manners
now
to laugh whenever Burton's report
is mentioned.
We've known you a long time,
but still I know so little about you.
You were very handsome then.
You don't mean that, but thanks
anyway.
Well, Chris, what do you think
about all this?
I would like to speak to your son
alone.
I hate to look like an idiot
before you once more.
I'll wait for you outside
by the swing.
He looks ridiculous, your Burton.
Don't say that.
He's obviously ill at ease.
He feels he's intruding on us.
If he decided to come, it's because
he considers the matter so important.
I didn't want to see outsiders
today any more than you did.
We don't talk to each other often
enough.
It's good to hear you say that.
Even on the last day.
The last day...
When the farewells are overdone,
you feel awful afterwards.
Let's meet after dinner.
We need to talk.
And still, why did you invite this
Burton fellow today of all days?
Where are the guests going to sleep?
Upstairs, I guess.
Well, I'll be down by the swing.
- But perhaps...
- Just a second.
The question of where they're
going to sleep can wait!
Listen, Chris...
What's the matter?
What is it down there, standing
in the garage and looking at me?
It's just a horse.
I've seen it already.
Come on!
He's very gentle.
Look how beautiful he is!
I think that Solaristics
is at an impasse
as a result of
irresponsible fantasizing.
I'm only interested in truth,
but you want to convince me
of your point of view.
I can't draw conclusions
based on "reasons of heart".
I'm not a poet.
My problem is simple:
Either end the research,
withdrawing the station from orbit
and legalizing the crisis in
Solaristics,
or take extreme measures,
like bombarding the ocean
with high intensity beams.
No, not that!
Didn't you want to continue
the research at any price?
And you want to destroy that which
we aren't capable of understanding?
No, I don't advocate knowledge
at any price.
Knowledge is only valid when
it rests on a foundation of morality.
Man is the only agent
who renders science immoral.
Don't forget Hiroshima.
Then don't make science immoral!
It's strange...
There's nothing strange about it.
Even you can't be sure that
all you had seen
weren'tjust hallucinations.
Thank you for your time. We have
nothing more to say to each other.
- Is anything the matter?
- I'm leaving.
Leaving?
He is a bookkeeper, not a scientist.
We're friends, Burton, but you
shouldn't say that about him!
We've known each other for 20 years.
It had to end someday, I guess.
Are you leaving the child?
Why did you have to offend him?
You're heartless.
It's dangerous to send
your kind to the cosmos.
Everything is far too fragile there!
The earth somehow manages to put up
with men of your sort,
though at what cost to humanity!
Are you jealous of the fact that he
will be the one to bury me, not you?
It'd been established that the Solaris
ocean is a peculiar kind of brain.
Later, even a more daring hypothesis
was put forward,
that is the Ocean is
a thinking substance.
For years this hypothesis could not
have been substantiated.
This program is about Solaris.
Very few true believers
have remained.
First of all, they are those
who are connected with the station.
On the station for a 85-strong crew,
only three men are still working.
They are astrobiologist Sartorius,
cyberneticist Snout
and physiologist Guibariane
who is dealing with the problem...
I'm calling from the city.
Burton!
Anna, please, we need to talk.
What I talked to Chris about was not
important. I should have told him
about Messenger who had
a different opinion at that meeting.
He got very much interested in
Fechner who died in Solaris Ocean.
It turned out that Fechner has an
orphaned son, he had left his family.
Messenger and I paid a visit
to Fechner's widow.
I saw this child with my own eyes.
You never told me about that.
- I didn't have a chance.
- All right, what about it?
He looked exactly like the child
I'd seen on Solaris.
Except that he wasn't twelve feet
tall.
It wouldn't be good for him
to think about it before the launch,
but he should remember this
when he's there.
There's no point in keeping these.
The only ones to be kept
are those in my room.
All my research notes, my thesis...
I wonder why we kept all these?
Should something happens, I'll find
someone to take care of them.
Oh, don't look for the film with
the campfire. I'm taking it with me.
Oh, sure, do that...
- Ready, Kelvin?
- Ready!
You have nothing to worry about.
Have a good trip.
- When is the lift-off?
- You're already under way!
Station Solaris!
Can you do something?
I seem to be losing stability.
Where are you all?
You've got company!
Doctor Snout?
Snout?
I'm Kelvin, psychologist.
It appears you weren't expecting me.
Did you receive the radiogram?
Yes, certainly.
Why are you so upset?
I'm sorry...
Where is Guibariane?
And Sartorius?
Sartorius is in his quarters.
Guibariane is dead.
Dead?
He committed suicide...
I knew Guibariane. It's not like
him to...
He was in a state
of profound depression.
Since these mysterious disorders
began...
Maybe you'd better rest, take a bath.
You may take any room.
Come here in an hour.
I'm impatient to meet with
Guibariane... I mean Sartorius.
I doubt if he'll let you in.
He's up in his laboratory.
Listen, I'm aware that something
extraordinary has happened,
and perhaps I...
Doctor Kelvin...
You see...
Please, come in an hour.
Go now, and rest.
Now there're only three of us on
the station: You, me and Sartorius.
You know what we look like
from our photographs.
If you see anything out of
the ordinary, not me or Sartorius,
try not to lose your head.
- What would I see?
- That depends on you.
- Hallucinations?
- No... but don't forget.
- Forget what?
- That we're not on earth.
Why don't we have our talk tonight?
No, let's make it tomorrow morning!
A. GUIBARIANE
HUMAN BEING
TO C. KELVIN
Hello, Chris.
I still have a little time left.
There're certain things I must tell
you,
that I must warn you about.
I suppose you've been told
what happened to me.
If not, Snout or Sartorius
can tell you the details.
What happened to me,
it matters little.
The trouble is that no one can really
explain it.
I'm afraid that what's happened to me
is only a beginning.
I wouldn't wish it, of course,
but it may happen to all of you.
Here, it may happen to anyone,
for sure.
But don't think that I've gone mad.
You know me well.
If I have enough time, I'll tell you
why I did this.
If it does happen to you,
you will know it's not madness.
That's the main thing.
As for continuing
our program of research,
I'm of the same opinion
as Sartorius.
Bombard the plasma of the ocean
by high-powered X-rays.
It's prohibited,
but there's no other choice.
We - or rather you - will be drawn in.
It may offer a way
to break this deadlock.
It's your only chance to establish
contact with this monster.
There's no other solution left.
If you...
Doctor Sartorius, my name is Kelvin.
I arrived two hours ago.
Look, I'm in a ridiculous
situation here.
Either you open up,
or I'll break the door!
All right, I'll open the door, but
don't come in. I'll come out.
My name is Kelvin.
You must have heard of me.
I worked with Guibariane.
Dr. Snout told me about Guibariane...
I can't believe it.
So, you know the story.
Yes, it's horrible. I have no details,
I only know he's dead.
All of us may die.
But he insisted upon being buried
on the earth.
Guibariane wanted to be in
the earth, with the worms.
Have you ever heard of Burton?
Yes, he was on the search party
for Fechner.
Fechner died a magnificent death,
and Guibariane was a coward.
Please... He's dead!
Why judge him?
Duty to the truth is the only concern
that should count.
You are misguided in your search.
Look...
This courage you pretend to
is only inhumanity.
Go away.
You're obviously overemotional.
You must adapt yourself.
Good health to you.
I saw Sartorius and we spoke.
I don't find him very likable.
He's a very talented scientist.
I'm afraid
I don't feel so well.
There's nothing wrong with you,
but you won't listen to advice.
Aside from the three of us, is there
anyone else on the station?
Did you see anything?
What were you warning me against?
What did you see?
A human being? Was she real?
Can she be touched or felt,
or wounded, hurt?
When did you see her the last time,
today?
And you, how do I know
who you are?
Shhh...
- Where did she come from?
- Leave me alone!
You're afraid...
Don't worry, I'm not going
to think you're insane.
Me, insane? Oh God,
you know so little...
Madness would be a blessing!
Snout, listen...
It's all so absurd.
They don't understand anything.
They're sure that I've gone mad.
Though it's something like insanity,
I've got to do this.
I'm afraid that Snout and Sartorius
will try to force their way in.
They don't understand what they're
doing. I'm frightened, Chris...
I can't...
No one will ever understand...
Guibariane, open the door!
Don't be a fool!
That's us, Snout and Sartorius!
We want to help you!
They say they want to help me.
All right, quit knocking.
I'm my own judge.
Have you seen her?
Try to understand, Chris, I'm not mad.
It has to do with my conscience.
I really hoped
you'd get here in time.
How did you...
It's so good!
But you can't possibly... How did
you find out where I was?
What do you mean "find out"?
Don't, Chris, that tickles.
Where are my shoes?
No... they're not there.
Who's this?
Chris, this is me...
You know...
I have a feeling
as if I've forgotten something.
What's the matter with me?
Do you love me?
Why do you have to ask, Hari,
as if you didn't know.
I've got to go out.
I won't be long, wait here.
- Can't I come with you?
- No. I'll be back soon.
No!
Why?
I don't know...
I can't...
You can't what?
I feel like I've got to be with you...
all the time, to see you...
Why are you being so childish?
I've work to do, Hari.
You're right, I'm acting childish.
As for you, you're as nervous
as Snout.
- As who?
- As Doctor Snout.
How do you know...
I've got to go.
If you want, you can come with me.
But you won't be able to get
into a suit with your dress on.
Help me, I can't do it by myself.
Why do you keep staring at me?