You 're...
from Baker?
Tell Baker I told him
all I know already.
Tell him I want to live in peace.
There is no use
to go on tormenting me!
I know nothing at all
about that case of coins.
Now that gold has disappeared.
If he'd listened,
we could've avoided this altogether.
I went to the army court.
There were no witnesses.
They couldn't uncover any more.
I can't tell Baker
what happened to the money.
Go back and tell him that.
Word's around you had a visitor.
And Baker knows it.
Name of Jackson.
Well...
Jackson was here...
...or Baker's got it all wrong.
He's not wrong.
Maybe Baker would like to know just
what you and Jackson had to say
about the cash box.
That's not what
I'm being paid for.
I'm only interested in what name
Jackson's hiding under now.
Why do you think Jackson
may be assuming another name?
I would've found him already.
When I start off
to find somebody, I find him.
That's why they pay me.
What is Baker paying you?
That your family?
Yes.
Nice family.
What does he pay you
for murdering me?
$500...
to get the name.
The name.
Carson. Bill Carson.
That's what he calls himself now.
That's a lot
of money... 1,000.
$1,000?
And some in gold.
That's a tidy sum.
But when I'm paid,
I always see the job through.
It's you.
Any information?
Too much.
He said quite a bit
that should interest you
and one or two things
that interested me.
Such as?
The name Jackson's
hiding under is Bill Carson.
That's your bit.
Keep talking.
He also mentioned something
about a certain cash box
which just happened
to disappear.
- That's my bit.
- Anything else?
Not enough for you, eh?
Well, you don't have to worry.
He'll never say anything
to anybody again.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, perfect.
Here. Here you are.
Here. This is for you.
You did a good job for me...
worth $500.
Yeah. I almost forgot.
He gave me 1,000.
I think his idea
was that I kill you.
But you know, the pity is,
when I'm paid,
I always follow my job through.
You know that.
No! Angel Eyes!
No. No pistol, amigo.
It won't do you any good.
There are three of us.
Hey, amigo...
You know you got a face beautiful
enough to be worth $2,000?
Yeah...
But you don't look
like the one who'll collect it.
A couple steps back.
Thank you.
How much are you worth now?
How much?
$2,000.
That's right. $2,000.
Not bad.
You 'll pay for this!
I hope you end up
in a graveyard
with the cholera
and the rabies and the plague!
Cut me loose!
Cut me loose,
you filthy bastard!
Put me down!
I hope your mother
ends up in a $2 whorehouse!
Cut me loose!
You can still save yourself.
Let me go,
and I'll pardon you.
Let me go!
I think I feel sick.
The blood
is bursting through my...
I'm dry, Blondie.
Agua. Water.
You slime!
You son of a bitch.
Let me go!
You 're brave
with a man who's tied up!
Come back!
Come back and fight...
You bastard!
Who the hell is that?
One bastard goes in,
another comes out.
Cut it out!
I'm an honest farmer!
I'm innocent of any...
So you 're an honest farmer.
You recognize this man?
- Me?
- Yeah, it's you.
Me? Who says so?
You can't even read.
Yeah, roll it up!
Roll it up!
I'll give you a good idea
where you can put it.
To hell with all you sheriffs
and all who gave birth to you!
Everybody, look!
He's giving him the filthy money!
Judas!
You sold my hide!
But you won't
enjoy that money, not a penny.
If there's justice
in the world,
that money will go
to the undertakers, every penny of it!
You know who you are?
You want to know
whose son you are?
You don't. I do.
Everybody does.
You 're the son of a thousand fathers,
all bastards like you.
And your mother...
Your mother, she's...
You bastard!
Your mother... it's better
not to talk of her!
I never hurt anybody!
Wanted in 14 counties
of this state,
the condemned is found guilty
of the crimes of murder,
armed robbery of citizens,
state banks, and post offices,
the theft of sacred objects,
arson in a state prison,
perjury, bigamy,
deserting his wife and children,
inciting prostitution,
kidnapping, extortion,
receiving stolen goods,
selling stolen goods,
passing counterfeit money,
and, contrary to the laws
of this state,
the condemned is guilty
of using marked cards and loaded dice.
Therefore, according
to the powers vested in us,
we sentence the accused
here before us...
Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez...
Known as ''The Rat.''
...and any other aliases
he might have...
to hang by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy
on his soul. Proceed.
Five for you...
Five for me.
and five for me.
Know how much
you 're worth now?
No. How much?
$3,000.
There are two kinds
of people in the world, my friend...
those with a rope
around their neck
and the people who have
the job of doing the cutting.
Listen, the neck at the end
of the rope is mine.
I run the risks.
So the next time,
I want more than half.
You may run the risks,
my friend,
but I do the cutting.
If we cut down
my percentage...
Cigar?
Liable to interfere
with my aim.
But if you miss,
you had better miss very well.
Whoever double-crosses me
and leaves me alive,
he understands nothing
about Tuco.
Nothing.
...wanted in 15 counties
of this state.
The condemned
standing before us...
sitting before us...
Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez...
has been found guilty
by the Third District Circuit Court
of the following crimes...
murder, assaulting
a justice of the peace,
raping a virgin
of the white race,
statutory rape of a minor
of the black race,
derailing a train in order
to rob the passengers...
Angel Eyes!
...highway robbery,
robbing an unknown number
of post offices...
What'd you find out, Shorty?
If you ask me,
seems like a book...
an armed unit escorting
a cash box of gold coins
meets a Yankee ambush,
and only three of them are saved...
Stevens, Baker, and Jackson.
The thing that wasn't
saved was the coins.
The army decides to hold
a hearing, and Jackson's acquitted.
He disappears
and becomes Bill Carson.
I know his name.
You don't know just who
you 're looking for. I do.
When he's found,
I'd be scared to be put in his shoes.
Where is Carson?
Carson re-enlisted.
The poor guy's minus an eye.
He lives with a girl
called Maria who'll tell you.
She's a fresh young whore
in the territory.
Where's she?
Now, what's the name
of that town?
Someplace fairly near.
Santa Ana.
Adios, half-soldier.
...detention and selling
fugitive slaves, burning down...
Luke, hand me down a whiskey.
...and the sheriff's office
in Sonora.
The condemned hired himself out
as a guide to a wagon train.
After receiving his payment,
he deserted the wagon train
on the hunting grounds
of the Sioux Indians.
Glad they got him...
a man guilty of all those crimes.
People with ropes around
their necks don't always hang.
What do you mean?
The condemned
is also guilty of...
Even a filthy beggar like that
has got a protecting angel.
...and misrepresenting himself
as a Mexican general.
A golden-haired angel
watches over him.
...from the Union Army.
For all these crimes, the accused
has made a full confession.
Therefore, we condemn him
to be hung by the neck until dead.
May the Lord have mercy
on his soul. Proceed.
Let's get the hell
out of here!
What are you trying to say?
''Anybody can miss a shot''?
Nobody misses when I'm
at the end of the rope.
You never had a rope
around your neck.
When that rope
starts to pull tight,
you can feel the devil
fight your ass.
Yeah, you 're right.
It's getting tougher.
The way I figure,
there's really not too much future
with a sawed-off runt like you.
What do you mean?
'Cause I don't think you 'll
ever be worth more than $3,000.
What do you mean?
I mean our partnership is untied.
No. Not you.
You remain tied.
I'll keep the money,
and you can have the rope.
You filthy,
double-crossing bastard!
Of all the stinking,
dirty trick...
The way back to town
is only 70 miles.
If you save your breath, I feel
a man like you could manage it.
Adios.
You filthy bastard!
Come here!
Cut this rope off!
Get off that horse,
you filthy coward!
If I ever catch you,
I'll rip your heart out and eat it.
I'll skin you alive!
I'll hang you by your thumbs!
You pig! You vulture!
I'll kill you!
Such ingratitude after all
the times I've saved your life.
Where are you going?
This is only a trick!
You wouldn't leave me here!
Come back!
Wait! Blondie!
Listen, Blondie!
I believe madam is home.
Sweet dreams
and many thanks!
You filthy rats!
Maria?
Honey.
Is that you, Bill?
Bill!
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
Go on talking about Bill Carson.
I don't know him.
You were calling to him
in the dark.
Where is he?
What are you
going to do to him?
I'll ask the questions.
Where is he?
Where? Where?
That's enough!
I don't know where he is.
He packed his things ten days ago
and went away with his unit.
They all left.
Which company?
Where'd they go.
Third Cavalry.
General Sibley.
They left for Santa Fe.
That's all I know.
I swear!
I'm very sorry,
but the store's closing.
- Revolvers.
- Yeah, revolvers.
Revolvers!
Well, here's where
I keep the best ones.
Here... Remington, Colt,
a Roat,
and a Smith-Wesson.
Colt... it's navy.
Joslyn.
Another Remington.
- And this one is...
- That's enough.
Cartridges.
You want to try the pistol?
Just step out back.
Let's go.
M ovo M ovo
Cartridge.
- How much?
- $20.
No.
$50.
How much?
$100.
$200.
It's all I've got.
Here.
Come here.
If you work for a living,
why do you
kill yourself working?
If you work for a living,
why do you
kill yourself working?
Potatoes.
You 've gotta be poor
to eat potatoes.
Really poor.
I'm rich.
But I'm lonely.
The world is divided
into two parts...
those who have friends
and those who are lonely
like poor Tuco.
You see, I used to have
a friend... Pedro.
Chico and Ramon... his two brothers
were my friends, too.
But who knows
where they are now?
It's too bad, friends.
Tough luck I haven't found you.
I had a good deal for you.
There's a big son of a bitch
who's got $4,000.
$4,000.
And I know where to find it.
If they would help me catch him,
I'd divide it four ways,
like a brother.
$1,000 each.
You 're alive, Tuco.
Is it true?
He's rich,
like you 're going to be.
But people are saying
you got killed in Albuquerque.
And people talk bullshit.
I'm alive, you bastards,
and I always will be.
And I've come
to give you $3,000.
Vamos.
This morning I heard
the whole thing.
Colonel Canby's
closing in with his Northerners.
No later than tomorrow,
they'll be in the city.
That's why these Southerners
are getting out.
As soon as these cowards
hear a blue shirt's around, they run.
These rebels
have no will to fight.
- Poor things.
- They'll soon be finished.
We get rid of these bastards,
then we begin making
money on those Yankees.
They carry gold,
not paper dollars.
And they're going
to beat the South.
Look. See that one with
the white beard sitting in the wagon?
General Sibley.
He looks dead.
He's finally getting
out of our hair.
Hooray for Dixie! Hooray!
Hooray for Dixie!
Where's the owner
of that horse?
- Please, sir, a bad heart...
- Where?
The war has
frightened me already.
I'm looking
for the owner of that horse.
He's tall, blond,
he smokes a cigar, and he's a pig.
- Where is he now?
- Leave him be.
He doesn't know
who rides every horse.
You stay quiet, old hen.
Upstairs.
Upstairs in room four, seor.
Hear that?
You rotten criminals.
How dare you?
Your spurs.
There are two kinds
of spurs, my friend...
those that come in
by the door...
by the window.
Take off that pistol belt.
It's empty.
Mine isn't.
Even when Judas hanged himself,
there was a storm, too.
That could be cannon fire.
Cannon fire or storm,
it's all the same to you.
You ever see this before,
my friend?
Throw it over the roof beam.
That's it.
Now get on that.
That's right.
Now make sure
the rope is tight.
It's got to hold
the weight of a pig.
Now put the rope
around your neck.
That's very good.
It's too big
for your neck, huh?
We'll fix that right away.
I have another system,
a little different than yours.
I don't shoot the rope.
I shoot the legs off the stool.
Adios.
Welcome, my friend.
If you 're looking
for a summer vacation spot,
you 've found it.
Our hotel is luxurious
and filled with conveniences.
And the attractions
don't stop there.
International cuisine,
healthful and nutritious food.
Corn cobs, Dixie style.
Our government
has spared no expense.
As you can see,
we are treated very well.
Have you ever heard of anyone
by the name of Bill Carson?
And you... have you ever heard
of someone named Canby? No?
He's a Yankee colonel
who decided to tear us to pieces.
The only thing we care about
is saving our own hides.
And you ask me if I know someone.
I just don't know what
you drifters could be thinking.
Carson has a patch over one eye.
He's with the Third.
If he's with the Third,
they've already left for Glorietta.
Canby's front line is right on their heels,
those poor young devils.
And the desert lies ahead of them.
I really doubt that
any of them are still alive.
And what if they were still alive?
Worse.
You must not have heard
anything about Batterville.
It's one of those
Yankee prison camps
you 'd better hope
you never end up in.
Keep it, it's yours.
We have found the accused,
Thomas Larson, alias Shorty Larson,
guilty of the following crimes...
horse theft,
theft of supplies
belonging to the Union Army,
theft of supplies belonging
to the Confederate Army,
wounding two vigilantes,
assault and battery
on one named Garry O'Keefe,
burglary, blackmail, robbery,
escaping from a state prison,
disturbing the peace,
pandering...
And Shorty?
...forgery, and murder.
Therefore, with the powers
vested in us...
No.
No?
...the aforementioned
Thomas Larson,
alias Shorty Larson,
to hang by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy
on his soul. Proceed.
Sorry, Shorty.
As soon as I hit the desert,
I'm thirsty.
Burns, huh?
They say people with fair skin
can't take too much.
Like that, you won't
have to carry so much.
Where are we going?
Where?
Where I'm going, amigo.
Over that way.
Another hundred miles
of beautiful sun-baked sand.
Even the armies are afraid
to march through there.
Sibley's men
are retreating up there.
Canby's men are coming here.
But no one will set foot
in this hell...
except you and me.
100 miles.
That's a nice walk.
What was it you told me
the last time?
''lf you save your breath, I feel
a man like you could manage it.''
And if you won't manage it,
you 'll die...
only slowly.
Very slowly, old friend.
After you, please.
Start walking.
Taking a rest?
Come on, Blondie,
we don't have very far to go.
Only 70 miles.
Only 81/2 hours more
before sunset.
That's not too bad.
Come on.
Okay, let's eat.
That is, I'll eat.
Meanwhile, you can
enjoy a sunbath.
You want some water?
Drink. Drink.
Come on, come on.
Well, Blondie, so long.
And so, Blondie...
...it's good-bye.
Easy. Easy.
Easy. Easy. Attaboy.
Water...
Water.
200,000 in gold.
It's yours.
Just get me water.
What's that you say?
Who the hell are you?
Carson...
My name is Bill Carson now.
Surprise attack.
All dead.
Carson, yeah. Glad to meet you.
I'm Lincoln's grandfather.
What was that you said
about the dollars?
200,000. All mine.
It was the Third Cavalry's.
Baker has nothing...
The gold... I hid the gold.
The gold is safe.
Where?
Where, here? Here?
Talk.
The... cemetery.
Which cemetery?
The one... on Sad Hill.
There's a grave by...
Which grave?
Have a name? Have a number?
Come on, you dummy, talk!
There's no number.
There's a name.
- It's written...
- It is?
Water...
You talk first.
I'll give you water later.
Sad Hill Cemetery. Okay.
In the grave. Okay.
But it must have a name
or a number on it!
There must be a thousand...
five thousand!
Water...
Don't die.
I'll get you water.
Stay there.
Don't move.
I'll get you water.
Don't die until later,
you son of a...
Get away from there!
- He's dead.
- Yeah.
I'll kill you.
If you do that,
you 'll always be poor...
just like the greasy rat
that you are.
If I were you,
I'd keep me alive.
What did he tell you?
A name.
A name on a grave.
What name?
Blondie, don't die.
I'm your friend.
Please don't die! Please!
Come on.
Come on!
Blondie? I'll help you.
I'll help you.
Don't move. I'll be right back.
I'll get the water.
Don't die like that pig.
Here, Blondie.
Here's water.
Water, Blondie.
Don't drink!
It's no good for you.
Feel better?
Blondie, what's the matter?
Please don't die!
Hey, open up.
Open up! Hurry.
Settle down, settle down.
Who's there?
What do you mean?
You think I'm the enemy?
If I were a Yankee, you wouldn't
have time to ask me that.
Come on.
Sergeant, listen to this
corporal for a moment.
Yes, sir.
Sergeant, I have a gravely
wounded man here,
if he's not dead already.
He's still alive?
Well, he seems to be.
- What happened?
- It was a trap.
Only the two of us got away.
Name and traveling papers.
Here. Corporal Bill Carson,
Third Regiment,
Second Cavalry Squadron,
arriving from San Rafael.
Is that enough?
You 're reading
while this man is dying.
Corporal, we're trying to withdraw
and you 're looking for an infirmary?
If you want one, you 'll have to
make yourself a Yankee prisoner.
- So where are we?
- Near Apache Canyon.
- Apache Canyon?
- Apache Canyon.
Is the Mission San Antonio
around here?
Sure, 18 miles south.
Take him there.
The brothers take care
of anyone who's wounded.
Keep your eyes open.
The area's full of Yankees.
- Thank you. Good-bye, Sergeant.
- Take care.
Got a very sick man here.
- But we have no more beds.
- Let him have yours.
- Where's Pablo Ramirez?
- Father Ramirez.
He is away at the moment.
He should be back any day now.
Well, it doesn't matter.
For the moment, we take
very good care of my friend.
And may God be praised.
God is on our side, too,
because he hates the Yankees.
Huh, Blondie?
- Father, is he still breathing?
- Yes, of course.
You 're heavy.
All right.
Put a fresh bandage on him.
Put him in my cell.
Easy!
Out, soldier.
Come on.
Look after him, please.
He's like a brother to me.
Hey, Father...
Father, did he speak?
Did he say anything?
Father, did he ask for me?
Did he speak, Father?
No, he hasn't spoken as yet.
You mustn't worry.
He's both young and strong.
That's what's
kept him going until now.
He should regain his strength
in a very short time.
You don't know how much
this boy's life means to me.
Thanks be to Jesus.
Thanks to all of you.
Blondie?
The old father tells me you 'll be
up and around in a few days.
You 're very lucky to have me
so close when it happened.
Think if you 'd been
on your own.
I mean when one is ill,
it's good to have
somebody close by...
friends or relations.
Do you have parents, Blondie?
A mother?
Not even a mother.
No one.
You 're all alone, huh?
Like me, Blondie.
We're all alone in the world.
I have you.
You have me.
Only for a little while, I mean.
It had to happen now.
What a dirty, rotten trick of fate.
We could have all that money
in our hands now.
I must tell you
the truth, Blondie.
In my place, you would
do the same thing.
It's all over for you now.
There's nothing
anyone can do anymore.
Oh, God, look at me.
It's my fault.
Mine. Mine. Mine. Mine.
I'll tell you one thing, Blondie.
If I knew that
my last hour had come, I swear,
in my place... in your place,
I would do the same thing.
I would tell about the gold.
Yes. Yes, I would.
I'd tell the name on the grave.
What good is the money
to you if you 're dead?
I know the name
of the cemetery,
but you know how many graves
there are there?
Please...
Blondie, please, have a little.
Here.
Coffee.
Please, tell me the name...
On the grave.
If I get my hands
on the $200,000,
I'll always honor your memory.
I swear.
Come... closer.
Tell me.
You dirty...
I'll sleep better
knowing my good friend
is by my side
to protect me.
''Tuco, water.''
Well, here's water.
But if I get that name from you,
I'll give you water.
All right, you dirty skunk,
get your ass off the bed.
Come on, come on,
the party's over.
The wagon is all ready to go.
The way the wounded
are pouring in,
we'd better get out of here
before we get caught up in the war.
Tuco, Father Ramirez is back.
This is something
I have to look into.
Get moving.
- Where? This way?
- Yes.
Hey, Pablo?
Don't you recognize me?
It's me! It's Tuco!
Let me embrace you!
I don't know the right thing.
I was passing by here.
I said to myself,
''I wonder if my brother
remembers his brother.''
Did I do wrong?
It doesn't matter.
I'm very happy.
You 've seen me, Tuco.
Yeah, well,
I'm very glad I came.
My uniform!
It's a long story.
But let's talk about you.
It's more important.
You look very well.
A bit thin, perhaps.
You were always thin,
eh, Pablito?
What about our parents?
Only now do you think of them.
To begin after nine years.
Nine years?
So it's nine years.
Nine years!
Our mother has been dead
a long time now.
Our father died
only a few days ago.
That's why I was away.
He asked for you to be there.
But there was only me.
And you?
Outside of evil,
what else have you managed to do?
It seems to me
you once had a wife someplace.
Not one. Lots of them.
One here, one there,
wherever I found them.
Go on. Preach me
a sermon, Pablo.
What good would that be?
Just keep on the way you 're going.
Go away.
And the Lord have mercy
on your soul.
I'll go. And while I'm waiting
for the Lord to remember me,
I, Tuco Ramirez,
brother of Brother Ramirez,
will tell you something.
You think you 're better than I am.
Where we came from, if one
did not want to die of poverty,
one became a priest
or a bandit.
You chose your way,
I chose mine.
Mine was harder!
You talk about
Mother and Father.
When you left to become
a priest, I stayed behind.
I must have been 10, 12... I don't
remember which... but I stayed.
I tried, but it was no good.
Now I'm gonna tell you something.
You became a priest because
you were too much of a coward
to do what I do.
Tuco.
Please forgive me, Brother.
My belly's full.
Nice guy, my brother.
I didn't tell you
my brother was in charge here?
Everything.
Like the pope almost.
He's in charge in Rome.
My brother, he say to me,
''Stay, Brother. Don't go home.
''We never see each other.
''Here there's plenty
to eat and drink.
Bring your friend, too.''
Whenever we see each other,
he never lets me go.
My brother,
he is crazy about me.
That's so.
Even a tramp like me,
no matter what happens,
I know there's a brother somewhere
who will never refuse me
a bowl of soup.
Sure.
Well, after a meal,
there's nothing like a good cigar.
Here's the Sierra Magdalena.
Going this way,
we'll cross the Rio Grande.
That sure is a long way.
Here to the northwest,
through all of Texas.
- After that...
- Then what?
Then we get there.
You 're not worried, are you?
Those men aren't worried about
anything anymore, are they?
But since I'm alive
and I've noticed
we'll be crossing Yankee
and Confederate lines a few times,
I thought you might tell me
where we're going.
Towards $200,000.
Is that good enough for you?
Look.
Hey, wake up, you.
- There are troops coming.
- Blue or gray?
They're gray like us.
Let's say hello, then get going.
Hoorah for the Confederacy!
Down with General Grant!
Hoorah for General...
What's his name?
- Lee.
- Lee. Lee!
God is with us
because he hates the Yanks, too!
God's not on our side,
'cause he hates idiots also.
Hup, 2, 3, 4.
Hup, 2, 3, 4...
Prisoners of war,
forward! March!
Hup, 2, 3, 4...
Halt!
Left... face!
Form a single file. Move!
- Jonathan Ross.
- Present.
- Richard Bouvier.
- Nathaniel Solomon.
- Present.
Robert Clark.
Present.
- Sam Richman.
- Present.
Bill Carson.
Bill Carson?
I said Bill Carson!
Hey, Blondie,
isn't that Angel Eyes?
All right,
what's he doing... sleeping?
Bill Carson!
Yeah. And you 'd better
be Bill Carson.
Bill Carson!
Yeah, that's me.
Please, Carson...
Answer ''present.''
What are you, deaf?
Suppose you say ''present,'' Carson.
I like big fat men like you.
When they fall,
they make more noise.
And sometimes
they never get up.
Wallace...
That's enough.
Sergeant!
The captain wants
to see you right away.
Be sure these two
get good treatment.
Blondie, did you hear that?
Good treatment.
Yeah.
For the last time, Sergeant,
I'm telling you I want
the prisoners treated as prisoners.
No more brutality.
There's hundreds of prisoners
and only a few men to guard them.
What am I supposed to do?
I have to have respect.
I think you 'll manage to gain their
respect by treating them better.
Are our men treated that well
in Andersonville Camp?
I don't give a goddamn
what they do in Andersonville.
While I'm in charge,
the prisoners are not to be tortured
or cheated...
or murdered.
That an accusation?
Sergeant, gangrene
is eating my leg away,
I know the prisoners here
are being robbed systematically.
I know there's scum around
who are bivouacked near the camp,
waiting for someone
to deliver this loot.
But as long as I'm commandant,
I won't permit any such trickery.
Am I clear?
Yes, sir...
Just as long
as you 're the commandant.
Yes, Sergeant.
I know this leg means
I won't last very long,
but I pray I can manage
to have enough time
to amass evidence
and bring to a court-martial
all those
who discredit and dishonor
the uniform of the Union.
I wish you luck.
You and the others
better lay low for a few days.
No, I'll keep this. You go.
Wallace will let you know.
Wallace, bring me Carson.
Right.
Listen, Angel Eyes said
for us to lay low for a few days.
But we'll keep close enough
to keep an eye on things.
Come on,
saddle your horses.
Get in.
Come on in, Tuco.
Don't be bashful.
There's no formalities here.
It's been a long time.
You 're hungry.
Sit down. Eat.
I knew it, I knew it.
The minute I saw you,
I said to myself...
''Look at that pig Angel Eyes.
''I'll bet he got himself
an easy job.
And he never forgets a friend.''
I never forget old friends, Tuco.
Right.
It's good to see
old friends again.
Good.
Especially when they've come
from so far away.
You have so much to talk about.
And you do have a lot
to talk about, haven't you?
You were captured near Fort Craig.
Well, if you were with Sibley,
that means then
that you were coming
from Santa Fe.
Was it hard crossing the desert?
Very hard.
Especially if you don't
have anything to drink.
Why are you going
under the name of Bill Carson now?
One name
is as good as another.
Like you!
I'll bet they don't
call you Angel Eyes.
Sergeant Angel Eyes!
Like a little music
with your meal, Tuco?
Music?
Yes, it's very good.
Very good for the digestion.
So...
Bill Carson's a fake name, huh?
That fake, too?
Bill Carson's name's
written on it.
Have some.
It's Bill Carson's tobacco.
Was Carson dead or alive
when you found him?
What'd he tell you
about the money?
I don't know
what you 're talking about.
More feeling.
You can sure consider yourself
much luckier than your pal.
Wallace will punch your friend
as long as the song goes.
So many of us
have had a session in there.
How's your digestion now?
You 'd better talk.
I have nothing to tell you.
Play that fiddle, you.
I talk.
What did he say
about the money?
It's buried in a grave.
Where?
Sad Hill Cemetery.
Which grave?
I don't know.
I don't know, I tell you.
Blondie...
Ask Blondie.
He knows
the name on the grave.
Blondie...
The war's over for you.
Put those clothes on.
Why?
We're going for a ride.
Where?
To find $200,000.
I know the name
of the cemetery now.
And you know
the name of the grave.
You 're not going to give me
the same treatment?
Would you talk?
No, probably not.
That's what I thought.
Not that you 're
any tougher than Tuco,
but you 're smart enough
to know that talking won't save you.
And Tuco...
Is he...
No. Not yet.
But he's in very good hands.
You 've changed partners,
but you still got the same deal.
I'm not greedy.
I'm only taking half.
There's two of us.
It should make it easier
than just one.
Yeah.
Hold it.
That's it. Don't move.
Now don't breathe.
Still... That's it.
Got it. Thank you.
Hey, Corporal, afraid he'll get lost?
Where's the rebel going?
To hell, with a rope around his neck
and a price on his head.
Yeah. $3,000, friend.
That's a lot of money
for a head.
I'll bet they didn't even
pay you a penny for your arm.
I told you once, friend,
if I ever get you down,
you 're gonna need a lot
of help to get up again.
You 're a lot luckier
than that one there.
You 'll get some grub, a rope,
and you 're all finished.
And there isn't any partner
this time to shoot you down.
Get up.
If your friends
stay out in the damp,
they're liable to catch a cold,
aren't they?
Or a bullet.
Hear that, boys?
Come on out here.
Since we're all going
in the same direction,
might as well go together.
One... two...
three... four...
five... six.
Six. Perfect number.
Isn't three the perfect number?
Yeah, but I got
six more bullets in my gun.
Sure would like to put
your paw on it, huh?
I would like to piss.
It's rough.
I've been shaken up
on this train nearly ten hours now.
You smell like a pig already,
but let's try not
to make things any worse.
Get going.
I can't while you 're watching me.
You made a lot of noise,
my friend.
You don't want to break
our friendship?
Well, I'll break it.
Halt.
Take your places.
Ready.
Aim.
Fire!
Clem, take care of the horses.
I been looking for you
for eight months.
Whenever I should've had
a gun in my right hand...
I thought of you.
Now I find you in exactly
the position that suits me.
I had lots of time to learn
how to shoot with my left.
When you have to shoot, shoot.
Don't talk.
Every gun makes its own tune.
And it's perfect timing,
large one.
Clem, follow him.
Just a minute.
I'll be right there.
Just give me time
to get dressed, and I'll open up.
Put your drawers on
and take your gun off.
Hey, Blondie,
how the hell did you
get out of that pigsty?
I'm here with your
old friend Angel Eyes.
You talked, you traitor.
You talked.
No, I didn't talk.
If I did, I probably
wouldn't be here now.
You... mean...
So only you know
your half of the secret?
Blondie!
I'm very happy
you 're working with me
and we're together again.
I get dressed,
I kill him, be right back.
Listen...
I forgot to mention...
He's not alone.
There's five of them.
Five?
Yeah, five of them.
So that's why you came to Tuco?
It doesn't matter.
I'll kill them all.
They shot him at close range.
Well, look who's here.
The other one will be along.
They'll come looking for us.
Watch out.
There's two of them.
I want that blond alive.
You, back there.
Come on, let's go.
Were you gonna die alone?
Halt!
Hey, Blondie,
Angel Eyes is mine, huh?
All right.
''See you soon, i-idi... ''
''ldiots.''
It's for you.
How peaceful and quiet, amigo.
Like a cemetery, for instance?
There should be a bridge
across that river.
We'd better wait for nightfall.
Trust in me, Blondie.
I got a good sense
of where I'm going.
Tuco has taken you this far.
I will take you all the way...
Gentlemen.
- Tell the captain.
- Yes, sir.
Come along now.
Follow me.
We found them near
the perimeter, sir.
Where do you hail from?
Illinois.
And you?
I'm with him.
Any reason
for being around here?
We want to enlist, General.
You better learn
to distinguish rank.
I'm a captain.
Get the hell out.
It sure as hell might be you today,
so go write your will.
Yes, sir.
So you want to enlist?
You got to take a test
to prove it.
Well, show me.
You 've got a career.
At the least,
I'd say you 'll make colonel.
- Really?
- Sure.
Like it says in the manual,
''You 've got every qualification
to become an expert
in the use of weapons.''
For this, sir, is the most
potent weapon in war.
The fighting spirit's in this bottle.
Volunteers.
You want to enlist?
Let's go.
Come on, gentlemen,
come on.
The shooting hasn't begun yet.
You 're still in time.
Whoever has the most liquor
to get the soldiers drunk
and send them to be slaughtered...
he's the winner.
We and the ones over
on the other side of the river
only have one thing in common...
All of us reek of alcohol.
What did you say your name was?
And you?
No.
Names don't matter.
Yes, because soon you can join
the gallant heroes of Branston Bridge.
We have two attacks a day.
- Two attacks a day?
- Sure.
The rebs have decided that damn
bridge is the key to this whole area.
Stupid, useless bridge.
A flyspeck
on headquarters' maps.
And headquarters has declared
we must take that ridiculous flyspeck...
...even if all of us are killed.
Otherwise, the key will get rusty
and just be a spot on the wall.
And that's not all.
Both sides want the bridge intact.
Intact is how the South wants it,
and we want it intact, too.
You 'll all turn to dust,
but one thing is sure, boys...
the Branston Bridge
will stand unbroken.
Is it bad to speak
the way I do to volunteers?
I've done a lot worse.
I've done it.
I've blown it up... boom!
In here, I've destroyed it all.
It's a court-martial offense
to imagine, to dream of blowing it up.
A serious crime.
Even to think of destroying
that bridge is just...
Why not really blow it up, Captain?
Yeah, Captain, it's nothing.
Let's scare the hell out of them.
I've been dreaming about it.
I've even worked out a plan.
I sure have.
The best time
is after the attack
when there's a truce
to get the wounded.
If I could do it, I could save
many thousands of men.
But what I lack is the guts.
They're beginning
their daily slaughter right on time.
Captain, all companies
are awaiting your orders.
Be right there.
Let's go.
All right, friends, come along
and enjoy the spectacle.
Companies, report!
Company B ready!
Company E ready!
Company D ready!
Companies!
Forward!
Blondie, it looks like the captain
is asking for a bullet in his guts.
Yeah.
I've never seen so many men
wasted so badly.
I have a feeling it's really
going to be a good long battle.
Blondie...
The money's
on the other side of the river.
Where?
Amigo, I said the other side,
and that's enough.
But while the Confederates
are there, we can't get across.
What would happen if somebody
were to blow up that bridge?
Yeah.
Then these idiots would go
somewhere else to fight.
Doctor, quick!
The captain's wounded!
Hurry. A stretcher.
Easy. Easy now.
Get things ready.
A little of this will help.
Take a slug of this, Captain.
What are you doing?
No! Leave me alone!
Blondie...
You realize we might be
risking our lives?
Yeah. And if I get killed,
you 'll never get your hands
on all that beautiful money.
Yeah, Tuco...
It sure would be a pity.
Doc...
Doctor...
If you help me live a little more,
I expect good news.
Why don't we tell each other
our half of the secret?
Why don't we?
You go first.
No, I think it's better that...
...you start.
All right.
The name of
the cemetery is...
Sad Hill.
Now it's your turn.
The name on the grave is...
Arch Stanton.
Arch Stanton?
Are you sure?
Yeah, sure I'm sure.
It'll be a lot easier with that.
Two can dig
a lot quicker than one.
Dig.
You 're not digging.
If you shoot me,
you won't see a cent of that money.
Why?
I'll tell you why.
'Cause there's nothing in there.
- Why, you son of a...
- You thought I'd trust you?
$200,000 is a lot of money.
We're going to have to earn it.
How?
I'll write the name
on the bottom of this stone.
The gun...
You pig!
You want to get me killed?
When'd you unload it?
Last night.
You see, in this world,
there's two kinds of people, my friend...
those with loaded guns...
and those who dig.
- You dig.
- Where?
Here.
''Unk... Unk... ''
There's no name on it.
There's no name here either.
You see, that's what
Bill Carson told me.
It was the grave marked ''unknown''
right beside Arch Stanton.
Go ahead.
Blondie!
It's all ours, Blondie!
You 're joking, Blondie.
You wouldn't play a joke
on me like that?
It's no joke.
It's a rope, Tuco.
Now, I want you to stand up there
and put your head in that noose.
Well, now...
Seems just like old times.
Four for you...
And four...
Four for me.
Blondie...
Sorry, Tuco.
Blondie!
You son of a...
Hey, Blondie!
You know what you are?
Just a dirty son of a b...