It is early Monday morning...
and I am in pain.
My sisters...
and Anna...
are taking turns
staying up.
Good morning.
- Did anything happen?
- No, she's been very quiet.
- Thank you.
- I fell asleep.
Anna, see to the fire.
I thank Thee, dear Lord
for allowing me...
to awaken well and cheerful
this morning...
after a good sleep
under Thy protection...
and for the enjoyment
of a restful night.
I beseech Thee also
today and each day...
to let the angels watch over
and protect my little girl...
whom Thou in Thy unfathomable
wisdom tookest unto Thyself...
in Thy homeland.
Amen.
Mother is in my thoughts
nearly every day...
although she's been dead
for over 20 years.
I remember
she would often seek...
the solitude and peace
of the grounds.
I also remember that I would
follow her at a distance...
and spy on her
without really meaning to...
because I loved her
to such a jealous extreme.
I loved her because
she was so gentle...
and beautiful and alive...
and so all-pervadingly
present.
But she could also be cold,
playfully cruel...
and rebuff me.
Yet I could not help
feeling sorry for her...
and now that I'm older,
I understand her much better.
I wish I could
see her again...
to tell her
what I understand...
of her boredom,
her impatience...
her longing
and her loneliness.
And when the wicked witch
at last realized...
that little Gretel
had tricked her...
her nose started
to grow and grow.
At Twelfth Night
Mother always gave a party...
and Aunt Olga would come
with her magic lantern...
and her fairy tales.
I always felt frightened
and left out.
When Mother spoke to me
in her hurried way...
I could hardly understand
what she wanted of me.
Mother and Maria always had
many things to whisper about...
but then they were so alike.
Jealously I used to wonder what
they were laughing at together.
Everyone was in gay spirits.
I was the only one who couldn't
join in the merriment.
Another time,
I remember it was autumn...
I hid behind the curtain...
and in secret watched her.
She was in the red drawing room
wearing her white dress...
sitting quite still
with her head bent...
and her hands resting
on the table.
Suddenly she saw me...
and in a gentle voice
called me.
- Come.
- Uncertain, I went up to her...
thinking that, as usual,
she was going to scold me.
But instead she gave me
a look so full of sorrow...
that I nearly
burst into tears.
I raised my hand
and put it against her cheek...
and for that moment
we were very close.
There's someone out there.
Anna.
Good morning, Agnes.
Good morning, Doctor.
She is very tired now.
I don't think it will be long.
Thank you.
I know the way.
David!
It's been so long.
When can I see you again?
No!
Some years earlier...
when Agnes had gone to Italy
for her health...
Maria and her husband, Joakim,
were staying at the manor.
One evening, Anna's
little daughter was taken ill...
and Maria sent
for the family doctor...
who lived in the nearby
country town.
- Now say "ah."
- Ah.
- Once again.
That hurt a little?
I can see that.
What a good girl.
That wasn't too bad, eh?
Off to bed with you now.
You'll feel better
after a good night's sleep.
- Thank you.
- Doctor, are you hungry?
If you'd like a little supper
the table's being prepared.
Oh yes, that would be nice.
Thank you.
Agnes and Karin are still
traveling in Italy.
I received a letter
from them last week.
Agnes is much better.
- Her cough is entirely gone.
- Mm-hmm.
And she's picked up
her painting again.
Karin's husband decided
to join them at Easter.
They've been having
good weather.
It's like summer, even though
the nights are chilly.
Your husband, he's well?
Joakim, he had some business
in town this evening...
and won't be back
'til tomorrow.
I told him I would ask you
to come here to look in...
on Anna's little girl.
- He sends his best regards.
- Thank you.
Anna's been told
to get the guest room ready.
The weather's so awful.
I don't think you ought
to go home on such a night.
- You've changed a lot.
- Really? Oh.
Is there anyone else?
Isn't there always?
I never would have thought
the problem could interest you.
Nor does it.
Hmm?
Do you wear spectacles
all the time now?
- Am I bothering you?
- No, it's all right.
Why are you so formal?
Couldn't you let the past
be forgotten?
Come here, Marie.
Come.
Look at yourself
in the mirror.
You're beautiful.
You are probably
more beautiful now than before.
But you have changed
a lot too.
I want you to see
how you've changed.
Now your eyes cast quick,
calculating side glances.
You used to look ahead
straightforwardly...
openly, unmasked.
Your mouth has taken on
an expression of discontent...
and hunger.
It used to be so soft.
Your complexion is pale now.
You use makeup.
Your fine, broad forehead...
now has four wrinkles
above each brow.
No, you can't see it
in this light...
but you can
in broad daylight.
Do you know what
caused those wrinkles?
- No.
- Indifference, Marie.
And this fine line
that runs from ear to chin...
is not as obvious any more...
but it is etched there by
your easygoing, indolent ways.
And there,
by the bridge of your nose.
Why do you sneer
so often, Marie?
You see it?
You sneer too often.
See, Marie?
And look under your eyes.
The sharp,
scarcely noticeable lines...
of your impatience
and your ennui.
Can you actually see
all of that in my face?
No, but I feel it
when you kiss me.
I think
you're joking with me.
It's evident
where you see it.
- Really? Where?
- You see it in yourself.
Because we're so alike,
you and I.
You mean the selfishness?
Coldness? Unconcern?
I usually find
your arguments boring.
Is there no absolution
for such as you and I?
I haven't any need
of being pardoned.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Thank you.
Good morning, Joakim.
- Welcome home.
- Good morning, Maria.
Anna's little girl
is quite ill, you know.
The doctor
was here last night.
He sends you his regards...
and hopes you can get together
to play chess again.
The weather was so bad
I asked him to stay overnight.
He left early this morning
before we were up.
Did you enjoy yourself in town
or was there too much work?
We have an invitation
from the Egermans.
They'd be delighted if we
stayed with them at Easter.
I think I would enjoy that.
It would make for a change.
What do you think about it?
Well, we'll see.
Run along and play.
Joakim.
Help me.
Help me, please.
No.
Anna.
Do you hear?
I only hear the wind
and the clocks ticking.
No, it's something else.
I don't hear anything else.
I'm freezing.
Good night.
Anna.
Come here.
Come to me.
You're so far away.
Come here.
Close to me.
Do I smell very bad?
- It hurts so much, Anna.
- I know, Agnes.
I'm going to stay with you.
- It will all be all right.
- It hurts so badly.
You don't have to worry
when I'm here.
You know that.
The pillow's so warm.
We can take the other one.
Come. Let's see.
Can you lift yourself up
a little?
Can you slide down now?
Is it better so?
Is it better?
You are so good to me.
Yes?
What's the matter?
Agnes is worse.
I don't think she's conscious.
She's breathing very strangely.
I'll get my shawl.
Karin!
- Karin!
- What is it?
- Agnes is worse.
- I'm coming.
- I'll go for the doctor.
- I'll go with you.
Anna! Anna! Anna!
- Where's the doctor?
- He wasn't home.
All right, Anna.
You had better get dressed.
I'll stay with her.
Anna!
I'm much better now.
Only rather warm.
Would you like
to have a wash now?
- And put on a clean gown?
- Yes, thank you.
- I'm a little thirsty.
- Yes, of course.
- Shall I read a little?
- Oh, I'd love it.
"Chapter 34, in which
Mr. Pickwick thinks...
"he had better go to Bath,
and goes accordingly.
"'But surely, my dear sir,'
said little Perker...
"as he stood
in Mr. Pickwick's apartment...
"on the morning
after the trial.
"'Surely you don't really mean,
really and seriously now...
"'and irritation apart...
"'that you won't pay
these costs and damages? '
"'Not one halfpenny,'
said Mr. Pickwick firmly.
"'Not one halfpenny.'
"'Hooray for the principle,
as the moneylender said...
"'when he wouldn't
renew the bill'...
"observed Mr. Weller, who
was clearing away breakfast.
"'Sam,' said Mr. Pickwick...
"'have the goodness
to step downstairs.'
"'Certainly, sir,'
replied Mr. Weller...
"and acting on Mr. Pickwick's
gentle hint, Sam retired."
Anna!
Can't anyone...
Can't anyone help me?
I can't!
Help me!
I can't.
God, our Father,
in His infinite wisdom...
has called you home to Him...
still in the bloom
of your youth.
In your life
He found you worthy...
of bearing a long
and torturous agony.
You submitted to it patiently
and without complaint...
in the certain knowledge that
your sins would be forgiven...
through the death on the cross
of your Lord, Jesus Christ.
May your Father in Heaven...
when you step
into His presence...
have mercy on your soul.
May He let His angels
remove from you the memory...
of your earthly pain.
Should it be...
that you gathered up
our suffering in agony...
into your body.
Should it be
you bore with you...
this hardship
through death.
Should it be
that you meet with God...
as you come to that
other land.
Should it be that
you find his countenance...
turned toward you then.
Should it be that you know
the language to speak...
so this God may hear
and understand.
Should it be that you then
talk with this God...
and he hear you out.
Should it be so...
pray for us.
Agnes, dear child,
please listen.
Listen to what
I have to tell you now.
Pray for us who
have been left in darkness...
left behind
on this miserable Earth...
with the sky above us,
grim and empty.
Lay your burden
at God's feet...
the whole
of all your suffering...
and plead with Him
to pardon us.
Plead with Him
that He may free us...
of our anxiety
and of our weariness...
of our misgivings
and fears.
Plead with Him
that He may make...
sense and meaning
of our lives.
Agnes, you who have borne...
your anguish and suffering
so long...
are most surely worthy...
of advocating our cause.
She was my confirmation child.
We often had talks together
through the many years.
Her faith was stronger
than mine.
If you don't mind,
I could see you tomorrow...
and we can discuss
the formalities of the funeral.
Thank you.
Some years earlier, Karin
and her husband Fredrik...
were pursuing
a diplomatic career.
During a visit
to their native land...
they stayed for some months
at the manor.
Please, Anna, may I have
a little more fish?
- Won't you keep me company?
- No, thank you.
- What are you smiling about?
- I'm not smiling.
Do you want coffee or are we
going to retire immediately?
I don't want coffee.
Thank you.
It's late.
I suggest we retire now.
It's but a tissue of lies.
All of it.
Don't look at me!
Don't look at me
like that, I say!
Sorry.
Forgive me.
Help me to undress.
You may go.
It's but a tissue of lies.
It's a monumental
tissue of lies.
Tissue of lies.
- What are you doing?
- Going through documents...
books and papers
concerning the estate.
Karin, I want us
to be friends.
I want us to talk
to each other.
After all, we're sisters.
We have so many
of the same memories.
Karin, it's so strange how
we don't reach one another...
how we only make small talk.
Karin, why won't you
be my friend?
We've both been
happy and unhappy.
We could laugh and cry
together.
We could talk together
for days and nights on end.
We could put our arms
around each other.
Karin?
I wander through
our childhood home sometimes...
where all is at once
strange but familiar...
and it seems
I am in a dream...
and an event of great importance
is in store for us.
Yes, I know I am childish.
You read much more than I do,
think much more than I do.
Your experience is far greater.
Karin, couldn't we devote
these days...
to getting to know
each other finally?
To coming closer together?
I can't stand to be silent
and distant, Karin.
Karin, have I said something
to hurt you?
It's easy to do, but I didn't
mean to hurt your feelings.
Karin!
What are you reading?
- I'm reading Agnes' diary.
- A diary?
"Thursday, September 30."
She's written, "I received
the most wonderful gift...
"anyone can receive
in this life.
"A gift that is called
many things: Togetherness...
"companionship, relatedness,
affection.
"I think this is
what is called 'grace.'"
No, don't touch me!
Don't come near me!
I can't stand
anyone touching me.
I don't want you to do that.
I don't want it.
I don't want you
to be kind to me.
I can't!
I can't stand it!
Constant torture.
It's like being
in the greatest hell.
I can't breathe any longer.
All of that guilt.
No!
Leave me alone.
Don't touch me.
I am sorry I lost control
of myself this morning.
I don't know what came over me.
I suppose it's all the emotion
concerning Agnes' death.
We were so fond of her.
Now that the funeral is over...
I'll have our lawyer look after
all the legal formalities.
The fruit please, Anna.
It's best we sell
the house and grounds.
You and I can divide up
all the rest of it.
I mean, the furniture
and other things...
like china, silverware,
books and pictures.
All right, Anna,
that will be all now.
What shall we do about Anna?
I suggest
that we give her notice...
and a few weeks extra pay.
And also a little article
of Agnes'.
She was quite devoted.
The fact of it is that
they were very attached.
Now she trails after us
in much too familiar a manner.
I don't think...
It's true.
I think...
about suicide.
I've often thought about it.
It's...
It's disgusting.
It's very degrading...
and everlastingly the same.
Henrik's an excellent lawyer,
I assure you.
My husband says
that I'm clumsy.
He's right.
I fumble.
My hands are too large,
you understand.
Most disobedient.
You look so disconcerted.
You thought our talk
would be different, didn't you?
Do you realize I hate you?
And how foolish I find
your insipid smiles...
and your idiotic
flirtatiousness.
How have I managed
to tolerate you so long...
and not say anything?
I know of what you're made...
with your empty caresses
and your false promises.
Can you conceive how anybody
can live with so much hate...
as has been my burden?
There's no relief,
no charity, no help.
There is nothing.
You understand?
Nothing can escape me...
for I see it all.
Now you hear how it sounds
when Karin talks.
You sit there grinning
your cold little grin.
What are you thinking?
Would you care to tell me?
May I have your opinion?
No!
That's just what I thought.
You'd rather stay silent.
And you are right, Maria!
Maria! Forgive me.
Maybe you mean well.
Maybe you just
want to know me better.
Maria, dear, forgive me.
I do run on and on.
No.
No, that's not true either.
Maria, look at me.
Don't you hear it?
Don't you hear the crying?
Someone is crying endlessly.
- Are you afraid of me now?
- No, not in the least.
I'm dead, you see.
The trouble is
I can't get to sleep.
I can't leave you all.
I'm so tired.
Can't anyone help me?
- It's but a dream, Agnes.
- No, it's not a dream.
Perhaps for you it's a dream...
but not for me.
I want Karin to come here.
Agnes wants Karin
to come to her.
Can't you hold my hands
and warm me?
Stay with me
until the horror is over.
It's so empty all around me.
Nobody would do what you ask.
I'm still alive.
I won't accept involvement
with your death.
Perchance, if I had loved you...
but I do not love you.
What you ask me to do
is repulsive.
I'm leaving you now.
In a few hours I'll be gone.
- Anna.
- Yes.
I want Maria to come.
Agnes wants Maria to come in.
Don't be afraid.
Please touch me.
Please talk with me.
Hold my hands and warm me.
You are my sister.
I don't want you to be alone.
Oh, how sorry I am for you.
Do you recall
when we were small...
and twilight came
as we played...
and both of us
became frightened...
and we'd cuddle very close
and hold each other tight.
It's simply the same thing now,
isn't it?
I can't hear
what you're saying.
You must come closer to me.
Closer.
Hold my hands.
I'll stay with you.
I'll stay here.
Don't cry.
You needn't be afraid.
I'll stay by her.
There's my daughter
I must think about.
She must realize that.
Also, my husband needs me.
It's pure morbidity,
disgusting, meaningless.
She's already begun to rot.
She has foul spots
on her hands.
I'll take care of her.
The funeral was tolerable.
No one wept or grew hysterical.
Thank you.
Have you finished packing, Anna?
I just have to bring
the last trunk down, ma'am.
Hurry up.
We are pressed for time.
The music was fine. Thankfully,
the bishop's address was short.
Fortunate that he had a chill
so we could call off the dinner.
Hadn't something
better be done for Anna?
Sorry, but I don't understand
what you mean.
She's looked after Agnes
for the last 12 years.
Shouldn't we offer her
a small sum...
or help her find a new place?
Out of the question.
She's young and strong...
and has had it very easy
up until now.
Her future
is not our responsibility.
I did promise her she could
take a memento with her.
- Of her own choosing?
- I think she has that right.
I do detest
that sort of spontaneity...
but you can't renege.
I think we should
speak to her right away.
Anna, you may stay on here
for a time if it is necessary.
You were promised
a memento of Agnes'.
Thank you.
I want nothing at all.
She's trying
to play a nice role.
But she won't
get anything for it.
- Stay 'til the month's end.
- Yes.
Well, if there's nothing left
for us to attend to.
Let's leave before the roads
to the station are snowed under.
Good-bye now, Anna.
Thank you.
Thank you for all you did.
Hurry now.
- Could I speak to you a second?
- Of course.
That evening we came close
to each other...
have you thought
about what we discussed?
Yes, of course,
I've thought a lot about it.
Could we hold
to all of our resolutions?
Dearest Karin, why on earth
shouldn't we do that?
I have no idea.
It's that everything seems
different since that evening.
I think we've become
very much closer.
What are you thinking about?
I'm thinking
about the conversation...
- No, you're not.
- I was thinking how Joakim...
hates it
if I keep him waiting.
I have no idea
why you call me to account...
as if I were on trial
for my thoughts, Karin.
What do you want?
- Nothing.
- No.
If there's nothing you want,
don't be hurt...
because I must say good-bye
to you now.
You touched me.
Don't you remember that?
I don't recall
each stupid act...
and never try forcing me
to answer for one.
Dearest Karin, give the children
my love and keep well.
'Til Twelfth Night.
As usual, we'll meet then.
How sad.
"Wednesday,
the third of September.
"The tang of autumn
fills the clear, still air...
"but it's mild and fine."
My sisters, Karin and Maria,
have come to see me.
It's wonderful
to be together again...
like in the old days,
and I am feeling much better.
We were even able to go
for a little walk together...
such an event for me...
especially since I haven't
been out of doors for so long.
Suddenly we began to laugh
and run toward the old swing...
that we hadn't seen
since we were children.
We sat in it like three
good little sisters...
and Anna pushed us,
slowly and gently.
All my aches and pains
were gone.
The people I am most fond of
in all the world were with me.
I could hear their chatting
around me.
I could feel the presence
of their bodies...
the warmth of their hands.
I wanted to hold the moment fast
and thought:
"Come what may,
this is happiness.
"I cannot wish
for anything better.
"Now, for a few minutes...
"I can experience perfection.
"And I feel profoundly grateful
to my life...
"which gives me so much."