Andrei Rublev
(The Passion According to Andrei)
Scenario: Andrei Mikhalkov-Konchalovsky
and Andrei Tarkovsky
Direction: Andrei Tarkovsky
Photography: Vadim Yusov
Art Direction: E. Chernyaev,
E. Novoderezhkin, S. Voronkov
Music: Viacheslav Ovchinnikov
Assistant Director: I. Petrov
Sound: I. Zelentsova
Editing: L. Feignova, Makeup: V. Rudina
Costumes: L. Novi, M. Baronovska
Intern Director: B. Oganesyan, Second
Assistant Directors: A. Macheret,
M. Volovich, A. Nikolaev
Camera Operator: V. Sevostyanov
Assistant Camera: A. Andrianov,
R. Ruvinov, P. Sudilin
Sets: E. Korablev
Special Effects:
V. Sevostyanov, P. Safonov
Historical Advisers: V. Pashuto,
S. Yamshchikov and M. Mertsalova
State Film Orchestra and
All-Union Radio Chorus
Conducted by Viachesalov Ovchinnikov
Producer: T. Ogorodnikova
Andrei Rublev: Anatoly Solonitsin,
Kirill: lvan Lapikov,
Danil Chorny: Nikolai Grinko
Theophanes the Greek: Nikolai Sergeyev
Durochka " Idiot Girl": Irma Raush
Boriska: Nikolai Burlyaev,
The Grand Prince,
and his brother: Yuri Nazarov
Supporting Cast
The Passion According to Andrei
Part One
- Pull the rope.
- This one?
- Arkhip, give me the strap.
- Hold it.
Take it.
Look!
It's Yefim, isn't it?
- Come here and help.
- Pull the rope.
- Hold on a second.
- Come on, quick!
Where is it?
- Where is it?
- Here.
Come on, fast.
Lift it.
Lord. Let it go right.
Untie it now.
The rope is tangled.
Hold it!
We won't have enough time.
I'm ready!
Archipushka! You try to hold them!
Just a second.
Come on!
Hold him, hold him!
I'm here. I'm here.
Cut the rope, man!
Cut the rope!
I'll show you, cut the rope!
My God!
Yefim!
- Where are you going?
- Archipushka!
I'm flying! I'm flying!
Hey! Chase me! Chase me!
My God! What is it?
Archipushka!
THE JESTER
Summer 1 400
Danil!
Danil! The Father
told you to go back!
There is no one to paint the icons.
For God's sake!
It's no business of yours.
You will be sorry for that. You
will come begging on your knees.
But the Father will not forgive you.
Come on. You never know.
We shall see.
It's not good.
What?
That we are leaving Troitsa.
It's a shame.
Aren't there enough painters
in Moscow without us, Danil?
We'll find some sort of work.
All this is right, but it's a pity that...
I passed this birch every
day and never noticed it.
When you know you'll never
see it again, it means something.
It's been ten years. Nine
for you, but ten for me.
No, seven for me, nine for you.
- It's raining.
- Come on here.
Let's go. We will not melt.
The jesters were walking.
Drunk on mead and beer...
...when they met their
master, the Boyar...
...and they sang, to greet him:
O master. O Boyar...
...everything is ready in the kitchen!
The Boyar's plump
wife is a choosy trollop.
Mistress, open the door.
The master's coming!
The Boyar yells: "Jesters are
all thieves and drunkards!
"You should be whipped
from Friday to Friday!"
"You goats and tramps,
drown in your beer!
"Soon you will be impaled!"
The Jesters grabbed him
between his navel and his knees.
They shaved his beard; what's
a Boyar without his beard?
Any woman would
rather he had a beard.
The Boyar yells,
hops about like a flea.
He scurries home,
raps on the window.
But his wife doesn't
recognize his naked cheeks...
...with no beard to grab hold of.
She whacked him with a rolling pin.
What a disgrace!
"Cover your naked cheeks
with your breeches.
"Clear off, beardless Boyar!"
He hobbled off, pursued by geese...
...and met a priest...
...who mistook him for a woman and
dragged him into the bushes.
Without breeches...
...he looks the same at each end.
The woman saw a naked head...
...and grabbed it by the beard.
May we shelter from the storm?
Come in.
Do you want some beer?
You are soaking wet.
Thank you, we don't imbibe.
And don't play around with women.
God sent priests, but
the devil sent jesters.
The woman saw a head!
By the beard!
My woman might have
been playing in the bushes.
I'll show you!
Come here, you.
What are you doing?
Give it back to him.
Where were you, Kirill?
Outside. Shall we go?
Danil, the rain's stopped; let's go.
Christ be with you, mistress.
THEOPH ANES THE GREEK
Summer-Winter-Spring-Summer
1 405-1 406
I'm innocent!
Let me go!
Is anyone in here?
Have you come to look?
Yes, to look.
Then look. We'll soon be finished.
So you are Theophanes the Greek?
Why look at me? Look there.
Where are you from?
From Andronnikov Monastery.
From Andronnikov Monastery?
Are you by chance Andrei Rublev?
No.
I've heard everyone
praise this Rublev.
He's good, but not as good as this.
Such delicate colors.
Oh Lord, it's just...
Why did you stop
praising me? Go on.
I can't. I can't find the right words.
Konstantin Kostechevsky
was right when he said:
"Only with true insight...
"...can you grasp its essence."
Whereas Andrei... and
I'll tell him to his face...
He's like my brother.
He's praised, it's true:
he paints well. With subtlety.
But there's something
lacking in all his work.
There's no awe, no faith...
...no faith that comes from
the depths of his soul.
No simplicity.
As Epiphanius said in
"The Life of Saint Sergeius":
"Simplicity, without gaudiness."
That is what this is. It's sacred.
Simplicity, without gaudiness...
you can't say it better.
I see you are a wise man.
If so, is that a good thing?
If one is ignorant, isn't it better
to be guided by one's heart?
In much wisdom
there is much grief...
...and he who increases
knowledge increases sorrow.
Proshka! Where is that oil?
Whose ears should I box?
It is as though the earth
has swallowed everyone.
They say you paint quickly.
I cannot work any
other way. I get bored.
I wasted a week on an icon once.
You threw it away?
No. I used the board
to press cabbage.
It's all so boring.
I have pupils and
assistants in abundance...
...but none of them is any good.
They can neither read nor write.
Listen, help me. Be my assistant.
Don't make fun of me.
I'm not making fun of you.
In spring, I must paint the Church
of the Annunciation in Moscow...
...and I have no
assistants to do it with.
The scaffolding is being built.
- Do you understand?
- I do understand.
But I wouldn't be able to cope.
I'll teach you. You never
prepared a wall for a fresco?
You've a brain; even these
idiots can prepare a wall.
I said no and I mean no.
You know best...
...but mind you don't
regret it; I am rancorous.
I may regret it, but it's a sin for you.
An unknown monk comes to you...
...and you like the fact that you
can talk about books with him...
...and you decide to
take him and favor him.
But I haven't looked at a book for
three years and I don't want to.
- Why?
- I have a different road.
Wicked bastards!
Where is Proshka? Where is Vikenty?
They ran to the square to see how
they were going to kill the ruler.
Wicked bastards!
See?
And you don't want to help?
- I shall die soon.
- You shouldn't say that.
The other night I
dreamed of an angel.
He said: "Come with me."
I said: " I shall die soon, without you."
You won't change
your mind, will you?
Only on one condition.
Whatever you want.
Money? Half my fee, okay?
No. I'll work for nothing
if you yourself...
...come to Andronnikov
Monastery to fetch me.
Before the community, the
metropolitan, ask me to help you...
...before the brotherhood,
before Andrei Rublev.
Then I shall serve you like a slave...
...like a dog, until the day I die.
What is your name?
Kirill.
Orthodox Christians, lovers of truth.
How long will this torture go
on, when will you end this?
You are thoughtless
sinners, yet you judge.
You faithless heathens!
He has already seven
times atoned for his sins...
...for both his sins and yours.
You are incredible
sinners yourselves.
And you judge...
...but you don't have God with you.
Rejoice, O young man, in thy youth...
...and let thy heart cheer thee
in the days of thy youth.
Walk in the ways of thine heart,
and in the sight of thine eyes...
...but know that for all these...
...God will bring thee into judgment.
Remember now thy Creator
in the days of thy youth...
...before the difficult days come...
...and the years draw nigh,
when thou shalt say...
..."I have no pleasure in them."
Remember thy Creator...
...before the silver cord be loosed.
Or the golden bowl be broken...
...or the pitcher
shattered at the fountain...
...or the wheel broken at the well.
Then shall the dust return
to the earth as it was...
...and the spirit shall return
unto God who gave it.
"Vanity of vanities,"
saith the preacher; "All is vanity."
Kirill, have you seen Father Nikodim?
Where has he got to
since this morning?
He took my gloves, then disappeared
as though the earth swallowed him.
I have to chop wood
and the logs are icy.
Why is your candle
burning? It's daylight.
Did you feed my dog?
Did you ask me to?
What's the matter with you?
Go away.
The words of the wise are like
goads, and the words of scholars...
...are like well-driven nails,
given by one Shepherd.
And further, my son, you
should stay away from these.
Of making many
books there is no end...
...and much study is
wearisome to the flesh.
Let us hear the conclusion
of the whole matter...
Fear God and keep
His commandments...
...for this is man's all.
A messenger has come!
Who has come? A messenger
from Moscow has come.
A messenger has come
from the Grand Prince.
- So?
- So so!
A messenger from
Theophanes the Greek.
The Grand Prince
orders you to Moscow...
...to paint the Cathedral of the
Annunciation, with Theophanes.
Is he really Andrei
Rublev, this fellow?
Yes, he's Rublev... and I'm Kirill.
Theophanes the Greek says
he wants you in Moscow...
...and he wishes to see you.
I thank Theophanes.
Tell him...
...that I'll come.
I'll come.
My head is splitting!
Bring my horse here.
What is wrong?
Choose whichever helpers you
like and be ready tomorrow.
Is there a blacksmith
here? If not, I'll fall off again.
There is a smithy outside,
beyond the chapel.
Farewell, God-fearing people!
Semyon! Come here!
Come here and help us!
Why are you standing? Come here!
Let's go today, shall we, Danil?
Go quickly, before
Theophanes changes his mind.
I'm not going.
Why aren't you going?
How can I manage without you?
As best you can.
I thought we'd go together.
Why did you think for
me? I was not invited.
I can't do it without you.
You can; you agreed
to go without asking me.
Theophanes simply beckoned.
Don't grieve; you're
not the first, or the last.
Even without you there's
plenty of work for me here.
Thank God for it.
Foma, Aleksei. Let's get ready.
Piotr, you're coming with me.
Did you forget something, Andrei?
I came to say farewell.
We've said farewell.
I came to say farewell, but...
It was hard for me before.
Then the devil created
enmity between us.
I can't go away like this.
I must make confession.
Will you hear it?
I cannot do anything, Danil...
...after living so many years
together in the same cell.
Apart from you, I have no one.
I see the world with your eyes.
I hear it with your ears...
...with your heart.
I am happy for you, you old fool.
If only you knew how happy.
Go to Moscow. Paint;
I shall be proud of you.
The devil tempted me the
other day too. Forgive me.
I'll come back, Danil.
Where are you going?
What about Vespers?
I'll manage without you.
What's wrong with you today, Kirill?
I'm tired of lying. I'm going
back into the secular world.
Why did we leave
the Trinity Monastery?
Andrei, Danil, you are
not saying anything.
Because the brothers valued
profit higher than faith.
They forgot why they had
entered a monastery. And now?
We sought to praise God with faith
and work, but what's happened?
The monastery's become a bazaar.
Servant of God, how many souls
did you trade in for monasticism?
Twenty or thirty?
And you ran after the
Father Superior, bargaining.
For two meadows, or even one,
you bought eternal salvation.
You don't need me to tell you,
but you prefer to keep quiet.
Perhaps I would also tolerate all
this loathsomeness if I had talent.
But what talent? Just a
slight ability to paint icons.
God be praised that
He gave me no talent.
I'm happy I'm untalented; I can
be honest and pure before God.
You are taking sin upon your soul!
I'll tell you something else, brothers.
What do you want to tell us
that we don't know already?
Do you know what happens to your
sort? Speak! I won't get offended!
Well, I...
Get out, you dog!
Out of my sight, you serpent!
Rejoin the secular world, slanderer!
Now do you see?
Kirill!
It is written: " And Jesus
went into the temple of God...
"...and cast out all them that
sold and bought in the temple...
"...and overthrew the tables
of the money changers...
"...and the seats of them
that sold doves.
" And said unto them," it is written,
" My house shall be called...
"...the house of prayer; but ye
have made it a den of thieves."
For three years I was
cleaning brushes for Danil...
...before he let me touch an icon.
And then only to clean it.
Don't you trust me?
You're always lying, Foma.
Yesterday your robe was
sticky; where were you?
At the beehive.
But you said you
were at the monastery.
Just look at yourself.
Put mud or something
on your cheek...
...or you will swell, like a hog.
It's too late now, it's useless.
You're constantly making up stories.
I even think you have a disease.
Me? What disease?
There is a disease where a
man lies without stopping.
Look, Foma.
Look, I say.
What?
You think you know everything so
I'm not going to teach you any more.
Why should I learn?
Anyway, I will have to spend
three years cleaning the brushes.
I'm sick and tired of you, Foma.
Go back to the monastery,
go wherever you want.
I can't understand why
I took you as a pupil.
You are always like that. First
you say one thing then another.
You yourself told
Theophanes I was perceptive.
You were different then;
you worked, you didn't lie.
And do you know
what Theophanes said?
" What does it matter
if he's perceptive?"
Whatever Theophanes has said...
...I can see blue colors
better than anyone else.
You eat too much; how can you
paint with a bloated stomach?
When your stomach's rumbling,
how can your mind work?
The rumbling is the
only sound you hear.
You're lucky, Foma. For
you, everything is simple.
If you are not painting, you
are sleeping or fooling around.
But only by prayer can
the soul transcend the flesh.
Would you go to learn from
another teacher instead of me?
Why not, if you tell me to go?
Come on, come on. Don't be angry.
What's that?
So you've decided to put
the apostle on the left, Andrei.
Did you take the glue off the fire?
Perceptive is he?
He should be beaten
every Saturday, like a dog.
You're obstinate, Andrei.
How did you see so much? Everyone
else is thinking only of himself.
I saw it, Theophanes.
The women of Moscow
gave their hair to the Tatars.
What else could the
poor creatures do?
Better to lose their hair than
be tortured. Is that heroic?
It is.
It is true that Russian women
are humiliated and unhappy.
It's not what I mean.
Tell me honestly, are the
people ignorant or not?
Well, are they?
They're ignorant, but
whose fault is that?
It's their own stupidity. Have you
never sinned through ignorance?
Everyone has.
And I have too. God forgive
us and make us better.
Well, never mind.
The Last Judgment is coming;
we'll burn like candles.
Mark my words.
Each will accuse the other of
his own sins, to defend himself.
Theophanes, how can you paint with
such ideas, even accept praise?
I have become a hermit
and lived in a cave.
I serve God, not man.
As regards praise, what is praised
today is abused tomorrow.
They will forget you, me, everything.
All is vanity and ashes. Worse
things have been forgotten.
Humanity has already committed
every stupidity and baseness...
...and now it only repeats them.
Everything is an eternal circle
and it repeats and repeats itself.
If Jesus returned to earth,
they would crucify him again.
Of course, if only
evil is remembered...
...then you will never be
happy in the sight of God.
Perhaps we must forget
some things; but not all.
I don't know how to say it.
Then be quiet and listen to me.
You think that one can
only do good alone?
Good. Remember
the New Testament.
Jesus taught people in the temples...
...so why did they
gather later? To kill him!
"Crucify him!" they shouted.
And the disciples? Judas
sold Him. Peter denied Him.
They all ran away,
yet they were the best.
But they repented.
That was afterwards,
when it was too late.
It's never too late to repent.
Of course, people do evil.
But you can not
blame them altogether.
It's difficult...
...and sinful, I think.
Judas sold the Christ, and
remember who bought him.
People.
And who accused Jesus?
The scribes and Pharisees...
...they could not find witnesses,
however hard they tried.
"Who will testify against this innocent?"
Only later on they found the traitors.
Two were found immediately.
Two, and not one.
There were only two.
The Pharisees were
masters of deceit, educated.
They had studied to gain power...
...to take advantage of
the people's ignorance.
We must remind people more
often that they are people.
Russians, of the same
blood, of the same land.
Evil is everywhere.
Someone will always sell
you for thirty pieces of silver.
New misfortunes constantly
befall the peasant...
...either Tatars three times an
autumn, or famine, or plague...
...and he still keeps on
working, working, working...
...meekly bearing his cross.
He does not despair,
he is silent and patient.
He only prays to God
for enough strength.
How could God not
forgive him his ignorance?
You know yourself. You're
tired and discouraged...
...and suddenly...
...in the crowd you
meet a human glance...
...and everything's lighter,
as it is after Communion.
Isn't it so?
You just spoke of Jesus.
Perhaps He was born and
crucified to reconcile God and man.
Jesus came from God,
so He is all-powerful.
And if He died on the cross,
it was predetermined...
...and His crucifixion
and death were God's will.
That would have aroused hatred
not in those who crucified Him...
...but in those who loved Him...
...if they had been near
Him at that moment...
...because they loved
Him as a man only.
But if He, of His own will, left them...
...He displayed injustice,
or even cruelty.
Maybe those who
crucified Him loved Him...
...because they helped
in this divine plan.
Do you understand
what you are saying?
They'll exile you to the north,
man, to renovate the icons.
Am I not right? You too
always say what you think.
But I'm not a monk; I'm free.
THE HOLID AY
Spring 1 408
Sergei, over here!
Light the fire.
Foma, let's get some logs.
Piotr has probably never seen...
...either Assumption Cathedral
or Saint Dmitry Cathedral.
Never mind, he will begin
working, and understand things.
Foma! Where are you?
We won't be on time.
It's okay, we'll be there tomorrow.
No. We'll never finish the Cathedral
of the Assumption by winter.
It's almost June, Andrei.
What is it?
Quiet! Do you hear it?
Nightingales?
Nothing else?
Come on.
- What is it?
- Come on.
They're practicing witchcraft.
Where are you going?
Come to me.
Hold on.
Darling.
Take your hand away.
There is an anthill.
Anthill?
Anthill.
- Who is this?
- I don't know.
Let's go.
It seemed to me...
...as if a black snake
was hiding himself.
What are you doing?
Let me go!
We'll let you go.
At dawn, we'll hang a stone around
your neck, to help you swim.
Heaven's fire will consume you!
The Last Judgment awaits!
Now we'll tie you to this cross...
...like Jesus Christ.
What are you doing, men?
You can't do this to me.
This is a sin. At least
hang me upside-down.
Men, brothers!
Leave him here for the night,
unless he ascends again.
He's not going anywhere.
- And who is this?
- Marfa.
Why did you want to be head
down? It would have been worse.
Why did you threaten us
with fire from heaven?
It is a sin to go naked
and do what you do.
What sin? Tonight is for
lovemaking; is love a sin?
Is it love to tie a man up like this?
You might call the monks...
...who would force us
to accept your faith.
Do you think it's easy to live in fear?
You live in fear because you
know no love but bestial love.
Carnality without soul; but
love should be brotherly.
Isn't all love the same? It's just love.
What are you doing?
Untie me.
Why are you looking at me?
Where were you?
Thank God.
Are these the people?
No, these are strangers.
Don't you see it?
There is some onion, if you want it.
Where were you?
These forests are impenetrable;
I'm all scratched.
The local people like it.
They are accustomed to it.
For people, everything
is a matter of custom.
Old people don't need to think...
...for their days pass
according to custom.
But perhaps they consciously
enjoy the way the days drag on.
- Couldn't you get here before?
- No. I couldn't.
That is your sin, your
conscience, your prayers.
Get him, and her!
Why are they doing that?
Because the accursed pagans
don't believe in one God.
Don't look, Sergei. There
is nothing to look at.
Let me go!
- Let me go!
- You can't see that!
Kick him so he shuts up!
Go, go! Don't dawdle!
Help, Fyodor! Help!
Fyodor!
Can't you deal with a woman?
Stop!
Hold her!
Marfa, run!
Catch her!
- Where are you going?
- She will drown herself!
Marfa! Run, Marfa!
Swim, Marfa!
THE LAST JUDGMENT
Summer 1 408
Come here!
He's just wasting materials.
Who needs it?
Foma!
- What do you want?
- Can I go for a swim?
- No, you can't.
- It's hot!
Don't be lying. It's not.
Maybe he's really hot. I'm hot too.
Of course, you are
working and he is sitting.
Let him go swim.
Don't spoil him.
Let him be sitting with everyone.
You shut up!
You sleep all day long like a log...
...and you come down only
to eat and go to the bathroom.
And have you found a job for me?
- You have found what you wanted.
- So what?
Since everyone is sitting here,
let Serezhka be sitting with us too.
If you had let him go, he
would have been back already.
Give him freedom...
...and he will sit in the
water until he turns blue.
He only thinks that it's hot...
...and that's why he is whining.
- He's not whining, you are.
It was me.
I was the first to say
it's hot, and not Sergei.
Why are you picking on Sergei?
That's it!
You want to go swimming, go!
Go! Why are you sitting?
Go, go!
Here! You see?
Wait! Wait!
Where's Andrei?
Not here? This is a
fine state of affairs.
I was at our bishop's house just now.
Such a fuss. Yelling!
He was purple with rage.
" I've lost patience!" he cried.
He meant you. All of you.
" For two whole months," he said,
"everything has been ready.
" But they haven't started yet.
" Nothing is ready; they asked for
so much money, but do nothing.
" None of them is working
and nothing is ready."
Did you ask for a lot of money?
How do I know?
He said, " I don't care. Danil
Chorny or Andrei Rublev...
"...it's all the same to me."
" It's all the same."
And he pulled a face like this.
" What do I care
about Andrei Rublev?
" By autumn," he says...
"...I want the cathedral
painted, and that's that!"
He's sent a courier with a
complaint to the Grand Prince.
He's sent a courier
to the Grand Prince.
It's a complaint about you, you know.
You haven't started yet.
You'd better hurry
up. Where's Andrei?
He's gone somewhere again.
Can't you start without him?
Go on, start without him.
Why are you smirking?
There are so many of you.
If he can't make his mind
up, can't one of you?
Two heads are better than one.
Where is Andrei?
I can't go on like that.
Answer me: yes or no?
Yes or no? Wasn't
everything decided in Moscow?
To the smallest detail; the Prince
said everything was in order.
What is not clear? What have we
been discussing for two months?
Explain it to me. I may be
old, I may have lost my wits.
The Last Judgment; either you
accept the task and paint it...
...or you refuse the commission.
And if we really refused?
If we went back, Danil?
How shall I face people?
I should die of shame.
We're wasting such good
time. This heat, no rain.
We could have finished
the cupola and the columns.
How wonderfully they
could have been done...
...how brightly, and beautifully.
On the right, the sinners...
...boiling in pitch, painted
to make your flesh crawl.
I have thought of a great devil,
with smoke from his nose and eyes.
- It's not the smoke that matters.
- Then what matters?
I don't know.
- Why aren't you looking at me?
- Because I can't.
I can't paint all that; it disgusts me.
I don't want to terrify people.
Understand me, Danil.
Collect yourself! Listen!
It's the Last Judgment!
I didn't invent it.
I can't do it. Do as
you will, but I can't.
Why didn't you speak
earlier, in Moscow?
You shouldn't have agreed.
This is dishonest.
I am what I am. You
couldn't teach me integrity.
I don't know what to paint.
What do you mean, you don't know?
We were ordered to
paint the Last Judgment.
You see...
...I think it will be better...
...if we don't paint the
Last Judgment at all.
What do you mean?
You know.
I want...
I don't want anything.
- Nothing.
- That's it.
Well, I'm leaving.
This is no work for me.
Thanks for your kindness and
your slaps; I learned something.
But now I'm going to work for myself.
They've asked me to
paint a church at Pafnutievo.
Not a great honor,
but it's still an honor.
I'm going to paint the Last Judgment.
Who will come with me?
Well, then, stay...
...but don't complain later.
When I was a child...
...I spake as a child, I understood
as a child, I thought as a child...
...but when I became a man,
I put away childish things.
For now we see
through a glass, darkly...
...but then face to face...
...now I know in part...
...but then shall I know...
...even as also I am known.
And now abideth...
...faith, hope, and charity...
...but the greatest of these is charity.
Though I speak with the
tongues of men and of angels...
...and have not charity...
...I am become as sounding
brass, or a tinkling cymbal.
And though I have
the gift of prophecy...
...and understand all
mysteries, and all knowledge...
...and though I have all faith, so
that I could remove mountains...
...and have not charity, I am nothing.
And though I bestow all
my goods to feed the poor...
...and though I give my body to
be burned, and have not charity...
...it profiteth me nothing.
Charity suffereth long, and
is kind; charity envieth not...
...charity vaunteth not
itself, is not puffed up...
...doth not behave
itself unseemly...
...seeketh not her own, is not
easily provoked, thinketh no evil...
...rejoiceth not in iniquity,
but rejoiceth in the truth...
...beareth all things...
...believeth all things, hopeth
all things, endureth all things.
Charity never faileth...
...but whether there be
prophecies, they shall fail...
...whether there be
tongues, they shall cease...
knowledge, it shall vanish away.
For we know in part...
Princess, is that nice?
It's sinful to splash milk.
Such a naughtiness.
- Why is it sinful?
- Because... wipe it off.
But it will dry by itself in a minute.
Let's walk by the stream.
Let me go, Stepan, or I'll
send you to the stables.
How do you like it?
I couldn't imagine it
better. It's light, beautiful.
It's light.
Take her out. Her
nurses have spoiled her.
I say!
No one can build a
mansion better than us.
Who could paint like that?
Look at the carving.
Only Mitiai can do this
directly, without tracing.
It's like a bird singing.
Look. Maybe it is like a bird singing.
I don't care. I can sleep on the
hay. You are the Grand Prince.
Don't you like it?
I'll tell you this. It
should be repainted.
Walls, ceiling, everything:
brighter, stronger colors.
I've been in this trade for forty years.
It's not the years that matter...
...but your ability to glorify the
Grand Prince with your work.
That's enough. Go.
We won't redo anything.
It's time to go. We have another job.
They are waiting for us in Z venigorod.
Where?
At your brother's. They
have the stone already.
A beautiful stone. Whiter than this.
When your brother came at Easter...
...we made a deal and he said: " Do
what you like, whatever the cost.
" I'll tax the peasants more, just
build me the best mansion possible."
Then go to Z venigorod.
Here, I have brought it.
When I looked at the
Prince, he became numb.
- When I mentioned Z venigorod?
- Yes, he became paralyzed.
He fears his brother will outshine him.
- Who carved that?
- I did.
Why didn't you set it in the wall?
It didn't come out right.
Pity; it's rather good.
Everything crumbles: I told the Prince
to spare no expense on the stone.
Maybe now he's sorry when
he heard about Z venigorod.
I could have carved
beautiful things for him.
Come on, you ass!
Where's Stepan?
Where did Stepan gallop to?
He went to Z venigorod
with the others.
I've dirtied my hands.
We'll build another mansion just
as good for the Prince's brother.
Will the stone be better there?
Yes, it will.
Look, the Captain of the Guard.
Hold on, old man.
You, ass! Help him! In the bushes!
Where's my whip?
Has anyone seen my whip?
Damn. I've lost it. Have
you seen my whip, ass?
- Seryoga.
- What?
Read the Scriptures.
From where?
From wherever you like.
" lmitate me, just as
I also imitate Christ.
" Now I praise you, brethren, that
ye remember me in all things...
"...and keep the ordinances
as I delivered them to you.
" But I would have you know, that
the head of every man is Christ...
"...and the head of the
woman is the man...
"...and the head of Christ is God.
" Every man praying or prophesying,
having his head covered...
"...dishonoreth his head. But every
woman that prayeth or prophesieth...
"...with her head uncovered,
dishonoreth her head...
"...for that is even all one
as if she were shaven.
" For if the woman be not
covered, let her also be shorn...
"...but if it be shame for a woman
to be shorn or shaven...
"...let her be covered.
" For a man ought
not to cover his head...
"...forasmuch as he is the
image and glory of God...
"...but the woman is
the glory of the man.
" For the man is not of the woman;
but the woman of the man.
" Neither was the man created for the
woman; but the woman for the man.
" For this cause ought the woman
to have power on her head...
"...because of the angels.
" Nevertheless neither is
the man without the woman...
"...neither the woman
without the man, in the Lord."
Go on reading.
" For as the woman is of the
man, even so is the man...
"...also by the woman;
but all things of God.
"Judge in yourselves: is it comely...
"...that a woman pray
unto God uncovered?
" Doth not even nature itself teach
you that, if a man have long hair...
"...it is a shame unto him?
" But if a woman have long
hair, it is a glory to her...
"...for her hair is given her for..."
Why have you stopped? Read.
"But if a woman have long
hair, it is a glory for her...
"But if any man seem
to be contentious...
"...we have no such custom...
"...neither the Churches of God.
"Now in this that I declare
unto you I praise you not...
"...that ye come together
not for the better...
"...but for the worse."
Danil, listen.
It's a feast.
It's a feast, Danil,
and you are saying...
They are not sinners...
She is not a sinner, even if
she does not wear a scarf.
She is not a sinner.
Leave him alone. Let
God's servant repent.
The Passion According to Andrei
Part Two
THE R AID
Autumn of 1 408
They are coming! The
Tatars are coming, Prince!
Hey, Prince! Is this your ford?
It has been raining, and
everything is flooded. Follow us.
We were just going to leave.
We expected you yesterday.
I couldn't resist attacking
a small town on my way.
I am sorry I am late.
Never mind. Let's go. It will be
shallow to the left. Keep to the left.
This isn't a trap?
Believe me, Vladimir is deserted.
My brother, the Grand
Prince, is in Lithuania.
Here is the town, behind that forest.
They say the Prince has a
son, but you want the throne.
We'll see.
I see you want the
throne. I understand.
You were told to keep left.
Grab this!
Come on, Prince! Don't lag behind!
Strong is your love for your brother.
This is our destiny.
When were you last
reconciled with him?
I never was. The
Metropolitan summoned us...
...and made us kiss the cross
and swear to live in harmony.
What are you saying?
The Metropolitan
summoned us to kiss the cross.
- When?
- Last winter.
Vladimir is a beautiful town.
Do you like it?
Let's go.
Forward! You dog,
stay close, or I'll kill you!
Keep close to the
Prince! To the gates!
Tatars!
Run away!
What is going on?
The Grand Prince is coming.
The brother has arrived.