subS
* a n d a n t e *
split+sYnc
* v a t e r L a n d ! *
2CD riP+AC3
* b r e Y e r s *
nOv 2oo2
* t E A M . L o V E i N A *
# Don't be shy #
#Just let your feelings
roll on by #
# Don't wear fear #
# Or nobody will know
you're there #
#Just lift your head #
# And let your feelings
out instead #
# No, don't be shy #
# Just let your feelings
roll on by #
# On by #
# You know, love #
# Is better
than a song #
# Love is where #
# All of us belong #
# So don't be shy #
# Just let your feelings
roll on by #
# Don't wear fear #
# Or nobody will know
you're there #
# That you're there #
# You're there #
# You're there,
you're there, there #
# You're there #
# You're there,
you're there #
# Don't be shy #
#Just let your feelings
roll on by #
# And don't wear fear #
# Or nobody will know
you're there #
#Just lift your head #
# And let your feelings
out instead #
# No, don't be shy #
# Just let your feelings
roll on by #
# On by #
# Oh, on by #
# On by, on by #
# On by, on by ##
I suppose you think
that's very funny, Harold.
- Hello?
- Hello.
- Fay?
- Yes.
Darling, cancel my appointment
with Rene this afternoon.
I know he'll be furious,
but I've had such a frightful day.
And with guests
coming this evening.
Oh, would you?
That's sweet.
Tell him I promise
to be in on Tuesday.
Thank you, Fay.
You're a darling.
Yes. Bye.
Bye.
Oh. Dinner at 8:00, Harold.
And do try and be
a little more vivacious.
[Greensleeves Plays]
Harold's father had
a similar sense of the absurd.
I remember once, in Paris, he had
just stepped out for cigarettes.
The next I knew,
he was arrested by the police
for floating nude
down the Seine,
experimenting in river currents
with rubber water wings.
Mauve ones.
Well, that cost
quite a bit
of influence et d'argent
to hush up, I can tell you.
Harold, dear,
don't play with your food.
What's the matter?
Don't you feel well?
I have a sore throat.
Oh. Well, now,
directly after dinner,
I want you to go
straight to bed.
Harold's always been
a very delicate child,
even as a baby.
He seemed totally prone to
every possible kind of illness.
Harold, dear,
eat up your beets.
I remember
once, in Tokyo,
I had to call the embassy
for a doctor.
Oh, my God.
This is too much.
I can't stand
much more of this.
I can't take any more.
Oh, my God.
This is just...
Oh, God!
Oh...
That's very interesting,
Harold,
and, I think,
very illuminating.
There seems to be
a definite pattern emerging.
And, of course, this
pattern, once isolated,
can be coped with.
Recognize the problem,
and you are halfway on the road
to its, uh,
its solution.
Uh, tell me, Harold,
what do you do for fun?
What activity gives you
a different sense of enjoyment
from the others?
Uh, what do you find
fulfilling?
What gives you that...
special satisfaction?
I go to funerals.
# Then I found myself
alone #
# Hopin' someone
would miss me #
# Thinkin' about my home #
# And the last woman
to kiss me #
# Kiss me #
# But sometimes
you have to moan #
# When nothing seems
to suit you #
# But, nevertheless,
you know #
# You're locked
towards the future #
# Ooh ooh ooh ooh #
# So off and on you go #
# The seconds tick
the time out #
# There's so much
left to know #
# And I'm on the road
to find out #
# Ooh ooh ooh... ##
Thou dost prepare for me
a table
in the sight
of my adversaries.
Thou dost anoint my head
with oil.
My chalice overflows.
Kindness and grace
shall follow me
all the days
of my life,
and I shall dwell
in the house of the Lord
for length of days.
The earth is the Lord's
and the fullness thereof--
the world and they
who dwell therein,
for He has established it
upon the waters
and set it firmly
upon the rivers.
Who shall ascend
the mountain of the Lord,
or who shall stand
in His holy place?
The innocent of hands
and the pure of heart
who has not turned
his mind to vanity
nor sworn deceitfully
to his neighbor.
He shall receive
the blessing from the Lord
and a reward
from God his Savior.
This is the generation
of those who seek Him.
# Oh, yeah #
# I wish I knew #
# What makes me me #
# What makes you you #
# It's just
another point ofview #
# Ooh #
# A state of mind
I'm going through #
# Yeah #
# So what I see
is never true #
# No ##
Harold?
Why you purchased
that monstrosity,
I have no idea.
You can have
any car you want,
but that ugly black horror
is an eyesore
and an
embarrassment.
Really, Harold, it is time
you settled down
and stopped flitting
away your talents
on these amateur theatrics,
these little divertissements,
no matter how psychologically
purging they may be.
I don't know what to do.
Go and have a talk
with your uncle Victor.
Perhaps he can fathom you.
After all, he was
General MacArthur's right-hand man.
Well, what
do you say, Harold?
Ah, it's a great life.
There's action,
adventure, advising,
and you'll get a chance
to see the war firsthand.
And there are plenty
of slant-eyed girls.
I'll make a man
out of you, Harold.
You'll travel the world,
put on a uniform,
and take on a man's job.
You'll walk tall
with a glint in your eye,
a spring in your step,
and the knowledge
in your heart
that you are
working for peace
and are serving
your country,
just like Nathan Hale.
Now, that's what
this country needs--
more Nathan Hales.
And, Harold,
I think I can see
a little
Nathan Hale in you.
[Rachmaninoff Plays]
Tell me, Harold,
how many
of these, uh, suicides
have you performed?
An accurate number
would be difficult to gauge.
Well, just give me
a rough estimate.
A rough estimate?
I'd say...
1 5.
1 5?
That's a rough estimate.
Were they all done
for your mother's benefit?
No. No.
I would not say benefit.
I only have a few minutes,
and I want to inform you
of my decision.
You have led
a very carefree,
idle, happy life
up to the present,
the life of a child.
But it is time now
to put away childish things
and take on
adult responsibilities.
Oh, we'd all like
to sail through life
with no thought of tomorrow,
but that cannot be.
We have our duties,
our obligations,
our principles.
In short, Harold,
I think it is time
for you to get married.
Let us pray to the Lord,
King of glory,
that He may
bless and deliver
the souls of all
the faithful departed
from the pain of hell
and the bottomless pit.
Deliver them
from the lion's mouth
and the darkness therein,
but rather, bring them
to the blessing of light,
holy life,
and eternal rest.
"O Lord,
"do not bring
your servant to trial,
"for no man--
Ssst!
"becomes holy
in Your sight
"unless You grant him forgiveness
of all his sins.
"We implore You, therefore,
"do not let the verdict
of Your judgment
"go against him
whom the loyal prayer
"of Christian faith
commends to mercy.
Ssst!
"Rather, by the help
of Your grace,
"may he escape the sentence
which he deserves,
"for during
his earthly life,
"he was signed with the seal
of the holy trinity.
You who live and reign
forever and ever."
Amen.
Ssst!
Like some licorice?
- No, thank you.
- You're welcome.
Did you know him?
No.
Me neither. I heard
he's 80 years old.
I'll be 80 next week.
Good time to move on,
don't you think?
I don't know.
Well, I mean,
75 is too early,
but at 85, you're
just marking time.
You may as well go
over the horizon.
I'll never understand this
mania for black.
Nobody sends black
flowers, do they?
Black flowers
are dead flowers.
Who sends dead flowers
to a funeral?
It's absurd.
What is your name?
Harold. Harold Chasen.
Oh, how do you do?
I'm Dame Marjorie Chardin,
but call me Maude.
Nice to meet you.
Thanks. I think we're going
to be great friends, don't you?
Can I give you a lift?
No, thank you.
I have my own car.
Well, I must be off.
We shall
have to meet again.
Ah.
Tell me, do you dance?
Pardon me?
Do you sing and dance?
Uh, no.
Uh, no. I thought not.
That woman.
She took my car.
I have here the forms
sent by the national
computer dating service.
They screen out
the fat and ugly,
so it's obviously a firm
of high standards.
First, here is
the personality interview,
which you are to
fill out and return.
Now then, are you
ready, Harold?
Here is the first question.
"Are you uncomfortable
meeting new people?"
I think that's a yes,
don't you agree, Harold?
"Should sex education be
taught outside the home?"
Oh, I would say no,
wouldn't you, Harold?
We'll give a "D" there.
3--"Should women run for president
of the United States?"
I don't see why not.
Absolutely yes.
"Do you
remember jokes
and take pleasure
in relating them to others?"
You don't do that,
do you, Harold? No.
Absolutely no.
"Do you often
get the feeling
that perhaps life
isn't worth living?"
What do you think,
Harold? "A"? "B"?
Oh, we'll put down "C,"
not sure. Mm-hmm.
"Is the subject of sex
being overexploited
by our mass media?"
That would have to
be yes, wouldn't it?
"Is it difficult for you
to accept criticism?"
No. We'll mark "D."
"Do you sometimes
have headaches or backaches
after a difficult day?"
Yes, I do, indeed.
"Do you go
to sleep easily?"
I'd say so.
"Do you believe in
capital punishment for murder?"
Yes, I do, indeed.
"In your opinion,
are social affairs
usually a waste of time?"
Heavens no.
"Can God influence
our lives?"
Oh, yes.
Absolutely yes.
"Does your personal religion
or philosophy
include a life
after death?"
Oh, yes, indeed.
That's absolutely.
"Did you enjoy life
when you were a child?"
Oh, yes, you were
a wonderful baby, Harold.
"Do you think
the sexual revolution
has gone too far?"
It certainly has.
"Do you find
the idea of wife swapping
distasteful?"
I even find
the question distasteful.
"Do you--
Harold, please!
"Do you have ups and downs
without obvious reason?"
Oh, that's you, Harold.
Ha ha ha ha.
# Lord, my body #
# Has been a good friend #
# But I won't need it #
# When I reach the end #
# Miles from nowhere #
# I guess I'll take
my time #
# Oh, yeah #
# To reach there ##
Ssst!
"Dearest brothers,
"let us faithfully
and lovingly
"remember our brother
"whom God has taken
to Himself
"from the trials
of this world.
"God have mercy.
"Christ have mercy.
Lord have mercy."
Our Father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
# Bring tea
for the tillerman #
# Steak for the son #
# Wine for the woman #
# Who made the rain come #
# Seagulls,
sing your hearts away #
# 'Cause while
us sinners sin #
# The children play #
# Oh, Lord,
how they play and play #
# For that happy day #
# Happy day ##
Uh, my boy, excuse me.
One moment, please.
Who was that old lady
waving to you earlier?
Hello, Harold.
can I give you a lift?
There you are, madam.
Were you not the lady
who drove my car off yesterday?
With the St. Christopher medal
on the dashboard?
Yes.
It was me.
Get in, Harold.
Were you also the one
who painted the saint?
Oh, yes. How did
you like that?
Well, I didn't.
Don't be
too discouraged.
For aesthetic appreciation,
always a little time.
What a delight, Harold,
to bump into you again.
I knew we were going
to be good friends.
You go to funerals
often, don't you?
Uh, yeah.
So do I.
They're such fun,
aren't they?
It's all change,
all revolving--
burials and birth,
one linked to the other,
the great circle of life.
Hey, this old thing
handles well.
Ever drive
a hearse, Harold?
Yeah.
Well, it's a new
experience for me.
Good on curves.
Shall I take you
home, Harold?
Uh, this is my car.
Your hearse?
Yearse.
Ohhh!
Then you shall
take me home.
So just before he left
for the monastery in Tibet,
big Sweeney
gave me his keys.
'Course I made additions
for the new models,
but not as many
as you might think.
Once you have
your basic set,
it's then only
a question ofvariation.
You hop in any car you want
and just drive off?
Not any car.
I like to keep a variety.
I'm always looking
for the new experience.
Maybe.
Nevertheless, I think
you're upsetting people.
I don't know
if that's right.
Well, if some people
get upset
because they feel they have
a hold on some things,
I'm acting as
a gentle reminder--
here today,
gone tomorrow,
so don't get
attached to things.
Now, with that
in mind,
I'm not against
collecting stuff.
I've collected quite
a lot of stuff in my time.
Yeah. This is all memorabilia,
but it's incidental,
not integral,
if you know what I mean.
Oh--the birds.
Wow.
Oh, I love them so much.
They're the only wildlife
I get to see anymore.
Ah, me. Free as a bird.
At one time I broke into pet shops
to liberate the canaries,
but I decided that was an idea
way before its time.
Zoos are full,
prisons are overflowing...
Ah, my. How the world
still dearly loves a cage.
Uh, please sit down,
Harold.
I'll put the kettle on.
We'll have a nice
hot cup of tea.
Thanks, but
I have to go.
But it's oat straw tea.
You've never had
oat straw tea, have you?
No.
Well, then.
But I have to go.
I have an appointment.
I really can't miss it.
Oh. At the dentist?
Kind of.
Well, then you'll just
have to come back and visit.
All right.
My door's always open.
- Promise?
- I promise.
Harold.
Harold?
I asked, do you
have any friends?
No.
None at all?
Maybe one.
Would you care to talk
about this friend?
No.
I find you a very
interesting case, Harold,
but this reluctance
on your part
is detrimental to
the psychoanalytical process.
Do you understand?
Very well.
Your mother tells me,
Harold,
that she's arranging
several dates for you
with some young ladies.
How do you
feel about that?
Hello. I'm Candy Gulf.
How do you do?
I'm Mrs. Chasen. Do come in.
Harold is
out in the garden.
He'll be here
in a moment.
Shall we sit down?
Oh, there's Harold.
Hello.
Oh, he seems very nice.
Oh, thank you.
- You are at the university?
- Yes, I am.
And what
are you studying?
Poli sci, minoring
in Home Ec.
- Poli Sci?
- Political Science.
- Oh.
- It's all about what's going on.
Is Harold interested
in what's going on?
I just think it's such
a super thing to study.
Of course, I can always
fall back on my Home Ec.
Now that's good planning.
Yes.
Tell me, are you a regular
with this computer club?
Oh, heavens, no! I don't have
to worry about dates.
Oh.
But some of the other girls
in my sorority
decided somebody
ought to try it,
so we drew straws,
and I lost.
Oh--but I-- I'm looking
forward to meeting Harold.
Well, I think
I should mention, Candy,
Harold does have his
little eccentric moments.
That's all right.
I have a brother
who's a real cutup, too.
Oh, I will never
forget the time
we had this old television set
with no parts in it.
Tommy stuck his head
behind it
and started giving
a whole newscast
before the entire family.
Must have been
very funny.
Aah! Harold!
Oh!
Oh, yes, dear.
Here is Harold now.
Harold,
this is Candy.
Candy's just been telling
such a funny little story about--
Oh!
Walter
Cronkite.
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
# I used to walk alone #
# Every step
seemed the same #
# This world
was not my home #
# So there was nothing
much to the game #
# Look up and
see the clouds #
# Look down and
see the cold fog #
# Until you came
into my life, girl #
# I saw nothing,
nothing more ##
Oh.
- Excuse me.
- Mmm?
I beg your pardon.
Well, what do you want?
I'm sorry.
I was looking for Maude.
Harold?
Maude.
How about
some ginger pie?
Fine. Thank you.
I'll heat some up.
My, Harold, I'm glad
to see you again.
Do you often
model for Glaucus?
Oh, heavens, no.
I don't have the time.
But I like
to keep in practice.
And poor Glaucus occasionally
needs his memory refreshed
as to the contours
of the female form.
Do you disapprove?
Me? no. Of course not.
Really?
Do you think
it's wrong?
No.
Oh! Heavens,
I'm glad you said that.
I want to show you
my painting.
This is
The Rape oflRome.
Over in the corner
is Leda and the Swan--
a self-portrait.
And over here
is my favorite.
It's titled...
Rainbow With Egg Underneath
and an Elephant.
Do you like it?
Oh, yeah.
Very much.
I then became
infatuated with these--
my odorifics.
Give the nose a treat,
I thought--
Have a kind of a--
a olfactory banquet.
So I began first
on the easiest--
roast beef, old books,
mown grass...and
Mexican farmyard.
Oh. Here's one you'll like.
Snowfall
on 42nd Street.
I'll put it on.
Now, you hold on
to this.
I'll pump it up.
OK. Now,
hold it up there.
Now, what
do you smell?
Subway?
Ha ha.
Perfume.
Cigarettes.
Snow.
Oh, it goes
on and on.
It's just great.
But then I decided
to switch to the tactile.
Uh...
what do you think?
I like this--
Oh, no, no, no.
Really get close
and reach in and feel.
Oh...there's
my kettle.
Uh...well...
stroke...
palm...
caress...
explore.
Unh...
Mmm.
Here we are.
Oat straw tea
and ginger pie.
Excuse the mismatched
saucers.
This is definitely
a new experience for me.
Oh, wonderful.
Try something new each day.
After all, we're given life
to find it out.
It doesn't last
forever.
You look
as if you could.
Did I tell you
I'll be 80 on Saturday?
You don't look 80.
That's the influence
of the right food,
the right exercises,
and the right breathing.
Greet the dawn with
the breath of fire.
Huh! Huh! Huh! Huh!
Huh! Huh! Hu...
Oh...
well, there's
no question.
My body's giving out.
I'm well into autumn.
It's all going
to be over after Saturday.
Tell me about yourself.
What do you do when
you aren't visiting funerals?
Yes, there is definitely
a certain attraction.
I ask you, though, Harold,
is it enough?
What do you mean?
Oh, well...
Mmm...
I like to watch
things grow.
They grow and bloom
and fade and die
and change
into something else.
Ah, life.
I should like to change
into a sunflower most of all.
They're so tall and simple.
What flower
would you like to be?
I don't know.
One of these, maybe.
Why do you say that?
Because they're all alike.
Oh, but they're not.
Look. See...
some are smaller,
some are fatter...
some grow to the left,
some to the right.
Some even have
lost some petals.
All kinds of
observable differences.
You see, Harold,
I feel that much
of the world's sorrow
comes from people
who are this...
yet allow themselves
to be treated as that.
# Well, I think it's fine #
# Buildin' jumbo planes #
# Or takin' a ride #
# On a cosmic train #
# Switch on summer #
# From a slot machine #
#Yes, get what
you want to, if you want #
# 'Cause you can get
anything #
# I know we've come
a long way #
# We're changin'
day to day #
# But tell me #
# Where do
the children play #
# Well, you roll on roads #
# Over fresh green grass #
# For your lorry loads #
# Pumpin' petrol gas #
# And you make them long #
# And you make them tough #
Power steering.
# But they just
go on and on #
# And it seems that
you can't get off #
# Oh, I know
we've come a long way #
# We're changin'
day to day #
# But tell me #
# Where do
the children play ##
Hey!
That little tree
is in trouble. Come on.
Look at it.
Oh.
It's suffocating.
Well, it's the smog.
You know, people
can live with it,
but trees,
it gives them asthma.
They can't breathe.
The leaves. Look,
they're turning brown.
Harold, we have got to do
something about this life.
What?
We'll transplant it
to the forest.
You can't do that.
Why not?
This is public property.
Well, exactly.
Well, we'll need tools.
You're right.
We'll go see Glaucus. Come on.
Wait a minute.
Oh, police. Come on.
Well,
good afternoon, officer.
Bit of trouble here?
Yes, ma'am. Someone
had trouble parking.
That's a tricky turn.
Tell me, that
car over there,
is that parked
all right?
Yes, ma'am, that's fine.
Thank you so much.
Uh, might turn the radio off.
Saves the battery.
A little after-dinner
liqueur, Harold?
Thank you,
I don't drink.
Oh, it's all right.
It's organic.
Thanks.
It has no
nutritional value,
but consistency is not
really a human trait.
What is that up there?
Oh, that's my umbrella.
That's just a relic.
I found it while packing
to come to America.
It used to be my defense
on picket lines and rallies
and political meetings--
being dragged off
by the police
and attacked by the thugs
of the opposition.
What were you
fighting for?
Oh, big issues--
liberty, rights, justice.
Kings died,
kingdoms fell.
I don't regret
the kingdom.
What sense in borders
and nations and patriotism?
But I miss the kings.
When I was
a little girl,
I was taken
to the palace in Vienna
to a garden party.
I can still see the sun shining,
the parasols,
the flashing uniforms
of the young officers.
I thought then that
I would marry a soldier.
Later on, Frederick
would chide me about it.
He was so serious.
A doctor
at the university...
and in the government.
But that was all before.
So...
you don't use
the umbrella anymore.
No more revolts?
Oh. Oh, yes.
Oh, every day.
But...I don't need
the defense anymore.
I embrace.
Still fighting
for the big issues,
but now in my small,
individual way.
Shall we have a song?
I don't--
I don't play--
Oh, come on.
- I'll show you.
- No.
# Sing out, sing out #
# If you want
to be free, be free #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to be #
#You know
that there are #
# And if you want
to be high, be high #
# If you want
to be low, be low #
# 'Cause there's
a million ways to go #
#You know
that there are #
# And if you want
to be me, be me #
# If you want
to be you, be you #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to do #
#You know
that there are #
Harold, join in.
#You know
that there are #
#You can do what #
#You want #
#The opportunity's on #
# And if you find #
# A new way #
#You can do it today #
#You can make it
all true #
# And you can
make it undo #
#You see #
# Ah, it's easy #
# Ah, you only need
to know #
# If you want
to sing out, sing out #
# And if you want
to be free, be free #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to be #
# You know
that there are #
# You know that there are #
# There are, there are #
# You know that there are ##
Oh, that was fun!
Let's play something
together.
I don't play anything.
Nothing?
Oh...dear me.
Everybody should be able
to make some music.
That's the cosmic dance.
Oh, come with me.
There has
to be something.
Now, let me see.
Got to oil this thing.
Oh. Hold on to this.
Let's--What is this?
This is it.
There we are.
You take--
This is the one. Take that.
Just be impulsive.
Be fanciful.
Let the music
flow out of you.
You--You got
to make some chords.
Put--Put your finger
on the second fret.
And this one on the third.
Then this one here.
Harold!
Harold?
Harold, dear!
Oh, there you are.
I have a little
surprise for you.
It's a present.
Come along.
There.
Isn't it darling?
I had them take away
that monstrous thing of yours
and send this one
'round instead.
It's so much more appropriate
for you, don't you think?
Oh, one thing more,
Harold.
I telephoned your second
computer date this morning,
and she seems
a very nice, quiet girl.
Cute little thing,
isn't it?
I like it very much.
Your license, lady?
I don't have one.
I don't believe in them.
How long you been
driving, lady?
About, uh, 45 minutes,
wouldn't you say, Harold?
We were hoping
to start sooner,
but it's rather hard
to find a truck.
Is this your truck?
Uh, oh, no.
I just took it.
You just took it?
Yes. See, I have
to plant my tree.
Well,
it's not mine, really,
but we would like
to get it into soil
as soon as possible.
Let me get this
straight, lady.
All right, then, we'll be off.
Nice chatting with you.
He was very nice.
Yeah.
I think
he's following us.
Is he?
Oh, the police. Always
wanting to play games.
Hey, lady!
Is the little tree
all right?
Oh, yeah. Fine.
Terrific!
There.
Mmm. I love the feel
of soil, don't you?
And the smell.
It's the earth.
The earth is my body,
my head is in the stars.
Who said that?
I don't know.
I suppose I did.
Oh, isn't it wonderful?
All around us,
living things.
All right, out, lady.
Come on.
Hello.
Haven't we met before?
None of that, lady.
Come on out.
It must have been
your brother.
There is
a family resemblance.
Get out of the car.
Just stand
over there, lady.
Come on. Get out, buster!
You're in a lot
of trouble, lady.
I got you down here
for several offenses
including possession
of a stolen vehicle,
resisting arrest,
and possession
of a stolen tree.
Where's the tree?
We planted it.
Is this your shovel?
No.
Possession
of a stolen shovel.
Don't get officious.
You're not yourself
when you're officious.
That is the curse
of a government job.
Aw, lady.
Are you going to take
a lot of time with this?
Lady, please.
Because if you are--
Lady, just quiet, please.
Grab the shovel,
Harold.
Lady! Stop or
I'll have to shoot!
I sure am picking up
on vices.
Vice, virtue.
It's best
not to be too moral.
You cheat yourself
out of too much life.
Aim above morality.
If you apply that
to life,
then you're bound
to live it fully.
I haven't lived.
I've died a few times.
What was that?
Well...
uh...
the first time was when
I was at boarding school,
in the chemistry lab.
I was in there
cleaning it up,
so I decided I'd do
a little experimenting,
you know.
So I get all this stuff out
and begin mixing it up.
Very scientific.
There was this
massive explosion.
It knocked me down,
blew out a huge hole
in the floor.
There was boards
and bricks
and flames
leaping up.
I figured, you know,
time to leave.
My career in school
was over.
So, uh...
I went home.
My mother
was giving a party,
so I went up the back stairs
into my room,
turned out the light,
and, uh, I got
this funny feeling.
The doorbell rang.
I went out
into the banister,
and these two
policemen came in,
found my mother,
and, uh...told her
that I was killed
in the fire.
She put one hand
up to her forehead.
With the other one,
she reached out,
as if groping
for support,
and with
this long sigh,
she collapsed
in their arms.
I decided right then
that I'd enjoy
being dead.
I understand.
A lot of people
enjoy being dead,
but they're not dead,
really.
They're just
backing away from life.
Reach out.
Take a chance.
Get hurt, even.
But play
as well as you can.
Go, team, go!
Gimme an "L,"
Gimme an "I,"
Gimme a "V,"
Gimme an "E."
L-I-V-E. Live!
Otherwise you got nothing
to talk about in the locker room.
I likeyou, Maude.
Hmm.
I likeyou, Harold.
[The Blue Danube
Waltz Plays]
Harold is down
at the garage.
He's been tuning up
his new car.
He's very mechanical.
What kind of car
is it?
It's a little jaguar.
Oh.
Looks like a hearse.
Very nice.
You know--compact.
Edith, I'd like you
to meet my son Harold.
Harold,
this is Edith...
- Phern.
Very pleased to make
your acquaintance.
I think you should
wash up, dear,
and join us
in the drawing room.
And what do you do,
my dear?
I'm a file clerk
at Harrison
Feed and Grain.
Well, what is it
exactly that you do?
I'm in charge of all the invoices
for the southwest.
How interesting.
And we supply,
for example,
most of the egg farmers
in Petaluma,
so you can imagine.
Yes.
Oh, here's Harold now.
Don't get up, dear.
Edith has been talking
about her job.
I'm a file clerk.
Henderson
Feed and Grain.
Harrison.
Harrison
Feed and Grain.
It's at Hamilton
and 4th.
I'm in charge
of the invoices.
I type the schedule
for the trucking fleet.
She supplies the whole southwest
with chicken feed.
Well, not exactly
the whole southwest,
although we do
a large business.
Barley was very big
last week--
1,500...
bushels.
In view of your
recent actions,
I find you have left me
with no recourse
but to listen to the solution
proposed by your uncle.
Consequently, I have
instructed him forthwith
to induct you
into the service,
and, for your own good,
to take up active duty
with the United States Army.
And I hope they have
more luck with you than I.
Maude, they're
going to draft me.
Well, don't go.
They'll put me in jail.
Well, historically,
you'd be in very good company.
Maude, can you help me?
With your skill
and my experience,
I think we can
come up with something.
Harold, look at me
like your father in this.
I know you have no desire
to join the army,
but once you're in,
you'll love it.
It's a great life.
Look at me--
chauffeur, respect,
money in the bank.
Oh, it has its drawbacks
like anything else, I suppose.
But the army
takes care of you,
and you've got
a buddy for life.
Good idea,
coming out here, Harold.
It's a lovely spot.
Thank you, Uncle.
Call me sir, Harold.
It's the first thing
you learn in the army--
an officer
deserves your respect.
Yes, sir.
Now let's examine
the facts on it.
I say this country's
been too harsh
in its outright
condemnation ofwar.
You can point to the many
material advantages
brought about by a crisis
in conflict policy.
Why, hell, World War II
gave us the ballpoint pen.
During wartime, the national
suicide rate goes down.
Is that a fact?
Why in hell did we
give up on the Germans?
Because the damn politicians
in Washington
chalked them up
on our side.
The wars ever since have
been a national disgrace.
Hell, look at history.
The two best wars
this country ever fought
were against the jerries.
Get the krauts across
the fence where they belong.
Let's get back to the kind
of enemy worth killing
and the kind ofwar
this country can support.
Wow. That's pretty
strong stuff, sir.
Well, I've always been a man
that speaks his piece.
Always hurt me.
I'm not liked in Washington.
I know that.
But I do have friends
in high places.
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat!
They kept falling. Shock!
Joe falls back,
a neat hole in his head.
Tat-tat-tat-tat!
Only one thing kept
going through my mind--
Kill! Kill!
For joe and Mac
and the rest of the guys!
Kill!
And then there was
a blinding flash!
And I woke up
on a stretcher.
"Did we hold? "
I asked the medic.
"Yes, sir!" he said.
And I slipped
into unconsciousness.
Boy.
Wow. That's
a terrific story, sir.
Well...
you'll have stories like that
to tell of your own someday.
Do you think so, sir?
Sure, you will.
Gee, I never dreamed
it could be that exciting.
It's the most exciting thing
in the world, Harold.
To pit your own life
against another.
Yes.
To kill.
The taste ofblood
in your mouth.
The moment of truth.
Another man's life
in your sight!
Yes!
Will they really
teach me to shoot?
Sure, they will,
a variety ofweapons.
To use a bayonet?
Yes!
How about
hand-to-hand combat?
Yes.
To strangle someone,
choke him,
squeeze out his life
in your own bare hands!
I think you're
getting carried away.
- How about to slit his throat?
- I don't know about that.
How about souvenirs?
Souvenirs?
Of your kill.
Eyes, ears, nose,
scalp, privates?
Harold!
What would be the chance
of getting one of these?
Boy, to think
I could make my own!
Harold,
that's disgusting!
It certainly is!
Madam, who are you?
I am petitioning
for peace.
- Parasite!
- Harold!
I came out here
to speak.
Commie bastard!
Get out of here!
Don't talk to me
like that,
you foul-mouthed
degenerate!
Traitor! Benedict Arnold!
Remember Nathan Hale!
Harold,
calm down.
Commie pig!
Don't you advance
on me.
You'll all end up
like this!
Ooh!
Just like this!
Harold!
Give me that!
I'll throw that in the sewer.
Madam, please.
She took my head.
Now calm down,
Harold.
She took my head!
Harold!
I'll kill her!
Harold! Harold!
Aah!
Madam,
give back the head!
Let's
have no trouble!
Harold!
I'll kill you!
Madam!
Harold! Damn you!
Let's have no trouble!
Aah!
You took my head!
You pig!
I'll kill you!
Help!
Harold!
I'll kill you!
Let go, Uncle!
Let go!
Harold!
Stop that!
What have you done?
Maude.
Hmm?
Do you pray?
Pray? No.
I communicate.
With God?
With life.
This is real nice.
Yeah.
Makes me want
to do somersaults.
Well, why don't you?
I'd feel stupid.
Harold,
everyone has the right
to make an ass
of themselves.
You can't let the world
judge you too much.
Uh...
do you care to join me
in a little cartwheel?
No. I feel
more like yelling.
Raah!
Aooga--
# Well, if you want
to sing out, sing out #
# And if you want
to be free, be free #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to be #
#You know that there are #
# And if you want
to be me, be me #
to be you, be you #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to do #
#You know that there are #
#You can do what you want #
#The opportunity's on #
# And if you
find a new way #
#You can do it today #
#You can make it
all true #
# And you can
make it undo, you see #
Maude.
I had the most
wonderful day today,
and...
you're
very beautiful.
Oh, Harold.
You make me feel
like a schoolgirl.
Shall I come
and visit you tomorrow?
Oh, I can't.
I have
a luncheon date
with a girl.
Oh.
I don't even know her.
My mother arranged it.
Look.
Oh.
Dreyfus once wrote
from Devil's Island
that he would see
the most glorious birds.
Many years later
in Brittany,
he realized they had
only been seagulls.
# Ah-ah-ah, it's easy #
# Ah-ah-ah,
you only need to know #
For me, they will always
be glorious birds.
# Well, if you want
to sing out, sing out #
# And if you want
to be free, be free #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to be #
# You know that there are #
#You know that there are #
#You know that there are ##
Now, Harold,
I cannot impress upon you
too strongly
the importance
of this meeting.
This is the last girl,
so kindly remember
that this is your third
and final chance.
And please try
to be serious, Harold.
If not for your sake,
for hers.
There she is.
Sunshine, I'd like you
to meet Harold.
Harold, this is
Sunshine Dore.
How--
How do you do?
Oh, I can't
complain.
Sunshine is an actress,
Harold.
I like to think so.
Oh, wonderful.
Why don't you go down
to the music room,
and I'll follow on later
with some drinks?
Oh, perhaps Starlight
would like a cigarette.
No. Sunshine.
Oh, yes, of course.
Sunshine.
Would you like
a cigarette?
No, thank you.
They stain my fingers.
Is Sunshine
your real name?
Well, actually, it was the name
of my drama teacher.
Louis Sunshine.
Perhaps
you've heard of him.
He was
such an influence
on the development
of my instrument.
That means my body
in theater talk.
Dore is my real name.
Well, Dorr, actually.
Oh, my!
What a lovely place
you have here.
Oh, do you play?
No.
I am learning the ba--
the harmonica.
Oh! Is this your father?
No.
My Uncle Victor.
He's in the army.
I do so like
the military, don't you?
Oh, what a wonderful
collection of knives!
May I see--
No, no. Don't touch.
They're very old.
Do you enjoy knives?
Oh, yes.
You might find this one
particularly interesting.
It's a hara-kiri blade.
What's hara-kiri?
Aah!
Sukiyaki.
Oh...
Harold.
Oh, that was marvelous.
Oh, it had
the ring of truth.
I played juliet
in the Sunshine Playhouse.
Louie thought it was
my best performance.
What's here?
A cup, closed
in my true love's hand?
Poison, I see, hath been
his timeless end.
O happy dagger!
This is thy sheath.
There rest--ooh!
And let me die--
Oh!
Ooh!
Harold!
That was
your last date.
- Aah!
Gee.
It wasn't very scary.
No. It had nothing
on this afternoon.
Oh, come on.
You loved it.
It was
a new experience.
Ha ha ha ha.
Oh!
Perfect!
Come on,
give us another one!
- Yay!
You sure have
a way with people.
Well, they're
my species.
Look at these stars.
Mmm.
Maude...
Yeah?
Here.
A gift.
Ahh...
"Harold
loves Maude."
And Maude
loves Harold.
This is
the nicest present
that I've received
in years.
So I'll always know
where it is.
# I think
I see the light #
# Comin' to me #
# Comin' through me #
# Givin' me
a second sight #
# So shine,
shine, shine #
# Shine, shine, shine #
# Shine, shine, shine ##
Oh, could I speak
with Fay, please?
Fay?
Darling, I know
Rene will be furious,
but...ifhe knew what
I had to put up with
in the last few days.
- Mother.
- Not now, dear.
So could you
take me Monday?
I'd like
to talk to you.
I'm on the phone, dear.
I'm getting married.
What did you say?
Hold the line, Fay.
To whom?
I suppose you think
this is very funny, Harold.
A sunflower.
You can't be serious.
Your mother spoke to me
about your marriage plan,
and although normally
I have nothing
against marriage,
I don't think
this is quite, uh...
normal.
Avery common neurosis,
particularly
in this society,
whereby the male child
subconsciously wishes
to sleep with his mother.
Of course,
what puzzles me, Harold,
is that you want to sleep
with your grandmother.
I would be remiss
in my duty
if I did not tell you
that the idea of...
intercourse...
the fact
of your firm young...
body...
commingling...
with the...
withered flesh...
sagging...breasts...
and...flabby...
bu...
buttocks...
makes me want...
to vomit.
Mmm.
Oh, Harold...
it's...dazzling.
[Humming
The Blue Danube Waltz]
You've thought
of everything.
And champagne.
It's all right.
It's organic.
- Oh, Harold.
- Wait.
For you.
And, uh...
after dinner...
one more little
surprise...
that, I hope,
will make you very happy.
Oh, Harold...
I am happy.
I couldn't imagine
a lovelier farewell.
Farewell?
Yes, it's
my 90th birthday.
Well, you're not
going anywhere....
are you?
Yes, dear.
I took the tablets
an hour ago.
I'll be gone
by midnight.
What?
What a fuss this is--
So unnecessary.
Don't die, Maude,
for Christ's sake.
Oh, Harold.
Oh, don't upset
yourself so.
I love you.
Oh, Harold...
that's wonderful.
Go and love some more.
No.
Never.
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
set me free #
# I have seen your face #
# And it's too much,
too much for me #
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
can't you see #
# You're eatin'
my heart away #
# And there's nothin' much
left of me #
# I've drunk your wine #
# You have made
your work mine #
# So won't you be fair #
# I don't want
no more of you #
# So won't you be
kind to me #
# just let me go where #
# I have to go there #
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
move away #
# I have seen your face #
# And it's too much
for me today #
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
can't you see #
# You have made me
a wreck #
# Now won't you
leave me in my misery #
# I've seen your eyes #
# And I can see
death's disguise #
# Hangin' on me #
# I am beat, I'm torn #
# Shattered and tossed
and worn #
# Too shocking to see #
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
move from me #
# I have paid my debt #
# Now, won't you
leave me in my misery #
# Trouble #
# Oh, trouble,
please be kind #
# I don't want no fight #
# And I haven't got
a lot of time... ##
# Well, if you want
to sing out, sing out #
# And if you want
to be free, be free #
# 'Cause there's
a million things to be #
#You know
that there are #
# And if you want
to live high, live high #
to live low, live low #
# 'Cause there's
a million ways to go #
#You know
that there are #
#You can do
what you want #
#The opportunity's on #
# And if you find
a new way #
#You can do it today #
#You can make it
all true #
# And you can
make it undo #
#You see #
# Ahh ahh ahh #
# It's easy #
# Aah ahh ahh #
#You only need
to know #
# Well, if you want
to say yes, say yes ##
rip by Andante (andante1983@yahoo.com)