http://3gpsms.wordpress.com
smuthustalin@yahoo.com
Ladies and gentlemen, we are about to
begin our descent into Los Angeles.
The sound you have just heard is
landing gear locking into place.
The Los Angeles weather is clear,
temperature 72.
We expect to make our four hours
eighteen minutes flight on schedule.
We enjoyed having you on board and look
forward to see you again in the near future.
Attention, please! Passengers in this
area is limited to 3 minutes on leave.
Please do not leave your cart unattended.
Hey, What's the matter?
The guests are all downstairs, Ben.
They're all waiting to see you.
Look, Dad, Could you explain to them
that I have to be alone for a while?
These are all our good friends, Ben.
Most of them have known you since -
well - practically since you were born.
What is it, Ben?
I'm just -
- worried?
Well -
About what?
I guess - about my future.
What about it?
I don't know.  I want it to be -
To be what?
Different.
Is anything wrong?
No, No, we're just on our way downstairs!
The Carlsons' are here.
They are? Come on.
They came all the way from Tarzana.
Come on, let's get cracking.
It's a wonderful thing to have
so many devoted friends.
Hey - there's our award winning scholar.
We're all very proud of you, Ben.
Thank you, Mrs. Carlson.
Is that the new car out there?
The little red Wop job?
That's Ben's graduation present.
Won't have much trouble picking
them up in that, will you?
So?
The girls, the chicks, the teeny boppers.
I think Ben has gotten beyond the
teeny bopper stage. Haven't you, Ben?
Yes, madam.
Excuse me. I think I'd just like to
check something on the car for a minute.
Here's the track star.
How are you, track star?
Just fine, Mr. Loomis.
I want to get a drink and then I want
to hear all about that thing you won.
That Hoppermanaward.
Helpingham.
Helpingham! Right! You wait right here.
Ben - we're all so proud of you.
Proud, proud, proud, proud, proud.
What are you going to do now?
I was going to go upstairs for a minute -
No - I meant with your future, Your life.
Well - that's a little hard to say -
Ben!
Excuse me.
Mr. McQuire
Ben.
Mr. McQuire.
Come on with me for a minute.
I want to talk to you.
Excuses, John.
I just want to say on word to you,
just one word.
Yes, sir.
Are you listening?
Yes I am.
Plastics.
Exactly how do you mean?
There is a great future in plastics.
Think about it. Will you think about it?
Yes, I will.
Enough said. That's a deal.
Here he is now. Here's Ben.
Excuse me just a minute -
Listen everybody, I want you all be quite.
I got Ben's college book here. I just want
we enjoy some wonderful things about Ben.
Be quiet, Please!
Captain of the cross country team
Head of the bating court
Associate editor of the college news paper
"New Junior here", Manager of "Junior and Senior"
Oh. I guess this isn't the bathroom, is it?
It's down the hall.
How are you, Benjamin?
Fine, thank you, Mrs Robinson.
The bathroom is down at the end of the hall.
Such a pleasent room.
Look, Mrs. Robinson, I don't mean
to be rude but, I am -
Is there an ashtray, thank you?
No.
Oh - I forgot. The track star doesn't smoke.
Is it a girl?
Is what a girl?
Whatever it is upsetting you.
Oh - no. I'm just sort of disturbed
about things. In general.
That's right.
Well, congratulations!
Thank you!
Oh, Benjamin, I want to ask you something.
What?
Will you take me home?
My husband took the car.
Will you drive me home?
Here, you take it.
Do you know how to work a foreign shift?
You don't?
No.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Right.
Will you come in, please?
What?
I like you to come in till
I get the lights on.
What for?
Because I don't feel safe
until I get the lights on.
Would you mind walking ahead of
me to the sun porch.
I feel funny about
coming into a dark house.
But it's light there.
Please.
What do you drink? Bourbon?
Look, Mrs Robinson, I drove you home.
I was glad to do it.
But I have some things on my mind.
Can you understand that?
Yes.
All right.
What do you drink?
Benjamin - I'm sorry to be this way, but
I don't want to be left alone in this house.
Why not?
Please wait till my husband gets home.
When is he coming back?
I don't know.
Drink?
No.
Are you always this much
afraid of being alone?
Yes.
Well, why can't you just lock
the doors and go to bed?
I'm very nuerotic.
May I ask you a question?
What do you think of me?
What do you mean?
You've known me nearly all of your life.
You must have formed some opinion.
Well - I've always thought that
you were a very - nice - person.
Did you know I was an alcoholic?
What?
Did you know that?
Look - I think I should be going.
Sit down, Benjamin.
Mrs. Robinson, if you don't mind my saying so,
this conversation is getting a little strange.
Now I'm sure that Mr. Robinson will
be here any minute and...
No.
What?
My husband will be back quite late.
He should be gone for several hours.
Oh my God.
Pardon?
Oh no, Mrs. Robinson, oh no.
What's wrong?
Mrs. Robinson, you didn't -
I mean you didn't expect -
What?
I mean - you didn't really think that
I would do something like that.
Like what?
What do you think?
Well, I don't know.
For God's sake, Mrs. Robinson.
Here we are, you've got me into your house.
You give me a drink. You put on music.
Now you start opening up
your personal life to me
and tell me your husband
won't be home for hours.
So?
Mrs. Robinson, you are
trying to seduce me.
Aren't you?
Well, no. I hadn't thought of it.
I feel rather flattered -
Mrs. Robinson, will you forgive
me for what I just said?
It's all right.
It's not all right, it's the worst
thing I've ever said to anyone.
Sit down.
Please forgive me. Because I like you.
I don't think of you that way. But I'm mixed up.
It's all right. Now finish your drink.
Mrs. Robinson, it makes me sick
that I said that to you.
Forget it right now. Finish your drink.
What is wrong with me?
Have you ever seen Elaine's portrait?
Her portrait?
Yes.
No.
We had it done last Christmas.
Would you like to see it?
Very much.
Here is Elaine's room.
Elaine certainly is an
attractive girl, isn't she?
I don't remember her as having brown eyes.
Benjamin?
Yes?
Will you come here a minute?
Over there?sure
Will you unzip my dress? I think I'll go to bed.
Oh. Well, goodnight.
Won't you unzip my dress?
I'd rather not, Mrs. Robinson.
If you still think I'm trying to seduce you -
No, I don't. But I just feel a little funny.
Benjamin - you've known me all your life.
I know that. But I'm -
Come on. It's hard for me to reach.
Thank you.
Right.
What are you so scared of?
I'm not scared, Mrs. Robinson.
Then why do you keep running away?
Because you're going to bed.
I don't think I should be up here.
Haven't you ever seen anybody in a slip before?
Yes, I have. But I just -
Look - what if Mr. Robinson walked in right now?
What if he did?
Well, it would look pretty funny, wouldn't it?
Don't you think he trusts us together?
Of course he does.
But he might get the wrong idea.
Anyone might.
I don't see why.
I'm twice as old as you are.
How could anyone think......
But they would! Don't you see?
Benjamin - I'm not trying to seduce you.
I know that. But please, Mrs. Robinson.
This is difficult for me.
Would you like me to seduce you?
What?
Is that what you're trying to tell me?
I'm going home now.
I apologize for what I said.
I hope you can forget it.
But I'm going home right now.
Benjamin?
Yes.
Will you bring up my purse before you go?
I have to go now. I'm sorry.
I really don't want to put this on again.
Won't you bring it up?
Where is it?
On the table in the hall.
Mrs. Robinson?
I'm in the bathroom.
Well here's the purse.
Could you bring it up?
Well I'll hand it to you. Come to
the railing and I'll hand it up.
Benjamin - I am getting pretty
tired of all this suspicion.
Now if you won't do me a simple favor,
I don't know what.
I'm putting it on the top step.
For God's sake, Benjamin, will you stop
acting that way and bring me the purse?
I'm putting it here by the door.
Will you bring it in to me?
I'd rather not.
All right. Put it in Elaine's room where we were.
Right.
Oh, God!
Let me out!
Don't be nervous.
Get away from that door.
Let me say something first.
Jesus Christ!
Benjamin, I want you to know
I'm available to you.
If you want sleep with me this time.
Oh my Christ!
If you want sleep with me this time
I want you to know you can call me up any time
you want and we'll make some kind of arrangement.
Do you understand what I said?
Let me out!
Benjamin, Do you understand what I said?
Yes. Yes. Let me out!
Because I find you very attractive
and any time you want-
Oh, Jesus!
Is that Ben's car in front?
Yes, Sir!
I drove - I drove Mrs. Robinson home.
She wanted me to drive her home so I -
I drove her home.
Well. I appreciate it.
She's upstairs. She wanted me to
wait down here till you got home.
Standing guard over the old castle, are you?
Yes, sir.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
It looks like you need a refill.
Oh no. I got to go home.
Is anything wrong? You look a little shaken up.
No. No - I'm just - I'm just a little worried about
my future. I'm a little upset about my future.
Come on. Let's have a nightcap together.
Scotch?
Bourbon.
Ben - how old are you now?
20. I'll be 21 next week.
That's a hell of a good age to be.
Thank you.
Thank you very much!
I wish I was that age again. Because, Ben -
Sir?
You'll never be young again.
I know.
Ben, can I say something to you?
What?
How long have we known each other now?
How long have you and I known each other?
How long have your Dad and I been partners?
Quite a while.
I've watched you grow up, Ben.
Yes, sir.
In many ways I feel as though
you were my own son.
Thank you.
So I hope you won't mind my giving
you a friendly piece of advice.
I'd like to hear it.
Ben - I think - I think you ought to be taking it
a little easier right now than you seem to be.
Sow a few wild oats. Take things as they come.
Have a good time with the girls and so forth.
Don't get up.
I was just telling Ben here he ought to sow
a few wild oats. Have a good time while
he can. You think that's sound advice?
Yes, I do.
I've got to go.
You have yourself a few fillings this summer.
I bet you're quite a ladies' man.
Oh no.
What? You look to me like the kind of guy that
has to fight them off. Doesn't he look to you
like the kind of guy who has to fight them off?
Yes, he does.
Oh say - Elaine gets down
from Berkeley on Saturday.
Oh yes.
I wish you give her a call.
I will.
Benjamin? Benjamin?
Yes.
Thank you for taking me home.
I'll see you soon, I hope.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention, please
for this afternoon's feature attraction.
Hey, over there! Yes, I mean you!
Your attention please!
Are you ready in there, feature attraction?
Could I speak to you for a second, Dad?
Listen, I'm going to ask a big round of applause
to bring this boy out here, all right?
Wait a minute, let me amend that, to bring this young
man out here, because today he is 21 years old.
Come on, let's get on with the show!
Hang on a minute, I got a few words to say -
You always do.
ah, ah! what's talking
Dad, could we just talk about this for a second?
I can't hold them much longer, Ben.
You better get out here.
I'd like to discuss this.
This boy - I'm sorry - this young man -
is soon to continue his education
as a Frank Halpingham Award Scholar
But before he does - before he does -
You're disappointing them, Ben.
You're disappointing them.
Dad - can you listen -
I'll give you ten seconds
He is going to give us a practical
demonstration of what I feel safe
in saying is a pretty exciting birthday present
And it better work or I'm out
over two hundred bucks.
Ok, let's herald now for - Benjamin Braddock!
Come on, let's herald now!
Folks, this remarkable young man is going to
perform for you some spectacular and amazing
feats of daring in water that is over 6 feet deep.
is going to perform for you some spectacular
and amazing feats of daring in water
that is over 6 feet deep
Hello.
I don't quite know how to put this -
Benjamin?
Look, I was thinking about that time after the party -
Where are you?
I was wondering if I could
buy you a drink or something.
Where are you?
Uh - The Taft Hotel.
Did you get a room?
No. Now I know it's pretty
late and if you'd rather -
Give me an hour.
What?
I'll be there in an hour.
Can I help you, sir!
What?  Oh - no - I'm just -
Are you here for an affair, sir?
What?
The Singleman party, sir?
Oh - yes.  The Singleman party.
It's in the main ballroom.
Ahh - thank you.
Hello.
You must be one of the Poets.
No - actually I'm not -
I'd like you to know my sister,
Miss DeWitte -
How do you do?
How do you do, Miss DeWitte?
- and my husband, Mr. Singleman -
Oh, sorry.
Fine, thank you.
That's Jeffrey, of course.
Of course.
I didn't get your name, sir.
Benjamin Braddock, sir.
Braddock - Braddock?
Yes, but I'm afraid -
I'll find your table in a moment.
Braddock. Not Braniff? We have a Braniff.
No - actually I'm just
looking for a friend.
Oh, but I don't understand.
I'm not with your party - I'm sorry.
Hey - I don't get it.
I've enjoyed meeting you, Mr. Braniff.
Hello, Benjamin.
Oh. Hello.
May I sit down?
Of course.
Thank you.
How are you?
Very well. Thank you.
May I have a drink?
A drink?  Of course.
He didn't see me.
Waiter! I will have a martini.
Yes, madam.
You don't have to be
so nervous, you know.
Nervous. Well, I am a bit nervous.
I mean it's - it's pretty hard
to be suave when you're -
Did you get us a room?
What?
Have you gotten us a room yet?
I haven't. No.
Do you want to?
Well, I don't. I mean I could or we could just talk.
Do you want me to get it?
You? Oh no. No, I'll get it.
Do you want to get it now?
-Now?
-Yes.
Well - I don't know.
Why don't you get it.
Why don't I get it? Well, I will then.
If you'll excuse me.
Yes sir?
A room. I'd like a room, please.
Single room or double room?
A single. Just for myself, please.
Will you sign the register, please?
Is anything wrong, sir?
What? No, Nothing.
Do you have any luggage, Mister -- Gladstone?
Luggage?  Yes.  Yes.  I do.
Where is it?
What?
Where is your luggage?
Well it's in the car. It's out in the car.
Very good, sir. I'll have a porter bring it in.
-Oh no. I mean I'd rather not go
to the trouble of bringing it all in.
I just have a toothbrush.
I can get it myself. If that's all right.
Of course.
I'll have a porter show you the room.
Oh. Well actually, I'd just as soon find it myself.
I just have the toothbrush to carry up
and I think I can manage it myself.
Whatever you say, sir.
Thank you!
Mrs. Robinson.
Yes?
For you.
Thank you.
Hello?
Mrs. Robinson?
Yes?
It's Benjamin.
Benjamin Braddock.
Benjamin, where are you?
Can you look through the glass.
Can you see me now?
Yes, I can.
I got a single room.
That's fine.
But there's one thing. The desk clerk
seemed to be a little bit suspicious.
I don't know what their policy is.
Well - do you want to go up first?
Yes - I think that would be good.
I'll be up in five minutes.
Well - goodbye then -
Benjamin.
Yes?
Isn't there something
you want to tell me?
To tell you?
Yes.
Well, I want you to know how
much I appreciate this, really.
The room number.
What?
The room number, Benjamin.
I think you ought to tell me that.
Oh? You're absolutely right.
It's 562.
Thank you.
You're welcome. Well - I'll see
you later, Mrs. Robinson.
Check, please.
I've got it.
I say I've got it.
Sir?
The toothbrush. I got it all right.
Very good, sir.
Yes.  Well - goodnight.
Goodnight, sir.
Hello, Benjamin.
Hello, Mrs Robinson.
Benjamin.
Yes?
I'll get undressed now. Is that all right?
Sure.
Shall I - I mean shall I just stand here?
I mean - I don't know what you want me to do.
Why don't you watch?
Oh, sure. Thank you.
Will you bring me a hanger?
What?
A hanger.
Oh, yes.
Wood?
What?
Wood or wire?  They have both.
Either one will be fine.
Okay.
Thank you!
Will you help me with this, please?
Certainly.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Benjamin, Would this be
easier for you in the dark?
Mrs. Robinson - I can't do this.
You what?
This is all terribly wrong.
Do you find me undesirable?
Oh no, Mrs. Robinson.
I think - I think you're the most
attractive of all my parents' friends.
I mean that. I found you desirable, but I-
For god's sake, can you
imange my parents?
Can you imange what they will say if
they just saw we are in this room like now?
What will they say?
I have no idea, Mrs. Robinson.
But for god's sake.
They brought me up, they
made a good life for me.
And I think they deserve better than this.
I think they deserve a little better than
jumping into bed with their partner's wife.
Are you afraid of me?
Oh, no, you are missing the point.
Look, maybe we could do something else together.
Mrs. Robinson, would you like to go to a movie.
Can I ask you a personal question?
I should do anything you want.
Is this your first time?
Is this - what?
It is, isn't it?
It is your first time.
That's a laugh, Mrs. Robinson.
That's really a laugh. Ha ha.
You can admit that, can't you?
Are you kidding?
It's nothing to be ashamed of -
Wait a minute!
On your first time -
Who said it was my first time.
that you're afraid -
Wait a minute.
- of bring - inadequate -  I mean just because
you happen to be inadequate in one way -
INADEQUATE!
Don't move.
Ben - what are you doing?
Well - I would say that I'm just
drifting. - here - in the pool.
Why?
Well - it's very comfortable -
just to drift here.
Have you thought about graduate school?
No.
Would you  mind telling me then -
what were those four years of
college for?  What was the point
of all that hard work?
You got me.
Now listen, Ben.
I think it's a very good thing that a young
man - after he's done some very good work -
should have a chance to relax and enjoy himself,
and lie around, and drink beer and so on.
But after a few weeks
I believe that person would want to take
some stock in himself and his situation
and start to think about
getting off his ass.
The Robinson's are here.
Hi, Ben.  What are you doing
with yourself these days?
Oh, not too much. Taking it easy.
That's what I'd do if I could.
Nothing wrong with that.
Hey, Ben, Elaine's coming
down from Berkeley soon.
I want you to call her up this time.
I will.
Because I just think you two would
hit it off real well together.
Say hello to Mrs. Robinson, Benjamin.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
Hello, Benjamin.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Sure.
Benjamin, Darling.
I'm going to ask you something
but you don't have to tell me
if you don't want to.
What?
Well I'm going to ask you what
you do when you go off at night.
When I go off?
You don't have to tell me if
you don't want to.
No, I do. I want to tell you.
I drive around.
What else?
Nothing else.
Well you don't drive around from midnight
until noon the next day, Benjamin.
Oh, no.
Then what do you do? Do you meet someone?
Meet someone?
Why did you say that?
Well this is your business,
I won't play games.
No wait. Wait, I don't meet anyone,
Mother. But why did you say that?
Benjamin, I don't want to pry
into your affairs,
but I'd rather you didn't say
anything at all than be dishonest.
Goodnight.
Well, wait.
Wait a minute.
Will you wait a minute, please?
Mrs. Robinson, do you think we could say
a few words to each other first this time?
I don't think we have much
to say to each other.
Look, for a month, all we ever do is to
come up here and leap into bed together.
Are you tired of it?
I'm not. No. But do you think
we could liven it up with a
conversation for change?
Well what do you want to talk about?
Anything.  Anything at all.
Do you want to tell me about
some of your college experiences?
Oh my God.
Think of another topic.
How about art.
Art. That's a good subject.
You start it off.
You start it off. I don't know
anything about it.
What do you want
to know about it.
Are you interested more in modern
art or more in classical art.
Neither.
You're not interested in art?
No.
Then why do you want to talk about it?
I don't.
Now look, we are going to do this thing.
we are going to have a conversation.
Tell me what you did today.
I got up.
I fixed breakfast for my husband.
There!
There's something we could have
a conversation about Your husband!
Him?
I mean everything. I don't know
anything about how you work this.
What do you say to him when
you leave the house at night?
Nothing. He's asleep.
Always? Doesn't he wake up
when you come home?
We have seperated bedrooms.
So you don't - I mean I don't
like to seem like I'm prying
but I guess you don't sleep
together or anything.
No we don't.
Well how long has
this been going on.
Forgot it.
Wait a minute,  Why do you hurry?
See if you can guess.
Well I can't.
Think real hard, Benjamin.
I can't see why you did, unless
You didn't have to marry
him or anything, did you?
Don't tell Elaine.
Oh no.  You had to marry him
because you got pregnant?
Are you shocked?
Well I never thought of you and Mr.
Robinson as the kind of people who...
Oh, I know. Let's get to bed.
Wait a minute.  Wait a minute.
So how did it happen?
What?
Mrs. Robinson, I mean do you feel like telling me
what were the circumstances?
Not particularly.
Was he a law student at the time?
And you were a student also.
At college.
Yes.
What was your major?
Benjamin, why are you asking
me all these questions?
Because I'm interested, Mrs. Robinson.
Now what was your
major subject at college?
Art.
Art?
But I thought you...
I guess you kind of lost interest
in it over the years then.
Kind of.
Well how did it happen?
What?
You and Mr. Robinson.
How do you think.
I mean did he take you
up to his room with him?
Did you go to a hotel?
Benjamin, what does
it possibly matter?
I'm curious.
We'd go to his car.
Oh no. In the car you did it?
I don't think we were the first.
What kind of car was it?
What?
Do you remember the
make of the car?
Oh my God.
Really. I want to know.
It was a Ford, Benjamin.
A Ford!  A Ford!  God damn it,
That's great! a Ford!
That's enough.
So old Elaine Robinson
got started in a Ford.
Don't talk about Elaine.
Don't talk about Elaine?
No.
Why not?
Because I don't want you to.
Why don't you?
I wish you'd tell me.
There's nothing to tell.
Well why is she a big taboo
subject all of a sudden?
Well - I guess I'll have to ask her out on a date
and find out what the problem is.
Benjamin, don't you ever take that
girl out. Do you understand that?
Well look. I have no
intention of taking her out.
Good.
I was just kidding around.
But why shouldn't I?
I have my reasons.
Then let's hear them.
No.
Let's hear your reasons, Mrs. Robinson.
Because I think I know what they are.
I'm not good enough for her
to associate with, am I?
I'm not good enough to
even talk about her, am I?
Let's drop it.
We're not dropping it.
I'm good enough for you but I'm too
slimy to associate with your daughter.
That's it, isn't it? ISN'T IT?
Yes
You go to hell. You go straight
to hell, Mrs. Robinson.
Do you think I'm proud of myself?
Do you think I'm proud of this?
I wouldn't know.
Well, I'm not.
No sir. I am not proud that I spend my time
with a brokendown alcoholic!
I see.
And if you think I come here for
any reason besides pure boredom,
then you're all wrong.
Because, Mrs. Robinson, this is the sickest,
most perverted thing that ever happened to me.
And you do what you want
but I'm getting the hell out.
Are you?
You're goddamn right I am.
That's how you feel about me.
That I'm a sick and disgusting person.
I won't start this.
What?
Don't start acting hurt.
Don't you expect me
to be a little hurt?
Mrs. Robinson, you lie here and tell me
I'm not good enough for your daughter.
Did I say that?
In some other words.
Benjamin, I want to apologize to you
if that's the impression you got.
Well two minutes ago you told me
I wasn't good enough for your daughter.
Now you say you're sorry
I got that impression.
I didn't mean it.  I don't think
you'd be right for each other.
But I would never say you weren't
as good a person as she is.
You wouldn't.
Of course I wouldn't.
What are you doing?
Well it's pretty obvious you
don't want me around any more.
Well look -
I was kind of upset there.
I'm sorry I said those things.
That's all right. I think I can
understand why I'm disgusting to you.
Oh no. Look, I like you.
I wouldn't keep coming here if I didn't like you.
But if it's sickening for you -
It's not!
I enjoy it! I look forward to it. It's the
one thing I have to look forward to.
You don't have to say that.
Well I wouldn't. I would
never say it if it wasn't true.
May I stay then?
Yes. Please. I want you to.
Thank you.
Well don't thank me,
because I want you to.
But you won't ever take out Elaine, will you?
I want you to promise me with that.
Look. Why the hell did you bring this up.
It never occured to me to take her out.
Then give me your word you won't.
This is absurd.
Promise me, Benjamin.
All right, I promise, for christ's sake.
I promise I will never take
out Elaine Robinson.
Thank you.
Benjanmin.
Let's not talk about it.
Let's not talk at all.
Elaine's back from school.
I think it might be a nice gesture
if you asked her out.
Suppose she's not good
enough for you, is that it?
Look - Elaine Robinson and I
do not get along.
How do you know?
You haven't seen her since high school.
Suppose
your evenings, whatever
you do with them, are just too valuable.
That has nothing to do with it -
I guess I'll just tell Mr. Robinson
that you're just too busy every
evening - doing God knows what -
Don't go on like this.
If Benjamin absolutely
refuses to take her out -
I do.
- then I'll simply invite all the
Robinsons' over on Thursday.
Well, Braddock - it's about
time you got around to this.
Hello.
Come on in. I'm afraid the young
lady isn't quite ready yet.
What would you say to a short one?
Scotch still your drink?
Bourbon.
I'll see if she's ready.
Now listen, this was not my
idea. It was my father's idea.
Benjamin, I thought I made myself
perfectly clear about this.
Look, we'll go out to dinner and
have a drink and I'll bring her back.
Because it was either that or a
dinner party for the two families.
And I'm afriad I couldn't quite
handle that, if you don't mind.
Look, I have no intention of ever taking
your precious daughter out again in her life.
So don't get upset about it.
But I am. I'm extremely
upset about it, Benjamin.
Hello.
Well, I want you to keep your wits about you tonight.
You never know what tricks Ben
picked up back there in the East.
You're living at home now. Is that right?
Yes.
Do you know what you're going to do?
No.
Are you going to graduate school?
Do you always drive like this?
Yes.
Sit down.
Why don't you watch the show?
Benjamin, do you dislike
me for some reason?
No - why should I?
I don't know.
You're missing a great effect here.
Are you like that?
Could you do it?
Stop.Hey!!!
Elaine, I'm sorry.
Will you take me home now?
I'm sorry I took you in there.
I think I'd better go
home now, please.
Where is the car?
I just want to tell you something.
I want to go home.
But could I just tell you this one thing?
What?
This whole idea, this date and everything.
It was my parents' idea.
They forced me into it.
Oh - that's very nice of
you to tell me.
No.  What I mean is - that's
why I've been acting this way.
I'm not like this.
I hate myself like this.
Listen, could you just stop crying, please?
No, I couldn't.
But could you try?
No.
I've had this feeling ever
since I've graduated.
This kind of compulsion that
I have to be rude all the time.
Do you know what I mean?
Yes, I do.
It's like I've been playing
some kind of - game -
but the rudes
don't make any sense to me.
They're being made up
by all the wrong people.
No, I mean no one makes them up,
they seem to have made themselves up.
Hey - I wonder if I could request
you to turn that down a little?
Would you like to come in?
I could make some coffee.
No, I mean - I wouldn't
want to wake anyone up.
We won't.  Let's go inside.
Wait a minute.
Is anything wrong?
No, I was just thinking.
It's still early.
We could do something,
go somewhere else.
All right.
Where we going?
I'm trying to think of where there's a place
to have a drink around here.
Isn't there one in the Taft Hotel?
What is the matter?
Nothing.  I'm just wondering
if they have a bar or not.
I mean let's go see. Let's
go see if they do or not.
Listen, Elaine, it seems to me
that there is a bar here.
I mean - as far as I know.
Of course there is. Look, the
Veranda Room, right there.
Good evening.
Hello, how are you, sir?
Good evening, Mr. Gladstone.
Hello again.
Hi, Mr. Gladstone.
How are you this evening?
Benjamin -
Let's get out of here, Elaine.
Let's go somewhere else.
Do they know you?
Of course not.
Good evening, sir.
Come on, Elaine. We're leaving.
Mr. Gladstone - how are you?
Benjamin, what's happening?
I don't know. They must think
I look like this guy Gladstone.
Hello, Mr. Brannif.
Elaine, I like you.
I like you so much.
Do you believe that?
Do you?
Yes.
You're the first - you're the first
thing for so long that I've liked.
The first person
I could stand to be with.
My whole life is such a waste.
It's just nothing.
I'm sorry.  I'll take you home now.
Benjamin - are you having
an affair with someone?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
That is not my business.
It just happened.
It was just this thing that happened
along with everything else.
Can you understand that?
Was she married or something?
Yes.
With a family?
Yes. She had a husband and a son.
Did they ever find out?
No.
And it's all over now.
Yes.
I'm glad.
Can we do something tomorrow?
All right.
During the day?  We'll go
for a drive or something.
Okay.
You sure you really want to?
Yes.
Because I wouldn't want you to
do it unless you really wanted to!
I do.
You do?
Benjamin, I really do.
Drive down the block.
Mrs. Robinson, Elaine I have
a date. We're going for a drive.
Do exactly as I say.
Listen to me very carefully, Benjamin
You are not to see Elaine again, ever.
Those are my orders. Is that clear?
Mrs. Robinson, do you think -
I can makes things quite unpleasant.
How?
In order to keep Elaine away from you,
I am prepared to tell her everything.
I don't believe you.
Then you'd better start believing me.
I just don't believe you would do that.
Try me.
Elaine! Elaine!
Benjamin?
I'm coming up.
I'm not dressed yet.
Benjamin - I said I wasn't dressed.
You've got to go over the back fence
and I'll meet you on the corner.
Benjamin, what's the matter?
Hurry up. Put your shoes on.
Benjamin, Benjamin.
Elaine.
What are you doing?
Elaine, I have to tell you something.
What is it?
That woman.
What?
The older woman we talked about.
You mean the one who -
Yes, the married woman.
It wasn't just some woman -
What are you telling me?
Benjamin, will you just tell
me what it is all about?
Oh, no.
Elaine -
Oh my God!
Please!
Get out of here!
Don't cry -
GET OUT!
Goodbye, Benjamin.
Say that again.
I'm going to marry Elaine Robinson.
Ha...Ha... Well - Well - Well
What's happening?
Ben says he and Elaine
are getting married.
I don't believe it.
That's what he says. Right?
I'm going up to Berkeley today.
Come on, let's call the Robinsons.
We've got something to celebrate.
No, I think you'll want
to wait on that.
They don't know?
No - they don't.
Well, when did you decide all this?
About an hour ago.
Wait a minute. You talked
to Elaine this morning?
No, she doesn't know about it.
You mean she doesn't know
that you're coming up to Berkeley?
No. Actually, she doesn't know
about us getting married yet.
When did you two talk this over?
We haven't.
You haven't?
Ben, this whole idea
sounds pretty half-baked.
No, it's not. It's completely baked.
It's a decision I've made.
But what makes you think
she wants to marry you?
She doesn't. To be perfectly
honest, she doesn't like me.
You are student?
Not exactly.
What's not exactly?
- no.
What are you then?
Well, I'm just sort of traveling through.
I like to know who's living in my house,
like to know what my boys are up to.
I'm not up too much.
I'm just visiting.
I mean - I've always wanted to see Berkeley.
You're not one of those agitators?
What?
One of those outside agitators.
Oh - no.
I hate that.
I won't stand for it.
Well, how about this for a coincidence.
I was wondering where
you were headed.
I'm meeting someone.
Ah. Where?
Where are you meeting this person?
At the zoo.
The Zoo. They have a pretty
good one here, do they?
I don't know, I've never seen it.
Oh. Well, I haven't either.
I might just ride out there with you.
Is that him over there?
No.
Where did he say he was going to meet you?
I thought he said by the monkey house.
Benjamin - I would like to know
what you're doing here.
Here?  In Berkelely?
Yes.
Well, I have this very pleasant room on Carter
Street, and I've been getting to some classes.
But you're not enrolled.
No, I just sit in.
They don't seem to mind.
They've been very congenial about it.
Benjamin - you're -
I don't know what to say.
Maybe we could get together
some time and talk about it.
Really incredible.
Here he comes.
What?
I've got a real feeling
that this is the fellow.
Elaine!
He certainly is a good walker.
Am I late? I'm sorry.
We thought you said by
the monkey house.
This is Benjamin Braddock.
Carl Smith.
Benjamin rode here with me on the bus.
Glad to meet you, Ben.
Great meeting you, Carl.
Swell seeing you.
Who is this?
I want to ask you a question. and I'm going.
Come in.
No. I want to know why
you're here in Berkeley?
Because - I am.
Is it because I'm here?
What do you think?
I think it is.
I said I think it is.
All right then! Yes!
Well, I want you to leave.
Oh, look, I love you!
How could you do that, Benjamin?
Do you just hate everything?
How could you possibly rape my mother?
What?
I don't understand -
I don't understand how you - how
anyone - could do a thing like that.
What did she say?
You got tell me what did she say.
Why?
Because it isn't true.
Tell me.
She said she was having a drink
in the hotel with a friend.
You waited for her in the parking lot and told
her she was too drunk to drive home
and you would get her a room for the night.
Then what?
Then you took her upstairs
and you raped her.
Oh, no, no, no, that's not what happened.
What happened was there
was this party at my parents.
I drove your mother home -
I don't want to hear it.
then we went upstairs
to see your portrait.
No - I no -
and when we got up in the room -
She is my mother!
- she starts taking her her clothes off
suddenly there she was without any
clothes on. I mean really naked.
Oh, hello, Mr. McCleery.
Who screamed?
It's all right, Mr. McCleery.
Screaming isn't all right.
Not in my house, it isn't.
It was just a visitor.
But it's all right now.
What did you do to her?
Look, she's all right. She's upset and
she screamed. But she's okay now.
Shall I get the cops?
What?
I'll get the cops.
Hey, wait a minute.
Damned look, see, here
she's having some water.
Now there's no need
for the cops or anything.
All right, boys, I think you can
get back to your rooms now.
I don't think we'll have
any more of this agitation.
Will we, Braddock?
No, sir.
I want you out of here.
What do you mean?
You heard me. Out of here.
What for?
Because I don't like you.
I'm sorry I screamed.
Benjamin, when you came up here,
what did you think was going
to happen between us?
Elaine - right now I don't
feel like talking much.
I'm sorry about everything.
but I think I'll just do this now.
Can I just sit here while you're packing?
If you want.
What are you going to do now?
I don't know.
Are you going home?
No.
Well, where are you going?
Elaine, you're going to stop asking me.
I don't want you to leave tomorrow.
I don't understand.
I don't want you to go anywhere.
until you have a definite plan.
Goodbye.
What's happening?
Benjamin?
What?
Will you kiss me!
Will you marry me?
You won't?
I don't know.
But you might.
I might.
Is that so? You might marry me?
Yes.
When?
I don't know.
How about tomorrow?
I don't mean to be pushy but -
I don't know. I don't
know what's happening.
You mean you're confused?
Well, look, don't be confused.
We're getting married.
I don't see how we can.
We just can.
I have to go now.
Elaine, are you serious about this?
I'll think about it.
You really will?
Yes.
We can go down and get our blood tests tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Or this afternoon.
It's a good day for it.
Benjamin, I haven't even
said I'll marry you yet.
We'll need our Birth Certificates.
I happen to have mine
with me. Where's yours?
I just don't think it would work.
Why wouldn't it?
I just don't think it would...
Tomorrow then - can we get our
blood tests tomorrow morning?
Why don't you just drag me off
if you want to marry me so much?
Why don't I just drag you off?
All right, I will.
Right after we get the blood tests.
I have to see Carl first.
Carl who?
Carl Smith. He's a medical student.
We've known him for years.
Who, that guy at the Zoo?
Yes.
Why do you have to see him?
Well, I said I might marry him.
You WHAT?
How did he do it?
Did he get down on his knees?
He didn't get down on his knees, I hope.
No, Benjamin.
Well, what did he say?  I'm curious.
He said he thought we'd
make a pretty good team.
Oh no. He said that.
Where did he do it?
I'd like to know where it happened?
It wasn't in his car, was it?
Good Night.
Are we getting married tomorrow?
No.
The day after tomorrow?
I don't know. Maybe we are
and maybe we aren't.
Do you want, do you want to
try and tell me why you did it?
Mr. Robinson?
Do you have a special grudge against me?
Do you feel a particularly strong resentment?
No.
Is there something I've said
that's caused this contempt?
Or just the things I stand for that you despise?
It was nothing to do with you, sir.
Well, Ben, it was quite
a bit to do with me.
Now look, please!
Ben, I think we're two civilized people.
Do you think it's necessary to threaten each other?
I'm not threatening you.
Do you want to unclench your fists, please.
Thank you.
I can see in the dark, you know.
I've been here quite a while.
I am trying to tell you I have no personal
feelings about you, Mr. Robinson.
I am trying to tell you
I do not resent you.
You don't respect me terribly
much either, do you?
No, Sir.
What?
Don't shout at me, Ben. I may not be younger
than you, but I still have good hearing.
Mr. Robinson.
Have you the patience to wait untill I finish?
I do think you know the consequences
of what you've done.
I do think you should know that my
wife and I are getting a divorce soon.
But why?
Why?
Listen to me.
What happened between Mrs. Robinson
and me was nothing. It mean anything.
We might just as well have been shaking hands.
Shaking hands. Well, that's not
saying much for my wife, is it?
You miss the point.
I guess I do.
The point is I don't love your wife.
I love your daughter, sir.
All right, now listen this.
I don't know what I can possibly do.
But I think I can.
I think I can get you behind bars if
you ever look at my daughter again.
I have seen Elaine and I make
damned sure you can get to...
Stay away from me, Ben!
I don't want to mince words with you.
As far as Elaine's concerned, you're to
get her out of your filthy mind right now.
Is that perfectly clear to you?
And that's all, Ben.
You'll pardon me if I don't
shake hands with you.
I think you are filth.
I think you are scum.
You are a degenerate!
Mr. McCleery, do you have some change?
I need to use the phone.
I want you out of here.
Look, I'll give you ten dollars
for a dime. I'll give you twenty.
For God's sake, will you
let me use that phone?
I'll call the police, now.
Could I make one phone call first?
Get out here!
Elaine Robinson has left the school. Her
roommate is coming down with a note for you.
Dear Benjamin, please forgive me.
Because I know what I'm doing
is the best thing for you.
My father is so upset
you've got to understand.
I love you, but it would never work out.
Elaine.
Hello, Benjamin.
Where is she?
Hello. Get me the police, please.
Where is Elaine?
I'll be with you in a moment.
Do you have a petrol car in the
vicinity of 1200 Glenview Road.
Good, we have a burgler here.
Just a second. I'll ask him.
Are you armed?
No, I don't believe he is.
Thank you!
What have you done to her?
I think we have everything quite
under control now, Benjamin.
Would you like a quick drink before you go?
You can't stop me from seeing her,
Mrs. Robinson.  I'll find her.
I'm sorry we won't be able to invite
you to the wedding, Benjamin
but the arrangements have been so rushed.
What the hell have you done?
Ahh.  I don't think you'll have
time for that drink after all.
I'll find her.
I don't think so.
Say, fellows. Any of you fellows
know where Carl Smith is?
He took off in the middle of
the night to get married.
Proabaly one step ahead of the shotgun.
Would you happen to know where he's
getting married? I'm supposed to be there.
Why not just ask Carter?
Would you happen to know
where I might find him?
Hey, Carter, where's the Make
Out King getting married?
Santa Barbara.
You don't happen to know exactly where
the Make Out King is getting married, do you?
I'm supposed to be there.
Where side of Santa Barbara?
I don't know. Maybe at his old man's house.
He only told me these words.
Are you going to the wedding?
Yes.
Hey, tell him to save the piece for me.
of the wedding cake.
Can I use your phone?
Yes.
657-2036
Hello - who is this?
This is Dr. Smith's answering service.
Is the doctor anywhere?
I'm afraid Doctor can't be reached right now.
If you like to...
I'd like to know where he is.
Well, you see, the doctor is at his son's
wedding, but I'm sure it's over by now.
He should be checking in any moment.
Listen to me. I am Dr. Smith's
brother - Reverend Smith -
and I am supposed to perform the
ceremony. I just got in from Portland.
and I've forgotten what church, you see?
Oh. Well, I'm not sure, but you
might try the First Presbyterian.
That's on Allan Street.
Thank you!
Allan Street. Where is it?
Alan Street. It's, it's
6 blocks up, and 3 over.
You need any gas, Father?
Oh, Jesus - God - no -
Elaine! Elaine! Elaine! Elaine!
Who is that guy?
What's he doing?
I'll take care of him.
He is too late.
Elaine! Elaine! Elaine! Elaine!
Get to stop him.
Ben!
You are crazy buck!
Elaine, it's too late.
Not for me!Not for me!