You know,
I just had a thought.
Why don't I check in a hotel
and rest.
- You go find your folks.
- Oh, John.
You wanted to meet them.
Let's go meet them.
The sooner we get it over with,
the better.
Mom may not even be at the gallery.
She'll probably be out to lunch.
Dad's at his office. You may not
meet them till dinner anyway.
You may be wrong about them.
You should have called
and told them we were coming.
You may be in for the biggest shock
of your young life.
After 23 years living
in the same house with them...
don't you think I know
my own mother and father?
I hope so.
There's no problem.
We'll only be a minute, and then
we'd like to go out to Claremont Drive.
Right.
I'll see if Mom's
in the office.
- Joey!
- Hilary, hi! How are you?
What a surprise.
- I'll be with you in just a moment.
- Okay.
- Strange.
- One of Hilary's favorites.
It's called a kinetic sculpture.
- A what?
- Look.
Why, isn't that something?
- Darling, what are you doing here?
- I thought Mother might be here.
Mrs. St. George, I'd like you
to meet Dr. Prentice.
Dr. Prentice,
I'm so pleased to meet you.
Mrs. St. George.
Pleasure to see you.
Christina's lunching
with Mr. Cazalet.
I can ring up.
No. Just tell her I'm back
and that I'll be home.
Has something happened?
I mean, is anything wrong?
Something's happened,
but everything's right. Thanks.
How was Hawaii?
Was it fun?
Hawaii was simply unbelievable.
Do you live in San Francisco, Doctor,
or are you just visiting?
- I'm just passing through.
- I see.
- It was a pleasure to have met you.
- Thank you.
Bye-bye.
No, Hilary runs the gallery now,
but it's Mom who has all the ideas.
Her idea for filling hotel rooms
with originals is brilliant.
It gives people who stay there
time to decide if they want them.
The hotel gets supplied
with free decor.
The guests get to look at good paintings
instead of bad reproductions.
The painter gets a chance to make a sale
and Mom gets her commission.
Next right.
- Isn't that clever?
- Oh, that is clever.
- What do I owe you?
- 10.50, mac.
Twelve bucks, right?
Right.
Oh, John.
Come meet Tillie.
Tillie, this is Dr. Prentice.
John, Miss Matilda Binks.
Pleased to meet you, Miss Binks.
I've certainly heard
a great deal about you.
What are you
doing home unexpected?
Your folks didn't know you was coming.
You told them you're back already?
I left a message for Mom
at the gallery.
It's lovely to see you.
I missed you.
You still ain't told me
why you're home early.
- You want those bags to go upstairs?
- Not my two. I'm not staying.
It's personal reasons.
I'll tell you all about it.
You eat any lunch yet,
or you expecting it now?
Could you make us sandwiches and coffee?
We'll have it on the terrace.
Do you like it?
It's beautiful.
Come out
and look from the terrace.
- What?
- Hey, who's that?
That's Dorothy. Isn't she a knockout?
She helps Tillie during the week.
- Which days?
- Never mind.
You know, I ought to call my folks
and get that out of the way.
Okay. Use the phone in the study.
- Are you gonna introduce me?
- Not on the phone.
- Aren't you gonna tell them about me?
- I'd rather write to them.
I have to meet them, don't I?
Before I come to Geneva?
Or are we going to keep our marriage
a secret from them?
Why didn't I think of that?
See, that's a thought.
I'll shut this
in case Dorothy goes by.
Los Angeles, please.
Area code 213.
Axminster, two, four, six, nine, nine.
Time and charges.
Well, I got a right
to my own opinions.
And you want my opinion?
I don't care to see a member
of my own race getting above hisself.
Then I don't want your opinion,
and if I ever do, I'll ask for it.
Oh, Tillie, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that, but you can't mean
what you're saying either.
And you're so wrong.
Look.
You're the last person I'd have expected
to take such a silly attitude.
You know I've always loved you,
and you're just as black as he is.
How could it be all right for me to
love you and wrong for me to love him?
Will you just stop
and think about that?
Listen. What are we having
for dinner tonight?
- Gotta make it something special.
- Celery soup and rump steak.
Oh, now, come on.
Turtle soup and tournedos...
and one of your best pies.
It's Mom!
Joey, darling.
What the hell? Joey!
- Mom, I'm here!
- Hello, darling. Are you all right?
- There's nothing wrong, is there?
- Nothing's wrong. Everything's fine.
I rang the gallery to tell Hilary
that Cazalet agreed to our scheme.
He has? That's marvelous.
I knew he would.
She said you were back. She thought
you might have a surprise for me.
What did she mean?
Do I hear someone?
- Is there someone here?
- Oh, Mom, I'm so happy.
I've never been so happy in all my life.
I'm just...
Bursting. Yeah, I can see that.
And I'm already feeling happy for you.
Do I know him?
No. That's just it.
I only met him myself ten days ago.
You wouldn't believe what's happened
in just ten days.
I think I might if you'd pipe down
long enough to tell me.
- Mom...
- Lots of wonderful things happen...
He's so wonderful!
I've never known anyone like him.
Never known anything like this.
I fell in love with him
in 20 minutes.
Well, that was quick.
Well, Dad, I wanted to stop
on the way back...
but time got so short
and I've got to get to work.
Yeah, but I still don't understand
why you couldn't spend one day with us.
Well, the fact is, Dad,
I met this girl.
You what? You met a girl?
Why didn't you say so?
Mary, he says he met a girl.
Why, that's good news.
- She live up there in San Francisco?
- She lives up here. I'm at her house.
He says he's at her house now,
the girl's house.
Well, that's different, son.
Where'd you meet her? Hawaii?
Yes, in Hawaii,
and I wanted to meet her folks, see?
That sounds good, son.
I mean, serious.
Yes, it's serious.
Well, this is quite a surprise.
Yeah, she's surprising
in a lot of ways, Dad.
Your mother says,
"Is she pretty? '
- Yes, she's very pretty.
- She's pretty. What?
Your mother says,
"How old is she, son?"
Mary, what the hell difference
does that make?
Well, she's only 23, Dad.
Twenty-three. Well, that's good.
You want my opinion?
You're 37.
That's just the right difference.
Women age faster than men,
you know what I mean?
- You reckon to marry the girl, son?
- Well, we've been talking about it.
But...
Dad, there's one or two problems,
you see?
That I'll write to you about...
on the plane to New York tonight,
all right?
He's so calm...
and sure of everything.
He doesn't have
any tensions in him.
He knows what he believes...
and what he thinks is right
and why and where he's going.
Oh, Mom, there's one thing
I must tell you.
He was married before,
and he had a son.
It was so tragic.
Both his wife and his son were killed
in a train accident...
in Belgium eight years ago.
And John...
I haven't even told you
his name.
Mom, it's John Wade Prentice.
Isn't that a lovely name?
John Wade...
Joanna Prentice...
I'll be.
But Mom...
there's something else
that I must tell you...
that John's been concerned about,
very deeply concerned.
He's been worrying for the past week
whether you and Dad would be upset if...
Well, it's about time.
I was wondering where you'd been.
Mom...
this is John.
Doctor Prentice...
I'm so pleased to meet you.
I'm pleased to meet you,
Mrs. Drayton.
I take it Joanna's already busted out
with the big news.
Well, she has told me a good deal
and all very quickly too.
Well, she's only known me
for ten days...
so she can't tell you
when I'm blushing.
That could be another problem
for us.
Mrs. Drayton,
I'm medically qualified...
so I hope you wouldn't
think it presumptuous if I say...
you ought to sit down
before you fall down.
He thinks you're gonna faint
because he's a Negro.
Well...
I don't think
I'm going to faint.
But I'll sit down anyway.
Can't we all sit down?
Well...
I suppose it would be all right
if I said, "My goodness," wouldn't it?
Well, my goodness.
- Do we mind her saying, "My goodness"?
- I don't mind.
What did they say?
Did you tell them about me?
- Yes.
- What'd they say?
They said I sounded serious
and asked if you were pretty.
I said you were.
They said this was a big surprise.
I said it was.
Well, what did they say when you
told them I wasn't a colored girl?
I didn't. It felt like
too big a shock for the telephone.
After all, a lot of people will think
that we're a very shocking pair.
Isn't that right?
I know what you mean.
Tillie's made us some sandwiches.
- Let's go outside.
- Yes, let's.
- Come on, Dr. Prentice.
- I can explain it all in two minutes.
You see, John was invited to lecture
at Hawaii University...
and we met at this big party
at the dean's.
After the party,
we went for a long drive.
- Thank you.
- And since then, we've been together.
We've been swimming every day.
Then John was supposed to fly back to
Los Angeles Saturday to see his parents.
That's where they live.
Thank you, Tillie.
Try one of these.
They're great.
- Do you want some coffee?
- No, thanks. No coffee.
Does your father know
that you're back?
No, I was going to phone him.
Do you think he'd come back early if...
He's coming back early, all right.
He's playing golf with Monsignor Ryan.
That's marvelous.
Then he can meet John
and we can all talk over dinner...
because John has to fly
to New York tonight to see a friend...
at Columbia University.
Then tomorrow night,
he's flying to Geneva...
to do three month's work
for the World Health Organization.
And I intend to fly to Geneva next week
so that we can be married.
And that's the whole situation.
In a nutshell.
Except that he thinks...
that the fact he's a Negro and I'm not
creates a serious problem.
Does he?
I've told him 97 times...
that it wouldn't make the slightest
difference to you or Dad.
But he just wouldn't believe me.
So that's why we're here.
And that's why he's watching you
so closely right now...
while he's pretending
not to watch you at all.
She's absolutely right, Mrs. Drayton.
I'm sorry.
I told her not to spring all this
on you so suddenly.
But... Look,
if your father's coming home...
you could at least say
that I'm somebody you met in Hawaii.
- Now, really?
- Give him a half hour to get adjusted.
But what for?
He still has to be told, doesn't he?
Well, you should make up your minds
because I think I just heard his car.
Mr. Matt.
- Hi. How are you?
- All hell's done broke loose.
- That waste disposal out again?
- It ain't that.
Just remember,
all hell's done broke loose.
- What's happened? Where's Christina?
- She's on the terrace with little Joey.
- With Joey?
- And somebody called Dr. Prentice.
Doctor? There's a doc...
Well, what's wrong?
What's happened? Joey!
Here he comes.
- Daddy! How are you?
- What's happened? What are you doing?
- Tillie said there was a doctor here.
- There is! Dr. John Wade Prentice.
- This is my dad.
- Pleased to meet you.
How are you? Nice to know you.
But what is it?
- Is something wrong?
- There's nothing wrong.
I decided to come home early.
Oh, Dr. Prentice and I
met in Hawaii...
and we flew back in the same plane
this morning.
Oh, well, sit down.
I thought something was really wrong.
Tillie said...
Tillie's behaving very strangely today.
Would you like coffee?
No, thanks. I have a date to play golf
with Monsignor Ryan.
How are you? What's the matter,
you having a chill?
No, darling, I'm fine.
I...
Doctor, where are you practicing?
In San Francisco?
- Sit down.
- No, sir.
I'm just here for one day.
Oh, where is your practice?
Hawaii?
Well, no, not...
I'm not established in any one place.
I'm in tropical medicines, mostly,
in Africa...
these past few years.
Well, that sounds interesting.
Everything about Dr. Prentice
is interesting.
I'm sure it is.
I wish I had more time,
but if you'll excuse me.
Couldn't you be a half hour late
and stay and talk with us?
I'd love to, but I mustn't keep
the Monsignor waiting.
No, I'm gonna be late as it is.
Will I be seeing you later, Doctor?
You certainly will.
Good.
Well, that's good.
Dr. Prentice will be here
for dinner, Matt.
Oh, fine. Then you can tell me
all about the African...
There's a great deal to tell too.
Isn't there, Mom?
Well, fine.
See you all later.
What the hell
is going on here?
- This doesn't make sense either.
- Well, I told you, didn't I?
What'd you tell him?
Look, Chris...
if you don't explain to me
in the next few minutes...
I can explain it, Mr. Drayton.
You can?
Well, let's have it
Well, it's my fault.
You see,
we have sort of a situation here.
Joanna and I didn't just meet
in Hawaii.
We spend a good deal of time
together.
I mean, all the time
after we met.
And, well, we have this problem:
I fell in love with your daughter.
And, as incredible
as it may seem...
she fell in love with me.
And we flew back
to San Francisco...
to see if you or Mrs. Drayton would have
any objections if we got married.
Joanna told her mother
as soon as she walked in...
and I had the stupid idea,
that maybe...
there was some way to...
break this gently.
Daddy, you're making
John and me nervous.
Am I?
Well, I wouldn't want to do that.
I wouldn't want to make anybody nervous.
How about you? Are you nervous?
Sit down, Doctor,
before you make me nervous.
Would anybody like
a cup of coffee?
What did she say
when Joanna told her?
- Did she raise any objections?
- None, so far. There hasn't been time.
What objections?
Dad, I know this is sort of a shock
because it's sudden and unexpected...
and it never occurred to me
that I might fall in love with a Negro.
But I did, and nothing in the world
is gonna change that.
Even if you had any objections,
I wouldn't let him go now if...
you were the governor of Alabama...
I mean, if Mom were.
Tell him, will you?
Tell John if you have any objections
and then you could go play golf.
Well, what is it
you expect me to say?
If you want me to think about this,
you'll have to give me time to think.
The doctor says you have a problem.
You certainly have.
If you're expecting a sensible
statement, you'll have to give me time.
Does that sound reasonable?
It's reasonable, Mr. Drayton,
but not quite practical.
You see, Matt...
there's sort of
a special problem.
See, I've got to fly
to New York tonight...
and on to Switzerland
tomorrow night.
Yes, and what Joey wants...
what she proposes...
is to go to Geneva herself
so they can be married...
within the next couple of weeks.
What the hell is all the rush?
We know that we want
to get married.
And unless somebody does have any
objections, why should we waste time?
John and I aren't gonna
change our minds.
Are you saying...
Are you telling me...
that you want an answer today...
about how your mother and I feel?
Of course. We want you and Mom
to state absolutely clearly...
that you have
no objections whatever...
and that when we do get married,
we'll have your blessing.
Now, are you gonna play golf
or not?
No.
I'll just call it off.
Excuse me, Doctor.
And that's my dad.
Do you like him?
- I don't know. Does he like me?
- I don't know either.
When he puts on
his American eagle face...
nobody can tell what he's thinking,
except Mom.
I don't think he liked any of us
after the silly way we began.
Excuse me, will you?
Give John some more coffee.
She's beautiful, Joanna.
She's even better looking than you.
You know that?
Hello, Edie?
Two things, Edie.
Both of them urgent.
Call up Monsignor Ryan and tell him
I can't play this afternoon.
Tell him something's come up,
something personal at home.
Then call the library...
and see if they've got any dope
on a John Wade Prentice.
Prentice. He's a doctor of medicine.
Fellow about 35, 36...
- Oh, Matt.
- He's a colored fellow.
Yeah.
If they haven't got anything...
call up the medical association
and see what they've got.
Get anything you can, will you, Edie?
All right. Hurry and call me back.
Surely there can't be
any necessity for that.
- It can't do any harm, either.
- But Joey said he was lecturing...
at the university in Hawaii.
Tell me something. This ever occur
to you that this might happen?
Never occurred to me either.
Not once.
Can you tell me your reaction?
- How do you feel about it?
- Oh, I don't know.
I was shaken at first.
I still am, I suppose.
But, Matt, they're serious.
They mean what they're saying.
Both of them.
They know what they're doing.
No, they may mean what they're saying,
I accept that.
But they don't know what they're doing.
I won't accept that.
If I'm not intruding...
Of course not.
Please, come in.
I'd like to have a couple of minutes
with the two of you, if I may?
Sure, Doctor.
Come on in.
There's something you both
ought to know. I made a decision.
Joanna doesn't know about it,
and I don't see why she should.
What is it, Doctor?
Joanna thinks she's committed...
and that our whole future
is settled...
but there is no real commitment.
And up to now,
nothing is settled at all.
I don't understand.
Joanna said you're going to be married
no matter what we think about it.
Well, that's not the case.
Unless you two approve...
and without any reservations at all...
there won't be any marriage.
Well, why, John?
Why have you decided that?
Well, Mrs. Drayton...
this thing has happened so quickly...
I'm just as startled
as you must be.
Two weeks ago, I would have said
such a thing was inconceivable.
But two weeks ago...
I had not met Joanna.
She's not at all
like anyone I've ever known.
It's not just that our color difference
doesn't matter to her.
It's that she doesn't seem to think
there is any difference.
The trouble is,
this thing has come up...
at a time when I already have
all the problems I need.
And I feel that I couldn't afford
to get married...
if it meant that I would have to take
on any special problems...
in addition to those
we're obviously going to have.
When you say "special problems,"
Doctor, what do you mean?
Well...
Your attitude, Mr. Drayton...
and yours, Mrs. Drayton.
Joanna is very close
to both of you.
If, by marrying me, she damaged
her relationship with either of you...
the pain of it
would be too much for her.
I wouldn't know how to deal
with that kind of situation.
In any case,
I wouldn't even want to try.
Well, I'm glad you told us,
Doctor.
Don't misunderstand me.
I love your daughter.
There is nothing I wouldn't do to keep
her as happy as she was the day we met.
But it seems to me,
without your approval...
we will make no sense at all.
That is why I'm asking for...
the clearest possible statement
of what your attitude is going to be.
I appreciate that, Doctor.
It's almost in the form
of an ultimatum.
Not quite, Mr. Drayton.
All you have to say
is good-bye.
Well, that's where it's at.
Thank you for the opportunity
to speak my peace.
Well...
still think you ought to have someone
check on him?
No.
He's right about Joey too.
- You know that, don't you?
- Yes.
Thank God he is. That's the way I feel.
Thank God he's right.
She's 23 years old,
and the way she is...
is just exactly the way
we brought her up to be.
We answered her questions.
She listened to our answers.
We told her it was wrong
to believe...
that white people were somehow
essentially superior to black people...
or the brown or the red
or the yellow ones, for that matter.
People who thought that way
were wrong to think that way.
Sometimes hateful, usually stupid,
but always wrong.
That's what we said...
and when we said it,
we did not add...
"But don't ever fall in love
with a colored man."
Edie, Mr. Drayton.
Do you want the whole story?
- Yeah, what is it, Edie?
- He's an important guy.
Just the main points:
Born Los Angeles, 1930...
graduated maxima cum laude
John Hopkins, '54...
assistant professor,
Yale Medical School, '55...
three years professor,
London School of Tropical Medicine...
three years assistant director,
World Health Organization...
two textbooks and a list of monographs
and medical society honors...
as long as your arm.
Married Elizabeth Bowers, 1955,
one son, John Wade.
Oh, both killed in an accident
in 1959.
- There's a lot more here.
- No, that's all right. Thanks.
What's the $2.20?
He made a call to Los Angeles
to his parents.
I guess he doesn't bum
free telephone calls either.
I can certainly understand why he didn't
have much to say about himself.
Who the hell would believe him?
I beg your pardon, lady.
He loves me, he loves me not.
Tell me, what do you think? Aren't they
exactly the way I said they were?
I must admit,
they are very special people.
- Shall I tell you something?
- What's that?
For a whole week,
I've been nervous.
No. I don't believe it.
Not about what they'd ultimately feel.
Just about their first reaction.
I thought it was just possible
for the first time in 23 years...
they might let me down
for the first half hour.
You're a phony. You know that?
You're a big phony.
Well...
She's always been
a happy human being.
She laughed out loud
before she was six months old.
She was happy as a baby.
Happy as a little girl.
Happy all through school and college.
But I don't think
I've ever seen her...
quite so happy
as she is right now.
And I have to be happy
for her, Matt.
And I am.
I feel happy for her.
And proud of the fact
that we helped make her.
And whatever happens now,
I feel glad...
that Joey's Joey.
How are you today?
Having a steak fry, huh?
Well, now, there she is.
How are you today?
Wanna give me a lift to Market Street?
Save me a cab.
You know it, doll.
I hope these is better
than the last we had, hotshot.
Lady, don't look at me. I deliver it.
I don't rustle the cattle.
You said to remind you
to open the wine.
Civil rights is one thing.
This here is something else.
I went out on to the terrace.
Oh, I'll never forget it.
It was so beautiful.
It was already dark
and the moon was rising.
I guess I didn't see him at first
because I was looking at the view.
But he was standing there.
Then all of a sudden
he moved or something, and I jumped.
And he just stood there,
looking at me and sort of...
- Ah, you're burning your shirt.
- Oh, yes. Sort of smiling.
"Hello," I said.
"Who are you?"
And I think he thought I was...
you know, attractive.
Anyway, finally, he said...
"Well, do you think
it could possibly matter?"
- And it's just crazy, and I admit it.
- You'd better let me do this.
But 20 minutes later,
I felt I was in love with him.
Mom, how long did it take you
to fall in love with Dad?
Oh, well, nothing like
so long as 20 minutes.
- You mean, is that really true?
- Yes, that's really true.
Oh, Mom.
Joey, I want to ask you something.
How deeply are you and John in...
No, I have no right to ask.
How deeply involved? Do you mean,
have we been to bed together?
I don't mind you asking me that.
We haven't.
He wouldn't.
I don't think he was in doubt
about my feelings, but he wouldn't.
You're burning my shirt.
He's been concerned the whole time
about my getting hurt somehow.
They're still talking.
Wouldn't you think
they'd have said everything by now?
Are you saying they don't have
any special sense of rhythm?
That's right.
But, hell, you can see it.
You can't turn on the television set
without seeing those kids dancing...
and I say the colored kids
are better than the white kids.
But there's an explanation for that.
It's our dancing, and it's our music.
We brought it here.
I mean, you can do the Watusi...
but we are the Watusi,
if you know what I mean.
I remember,
when I was about your age...
my sports editor telling me that Negroes
would never be able to play baseball.
Now, I suppose if he wanted to...
Willie Mays could be elected
mayor of San Francisco.
I own a newspaper,
but I couldn't be elected dogcatcher.
Well, I don't guess
you want to be dogcatcher any more...
than he wants to be
mayor of San Francisco.
No, I suppose that's right.
Doctor, we've talked about
a good many things...
but there's one thing
we haven't talked about.
Have you given any thought to
the problems your children will have?
Yes, and they'll have some.
And we'll have the children.
Otherwise,
you couldn't call it a marriage.
Is that the way Joey feels?
She feels that all of our children will
be president of the United States...
and they'll all have
colorful administrations.
Well, you made her, Mr. Drayton.
I just met her in Hawaii.
But how do you feel
about that problem?
Well, frankly, I think your daughter
is a bit optimistic.
I'd settle
for secretary of state.
Would you think it was some kind
of cowardice if I told you...
that no matter how confident you two are
I'm just a little scared.
No, it wouldn't.
But you never know.
Things are changing.
I have a feeling they're
not changing anywhere else...
as fast as they are
in my own backyard.
Just tell me this.
Don't you think this quick decision...
about how we feel about this thing
is just a little unfair?
In a way, I do.
But it wasn't my idea
that everything be settled so quickly.
Your daughter said
there's no problem.
She says, "My dad is a lifelong fighting
liberal who loathes race prejudice...
and has spent his whole life
fighting against discrimination."
She said, "My parents...
They'll welcome you with open arms."
And I said...
"Oh, I sure want to meet them."
Telephone!
It's Los Angeles!
- Take it in my study.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
- Dr. Prentice?
- Yes, this is he.
- Hello. That you, Little John?
Hi, Dad. What's up, man?
Dr. Graves call again?
Oh, no, it's not that, son.
I just had an idea.
What would you say to us
flying up there to spend the evening?
- This evening?
- We could be up there at 6:30.
I thought maybe we could take you
and your young lady friend for dinner.
- Tell them to come to dinner.
- Just a minute.
- I'm having dinner with her folks.
- Don't be silly.
- Tell them they're invited to dinner.
- Who's that speaking? The young lady?
Yes, that's her.
No, just a minute. You haven't asked
your mother, and there's Tillie.
Won't you come to dinner,
you and Mrs. Prentice?
John and I will meet your plane.
- Stop butting in.
- Who am I talking to? John?
Hi, Dad.
Looks like she wants us
even if you don't. We want to meet her.
- So we'll see you at 6:30. What?
- Oh, no.
- See?
- Your mother says she's pleased.
Oh, hell, he knows that.
All right, son.
- Dad!
- We'll see you later. Bye.
What's the matter?
Mom!
John's father and mother
are coming to dinner.
Oh, good.
- Marvelous.
- We'll meet their plane at 6:30.
Fine.
You'll tell Tillie, won't you?
I told you,
my folks, they don't...
They think
you're a colored girl.
- Why didn't you tell them?
- I was gonna write to them.
What difference does it make?
Do you think they wouldn't come?
Call them back and tell them.
They're gonna know anyway at 6:30
because I'll go with you to meet them.
That's not a good idea.
I'll meet them.
It gives me a chance to explain.
I have to explain.
Why do you keep trying
to dramatize everything?
Look, I've told Pete and Judith that
we'll meet them for a drink at 5:30.
It gives us just enough time
to get to the airport.
She's my best and oldest friend
so you've just got to let them meet you.
Did he tell you
about this medical plan of his?
No. What?
It's the damndest thing
you ever heard of.
They put a whole medical school
on about 20 trucks.
Then they run
into some African country...
pick up the brightest native kids...
hundreds at a time...
and put them through courses just like
they do the U.S. Army Corpsmen.
Only his idea is
that they're all specialists.
You know, each one trained
to do one simple thing...
like sewing up a wound
or delivering a baby or what have you.
They go into places where people
have never heard of an aspirin tablet...
let alone a doctor.
Imagine what that means.
For every thousand kids they train,
they can save a million lives a year.
Now just think of that.
He seems to have made
quite an impression on you.
Yeah.
I asked him how he got so far.
You know, he's only 37.
He said he thought he got the best
breaks because everybody he met...
didn't want him to think
they were prejudiced against him.
Yeah, he made an impression, all right.
I wouldn't know how to fault him.
Are you trying to fault him?
No, I'm not trying to fault him.
You know, his father is a mailman.
Retired now.
Lives in Los Angeles.
Now how do you suppose
a colored mailman...
produced a son
with all the qualities he has?
- You'll find out this evening.
- What?
Guess who's coming to dinner?
Who?
You mean, his parents?
Now wait a minute.
- Whose idea was that?
- Joey invited them.
Yeah, Joey. We're being pressurized.
You know that, don't you?
First there wasn't gonna be a marriage
unless we approved.
Then we had one day
to make up our minds.
Now we have to spend hours entertaining
somebody we never heard of.
What the hell
is coming off here?
Oh, don't look at
those baby pictures.
That was at Klosters,
the year before last.
I'll get it!
Just a second.
Monsignor Ryan!
How wonderful to see you.
- Well, good afternoon.
- Come on in. Good afternoon.
Why are you here
when you should be in Hawaii?
What is the problem that caused your
father to chicken out on our golf game?
- Who is this gentleman?
- Monsignor, this is Dr. John Prentice.
We met in Hawaii 11 days ago.
The two of us are going to be married.
Are you, indeed?
I take it you mean to each other.
- Dr. Prentice.
- Monsignor.
Well, of course,
you're the problem.
I'm afraid I am.
I knew nothing of this.
Why haven't your parents informed me?
They didn't know either.
We only flew back this morning.
Excuse me a second.
I forgot to tell Tillie something.
Well...
- This was all very sudden, was it not?
- Yes, it was.
I suppose you two have had time
to consider what you're doing.
No, we've not.
We'll be two more for dinner.
How many steaks did you get?
I got four
'cause I was told four.
Order two more because the doctor's
father and mother are coming.
- We'll be six.
- His father and mother! Here?
That's right.
If the butcher can't send 'em...
tell him to put 'em
in a taxi.
It's gettin' more like
a holy rollers meetin' every minute.
Of course!
I know about you.
I read an article about you
in "Common Wheel."
I shall want to talk to you
about that.
You know, this fellow you brought home
is a very important man?
- Are you aware of that?
- I'm wholly aware of it.
When I'm married to him,
I'll be important.
I guess you will,
as a matter of fact.
- Where's Arnold Palmer?
- Dad and Mom are in the garden.
Good. Well, just go on
with what you're doing. Fore!
Of all the friends we've ever had,
I guess he's the closest.
We're not Catholics, but he and Dad
and Mom have done things together.
You know,
sat on committees and things.
He's a wonderful man,
and we love him.
You're a remarkable fellow, Mike.
You get younger every minute.
- Did you...
- Yes, I've just seen him.
Handsome fellow, isn't he?
Little Joey is nothing less
than radiant.
It warms me chilly old heart
just to look at her.
Aren't you just
a little shocked?
Shocked?
Why should I be shocked?
I've known a good many cases
of marriages between races in my time.
Strangely enough,
they usually work out quite well.
I don't know why.
Maybe because it requires
some special quality of effort...
more consideration and compassion...
than most marriages
seem to generate these days.
- Could that be it?
- Yes, it could.
I'm glad you said that.
That's a beautiful thought.
You do have beautiful thoughts.
That's my trade, you know.
What about laddie over here?
You making heavy weather of it?
You know, this man is quite
a famous fellow in his own right.
He's done incredible work in Asia
and some awful place in Africa.
Mom! Hilary's here.
She wants to see you.
Excuse me, will you? Express some more
beautiful thoughts to the lad there.
Thank you.
I hope you won't think
that I'm prying, Doctor...
but naturally
one is curious.
- Naturally.
- We are going to be married.
Are you?
Well, I didn't even know.
I mean, Christina
hadn't even mentioned that...
She didn't know.
It was a surprise to her too.
A surprise.
Well, I should think it was.
My dear!
Joey tells me that congratulations
are in order, and you didn't even know.
What's the problem, Hilary?
What brings you all the way up here?
- Mr. Cazalet phoned about the pictures.
- Oh, that. Excuse us, will you?
I'll walk out to your car
with you.
- I hope I'll be seeing you shortly.
- Actually, no.
Dr. Prentice is leaving tonight...
and Joey within
the next couple of weeks.
Well, then you must permit me
to wish you every happiness.
Come along.
My poor dear,
what a shock for you.
I knew something was up
when I came into the gallery.
But this!
Whatever are you going to do about it?
- I mean, the child is of age.
- Yes, the child is 23.
Why didn't you simply ring up
with the Cazalet information?
Well, I must admit,
I was intensely curious.
I couldn't believe it.
It's so unlike Joey to do anything
so appallingly stupid.
- Yes, come along.
- But what you must be going through.
You must try not to worry about it.
Now I have some instructions
for you.
I want you to go straight back
to the gallery. Start your motor.
When you to the gallery,
tell Jennifer...
she will be looking after things
temporarily.
She's to give me a ring if there's
anything she can't deal with herself.
Then go into the office
and make out a check for cash...
for the sum of $5,000.
Then carefully...
remove absolutely everything...
that might subsequently remind me
that you had ever been there...
including that yellow thing
with the blue bulbs...
which you have
such an affection for.
Then take the check for $5,000...
which I feel you deserve...
and get permanently lost.
It's not that I don't want
to know you, although I don't.
It's just that I'm afraid
we're not really the sort of people...
that you can afford
to be associated with.
Don't speak.
Just go.
You see that boy?
The tall one?
If he'd played his cards right,
you'd never even have met me.
But he fell for some girl
from Pomona.
- That'll teach him.
- Mom!
Do you know what Hilary was doing?
She was being an absolute bitch.
She was. I almost wish you'd fire her.
I really do.
Joey, how can you be so hard?
She has a really quite ruthless streak.
You ought to be warned about it.
She gets it
from her father.
They need all the help
you can give them...
because they're going to have
special difficulties.
No, don't budge.
Please, sit.
Of course, they know all that.
They're serious people.
Fine, intelligent people.
And if they know
what lies in store for them...
and they still want each other
enough to accept it...
I think it's plain as anything
that they love each other very much.
You'll have to agree that any two people
who love each other that much...
deserve all the best luck
in the world.
I don't know.
I wish I didn't have the feeling
that they'll never make it...
that the whole thing's
impossible.
You feel that way, do you?
You're really thrashing about then.
That's very interesting, indeed.
And rather amusing, too,
to see a broken-down...
old phony liberal come face-to-face
with his principles.
Of course,
I always have believed...
that in that
fighting liberal facade...
there must be some sort
of reactionary bigot trying to get out.
Oh, go to hell. You and your crowd
are still preaching hell.
Well, I'm off.
As much as I'm enjoying
your discomfiture...
I may be able to save a few souls
before supper.
But, I am, as it happens,
free for dinner.
Please, come, 7:30.
The doctor's family are flying up
from Los Angeles.
Oh, well, in that case,
you'll actually need me.
Otherwise, your side
won't even outnumber the blacks.
Thank you, my dear.
Half past seven.
What was that the Beatles sang?
We can work it out
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Mom did it.
Do you think it looks like him?
Well, it looks a little grim,
doesn't it?
- No, don't let me disturb you.
- Not at all.
I hope you don't mind, but I've wrangled
an invitation to dinner.
- Marvelous! I'm delighted you're coming.
- Thank you, my dear.
- I'm very delighted to have met you.
- My pleasure, Monsignor.
- See you this evening.
- Certainly.
You know,
you two make me feel...
quite extraordinarily happy.
I'd better tell Tillie. If you listen,
you'll hear her going through the roof.
I brought you
the latest bulletin.
Guess who's coming
to dinner now?
The Reverend Martin Luther King?
You're so close.
It's Monsignor Ryan.
Bake a second pie, will you?
You know how he loves your cooking.
Listen, is the big guest room
in order?
Dr. Prentice wants to have
a shower and change.
- He does?
- He does.
Well, she's 23 years old.
I guess she has
a right to do as she pleases.
Yes, but that's not the point.
The doctor said...
I know what the doctor said. Could we
get out of here for a few minutes?
- Sure.
- What are the others doing?
They're meeting Peter and Judith
for a drink...
and then they're going on
to the airport.
All right, come on.
Come on, will you?
Whatever happened to what's-his-name?
Homer?
That lawyer?
I thought she liked him very much.
Nothing happened to Homer.
Dr. Prentice just happened to Joey.
It was only last Christmas
she said Homer had the inside track.
Isn't that the place where we got
the good ice cream? Let's get some.
It's after 5:00.
You'll spoil...
A little ice cream can't hurt.
- Yes?
- When I had ice cream before...
I had a special kind of flavor
that I liked very much.
- But I can't remember what it was.
- I'll bring you the list.
No, you must know what it is.
Daiquiri Ice? Honeycomb Candy?
Cocoa Coconut? Jamoca Almond Fudge?
Mocha Jamoca? Peanut Butter and Jelly?
Cinnamon Banana Mint?
- Must have been some other place.
- Fresh Oregon Boysenberry Sherbet?
That's it.
I'm sure that's it. Bring me
a Fresh Oregon Boysenberry.
- Bring me a big one.
- Right.
- Will you have some? It's delicious.
- No. Black coffee.
One double Fresh Oregon Boysenberry
Sherbet and one black coffee. Thanks.
You know, Matt...
I think Mike was right
that Joey is lucky.
The work he's doing
is so important...
she'll be able to help him with it
and share it all with him.
The best break
any wife can have.
You know, for us,
it's all been great...
but do you know
what was the best time of all?
It was in the beginning
when everything was a struggle...
and you were working too hard
and sometimes frightened...
and there were times
when I felt...
that I really knew
that I was a help to you.
That was the very best time of all
for me.
- One black coffee.
- Thank you.
And one Fresh
Oregon Boysenberry Sherbet.
Thank you.
This is not the stuff.
I never had this stuff
before in my life.
You know, it's not bad.
Not bad at all.
I kinda like it.
Fresh Oregon Boysenberry.
Yes, sir.
Well, when I had
the ice cream before...
this isn't the stuff I had,
but I like it.
- It's very good. I like it very much.
- Okay.
- How do you do, Miss Binks?
- I got somethin' to say to you, boy.
Exactly what you tryin' to pull here?
I'm not trying to pull anything.
I was looking to find me a wife.
Ain't that just likely!
You wanna answer me somethin'?
What kinda doctor
you supposed to be anyhow?
Would you believe horse?
You make with witticisms
and all, huh?
Let me tell you somethin'.
You may think you're foolin'
Miss Joey and her folks.
But you ain't foolin' me for a minute.
I see what you are.
You're one of those smooth-talkin',
smart-ass niggers...
just out for all you can get,
with your black power...
and all that other
trouble-makin' nonsense.
And you listen here. I brought up that
child from a baby in her cradle...
and ain't nobody gonna harm her none
while I'm here watchin'.
And as long as you are anywhere around
this house, I'm right here watchin'.
You read me, boy?
You bring any trouble in here...
and you just like to find out
what black power really means!
And furthermore to that,
you ain't all that good-lookin'!
That was very good.
If I come in again, remind me about
the Oregon Boysenberry, will you?
Yeah, I sure will.
Thank you, sir.
Should we take home
a couple of quarts for dessert?
No, Tillie's baked some pies.
You stupid idiot!
Why can't you
look where you're going?
Sorry, son,
but your car is so low...
Of course you didn't see me!
You weren't even looking
where you were going!
Look what you did to my car!
It's my fault.
My insurance...
Yeah, yeah. Who cares
about your lousy insurance?
I worked over three months on that!
How much will it cost
to have it repaired?
Look at it! Thirty or forty bucks
it'll cost. Did you see it?
Stupid old man.
He oughtn't be allowed out.
He ought to be put away someplace
in a home or something.
There's fifty bucks! Don't bother
to have it fixed. Buy a new one!
Some of these old guys,
they're senile!
Stupid old man.
There oughta be a law!
What the hell is it today?
Less than 12'/. Of the people
in this city are colored people.
I can't even have a dish
of Oregon "Boosenberry"...
without runnin' into one of them.
You've
Got to
Give a little
Take a little
And let your poor heart
Break a little
That's the story of
That's the glory of love
You've gotta laugh a little
Cry a little
Before the clouds
Roll by a little
That's the story of
I can't tell you
how happy I am for you.
And the whole thing having
happened so quickly.
You remember what it was
with Peter and me.
It took us three years
to decide to get married...
and we'd been living together
for two.
To John and Joey.
John and Joanna. He won't call me
anything but Joanna.
- I'm beginning to like it too.
- To John and Joanna.
Where you're so lucky
is in Joey's folks... Uh, Joanna's folks.
You've only just met them,
but take my word for it.
Matt Drayton really stands
for something in this town.
Yes. I know the Guardian's
always been a very good paper.
It's a great paper,
and he made it what it is.
There's never been a public issue on
which Matt Drayton didn't take a stand.
When exactly are you flying over?
Sometime next week?
Just as soon
as I can arrange everything.
Why next week? Why aren't you
flying over with John?
Why am I not flying over with you?
- Is your passport in order?
- Yes.
- Do you need clothes or anything?
- Nothing I couldn't get over there.
Then it seems crazy for you to be
going alone when you could go together.
- Why don't you both leave tonight?
- Why not?
It's 6:00. In an hour
they'll all be here for dinner.
The doctor's plane leaves
at 10:45.
No matter what it is, you're going
to have to tell them how you feel.
I need more than one day
to make a decision like that.
It's the silliest thing
I ever heard of.
But I'll tell you this.
I am not going to try to pretend
that I'm happy about the whole thing...
because I'm not.
And if the doctor's decision
depends upon that, then too bad.
And I'm thinking only
of Joey's welfare.
I have nothing against him personally,
but he's a grown man.
He behaved irresponsibly in the first
place by letting this thing happen.
Now he wants me to be happy
about a situation...
when I happen to know that they'll both
get their brains knocked out.
I'm sorry,
but that's the way I feel.
And I know how you're reacting.
You're so wrapped up in Joey's
excitement over the whole thing...
that you are not behaving
in her best interest!
Yes, Mom.
But there wasn't any reason
not to go tonight.
You can understand,
can't you, Mom?
My passport's in order. There's
nothing at all that I really need.
And it won't
take me an hour to pack.
I'll be able to be with him.
We'll be together the whole time.
Mom, they're here.
I can see them.
They look like awfully nice people.
His mother looks lovely.
You break it to Dad for me,
will you?
Well...
I guess I should have called you back
because there is this one thing...
I should have...
I've been meaning
to write to you about it.
There was one thing
I didn't explain, Dad.
And...
I'm afraid it's gonna be
kind of a shock.
You see what I mean?
Mom, Dad,
this is Joanna Drayton.
Joanna, my mom and dad.
Mrs. Prentice, I'm so happy.
- Miss Drayton?
- Yes.
Mr. Prentice,
I'm very pleased to meet you.
I can explain.
I can imagine what's going on
in your mind...
but we can explain.
You can?
Of course we can.
You have bags?
Of course you have bags.
Let's go get your bags.
Mama?
- What did your folks say?
- All's well.
- Did you talk to your father?
- To Mom. But she'll tell him.
Tonight?
- I thought I ought to tell you.
- That's out of the question.
This whole damn thing is...
No, that's out of the question.
I'll tell you something else.
I couldn't do what you're about to do...
so I don't begin to understand
how you propose to go about it.
But you can't break their hearts
over a drink...
and expect them
to sit down to dinner.
Don't you think I know that?
I have to talk to the doctor...
I'll talk to him after dinner.
Tell him exactly how I feel.
I'm not trying
to give you an argument.
There's nothing I can say
that you don't know.
It's important that you understand
just how wrong I think you...
I believe you're making the worst
mistake you've ever made in your...
You're gonna regret it with more
bitterness that you've ever known...
for as long as you live.
You're wrong.
You're as wrong as you can be.
Because I'm thinking of her
and even the doctor is going to know...
I'm thinking of her.
There's something else.
I'm surprised
it hasn't occurred to you.
The doctor will accept
whatever you say to him...
because he's a terribly sensitive man
and because he said he would.
But Joey won't. The most obvious
mistake you're making...
is in underestimating
your own daughter.
She'll fight you and
your whole attitude...
and everything you do and every
argument you ever try to give her.
And one thing more.
Until today, I would never have believed
that I could say such a thing...
but when she fights you...
and for what it may be worth...
I'm going to be on her side.
I never believed I'd hear you
say a thing like that.
- Can I get you another drink?
- No, thanks. I'll get it myself.
I wish we had more time.
What, Mom?
I was going to ask Miss Drayton
how her father and mother reacted to...
Yeah. I wanted to ask that too.
Please call me Joanna.
They were shaken, all right.
I don't think
I've ever seen them so surprised.
The thing that really shook them...
was that I wanted to marry anybody
they hadn't even heard about.
I can't blame them
for being sort of stunned by it all.
Well. Then you couldn't blame us if we
were a little stunned, too, could you?
I mean, I wouldn't appear unreasonable
if I suggested...
that the two of you were behaving like
a couple of escaped lunatics, would I?
This whole thing...
happened so quickly...
it's like trying to ride a rocket.
We didn't plan it that way.
It just happened that way.
It's a little hard on Joanna's folks and
I'm sure it's gonna be hard on you.
We've got one evening
to discuss it...
and if you have any objections,
you'd better raise them in a hurry...
because in exactly four hours
we're gonna be on that plane and gone.
I don't think I could list
all my objections in four hours.
I think I'd need
more like eight hours.
Well, you've only got four hours.
So you'll just have to talk
twice as fast.
Hello, darling.
How are you?
Forgive me.
I am a little bit early.
Ego absolvo te.
Come in.
I don't like to be
always repeating myself...
but how long is it since
that I remarked that I thought...
that you were the loveliest woman
I have ever known?
You know, there is a kind of envy
that is no way sinful.
That's what I've always
had for Matt all these years.
- What can I give you to drink?
- Well, I like Scotch if...
- Are we drinking wine?
- Yes.
Oh. I'll have
a little drop of Scotch anyhow.
Equal amount of soda, please.
Thank you.
My dear, what's the matter?
Sorry.
We're in trouble.
Mike...
we're in terrible trouble,
terrible trouble.
John told us...
Matt and me...
that he wouldn't marry Joey
unless we could say...
that we approved the marriage
with no reservations whatever.
Joey doesn't know
that he said that.
Now she's suddenly decided to go
with him tonight. She has her tickets.
The two of them are on their way in
from the airport with John's parents...
and neither of them knows
that Matt has decided...
Well.
Matt has decided
that he can't approve.
That's not true.
Please tell me it's not true.
- Where is Matt?
- He's upstairs changing. He's...
He's not himself.
Excuse me.
It's incredible!
- Table all right?
- It's fine.
- Thank you.
- Miss Christina, what's gonna happen?
I don't know, Tillie.
You and Mr. Matt, you gonna put a stop
to this damn nonsense foolishness?
I don't want to put a stop
to anything.
He's a fine man.
He's a wonderful man,
and Joey is very much in love with him.
And it isn't just
damn nonsense foolishness.
Well, I tell you, Miss Christina.
The way you are talkin',
I don't understand nothin' no more.
Nobody understands nothin' no more.
No, I don't think you're butting
into something that doesn't concern...
Damn blast these lousy laundries.
I understand how you feel.
I understand how everybody feels.
But you have to
understand something too.
They've boxed me
into a hell of a corner here.
And no matter what Christina says
or what you say...
I am not going to behave
irresponsibly.
I'm not gonna tell them they can't get
married. I don't have the right.
But they don't have the right
to come in here...
and expect me to be happy
about something any normal man...
Oh, for God's sake!
You're on the point of destroying
all the happiness there is...
in one of the happiest families
I've ever known.
Have you any appreciation
at all for Christina...
Have you any appreciation at all
of how that woman has behaved today?
From the moment they walked in, she was
for it, as if there were no problems.
But there are no problems that Joey
and young Prentice don't know about.
Christina has more respect for Joey's
judgment than you have. I must say...
Oh, come off it!
If Joey came home with some fuzzy-wuzzy
and said "This is the man for me"...
Christina would say,
"Oh, really? How wonderful.
Where will we get enough roses
to fill the Rose Bowl?"
I'm trying to remember
where I've seen you so angry.
Oh, yes. When you took
nine shots on the seventh green.
Would you mind
getting the hell out of here?
I think I know why you're angry too.
Not with the doctor,
whom you obviously respect.
Not with Joey or Christina,
not even with me.
You're angry with yourself.
You're a pontificating
old poop!
You're angry because all of a sudden,
and in a single day, you've been thrown.
You're the last man in the world I would
have expected to behave the way you are.
You're not yourself.
You're off balance.
You don't know who your are,
what you are or what you're doing.
That's your trouble.
You've gone back on yourself, laddie,
and in your heart you know it.
Now, listen, there's a limit
to what I'll take, even from you.
For 30 years, there's been no man
I've admired or respected more.
You know that.
And for the first time in all
those 30 years, I feel sorry for you.
Damn it, that's enough!
Are you really capable
of putting yourself in my position?
Unless you've got
some kids of your own...
hidden away somewhere
that haven't shown up in the record...
how can you possibly know how a father
would feel in a situation like this?
You don't know!
I happen to believe they wouldn't
have a dog's chance...
not in this country,
not in the whole, stinking world.
They are this country.
They'll change this stinking world.
Yeah, sure. Fifty years, maybe,
or a hundred years.
But not in your lifetime.
Maybe not even in mine.
My dear friend...
I wish with all my heart
you could be restrained.
And if I were ten years younger...
to prevent you
from going downstairs...
I believe I'd make some sort of effort
to wrestle you to the floor.
That'll be the day.
Is that the car?
Did you hear a car?
Mrs. Prentice,
I'm Christina Drayton.
- How do you do?
- How do you do, Mr. Prentice?
I'm so pleased to meet you.
Come on in.
Let me take your coat and hat.
And yours?
Thank you.
How good of you to come
all this long way to see us. Do go in.
What did Dad say? Did you tell him?
I'll bet he was shaken.
- It was a surprise.
- Does he want to talk to me?
Yes, I'm sure he does. Later.
Please come in.
May I get you a drink?
What would you like?
May I have some sherry, please?
What a lovely room.
Thank you. John, would you be bartender?
I'll have some sherry too.
- Of course.
- Shall we sit over here?
What will you have, Dad?
Bourbon?
- Thank you.
- You have such a magnificent view.
Thank you. Please sit down.
Sit down, Mr. Prentice.
Did you have a pleasant flight?
Very pleasant, thank you.
The view of the sunset
was breathtaking.
Only took forty minutes.
Four hundred miles.
It's incredible, isn't it?
My husband will be down directly,
I think.
He's upstairs changing.
And we have a friend of ours
who's coming to dinner with us.
Monsignor Ryan.
I'm sure theyll be down
in a minute.
- Thank you.
- Mom.
- There you are, Dad.
Thanks, son.
Are you Catholics?
Well, no, we're not.
I'm afraid we're
nothing in particular.
Monsignor Ryan just happens to be
a very old friend.
Do you come often
to San Francisco?
I've got to talk to your father.
There he is.
Dad, I'd like you to meet
Mr. And Mrs. Prentice.
- This is my father.
- Mrs. Prentice, nice to meet you.
- How do you do?
- Mr. Prentice, happy to meet you.
- May I present Monsignor Ryan?
- How do you do, ma'am?
- How do you do?
Glad to meet you, sir.
- Are you and John tending bar?
- Yes.
The monsignor and I
are both drinking Scotch.
Coming up.
Sit down.
Well.
Did you have a nice flight
from Los Angeles?
Oh, yes. Very nice flight.
Only 40 minutes.
Only 40 minutes from Los Angeles.
- Terrifying.
- If you're going to talk about flying...
you could talk
about flying to Geneva...
because John and I
are hoping to persuade...
all of you to fly over
for the wedding.
Would anybody like to talk about that
before I go up and start packing?
I take it they've told you
all about their plans?
Of course. It's only when you're
eloping that you keep it a secret.
I don't know about you,
Mr. Prentice...
but it seems to me that these two
are rushing it just a little bit.
It seemed that way to me too.
It seems like that to you too?
That's right.
I'm certainly relieved
to hear that.
I was beginning to think I was the only
one around here who had any...
I would like Mrs. Prentice
to see the view.
What the hell are you talking about?
What view?
From the terrace.
Before it gets too cold.
- Would you care to see the view?
- Oh, yes, thank you. I would.
Good. Excuse us.
Bring your drink with you.
Have you had any chance
to speak privately with John?
Well, no.
Because it's important that
you understand what's happened here...
and what I'm terribly afraid
is going to happen.
May I explain the situation to you
or try to?
Yes, please.
I wish you would.
First, I have to ask you...
Forgive my being so abrupt
and so direct.
Are you shocked
by the fact that John...
that your son is involved
with a white girl?
Surprised.
It never happened before.
I guess it never occurred to me
that such a thing might happen.
But it wouldn't be true
to say that I'm shocked.
Are you?
Well.
I think I was at first
this afternoon.
Because it came
as a complete surprise to us too.
But now I know
how they feel about each other.
Joey's still very young...
but she's not a child.
And they're...
deeply in love
with each other.
Are you about to tell me...
that you'd be willing to approve
the marriage but your husband won't?
Is that it?
Yes, that's it.
My husband won't either.
I wish there were more time...
if only so that we could adjust
to the situation.
But the way things are,
there just isn't any time.
If we're going to accept
the thing at all, it seems to me...
we'll have to trust
the two of them...
and accept that they know
what they're doing.
And, Mrs. Drayton...
my husband just won't do that.
They seem to be having
quite a conversation out there.
It might do no harm
if we could have a few words.
Yeah, sure.
We can go in my study.
Will you excuse us, please?
I'll have another drink
if you will, Doctor?
If you'll excuse me, I'll go up
and throw a few things together.
Like for the next ten years.
Mr. Drayton...
I don't know you at all, and
I certainly wouldn't want to offend you.
But are you some kind of a nut?
Are you going to tell me that you
approve of what's been going on here?
- I wasn't going to tell you that at all.
- Because if you do...
You may be a big, successful
newspaper publisher...
and I'm nothing but
a pensioned-off mailman...
but you are right out of your mind.
I have a pretty good idea
of what my father is saying to him.
But I wish I knew...
You were talking with him upstairs.
Have you any idea what
Mr. Drayton is saying to my father?
I can tell you one thing.
I was very sorry to hear...
that you intend
to withdraw from the situation...
if you encounter any opposition.
She's up there packing.
Your mother
would like to speak to you.
This is a mess.
Where's Joey?
- She's upstairs, my dear.
- I'm going up.
Everything is ready
whenever you all are ready.
We're not ready, Tillie.
Well!
What you're saying is that you feel
practically the same as I do about this.
That's right.
But even so...
this is a hell of an unhappy situation
for both your son and my daughter.
I think it would be best
if you talked to John yourself.
I said that...
if they didn't approve,
there'd be no marriage.
I set the terms, Mama.
They don't disapprove.
Only Mr. Drayton.
Are you sure?
She said she'd even drive
the two of you to the airport.
I've lived with your father
for almost 40 years.
God willing,
there'll be a lot more.
And even though...
I've only known about this situation
for one hour...
I feel the same way
Mrs. Drayton does.
She says Joanna
will never give you up.
I guess...
it depends upon
how much you want her.
Want her?
I want her, Mama.
You know what it's been like for me
these past eight years?
I felt like I never wanted
anybody again.
But, Mama...
these last few days with her...
it's like I'm alive again
and it's marvelous.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Your father wants to talk to you.
- Does he?
- He's in my study.
I've been talking to your husband.
He seems pretty much upset
by all this.
I know.
Your wife says you are too.
Not upset, exactly.
It's a very difficult problem.
For whom?
For you and my husband?
I think you'll solve your problem,
all right.
All you have to do is tell them
you're against them.
That's all.
And you'll have no problem.
You're not going to tell me
you're happy about this relationship?
This is not a night
for talking about happiness.
This is an unhappy night.
You've been talking to Christina.
I know how she feels.
Can you imagine for one minute that
I want to see either one of them hurt?
No more than my husband does.
But hurt they're going to be.
Worse than my husband knows.
I think worse than you know too.
I tell you he's as much
against this thing as I am.
Maybe more!
Son, you've got to listen to me.
I'm not trying to tell you
how to live your life...
but you've never
made a mistake like this before.
You've been nothin'
but a source of pride...
for me and your mother
your whole life.
But you don't know what you're doin'.
This affair here...
It all happened too fast.
You said so yourself.
But you've got to stop and think.
Have you thought what people
would say about you?
In 16 or 17 states you'd
be breakin' the law. You'd be criminals.
And say they changed the law.
That don't change
the way people feel about this thing.
For a man who all his life never
put a wrong foot anywhere...
you're way out of line!
That's for me to decide, man.
- So just shut up and let me...
- You don't say that to me!
You haven't got the right to ever say
a thing like that to me.
Not after what I've been to you!
And you know that,
and I know that.
Yeah, I know what you are
and what you've made of yourself.
But I worked my ass off to get the money
to buy you all the chances you had!
You know how far
I carried that bag in 30 years?
75,000 miles.
And mowin' lawns in the dark so you
wouldn't have to be stokin' furnaces...
and could bear down on the books.
There were things your mother should
have had that she insisted go for you.
And I don't mean fancy things.
I mean a decent coat.
A lousy coat!
And you're gonna tell me
that means nothin' to you...
and you could
break your mother's heart?
What happens to men
when they grow old?
Why do they forget everything?
I believe...
those two young people
need each other...
like they need
the air to breathe in.
Anybody can see that
by just looking at them.
But you and my husband are...
You might as well be blind men.
You can only see
that they have a problem.
But do you really know
what's happened to them?
How they feel about each other?
I believe...
that men grow old.
And when the...
When sexual things no longer matter
to them, they forget it all.
Forget what true passion is.
If you ever felt what my son...
feels for your daughter,
you've forgotten everything about it.
My husband too.
You knew once...
but that was a long time ago.
Now the two of you don't know.
And the strange thing...
for your wife and me...
is that you don't even remember.
If you did...
how could you do
what you are doing?
I don't care what your mother says.
Maybe she's gone haywire too.
This is between you and me.
That's the first thing you've said
that makes any sense...
because that's exactly where it's at.
- And what I mean to say is...
- You've said what you had to say.
You listen to me.
You say you don't want to tell me
how to live my life?
What do you think
you've been doing?
You tell me what rights I've got
or haven't got...
and what I owe to you
for what you've done for me.
Let me tell you something.
I owe you nothing.
If you carried that bag
a million miles...
you did what you
were supposed to do...
because you brought me
into this world...
and from that day you owed me...
everything you could ever do for me,
like I will owe my son...
if I ever have another.
But you don't own me.
You can't tell me when or where
I'm out of line...
or try to get me to live my life
according to your rules.
You don't even know
what I am, Dad.
You don't know who I am,
how I feel, what I think.
And if I tried to explain it the rest of
your life, you would never understand.
You are 30 years older than I am.
You and your whole lousy generation...
believes the way it was for you
is the way it's got to be!
And not until your whole generation
has lain down and died...
will the deadweight of you
be off our backs!
You understand?
You've got to get off my back.
Dad.
You're my father.
I'm your son.
I love you.
I always have
and I always will.
But you think of yourself
as a colored man.
I think of myself...
as a man.
Now, I've got a decision to make.
And I've got to make it alone.
And I gotta make it in a hurry.
So...
would you go out there...
and see after my mother?
You've just got to talk John's parents
into flying over with you.
It would mean so much to John
to have them there...
and I know they can afford it.
You know, I think John's father
is gonna make it a bit rough for him.
Did you see his expression when he
walked off to have a talk with Dad?
But isn't she lovely?
- Don't you like her already?
- Yes, darling, I do.
She's a good one.
When John's father first saw
that I was a white girl...
I thought he was going to faint.
What about your father?
Yes, that was funny, wasn't it?
Oh, Mom, isn't this thrilling?
Aren't you just...
Yes, darling, I am. Just.
I should be able to say something
to you, Mrs. Prentice.
In my trade, there are
a hundred clich phrases of comfort...
for every human condition.
But in the midst
of this heartbreaking distress...
I must admit...
I'm completely stumped.
There's simply
nothing I could say.
Mary, you've just got to understand...
Please, John.
The monsignor is right.
Please say no more.
I'll be a son of a bitch.
Close the door, Mr. Drayton.
You didn't have the guts
to tell me face-to-face, did you?
Before you start telling me
how much guts I've got...
I told you
I'd have something to say.
Now I'm ready to say it.
Are you gonna stay in here?
You know that I'm
completely sympathetic, don't you?
You know that I have
no reservations about anything.
And that whatever makes you happy
is my happiness too.
Of course I know that.
Then listen to me, darling.
There's something
I have to tell you...
about this situation...
which you don't really...
What are you doing up there?
Come on down here, both of you!
How about your glasses?
- Can I get you a drink?
- No, thank you.
No, you've had
enough as it is already.
What's going on?
There's something I want to say
and I'd like you to sit down...
see if you can keep quiet
for once in your life.
Please, sit down, John.
Sit down, Chris, please.
I have a few things to say and
you might just think they're important.
This has been a strange day. I don't
think that's putting it too strongly.
I might even say
it's been an extraordinary day.
I've been out there
thinking about the day...
and the way it has gone...
and it seems to me that now...
I need to make a few
personal statements.
For a variety of reasons.
The day began for me when I walked into
this house and Tillie said to me...
Excuse me.
Tillie!
This'll only take a second.
- Everything's been ready for...
- I know.
All right. Sit down.
This is Miss Matilda Binks...
who's been a member of this family
for 22 years...
and who today has been
making a great deal of trouble.
Sit down, Tillie.
Now. The minute I walked
into this house this afternoon...
Miss Binks said to me,
"Well, all hell's done broke loose now."
I asked her, naturally enough,
to what she referred...
and she said, "You'll see."
And I did.
Then after some preliminary guessing
games, at which I was never very good...
it was explained to me
by my daughter...
that she intended to get married.
And that her intended was a young man
whom I had never met...
who happened to be a Negro.
I think it's fair to say
that I responded to this news...
in the same manner that any
normal father would respond to it...
unless, of course, his daughter
happened to be a Negro too.
In a word, I was flabbergasted. And
while I was still being flabbergasted...
I was informed by my daughter...
a very determined young woman...
much like her mother...
that the marriage was on...
no matter what her mother and I
might feel about it.
Then the next startling development
occurred when you walked in...
and said that unless we...
her mother and I...
approved of the marriage,
there would be no marriage.
You didn't!
What a funny thing to do.
This may be the last chance
I'll ever have...
to tell you to do anything.
So I'm telling you
shut up.
Now.
It became clear that we had one
single day to make up our minds...
as to how we felt
about this whole situation.
So what happened?
My wife, typically enough...
decided to simply ignore...
every practical aspect
of the situation...
and was carried away
in some kind of romantic haze...
which made her, in my view...
totally inaccessible
to anything in the way of reason.
Now I have not as yet referred
to His Reverence...
who began by forcing his way
into the situation...
and then insulting my intelligence...,.
By mouthing 300 platitudes...
and ending just a half hour ago
by coming to my room...
and challenging me
to a wrestling match.
- What time is your plane?
- 10:45.
Right.
Now, Mr. Prentice...
clearly a most reasonable man...
says he has no wish to offend me...
but wants to know
if I'm some kind of a nut.
And Mrs. Prentice says...
that like her husband,
I'm a burnt-out old shell of a man...
who cannot even
remember what it's like...
to love a woman...
the way her son loves my daughter.
And strange as it seems...
that's the first statement
made to me all day...
with which I am prepared
to take issue.
Because I think you're wrong.
You're as wrong as you can be.
I admit that I hadn't considered it,
hadn't even thought about it...
but I know exactly
how he feels about her.
And there is nothing,
absolutely nothing...
that your son feels
for my daughter...
that I didn't feel for Christina.
Old? Yes.
Burnt out? Certainly.
But I can tell you
the memories are still there...
clear, intact, indestructible.
And they'll be there
if I live to be 110.
Where John
made his mistake, I think...
was attaching so much importance
to what her mother and I might think.
Because in the final analysis,
it doesn't matter a damn what we think.
The only thing that matters
is what they feel...
and how much they feel...
for each other.
And if it's half...
of what we felt...
that's everything.
As for you two and
the problems you're going to have...
they seem almost unimaginable.
But you'll have no problem with me.
And I think...
that when Christina and I
and your mother...
have some time to work on him...
you'll have no problem
with your father.
But you do know...
I'm sure you know...
what you're up against.
There'll be a hundred million people
right here in this country...
who'll be shocked and offended...
and appalled at the two of you.
And the two of you will just
have to ride that out.
Maybe every day
for the rest of your lives.
You can try to ignore those people...
or you can feel sorry for them
and for their prejudices...
and their bigotry and
their blind hatreds and stupid fears.
But where necessary...
you'll just have
to cling tight to each other...
and say screw all those people!
Anybody could make a hell of a
good case against your getting married.
The arguments are so obvious
that nobody has to make them.
But you're two wonderful people...
who happened to fall in love...
and happen to have
a pigmentation problem.
And I think that now...
no matter what kind of a case
some bastard could make...
against your getting married...
there would be only one thing worse.
And that would be if...
knowing what you two are...
knowing what you two have...
and knowing what you two feel...
you didn't get married.
Well, Tillie, when the hell
are we gonna get some dinner?