- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Mr. Ramirez and his friends
will be out of business.
He won't be using heroin-flavored
bananas to finance revolutions.
Don't go back to your hotel.
They'll be watching you.
A plane leaves for Miami in an hour.
I'll be on it...
...but first I have some
unfinished business to attend to.
Forgive me.
Why do you always wear that thing?
I have a slight inferiority complex.
Where was I? Oh, yes.
Shocking.
Positively shocking.
- How's this?
- That's nice. Very nice.
- Just here?
- A little lower, darling.
I thought I'd find you
in good hands.
Felix! How are you?
- Dink, meet Felix Leiter.
- Hello.
- Felix, say hello to Dink.
- Hi, Dink.
Dink, say goodbye to Felix.
Man-talk.
You must be slipping, 007, letting
the opposition get that close to you.
They got closer to you in Jamaica,
didn't they? What's on your mind?
- I'm on holiday.
- Not anymore. Signal from London.
I knew M wouldn't book me into the best
hotel in Miami Beach out of gratitude.
He asked us to keep an eye
on him for you.
Auric Goldfinger.
Sounds like a French nail varnish.
He's British
but he doesn't sound like it.
Big operator. Worldwide interests,
all apparently reputable.
Owns one of the finest stud farms
in the States.
- What's the tie-up with Washington?
- He's clean as far as CIA's concerned.
Where do I find him?
That's his pigeon waiting for him.
Goldfinger's been taking him
to the cleaners every day for a week.
Morning, Mr. Simmons.
Ready for our game?
Sure I am. When you're 10 grand in
the hole, you're ready for anything.
- Could I have my usual seat?
- You and your suntan!
Goldfinger's a fabulous card player.
- Same stakes?
- Let's double it.
Five dollars a point.
- Did you say five?
- My luck's got to change.
Okay.
I'll get back to the office
and cable M you're on the job.
- Fill me in on the rest at dinner.
- I'll call you later.
- Four.
- So soon?
How many?
Seven, 12, 18, 32...
...44.
Miss?
What are you...?
That's Mr. Goldfinger's suite!
Yes, I know.
You're very sweet.
He just drew the king of clubs.
That makes his count 59.
He's got a diamond run.
Eight, nine, 10.
He's holding on to the six of spades.
I guess he thinks you want it.
That last draw
was the eight of hearts.
He needs kings and queens.
- Who are you?
- Bond. James Bond.
Come on, come on.
That's more like it.
- What's your name?
- Jill.
- Jill who?
- Jill Masterson.
- Tell me, Jill, why does he do it?
- He likes to win.
- Why do you do it?
- He pays me.
- Is that all he pays you for?
- And for being seen with him.
- Just seen?
- Just seen.
I'm so glad.
You're much too nice to be mixed up
in anything like this.
Now hear this, Goldfinger.
Your luck has just changed.
I doubt if the Miami Beach police
would take kindly...
...to what you're doing.
Nod your head if you agree.
Nod.
Good. Now start losing, Goldfinger.
Shall we say $ 10,000?
Let's be generous.
Let's make it $ 15,000.
May I see?
I can see this is really my day. Gin.
Over and out.
That should keep him occupied
for some time.
I'm beginning to like you,
Mr. Bond.
Oh, call me James.
More than anyone I've met
in a long time, James.
What on earth are we going to
do about it?
- Yes, what?
- I'll tell you at dinner.
Where?
I know the best place in town.
Station WEBS brings you the latest
in world news.
Washington.
At the White House this afternoon...
... the president said
he was entirely satisfied...
That makes two of us.
- Hello.
- Leiter here.
Felix.
What's that? Dinner?
No, I'm sorry, I can't.
Something big's come up.
Right.
- How about breakfast?
- Okay.
Not too early.
- I'll call you around 9.
- Yes, 9:00 would be fine.
- So long, James.
- Good night, Felix.
It's lost its chill.
Oh, why, you!
- There's another in the fridge.
- Who needs it?
My dear girl, there are some things
that just aren't done.
Such as drinking Dom Perignon '53...
...above the temperature
of 38 degrees Fahrenheit.
That's as bad as listening
to the Beatles without earmuffs.
Now, where is this passion juice?
Jill?
- Yes, Mr. Bond.
- Beach 7-9432.
Room 119.
- Hello?
- Felix? Get over here right away.
- What's up?
- The girl's dead.
- Dink?
- No, Jill Masterson.
And she's covered in paint.
Gold paint.
Gold?
All over?
She died of skin suffocation. It's been
known to happen to cabaret dancers.
It's all right as long as you leave
a bare patch at the base of the spine...
...to allow the skin to breathe.
- Someone obviously didn't.
- And I know who.
This isn't a personal vendetta, 007.
It's an assignment, like any other.
But if you can't treat it as such,
coldly and objectively...
...then 008 can replace you.
You've hardly distinguished yourself.
You were supposed to
observe Goldfinger...
...not borrow his girlfriend.
Instead, Goldfinger goes to Europe.
It's only by the grace of God...
...Mr. Leiter, and my intervention
with the British embassy...
...that you're not in the custody
of the Miami Beach police.
I'm aware of my shortcomings.
But I'm prepared to continue
this assignment...
...in the spirit you suggest...
...if I knew what it was about...
...sir.
What do you know about gold?
Not paint. Bullion.
I know it when I see it.
Meet me here at 7. Black tie.
What do you know about gold,
Moneypenny?
The only gold I know about
is the kind you wear.
You know, on the third finger
of your left hand.
One of these days
we must look into that.
What about tonight?
You come for dinner...
...and I'll cook you
a beautiful angel cake.
Nothing would give me
greater pleasure...
...but I do have
a business appointment.
That's the flimsiest excuse
you've ever given me.
Well, some girls have all the luck.
- Who is she, James?
- "She" is me, Miss Moneypenny.
And kindly omit the customary byplay
with 007. He's dining with me.
I don't want him to be late.
So there's hope for me yet.
Moneypenny,
won't you ever believe me?
We at the Bank of England are the
official depository for gold bullion...
...just as Fort Knox, Kentucky
is for the United States.
We know the amounts
we each hold...
...and the amounts deposited
in other banks.
And we can estimate what is
being held for industrial purposes.
This enables the two governments
to establish...
...the true value of the dollar
and the pound.
Consequently, we are vitally concerned
with unauthorized leakages.
I take it you mean smuggling.
Yes.
Gold, which can be melted down
and recast, is virtually untraceable...
...which makes it, unlike diamonds,
ideal for smuggling...
...attracting the biggest
and most ingenious criminals.
Thank you. That'll be all.
Thank you, sir.
Have a little more
of this rather disappointing brandy.
What's wrong with it?
I'd say it was a 30-year-old Fins,
indifferently blended, sir...
...with an overdose of Bons Bois.
Colonel Smithers
is giving the lecture, 007.
Mr. Goldfinger has gold bullion
on deposit in Zurich...
...Amsterdam, Caracas and Hong Kong
worth 20 million pounds.
- Most of it came from this country.
- Why move it?
Because the price of gold varies
from country to country.
If you buy it here at $30 an ounce,
you can sell it in Pakistan at $ 110...
...and triple your money.
- Lf you have facilities for melting it.
- Has he?
Apart from being a legitimate
bullion dealer, Mr. Goldfinger poses...
No, that's not fair.
Is, among his other interests,
a legitimate international jeweler.
He's legally entitled to operate
modest metallurgical installations.
His British one is down in Kent.
As yet, we've failed to discover
how he transfers his gold overseas...
...and Lord knows we've tried.
If your department can establish
that it is done illegally...
...the bank can begin proceedings
to recover the bulk of his holdings.
It's time Mr. Goldfinger and I met.
Socially, of course.
I was hoping you'd say that.
It might lead to a business talk.
Mr. Goldfinger's kind of business.
- I'll need some sort of bait.
- I agree.
This is the only one we have...
...from the Nazi hoard
at the bottom of Lake Toplitz.
But there are undoubtedly others.
Mr. Bond can make whatever use of it
he thinks fit...
...providing he returns it,
of course.
It's worth 5000 pounds.
You'll draw it from Q branch
with the rest of your equipment.
Of course, sir.
- Good morning, Q.
- Good morning, 007.
This way, please.
My, we are busy this morning.
It's not perfected yet.
- Where's my Bentley?
- It's had its day, I'm afraid.
- It's never let me down.
- M's orders, 007.
You'll be using this Aston Martin DB-5
with modifications.
Pay attention, please.
Windscreen: Bulletproof...
...as are the side and rear windows.
Revolving number plates, naturally.
Valid all countries.
Here's a nice transmitting device
called a "homer."
You prime it by pressing that back
like this. You see?
The smaller model
is now standard field issue...
...to be fitted
into the heel of your shoe.
Its larger brother is magnetic.
Right. It's to be concealed
in the car you're trailing...
...while you keep out of sight.
Reception on the dashboard here.
Audiovisual, range 150 miles.
Ingenious and useful too.
Allow a man to stop off
for a quick one en route.
It's not been perfected out of years
of patient research and time...
...for that purpose, 007.
Incidentally,
we'd appreciate its return...
...along with all your other equipment.
Intact, for once,
when you return from the field.
You'd be surprised, the amount of
wear and tear that goes on in the field.
Anything else?
I won't keep you for more than an hour
if you give me your undivided attention.
We've installed
interesting modifications.
You see this arm?
Open the top and inside are
your defense mechanism controls.
Smoke screen, oil slick,
rear bulletproof screen...
...and left and right
front-wing machine guns.
This one I'm particularly keen about.
See the gear lever here?
If you take the top off,
you'll find a little red button.
- Whatever you do, don't touch it.
- Why not?
Because you'll release
this section of the roof...
...and engage and fire
the passenger ejector seat.
Ejector seat? You're joking.
I never joke about my work, 007.
- Ready?
- Yes, sir.
There's an old member dropped by,
same handicap as yours.
- Would you rather play with him?
- Where is he?
- Mr. Bond?
- Yes?
This is Mr. Goldfinger.
- How do you do?
- You can begin. The first tee is clear.
- Fine.
- I'll get Hawker to carry for you.
- That'll be splendid.
Shall we make it a shilling a hole?
You must excuse Oddjob, Mr. Bond.
He's an admirable manservant...
...but mute.
He's not a very good caddy.
Golf is not yet the national game
of Korea, eh?
This meeting is
not a coincidence, eh?
What's your game, Mr. Bond?
My game?
You didn't come here to play golf.
A 1940 smelt from Essen.
- Part of a smelt of 600.
- They vanished in 1944.
- When the Nazis were on the run.
- Do you have access to more?
- Yes, from the same source.
- Interesting.
- Two holes to go.
- Yes, and all square.
- No objection to increasing the stakes?
- What do you have in mind?
The bar of gold you have with you,
naturally.
- It's worth 5000 pounds.
- I'll stake the cash equivalent.
Naturally.
Strict rules of golf?
But of course.
Bad luck. You're in the rough.
What a pity. Here it is.
No, it's not.
He plays a Slazenger 1.
Strict rules of golf, Goldfinger.
Five minutes are almost up.
The lost ball will cost you stroke
and distance.
I'm still training him as a caddy.
Successfully too.
Slazenger number 1?
Good.
If that's his original ball,
I'm Arnold Palmer.
It isn't.
- How do you know?
- I'm standing on it.
Why, you crafty old...
Leave it.
- The ball you found, sir?
- Yes, Slazenger 7.
Let's have fun with Mr. Goldfinger.
- Like me to mark it or knock it in?
- Play it.
- This for a half?
- That's right.
One to go.
That'll be the clincher.
Did you switch them, sir?
- Then we've got him.
- Lf he doesn't notice the switch.
- It's your honor, sir.
- It's all right.
Down in five.
I have to sink this
to have the game, right?
- You win, Goldfinger.
- It seems I'm too good for you.
You play a Slazenger 1, don't you?
Yes, why?
This is a Slazenger 7.
Here's my Penfold Hearts.
You must've played the wrong ball
somewhere on the 18th fairway.
We're playing strict rules, so I'm afraid
you lose the hole and the match.
She's a beauty.
Phantom III, '37, isn't she?
- You are a clever, resourceful man.
- Thank you.
Perhaps too clever.
Twice our paths have crossed.
Let's leave it at that.
I should think our first meeting
would've convinced you.
I see. You're worried about me
not giving you a return game.
Both of us know perfectly well
what we are talking about.
But I see it is necessary
to remind you. Oddjob!
Many people have tried to involve
themselves in my affairs...
...unsuccessfully.
Remarkable. But what does
the club secretary have to say?
Nothing, Mr. Bond.
I own the club.
I assume you want the check
made out to cash.
That would be satisfactory.
Goodbye, Mr. Bond.
I believe this is yours.
May I have your attention, please.
British United Air Ferries
announce the final call...
... for the departure
of their VF400 flight to Geneva.
I've got you booked on the next flight
to Geneva leaving in half an hour.
- Thank you.
- Right.
Discipline, 007.
Discipline.
Are you all right?
Here, let me help you.
- You're lucky to be alive.
- No thanks to you.
You should've pulled over further.
- Look at them!
- A double blowout.
I've never seen this before.
How could new tires?
A defect of some kind, most likely.
I'm so glad it's only the car
and not you.
You don't look like the sort
who should be ditched.
Never mind that.
Please take me to the nearest garage.
Certainly.
By the way, my name is Bond...
As quickly as possible.
- I'll take that.
- Yes, of course.
What's your name?
Soames. Tilly Soames.
Here for the hunting season?
I had a case just like that one.
It's for my ice skates.
Lovely sport.
- Where do you skate?
- Saint Moritz.
I didn't know there was ice there
this time of year.
There's a garage.
It'll take 24 hours to get new tires.
There's a hotel nearby.
- I'll run you down.
- That won't be necessary.
I hate to leave you here alone.
- I can take care of myself.
- Yes, I'm sure you can.
Well, don't forget to write.
Smuggling is an art.
And art requires...
In this case, the bodywork
of my Rolls-Royce is 18-karat gold.
We dismantle it here.
We reduce the gold
in this special furnace to ingots...
...which, in turn, will weigh
approximately 2 tons in bullion.
I make six trips a year
to the continent in the Rolls-Royce.
It would be wiser to suspend
your other activities.
Mr. Ling, assure your principals
Operation Grand Slam...
...will have my undivided attention.
Now, there are certain matters...
Let me go!
You're breaking my back!
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I want to kill him.
- Kill who?
- Goldfinger.
- I want him alive.
- I want him dead! He killed my sister.
T.M. Tilly Masterson.
I knew your sister Jill
and what he did to her in Miami.
No, you don't! Let me go!
If you wanted to kill him,
why did you shoot at me?
- I didn't. I was shooting at him.
- You're a lousy shot.
But somebody else around here isn't.
Come on.
Quick, get in the car.
I'll take care of him.
Run for that bracken when I tell you.
Now!
Good evening, 007.
My name is James Bond.
And members of
your curious profession...
...are few in number.
You have been recognized...
...by one of your opposite numbers,
who is also licensed to kill.
And that interesting car of yours!
I, too, have a new toy,
but considerably more practical.
You are looking at
an industrial laser...
...which emits an extraordinary light
not to be found in nature.
It can project a spot on the moon.
Or, at closer range, cut through
solid metal. I will show you.
This is gold, Mr. Bond.
All my life I've been in love
with its color...
...its brilliance,
its divine heaviness.
I welcome any enterprise
that will increase my stock...
...which is considerable.
You've made your point.
Thank you for the demonstration.
Choose your next witticism carefully.
It may be your last.
The purpose of our two previous
encounters is now clear to me.
I do not intend to be distracted
by another. Good night, Mr. Bond.
- Do you expect me to talk?
- No, Mr. Bond, I expect you to die.
There is nothing you can talk to me
about that I don't already know.
You're forgetting one thing.
If I fail to report,
008 replaces me.
I trust he will be more successful.
He knows what I know.
You know nothing, Mr. Bond.
Operation Grand Slam, for instance.
Two words you may
have overheard...
...which cannot have any significance
to you or anyone in your organization.
Can you afford to take that chance?
You are right, Mr. Bond.
You are worth more to me alive.
Who are you?
My name is Pussy Galore.
I must be dreaming.
- I thought I'd wake up dead.
- Tranquilizer gun. Knockout shot.
I see.
I'm delighted to be here.
And, by the way,
where is here?
Thirty-five thousand feet,
flying southwest over Newfoundland.
That explains the humming.
You're in Mr. Goldfinger's Lockheed
JetStar heading for Baltimore.
- You're his guest.
- I'm honored.
I never realized he enjoyed
my company that much.
It won't be all fun and games.
Mei-Lei.
Can I do something for you,
Mr. Bond?
Just a drink. A martini, shaken...
...not stirred.
- Won't you join me?
- Not on duty.
I'm Mr. Goldfinger's personal pilot.
You are?
And how personal is that?
I'm a damn good pilot. Period.
That's good news.
- Where is our host?
- He flew ahead.
Thank you.
Here's to Operation Grand Slam.
This should be a memorable flight.
You can turn off the charm.
I'm immune.
We land in Baltimore...
... our port of entry
into the United States, in 55 minutes.
Mei-Lei...
...I would like to arrive
more appropriately dressed.
Did any of my luggage
survive with me?
And my attache case?
Black attache case damaged
when examined. So sorry.
Apology is quite unnecessary.
Sydney, tell Mei-Lei
to keep an eye on him.
We'll be landing in 20 minutes.
Want to play it easy, or the hard way?
And this isn't a tranquilizer.
You know a lot more about planes
than guns.
That's a Smith & Wesson.45.
If you fired this close, the bullet would
go through me and the fuselage...
...like a blowtorch through butter.
The cabin will depressurize, and we'll
be sucked into outer space together.
If that's how you want to enter
the States, you're welcome.
As for me, I prefer the easier way.
That's very sensible.
There's always so much
going on around Mr. Goldfinger.
I wouldn't dream of not accepting
his hospitality.
He'll be very glad to see you too.
You like close shaves, don't you?
Washington, sir,
on the green scrambler.
- M here.
- Leiter, sir.
It's about 007, sir.
We picked up his homer signal.
It's monitored into Baltimore
where he's just landed.
Baltimore? Nice of him to let us know.
Last we heard he was in Switzerland.
He came in on a private jet registered
to our old friend, Auric Goldfinger.
I'm glad he's making progress.
Keep an eye on him.
Their flight plan gives Kentucky
as their final destination.
Don't charge in on him
and spoil anything.
He's evidently well on top
at the moment.
- Mr. Bond, please.
- Of course.
Anytime.
Thank you.
Do mind your step, captain.
Just keep playing it easy.
Will you see everything's arranged
with Mr. Goldfinger?
Of course.
Talented chaps.
They should be.
I trained them.
Come on.
You're a woman of many parts, Pussy.
I believe the bourbon and branch water
is splendid here in Kentucky.
Now that we're both off duty,
perhaps...
Manners, Oddjob. I thought
you always took your hat off to a lady.
- He kills little girls like you.
- Little boys too.
- Dress rehearsal went like a dream.
- Good.
You'll get your final briefing tonight.
That'll be all for now.
Welcome to Auric Stud, Mr. Bond.
- Lovely animal, isn't she?
- Certainly better bred than the owner.
Show Mr. Bond
to his quarters, please.
Felix.
- Maybe we should drop in on him.
- He'll shout if he needs us.
They're all here, Mr. Goldfinger.
Oh, yes, yes! Thank you, Kisch.
Solo's gonna wear a hole
in his shoes.
Gentlemen.
Why weren't we told New York
and the West Coast were in on this?
- Look who's talking.
- I do not do business with Chicago.
I thought we had a private
business deal to settle.
Now I find I'm attending
a hoods' convention.
- I made a delivery. Where's my money?
- I made a delivery too.
You all made the deliveries
we contracted for.
And you owe me 1 million bucks.
I owe each of you a million
in gold bullion.
So pay!
Gentlemen, you can have
the million today...
...or 10 millions tomorrow!
Did you say 10 million?
As soon as my bank opens
in the morning.
Banks don't open on Sunday.
My bank will.
What's with that trick pool table?
- Cover him!
- Cover those doors.
Turn those lights back on!
What are you trying
to pull, Goldfinger?
There is no cause
for alarm, gentlemen.
I don't like being cooped up like this.
What's that map doing there?
This is my bank,
the Gold Depository at Fort Knox.
In its vaults are $ 15 billion...
...the entire gold supply
of the United States.
Knock off Fort Knox?
Got a key or something?
Of a kind.
- There are 35,000 troops there.
- Forty-one thousand.
And who's gonna say "boo" to them?
- Hey, what's going on?
- What is this?
Man has climbed Mount Everest...
...gone to the bottom of the ocean.
He has fired rockets to the moon,
split the atom.
Achieved miracles...
...in every field of human endeavor
except crime!
The underworld will
rock with applause for centuries.
- Cut the commercial.
- Get to the point.
You're wasting my time.
The depository's impregnable.
The joint is bombproof, electrified,
lousy with...
Bear with me, please!
Fort Knox is a bank like any other.
Larger, better protected perhaps,
but nonetheless, a bank.
It can be,
I think the expression is...
...blown!
My plan is foolproof.
I call it...
...Operation Grand Slam.
I have devoted 15 years
of my life to it.
Every detail has been
scrupulously prepared.
Every eventuality
has been considered.
We'll operate
on a split-second schedule.
Your organization, Mr. Midnight,
brought a consignment...
...of these canisters
across the Canadian border.
They contain Delta Nine.
- What's that?
- An invisible nerve gas.
It disperses 15 minutes
after inducing...
...complete unconsciousness
for 24 hours.
Tomorrow at dawn...
...the Flying Circus of my pilot,
Miss Pussy Galore...
...will spray it
into the atmosphere.
Once the population, including
the military, has been immobilized...
...my task force,
which Mr. Strap and his people...
...smuggled across the Rio Grande
from Mexico...
...will approach Fort Knox...
...in motorized equipment
along Bullion Boulevard...
...which runs past the depository...
...and intersects
with Gold Vault Road.
This fence
surrounding the depository...
...as Mr. Strap reminded us,
is electrified.
It will be dynamited.
My task force will then move to
the main entrance and demolish it.
How, may I ask?
You made that possible, Mr. Solo.
By arranging through your influence
in shipping circles...
...to bring through customs,
uninspected...
...a consignment labeled
"machine parts."
All that will remain
is to descend to the vaults...
...where the bullion is stored.
I've heard enough. If you have
no objection, I'll take my money now.
What's the matter, Solo?
Too big for you to handle?
We must respect Mr. Solo's decision.
Excuse me while I take care of him.
Make yourselves comfortable.
Pussy!
Who taught you judo?
The gun you took.
Oh, the gun.
The gun, of course.
We must have a few fast falls
together sometime.
Strap, if he's got the right answers...
...we don't have to be there.
The boys can handle everything.
- They closed up the fire pit.
- I don't like this.
What's going on here?
The gas!
Such a pity you did not choose
to remain with the others, Mr. Solo.
Mr. Bond, I thought you were resting
in your quarters.
They are delightful,
but it's much too nice to stay indoors.
I ran into Miss Galore
and she suggested that we join you.
Mr. Solo, Mr. Bond.
Another of my distinguished guests.
Leaving us so soon, Mr. Solo?
Unfortunately,
he has a pressing engagement.
I'd like to get started, Goldfinger.
Boy.
When you gotta go,
you gotta go.
My plane will get you
to New York on time...
...with your excess luggage.
Allow me.
My chauffeur is an excellent driver.
You will be at the airport soon.
Goodbye, Mr. Solo.
Some other time, perhaps.
Happy landings, old boy.
I found him under the model.
Operation Grand Slam.
I did enjoy your briefing.
So did I.
He's on the move!
Slow down. Don't crowd him.
Are you blind or something?
You missed the turn.
They've turned to the right
just ahead.
Where's this old pal
of yours headed?
Ten will get you one,
it's a drink or a dame.
Dead.
- Mechanical failure, maybe.
- Unless he switched it off.
Why would he do that?
- Drive to the farm. It's all we can do.
- Right.
Thank you.
Your share of Operation Grand Slam
will make you a very rich woman.
Why else would I be in it,
Mr. Goldfinger?
You'll retire to England,
I suppose?
No, I've spotted a little island
in the Bahamas.
I'll hang up a sign,
"No trespassing"...
...and go back to nature.
- Yes, Kisch?
- Two men in a car with binoculars.
Touts, looking for racing tips.
There's another possibility, however.
Kisch, ask Mr. Bond to join us.
We were right to spare Mr. Bond's life
in Switzerland if those are his friends.
Let's convince them
he needs no assistance.
For their benefit, Pussy,
let's make him as happy as possible.
I suggest you change
into something more suitable.
Certainly.
Business before pleasure.
He wants you.
Mr. Bond, sit down, please.
Mint julep?
Traditional, but satisfying.
Yes, thanks.
Sour mash, but not too sweet, please.
You disappoint me, Goldfinger.
You know Operation Grand Slam
simply won't work.
Incidentally,
Delta Nine nerve gas is fatal.
You are unusually well-informed,
Mr. Bond.
You'll kill 60,000 people uselessly.
American motorists kill that many
every two years.
Yes. Well, I've worked out
a few statistics of my own.
Fifteen billion dollars in gold bullion
weighs 10,500 tons.
Sixty men would take 12 days...
...to load it onto 200 trucks.
At the most,
you'll have two hours...
...before the military moves in
and makes you put it back.
Who mentioned anything
about removing it?
The julep tart enough for you?
You plan to break into
the world's largest bank...
...but not to steal anything?
Why?
Go on, Mr. Bond.
Mr. Ling, the Red Chinese agent
at the factory...
...is a specialist in nuclear fission.
But of course!
His government's given you a bomb.
I prefer to call it an atomic device.
It's small, but particularly dirty.
- Cobalt and iodine?
- Precisely.
If you explode it in Fort Knox...
...the entire gold supply
of the United States...
...will be radioactive for...
...57 years.
Fifty-eight, to be exact.
I apologize. It's an inspired deal.
They get what they want,
economic chaos in the West.
And the value of your gold
increases many times.
I conservatively estimate
ten times.
Brilliant.
But the atomic device,
as you call it...
...is already, obviously,
in this country.
Obviously.
But bringing it to Fort Knox undetected
could be very risky.
On the contrary,
the risk is all on your side.
If the authorities try locating it,
who knows where it might be exploded.
Perhaps the Polaris submarine pens
at New London.
Cape Kennedy?
Near the White House?
But we are speculating idly.
Operation Grand Slam
will be successful.
You will be there to see for yourself.
Too closely for comfort, I'm afraid.
Forgive me, Mr. Bond.
I must arrange to separate my gold
from the late Mr. Solo.
As you said,
he had a pressing engagement.
Very chic, Miss Galore!
Don't you agree?
Please entertain Mr. Bond
for me, Pussy.
I'll join you both later.
Well, how about it, handsome?
Don't you think it's time
we got to know each other socially?
Well, the new Miss Galore.
Where do you hide
your gold knuckles in this outfit?
I never carry weapons
after business hours.
Yeah? So you're off duty.
- I'm completely defenseless.
- So am I.
That's my James.
- Beautiful place Goldfinger has here.
- Yes. I'm glad you're enjoying it.
Too bad it all has to end
tomorrow morning.
He's quite mad, you know.
Well, now, what do we have here?
007 seems to have the situation
well in hand.
I'm bushed.
Let's get back to the motel.
- You're quite a girl.
- I'm strictly the outdoor type.
I'd like to think
you're not in all of this caper.
Skip it. I'm not interested.
Let's go.
What would it take
for you to see things my way?
- A lot more than you've got.
- How do you know?
I don't want to know.
Isn't it customary to grant
a condemned man his last request?
You've asked for this.
Get up.
Certainly.
Now let's both play.
Pussy Galore to Champagne leader.
Commence Rock-A-Bye Baby.
Good luck.
Speed: 220.
Wind check: Westerly.
Champagne leader
to Champagne section.
Commence dive now!
Ready for Rock-A-Bye Baby.
Commence spray on countdown.
Five...
... four, three...
... two, zero.
Champagne leader
to Grand Slam leader.
The baby is asleep.
I repeat, the baby is asleep.
We're going home now.
Out.
Good morning, Mr. Bond. For once,
you are exactly where I want you.
- The bomb's here.
- Let's get moving, brigadier.
- Right. Move in.
- Move in, commando tactics.
Minimum offensive fire until
I signal bomb has been neutralized.
Bomb disposal unit
to accompany DOG.
Goodbye, Mr. Bond.
Mr. Ling, it's merely
a matter of timing.
He's one of them, so is the girl!
I'll get her. You get the door open.
We're trapped.
The bomb. I'll take the fuse out.
Don't be a fool!
You can be a hero, I'm not.
No. No!
Come on. Get going. Hurry up!
What kept you?
You okay?
Where's your butler friend?
He blew a fuse.
Three more ticks and Mr. Goldfinger
would have hit the jackpot.
- Did you get him?
- Not yet, but he won't get far.
- And Pussy?
- She switched the gas in the canisters.
By the way,
what made her call Washington?
I must have appealed
to her maternal instincts.
James, get aboard.
You can't keep the president waiting.
Special plane,
lunch at the White House. How come?
The president wants
to thank you personally.
- It was nothing, really.
- I know that, but he doesn't.
I suppose I'll be able
to get a drink here.
I told the stewardess
liquor for three.
- Who are the other two?
- There are no other two.
- Goodbye, Felix.
- So long. Good luck.
- Thank you, brigadier.
- Good luck.
I am glad to have you aboard.
Congratulations on your promotion,
Goldfinger.
Are you having lunch
at the White House too?
In two hours, I shall be in Cuba.
And you have interfered with my plans
for the last time, Mr. Bond.
It's dangerous to fire guns in planes.
I even had to warn Pussy about it.
- By the way, where is she?
- I will deal with her later.
She is where she ought to be,
at the controls.
What happened?
Where's Goldfinger?
Playing his golden harp.
It's no good.
No, you don't!
This is no time to be rescued.