It's time.
Hey, there.
Morning.
How are
you today?
Hey. What are you doing up?
Moo.
Is that daddy?
Hey, there, cowgirl.
She's a little
feisty today.
Babies are supposed
to be sleeping.
I'm too
hungry for my own good.
Yes.
I got to get ready.
Wrong day
to be forgetting stuff.
Listen, everyone is
telling you how lucky you are.
Don't screw this up.
All right. Jesus.
She go back to sleep?
Yep. Ate like a pig.
I know how lucky I am.
I ace this assignment,
department's wide open.
Get my own division someday.
You should see
those guys' houses.
Hello?
Why, yes.
Don't worry.
I will.
Yeah,
he's right here.
Hello.
Hoyt?
Uh, yes, sir.
You on your way
to roll call?
Yeah, I'm on my way
Out the door
right now.
Hoyt.
Uh, yes, sir?
Patrol fairies
go to roll call.
We don't
OK, that's
good to know.
Listen, there's a coffee shop
at seventh and whitman.
See you there at 10:00.
Be in civvies.
Comfortable shoes.
Got a backup gun?
Something pocket-Sized?
Uh, no, sir,
I don't.
I got the department
issue Beretta.
Good, good.
Bring it. Cuffs too.
Going to be
in the office all day,
But who knows, maybe
we'll do some business.
We're an aggressive unit.
I know. Sir, that's
why I signed up.
And, you know,
I just want to say
Thank you for
giving me this...
What's wrong?
I feel like
it's the first day
Of football tryouts.
I mean, I wish it was
tomorrow already
So I'd know whether
I made his squad.
Listen, it's not tomorrow,
it's today.
I know it's going to work out.
You do?
Mm-Hmm.
Good morning, sir.
Uh, no,
thank you, ma'am.
Oh, get some chow in you
Before we go
to the office. My dollar.
Uh, thank you, sir,
but I ate.
All right, fine. Don't.
It's nice here.
May I read my paper?
I'm sorry, sir. I...
Thank you.
You know what? I'll get
something to eat.
No. Hell, no, you won't.
You fucked that up.
I'm trying to read my paper.
Please, shut up.
I sure wouldn't mind
not roasting
In a hot black and white
all summer.
Tell me a story, Hoyt.
Like, my story?
No, not your story.
A story.
Since you can't
keep your mouth shut
Long enough for me
to read my paper,
Tell me a story.
I don't think
I know any stories.
You don't know any stories?
All right,
I'll tell you a story.
This is a newspaper, right?
It's 90% bullshit,
but it's entertaining.
That's why I read it,
because it entertains me.
You won't let me read it,
so you entertain me
With your bullshit.
Tell me a story right now. Go.
Well, there was
a D.U.I. Stop...
A d.U.I. Stop?
Well, let me load up my guns.
A d.U.I.?! Oh, shit!
Listen, all right?
It's good.
We were on mid-Watch...
We?
Oh, me and Debbie...
Who's Debbie?
Uh, oh, I'm sorry.
Uh, Debbie Maxwell,
my training officer.
You had a female
training officer?
Yes, sir.
Ah, OK. OK.
All right. All right.
Ha ha ha! So what was she?
Black? White?
She was white.
Ah-Ha. Lick her license?
Uh, what?
A lick her license.
Was she a dyke? A lesbian?
Oh.
Is she any good?
Yeah, she's pretty good.
OK. Pretty good Debbie,
mid-Watch. Go.
All right. So it was
a real quiet night...
Boom!
Ha ha! You never know.
That's the point. Go.
All right, well,
it was a quiet night.
We're rolling
on vanowen. I'm driving.
This Acura,
just a beautiful car,
Comes out a side street,
All over the median.
In excess.
I light it up,
hit the wailer.
Guy drives on
like I'm invisible
For 10 blocks
before he pulls over.
All right?
Plates run clean,
So I field test
and arrest.
And I'm belting him
in our unit,
And Debbie's
tossing his car.
She calls me over
to the vehicle
And shows me a snub .38
and 2 shotguns
Fully loaded and locked.
No shit?
No shit. So, uh,
she calls our supervisor
And I keep searching.
I find 500 grams of meth
in the dash.
Turns out this d.U.I.
Is on bail
for distribution.
He's on his way
to smoke his ex-Partner
Before trial.
Boom.
We prevented a murder.
You go him. That's amazing.
It is.
That you could be out there
with a fine bitch for a year,
And the most entertaining story
that you can come up with
To tell me is a drunk stop.
But I don't believe you.
You tapped that ass,
didn't you?
Tell the truth.
You know you tapped that ass.
You put her in the backseat.
Bam! Code x.
Look, man, I got a wife.
You got a dick.
You do have a dick, don't you?
Yes.
OK, your dick lines up
Straight like that, right?
To the right of it
and to the left of it
Are pockets, right?
In those pockets are money.
Look in either one of them,
pay the bill.
Hey, grab that menu
off that window for me,
All right?
Get in. It's unlocked.
Just throw that
in the glove box.
This car is not
from the motor pool.
No, it's not.
Sexy, though, isn't it?
So where's the office?
Back at division?
You're in
the office, baby.
Going up.
Today's a training day,
officer Hoyt.
Show you around.
Give you a taste of
the business, you know?
I got 38 cases
pending trials,
63 in active
investigation,
Another 250 on the log
I can't clear.
I supervise 5 officers.
That's 5 different
personalities.
5 sets of problems.
You could be number 6
if you act right.
But I am holding no
hands, you understand?
I am not baby-Sitting.
You got today
And today only
to show me who
And what you're made of.
You don't
like narcotics,
Get the fuck
out of my car,
Go back to the office,
Get a nice, pussy
desk job, you know?
Chasing bad checks or
something. You hear me?
I hear you.
OK.
Why do you
want to be a narc?
I want to, um,
serve my community
By ridding it
of dangerous drugs.
Right. Right. But why
do you want to be a narc?
Ha ha ha. Uh, I want
to make detective.
There you go.
You can do it.
Stick with me.
Unlearn that bullshit
They teach you
at the academy, though.
Don't bring none
of that shit in here.
Shit will get you
killed out here.
I will do anything
you want me to do.
My niggah.
Roll your window down.
Start there.
Ha ha ha. See, you got to
hear the street.
You got to smell it,
you know?
You got to taste that
shit, feel it.
How's your Espaol?
Um...mas o menos.
Learn that shit,
brother.
Learn that shit.
That shit will get you killed.
These motherfuckers out here
plotting all kinds of shit
Behind your back.
Shit, man. You going to
teach me that old school,
Hard charging,
beat up everything that moves,
Rodney king shit?
We don't do that no more.
That day's dead, dog.
We don't roll
like that no more.
Now we use this.
Brain power.
These niggahs are
too strong out here anyway.
You think I'm crazy,
right? Huh?
I don't know what to think.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Good.
Ah...
How long have
you been married?
About a year.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You got
a kid, right?
That's right. A little girl.
9 months old.
Yeah. I got 4.
Boys.
You need a son,
you let me know.
I'll hook your old
lady up, you know?
I can't miss.
Can we not talk
about my family,
All right?
I respect that.
I'm married.
I got my queen, too.
I remember
what it was like
To have a pretty
young bride.
You probably
fuck her
Face to face,
don't you?
All right, man.
Let's just not talk about
my wife, all right?
Yeah, that's my point,
you see?
You're so in love,
The shit is coming
out of your eyes.
The day you bring
your old lady to the office
Is the day that you don't
make it back home.
You got to hide that love deep
inside you, you understand?
Otherwise, these maggots
out here on the street,
They'll find it.
They'll use it against you,
And they will chew you up...
Never wear that
wedding ring to work.
I'm serious about that.
All right.
All right. Thanks.
What's here?
Transactions.
You see that
salvatrucha zero head
Sitting over there
on the fence
Trying to act like
he's not slanging dope?
Yeah.
Yeah. That's my boy.
That's my boy neto.
The punk's only 17,
But he can kill
with the best of them.
He works for me.
Jesus, he's an...
He's an informer?
Teammate, you know?
I got eyes everywhere.
He gets to pedal
a little reefer,
Make a little cash
for the family.
He gives me
the head's up
When big things
are happening.
Big transactions.
boom. Boom,
boom, boom, boom, boom.
And you trust him?
Damn right I trust him.
I sprung his mom
from I.N.S. Detention.
Here we go.
Here we go. Here we go.
Watch this.
That's right.
Come on down.
Come on. Look at it.
Sexy, isn't it?
That's right.
See the hand-To-Hand?
Yeah, I saw it.
I saw it.
All right. When was
the last time
You did
a felony stop?
Uh, a couple weeks ago.
Good. You need practice.
They look like
college kids.
They'll get education today.
I want the Brady bunch
grabbing glass.
I'm going to take the front,
you take the back.
Stay off of the rover.
Let's go.
Yeah, you little fuckers.
Run, baby, run.
That's right.
Police officers.
Let's see your hands.
Police.
Put your hands up!
Put them up!
Driver, right side
passenger, hands on
The windshield. Put them
on the windshield!
You, in the back, hands
on the side of the glass.
Look straight ahead.
Put it in park!
Stick shift.
Grab the keys and throw
them out the window.
Put your hands
on your chest.
on your chest!
All right. Fork
it over, smart man.
What?
You know what
I'm talking about.
Aah!
The marijuana.
Give it to me!
Ow!
OK, OK, OK.
Sorry, sir. I...
Shut up.
Too late for that.
Give me that pipe
you got.
Down there on
the floor, too.
My mom gave me
this pipe.
I don't care
who gave it to you.
She could pick it up
in jail. What else you got?
Give me them cigarettes, too.
Give me, give me, give me,
give me, give me. Hey!
Control your suspect.
Miss, palms
on the glass.
you move those hands,
I'll slap the taste
out of your mouth,
You understand me?
Put your face right up
against the glass.
Right there.
Now, what are you
doing down here?
You know this is a gang
neighborhood, don't you?
Ow, ow! Yeah, yeah!
You know it's
a gang neighborhood?
Then don't
come down here.
I see you
down here again,
I'm going to
take your vehicle.
...make you walk home.
I'm going to let
the homeboys up the hill...
...Run a train
on your girlfriend.
You know what a train
is, don't you, huh?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
All right, gentlemen.
Thanks for
your cooperation.
Let's go.
Safe your iron, son.
Shit!
I like that shit.
Hey, I like the way
you moved out there.
You were trained
very well.
Check that out.
It's a shitty dime.
See the small hairs,
Undeveloped seeds...
All the stems in it?
See how immature it is?
That's classic
brick-Pack Mexican.
That's garbage.
Let me see. Give me.
Yeah, it's old, too.
Shit is probably
from last year.
To be truly effective,
A good narcotics agent
must know and love narcotics.
In fact,
a good narcotics agent
Should have narcotics
in his blood.
what...
What, are you going to
smoke that?
Nope, you are.
hell if I am.
Yeah? Yeah?
You're not?
No.
Why, you a Mormon
or something?
You're a Jesus freak?
No, man. I'm not
losing my job.
This is your job.
I can't do that.
Smoke it.
This isn't a test.
Just take a hit.
No, man, listen.
I became a cop
To stop people
from using...
Yeah, yeah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
It's not a review board
and it isn't cocaine.
Take a hit.
No, man.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah, right.
If I was a dealer,
You'd be dead by
now, motherfucker.
You turn shit down
on the street,
And the chief
brings your wife
A crisply
folded flag.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
Talking about...
You know what?
I don't want
you in my unit,
And I don't want you
in my division.
Get the fuck
out of my car.
Go back to
the valley, rookie.
Pooping ass.
Give me that thing.
I'll smoke it, man.
Give it to me.
You want me to smoke it,
I'll smoke it.
ah, virgin lungs.
Man up, now.
Man up, niggah.
Here you go.
Go ahead.
Dog, you didn't
even get it.
come on!
Shut the fuck up,
and just wait.
Oh, god.
man the fuck up.
Finish that shit.
Aha!
Let's go, niggah.
Let's go.
Oh, shit.
You OK, kid?
That was a man-Size
hit you took, dog.
When was the last time
you smoked weed?
Uh, the last... Last,
uh, 12th grade.
We were...
Oh, we were, um...
Smoking weed.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, left that out
Of your service
jacket, didn't you?
Yeah, I knew
you got secrets.
Everybody got secrets.
Didn't know
You liked
to get wet, though.
What's "wet?"
Butt-Naked. Ill.
Sherms. Dust.
P.C.P. Primos.
P-Dog. That's what you had.
That's what
you were smoking.
You couldn't taste it?
Nah, I never done it.
You have now.
I haven't,
but you have.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Man, I'm going to
get piss-Tested,
And I'm
going to get fired.
Lieutenant's got our back.
We know a week
before we piss.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Boom!
Why did you
do this to me?
Ah, you're an adult,
man. Shit.
Nobody told you
to smoke that.
You made the decision.
Live with your decision.
Isn't like I put
a gun to your head.
shit, man.
Oh, man. Shit.
Come on. Get your
shit together now.
This is
my dog's house.
We'll see what
he thinks of you.
Brother,
get your ass in here.
roger, what's up, boy?
All right. How they
treating you, huh?
Give me a pound.
All right.
I didn't
wake you up, did I?
no, baby.
You know I never sleep.
That's right. Hey,
this is my new guy Jake.
Come on in.
Yeah, time to get
my swerve on here.
What you
drinking, dog?
What am I drinking?
The best.
The best. I know. It's
the best for the best.
I heard you had
a beef in Vegas.
There's a green light
on your ass.
Nah, no problem.
It's all good.
the Russians
want your head.
You know I got your back.
I know that.
Thank you.
Here.
Get that medicine
up in you.
Back to
the world, dog.
Back to the world.
You went and got yourself
a daisy fresh rookie.
Jesus, Alonzo, he's high
as a motherfucker.
What the hell
you give him?
Oh, Mexico's finest.
Yeah.
oh.
Garbage.
Where did you grow up?
North Hollywood.
what's
your last name?
Hoyt.
Hoyt. Hoyt...
Strong safety,
north Hollywood high.
that's right.
How did you know that?
Yeah, how the fuck
did you know that?
I follow all
the good players.
Uh, excuse me.
Strong safety, huh?
it's me.
What's up?
I can't do
a thing for you.
It's your mess.
You clean it up.
Don't be calling me.
Hey...
Here's a joke, boy.
A man walks out of his house
on his way to work,
Sees this snail
lying on his porch.
So he picks it up,
chucks it over the roof
Into the backyard.
Snail bounces off a rock,
Busts its shell up
all to shit,
Lands in the grass.
Hmm? Snail lies there dying.
But the snail doesn't die.
And then after a while,
it can crawl again.
And one day the snail
up and heads back
To the front of the house.
And finally, after,
oh, about a year,
The little guy crawls
back on the porch.
Right then the man
walks out of his house
On his way to work.
He sees this snail again.
So he looks at it,
and he says...
"What the fuck is
your problem?!"
That's not funny.
What you
laughing for then,
...If it isn't funny?
I don't know, man. I...
Hey, hey!
You figure that joke out,
You'll figure
the streets out.
Shit, there is
nothing to figure out.
That's just some
senseless bullshit.
Don't listen to him.
Yeah, well, I...
I already
figured them out.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, really?
Yeah.
You already
figured the streets out?
Yeah, well, it's...
It's all about
smiles and cries.
Put the drink down, man.
This motherfucker is
out of his mind.
Hey, hold on, Alonzo.
Hold on, hold on.
Smiles and cries.
I hear you.
Yeah, you got to...
You got to control
your smiles and cries,
Because that's
all you have,
And nobody can
take that away from you.
Oh, shit.
What you think, dog?
Hmm?
Think this greenhorn
can handle undercover?
You were just like him.
What?
Same silly-Ass look
and everything.
Saving the god damn world!
Yeah.
Yeah!
Yeah, now that's
some smiles and cries
For your ass.
Yeah. Shit lasted
about a week.
yeah.
I got to get back
to the office.
Thanks for the snort,
dog.
Always good
to see you, brother.
Yeah.
Yes, sir!
Mm-Hmm. What you doing
later on?
Stay in the house,
save some cheddar.
I'm less than a year
away from my dream.
Philippine islands,
here I come,
And I am never
coming back!
That's right.
Let me go with you.
You're invited.
Aaugh!
Hey.
Open your eyes, man,
you'll feel a lot better.
Boom! Come on, man,
sit your ass up.
Who are you?
I'm the zigzag man.
Who the fuck are you?
I'm a cop, man.
Watch out.
Alright.
Don't shoot nobody.
Why don't you get
that beer in you, man?
That will give you ballast.
Oh, no.
For real.
Get that up in you, man.
You'll feel better.
Stop the car, man!
What?
Stop the car. Stop...
Stop the car!
I saw something.
Stop the fucking car!
All right, hold on.
Hold the fuck...
Hey. Hey! Hey!
Fuck me, man! Shit!
Police officer!
Get away from the girl!
Get away from her!
I'm going to fuck you, too, cop!
Aah!
We didn't
do shit, man!
That bitch is crazy!
Unh!
Roll over, man.
Roll the fuck over!
Fucking-Ass prick!
My niggah!
Go ahead, cowboy.
You got
mad squabbles, boy!
Thanks for the help.
Yeah, you should have
shot them.
What's happening?
Oh, hey.
You're fucking dead!
OK, wait a minute.
Hold it. Hold it!
You, too,
fucking white boy!
My cousins are
from Hillside Trece,
And they're going to
blast you fools!
Calm down. Calm down,
all right? Are you OK?
No, I'm not OK.
Look at my nose, man!
It's just a little
nosebleed.
Just put a little ice
on it, you're going to be fine.
What are you doing
out here anyway? Huh?
These pieces of shit,
they probably got aids,
You know? Why are you
not in school?
I was just going
to a ditch party...
You almost became a part
of the ditch party.
Now, you say
your cousins from where?
From Hillside Trece!
You fucking remember that, too!
Tell your cousins
to get your back,
All right?
Grab your bag
and go home right now.
Whoa, I need to get...
Go home right now!
We don't need
no statement. Go! Go.
Yeah, they're going to
fuck you up, iputo!
We're going to cut them loose?
What, do you want
to beat them up? Go ahead.
Get down. Protect
and serve, brother.
I got a punching bag
at home.
These guys should
be off the streets.
You hear that, homey?
You want to go home, or you
want to go to jail, huh?
What you think?!
Ahh. Got room for you
at the booty house.
You ever been
to the booty house?
Huh?
Big boys have you
grab your ankles, man.
Suck my dick, bitch!
I know people!
That's how it starts.
What about you, my man?
What you got?
You ain't got nothing?
No, man.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Where's your horn?
I have got no horn.
No?
Uh-Uh.
You got money, though.
Aw, you lied to me.
You lied to me.
Lucky I don't make you
eat that, dog.
Stand up, you. Stand up.
Stand the fuck up!
Yeah. Oh, shit, huh?!
Huh? Huh?
Turn around, sucker.
Turn around.
So you like raping
young girls, huh?
Hmm? You like to rape
young girls?
That's your m.O.?
No, no...
That's what you like,
isn't it?
You like to rape
young girls.
That's what you like
to do, right?
Don't lie to me.
You told me to "suck
your dick, bitch."
Isn't that what
you said to me?
Look at me.
You wanted me
to suck your dick.
That's what you said,
right?
That what you said? Hmm?
Didn't you say,
"suck my dick, bitch"?
Don't lie to me. That's
what... You keep telling me,
I'm a liar.
You didn't say,
"Suck my dick, bitch"?
That's not what
you said to me?
So I'm lying?
Am I lying?
No. Please. Please!
Where is it?
I can't even find it.
Let me see.
Pull your pants down.
Pull them down.
Which nut you want?
I'll leave you one nut.
Which one you want?
Make a decision.
All right, all right.
Put your hands
on your head.
Close your eyes.
Uhh!
You're lucky I have
more pressing business.
I'd cut your fucking
dick off
And stick it right up that
little funky ass of yours,
Bitch!
Damn, I'm thirsty!
I want a beer.
What about you?
You want a beer?
I'm going to leave
you three to it, man.
Pussy-Ass bitch!
When I see you again, I'm going to
fuck your shit up, bitch!
You aren't going to
see shit coming, man!
I'll sneak up behind you
Like a
motherfucking ninja, man.
I'll crack your head open,
you fucking pig! Come on!
That girl's 14.
She all woman, though, man.
You tax that ass
for days, man.
Yeah, keep walking,
bitch! Unh!
You want a beer?
No, I don't
want a beer, man.
No? You mad?
You want to book
that 60 bucks, huh?
Here. Go ahead.
Book it
into evidence, man.
Where are your suspects,
though?
You got to go back
and get the suspects.
I don't know where they are.
You let them go.
Oh, I let them go.
Yeah, you let them go.
They're...
Hey, man, you want
to run and gun, man,
Stay in patrol, OK?
This is investigations,
Alright?
Let the garbage men
handle the garbage.
We're professional
anglers, OK?
We go after
the big fish.
Chasing them
monkey-Strung
Crackhead motherfuckers
anyway! You know,
They'd have killed you
without hesitating.
That's why they belong
in prison.
For what?
They got beat down,
They lost their rock,
they lost their money.
Them eses from hillside
probably going to smoke them.
I mean, Jesus,
what more you want?
I want justice.
Is that not justice?
That's street justice.
What's wrong
with street justice?
Just let the animals
wipe themselves out.
God willing! Fuck them,
And everybody
who looks like them.
Unfortunately, it doesn't
work that way.
The good guys,
they die first, right?
The school kids and moms,
family men...
They the ones
catch the stray bullets
In the noodle.
To protect the sheep,
you got to catch the wolf,
And it takes a wolf
to catch a wolf.
You understand?
What!?
I said you protect the sheep
By killing
the motherfucking wolves.
No, you didn't hear me.
You listening,
But you didn't hear me.
All right, whatever.
Yeah, whatever.
Whatever the fuck ever.
Well, let me
ask you this.
When do you
lock anybody up?
I mean, it seems you're pretty
busy keeping people out.
What the fuck
you talking about?!
You don't know what you're
talking about, Betty Boop!
Got nothing but shit
between your ears.
Shit, they build jails
because of me!
Judges have handed out
over 15,000 man-Years
Of incarceration time based
on my investigations, OK?
My record speaks for itself.
How many felons
have you collared?
Huh?
Yeah, I rest my case.
Oh, look, man, I'm not
smoking crack, all right?
Glad to hear that. Just
put it in the glove box.
Put the $60
in there, too.
That will come in handy
later on.
We'll use it like... Like
a credit card or something.
Hey, no matter what I say,
you did the right thing.
Reminds me
of when I was out there
Chasing down bad guys,
rocking their world.
That was some pretty amazing
shit you did back there, Hoyt.
thanks.
Hey, I noticed
you applied that, uh,
That choke hold,
though, huh?
I thought that was
a no-No procedure, boy.
I was getting
my ass kicked.
And you did
what you had to do, right?
You did
what you had to do.
That's right.
That's what a wolf does.
You a wolf?
Heh heh heh.
Come on, wolf!
come on, dog.
Heh heh. No, I said
a wolf, not a rooster!
A wolf.
That's a rooster.
Give me a wolf.
Fuck this, man!
Give me that beer.
Alright, there you go.
That's my niggah.
You got the magic eye,
Hoyt.
You have the magic eye!
You up your street IQ,
You going to do some damage
out here, I guarantee.
Crime fighter.
What you need, homey?
Uh, crack.
About 20 bucks worth.
Crack?!
Yeah.
Smell like bacon
in this motherfucker.
What, I look like a sucker
to you, niggah?!
Fuck you, rookie!
Go on, fetch, dog.
You want me to...
come on, man!
Shit!
Yo!
Yo, give me a break, man!
Hey! Yo! Slow up!
Excuse me.
Come on, buddy, stop.
I'm a police officer.
Police officer!
Stop!
Come on, man, give me a break,
all right? Shit!
you get out.
You don't look at my things.
Get out of here,
or I call police!
Police officer, ma'am.
Calm down.
Yo, man, I said stop,
all right?!
I said stop!
You're making this
so much harder. All right.
Just calm down. Calm down!
You love this shit, huh?
hey, man...
Pick him up.
Civil rights violating
motherfuckers!
Watch his legs.
Fuck!
You fucked
with my legs, man!
Pick his legs up, man.
Pick his legs up.
You motherfuckers have
got nothing better to do
Than fuck
with me, man?! Shit!
Alright,
who you working for?
Fuck, man, you know I don't
work for nobody.
I'm on disability,
man, shit!
That's bullshit. You're
cracking and you know it.
Man, I don't sell that shit
no more. You know that.
No rocks?
No rocks, man,
but I found this.
Oh, no, you don't.
Man, that isn't mine, man.
That motherfucker
Planted that shit
on me, man.
Put me in the front seat
with him,
And I bet I whup his ass!
Yeah.
Who you working for?
I told you I don't work
for nobody, man.
Why the fuck
is y'all sweating me
Any-Motherfucking-Way, man?
Where the rocks at?
I haven't got nothing on me.
I gave it up, dog.
Where the rocks at?
Open your mouth.
What is you, a doctor now?
I'm a dentist.
Open your mouth.
Lift up your tongue.
I haven't got shit.
Your partner already done
searched me. I'm straight.
Yeah, OK.
You got a pen?
You got a writing pen?
I didn't even see
the motherfucker coming.
You haven't got nothing
in there, right?
Huh?
Nothing, man!
You haven't got nothing, huh?
God!
Damn!
Now what is that?
Motherfucking
crack, man.
That's right,
jimmy crack corn.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
Oh, you're
federally fucked now.
You got crack...
And a gun.
Now you know with your record,
you can get 10 years per bullet?
Do you know that?
Man!
Now you're going to
give me a name, now.
That's 10
right there, dog.
Come on, man, you know
I am no snitch.
I know you are
no snitch.
Give me a name.
Fuck!
That's 20.
Give me a name.
That's 30 years.
You want to go to jail,
or you want to go home?
He in the county, man!
Who?
This niggah
named sandman.
That's all the fuck
I know, man. Shit!
Sandman?
Sandman!
See how easy that was?
Unhook him.
I'm sick of
this shit, man!
Want to collect the evidence?
Fuck that, man.
my niggah.
it's bob.
good afternoon, bob.
Yeah, yeah, it's Alonzo.
Hey, listen,
you got your gang book?
yeah, what do you need?
Yeah, I need
a res on a sandman.
Uh-Huh.
Yeah, with the mobsters.
He may be in custody.
OK, hold on. I'll
check it out for you.
Yeah, no problem.
I'll hold on.
That stuff
doesn't fly anymore, man,
Shoving a pen down.
I mean, what if
that guy complains?
To who?...yeah...
23130 113th street.
Kevin miller,
AKA Sandman, got it?
I like my badge.
Yeah, I got it.
I know where it is.
Out there by, uh,
imperial courts.
exactly, uh-Huh.
Right, OK.
Thanks a lot.
No problem.
We go after sandman?
We go after the sandman.
What, are you opening
a circuit city?
Nah, it's unclaimed shit
from property.
Hand it out to my C.I.S,
witnesses, victims.
Try to help them out
with their families.
Here, put this on.
Come on, let's go.
Now listen, intel says
that she lives here alone.
She got 2 female juveniles,
One possible male juvenile.
Well, if he's not here,
why are we here?
We're here
to serve this warrant.
come on, man.
We can't do that.
Hell, yeah, we can.
We the police.
We can do the fuck
we want to do.
Why don't we just
get a real warrant.
Listen, we're trying
to get shit done, all right?
Just stand over there
and don't get me killed,
All right, new guy?
Police, we got
a search warrant.
LAPD., open up.
Kevin isn't here.
He at the honor ranch.
OK, just open the door.
We don't want to
have to kick it in, now.
Kevin isn't here.
He up at the honor ranch.
Open the door, ma'am.
We don't want to have
to knock the door down.
he isn't even here.
I said Kevin
at the honor ranch,
He isn't even over here.
Right. We got
a search warrant.
Unlock the door,
please, ma'am.
damn!
Is nobody here!
Get your big ass down!
Right down! Down!
Get down!
Don't move!
Spread them out!
Anybody in the house?
is anybody in the house?
My nephew Dimitri,
He's in the bedroom.
He's 10 years old.
OK, OK.
All right, I'm going to
clear the house,
Check her for weapons.
Kitchen's clear.
Dimitri?
Yeah?
Put your hands up, son.
Put them up! Put them up!
Anybody else in there?
No.
You sure?
Yeah.
OK, just stay right there,
right there, right there.
Don't move.
Don't you move.
OK, stand up.
Stand up.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
Keep your hands where
I can see them.
Sit down and place them
on your knees.
Just sit down, OK?
We're the good guys,
you got nothing to worry about.
You just take a seat
right over there,
Next to your auntie.
Right over
there, son.
Right there.
Right over in there.
House is code 4.
I'm going to
start the search.
I want to see that warrant.
My what?
I want to see the warrant.
You... You're supposed
to give me a copy.
Yeah, well,
my partner has it.
He'll be out
with it in a second.
Where the fuck is your back-Up?
Ma'am, do me a favor,
and just be quiet
Until we're through
with our investigation.
Well, you got the gun,
don't you, boss?
That's right, I do.
Punk-Ass, bitch-Ass,
crooked-Ass cop.
OK.
You're a rookie.
Give me a break, OK.
Dimitri, how you doing
over there, huh?
You cool? You cool?
Come on.
All right,
don't worry about it,
You're cool.
Just stay cool.
Great.
Ma'am, please stay seated!
You come up here like
You pay the rent,
motherfucker.
Sit down!
And you all stink!
You got to get
liquored up
To do your business
up in here!
All right,
sit down, now!
You going to shoot me, boss?
Dimitri, close your eyes.
The punk-Ass cop
is going to shoot me!
Sit down, right now!
OK, OK, OK.
Everything is fine.
We made a mistake.
Didn't find a damn thing.
I'm very sorry. And, uh,
Thanks for your cooperation.
Let's go.
I want to see
that warrant!
What?
I want to see
that god damn warrant.
Here you go.
Let's go.
You motherfuckers!
Hey, jackers!
Listen, you better give me
My fucking money back,
motherfucker.
You are no police!
Fuck you! Give me my
fucking money back!
Hey, jackers, what y'all
sitting over there
Looking pretty for?!
Blast them fools!
Give me my money back,
motherfuckers!
You are no police!
Start, you motherfucker.
Fuck! Gun!
Shit, man, just get
the fuck out of here!
Calm the fuck down, OK?
Just stay in the car.
Yeah, motherfucker!
god damn it, man,
That was not cool, all right?
That was not cool at all,
Where you're opening fire
in the middle of a neighborhood.
Shit, man,
where was the sandman, huh?
I mean, what the hell
were you doing back there?
I was checking for
narcotics activity, you know,
Drugs, guns, baggies,
you know.
Yeah, cash!
Speak on it, son.
Man, she's screaming
about money, all right.
Oh, that bitch
is talking shit!
She's screaming about
trying to get us killed.
Whatever,
all right, man?
I'm going to be on
the 6:00 news
In an orange jumpsuit
and handcuffs
Because of you, OK, man.
With the scandals
and what not,
It is open season
on misconduct.
They will nail us
to the wall.
Pull over.
On the highway?
Shit!
What?
Listen,
You're in a privileged position
to learn a thing or two.
Keep your mouth shut
and your eyes open.
You say you're serious
About doing some good
in the real world,
Well, this is
the place to learn.
But if this kind of shit
shakes you up,
Maybe you ought to go back
to your division, you know?
Cry to the watch commander
To give you a nice job
lighting flares
Or measuring car wrecks.
You got to decide
whether you're a wolf...
Or a sheep.
Get your ink
Or...
Go give him a hand.
what are we doing
going in here, man?
We'll get killed
coming in here.
Ah, you know about
this place, huh?
Yeah, it's
the jungle, right?
That's right.
They say don't come in here
With anything
less than a platoon.
That's right.
That's the heart
of it, right here.
Jungle Damu
headquarters.
Stoners...
Yeah, a lot of
murder investigations
Lead right here.
One way in, one way out.
Thought we were going to get
something to eat?
Hey, don't ever
come up here without me,
You hear me?
I'm serious.
For your safety.
How come you got
the golden pass?
Because I treat
them fair.
They know if
they cross the line,
I'm taxing that ass.
What's that up there?
They're flipping pigeons.
They want to let everybody
know I'm here.
One time, what's up, bone?
What's up,
Alonzo?
What's happening
with you, Damu?
It's all good,
it's all good.
I just want to tell you,
man, I appreciate
What you did
for my nephew.
That's some
real shit.
For sure. For sure.
Heh.
You better call me.
Man, I'm sick
of this shit, man.
I can't stand
that motherfucker.
Who are they?
Nobody. Some
buster-Ass niggahs.
I got them all
under my thumb.
What's up, Alonzo?
All right, spider.
What's happening?
What's happening,
dog?
Alright.
Hey, what's up, girl?
Look at you.
Hi, Alonzo.
Go ahead.
All that jelly
and no toast.
Who lives here?
Just one of my lovelies.
You know, one of my dimes.
A loving touch, you know.
Don't worry about it.
Policia. Policia, senorita.
Papi.
Ah, mami.
Ooh...
New guy. Jake.
Hi.
Hi. Jake.
Nice to meet you.
Come in.
Welcome to my house.
Yeah, yeah, hook him
up with some food.
You know,
take care of him?
Yeah, of course.
Huh?
All right.
Of course.
How are you?
Good, good.
Good.
I have cable.
You watch whatever
you want, OK?
All right, thanks.
This is your house.
I'll be right back.
How you doing?
Fine.
OK.
Now this...
Is all
El Salvadorian food.
Thank you.
It looks great.
I have to go.
Yeah...all right.
Let's go.
We got a meeting
in 15 minutes.
Yeah, I just need to...
Forget that.
Let's go.
I'll see you, buddy.
Como esta, mijo?
Te portas bien?
Si.
Si?
Esta...
Creciendo, papasito.
Creciendo.
You OK?
Si.
OK.
Here, use this.
Who's here?
LAPD.'S finest.
Don't speak unless
you're spoken to.
Come on.
Good to see you, gents.
That's my new guy.
He works on my squad.
Jake Hoyt.
Captain Lou Jacobs.
You ever need to talk
to the feds,
You talk to him first.
This is a good man.
He can take
your back for you.
Pleased
to meet you, sir.
Stan Gursky over here...
He runs
the DA. Shooting team.
You think about him
before you pull the trigger,
Because if you're wrong,
He'll snatch your fucking
nuts out, use them for dice.
Detective
Doug Rosselli right here...
Handles high-Dollar
theft cases
For the French
poodle crowd.
You know,
if you lose a Picasso,
He'll find it for you
or die trying.
He's a good man.
Pleased to meet you.
Good man.
Should I...
Boom. Shoo.
Get yourself a baseball
steak or something.
All right, gents.
I don't know why
I'm meeting you.
I don't talk
to dead men.
I am not dead yet.
Fucking prick.
Excuse me.
Why the long face,
Doug, huh?
Feds seize your house
or something?
Fuck yourself,
Alonzo.
tell him the story.
Come on,
tell the story.
Oh, you think it's
so funny, you tell it.
No, no. It's your story.
You tell it.
Asshole.
all right,
all right, all right.
There's this...
serial burglar, and, uh,
Chasing him
for 12 months.
A real slickster,
gave up nothing.
Captain's riding my ass
the entire time.
Sentencing was today.
judge is female.
That's right.
Landers.
Yeah, I know Landers.
She's a sharp lady.
No?
so before
the hearing,
Guy gets hold of
some peanut butter,
Packs his ass crack
with it...
What?
Then he's standing tall
before the bench,
And he's waiting
to give his statement.
So he shoves
his hand down his pants,
Comes out with a gob
of extra-Chunky Jif.
Bailiffs won't
come near him.
Now he's... Now he's looking
the judge right in the eyes
And licks his fingers clean.
Holy shit.
So the judge says, uh,
"Oh, this poor man's insane.
He can't go to prison."
Orders him to psychiatric.
She fell for it.
Yeah. That's because
she's so fucking smart.
Time she found out
it was sandwich spread,
The order was signed,
the guy's been transferred.
Proceedings closed.
Yeah, closed.
That prick will do 6 months
in the puzzle factory,
Then they'll call him normal
and let him loose.
Never, ever do
a day in prison.
Yeah, give him
credit, though.
Shit, he worked
the system,
Deserves
his freedom.
Yeah? Think so?
Or not.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to find
this guy on the street...
And I'm going to do him.
You better take his
bullets from him, Stan.
Shit.
ahh...
Alonzo...
Heard you had an expensive
weekend in Vegas.
How did you ever
screw up so bad?
Nothing. It's nothing.
Forget it.
You know, I didn't know.
It's not my town.
I'm not omniscient.
The Russians don't
care if you have a badge.
They'll whack you.
You ought to hop
a jet out of here.
Why?
It's an easy fix.
How?
I'll just cash
in an account.
oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Whose?
One of my old ones.
My first one.
It's not a problem.
Look, the guy's
A high-Security risk
anyway.
If I'm not around,
who's going to keep him
Off the radar, you?
I'm just taxing him,
that's all.
OK?
Well, it's your call.
I do not want you
to dick this up.
I do not want to see you
on the front page
Like those other assholes.
Yeah, I understand.
Who's driving?
Uh, me.
Grey Mercedes.
OK.
Get the car.
All right. All right.
Uh, what, the black
Monte Carlo there
With the back windows
shot out.
hey, yeah, it's me.
Listen, we got
the green light.
Right. That's right.
I want you to fax
a copy of the warrant
To the clerk,
get her to get the judge
To sign it,
and I want you and Paul
To bring it to me
at location one.
You got that? Now,
get a hold of Jeff,
Tell him to pick up
some tools...
Picks and shovels.
Make sure he signs them
out from maintenance.
That's right. Copy?
That's right.
All right, hurry up.
Later.
So how much cash
was in that jacket?
40 gs.
What's...
What's that for?
You really want to know?
Yeah, I really
want to know.
Yeah...
There's nothing free
in this world, Jake.
Not even
arrest warrants.
Shit, man.
I didn't want to know.
Yo, homes. Check
this motherfucker out.
Nice suit, mark.
beautiful suit.
yeah,
fuck you guys.
All right.
Nice, nice, nice.
What's up, Alonzo?
You got the picks
and shovels?
They're in the truck.
You're going to
dig a ditch?
No, you are.
That's a nice suit
you got on there.
that's
what I said.
What up, killer?
I can't call it.
What's up with you?
I've been hearing
a lot of shit
Out here on these streets,
man. You all right?
It's all good. I talked
to the 3 wise men.
Everything is lovely.
Shit, if you say
we can get away with it,
I'm with you.
Know what I'm saying?
Who the fuck is this?
Jake Hoyt. It's
my first day in the unit.
I'm from valley patrol.
You a long way
from Starbucks, homey.
Now, why the fuck
is he in on this?
Got to get his cherry
popped sometime.
Look, man, stay the fuck
out of my way, all right?
It's just for
the big dogs. Feel me?
Here it is, dog.
It's all good and legit.
Signed by the judge, OK?
Thanks to the sandman.
Now listen up.
Safety is first.
He gives us shit... Boom,
we're giving him lead.
Let's do this right
so we can all go home
And do the wife
or the girlfriend thing,
All right?
Let's suit up, ladies.
Time to punch in.
Freeze up!
Down on the floor!
Get down, motherfucker!
What are you clowns
doing here?
hey, new guy,
watch him.
If he moves,
cap his ass!
Yeah, I'm on him.
Do you know what
you're doing, son?
drop what's in
your hands before zero.
5...
4, 3, 2...
boom.
Give me a reason.
Alonzo's going to have
y'all's ass.
What's up, roger?
What's going down, brother?
Oh, it's all good, baby.
It's all good.
That's for you.
What am I supposed to do
with this, wipe my ass?
Bad news, dog.
You don't mind
if I have some of
Your $300-A-Glass shit
there, will you?
Please.
Had lunch with
the wise men today.
They said you got
to render unto Caesar.
Fucking vampires
want my pension?
Nah, it's nothing
like that.
Ahh...
Hmm.
They just want to tax
you a little bit.
You know,
they got their boats
And mistresses
and, you know,
House payments.
Nothing I can do
about it, you know?
They're
making me do it.
I'm just a lowly
civil servant.
ahh,
you're their bitch.
What happens to me?
I got your back, bro.
I promised you
you'd never have to
Go back to prison.
You aren't even going to
miss what we take.
I'm sorry. Orders
is orders, dog.
No you aren't, cop.
Tim, Jeff, Jake,
We're going to work
in the kitchen.
Grab the tools.
Give me the bitch.
You guys hold him down.
Who's paying
for my floor?
The city.
Right here.
Ow!
That's it. That's
what I'm talking about.
What's in here, coke?
Don't worry about it.
You'll see.
Hey, grab that hammer
right there.
Knock this lock off.
Yeah. 1, 2...
Shit...
That's a quarter million
dollars you holding
Right there
in your hand.
Over 4 million
in here.
First day
on the job,
You hit
a $3 million seizure.
Wait, you said 4.
Ah, taxation without
representation, brother.
Nothing is free
in this world,
You lucky
first-Day motherfucker.
Buy your wife
a minivan with that.
Put the kids
through college.
Give me that bag.
No, you know.
I mean, the only checks
I cash say, uh,
"LAPD." On them, right?
Somebody didn't sleep
through ethics, did they?
what's the matter?
You don't want
a piece of this, huh?
Well, I...
No, right?
Not like this.
I mean...no.
No?
right, right, OK.
First time.
You're not comfortable.
I'll hold it
for you, OK?
What about you,
are you comfortable?
Oh, I'm comfortable.
How's
your comfort level?
I'm very comfortable.
come on,
let's wrap this up.
Uh, I...
Don't touch a thing.
Evidence.
That's it.
Alonzo, what are those
assholes thinking?
That I'm really
going to stand still
And let them
horsefuck me?
Could put you
out of your misery.
Hey, Jake, here.
Hey, come sit down.
Sit down. Right here.
I'll tell you a secret.
When you kill
someone on duty...
They have
to be your slave...
In the afterlife.
there you go.
Start an entourage.
What, you want me
to shoot him?
Yeah.
Come on, kid.
Do me a favor.
Come on.
Do yourself a favor.
Hit him.
Are you serious?
Hey, close the blinds.
All right, I'll...
I'll shoot him.
Go.
Pow!
Boom!
Shoot him.
No, man. I'm...
Youngsters
these days, huh?
You're not
going to shoot him?
No, man.
All right,
Give it to me.
Rookies.
Yeah, you want
to get shit done,
You got to get it
done yourself.
Holy shit!
Come on, breathe.
Breathe. There you go.
Just let it go.
Breathe, dog.
Yeah, he's finished.
Where's the stinger?
It's right here.
All right, Jeff.
You took fire coming
through the door.
I need
some time off, but...
OK, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, OK?
Watch the shades.
All right.
OK.
All right, you ready?
Kiss me, baby.
One...
Oh!
yeah?
You all right?
Yeah.
I got to give you
one more, though.
Do it.
Ah, fuck!
All right, listen.
It's not what you know,
It's what you can prove.
OK, here's the scenario.
Mark and Paul,
you kicked the door.
Jeff's
the first one through.
Roger opens fire...
Hits Jeff twice, right?
Fuck.
What's the matter,
one go through?
Shit!
Yeah, man.
You shot him.
You fucking
shot me, man!
All right, all right.
You'll get a medal.
Don't worry about it.
Get me an ambulance!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
You want to go to jail
or you want to go home?
All right, here's
the scenario, all right?
Let me quarterback
this thing.
Mark, Paul,
you kicked the door in.
Jeff's
the first one through.
Roger opens fire...
Bang, bang.
Hits Jeff twice.
Our new guy, Hoyt,
He's in second,
Drops roger with
some fine shotgun work.
Who shot roger?
New guy...
Came in spraying.
Paul?
Boot shot him.
What did
you guys see?
Hoyt blasted him.
Yeah, fuck Hoyt, OK?
Ambulance time.
Done.
Paul, call them up.
11-49-9-9-8.
Shots fired.
Officer down.
Repeat, officer down.
5951 Baxter street.
Congratulations, son.
You're going to get a medal
of valor for this.
I didn't shoot him.
A roomful of cops
said you did.
But I didn't.
You did.
A Los Angles
police department
Narcotics officer
was killed today
Serving a high-Risk
warrant in echo park.
Give me the bitch.
LAPD. Spokesperson
Said the officer
Is survived...
By his wife
and infant child.
Shit gets deeper.
You get the picture?
Yeah, I got the picture.
Hey, hey, hey!
That is the second time
you pointed a gun at me!
There will not
be a third.
God damn, boy!
That's what I'm
talking about, Jake.
My niggah. Are you all
watching this? That's it.
It'd be my pleasure to put
a hydra shock in that melon.
Hey, hey, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
no, but I'm
going to be cool.
Now drop
the fucking gun now!
You want to shoot me,
Paul, go ahead,
But I'm taking
him with me.
I'm going,
Alonzo.
This motherfucker is
a fed, man.
No, he is no fed.
He's just a choir boy
With a heart that got
the drop on all you fools.
Listen, everybody just
take a deep breath,
And just diffuse this thing.
You hear me, Jake?
You can't pull
this shit on me, man.
I didn't
sign up for this.
OK, OK.
I know you're angry.
Everybody,
just put your guns down.
Hell, no.
no, no, no, no...
Choir boy first.
Hey, listen to me.
Put the guns down!
That's an order.
Put them down!
Use your ears
and you hear me, Jake.
Sometime we got to take
this shit all the way.
It's not like we do this
every day, all right?
It's just the nature
of the business.
Now, no one will
ever ask you again
To pull the trigger if you
don't want to, all right?
Hey, mark, where are
you transferring to?
S.I.S.
Detective.
You give me 18 months,
I give you a career.
We make the big
seizures, Jake.
We make
the big arrests.
But if you're
in my unit,
You got to be in it
all the way
Or not at all,
you understand me?
I mean, I thought
you were man enough
To handle this shit.
I guess I was wrong.
5 proven,
decorated officers
Says that you're
the shooter, OK?
The investigators
are going to want to pull...
... a tube of your blood
to check for intoxicants.
What are they going to find,
Jake? Do the math.
You been smoking P.C.P.
All day, haven't you?
Huh? Remember?
You've been
planning this all day.
I've been planning it
all week, son.
You talk that crazy shit,
I'll make sure your blood
Gets to the lab.
You want to walk your little
baby nuts around the block,
You won't make it
to the corner,
But if you're cool...
If you're cool...
You're a hero.
You're a virgin shooter
above suspicion.
Alonzo,
there's 2 shots left
In that other stinger.
We need to just kill
your boy right now,
And say roger got him
coming through the door.
No, we are
killing nobody.
This is a good man
right here.
He's got the magic eye.
I can feel it.
Just had a little
freak out, that's all.
We all been there.
No, I say he's cool.
And I say nobody is
going to hurt him.
But you do have
a decision to make, Jake.
because in about
10 seconds,
This place is going to be
overrun with blue suits.
So why don't you
please go outside,
Clear your head...
Or shoot me.
hey, Paul.
You're dead,
motherfucker!
You hear me?
You're fucking dead!
Yeah.
Ha, that's right.
Well, lay off that rice.
All right.
Yeah, just make sure that
bathtub is clean, homey.
All right?
All right. Later.
You all right?
It behooves you
not to dick around
On this one.
Justifiable homicide
in the line of duty, OK?
Now what happened...
What happened was murder...
And armed robbery.
Oh, wait. We... We had badges,
so it's different?
Oh, son, open your eyes.
Can't you see? Huh?
That man was your friend,
And you killed him
like a fly.
come on.
My friend, huh?
Yeah.
Tell me why.
Because he knows
my first name?
Son, this is the game.
I'm playing his ass.
That's my job.
That's your job.
Roger sold dope to kids.
The world is a better
place without him.
Hey, this man was
the biggest major violator
In Los Angles.
I watched that cocksucker
operate with impunity
For over 10 years,
and now I got him.
This shit is chess.
It isn't checkers.
What you think we going to do?
We going to... We going to roll up
in a black-And-White, huh?
Slap the cuffs on him.
"You're under arrest."
That's a high roller, dog.
Take the money.
Hey, man, I already told you,
I'm not going to take that.
OK, don't. Just burn it,
barbecue it,
Fish fry it.
I don't give a fuck,
But the boys will
feel better about it.
Fuck their feelings.
Jake, you're
not making them feel
Like you're
part of the team.
The team?
You guys are fucking insane.
All right.
I'll go back to the valley.
I'll cut parking tickets,
you know?
God.
It... It can't be like this.
It is this way, man.
I'm sorry I exposed you
to it, but it is.
It's ugly,
but it's necessary.
I became a cop
to put away drug dealers,
The poisoners, the criminals,
not to be one.
You sound just like me,
And I know what
you're going through.
I know what
you're feeling.
You're scared.
I'm not scared.
Yes, you are.
You're terrified.
Everybody goes through
that the first time.
I went through it.
The sooner you can match
what's in your head
With what's going on
in the real world,
The better
you're going to feel.
In this business,
You got to have
a little dirt on you
For anybody
to trust you,
And when all this
is behind you,
There's going to be
a whole other world
That opens up for you.
I walk a higher path, son.
I can give you the keys
to all the doors.
What are you talking about?
My guys are pretty good,
but they're not leaders.
They're clowns.
You're a leader.
You want my job?
You got it.
You want to lock up
poisoners?
This is the best place
to do it.
But you got to just,
you know, take your time.
You make detective.
You play the game.
You grow wise, and then
you can change things,
But you got to change them
from the inside, son.
Let's go downtown
to the station.
You talk to my guy Stan,
And he'll walk you through
What you got to say
to the DA. Guys, OK?
OK.
What the hell we doing now?
An informant of mine is
up in chino.
I promised I'd take care
of his family for him.
I bring them some food,
you know, stuff like that.
Got to help out the family.
Believe it or not,
I do try to do some
good in the community.
It was, like,
right there, right?
Just right there.
What's up, dog?
You know where
you're at, fool?
What the fuck
you looking at?
All right.
What's up, punk?
hey, we got some
things for the family.
Kitchen's this way.
we're on every day.
every day?
OK, tell us a little bit
about that touring thing
With divas of dance 2000.
That sounds exciting.
put the shit
on the counter.
where's the head?
right through.
so you're happy?
oh, yes!
Now for example...
I'm going to go
to the head, OK?
I'm going to be 2 seconds.
We rolling.
Hey, that's nice, homes.
Let me
get the CD player, eh?
You get the blender.
CD player's mine.
Dreamer, get
your ass in here!
Count that shit
in the bedroom, huh?
Thanks a lot, eh. I was
doing stuff, you know?
Better learn how to count,
fucking math whiz.
yeah.
You looked at them.
No, I didn't. Now what?
You calling me a fucking
cheater, Tse, or what?
Deal again, huh, sniper.
Dama.
You play cards, cop?
Uh, nah, not really.
Hey, you want a beer, homes?
Something to drink?
Have a cold one.
Eh, no, thanks.
I'm good.
come on,
sit down, eh,
Play a card game
with us.
don't be rude, Tse.
You're the invited guest.
Why don't you sit down
and play one hand?
There you go.
Don't sweat it, judo.
We aren't
playing for money.
Nah. It's just we
got to roll in a second.
Alonzo's taking a shit.
Go ahead. Take a seat.
All right,
I'll play one hand.
What do you guys got
going on here, 5 card draw?
yeah,
jokers are wild.
Jokers wild.
Hey, so, um, why don't you
tell us something, homes.
How long you been a pig?
I'm... My bad, my bad.
I meant... I meant...
I meant a police officer.
That's what I meant.
I been a pig
for 19 months.
Is that right?
That's right.
And you like it or what?
I should have been
a fireman.
I need one more.
What you got, dog?
3 of a kind, 3 jacks.
Ahh, chingo.
Didn't get shit.
Pujo, baby! Whoo!
2 pair!
What the fuck are
you doing, sniper?
Porca won.
Smiley, homes,
I got 2 pair, eh!
3 of a kind
beats 2 pair,
You fucking dumb truck.
Serio?
serios, Tse.
Hey, you're fucking
stupid, Tse.
Why don't you
take your medication
Or something, homes.
Seriously, eh.
I know I'm number one.
See why we don't
play for money, homes?
because of this Vato, eh.
Hey, that's nice, eh.
Let me see your Cohete there.
What?
Your gun, homes,
underneath your shirt.
Let him see it.
no, that's
all right, man.
Come on, man. What is it,
like, a .380 stainless?
9 millimeter Beretta.
Like... Like this one here?
Just like that one.
is that right?
But see, here's where
the problem comes into play.
I seen this one.
I want to see yours.
Come on, Tse. I am
going to shoot nobody.
Ha ha, qu? No.
Come on, homes.
Let me check it out, eh?
Qu? No.
Whoo! Damn!
You learn that
in the academy or what?
yeah, man.
It's a neat little trick.
This is nice, homes.
Nice right here.
Fuck Vato up with this,
huh, qu? No?
Hell, yeah, homes.
You know what you do
is you aim...
Kind of like that.
Ahh, ha ha!
I just playing
with you, dog.
Yeah, right. I got to go.
Yo, Alonzo!
Let me see that.
kick back
and party, eh?
There is nothing
out there for you.
What are you
talking about?
hey, white boy...
You ask me, homes...
But that's just,
of course, if you ask...
I think Alonzo played you
for a fool, Tse.
big time, homes.
Wait, where you going?
Where you going? Huh?
It's your deal.
it's all there.
sure?
If you don't believe me,
you can count it yourself.
Alonzo pulled off
a miracle, eh?
Times are tight.
Scared up a lot of cash.
Who did he jack, homes?
I don't know.
He jacked roger.
Blasted
the fool, huh?
Alonzo, homes, I think
he's a low-Down, dirty,
Ruthless Vato, eh,
but I like that, homes.
I like that.
no, that's why I
never shake his hand, homes.
He don't respect nada.
You know what
the money's for?
Alonzo,
he's a hothead.
Last week in Vegas,
Some Russian
starts talking shit,
And Alonzo,
he just snapped.
Beat his ass to death.
Well, turns out
that Russian...
He's a somebody.
Now, Alonzo...
He's into the Russians
for a million.
How do you know that?
They gave Alonzo
till tonight to pay up,
But his name's still
on their list, huh?
Nobody thought he could
get cash that big.
Good thing he got
his blood money,
because there's
a crew on standby.
If he don't turn up
downtown with the cash
By midnight, and
not a minute after...
Whew, your Vato...
He's dead.
Hey, pig, you ever had
your shit pushed in?
Your shit pushed in?
Simple question.
Nah?
No.
I had my shit pushed in.
Yeah, man, I had my shit
pushed in, bro...
Big time!
smiley?
Sure, I'm always getting
love from the homeys.
hit them!
Damn, you guys
fucked him up, eh?
Get the girls next door.
Dreamer, get the fuck
out of here!
Oh!
You fucked up.
You're under arrest,
bitch...
For being a judo, cop,
And dogging me
in the mouth
In my own pad.
You got the right
to be bitch-Slapped,
You little motherfucker!
Aah!
Drag his ass in the tub.
Motherfucker!
Come on,
raid his ass!
Ahh, shit!
God!
Aah!
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Aah! Aah! Help!
Help! Help! Help!
Aah. Aah. Shit.
Aah!
do it, eh?
close the door.
It's going to be loud.
Hey, smiley.
Back up, Tse out of.
Let me get
his money first, OK?
Hold off, Tse.
Come on. Hurry up.
Hey, smiley.
You going to trip out, homes.
Is that your little
cousin or what, eh?
Where would you get this?
Oh, fuck! I found it!
Alonzo
give it to you?
I found it!
Where?
I found it
in MacArthur park!
where?
MacArthur park.
No, homes.
You fucked up.
Hey, wait up, Tse out of.
I can't even see, homes.
aah! Please!
shut the fuck up!
If you're religious,
Go ahead and get in
your last prayer.
Listen to me, man.
Listen to me.
That girl was being raped,
all right?
I saw these
2 fucking drug addicts
Attacking her,
and I stopped them, man!
What?
I swear to god!
I stopped them!
You're lying to me.
I'm not lying!
You're lying to me!
I swear to god!
She was being raped!
All right,
And I stopped them!
Oh, please, man!
I got a little kid.
Shut the fuck up, faggot!
Blast his ass, homes.
I have a little girl!
do it, eh.
I'm going to get to the bottom
of your bullshit.
She's my cousin, homes.
She's a civilian.
Is not right involving her.
You just fucked up.
You're lying to me,
I'm going to blow
your fucking balls off.
hello.
Hey, what's up, Letty?
What you doing?
Hey, smiley.
Just, uh, doing homework.
You want to talk
to Tony?
Oh, no, no. I want
to talk to you.
Uh, you go
to school today?
Yep...yep.
All day.
You didn't ditch?
No. No. I want to
every class. Why?
I heard different.
nuh-Uh.
Cops talk to you today?
Um...
No...no.
All right, Letty,
tell me what happened,
OK? Don't bullshit me.
Um, all right.
I got jumped by
these 2 crackheads today.
You got jumped, huh?
Well, I think
they wanted to, like,
Rape me or something.
I don't know.
I mean, he just slapped me
around and everything,
But nothing happened, OK,
because this cop came.
I mean, he came
out of nowhere,
And they almost
killed him, though,
But he kicked
their asses like that.
This cop,
what would he look like?
Um, he was a white boy,
And he looked
real young, too.
You sure you OK?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Nothing happened.
Hey, Letty.
Yeah.
We're going to talk more
about this later.
OK.
All right.
What's up? What happened?
Aren't you going to blast him
or what, homes?
Vato was telling
the truth.
Life's a trip,
qu? No?
This is some
trippy-Ass shit, homes.
Hey.
Thanks for getting
my cousin's back, huh?
Here, put this
on your head.
You'll mess up my floor.
You know this shit
was just business, right?
right?
Right.
what you doing
on the block, rookie?
You know you don't
belong around here.
what's up?
must be lost, motherfucker.
You got business here,
rookie?
I'm here for Alonzo.
Hey. Is your dad home?
In the bedroom.
He's in the bedroom?
All right, all right.
You want to
open up the door?
OK.
Thanks. You watching TV?
Anything good on?
Do you want me
to call my mom?
No, I don't.
I'll tell you what I want.
I want you to find
a good hiding spot.
Do you have a favorite one,
a favorite place to hide?
The closet.
Right here in the closet?
That's perfect.
OK, open up the closet.
All right. Good, good.
Can you sit down in there?
All right. Now stay in here.
Be very quiet.
I'll be right back.
All right?
it's all good, baby.
all right.
You, against the wall.
Move real slow.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
I want you to put
that money in that bag,
Take your weapons
And place them inside
that pillowcase right there.
Congratulations, son.
You made it.
You passed the test.
You're a narc. You're in.
Please, put the gun down
Before you give my girl
a heart attack here.
Put the gun down.
I said take the money
and put it in that bag,
Take your weapons
And place them
inside that pillowcase.
You can fuck
your appointment
With the Russians.
You're not
going to make it.
Ohh, OK.
OK. Hand me
the pillowcase, baby.
Baby! Hand me
the pillowcase.
So you're going to
hook me and book me, huh?
You're the one that was
smoking the dust, Jake,
You're the one that
ran out like a maniac,
And you're the one
that shot roger.
Here you go.
And how about
the one on your ankle?
You want the one
in my back pocket, too?
Yeah, I would.
You got one problem,
though, Jake.
You got no witnesses.
Who're your fucking
witnesses, huh?
Roger? Smiley?
You think my troops
are going to help you?
It's not what you know.
It's what you can prove.
Here.
What can you prove, huh?
Nothing. Where's
your evidence, huh?
It's right there.
Oh, shit.
aw,
it's on now, Jake.
Don't move.
Where you at, Jake?
Damn.
Come on out, dog!
Ah! I see you.
Oh, shit.
Ha ha ha ha.
you know,
I'm surgical
With this bitch, Jake.
How you want it, dog,
huh?
Closed casket?
You remember that fool
in the wheelchair?
How you think
he got there?
mommy.
Alonzito!
You see what I see, Jake?
Officer Hoyt.
Job number one:
preserve life.
There's my son.
Don't hurt him.
We walking out of here
together, mijo.
no.
no, mijo,
es El cucuy.
no! Alonzito!
Alonzito!
You all right?
I want my mommy.
I know. I know.
I know.
Just sit tight,
all right?
It's going to be
all right.
Ohh, god!
All right, let me see
your hands. Where is he?
The window.
Come on, come on, come on!
Get your kid and stay down.
Alonzito!
Jesus.
Aah!
Uhh! Aah!
Ohh!
hey, man, dude's over
here tripping, in blood?
It's no fun when the rabbit
has the gun, is it?
My niggah.
Hey...
First Damu puts one
in his head...
I make you a rich man.
Come on, now...
who want to get paid?
Who want to get paid?!
they're not like you.
You know what
I learned today?
I'm not like you.
That's good, Jake.
I'm glad to hear that.
Good.
What now?
Huh?
What you going to do?
You going to shoot me?
You going to bust your cherry
killing a cop?
There it is, Jake.
Hit me.
You have never killed
nobody before, have you?
It isn't like
stepping on ants, Jake.
Takes a man to kill.
You man enough
to kill, Jake?
Hit me right there.
Kill me, Jake.
Kill me.
Hit me. Hit me.
You can't do it.
Somebody drop
this fool for me.
You got us
twisted, homey.
You got to put your own work
in around here.
Alright.
It's like that, bone?
It's like that.
Player to player...
Pimp to pimp.
I don't believe
you shoot me, niggah.
Don't do it.
Nah, I don't believe you
got it in you, Jake.
Ah, shit.
I'm going to get
that gun...
And then I'm going to
get that money.
And you aren't going to do
a damn thing
because you aren't going to
shoot no cop in the back,
Are you?
Don't do it.
You know what
They give you
for that?
The gas chamber.
You know what the gas
chamber smells like?
Pine oil.
That's where
you headed, boy...
To pine oil heaven.
I'm going to get that gun,
And then I'm going to
get that money.
I don't believe you
got it in you, Jake.
I'm going to go get it
right now.
Aah!
Oh!
Shit!
Aaahhhh...
You motherfucker!
The next one
will kill you.
Ohhh! Son of a bitch!
You shot me in the ass!
OK. Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait. OK. OK.
OK. All right, listen.
Come on, Jake,
I need the money.
Give me the money, Jake.
Give me the money, please,
Jake. Give me that money!
It's not going to happen.
Oh, you... You
going to jack me now?
You going to take my own
money from me? Huh?
I told you,
that's my evidence.
You want to go to jail
or you want to go home?
I want to go home, Jake.
Come on. Give me the money
and let me go home.
Yeah. You want
to go home?
Yeah, let me
go home, Jake.
Come on, give me the money
and let me go home.
Give me the money
Come on, Jake.
That's right,
come on, Jake.
You don't deserve this.
OK.
OK, you
motherfucker.
Jake.
Go ahead
and bounce, homey.
Get up out of here.
We got your back.
what?
It's like that.
oh, no,
you didn't.
Wait a minute.
No, you di...
Hey! Hey, Jake!
Hey!
Jake!
Come back here!
You disloyal,
Fool-Ass,
bitch-Made punk.
Jake!
I need my money!
Oh, you motherfuckers.
Ha ha ha! OK.
All right.
I'm putting cases
on all you bitches.
Huh? You think you
can do this shit?
Jake!
You think you
can do this to me?!
You motherfuckers will
be playing basketball
In pelican bay when
I get finished with you!
Shoe program, niggah!
23-Hour lock down!
I'm the man
up in this place!
You'll never see
the light of day!
Who the fuck do you think
you fucking with?!
I'm the police!
I run shit here!
You just live here!
Yeah, that's right!
You better walk away!
Go on, walk away,
because I'm going to burn
This motherfucker down!
King Kong
has not got shit on me!
that's all right.
That's all right.
Shit. I don't fuck...
I'm winning anyway.
I'm winning.
I'm winning
any motherfucking way.
I can't lose.
Shit. You can shoot me...
But you can't kill me.
Shit.
Ha!
Oh, what a day.
Ha ha!
What a motherfucking day.
Heh. Heh.
Unh!
A Los Angles
police department
Narcotics officer
was killed today
Serving a high-Risk warrant
near LAX.
An LAPD. Spokesperson
said officer Alonzo Harris
Was survived by his wife
and 4 sons.
the highly decorated officer,
A 13-Year LAPD. Veteran...
Uh-Huh.
We wolves, baby.
We wolves.
Fire!
Number one.