How did those soldiers ever manage
to dig out these tunnels?
Let's get a rotation in here.
Hey, I found something!
Hanako...
We soldiers dig.
We dig all day.
This is the hole that we will fight...
and die in.
Hanako...
am I digging my own grave?
Today, I head for
the post where my men await.
I am determined to serve
and give my life for my country.
I believe I have organized
everything at home...
but I am sorry I wasn't able to attend
to the kitchen floor before I left.
I had all the intention...
but had to leave
without having the time...
and I am still worried about it.
So make sure to have
Taro take care of it promptly.
Damn this island!
The Americans can have it.
Nothing grows here.
It smells. It's hot. There are too many
damn bugs, and there's no water.
This island is part
of Japan's sacred homeland.
There's nothing sacred about this island.
Saigo.
We should just give the island
to the Americans...
and then we can go home.
Saigo!
What did you say, soldier?
I said if we beat the Americans,
then we can go home.
You there, is that what he said?
Yes, sir.
I'm Kuribayashi.
Welcome, General.
I am Admiral Ohsugi.
How long have you been
waiting here for me?
Three hours, sir.
Sorry to hear that.
They wouldn't allow me to wire my arrival
after what happened to Admiral Yamamoto.
I understand, sir.
This is my aide, Lieutenant Fujita.
What's the matter, Admiral?
You don't look very well.
It's nothing, sir. The water
doesn't agree with me here.
Sorry to hear that.
This way to your quarters.
Admiral, I want to make a round
of the island first.
Shall I fetch a vehicle?
No, let's walk.
Walking is good for the health.
It might be just what you need, Ohsugi.
So that's Suribachi.
You unpatriotic...
no-good peasants!
Hey, stop it!
Stand up!
What are you doing?
These soldiers...
were conspiring
with unpatriotic words, sir.
I see.
And, Captain, do you have
such an excess of soldiers...
that you could put two
of them out of commission?
No, sir.
Then stop beating them.
Deny their lunch rations instead.
A good captain uses his brain,
not just his whip.
What is all this?
All this?
Trenches, sir.
Why are the men digging trenches here?
This is where the Americans
are expected to land.
Have them stop immediately.
But, General...
And, Captain...
make sure these men get proper breaks.
They look like they're from Mars.
Stop digging!
Just as well.
My stomach has been
bothering me anyway.
A toast to General Kuribayashi...
a fine commander.
Better than sake!
I heard he lived in America.
Maybe that's why he
doesn't want us digging trenches.
Maybe he likes Americans.
No, stupid.
He studied the Americans.
So now he knows how to beat them.
I heard from someone in the 204th...
that another general was
supposed to command the island...
but he didn't want the job.
So Premier Tojo gave it
to Kuribayashi instead.
Nozaki, you hear a lot of things...
but your ears are full of wax!
Anyway, you can't trust anyone
from the 204th.
They're part of the Navy.
I think this Kuribayashi
must be a superb general.
Look...
we're not digging those damn trenches
in the sand anymore, are we?
This heat is more than I had anticipated.
This island is bigger than I thought.
I'm exhausted.
Ito, reporting for duty.
Thank you for coming right away.
How much air force
do we have available?
41 Zekes and 13 bombers, sir.
Is that all?
In order to support Saipan,
we lost 66 planes a few days ago.
We will have to rely on support
from the Combined Fleet then.
Is this the current defense plan?
And what about the Army troops?
Where will they be stationed?
I don't know exactly.
They are under independent
command of Colonel Adachi.
You have not coordinated
your plans with the Army?
According to Navy rules,
until the enemy lands...
This is a real war!
You are aware of that, aren't you?
This will not work.
You are concentrating all
your efforts on the beaches.
- Move the artillery to higher ground.
- But, sir, we just had them...
moved down to the beaches.
Well, move them back.
Coordinate with the Army
and have them start immediately.
Fortifications at Suribachi are the priority.
I'm going to walk some more.
- It's pitch black out there, sir.
- I know.
This one is trouble.
Army commanders usually are, sir.
Another letter?
You know that the mail only goes out
when there's a boat available?
I have a lot of family.
Then how come all your letters
are addressed to your wife?
Nosey!
Here, let me do you a favor.
Otherwise, your letters
will never make it through.
Hey, what are you doing?
I used to work at the censorship office
in Tokyo before I was transferred.
You mean demoted.
"To Hanako: We soldiers dig.
We dig all day."
No, no, no. This will never pass.
Give me that back!
There. You'll thank me
for this later, Saigo.
Next!
Good!
Are you blind?
Can't you see the target?
Even my six-year-old could
shoot better than you do.
Do it again!
You're an embarrassment!
You call yourself an lmperial soldier?
Tonight you will clean the boots
of your entire troop.
Go to the rear!
They should learn to clean their guns
properly, rather than their boots.
What are those tanks doing here?
Those are out of commission, sir.
They are waiting for parts.
- For how long?
- About a month, sir.
Taro, America is filled with cars.
I have to be very careful
when I cross the street...
there are so many cars everywhere.
Taro, are you behaving yourself
and listening to your mother?
I miss you.
These civilians need to be
evacuated as soon as possible.
Yes, sir.
Hanako...
we have a celebrity here.
Baron Nishi, the Olympic gold medalist
in horse jumping.
He will lead the 26th tank regiment...
and has just arrived from Tokyo.
Nishi is very handsome, and
there are rumors of his womanizing skills.
But there are no women
left on the island to woo.
Lieutenant Colonel Nishi!
You brought your horse.
From Chichi Jima.
I used to be a cavalryman myself,
you know.
Of course, I know.
I've been looking forward
to serving under you.
One who understands horses
the way I do.
When we used to ride horses
through the battlefield...
those were the good old days...
not like these mechanized contraptions.
I could send for another horse...
and we could ride together.
I'm afraid my riding days are over.
But tell me about this famous horse
of yours that you won the Olympics with.
My stallion, Uranus.
Oh, yes, this horse has a fine back.
I bought him in Italy.
They were happy to get rid of him.
He was such a wild horse.
No one could tame the beast,
but I told them...
such a headstrong horse...
is a perfect match for me.
Come dine with me tonight.
I feel like having a drink.
I think that can be arranged.
How did you manage to get
the Johnnie Walker?
I drank some already.
I'm sorry. This is all we have.
That's fine, as long as we have this.
What is this empty plate?
I have told our cook that all officers will
have the same rations and food as our men.
I'm sorry, but serving three dishes
is regulation.
Oh, but of course we have the right to be
served more than three dishes per meal.
You're absolutely right.
When you think about it...
it is regrettable that most of the
Combined Fleet was destroyed.
We still have some battleships left...
but we have very little striking power
from the air or sea.
Nishi, what do you mean?
So you have not heard about
the Mariana battle?
Admiral Ozawa's carrier and boat planes
were destroyed.
The lmperial headquarters...
is deceiving not just the people,
but us as well.
If you want my honest opinion, General...
the best thing to do...
would be to sink the island
to the bottom of the sea.
And yet, you still came?
Well...
I figured your men were going to need
all the tanks that I could bring.
This must be it.
Yes, the enemy must land here.
Run!
Like you were one of the Americans!
Go on! Which direction would you take?
Hey...
I think your general has gone mad.
Look at the gun he has.
He probably took it
from a dead American.
Maybe.
Break time is over.
Back to work!
Are you all right, Kashiwara?
You look pale.
I'm fine. It's just the damn water.
But... l... really... need to go.
There will be a major change
in our strategy.
We will dig caves in the Motoyama,
Higashiyama, and Suribachi-yama areas.
We will build these underground
fortifications, and fight to the end.
- What about the beach defenses, sir?
- Not needed.
But, sir, the beach trenches
are our first line of defense.
Without the beach trenches,
how do you expect us to win?
Hayashi, do you know how many cars
America produces in a year?
Five million.
The Americans' technological advancements
cannot be underestimated.
They will cross the beaches eventually.
If we waste our soldiers there,
there is no hope for victory.
It is inevitable that men will die...
but I never heard of an island operation
without beach fortifications.
General, it will be a futile waste of time
to start digging tunnels now.
We should force the enemy
near the island...
and launch a pincer drive
from the sea and air.
I agree. That makes the most sense.
Ohsugi...
doesn't the Navy know?
The Combined Fleet has been completely
destroyed off the Marianas.
The island is now isolated.
What's more, I received a new order from
the lmperial headquarters this morning.
The remaining fighter planes are to be
sent back to Tokyo to defend the mainland.
Outrageous! How are we to fight?
We do not have time for discussion.
We should head back.
Dear Mother...
I have been commissioned
to a new troop today.
I cannot talk about this transfer now.
Take good care of yourself.
Look at this picture.
That's some fancy castle.
You know who this castle was built for?
Someone who was already dead.
They must have had
a lot of money back then...
to build a castle like that
for a dead person.
Why are you reading that book anyway?
We're never going to war over there.
We'll be lucky if we even get
a hole in the ground when we're dead.
Don't talk about that. It's bad luck.
Is this the 312th?
That's right.
I'm Nozaki. This is Saigo.
Shimizu, you can put your bedroll there.
There's an empty space in the back.
Don't mind him.
His friend Kashiwara just died.
That used to be his spot.
But we are all going to die.
That's the plan, isn't it?
For our country, it is an honor.
Kashiwara died of honorable dysentery.
Shimizu, where are you from?
Kanagawa-ken.
Ozawa is from there, aren't you?
That's right.
Where were you trained?
Maybe we were at the same school?
No.
I trained in Tokyo.
I trained in Tokyo, too. Where?
The Koho Kimmu Yoin Yoseijo.
Hey...
why do you think they put
a Kempeitai in our unit?
I don't know.
He's not wearing the white armband.
He's not Kempeitai.
He went to the Kempeitai
military academy.
Maybe he was kicked out.
He acts like aKempeitai.
Look at his holster.
That's not standard issue.
He's been put here to spy on us.
Why would he spy on us?
Maybe it's those letters
you've been writing.
You should be careful.
Weed soup again?
Kuribayashi is conserving
our food supplies for the battle.
We'll be dead
before the Americans even get here.
And you would think that with all my
war effort contributions...
we should be eating kasutera cakes
or sandwiches.
What?
I ran a bakery in Ohmiya with my wife.
Back when we could still get sugar...
we sold ampan and kasutera cakes.
However, his Kempeitai brethren...
used to come and take
whatever they wanted.
For the war...
For the country...
Why bread?
We ran into those types
at our clothing store as well.
When we started making sandwiches...
they took those, too.
And when we ran out of meat
and just had bread, they still came.
Eventually, they took all of our
baking equipment for the metal...
and we were out of business.
I should have been a fisherman.
It must have been hard on your wife...
without the shop
and without her husband.
Tell them to go away.
We have nothing to sell.
Congratulations! Your husband
is going to war.
Thank you very much.
I'm happy to serve the country.
Prayers for your eternal success at arms.
I beg of you! We have only each other.
This is not the time.
We have all sent our husbands
and sons to war.
We all have to do our part.
At least you'll have a little one
to carry on your name.
I can't eat with you like that.
What am I going to do after you die?
I'm not in the coffin yet.
The men never come home,
not even a soul.
They'll never let you come home.
Don't worry.
And now, with the baby.
Can you hear me?
It's Dad.
Listen.
Don't tell anyone
what I'm telling you now.
It's a secret.
Your dad...
is going to come home for you.
Hurry up!
The enemy approaches!
This is ridiculous!
Why waste time digging these tunnels?
They are all going to die anyway.
At least he conceded
to the pillboxes on the beach.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Care for a drink?
You have been looking
quite pale these days.
It's the water. It has
never agreed with me.
That's not good.
Why don't you go back
to the mainland to recoup?
I have commissioned Admiral Ichimaru
to take your place.
We are wasting time
digging these tunnels.
General, the island won't last
five days without fleet support.
We should fight to the death.
The tunnel-digging may be futile.
Maybe the stand on lwo will be futile.
Maybe the whole war is futile.
But will you give up then?
We will defend this island
until we are dead!
Until the very last soldier is dead!
If our children can live safely
for one more day...
it would be worth the one more day
that we defend this island!
Ohsugi...
if you have an ounce
of pride left as an officer...
I beg of you...
go back to headquarters
and ask them to send support.
So the rumor is true?
I couldn't believe it.
I'm grateful to be leaving this island.
We may have had our differences...
but I'm truly sorry to see you go.
General Hayashi, it is up to you now.
Kuribayashi belongs behind a desk,
not commanding war.
I understand.
There are many of us
who agree with you, sir.
Listen.
The Americans are likely to land here.
Crossfire positions will be here...
here...
and here.
The fact is...
we are completely
outnumbered in every sector.
But we have a great advantage.
Can anyone tell me what that is?
The Americans are weak-willed
and inferior to Japanese soldiers.
Very good, Shimizu.
Why is that?
They are not as disciplined...
and they let their emotions
interfere with their duty.
That is correct.
Here is the uniform
of an American medic.
He should be your target.
For Americans will risk the lives
of many soldiers to save this one.
Understood?
General, may I speak with you?
Please keep an eye on
Major General Hayashi.
Thank you for your concern, Nishi...
but we don't have any time to waste.
We must think about what
we can do at this moment.
Admiral Ichimaru.
Reporting for duty, sir.
Excuse me.
Thank you for coming
on such short notice.
Jupiter!
Jupiter.
Yamazaki...
what are you doing just
sitting there? Help us...
I think he's writing about us in his reports.
He's just writing a letter.
It's been two months, Nozaki.
He would have reported us by now.
How can you be sure?
Will they ever stop?
Day and night, day and night...
It's driving me crazy!
If the damn Americans
are going to invade...
why don't they hurry up and land?
Tako-Chan...
the four chicks that were born
two months ago have grown so much.
The mother chicken leads them
for food every day...
but they're giving me a hard time, picking
at the vegetable garden I have grown.
The fleet of American ships
has left Saipan.
So they are on their way.
Ready the troops.
Men...
the time has come
to show your true colors.
As a member of the honorable
lmperial Army...
I trust that you will fight with honor.
This island is of utmost importance
to Japan.
Should the island fall...
the enemy...
will use it as their base
to attack our homeland.
For the mainland...
For our homeland...
Until the very last man.
Our duty is to stop the enemy right here.
Not one of you...
is allowed to die until you have killed
10 enemy soldiers.
Do not expect to return home alive.
I will always be in front of you.
Long live the Emperor.
Take care and be well.
I will fight courageously until the end,
in the spirit of Yamato.
My heart will always be with you.
Takeichi.
Every household is assigned a quota...
of bag-making for the gunpowder.
I cannot help but get tense when I think
that these will be used in battle.
Taro and Yoko laugh at me for this.
Takako, on evacuation in Nagano,
is also doing well.
I pray for your safety.
Sincerely, Yoshi.
No one can shoot me now.
That's a nice belt.
My wife sent me one, too.
Doesn't look like Mr. Kempeitai
has a thousand-stitch belt, does he?
Maybe he thinks it will clash
with his uniform.
He probably doesn't believe
in superstitions, anyway.
His mother made him one after all.
- Maybe they're trying to sink the island.
- My head hurts.
How many ships do you think
there are out there?
At least 30. Maybe even 50.
- They must be really close.
- I need to take a leak.
Don't go near the sewers.
Dysentery is spreading through there.
Where do I go then?
There is a pot at the end of the cave.
The shit pot is full.
Someone needs to throw it out.
If anything happens to that pot...
you'll be carrying our shit away
with your hands.
Is this some kind of a joke?
Why are you always picking on me?
Thank you, God. I take back
what I said before.
Shall we commence fire?
Not yet.
The men wish to commence firing.
Hold your fire!
They will take the beach
in no time if we do not resist.
Wait until the beach is full.
Let's go. Commence firing!
Commence firing!
The guns of the Kitakubo unit
were destroyed.
All the pillbox units on the beach
have been destroyed.
However, all other forces are intact...
and we estimate more than
1,000 enemy casualties.
The pillbox destruction was unavoidable.
Overall, that is good news.
How are the men
holding up at Suribachi?
Forces are intact.
What is the enemy situation?
Approximately 20,000 men and 80 tanks.
There has to be more than that.
They still have men waiting in the boats.
Currently the enemy front extends...
between Suribachi
and the south landing...
and Chidori airfield south.
Just as I thought... Suribachi
and the Motoyama airfield.
They are making a two-pronged attack.
That's not enough! I need more ammo.
Take his place!
- The machine gun is blasted.
- Use your rifle!
Watch out! lmbecile!
I can't rely on you.
Go send a report to Colonel Adachi
that we need another machine gun.
Hurry up!
Colonel Adachi is asking
for reinforcements.
We can't afford to send reinforcements.
Tell him to hold out.
Shoot him!
- What's the matter?
- We're out of bullets!
We are losing Suribachi.
All is lost. Request permission
to lead a suicide mission.
No. You must try to hold them off.
Do what you can to survive
and join forces in the north caves.
But, sir...
I have failed to hold Suribachi.
Permit me to die with honor with my men.
No, Colonel.
This is an order!
Adachi.
Adachi!
Sir, Captain Tanida
requests machine guns.
It's over.
Suicide...
That's the only thing left.
But...
Here, take this to your commander.
I heard General Kuribayashi
order Colonel Adachi to escape.
Quiet!
Escape is the coward's way.
Sit down!
Men...
we are...
honorable soldiers of the Emperor.
Don't ever forget that.
The only way left for us...
is to die with honor.
This is our fate...
to find our place at Yasukuni Shrine.
I'll see you there.
Soldiers, farewell!
Stop!
You should die like an honorable soldier.
Look, Shimizu...
we can still join the troops
in the northern caves.
Our orders are to stay here until death.
I heard General Kuribayashi himself.
That's what he said...
over the radio.
It's true.
We can die here...
or we can continue fighting.
Which would better serve the Emperor?
Which one?
Where does this go?
It will take us closer to Motoyama.
Do you have orders to move back?
Where are the rest of your men?
All dead.
It's the same with us.
There should be an outlet
somewhere near here.
Be quiet!
So you thought you could blow us up,
or burn us alive, did you?
- Have we heard from Suribachi?
- No, sir.
Send a messenger!
Lieutenant Oiso has ordered us
to rendezvous at the east cave.
We will make a run for Motoyama.
There is no cover for two kilometers.
It will be every man for himself.
See you on the other side.
If not on this earth,
then in the next world.
Don't run with the herd.
That's where the enemy will fire.
Stay back.
That's cowardice!
There is no use for a dead soldier.
Wait until the flare is gone.
Crawl forward.
What happened to the messenger?
He never came back.
I will go to Adachi myself.
Motoyama's transmitter
still works, General.
Why not try there, sir?
Sir, these men retreated
from Mt. Suribachi.
What are your names?
Saigo, from the 312th.
Shimizu, reporting for duty.
You escaped from Suribachi?
How dare you!
It was your duty
to stay in your position until death.
You should have died...
with your fellow troop members.
You are both a disgrace.
Get on your knees.
- But, sir...
- I said, get on your knees!
I don't want you to kill
my soldiers needlessly.
Put down your sword.
Put it down!
What's going on here?
These men ran from Suribachi.
Lt. Ito, I gave the order that all survivors
retreat to the north caves.
I am very sorry, General.
It's just...
Suribachi...
has fallen.
Now that Suribachi has been taken...
the enemy will maneuver all forces
onto the hillside.
We must move
our command center north, sir.
Ito...
fight for your fallen brethren...
until the end.
Get up!
Major General Hayashi
is leading an attack.
We are to join him.
Kuribayashi's orders are
to remain in the caves.
Lieutenant lto says Kuribayashi
is a weak American sympathizer.
We will take back Mt. Suribachi.
Where is Major General Hayashi?
We don't know, sir.
Who is in charge here?
I'm not sure.
Stay here until
I determine the plan of action.
We're dead.
Pull back!
We'll get reinforcements.
Why didn't your regiment join the attack?
Don't sit here like rats!
Come out of your caves and fight!
Where is your commander?
We haven't received the order to attack.
Didn't you receive the order
from General Hayashi?
Kuribayashi countermanded
Hayashi's order.
There is to be no attack.
We will take back Suribachi...
with or without Kuribayashi.
There are already troops on the attack.
Get your men in order.
Lieutenant, may I remind you
of your rank!
Your disrespect for senior officers...
puts your men at needless risk.
I suggest you go back to your cave...
or hand over your men.
Enough.
We'll do it ourselves.
That's against regulations.
That's the officer who tried to kill us.
He doesn't care.
I won't go back.
I've had enough of cave fighting.
You men are now under
Lieutenant Colonel Nishi's command.
I will throw myself under an enemy tank.
I will take out one of their machines.
Hurry.
What is the status?
A thousand men were lost...
in a night attack along Chidori airfield.
Why? I have given them strict orders
not to kill themselves.
It seems that the order to retreat
was not conveyed to all sectors.
Hayashi.
Damn you!
And the American advancement?
A battalion is headed north and we
are fighting back along the west ridge.
Good. Once they cross the west ridge,
they will be surrounded on three sides.
This just arrived.
Read it.
From headquarters...
"We regret that we are unable to send
reinforcements to lwo at this time.
We earnestly hope you will
fight honorably...
and die for your country."
Bring him in.
Shall I finish him off?
No. Treat him.
But, sir...
Okubo, you would expect the same,
wouldn't you?
Endo, treat him.
We are low on morphine as it is.
Sir, the Americans would not treat
a wounded Japanese soldier.
Son, have you ever met one?
Treat him.
Where are you, American tanks?
Come and get me!
How is the prisoner doing?
He is awake, sir.
I will question the prisoner
for information.
Damn.
I've had enough of this.
I'm going to surrender.
Go ahead and arrest me.
I don't care anymore. That's what
you were put here for, isn't it?
To report treasonous thoughts.
I was put here because...
I was discharged from the Kempeitai.
Discharged?
I had only been in service
for five days.
Shimizu...
you must always be firm.
Any mercy and people
will take advantage of you.
That's unpatriotic.
Go sort it out, Shimizu.
You do not have the lmperial flag
properly displayed.
I'm sorry.
My husband has gone to war
and I couldn't put it up myself.
It is unpatriotic
not to have the flag displayed.
If you help me, I'll put it up now.
Get that dog to shut up.
What was that, sir?
That dog is a nuisance.
It is disruptive of Army communications.
I am very sorry, sir.
Shimizu. Dispose of the dog.
We can't have a dog interfering
with important military commands.
Take the dog in the back.
It's only a dog.
It won't happen again.
Take it out back.
Keep the children inside.
Hurry up.
Take the dog into the house
and keep him quiet...
and never let him out.
It's taken care of, sir.
Are you trying to make a fool out of me?
If you can't even shoot a dog,
you'll never be able to handle the Reds.
You are unpatriotic!
I was discharged for insubordination...
and sent here.
Don't look so glum, Shimizu.
At least now only the enemy hates you.
I don't blame the dog.
Taro...
tonight I attended my farewell party.
The wives also attended,
so there was a lot of fuss.
Greeting all the ladies...
kept me from enjoying the food.
Is there any information
of the enemy's plan?
No, it's just a letter.
It's from his mother.
"Sam...
I have mailed you
a couple of books to read.
I hope that you like them.
Yesterday...
the dogs dug a hole under the fence.
They ran all over the neighborhood.
By the time we found them...
the Harrisons' roosters were terrorized.
Don't worry about us.
Just take care of yourself
and come back safely.
Remember what I said to you...
always do what is right...
because it is right.
I pray for a speedy end to the war...
and your safe return.
Love, Mom."
I'm sorry, sir. There is no more medicine.
It's all right. I'm useless now.
Go help the others!
Okubo, come here.
How are we on ammunition?
Not good, sir.
Our mortars have been taken out...
and we're out of machine gun ammo.
We have only our rifles.
Okubo...
you are now in charge of the men.
We can no longer hold this area.
You must guide
the rest of the men north.
Take whatever food and ammo
we have left.
What about you, sir?
I'm tired of sharing this cave
with all of you.
I'm a one-man show from here on out.
What are you talking about, sir?
Your first order of business...
is to find some water.
Men...
do your best.
Do what is right...
because it is right.
Understood?
I will make sure that they send you
medicine and food.
It has been a great honor...
to serve...
under you.
Hand me my rifle.
I'm sorry, Okubo.
Why am I not getting any reports?
Have we heard from Admiral Ichimaru?
- No, sir.
- What about Nishi or Hayashi?
- Send out messengers!
- We have. Many times.
None of them have come back.
You can't plan strategy like this!
I have been thinking about
what Lt. Colonel Nishi said.
He's right.
I don't know anything about the enemy.
I believed that the Americans
were cowards...
but they weren't.
I was taught...
that they were savages...
but that American soldier...
his mother's words...
were the same as my mother's.
I want to fulfill my duty
for the general...
and our country...
but I don't want to die for nothing.
What do you think?
You...
haven't lived enough to realize...
what you are sacrificing.
Will you surrender with me?
Careful.
They'll notice if we leave together.
You go first.
I'll make up an excuse.
After a while, I'll tell them
I'm going to check on you.
We'll be gone before they even notice.
Pretend that you have dysentery.
Give me your dysentery look.
I guess that'll have to do.
Where are you going?
I've got dysentery.
You're going to surrender, aren't you?
If you are, take me with you.
- I've had enough of this war.
- Be quiet!
Where are you going?
He said he wasn't feeling well.
It could be dysentery.
You two! Stop!
Sir, maybe they got spooked.
Miura, you're on guard.
Make sure we have no more deserters.
What unit were you with?
Higashiyama 314th.
Did you hear...
I heard that they would give you a meal.
A meal...
That sounds good.
I'm from Yokohama, too.
After this is over, you can come visit me.
Lieutenant!
Let this be a lesson to anyone else...
who wants to surrender.
We need to get through the crossfire
to reach the north...
and join our forces at the front.
Listen.
We'll head for that cave
and make our way from there.
Don't waste a bullet!
Not a single one.
Don't shoot recklessly.
These are Nishi's troops
and the survivors from Suribachi.
Are there no officers?
You all did a good job making it here.
Fujita, water for them.
I'm sorry, sir. There is no more water.
I'm sorry.
At least you can rest.
You look familiar.
You almost lost your head.
That was the second time you saved me.
The first time...
was the day you landed on the island.
Of course. I remember.
Well, everything happens in threes.
Hanako...
This letter will probably
never get to you...
but...
it comforts me to write.
For five days, we've been
without water and food.
To survive...
we do unspeakable things.
There is no escape now.
But...
my only concern is for you and the baby.
Dig up some worms.
The battle is approaching its end...
and there is no more ammunition,
no more water.
All the survivors will engage
in a general attack.
I pray for the victory
and safety of the Empire.
I bid you farewell.
For the country,
I could not fulfill all of my duties.
Now that we have no ammunition,
it is with regret that we must perish.
You made it all the way from Suribachi?
That must have been quite a journey.
You are quite a soldier.
No, sir.
I'm just a simple baker.
You were a baker?
Any family?
A wife...
and a baby girl born
last summer in Ohmiya.
I haven't met her yet.
It's strange.
I promised myself to fight
until death for my family...
but the thought of my family
makes it difficult to keep that promise.
A radio transmission from the homeland.
For General Kuribayashi...
and his troops, who are fighting bravely
for our country...
a song will be sung by the children
of Nagano...
which is Kuribayashi's hometown.
On the waves of the Pacific
down south from the Imperial City
a small lonely island floats
The fate of our Imperial country
lies in the hands of this island
lwo Jima
As long as we stand
we shall feel safe, as the Imperial land
shall forever be at peace
We shall fight with pride
and honor at any price
Our proud island
lwo Jima
Do me a favor.
Stay here and burn all these documents,
and my military chest.
Everything happens in threes.
We will make a general attack.
Although Japan has lost...
one day...
our people will praise your dedication.
A day will come when they
will weep and pray for your souls.
Be proud to die for your country.
I will always be in front of you.
No more.
Thank you, Fujita.
This is an order.
You again.
I have one more favor to ask of you.
Bury me...
so that no one will find me.
Taro...
I will be home soon.
I'm glad to be going back to Japan...
but I'm a bit sad
to leave my friends behind.
I drove home...
but...
it's lonely driving all by myself.
Is this still Japanese soil?
This is still Japan.
Be careful.