This has been
a long time coming, fellas.
Three years on the plates alone.
But you'll find the product
worth the wait.
Go ahead. Take a good look, boys.
Jeez, Mr. Sol, I can't tell
the difference.
You'd need a neutron microscope.
Identical, to Ben Franklin's stubble.
I want half a mil a week laundered in
the casino. 3/4 mil by March.
Anybody got a problem with that?
The Bat!
Get him!
Chuckie Sol.
Batman!
How'd you get here?
Your Angel of Death awaits.
You ain't the Bat!
Who are you? What do you want?
I want you, Chuckie-boy.
This time I got you,
you lousy, stinking...
What...?!
- Look!
- Good Lord!
- What happened?
- Hey, look! It's Batman!
I'm telling you, it's vigilantism
at its deadliest.
How many times are we gonna let
Batman cross the line?
Councilman, you can't blame Batman
for what happened to Chuckie Sol.
Why not?
He's a loose cannon, commissioner.
It's not just my opinion. A lot of
people, including the police...
...think Batman's as unstable
as the crooks.
What kind of city are we running...
... - when we depend on the support
of a potential madman?!
Such rot, sir. Why, you're
the very model of sanity.
By the way, I pressed your tights and
put away your exploding gas balls.
Thank you, Alfred.
Might one inquire what this is?
A piece of windshield
from Chuckie Sol's car.
There's a chemical residue on it.
A dense, long-chain macromolecular
polymer. Adaptogenic, of course.
Of course.
I should be landing any minute.
- It'll be good to see you again.
- You too-
And don't worry about a thing. We'll
clear up these old family finances.
Don't forget...
...you've got a bigtime councilman
on your side.
I can't believe it's been 10 years.
Thinking of looking up some old friends?
Arthur, don't start that again.
He's ancient history.
That's encouraging. I'll see you soon.
Oh, come on, Bruce! All alone
in this big mansion...
Haven't you ever thought about marriage,
even once?
Never say the "M" word in front of
Bruce. It makes him nervous.
What about the "l" word?
The "l" word?
"Ingagement."
I'd watch out for Brucie
if I were you, girls.
He makes you think you're the only woman
he's ever been interested in.
And just when you're wondering where to
register the china...
...he forgets your phone number.
That's Bruce Wayne's style.
Bruce?
Excuse me.
Friend in need?
Councilman.
So how goes the Bat bashing?
Better than your love life.
You seem to pick them knowing there's no
chance for a serious relationship.
Since that one girl. What was her name?
Anne? Andi? Andrea?
Yes, Andrea Beaumont!
There was a sweet number.
How'd you let her get loose?
Thanks for the handkerchief, Arthur.
You know where you can stick it.
Andrea...
If Daddy gets any more protective,
he'll build a moat around my bedroom.
Times like this
I wish you were around to...
Excuse me. I thought you were
saying something. To me, I mean.
Know who that was?
Bruce Wayne. You know,
Wayne Enterprises?
I've seen him on campus. Very moody.
Cute, though.
- Yes?
- I heard my name. I thought...
- Who are you talking to?
- My mother.
Oh. I didn't mean to...
That's okay. We're done.
Mom doesn't have much to say today.
I'm not the only one
who talks to their loved ones.
I didn't say anything.
When I talk to her out loud,
I can imagine how she'd reply.
I can hear her, like she's right there.
I talked to my parents.
What did you say?
- I made a vow.
- What vow?
A secret one.
A man of mystery!
Have you kept your vow?
So far.
Andrea Beaumont.
Bruce Wayne.
I know. "The boy billionaire."
With all that money, why do you always
look like you want to jump off a cliff?
- Why should you care?
- I don't.
Mother was asking.
Let's step on it!
We ain't got all night.
Wait for me!
Coming through.
Okay, Skaz. We're done shopping.
All clear here.
Well, Bruce, here goes.
Let's blow this pop stand.
On your stomachs, arms spread!
Who's this clown?
You heard me!
Yeah, you heard him, boys.
You heard Mr. Kung Fu.
- I'm shaking.
- Say your prayers, sucker!
Yes...!
Excuse me.
Hey, Jonesey!
There!
I read about your anonymous exploits,
and I must say...
...are you sure you won't
reconsider rugby?
Sorry, Alfred, but the plan is working.
I had the edge. I could feel it!
There was only one thing wrong.
They weren't afraid of me.
I've got to strike fear in them.
Pardon, Master Bruce. We may want
to postpone the shoptalk.
I believe you have a visitor.
Hi! Hey, what happened to you?
Trip over some loose cash?
It's been 3 days since we met, and still
no calls. I figured you must be dead.
You expect every guy you meet
to call you?
The ones that are smart enough
to dial a phone.
- What is that?
- Jujitsu.
Gesundheit.
That was a joke.
Jujitsu is no joke.
It takes years to master.
Got a few moves of my own.
Miss Hovey's self-defense class
for girls.
Oh, he laughs!
Nice footwork. Can you dance too?
Pardon, sir, but Miss Bambi
is dancing on the piano.
Brucie! Where are you?
You guys wait here.
Whatever you say, Mr. Bronski.
They say the Bat iced this guy.
I know.
Chuckie, Chuckie...
You always were a loser.
Buzz...
Who's there?
Buzz Bronski.
Your Angel of Death awaits.
Get away, you freak!
Time to pay for your sins, Mr. Bronski.
All right, creep. Catch this!
What the...?
Jake! Dougan!
Boys!
Come on!
He was up here!
Boss! Boss!
Boys! Hurry!
You always were a loser, Mr. Bronski.
Farewell, Mr. Bronski!
Oh, man!
It's the Bat!
It's the stinking Bat!
Buzz!
What do you mean?
You have to go after him!
He didn't do it!
It's garbage, Mr. Reeves.
Batman does not kill. Period!
You want him, you get him.
I'll have no part of it.
Well, gentlemen?
Any ideas?
He's usually here by now.
There appears to be some chemical
residue on the lawn.
Could match the traces on the glass.
Not much,
but it's been that kind of day.
You'd think they could afford
a weed-eater.
Sorry, Mom, but the whole world's
going to seed.
You!
Bruce?
I'm having the banker cut through some
red tape. He can roll your money into...
...a higher-yield account.
Amount? What amount?
I said "account."
I'm sorry, I was just... reminiscing.
That's okay.
You must have a lot on your mind.
Monsieur?
Remember this place?
Sure. You, me and Daddy used to come
here all the time.
How is the old guy?
You're still close, aren't you?
Closer than ever.
I'm sorry he couldn't
make it into town, but...
...l've always wished I could have
some time alone with you.
Well, who knows what the future
might bring?
Welcome to the Gotham World's Fair,
a dream of the future-
A bright tomorrow filled with hope
and promise for all mankind-
This is a vision
of the shimmering utopia... -
... - where we shall all spend
the rest of our lives-
Do you think we'll really see
any of this in our lifetime?
Bruce, I'm talking to you.
Oh! I'm sorry, Andi.
- My mind was on something else.
- What?
Oh, just, you know...
The future!
Anyone's in particular,
or just the generic brand?
You know.
No, I don't. Since when
do you talk to me about your plans?
By the way...
...Dad's been wanting to meet you.
- Oh, yeah?
I told him you're not up to it yet.
I can meet him.
Great!
I'll call him right now.
You sure about this?
Sure, I'm sure.
What am I doing?
This isn't part of the plan.
I must be going nuts.
If I may make so bold, Master Bruce,
I'd say quite the reverse.
Mr. Beaumont,
here are the partnership papers.
If you could just go over them...
IKnock, knock!
This is a most pleasant interruption!
At last I meet the elusive Bruce Wayne.
Nice to meet you, sir.
"Sir"? Don't be so formal, Bruce.
She's said so much about you,
I feel we're practically family.
Daddy...
Don't mind me. I was just leaving.
I'm sorry.
Arthur Reeves, one of the hot Young
Turks from my legal department.
You should get to know him.
I hope we're not interrupting.
Not at all! I'm never too busy
for my Andi and her friends.
I tell you, Bruce, I do
a lot of financial planning.
In money matters, you can't
take the future for granted.
But money means little without
loved ones to share it with.
Nothing's more important than family.
Yes, Mr. Beaumont.
- Carl.
- Excuse me, sir...
...a Mr. Valestra is here to see you.
He says he has an appointment...
If he says he has an appointment...
...then he has an appointment.
That's what I like about your pop,
kiddo.
He knows his priorities.
Is my shirt too big,
or is that my flesh crawling?
Mr. Valestra is not what you'd call
a "people person."
No kidding!
That's just Daddy's business.
He deals with everyone.
It's not your father, Andi, it's...
...it's everything!
I said hand over the cashbox, man!
Give me!
- Pops here needs some persuasion.
- Don't hurt me!
- Stay here! I gotta stop this.
- Bruce, don't.
What should I do? Just stand here?
Just come back to me in one piece,
please?
Better have your
insurance paid up, sucker!
Come on! Pick up the box!
Pick up the box!
Thank God you're all right.
I was so frightened!
Let me have a look at you.
Andrea, please!
What am I still doing this for?
It's gotta be one or the other.
I can't have it both ways.
I can't put myself on the line
if someone's waiting for me at home.
Miss Beaumont would be glad to know
you feel that way.
She's holding on line one, sir.
Master Bruce?
Alfred, I can't. Not now.
What shall I say, sir?
I don't know.
I just don't know!
It doesn't mean I don't care anymore.
I don't want to let you down, honest.
But it just doesn't hurt
so bad anymore.
You can understand, can't you?
I can give money to the city
to hire more cops.
Let others take the risk.
It's different now!
Please. I need it to be different now.
I know I made a promise.
But I didn't see this coming!
I didn't count on being happy.
Please...
...tell me that it's okay.
Maybe they already have.
Maybe they sent me.
Get in.
All I want to know is, is it true?
Is the Batman really hitting our people?
We have eyewitnesses.
Beautiful.
That's just beautiful. Why?
He never leaned on us before.
I'm too old for this.
You could demand police protection.
What are you, a comedian?
This is the Batman we're talking about.
A freak job!
He'll crucify me!
Pull over.
It's not very healthy in here.
"O'Neil Funding Corporation."
"Adam's Tool and Die."
I should've known.
Sir?
Chuckie Sol and Buzz Bronski.
They have a history as partners
in dummy corporations...
...set up over 10 years ago.
The third director
was one Salvatore Valestra.
Sal's having company tonight.
Don't wait up.
Meaning, I trust that once you're done
with him, you'll be seeing her?
You think you know everything about me,
don't you?
I diapered your bottom.
I bloody well ought to... sir!
Well, you're wrong!
Andrea's father...?
You know how I've always
wanted to see Europe.
Dad has business there. It's a hush-
hush deal. He won't tell me a thing.
Not even when we'd be coming back.
Will you at least let me try
to talk you out of it?
Wait, please.
Never mind.
I'm no good at this.
Here. You'll get the idea.
What do you say?
Of course I will!
I never thought this would happen.
I always felt like I'd
thrown you a curve ball.
Like you never knew what to do with me,
since I wasn't in the plan.
You are now. I'm changing the plan.
Looks like Dad's got company.
Business-type company.
He doesn't usually see clients here.
Not at this hour.
Maybe we should wait
to tell him the good news.
- Maybe.
- Good night, Bruce.
- Alfred.
- Miss.
It's another cave, all right.
As big as the house, judging from
all the bats that came out of it.
Alfred, what's wrong?
This just arrived, sir.
"Left with Dad.
Too young...
...need time.
Forget about me."
My God!
If there was just some other way...
I hate that song.
Gasp!
Can it be?
Old Sallie "The Wheezer" Valestra.
Welcome, paisan!
It's been a dog's age.
Hello, Joker.
Didn't mean to drop by unannounced.
Oh, Salvatore!
Why so formal?
Mi casa nostra es su casa nostra-
What does an old-timer like you
want with a two-timer like me?
Business.
Oh, business!
Sounds like fun! Come!
We'll repair to more
comfortable environs.
Now hold on to your hat,
and watch those valuables.
It's going to be a bumpy ride!
Honey, I'm home!
Don't mind my home-security system.
Down, Rusty.
Can't be too careful,
with all those weirdos around.
What? Meat loaf again?
Oh, I had it for lunch!
Isn't Hazel here a cutie?
True, she's a real homebody, but you
can't help who you fall in love with.
Come. Have a seat, Sal.
Tell me what's on your so-called mind.
It's Batman.
He's gone nuts!
First he whacked Chuckie Sol...
...then Buzz.
Now he's after me.
I've been reading lately how old
guano-man is wound tight enough to snap.
Wouldn't it be great if I'd finally
driven him off the deep end?
This isn't a joke!
He's knocking us off, and
only you can take him down.
Five million up front, with
whatever you want to finish him off.
What do I look like? Pest control?
Think, you fool! Once he gets me,
how long till he gets you?
You know what I'm talking about.
Your hands are just as dirty.
Dirtier!
Don't touch me, old man!
I don't know where you've been!
Oh, Sal, no one could
take a joke like you.
- Of course I'll help you out.
- Really?
Certainement-
No way is anybody
gonna hurt my pal Sal.
That's it!
That's what I want to see.
A nice, big smile.
- Thanks for another lovely dinner.
- My pleasure.
You know, it's not good to go to bed
on a full stomach.
We could stay up...
...talk for a while.
I've got a killer day tomorrow, Artie.
But call me, okay?
Good night.
So we meet again. I like the cape.
I'm not sure about the mask though.
Have you ever seen this?
But that's your father.
He set up their corporate partnership.
So? That's his job.
He's the one element
that tied these gangsters together.
- Where's your father now?
- Haven't a clue.
Why don't you try Madagascar?
That's not what you told Reeves.
You said you were closer than ever
to your father.
You had me bugged?
I can read lips.
Then read them now. Get out.
Still following your Dad's orders?
The way I see it, the only one in this
room controlled by his parents is you.
Sal Valestra...
...your Angel of Death awaits.
Guess the joke is on me!
You're not Batman after a//-
Looks like there's a new face
in Gotham... -
... - and soon his name
will be all over town-
To say nothing of his legs,
feet, spleen... -
... - and head!
Stay away! This is not your fight!
This madness ends now!
Batman, this is the police-
You are under arrest-
Step away from the edge of the roof-
Put your hands on top of your head
and stay in the light-
Stay on him!
This is 6-30 in pursuit-
Subject moving north along Denny Drive-
All units approach with caution-
Subject is armed and dangerous-
Use of deadly force is authorized-
Take it down! I gotta get closer!
Freeze!
He's heading for the
construction site!
SWAT deployment teams, move
into position- All units acknowledge-
Roger that- Moving into position-
All available units to 4th and Madison,
the construction site-
Charlie-three, prepare for tear gas-
There he is, men!
Hey, wait!
You jerk!
Get a light up there!
Delta-three to ground-
He's down- We have him!
Fire!
Quick, around the back!
Come on, you grunts!
Hurry!
Who's that?
There are certain advantages
to having a sturdy cranium.
But then, hardheadedness
was always your virtue.
Well, I'm sure I have things
to do elsewhere.
You have an excellent sense of timing.
It was all over TV.
I had to do something.
I'm grateful, of course.
But I need to know why you won't
tell me the truth about your father.
I suppose the "world's greatest
detective" will find out eventually.
You remember Daddy was having a meeting
that night with his partners...
You're a liar and a cheat, Carl.
You've taken what's ours.
- You're gonna pay one way or another.
- No! Please!
Daddy! What's going on?
I'm sorry you had to see this,
Miss Beaumont.
Let her go!
Watch it, Carl!
Please, Sal, give me one more day.
I swear I'll get the money.
Convince me.
This time tomorrow.
On my mother's grave.
As soon as the European banks open,
I'll have it wired to you.
Twenty-four hours.
This time tomorrow
we'll have the money...
...or I'll have your heart
in my hand.
Let's go, boys.
Are you all right?
Pack a suitcase.
We've got to get to the airport, now!
But you said you'd have the money.
It's not that simple.
It's tied up in investments.
- It could take weeks.
- But I can't leave!
Bruce proposed.
We're getting married.
Listen to me.
I just used up the last shred
of pity Sal Valestra has.
If I don't pay him within 24 hours,
they'll kill us both!
Why did you do this? Why did you
get involved with these people?
I'm sorry, Andi.
I just wanted a chance for you.
I'll get you out of this.
We'll be free of those guys.
Whatever it takes.
That's a promise.
From that night, we were on the run-
We hid all over Europe, eventually
settled on the Mediterranean coast-
Dad was able to parlay the money
he embezzled into a fortune-
Finally, he thought he had enough
to pay them back.
It would never be enough.
They wanted interest compounded
in blood. He had to find another way.
The man in the costume...
Your father?
He said he'd get them. Somehow.
When I heard about Chuckie Sol...
...I had to come back...
...to find him, to stop him.
I'm sorry, Bruce.
That's twice now I've come
into your life and screwed it up.
Can we make it work this time?
I want to say yes...
...but you know it'll come down
between me and your father.
Daddy doesn't matter anymore.
I'll see you tonight.
I'll be here.
It's so good to see you
and Miss Beaumont together again.
Might one ask what this bodes
for your alter ego?
I'm not sure, Alfred.
Everything's happening so fast.
So much has changed.
You still love each other.
That's true.
I love her.
Maybe after this is settled...
Maybe then...
I'm sure they'd have
wanted you to be happy.
Is something wrong?
Maybe.
You're saying there were 4 precincts on
Batman's heels, and he still got away?
Unbelievable!
Tsk, tsk.
And to think our tax money
goes to pay those jerks.
You!
That's right, Artie. Bring in the
press, why don't you? What a photo-op.
The Councilman and his wacky pal!
You're no friend of mine.
Oh, Artie, I'm crushed!
How the high and mighty forget!
Don't you remember?
You, me...
...Sallie and the gang?
What are you talking about?
I never met them or you.
I worked for Beaumont.
I didn't know what he was doing.
But you knew about it afterwards.
And put it to good use, eh?
What do you want?
To find out who has iced the old gang.
Haven't you read the papers?
It's Batman!
Wrong! It ain't the Bat.
Nope, I've seen the guy.
He looks more like
the Ghost of Christmas Future.
Nowhere near as cute as Batboy.
You say it's someone else?
Someone who wouldn't mind seeing
our old pals out of the way.
Maybe...
...gulp... sob...
...me too!
That's when I thought
about you, Arturo.
An important, upstanding guy like you
could find it awkward...
...if certain secrets were
revealed about his past.
Wait. You're not saying that l...
Mr- Reeves, Miss Beaumont
on the line-
Beaumont? Not the babe!
Oh, you devil!
Arthur, are you there?
Hello, Andrea.
We're still on for lunch, right?
I'm sorry, I can't. I got hung up.
I'll explain everything tonight.
All right.
I'll see you then.
Now, ain't that a co-inky-dink?
We're talking about the old man...
...and the spawn of his loins
just happens to call.
Makes you want to laugh, doesn't it?
Good heavens!
Councilman, please.
You've got to control yourself.
I'm trying, for God's sake!
Here's the relaxant, doctor.
I need some help.
IKeep him still!
Councilman, please!
That's it.
That's right...
That should relax you enough
for the toxin to run its course.
Try to stay calm.
Oh, no!
Why did the Joker meet with you?
Is it about
the gangster murders?
He thinks you're involved. Why?!
I don't know.
That's not the answer I want.
Beaumont needed me to help him
and his kid get out of town.
He kept in touch.
When did you last speak?
Years ago.
My first election campaign.
I was running out of money
and asked Beaumont for help.
He said no!
So you sold him to the Mob.
I was broke, desperate!
They said all they wanted
was their money back.
Councilman.
Councilman, please!
Hello, anybody home?
Listen, boopsie, even though
you never call and never write...
...I still got a soft spot for you.
So I'm sending you a fun gift.
Airmail.
And there's no use jumping
out the window this time, toots-
The plane of the future
is going to make you history-
Hello? Hello, operator?
I believe my party's been... -
... - disconnected!
You!
But he paid you!
Dad?!
Well, Haze, guess it's
time to call it a night.
What do you say, hon?
Feeling the old electricity tonight?
Ain't it always the way? You get
in the mood and company shows up.
Joker...
...your Angel of Death awaits.
I'm impressed, lady.
You're harder to kill
than a cockroach on steroids.
So, you figured it out?
Gotta hand it to you. Nice scheme!
Costume's a bit theatrical,
but hey, who am I to talk?
Very cute...
...but I can blow smoke too, toots!
Nice trick, sweetheart.
You could teach old Batsy
a thing or two about disappearing.
You're not smiling, Joker.
I thought you found death amusing.
Me? Oh, no.
You won't hear a giggle out of me.
Made you look!
Well, if it isn't Smokey the Babe!
Just in time to meet her biggest fan!
How about a little pick-me-up?
Your father's dead, isn't he?
You came into town early
to get Chuckie Sol...
...so you could shift the blame
to your father.
They took everything, Bruce.
My dad, my life...
...you.
I'm not saying it's right, or even
sane, but it's all I've got left.
So either help me
or get out of the way!
You know I can't do that.
Look at what they did to us...
...what we could have had!
They had to pay.
But Andi, what will vengeance solve?
If anyone knows the answer
to that, Bruce...
...it's you.
Leave, Andi.
Now.
Please.
Oh, Batsy!
Yoo-hoo!
You're too late, Batman!
There are 20 miles of tunnels
under this place.
And they're all filled
with explosives.
In five minutes, everything goes up!
You just don't know
when to quit, do you?
What are you doing?
You're crazy! I'm your only chance
to get out of here!
Let me go or we'll both die!
Whatever it takes!
For once...
...l'm stuck without a punch line.
Okay...
...I give up.
I surrendered already.
Tell her, Batman.
You've got to get out of here.
The place is wired to explode!
No. One way or another,
it ends tonight.
Goodbye, my love.
I couldn't save her, Alfred.
I don't think she wanted to be saved.
Vengeance blackens the soul, Bruce.
I always feared you would become
that which you fought against.
You walk the edge of that abyss
every night, but you haven't fallen in.
And I thank heaven for that.
But Andrea fell into
that pit years ago.
No one, not even you,
could have pulled her back.
What is it?
Quite a sight.
I'm sorry...
...do you want to be alone?
I am.
Subtitles by -=[Dj Mp3]=-
http://usuarios.lycos.es/clonemasters