2 pounds. And fat ones.
That's shoulder, right?
The Kube Brother's
usual. Tell me about it!
How much?
2 measures.
Well, Mr Interligator...
How's your wife doing?
Poorly.
Roger, your muffler.
I've got it.
She tried to
take her life again?
Thank heaven, she's alive.
Butcher...,
I think you've
got a customer coming.
Who's next?
I am!
That for me?
At your service.
Put it on my bill.
We know where...
she keeps her bill alright!
Your turn!
Carburator's acting up again.
That'll cost you...
the ride, plus luggage...
How're you paying?
Lentils?
That's all I've got.
Listen. Those shoes
there would do the trick...
Closed.
That's all today.
I didn't come for that.
Anyway, I don't eat meat.
I came about the ad.
What ad?
In the paper.
What paper?
"Hard Times".
"Light building
maintenance. Odd jobs..."
"Room and board.
Southern exposure."
It's the right place, number 129a?
Here or there,
this is nowhere.
There's no neighbor hassle!
And no visitors.
Well...
I must've made a mistake.
Not so fast! If I got you
right, you're looking for a job?
Come here.
Turn around.
Pardon?
Turn around!
What do you weigh?
137... 140. Why?
You're no heavyweight!
I've got work...
...but it takes muscle.
No problem!
I'm a butcher
but I don't mince words.
You don't seem to
be cut out for the job.
You don't have the bones, the chest...
I'll try you out,
but you'll have to bust ass!
What a stroke of luck!
Thanks.
Come on.
So what does the work involve?
"Light building
maintenance. Odd jobs.."
"Room and board.
Southern exposure."
Like in the ad?
How about that?
Just like the ad!
Watch it, there's a step loose.
You'll fix it with the rest...
Paint, electricity, cleaning...
The works!
You'll like it here.
And there're no neighbors opposite.
Hang the key there.
I'll let you get settled.
Thanks.
How're things in town?
Terrible.
With rationing, people'd
eat their shoes. It's touchy.
They have no smarts.
It's a mess.
And till things grow back...!
They'll never grow back.
You're no optimist.
Get that into your skull,
for chrissake!
Your hair isn't growing back.
Same difference.
Can't we open
the windows 5 minutes?
I like the smell of glue.
It smells like fish.
It brings back memories.
What do you think of the new guy?
You deaf?
He's skinny.
Thinking about her again?
They say she hears voices now.
Is it too much effort
to put that closer?
Hi!
Forget it, she's deaf as a post.
If she gets lost, we'll find her.
Go back home,
there's nothing left.
I'm telling you
there's nothing left!
You finished?
Don't stay up there.
Fix the 3rd floor bulb.
-Hi Butcher!
-Hi, Postman!
Got a parcel for you daughter.
Upstairs.
Watch the step.
Mind your business!
Go for it, Marcel!
Grab it!
I've got it!
Throw it here!
You bastard!
Postal Administration!
Article 12:
"You have 20 sec to scatter
and return to your domiciles."
Now!
You have no kids to feed.
That means kids too!
Can't you read? idiot!
"Julie Clapet"
He's a friend.
A friend?
Here, Julie...
Sign here, Julie.
I call you Julie because
I like you. But I won't rush you.
See you soon, Julie.
Here... for the ad.
At your service.
That new guy looks weird!
An ex-circus man!
From the circus?
It must be nibbles.
That's why they...
Would you care to taste them?
Yes! I'd love to.
Then 7pm at my place,
time to prepare.
-Say, he after her?
-After who?
Your girl. She's sure a cute
young lady. She needs someone...
She's got me! Got that!
By the way, I've got news.
They shot one down 2 days ago.
A superb 30 yard moving target.
No body?
They cart their dead away.
Vermin! They say
they even eat money.
Got to get rid
of them for good, see?
Those seed eating faggots...
They'll get it, alright!
Bye Butcher!
Bye Postman!
Think it's for tonight?
I hope so.
Goddamn Butcher!
I know he won't do it tonight.
He dawdles just to piss me off!
It works.
What is he waiting for?
For the new guy to
escape in a garbage can too?
How long did he last us?
A week.
Not counting the bouillon
A week! We finished
the last chunk 2 days ago.
I'm hungry.
I have a pit inside!
My dear Hercules...
Every man for himself...
It's me.
Hi.
Come in.
Please, come in.
This is for you.
Thanks
Sit down.
Did you paint this?
Yes... its nothing much.
I made tea.
Shall I pour it?
yes, please.
I hope you don't
find me too forward.
Not at all. Why should I?
A girl invites you to her
home... a bit improper, maybe?
Well, actually...
I wanted to thank you
for this morning.
Thank me for what?
You rescued my package in the stairs.
I was moved by your gesture.
It's only natural.
But usually,
people only think of themselves...
...these days.
It's normal,...
they have nothing.
Deep down, they're good people.
I'm glad they like me.
They're very kind.
Things're fine with your dad too.
I believe he thinks
I'm a nice guy.
"Why not try gourmet cheese spread?"
"That's new!"
"And it's handy."
They talk to me about you.
Who?
The voices in my head.
Of course, the voices!
What do they say?
Let me think...
They talk in such a way...
Do they talk about love?
Aurore, you're missing
something hilarious!
Anyway, I have no choice.
Here... Tomorrow, at 11 sharp.
Ring! Don't let me down.
Move out? What for?
I've just moved in!
This place isn't that great.
Its insanitary, the walls
are crumbling, it leaks...
Maybe you don't like me?
You act as if you want me to leave...
On the contrary,...
That's not what I meant.
It does that...
sometimes.
Did I hurt you?
I'm alright.
We really clashed.
I'm so clumsy.
Don't budge.
I'm blind as a mole.
Everything's foggy.
I could get lost in it.
Since I break things,
I always buy two.
You play the cello.
I play music too.
Wait, I'll be back.
Shit not again!
What're you doing?
I wanted to take a bath.
Again?
You sharpen your knives enough!
A musical saw!
It has nice sound.
Sit down.
I used to play it with the doctor.
Livingstone...
"Dr Livingstone"!
He was my partner.
It'll rust now that he's gone.
Where did he go?
He disappeared after a show...
We only found his carcass.
They ate him.
Can you imagine, they ate him!
That night, I lost everything.
So, the 1st ad I read...
And here I am.
I must tell you something.
Hush... listen!
Do you know that tune?
It was his favorite.
Notice how the nights are clear?
We're entering
the Virgo age. That's my sign.
No joke?
I swear it!
Virgo, ascendant Leo.
Cut it out, not everyone's
Gorilla, ascendant Bulldozer!
I'm in luck, there's lots in store.
"Get ready, the wind's shifting."
You'd like to pack up
and leave, right?
You wouldn't get far.
It's worse out there, they draw straws.
It'd be ashamed to see those hams go.
And those little sucklings...
Don't joke about that, I hate it.
You're better off here.
At least, we got a system.
My ass! Those helpers
you ice are drawing straws too.
That's fate!
And you can't help Fate.
Just like you said:
"The wind's shifting."
Everyone's gonna get it.
Mr Louison,
I'm not supposed to tell you but...
...what happened to
your friend happens here.
It takes place at night in the stairs.
That's why no one goes out.
And my father...
SOPORIFIC HERBS
Hi.
-I'm here for the springs.
-Come in.
This is antique!
It has seen a lot of use.
What's the problem?
It squeaks. That's a pain.
Could you bounce just a little?
I can't see anything.
It does it most...
when there're 2 of us.
Let's try it.
As I thought,
the 2nd spring to the right.
"Come, Aurore..."
"Come..."
"We are here..."
"...to help you..."
"Come..."
"Freed from life.."
"Come with us, Aurore."
"Soothed..."
COME AT 11 SHARP. RING HARD!
"Rotten world..."
That should do it.
Here.
Thanks.
What are Troglodists?
Outlaws. It's the big story,
but no one sees them.
Tales to keep people busy.
A typical Capricorn statement!
You lose, I'm Aquarius.
The sign of the future!
The future...
It's soon history around here.
It's so easy to miss a step.
Don't worry about me.
You little brats,
give that back!
Quit sneering,
or I'll whack you one!
I'll beat one with the other!
Give that back,
I won't stand for it!
Nice work!
Little rugrats,...
How'll we get it down?
This is a job for the Australian!
The Australian?
Stand back.
That's some tool!
The Australian is nothing
without its master.
How about that!
So, Tapioca, you find a job?
No, not yet.
That's bad news,
your bill's running up.
Not to mention the rent.
I'm in a bit of a fix.
But I've got some good stuff.
Have a look?
Black market? You're a louse!
But take a look.
What's that?
A rat-call. That's the
female cry. It attracts males.
But there're no
rats left. And what?
That is a bullshit detector.
Try it.
Try what?
Give me some bullshit.
Come on!
I can't do it on cue.
"Life is beautiful."
A bullshit of a
detector! Turn it off!
We can't hear anything.
If you can't pay up,
we'll have to find a way.
Fast. Otherwise,...
you'll wind up hooked to me.
Very funny!
What about that clown?
He's been around long enough.
We're edgy
Don't care!
He'll redo the ceilings.
Meanwhile, he takes
root and we wither away.
I have mouths to feed.
I bet! The granny's, for instance.
Why do you mention her?
I know why.
What do you mean?
Want to pay up?
Give up granny . Tonight.
Take it easy.
She's one of ours.
The rules say...
The rules...
Age limit is a rule too.
She soon won't be...
...good for more than marrow paste.
She's my mother-in-law!
Take Mrs Interligator, that's all...
...she wants.
Quit yelling.
-Its charity.
-Please.
Interligator needs his wife.
And he's a good tenant: He pays!
The damn rich always manage.
With your debts, you've no choice.
Need I insist?
It's you, Julie...
You scared me.
Counting your money again?
Yes. Tell me...
It's rare to see you here.
That's nice of you.
Like your gift?
It must've cost you.
Anything to make you happy.
You've loved candy
since you were little.
But I don't like it anymore.
Let him go.
You always ask that.
It's the same thing each time.
No, this time...
So it is different,
just look at you! I see his game.
Making your head spin
with his puppy eyes, his dreams...
There's no room for dreams!
Stop it!
It's a tough world
and I didn't make it.
You hate my trade.
It's an art like any other!
Let him go.
And you'll go with him?
You wont last 2 weeks!
And I wont lost u.
You lost me long ago!
Julie!
TROGLODISM:
AN UNDERGROUND ORGANIZATION?
Hi, girl.
Guess what?
We'll play a game.
I scare you, you scream.
and the clown upstairs...
...runs down to your rescue.
Shall we start?
What's wrong?
Don't just stare!
Scream damnit!
You come from N.E. sector.
Just to bug us about...
...your Mr Whosit's troubles?
Mr Louison.
Don't know him! No more names,
no more IDs. We're at war.
You're with outlaws!
He's Rolls. I'm January.
Voltange. Rolan.
Tourneur. Milan. Trap.
Pank. Fox. Paumeau.
We watch out for moles from up there.
You could be one!
I'm not a liar.
It's true!
You, a surfacer,
talk about truth?
Look.
Know what this is?
The shirt...
...of our brother Matt.
Shot pointblank like a rabbit.
That's truth!
Live game, that's what we are.
And you're mad predators.
I'm not, I swear!
You're one of them!
A meatsucker!
Is that the way you talk ...
...to ladies in your rat hole?
Careful!
Oh my god!
Tell Calamity Jane to straighten out.
Or hell will break loose.
Got it.
There's a month's harvest there.
Plus the risks involved.
-Matt died for that.
-Tell her.
Corn!
There's plenty in my building.
30 huge bags
in my father's basement.
What's Whosit look like?
His name's Louison.
The guy we're supposed to grab.
May I help you?
No... It's just
an old coffee grinder.
Coffee? Some have it made!
So we went out for a walk
last night? A long one too!
There's ruckus,
there're screams...
This place is really hopping!
Your dad may work
at night but still!
Oh Julie!
You OK?
Sorry, I was
rehearsing a new number.
Wait!
Here...
Didn't you hear anything last night?
After your herbs, you kidding?
A teapot a night as you prescribed.
I'll bring you more,
you're almost out.
You should drink some,
you look overwrought.
Cheer up, she died a natural death.
Come on.
Still,
I'd like to say goodbye.
We'll do that right now.
My poor Robert...
What made you rush
into the stairs last night?
I did it for Aurore.
I wanted to save her.
She wasn't the one who screamed!
Anyway... here!
Still, I did it for her.
Besides, the butcher
was very decent. He apologized.
Invite you to dinner?
Well, I haven't much...
Fine! We'll feel lighter.
9pm right?
Sharp! I'm very punctual.
Rather rare for a girl, no?
For a girl, you're rather rare!
I owe you alot, you know.
Did you forgive?
Livingstone?
One must always forgive.
Depends. It's not always possible.
Don't say that.
No one is entirely evil.
Its circumstance.
Or they don't realize
they've done wrong.
36th sector, 5th division,
Wriggler's Avenue.
What'd that girl say?
The girl!
Sector 3/4 69deg N.E.
Albumin Square, here!
Let's go!
Scout to Sauce-Master.
Heading to target, 69 deg N.E.
Sauce-Master to Scout.
Read you, Roger.
Watch your steaks, guys!
"Come Aurore..."
"They are the worms..."
"You are the fruit!"
Again? Shoot!
It's rather quiet.
No! Not father's clubs!
Yes, your father's clubs!
See who's on TV tonight?
-I don't have a TV.
-Look!
That's your next customer, isn't it?
I'll be damned!
I've got to take off.
No offense,
but allow me the right...
to come back tonight...
...and pay my thoughts to your daughter.
Dangerous, what's that?
Audacious, we're that!
Courageous, I'll take three.
Generous, U, U, U and me!
Scout to Sauce-Master.
Corn located at site.
I repeat: Corn located.
Proceeding with mission,
phase B. Target: Louison.
I repeat: Target, Louison.
An ambush!
Aurore, what's wrong now?
Georges...
Throw in your apron?
Now I've heard everything!
Its been on my mind a while...
We're aging.
I'm losing my touch.
And so many victims...
I feel sorry for them.
Sorry?
That's not like you at all!
No one's entirely evil.
It's circumstance.
Or you don't realize
you've done wrong.
Some say you have to
forgive. You forgive me?
An old bastard like you?
I bet I could.
You are a dol.
The guys you iced wouldn't forgive.
Or you'd have to insist.
Only Julie could forgive me.
You ask her?
She won't ever.
You're her father.
She won't even speak to me.
Want me to see her?
I could talk to her.
She only thinks about that Louison.
He's not a bad guy, after all.
By the way, he's on TV tonight.
Why don't you go tell him?
I bet he doesn't even know.
He's in the clouds...
Really, you should eat something.
Not hungry!
Fox!
You have been hiding things.
You're on TV tonight.
How about that!
Livingstone...
The Criekville Casino...
I remember, we made a hit with
the Tica Tica Walk.
Tica Tica, what?
Oh shit.
That's your new number?
Let me...
...explain...
Sorry to disturb you.
I goofed again!
He has clown shoes alright.
Mission accomplished.
Call in the others.
Recipe 8: Cordon Bleu to Sniper.
Quiet down!
Artichoke Heart Souffl:
Preparation, H minus 35 minutes.
Throw in the onions.
Simmer the snipers.
Cover them for 15 minutes.
I repeat: 15 minutes.
H minus 20 minutes: Stir the sauce.
I repeat: H minus 20 minutes.
CIRCUS STARS
Julie! I didn't think you'd come.
I'll have a cup of tea.
Pardon?
A cup of tea?
You have...
I'll have one too.
Yes a nice cup of tea!
Aurore,...
...come watch, it's captivating!
"Come, Aurore"
"Come..."
I got contact lens.
"They'll make us weep and tremble..."
"Here's Stan and Livingstone!"
You didn't tell me.
Julie...
Livingstone...
Livingstone... Julie...
What a pain!
It's the antenna, pop!
What a drag!
It's the antenna.
Go straighten the wire.
In this storm ? No way!
Bastard!
It's the antenna, with the wind.
Louison!
"Aurore..."
"Come..."
"It's so much better here with us..."
Louison!
Come back!
I can't hear you.
Go inside, Julie.
Watch out!
Mr Louison?
To the right!
More!
Ok.
That is perfect!
Perfect!
Don't move!
Georges!
Aurore...
"...no more Robert..."
I fell...
"...that pervert..."
".. who just wants to sink you..."
"...in the mire.."
"Drag you in the sewer..."
"Fill you with manure..."
So it was you!
It was you all along...
I swear I'll explain.
Bastard!
It came from downstairs.
I'll hurt your leg, Robert!
Stop!
help!
You crumb! Son of a bitch!
I fell.
Yes, Aurore.
I wanted to stand
on the chair, I fell.
Yes Aurore.
The Troglos!
The Troglos are kidnapping someone!
Nice of you to make coffee.
Expecting company?
Undress.
Julie come on!
The Interligator woman
blew herself sky high.
She took her husband with
her. The place's in flame.
Stop them! Robert!
What're you doing here?
Wipe that stuff off now,
...and go home
immediately, hear me?
Take the lipstick off!
And you, I'll skin you alive!
Wait, I'll get u!
I'll get u!
Who's coming?
Snipers!
How did it go? Alright?
Everybody OK?
Look what I found.
And the others?
How did it go?
They were all arms...
a real joy ride!
And we're all here.
Shit!
Where'd she come from?
That the guy to grab?
That the one you located?
Can you explain?
What?
Wasn't that the plan?
"Albumin Square. Name: Louison."
Here, that's what it says.
It also says,
"Sex: male. Shoes: clown's."
What do you say to that?
We'd better check.
Sex: male!
So?
Look in the package and tell me...
...if the sex is male. Alright?
That's not my job. Mission
Louison was the package. You got it.
Is the sex in the
package male or not?
Who knows?
I'm in a loony bin!
I've had it with this bullshit!
There's been a mistake.
Let me go!
See guys, pure female!
Cordon Bleu calling Onion snipers...
Artichoke Heart.
I repeat:
Artichoke Heart in immediate danger!
Cordon Bleu calling Onion Snipers...
We'll pick them off like flies.
Must be cooking up there.
Count on those weirdos,
they'll fix your buddy..
for good.
What do you say? we go?
Of course we're going!
All together!
Doesn't she ever shut up?
They play too rough.
A contract...
is a contract.
Who's not in?
Rap, you come with me.
Milan, Fox Tourneur...
Take the others. Move it!
What about me?
Don't forget me!
Bastards!
In case I don't come back.
Open up!
You dimwit, give up,
we'll let you go.
We won't touch you.
We forget the whole thing.
Alright?
I need my cleavers! All of them!
Right, the cleavers!
We'll slaughter them!
Think you're on safari, bitch?
That's my wife!
No men or women now,
only volunteers!
Precisely!
Obedient ones!
Touch one...
Just one hair of my daughter
and I'll slice you into pieces.
Go get my cleavers. Hoof it!
On the double!
Where are you?
I don't like this.
It won't be long now.
Julie, go away!
It's me they're after.
Don't cry. I'll manage.
Don't cry.
It's my contacts.
What?
What are you up to?
Move your ass.
I can't. I've gained weight.
Wait... come back!
Tourneur, wait!
Shit, Tourneur's been hit!
Hey Postman, things OK?
I got one. Come see.
Those monsters are everywhere.
They've lost one,
they won't be back.
Good old Tourneur hang on!
That lead weighs you down...
No other damage?
We'll clear you out.
You'll be alright!
Let's get this over with!
Come on, push!
Let me by!
Water's running.
What the hell are they doing?
Stand back!
What are they up to?
Marcel!
Are you alright, Marcel?
Come on, get up!
Get up!
Go on! Go!
Julie, follow me!
Careful!
Julie!
About time!
Miss please...
You're dragonfly
in a mating season...
...so an old toad like me...
Beat it, old jerk, I'm busy.
Let the lady by, will you?
I go from one footbath
to another... Just my luck!
I despise you, hate you!
This time, you're done for, clown.
No more bullshit!
You're gonna sing my song!
A cleaver, damnit!
Move it!
-Take this.
-You, here?
This is a job for the Australian.
Anyway...
...you come in handy.
Holy shit!
Goddamn, Troglos!
Bastards, my Julie!
My Julie!
It's your fault, you'll pay!
Have I got something there?
Answer me, meathead!
You tell me...
I'm not dreaming...
I got something right?