This "pestilent dust"
has appeared only three times.
It was found to be limestone...
Messy, but innocuous.
- lnnocuous?
- Harmless.
I know what it means. May l?
Your Honour...
Imagine how
the neighbourhood children feel.
The pounding of construction
ringing in their ears.
This skyscraper, a tribute
to mankind's greed, grows daily.
It casts a shadow over their lives
and surrounds them with toxic dust.
Kendall Construction is rebuilding
this neighbourhood.
Granting a restraining order here
will throw 753 people out of work.
You cannot validate this groundless
example of rapacious litigation.
- It is a threat to our society.
- Let's not go off the deep end.
You have made
a compelling case, Mr. Miller.
- But there is no irreparable harm.
- Not yet.
- Is that you?
- Yeah, it's me.
- A client of yours?
- Funny!
Excuse me, sir...
I went to a restaurant the other day
and ordered coffee.
The waiter asked, "Would you
like sugar or Sweet & Low?"
I said, "Do I look like
I should be on a diet?"
- Andy.
- Hi, Doc.
Your blood work came back.
When I return, we'll discuss it.
I'll be right here.
- Hi, how are you feeling?
- Pretty good.
Make a fist for me.
We're gonna have to start
looking for veins in your feet.
- Terrific job on the Kendall case.
- Thanks, Kenneth.
Anthea, just the paralegal
extraordinaire I was hoping to see.
- The answer is no.
- Dinner at Felicia's...
- I've got a class.
- My briefs need proofing.
Exploit somebody else.
Since you've asked...
- Your exam!
- 98.
98! Congratulations!
- Let's talk about the Hansen case.
- Yeah. Thank Amy for the painting.
Here are the numbers. The copy's
on your desk. Do you need me?
No. It's 6:30. Go home.
Hello? Hi, darling.
What a surprise. How are you?
- Good.
- What does Dr. Gillman say?
She says I am fine.
My blood work is excellent.
- How about my platelets?
- Even my platelets look good.
Mom, more importantly,
how are you?
- I'm fine. Your dad is fine.
- What are you doing?
- Andy, am I interrupting you?
- In a word, Bob.
Charles wants to see you upstairs.
I was just about to take a break.
You're sure I'm not underdressed?
Andy has expressed a keen interest
in Highline versus Sander Systems.
- The participants interest me.
- It's an anti-trust action.
Is it? Sander Systems copies
Highline's spreadsheet program.
For me, the legal principle involved
is copyright infringement.
Tell me this, Andy. Which side would
you like to see emerge victorious?
Don't be influenced by my friendship
with Sander's CEO Bill Wright.
- I'd like to see Highline win.
- Why, Beckett?
If Sander Systems wins, an energetic
young company is destroyed.
Copyright laws were enacted to stop
exactly what Sander are doing.
- You know who reps Highline.
- Rodney Bailey.
He couldn't find his way around
copyright law with a map.
Apparently the fellas
at Highline agree with you.
Therefore, as of 9:03 this evening,
right after the dessert course, -
- they're now represented by Wyant,
Wheeler, Hellerman, Tetlow & Brown.
Outstanding!
And more specifically,
senior associate Andrew Beckett.
- Thank you, Robert.
- Start on Highline right away.
- I'm right on it.
- We have to file within ten days.
- Tokyo on line four, Bob.
- Walter, thank you.
- Thank you, Kenneth.
- Congratulations.
- What's that on your forehead?
- Where?
That, right there on your forehead.
I got whacked
with a racquet ball... Excuse me.
Charles... I sincerely appreciate
your faith in my abilities.
Faith is a belief in something
for which we have no evidence.
It does not apply in this situation.
Go home.
No... go back to work!
- Thank you, Charles.
- No sweat, buddy.
Tommy, how are you?
The complaint is on my desk, Shelby.
Tell Jamey to get on top of it.
Anything else?
No, I'll be working out of the house
for the rest of the afternoon.
Bye.
You want to apply the foundation
as evenly as you can.
It shouldn't look like
you threw it on with a spoon.
You don't think this
is a little too orange for me?
It's Tahitian Bronze.
That works best on these lesions.
- Say you've been to Aruba.
- I've called in sick for four days.
Now they'll think I was on a cruise.
- Fax.
- Thank you, Bruno.
We could try this Light Egypt...
- What?
- Andy?
Excuse me.
Just like my cousin Fredo.
Hi... Does anybody want a bagel?
Are you okay, Andy?
I need to go to the hospital.
- It's all right.
- I'm getting out of here.
- One more.
- Thank you for driving me here.
I told Dr. Gillman to take a day off
and she took a day off!
- Did they take a specimen?
- Blood... I'm empty.
You have a fever, baby.
- This is my guy. Excuse me...
- Just one second.
I ran to the bathroom. I almost
lost it in front of everybody.
- It's nothing to be ashamed of.
- It's just...
- Any news on my blood work?
- No. We'll do a colonoscopy.
- It sounds delightful.
- Wait. Why do that?
- Who are you?
- Who are you, Doctor...
This is my partner.
- He records all my hospital visits.
- I'm Dr. Klenstein.
A colonoscopy will show us if it's
the K.S. causing the diarrhoea.
- It could be an infection...
- A reaction to AZT.
That's possible...
He's not having this
until we cancel out everything else.
I'm trying to help your partner.
You're not a member of his family.
- I could have you removed.
- He's upset. He's sorry.
- No, don't apologize for me.
- Okay, he's not sorry.
Let's see what the blood work
tells us. I'll give a specimen.
Maybe we'll hear from Dr. Gillman.
Everybody happy?
- I'll check on the blood work.
- Sorry...
- That's the third time.
- Dr. Klenstein...
I have to call the office.
I want you to relax.
- I am relaxed.
- Good. Is there a phone around?
If you have been injured, you may
be entitled to a cash settlement...
Good Lord!
- Mr. Beckett's office.
- Shelby, it's me.
- Jamey beeped me.
- I'm glad you called.
It's about the Highline complaint.
Jamey is going ballistic!
- Calm down. Put him on.
- One second.
- Where's the Highline complaint?
- Wait! Slow down.
It was supposed to be here
this morning.
I left it in my office last night.
I put the corrected copy on my desk.
- I'm telling you, it's not here.
- All right, try my hard disk.
You'll have
to print it out yourself.
- What did you file it under?
- HL1.
You know that there's
a statute of limitations on this.
It runs out...
... in 75 minutes.
- It's not here. Andy.
- It's not there? I'm on my way!
Every problem has a solution.
Push, baby.
It's a girl!
- Take a picture, Joe.
- I can't get the film in there.
Help me, baby.
Look at her. A sweet little...
She's perfect.
Go down to the deli.
Get a pound of Scotch salmon.
Rolls, bagels...
Give me a call.
- And some champagne.
- You're that TV guy.
Dom Perignon.
$100? No, get a nice Californian.
Get it over here, she's starving.
No, not the baby... Lisa!
- lris... anybody call?
- Yes, an Andrew Beckett.
- Who's Andrew Beckett?
- Hey, Joseph!
Explain it like I'm a six-year-old.
The entire street is clear except
for a large hole under construction.
It's marked and blocked off.
You decide to cross the street
and fall down the hole.
- Now you want to sue the city.
- Yes. Do I have a case?
- Yeah, of course you do.
- Great.
Go with my assistant lris.
Sort out the fee arrangement.
We take no cash
unless we get justice.
- How's your back? Any pain?
- Now that you mention it...
- lris, take good care of him.
- I will. Mr. Beckett's here.
Mr. Beckett.
Come in.
Good to see you again, counsellor.
Judge Tate. Kendall Construction.
"lnnocuous!"
- What happened to your face?
- I have AlDS.
I'm sorry.
- Can I sit down?
- Yeah.
Look at this...
you have a new baby.
Yeah, a little baby girl.
- "It's a girl." Congratulations.
- Yeah, one week old.
- Kids are great.
- Yeah, I'm real excited about it.
- What can I do for you?
- I've been fired by Wyant Wheeler.
I want to sue them
for wrongful termination.
You want to sue Wyant, Wheeler,
Hellerman, Tetlow & Brown?
- Yes. I'm seeking representation.
- Continue.
I misplaced an important complaint.
That's their story.
Do you want to hear mine?
- Have you been to other lawyers?
- Yes, nine.
Continue.
The night before it was due, I left
a copy of the complaint on my desk.
The next day the complaint vanished.
No hard copy.
All traces of it mysteriously gone
from my computer.
Miraculously, a copy was found
just in time to get it to court.
But the next day I was summoned
to a meeting with the partners.
Hel lo, Andy. Come on in.
Hit the windows.
- Thanks. Come on in.
- Hel lo, everybody.
Thanks for coming in.
Before we begin, I'd like to say
that everyone here is your friend.
- I know that, Charles.
- More than your friend. Family.
Charles... I must apologize again
for the Highline mishap yesterday.
That was some scary moment
around here.
Thank God that no damage was done.
- This time. What about next time?
- There won't be a next time.
Something's come over you lately.
I don't know...
- A kind of stupor or fogginess.
- You have an attitude problem.
Really?
- Who thinks that?
- I do.
Excuse me...
Am I being fired?
Let me put it this way: Your place
at this firm is no longer secure.
It isn't fair to keep you here
when your prospects are limited.
- I don't want to rush you...
- We've got a committee meeting.
This is preposterous.
It doesn't make any sense.
- You do have an attitude problem.
- Take it easy.
Why did you ever give me Highline?
You nearly blew the entire case.
It could have been a catastrophe.
You concealed your illness.
That's correct.
Explain it like I'm a two-year-old.
I can't seem to grasp this.
Weren't you obliged to tell
your employer you had AlDS?
That's not the point.
I always served my clients
with absolute excellence.
If they hadn't fired me,
I'd still do that.
They couldn't fire you
for being sick, -
- so they tried
to make you look imcompetent.
Correct. I was sabotaged.
I don't buy it, counsellor.
- That's very disappointing.
- I don't see a case.
I have a case.
- If you don't want it...
- That's correct. I don't.
Thank you for your time.
Mr. Beckett...
I'm sorry about what happened.
It's a bitch.
- Have a nice day, Mr. Beckett.
- What's the matter with that guy?
Iris, get me Armbruster.
I want to see Armbruster
sometime this afternoon.
Right away, lris.
HlV-virus can only be transmitted
by the exchange of bodily fluids.
Blood, semen,
and vaginal secretions.
But they're finding out new things
about this disease every day.
Today you tell me there's no danger.
But six months from now
you may know different.
Maybe you can carry it
on your shirt or your clothes.
What are you doing?
- We're gonna draw blood.
- Why?
Joe, I've known you a long time.
Your private life is your business.
I don't need an AlDS test.
Just send the bill to my office.
Thanks for the information.
- You have a problem with gays.
- Not especially.
- Do you know any gays?
- Do you?
- Yes.
- Who?
Karen Berman. My Aunt Teresa.
Cousin Tommy in Rochester.
Eddie Meyers from the office.
- Stanley, who fixed the kitchen.
- Aunt Teresa is gay?
That beautiful, voluptuous woman
is a lesbian?
- Since when?
- Probably since she was born.
I admit it, okay. I'm prejudiced.
I don't like homosexuals.
The way they do that thing.
Don't they get confused?
"ls this yours or mine?"
I don't want to be in bed with
anybody who is stronger than me.
You can call me old-fashioned
and conservative, but I'm a man.
Any man will tell you
how disgusting that whole idea is.
- Little cave man of the house.
- You damn skippy.
- Stay away from your Aunt Teresa.
- Don't say that to her.
Guys trying to be macho
and faggot at the same time.
- I'm being totally honest with you.
- Yeah, you are.
Would you accept a client
if you were constantly thinking:
"l don't want this person
to touch me or even breathe on me?"
- Not if I was you, honey.
- Exactly... What?
Merry Christmas.
- Thank you.
- Happy New Year.
- You're the...
- TV guy.
This is the supplement.
You're right. There is a section
on HlV-related discrimination.
Thank you very much.
We do have
a private research room.
- I'm fine right here.
- I'm looking for the Murdoch case.
Just a moment.
Wouldn't you be more comfortable
in a research room?
No...
would it make you more comfortable?
Beckett, how are you doing?
Counsellor.
Whatever, sir.
Excuse me.
Who did you get?
Did you find a lawyer?
I'm a lawyer.
- How's your baby?
- She's... wonderful.
- What's her name?
- Larice.
- That's a beautiful name.
- We named her after my sister.
Look...
How did they find out you had AlDS?
One of the partners
noticed a lesion on my forehead.
But how..?
How do you go from that,
which could have been anything, -
- to deducing that you had AlDS
and terminating you on that basis?
That's a good point.
The partner who spotted the lesion,
Walter Kenton, -
- worked for Walsh, Ulmer & Brahm
in D.C.
A paralegal there, Melissa Benedict,
showed lesions on and off.
It was common knowledge
that she had AlDS.
- But they didn't fire her.
- No, they did not fire her.
Have you got a relevant precedent?
The Arline decision...
Supreme Court.
"The Federal Rehabilitation Act
of 1973, -
- prohibits discrimination
against handicapped persons -
- if they can perform the duties
required of them."
"Though the ruling did not specify
AlDS discrimination..."
"... subsequent decisions have held
that AlDS is a handicap -
- because of the physical
limitations it imposes -
- and the prejudice surrounding it,
which exacts a social death...
... that proceeds
the actual physical one."
"This is the essence
of discrimination."
"Formulating opinions about others
not based on their merits, -
- but on their membership in a group
with the same characteristics."
- Charles Wheeler.
- Julius Erving. Glad to see you.
Ken Starr.
It'll only take a minute.
Charles Wheeler. How are you doing?
A summons for you.
Take a look at it.
Dr. J., you're the best.
If you ever need a lawyer,
just give me a call.
See you in court.
You're the TV guy.
What's up?
I want to know everything
about Andy's personal life.
Does he frequent
those pathetic bars?
What other homosexual facilities
does he go to?
What deviant groups
does he secretly belong to?
- What is it, Bob?
- Let's make a settlement offer.
Andy brought AlDS into our offices,
into our men's room.
He brought AlDS
to our annual family picnic!
- We ought to be suing him.
- Show some compassion.
We gave him Highline.
Did Beckett say, "l won't be able to
function to the best of my ability?"
Now, discarding the trust
I conferred upon him, -
- Andrew Beckett proposes
to haul me into court.
To sling accusations at me.
To call me a bigot...
... in full view of the Philadelphia
judicial establishment.
Beckett doesn't want to go to court.
- A jury might side with him.
- Wait a minute...
He was fired for incompetence,
not because he has AlDS.
- Did you know he was sick?
- Did you, Bob?
No... not really.
Everybody,
this is the house that I grew up in.
Right here in
Lower Merion, Pennsylvania.
Here's proof.
There. My hand prints
from when I was a cute little boy.
Today is the 40th wedding
anniversary of my mom and dad.
- A tough life in all that poverty.
- Those can be some mean streets.
Here's the front door. I once
broke this finger in this door.
- Where's my brother?
- There's my sister Jill.
- Say hello, Alexis.
- Mommy's pregnant again.
Are you really?
- Hello, Meghan.
- Uncle Andy.
- Where's Dad?
- Fixing the snowblower.
It snows once in seven years,
and Dad buys a new snowblower.
- How are you?
- Today's a good day.
Meghan, you're doing a great job.
I've got to say hello to my sisters.
Put me down!
Parts of the trial
will be hard for you to hear, -
- about my personal life.
And there's going to be publicity.
- Do you want me to take her?
- No, she's fine.
I think it's great you're asking...
but this is really your call.
Thanks, brother.
You're my kid brother.
That's all that matters, okay?
To be honest,
I'm worried about Mommy and Daddy.
They've been through so much, and
there are some tough times ahead.
Andy, the way that you've
handled this whole thing...
... you and Miguel...
with so much courage...
There's nothing
that anybody could say -
- that could make us feel anything
but incredibly proud of you.
I didn't raise my kids
to sit in the back of the bus.
You get in there
and you fight for your rights.
I love you guys.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Forget everything you've seen
on TV and in the movies.
There will be no surprise witnesses
or tearful confessions.
You're going to be presented
with a simple fact.
Andrew Beckett was fired.
You'll hear two explanations
for why he was fired.
It is up to you
to sift through the facts -
- until you determine
what you think to be the truth.
Certain points must be proven.
One: Andrew Beckett was...
... is a brilliant lawyer.
Two: Andrew Beckett,
has a debilitating disease.
He made the legal choice to keep
this fact from his employers.
Three: His employer discovered this.
The illness here is AlDS.
Four: They panicked.
They did what most of us
would like to do with AlDS.
Get it and everybody who has it
as far away from us as possible.
Such behaviour may seem reasonable
to you. It does to me.
AlDS is an incurable disease.
But no matter what moral judgement
you make upon his employers, -
- the fact that Beckett was fired
because he had AlDS...
... means they broke the law.
Fact:
Andrew Beckett's performance
on the job varied from competent...
... to, often times, mediocre...
... to sometimes
flagrantly incompetent.
Fact:
He claims
he's the victim of lies and deceit.
Fact:
It was Andrew Beckett who lied
about his disease to his employers.
Fact:
He was successful in his duplicity.
The partners at Wyant Wheeler
did not know -
- that Andrew Beckett had AlDS
when they fired him.
Fact:
Andrew Beckett is dying.
Andrew Beckett is angry.
His lifestyle and reckless behaviour
have cut short his life.
In his anger and rage
he is lashing out.
He wants someone to pay.
Thank you.
Andrew Beckett represented
your firm in 1990, is that correct?
- That's correct.
- Were you pleased with his work?
We were satisfied
with the outcome of the litigation.
Satisfied.
Mr. Laird, you gave me sworn
testimony in your deposition.
- Is that correct?
- Correct.
You said you were impressed
and delighted with Beckett's work.
Do you recall saying that?
In all honesty I was delighted
with aspects of Andy's efforts.
But in general, I found the work
to be merely satisfactory.
Do you agree...
... that a baloney sandwich
is a satisfactory meal?
Whereas, caviar and champagne,
roast duck and baked Alaska...
... might be considered delightful?
We object. These gastronomical
comments are irrelevant.
Five months ago you characterised
Andrew Beckett as caviar.
Now he's a baloney sandwich.
What powerful force
caused this change of mind?
He hasn't changed his mind.
He's amplified his answer.
Objection sustained.
Mr. Laird, explain this to me
like I'm a four-year-old.
Did Andrew Beckett
win your lawsuit for you?
- Yes, we won.
- Congratulations. What a...
... satisfactory experience.
Ready, Mr. Beckett.
Adam and Eve, not Adam and Steve!
Do you see this
as a gay-rights issue?
I am not political.
I just want what is fair.
You are gay?
That's none of your business,
but yes, I am.
Do homosexuals
deserve special treatment?
Hell no!
Philadelphia
is the city of brotherly love.
The Declaration of Independence
was signed here.
That document says:
"All men are created equal. "
Give me a break.
- We scorn discriminatory practices.
- Thank you, Mayor.
You're not getting a little light
in the sneakers, are you, pal?
Yeah, I am, Filko. I'm changing.
I'm on the prowl.
And I'm looking for a hunk.
A real man... Iike you.
You know what we do.
You want to play sailor?
- Columbus and the first mate.
- That's not funny!
These people make me sick...
but the law's been broken.
You remember the law, don't you?
- At least we agree on one thing.
- What's that?
Tutti-fruttis make me sick, too.
Ms. Benedict, you worked
for Walsh, Ulmer & Brahm.
- At the same time as Walter Kenton?
- That's correct.
He knew the lesions on your face
and arms were caused by AlDS?
Definitely, I told all the partners.
How did Walter Kenton
treat you after that?
Every time we met,
he'd get this look on his face.
The "Oh God!" expression. As in,
"Oh God, that woman has AlDS."
Thank you. No more questions.
Ms. Benedict,
how did you contract AlDS?
Through a transfusion
just after childbirth.
So it was not your behaviour
which caused you to be infected.
You were unable to avoid it.
I guess.
Thank you.
But I don't consider myself
different to anyone else with AlDS.
I'm not guilty. I'm not innocent.
I'm just trying to survive.
Thank you, Ms. Benedict.
No further questions at this time.
You may step down, Ms. Benedict.
Apart from the marks on his face,
were there other things -
- that made you suspect he had AlDS?
He was thin and he seemed tired,
but he was working so hard.
Something was wrong.
They're trying to pretend
that they didn't notice anything.
- Objection.
- Just answer the question.
Have you ever felt discriminated
against at Wyant Wheeler?
- Yes.
- In what way?
Mr. Wheeler's secretary Lydia -
- said that Mr. Wheeler
had a problem with my earrings.
Apparently Mr. Wheeler felt
that they were too "ethnic".
She told me he'd like something
a little less garish...
- Something more "American".
- What did you say?
I said, "My earrings are American.
They're African-American."
- Let's have order, please.
- No more questions.
Ms. Burton,
weren't you recently promoted?
Yes, I'm in charge
of the paralegal department.
Congratulations on your unfettered
success at Wyant Wheeler.
Unfettered?
I don't understand this.
The promotion of an obviously
intelligent, articulate...
... qualified
African-American woman -
- in a firm which practices
wanton discrimination.
- That is what's claimed here.
- I can't explain it.
Could it be that
these instances of discrimination -
- are in fact misunderstandings that
have been blown out of proportion?
I think counsel tends
to oversimplify the issue.
Thank you, Ms. Burton,
I'll take that into consideration.
How's the trial going?
I saw you on TV.
I'm a law student at Penn.
You saw me on TV?
It's a good school, Penn.
I'm in my second year.
I just wanted to tell you -
- this case is extremely important.
You're doing a fantastic job.
When you graduate, call me.
Thank you very much.
Listen, Joe...
- Would you like to get a beer?
- No, my wife is...
I don't pick up people
in drug stores every day.
- Do you think I'm gay?
- Aren't you?
- Do I look gay to you?
- Relax.
- I ought to kick your faggoty ass.
Take it as a compliment.
That is exactly the kind of bullshit
that makes people hate your...
... faggoty asses.
- You try and kick my ass, asshole.
- No, you're the asshole, buddy!
Continue, Ms. O'Hara.
We were going crazy
looking for this complaint.
Mr. Beckett was screaming.
He looked so freaky.
Mr. Kenton kept saying,
"You lost the Highline complaint!"
All of a sudden,
Jamey comes in with the complaint.
- He says "lt was in Central Files!"
- Central Files?
That's where files are sent
when cases are closed.
Jamey got to the court just in time.
Everybody was completely wasted.
Mr. Beckett just kept saying,
"I'm sorry. I don't understand."
Thank you.
No further questions.
Mr. Miller.
- May l?
- Certainly.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
- Do you want a glass of water?
- No.
- Was Andy a good boss?
- Yes.
He was very sweet.
How would you characterize
his work as an attorney?
How would I know?
I just worked for him.
Excuse me, Your Honour,
is this for the record?
Mr. Miller, perhaps you should
return to counsel's table.
Ms. O'Hara...
Were you aware of any problems -
- that the senior partners had
with Andrew's work prior to this?
- No, I wasn't.
- Thank you. No more questions.
- Was Mr. Beckett forgetful?
- Not to my knowledge. No.
How would you go about
making a lawyer look incompetent?
Hiding an important document
for a few hours?
Making it look like
the responsible lawyer misplaced it?
Would the partners do that
if they found out Andy was sick?
Perhaps.
We've had lawyers who've had
heart attacks, ulcers, cancer...
Did you have something to do with
this file being lost accidentally?
- Objection.
- Did you misplace this file?
- Absolutely not.
- Are you a homosexual?
Answer the question.
Are you a homo? A faggot?
You know, a queen? A fairy?
Rump-roaster? Are you gay?
Objection!
Counsel's attacking his own witness.
Mr. Collin's sexual orientation
has nothing to do with this case.
Please have a seat, Ms. Conine.
Approach the bench, Mr. Miller.
Kindly share with me exactly
what's going on in your head.
Because I haven't a clue.
Your Honour...
Everybody in this room is thinking
about sexual orientation.
Sexual preference, whatever.
Who does what to whom,
and how they do it.
They're thinking
about Andrew Beckett.
Mr. Wheeler, Ms. Conine,
even you, Your Honour.
They're wondering.
I know they're thinking about me.
Let's get it out in the open...
... out of the closet.
This case isn't just about AlDS.
Let's talk about
what this case is really all about.
The general public's loathing,
hatred and fear of homosexuals.
And how that hatred translated
into the firing of this homosexual.
My client. Andrew Beckett.
Please have a seat, Mr. Miller.
Very good.
In this court, justice is blind
to matters of race, creed, colour, -
- and sexual orientation.
With all due respect,
Your Honour...
We don't live in this courtroom,
do we?
No, but with regard to this witness,
I'll sustain the objection.
How many weeks at a time
would you be out to sea?
Anywhere from two weeks
to several months.
- Any women on board?
- Not when I was in the Navy.
During these long voyages,
no women in sight...
Hundreds of hard working,
robust young men in their prime...
At the peak of their
natural appetites and desires...
- Anything going on?
- Like what?
Like two sailors down below
making flippy-flop.
Objection.
There was one.
- Objection.
- Continue, Mr. Miller.
You mean a homosexual?
He strutted around naked
trying to be noticed. It was sick.
It was destroying our morale.
We let him know what we thought.
- Did you write him a letter?
- We stuck his head in a latrine.
You taught him a lesson. Just like
firing Beckett taught him a lesson.
- You knew Ms. Benedict had AlDS?
- She didn't try to conceal it.
So you know the difference
between a bruise and a lesion?
Beckett told me
he'd been hit by a ball.
How did hearing of Ms. Benedict's
illness affect you?
She said that you were repulsed
by her and avoided her.
I feel nothing but the deepest
sympathy for people like Melissa, -
- who contracted this disease
through no fault of their own.
Andy, don't move now.
It's not going through.
We may have to flush it out again.
The vein's closed.
- We'd better call Barbara.
- Nurse Ratchett?
Tell her to come over.
There's so much stuff
I need to get done.
Can't we just skip
treatment for tonight?
No, we are not skipping
this treatment.
It's my arm and my treatment,
and I say skip it.
You know something?
- That stuff is saving your life.
- What's the matter with you?
- Close the law book.
- Let me...
The least you can do
is look at me -
- and give me
a little of your time. Got it?
You are worried we don't have
very much time left, aren't you?
No.
I'll tell you what...
We'll plan my memorial service
and prepare for the inevitable.
Maybe you should think about it.
No.
No... I've got a better idea.
Hi, Andrew. Hi, Miguel.
Joe Miller...
Lisa, nice to meet you!
This is Miguel's sister. Maria.
- Would you like a drink?
- I'll take care of Joe.
- You're looking... alive tonight.
- I had a blood transfusion.
Do you like it? I'm a lawsuit.
- Not bad. What are you drinking?
- Wine is good.
Could I have some of the red?
- I've got some questions for you.
- I'm at a party right now.
We'll get to it later.
Hi, Joe Miller.
- Do I know you?
- Mona Lisa.
- Lawsuit.
- Nice. Have fun.
Thank you.
- Congratulations, counsellor.
- With what?
You survived what I presume to be
your first gay party, intact.
When you're brought up
the way most people are, -
- there's not a lot of discussion
about homosexuality.
As a kid you're taught
that queers are funny.
Queers dress up like their mother.
That they're a danger to kids.
And that all they want to do
is get into your pants.
That pretty much sums up
the general thinking out there.
- Thanks for sharing that with me.
- Let's go over this testimony.
First, I'll ask you:
Can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined Wyant Wheeler?
Miller?
Do you ever pray?
That's not the answer I want.
But, yes, I pray.
- What do you pray for?
- I pray that...
I pray that my baby is healthy.
I prayed at her delivery.
I pray the Phillies win the pennant.
Now can we get to the questions?
Can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined Wyant Wheeler?
- Can you do that?
- I may miss the end of this trial.
Yes, I've considered that.
I've made some provisions in my will
for some charities.
- Miguel will need a lawyer.
- I know a good probate.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined Wyant Wheeler?
Do you like opera?
I'm not that familiar with opera.
This is my favourite aria.
This is Maria Callas.
This is "Andrea Chenier".
Umberto Giordano.
This is Madeleine.
She's saying how...
... during the French Revolution
a mob set fire to her house.
And her mother died... saving her.
"Look, the place that
cradled me is burning."
Can you hear
the heartache in her voice?
Can you feel it, Joe?
In come the strings
and it changes everything.
The music fills with a hope.
And that'll change again. Listen.
Listen.
"l bring sorrow
to those who love me."
Oh, that single cello.
"lt was during this sorrow
that love came to me."
"A voice filled with harmony."
"lt said, live still."
"l am life."
"Heaven is in your eyes."
"ls everything around you
just the blood and mud?"
"l am divine."
"l am oblivion."
"l am the god...
... that comes down from the heavens
and makes of the earth a heaven."
"l am love!"
"l am love."
I'd better get out of here.
Lisa... I told her that...
- I'll look over the Q & A.
- No, you're ready.
Jesus...
God!
I love you, little Larice.
Left hand on the Bible.
Do you swear to tell the truth?
- I do.
- Please be seated.
Andrew...
Can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined Wyant Wheeler?
Wyant Wheeler
aggressively recruited me.
The were a very prestigious firm.
I was impressed with the partners.
- lncluding Charles Wheeler?
- Particularly Charles.
- What impressed you?
- The kind of lawyer he was.
- What kind was that?
- One of great legal knowledge.
A genuine leader. Gifted at
bringing out the best in others.
An awesome ability to illuminate
complex legal problems -
- to a colleague, a courtroom,
to the man on the street.
The kind of man who can play three
sets of tennis but doesn't sweat.
Underneath an elegant surface
he has an adventurous spirit.
Did you ever tell Charles Wheeler
you were gay?
- No, I didn't.
- Why not?
In a law firm you're not really
supposed to have a personal life.
I did plan
to tell Charles eventually.
But then something happened
at the racquet club.
About three years ago.
Somebody started telling jokes.
What do you call a woman who
has PMS and ESP at the same time?
- I don't know.
- A bitch who knows everything.
Sounds like somebody I know.
- How does a faggot fake an orgasm?
- He throws hot yogurt on your back.
- How did that make you feel?
- Relieved...
... that I never told him I was gay.
Just very relieved.
- Are you a good lawyer?
- I'm an excellent lawyer.
- What makes you that?
- I love the law.
I know the law.
I excel at practicing it.
- What do you love about the law?
- Many things.
What do I love most about the law?
Every now and again,
not often, but occasionally, -
- you get to be a part
of justice being done.
It really is quite a thrill
when that happens.
Thank you, Andrew.
You said earlier you aspired to be
a person of adventurous spirit.
- Is that correct?
- Something like that.
- Do you take risks?
- In this job you have to.
Did your doctor ever tell you
to reduce stress?
That long hours at work
might speed up your illness?
My doctor mentioned
the impact AlDS... Excuse me...
My doctor mentioned the impact
of stress on the immune system.
Have you ever been to the
Stallion Showcase Cinema?
I've been to...
... that...
I've been to that theatre
three times in my life.
- What type of movies do they show?
- Gay movies.
- Gay pornographic movies?
- Yes.
Objection, Your Honour.
This kind of questioning is vital
to the issue of credibility.
Let's see where this is going.
Continue, counsellor.
- Do men have sex there?
- Some men.
Have you ever had sex
with anyone in that theatre?
- I'm Robert.
- Andy.
Yes, once.
Approximately what year
did that event take place?
I guess it was 1984...
... 84 or 85.
Were you aware in 1984
of the fatal disease called AlDS?
And that you could contract it
through sexual activity?
I'd heard of something...
The gay plague.
The gay cancer.
We didn't know how you could get it
or that it killed you.
Do you need a break, Mr. Beckett?
No... I could use some water.
John, would you bring
Mr. Beckett some water, please?
While you were at Wyant Wheeler,
you did hide the fact -
- that you were an active
homosexual. is that correct?
No. That's not correct.
I never lied about it.
As a homosexual, one is often
forced to conceal one's sexuality.
- lsn't that right?
- In some circumstances, yes.
You have spent your life pretending
to be something that you're not.
- Concealment and dishonesty...
- I object.
I'll withdraw it.
Were you living with
Miguel Alvarez in 1984, -
- when you had your...
... anonymous sexual encounter
in the porn theatre?
Yes.
- So you could have infected him?
- Miguel has not been infected.
You didn't answer my question.
Could you have infected him?
Yes.
You say the lesions on your face
were clearly visible.
That's right.
Is it your contention that when
the partners saw these lesions, -
- they leapt to the conclusion
you had AlDS and they fired you?
As painful as it is...
... to accuse my colleagues
of such reprehensible behaviour...
... it is the only conclusion
I could come to.
Do you have any lesions on your face
at this time?
One, here... by my ear.
- May I approach the witness?
- Yes, you may.
Remembering that you're under oath,
answering truthfully...
Can you see the lesions on your face
in this mirror from three feet away?
Answering truthfully.
At the time I was fired,
the lesions were much bigger.
Answer my question, please.
No, I can't really see them.
No more questions.
We'll take a break now.
We'll reconvene in the morning.
I hate this case.
- I'd like five minutes in redirect.
- Mr. Beckett, can you go on?
Three minutes.
May I borrow your mirror, please?
Andrew...
Do you have any lesions
on your body -
- that resemble the lesions you had
on your face when you were fired?
Yes, on my torso.
I would like to ask Andrew
to remove his shirt -
- so we can all
see what we're talking about.
Objection. It would
unfairly influence the jury.
If Andrew's illness forced him
to use a wheelchair, -
- would he have to park it outside
so as not to influence the jury?
This is AlDS.
Let's see what we're talking about.
I'll allow it.
Please remove your shirt.
- God, what a nightmare.
- He asked for it.
- Can you see these lesions?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Do you swear to tell the truth?
- I do.
Please be seated.
Mr. Wheeler, were you aware
that Andrew Beckett had AlDS -
- at the time of his departure
from Wyant Wheeler?
- No.
- For absolute clarity...
Did you fire Andrew Beckett
because he had AlDS?
No. I did not fire Andrew Beckett
because he had AlDS.
Can you explain in a way
that leaves no doubt -
- why you promoted
Andrew Beckett in your firm?
And then, most importantly,
why you asked him to leave?
If you're the owner of a ball club,
you recruit the hot rookie.
Andy was tremendously promising.
Fresh out of Penn. Crackerjack.
That's why we hired him,
and why we stuck by him for so long.
Why did you give him
all this opportunity?
When you've groomed someone
the way we groomed Andy, -
- nurturing him and lavishing
special treatment on him, -
- it's quite an investment.
We were waiting for the promise
to deliver.
But ultimately, we could not ignore
the gap between reality and promise.
Thank you, Mr. Wheeler.
No more questions, Your Honour.
- Objection, Your Honour.
- All right, Mr. Miller.
Mr. Wheeler, you are magnificent.
You are my hero. Andrew's right.
You are the greatest.
Are you gay?
Objection.
- How dare you!
- The witness will kindly answer.
No, I am not a homosexual.
Isn't it true that when you realized
your future senior partner was gay -
- and had AlDS, it drove fear right
through your heterosexual heart?
Remembering the hugs
and the handshakes. The sauna.
The friendly pats on the backside
that guys exchange sometimes.
It made you say, "My God!
What does this say about me?"
Objection.
The witness will please
respond to the question.
Mr. Miller, your innuendos
and locker-room fantasies -
- can't hide the fact your client
only worked when he wanted to.
Telling us what he thought we needed
to know about who he really was.
Andy insisted on bending the rules.
His work suffered as a result.
Explain it like I'm a six-year-old,
because I just don't get it.
Who makes these rules? You?
Read your Bible, Mr. Miller.
Old and New Testament.
Valuable rules.
- Excuse me...
- Andrew?
I can't...
Somebody get a doctor.
Turn him over.
Call an ambulance.
Let him breathe. Please, make room.
It's not working!
It's making him worse!
Did you notice any changes
in Andrew's appearance -
- in the year
leading up to his termination?
- Yes, I did.
- Were they for the better or worse?
Sometimes for the better,
but generally for the worse.
Mr. Seidman, what did you think
caused these changes in appearance?
I was afraid...
I suspected Andy had AlDS.
- Order!
- Thank you. Your witness.
Did you share your suspicions
with any of the other partners -
- before the decision
to fire Andrew Beckett was made?
No, I didn't mention it to anyone.
Not even Andy.
I didn't even give him a chance
to talk about it.
And I think I'm going to regret that
for as long as I live.
- Any more questions?
- That's all.
They are saying
that he wasn't a good lawyer.
Yet they gave him a lawsuit for
one of their most important clients.
They say that doesn't prove
anything. It was just a test.
They call it a "carrot".
They wanted to see
if he would rise to the occasion.
Say I had to send up a pilot up
in a plane that cost $350 million.
Who am I gonna put in that plane?
Some rookie, to see
if he can rise to the challenge?
Or am I gonna give that assignment
to my best pilot?
My most experienced... my top gun.
I just don't get that.
Will somebody explain it to me...
"like I'm a six-year-old".
- Juror number 6?
- I agree.
- Juror number 7?
- Juror number 10?
- I disagree.
- Juror number 1 1?
- I agree.
- Juror number 12?
- Have you awarded any damages?
- Yes, we have.
For back pay and loss of benefits,
we award $143,000.
For mental anguish and humiliation,
we award $100,000.
And for punitive damages,
we award $4,782,000.
You may record the verdict.
Everyone remain seated
until the jury is removed.
This trial is now concluded.
Congratulations.
- We'll get a reversal on this one.
- We'll get started in the morning.
Congratulations, Mr. Miller.
I'll see you at the appeal.
Congratulations, well done.
- Thanks a lot.
- I'll see you at the hospital.
Mr. Miller, hi.
He's just down the hall.
I doubt he'll leave the hospital.
If he does, he won't be
how he was before this crisis.
He's lost the vision in one eye.
And because of CMV
he will not regain his vision.
- Next door on the right.
- CMV has ravaged his body.
Congratulations.
The man of the hour.
Hi, Joe.
We are so grateful to you.
- Can I take that for you?
- It's some cheese... and stuff.
How are you doing?
What do you call a thousand lawyers
chained together on the sea bed?
- I don't know.
- A good start.
Excellent work, counsellor.
I thank you.
It was great working with you,
counsellor.
I'd better go.
Sure thing.
I'll see you later?
Thanks for stopping by.
I'll see you again.
I'll keep it on ice for you.
- He's a fighter.
- I just want to get him home.
Thank you, Joe.
What do you call a thousand lawyers
chained together on the sea bed?
- A good start.
- Very amusing.
I'll see you tomorrow, buddy.
God bless you, Andy.
Good night, son.
Try to get some rest.
- I love you, Andy.
- I love you too, Dad.
See you first thing tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
- Come on, sweetheart.
Good night, my angel.
My sweet boy.
Let me help you.
Miguel...
I'm ready.
Joe, it's Miguel.
English subtitles - lFT