Due to the threat of Fascism
and world War l,
A crowd ofjobless pilot
Is driving their planes in the sky,
Doing the thief business.
The air security unit
takes encircle and suppress action.
Air pirates are most afraid of
this movie's leading actor,
Porco Rosso.
Porco was once the hero in the air unit,
but for unknown reason
He refused to return to the unit,
and make curse,
He then became a fat piggy.
Only his old air unit partner Gina knows
How he used to be. How did Porco fight with
air pirates ...
Porcoros
Yeah?!
Porco Rosso, get going.
'Mamma Aiuto' is on the move.
'Mamma Aiuto'?
I don't need a cheap job.
A charter ship from Venice was attacked.
They are stealing fuel from the ship.
Is that it?
Ah... Well...
Girl students on vacation were on board.
It's going to be more costly then you think.
I'm going to apply part three
of the contract 14 to this case.
And part four, too.
Stop,
or I'm going to sink you! Stop!
I'm going to be kidnapped, yeah!
They're pirates, sea pirates!
It's 'sea pirates'. It's 'air pirates'.
It needs 'overhaul', huh...
Are you bad guys?
Yeah.
Are we hostages?
You guys are called air pirates,
aren't you?
You know a lot.
It's a skull.
Neat, isn't it?
Hurry up kids! I'm busy.
Do you want all 15 of them?
It's not nice for a girl
to be left behind, don't you think.
I'm late
The girls were kidnapped!
Bring the girls back!
They went that way!
No...! not that way!
I know what they are thinking.
Because they're poor and stingy
and want to save on gasoline
they will change their course to nearest island
as soon as they're out of sight.
Shit!
Damn it!
This is no good.
Here we are.
What the heck is this?
A sightseeing plane around the islands.
A pig!
It's a pig!
It's a pig. What a cute pig...
You girls could be kidnapped here.
Watch out babes!
Cool! He's cool!!
What a nuisance!
We are flying! Let me see, let me see!
Hey, kids. Don't.
Shut up, shut up, please.
Hey, do something, will you?
That's why I asked
if we wanted to take all of them.
Ok, just for a little bit.
Coz you are too naughty...
Wow! Wonderful!
Hey, look at that!
It's a red plane.
Where, where!
He is over there, isn't he?
Yes!
I'm not going to let you go any further.
See, he is coming.
That's Porco Rosso!
Hey, I can't see. I can't see.
Holly cow!
It stopped.
We are gonna fall.
Not yet!
We have one more engine!
Damn it. What the heck are you doing!
Shoot, shoot him, shoot him down!
Wow! That red plane is cool isn't it?
You can't hit him, can you?
You're in my way.
The morse code!
You loose. Listen to me.
Shut up!
There, he is coming! Here!
Get your heads down!
Where,
where is he?
He must be hiding.
Wow. We are sinking.
Let's go, let's go! Come!
We are not sinking.
This is a plane!
Sank!
Don't! It's dangerous!
Stop them.
They are very valuable hostages to us!
Don't worry, mister.
We are students at the swimming school.
Oh, no. Me, too.
Contact from the pig again.
I'm going to allow you
to take half of the gold coins.
But leave the rest of the coins
and the hostages, behind!
If you don't,
I'm going to kill you all!
says the pig. But...
A half of the coins!?
Keep your mouth shut!
Come on, Pig.
Let's have the fight!
You go to hell!
Here we go! What?!
It's broken.
It's over, it's over.
Bye bye, play with us again, will you?
Bye bye.
Everything is fine, isn't it?
Since we have enough money for repairs
You, idiot. Be greedy!
Calm down, calm down, will you.
Don't touch that,
it will get broken.
Don't go close to the propeller.
Uhm? Pee? Do it around there, will you?
Mamma Aiuto's guys
said they couldn't come to see us.
Shit! Such a pig became a hero...
but, the young fella is an American,
isn't he?
If he is,
that's a shame for the pilots
of the Adriatic.
Oh, not at all.
His grandmother is quarter ltalian.
Anyway, we should do something
about the Porco.
We have a great deal of trouble.
But, 10%/! That's not fair.
Here he comes.
He sucks. He is a fake.
Shhh...
Mr. Porco Rosso!
I'm a reporter for
the Neptune newspaper,
you did anther great job,
again.
I think 'Mamma Aiuto'
is not going to appear again for a while.
About your estimated bounty this year, people
said the amount must be over that of the last year...
Ouch! ... Wait. Let go of me.
Listen to a song in silence.
She is a wonderful lady.
Madam Gina of the hotel Adriano
is very famous among the pilots
through out this country.
During her song, even air pirates
and bounty hunters become good guys.
Is that plane up front yours?
Yeah, it's a plane of the rattle snake,
bringing me fame and fortune.
The plane beat an ltalian
at the Schneider cup, twice.
Not only is it fast,
but it is also and excellent fighter.
I heard that a small pig named Porco Rosso
is famous around here.
If you make a deal with the air pirates,
watch your tail 'cowboy'.
They are misers and are poor, too.
They stink,
for they don't take a shower.
Uh... I know that.
What!
Come on, you little chicken shit!
What's going on tonight?
You're up to no good, aren't you?
He, he, he, he, yes mam.
I'm glad you came,
but don't play war games.
We know, Gina.
We don't work within 50km
from this establishment.
We are getting along with even that pig.
You're good boys.
See you later.
Whaa, whaa, what are you doing!
Hi, Porco, tell me your story.
Next time two of us are alone.
That Mr. America is funny.
As soon as he sees me...
Will you marry me?
So I told him: I married three pilots,
first died in the war,
the second died in Atlantic Ocean,
and the last one died in Asia..
You got the news?
I got it today.
It's says the remains were found
in the forest of Bengal.
I have been waiting for three years.
My tears dried up long ago.
Good guys always die.
For my friend.
Marco, thank you for staying with me
all these years. You are the best friend.
The only thing I don't like
is that you don't want
to take that picture off.
Don't break it, you promised me.
That's only left picture
of Marco as a human
How can we break your curse?
That American is very talented...
I envy you.
I wish I would make money like you.
This is the payment for this month.
You've payed off the entire loan
for the airplane.
Let's see, how about buying some patriots bond
in devotion to our country?
I'll let the humans do that.
Welcome, Mr. Porco Rosso.
This is ready.
Give me 60 rounds of ammo as well.
O.K.
This country is busy, isn't it?
Oh, yeah.
The government is probably going to change?
If so,
people like you will be outlaws.
Country and law
don't mean anything to a pig.
You're right, Mr. So goes for a mole.
Is it ok like usual?
We have a new supply of an incendiary bomb.
Hey, kid. I'm not going to war.
See you.
Welcome...
Excuse me, boss.
Could you tell me the difference
between a soldier and a bounty hunter?
Uhm... You're a scum
if you can't win in war.
You're useless and stupid
if you can't make a fortune.
I've never heard of an air pirate
who was deeply in debt.
We had nothing to barter with, Captain.
We couldn't even pay for paint.
There's ships up ahead!
Why do I have to stay
with such pathetic looking group?
It's due to the pig, the crimson pig.
What?
Guys of 'Aiuto',
they don't even have money for paint.
Poor looking boys.
Well, we are finally complete.
Hey, is Mr. America around?
Yes, he is in the sun.
Juts like we told.
I sighted the target!
It's the Queen of Mediterranean!
Are we going to take on such a big ship?
That's why we prepared well.
Don't be afraid!
My engine is in trouble.
I'm going to back you up. You go first.
You are cunning!
Do as we agreed!
We share cost of repairs
and expenses when we loose, don't we?
You, stingy...
Of course we share them!
we need to share the bullets too?
Altak is the only right candidate
to speak out here!
We've just discussed this issue.
You cunning bitch!
If we can't share that, I will quit...
Shut up! Calm down!
Attention please, attention please.
Air pirates are attacking this ship,
but there is nothing to worry about.
This ship has excellent fighters.
Let me introduce them.
No. 1 is the black stallion,
signore Bulkar,
and No.2 is the seawolf, Visconti.
I didn't know they had fighter protection.
How can it be?
It's totally a mess.
Come in this way.
It's Curtis
Pass it to me!
This engine finally had it. Well,
Iooks like I'll have to take it to Milan.
... they were shot down,
but they succeeded in escaping
by parachute.
The air pirates, who took all the money
and gold away from the ship,
Ieft the following message,
'You are next, pig!
Come get it, pig!'.
I repeat,
'You are next,pig.
Come get it, pig.'
This crime...
You guys are special kind of trash.
I'm sorry, but I'm going on vacation.
White sheets,
beautiful ladies...
Don't give out on me yet, Mr. Engine.
I don't like this weather.
Well, guess I'll have
to go under the clouds.
Oh, good boy, hang in there.
Yes, you are a good boy, engine.
Rosso!
Fight me man to man.
I don't have time to play with you.
Don't run away,
or I'm going to tell everybody about it.
See you later, Mr. America, ha ha ha...
Shit, I'm out of the clouds.
Jesus.
Gotcha!
No, you didn't.
It's broken.
I did it!
Now, I'm a celebrity.
They are not going to believe me
if I don't bring back any proof.
Let's see...
Yes!
This cheap, crimson colored piece.
This is it.
This will be a nice gift
for my mom in Alabama.
Please hurry up.
Madam,
madam. Telephone, please.
He is alive after all.
Please get the phone at the front desk.
Marco, is this you?
Did you get hurt?
I was about to leave to pick you up.
Ok, that's fine.
I lost some weight, because I was stranded
on a desert island. I'm going to
Milan to repair my plane.
If that Mr. America stops by your hotel,
tell him this, please,
See you again next time.
What? You think of me as a
bulletin board or something?!
However I'm worried about you guys,
pilots like you regard women
as nails in a landing pier
or something insignificant.
Marco,
you're going to end up as roast pork someday.
I'd hate to witness such a miserable funeral.
A pig who doesn't fly is just an ordinary pig.
Marco, you fool!
Bright red broken wing.
I guess you would come tonight.
I come to disturb you again!
You lost too much this time.
Why don't you just build another one?
I want to keep this one.
I know how you feel.
Step aside, please.
I need drive into the factory.
Who is that cute girl?
My granddaughter,
who was living in America.
Alright, alright, alright.
Nice plane.
It's neat grandpa.
Good design.
There is almost no workers to do the job
like this these days.
She doesn't resemble you.
Is she really your granddaughter?
Don't touch her!
Fio, I leave this to you.
Ok. I'll do it.
The opponent is Curtis.
I need 15 knots more.
Curtis? I've hear of him.
See this.
This is a Hallvolley, isn't it.
Don't ask how I got this.
An ltalian plane
which had this engine lost a race
with Curtis at Schneider's cup in 1927.
But it lost due to poor engineering,
not this engine.
This is exciting.
Don't tune it up too delicately.
My plane is not for such racing.
An Asian proverb calls this Preaching
a sermon to buddha.. Did you know that?
Are you going to take all of my money?
These days,
rolls of bills aren't worth a damn.
Give me money in your pocket,
for propeller and paint and ...
This is for living expenses,
such as hotel and meals.
You can stay here.
I'm not going to charge you much. Meals included.
I don't see your sons.
Are they alright?
All three left looking for works.
Then... who is going to design my plane?
Fio is.
Fio! That's a girl I saw, isn't she.
She is young,
but she's got something my sons lack.
Hey, old man.
We've known each other for long time,
but I'll look
for another repairman this time.
Wait.
You are nervous because
I'm a woman, aren't you?
Or, I'm too young to do it?
Both, Miss.
Ok. I agree with you.
Well, can you tell me the first priority
of being a good pilot?
Experience?
No, inspiration, I think.
Oh, I'm glad you didn't say experience.
Anyway, I heard from grandpa
that you flew at an early age.
And have been an excellent pilot since then.
That was 1910, when I was 17.
17! That's the same age I am now.
I can't quit being a woman,
but let me do the job, will you?
If I can't do it well, don't pay me.
Is it ok, grandpa?
She is my granddaughter, she'll do well.
In my case, I was able
to fix engines at the age of 12.
Could you sleep here tonight?
I'll make your bed tomorrow.
The breakfast is at 7:00am.
You can take a hot shower.
I've you left a towel already.
Have a good night.
You don't have enough money.
We know each other well,
so will make the rest a loan.
Good-morning. Did you sleep well?
Did you stay up all night?
This is the rough plan.
What do you think?
I want to redesign this wing section,
leaving the plane shape as it is.
This will make your plane fly faster.
I'm surprised at the original plan.
The wing was also made of wood.
This plane is great.
The designer who designed
this wing must have know the wood very well.
I'm really impressed.
This is the only plane of its kind made,
nobody used it,
just put in the store room.
No wonder!
I'm surprised that this radical design
allows you to take off from water surface.
Only take offs and
landings give me some difficulty.
It behaves strange during the flight.
At 0.5 degrees to the angle
of the wings, right?
Everything should be fine then.
You'll let me continue with this,
won't you?
Thank you, Mr.! I'll do my best!
But let me tell you something, Miss.
Don't stay up all night.
Insomnia prevents
you from doing an excellent job.
And it is not good for your beauty.
Thank you for your advice.
Well,
to be honest,
I couldn't sleep well last night.
I was worried that
you won't let me do this job.
Well, I'm very sleepy now.
I'll make a coffee for you.
Is she going to build this plane alone?
Next is my niece, Monica.
She is will be in charge of general construction.
Nice to meet you.
This is a wife of my nephew, Silvana.
She is going to do finishing construction.
These are daughters of my relatives.
Sophia, Laura, Constance, Valentina.
This is Fio's elder sister, Giliora.
Oh, you're looking for me?
This is Sandra, my cousin.
You look so pretty Marietta.
Wives of my sons,
Maria,
Tina, Anna, and her younger sister Birreta.
Angelino!
Grandma!
Are you still alive?
You've grown up to be a nice boy!
Are you ladies going to work?
Yes, I'd like to have some money
for my great-grandchildren.
There are no man here, right?
Ah...
All these are your relatives?
Yes, they don't have any jobs these days.
All the men went to other places to work.
Because of the 'Great Depression'?
Don't worry.
Girls are nice,
they work very well and are also gutsy.
Making an airplane is in no way
like baking a cake, I think...
Dear God.
You gave my company,
which was about to go bankrupt,
a piece of bread and a job.
Please forgive us,
who make a fighter plane with ladies.
Amen.
Well, let's eat well and work hard!
Sounds good!
This engine is quite something!
What do you say, it's nice, isn't it?
Don't over do it
or this factory will be gone.
Huh, you think Curtis is not worth it?
Uh-hm, sure, this is a good idea.
So, let me do it.
But, this is going to cost a fortune.
I got a lot of bills already.
I'm not sure what sponsor thinks.
Porco...
Ok, ok. Don't look at me like that.
Do it your way.
Yes! I've already talked to manufacturers.
I will order these immediately.
Porco, I love you!
Wait at least three months, will you?
I want to change my job
and become an air pirate.
She is a nice girl, isn't she.
Don't touch her.
If I would be henpecked,
I could not feel happy.
You're a major, ah.
You rose in the world, Fierrali.
You, fool. Why did you come back?
I make it a rule to go wherever I want to.
The government is not going
to let you go this time.
Did somebody follow you?
I gave them the slip.
A warrant for your arrest
is going to be issued.
Hey, this is no time to laugh.
They say they will confiscate your plane.
This movie is crap, don't you think.
Hey, Marco, come back to the air force.
I would make a room for you.
I'd rather be a pig then a fascist.
The era of sky adventures has gone.
The only thing left for us to do is
to fly for such ridiculous reasons
as the country or the nation.
You are a pig after all, huh?
Thanks for your advice, Fierrali.
Give my regards to the others.
This is a nice film, don't you think.
Watch your tail cowboy.
They don't sue a pigs, but...
Goodbye, my comrade.
Porco, need a ride?
Hey, you're a life saver.
I borrowed this because
I need to take your plane to the lake tomorrow.
It's for a test flight, right?
I don't need the test flight.
I need to fly as soon as possible.
Don't be such a fool.
I'm not going to give you the plane
without testing it.
Besides, it will take almost a day
to take it apart and transport it to the lake.
We don't have much time.
Take a look back, will you, slowly.
That's the fascists secret police.
They were following you, Fio.
Me? Why? For what?
Because I gave them the slip.
And, because you are working on my plane.
Porco, are you really a spy?
Ha, ha, ha, ha! l? A spy?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Look, a secret agent works much harder then l.
But, you were a hero at the time of war.
This is strange if you didn't do anything...
I think so, too.
This is not right way!
Looks like your used to being in big trouble.
Well, we will be very busy.
You can fly anytime you want.
Two guys are hiding in the backyard,
and three in the front.
This excites me!
Hey, don't ramble.
See you later.
Take care of yourself.
Fio! What are you doing?
I'm going, too. Wait for five minutes, please!
I want to prepare my seat.
Give me a break!
Do you understand what you are saying!
Shh... Don't talk so loud.
Fio.
Look. You are a daughter of a decent man.
Besides, you are not married yet.
Would you hold this for a moment?
Thank you. I made this in a hurry, look!
This really fits.
Would you hold that?
Hey, Miss. I'm a wanted
bounty hunter by the government.
I'm not going to be playing with this plane.
I'm sorry,
but I have responsibility for this plane.
But, I'm going to take off from the canal
in the back.
And I'm not even sure
if I can fly without any problems.
And, when you're going to fight Curtis
you'll need me as an excellent engineer.
Hey, I'm a man, you know.
We are going to be
camping alone on a deserted island.
I don't care,
I like camping very much.
I'm not talking about THAT.
Take her with you.
I want you to win and pay the debt.
You've got to beat Curtis
My company may go bankrupt
if you don't pay it.
Are you really
this girl's grandfather?
You don't have to pay her any money.
I'm going to install this phone for you two.
You really want her to
be wanted by the police.
No. I'm going to be Porco's hostage.
That way they can excuse
their cooperation with you.
So, please, take me with you.
Take off the machine gun on the right side.
What? There's almost no space
even if you got a small butt.
Take off one machine gun!
Whoa! Thanks! My butt is bigger then it looks.
It will be just a minute
for me to take the gun off.
I want to take off as soon as possible.
If I don't do it,
looks like the old ladies are gonna say
they want to come with me as well.
Grandma, hurry, hurry.
Fio. You don't have get me a souvenir.
Contact.
Open the door!
Let it go!
Give me money!
How is the steering, Porco?
This is kind of like a tomboy,
just like you.
Stop the plane at once!
We need to make adjustments!
We don't have the time to do it.
Just do your job!
It's wet with water.
There a ship up ahead!
Let's fly!
Easy, easy, tomboy!
The turning wing is shifting to the right.
Use the tab!
The tab?
The one I put in anew!
Hurry!
Good. It became a nice boy all of a sudden.
Beautiful.
How beautiful the world is!?
Is he following us?
No. He is not attacking.
That's a parade plane of the
ltalian Air Force.
Looks like it's Fierrali...
Do you know him?
The Air Force lies in wait up ahead.
He says he'll tell us how to escape them.
He also says that
we should fly low to the Adriatic Sea.
Thanks, comrade!
Thank you!
He said,
Don't cast pearls before a swine,
Iooking at you, Fio.
You are so beautiful.
You look like a rose blooming
in a secret flower garden.
You, bastard! This is private garden.
I really want you to look at this.
Oh, this is from Hollywood.
About the production
of the scenario and casting you sent,
we are in the middle of preliminary trials
The title is A bouquet of the Adriatic Sea.
That's nice.
Really? That means O.K., doesn't it?
Gina, come to Hollywood with me.
I was air pirates' guardsman
to obtain a fame and fortune.
Next I want to be a Hollywood star.
And, then?
The President!
I'm serious.
I promise to make you the first lady.
Gina.
I like your for such stupidity.
Really?
But I say no,
because I already have a gamble going.
When I'm in this garden,
if he comes over here, I will love him.
But he comes only to the
restaurant at night.
And never emerges in the daylight.
That guy is coming back.
Fool...
He left without getting off the plane.
I lost the gamble again.
You're kidding!
The gamble is about that guy?
Is that a problem?
Life is more complicated
here than in your country.
Here I can fall in love anytime I want.
Kid, go to Hollywood by yourself, OK?
Kid...
I hit my head because you did an acrobatic
maneuver all of a sudden.
I just said hello to my friend.
To Gina of the hotel Adriano?
She wore a white dress and
was at the terrace of the hotel, wasn't she?
My grandpa told me that
all pilots of the Adriatic Sea
fall in love with Gina
You speculate a lot.
So, how is the lady?
You fell in love with her too,
didn't you?
We are going down refuel.
Close your mouth,
or you'll bite your tongue.
Wa! Wait! Uwaa...
A girl on a fighter?
Where's Porco?
He is talking with my dad.
Not only the temporary government
but guys in the King's faction have
tried to get along with the air pirates.
Here you are.
Thanks.
No thanks for such a bad news...
You'd better present yourself to either side.
They will pay a fortune for your skill.
You got a cigarette?
Curtis is will go back to
America sooner or later.
It's us who should to go to America.
Goodbye
to freedom in the Adriatic Sea.
Is it Byron's?
No, it's mine.
See you later.
Porco, this is bad news.
The gas price is three times
as much as in ltaly.
Don't be like a businessman,
make it cheaper.
This gas is genuine.
That's why I hate women.
Hey, Mr. Would you tell her...
Pay him, Fio.
After that, put your big butt and your looks
in the space between the machine guns.
We're going to fly to my home.
I'll add the gas bill to the other bills.
Nobody can live alone.
We rely on each other.
Nobody lives around here,
even though the landscape is beautiful.
Here we are.
That island is my home.
It's a wonderful place.
An excellent co-ordinator.
Ohh... my butt is stiff from the long flight.
The pig...
Don't move!
They stinks, again...
Boss, we caught him! Boss!
Shit! Don't step on me... Back off!
I was waiting for you, pig!
I knew you'd coming here.
You gave us a lot of trouble.
It's a girl.
The pig is with a girl.
She is pretty...
Shut up! What's about a girl?
About a half of the worlds
population are women!
Hey, that girl is not an ordinary one.
She is a chief engineer
at the Piccolo company.
But, she is very young and pretty.
That girl?
She made my plane much better then before.
She may be young, but she's really something.
Is that true?
You are good with airplanes in general.
Be polite, boys.
She came with me to collect my debts.
You are deeply in debt after all.
It serves you right!
Damage?
Are you going to break the plane I made?
Are you going to break
such beautiful airplane with axes?
Miss,
there is a complicated reason behind this...
You are going to break, aren't you?
But, what I want to say is...
Are you guys really fighter pilots?
Would you back off? My shoes.
I have grown up with a lot of stories
about the pilots since I was a small child.
My grandpa always told me that
no one is as nice as the pilots.
It's because sea and
sky purify their hearts.
Hence, the pilots are much
braver then the sailors,
and more proud then the ordinary pilots
Don't tell me.
I know that.
What they want the most, he said,
is neither money nor women,
but honor.
Yes,
you're right!
A toast to the pilots!
She's really something.
I understand.
I'll give up on breaking the plane,
you made, with axes.
But we'll be mortified
if we don't do anything.
Let's lynch the pig!
Lynch the pig!
What the hell you talking about!
You guys don't understand anything.
I asked whether you feel ashamed or not.
Aren't you ashamed of being helped by Curtis,
the American?
If your mother heard of that,
she would cry,
and don't even take a shower.
Porco came back to fight against Curtis,
for pride and honor of the
pilots of the Adriatic.
You guys are lowest of the low!
I told you not to hire Curtis, eh!
Just like a girl.
Don't try to excuse yourself.
Boss, what are we supposed to do?
She convinced us.
How about asking Curtis to fight the pig?
Do we ask him to fight the PIG, again?
The contract is already over.
I'm ashamed of it...
That's Curtis!
I got it.
I'm not going to run away!
You made your passage through there?
Hey, hold this.
You want a return match, don't you.
But I won once, already.
Besides, I am not a bounty hunter
for these guys.
What's your proposition?
Beautiful!
Will you marry me if I win?
I'm serious.
O.K.
Instead, if Porco wins,
you pay these bills.
Wait, Fio!
You back off!
Miss, you still have time
to think about that.
Ask him, not me.
This is very expensive.
It's very cheap.
Are you going to fight or not?
I'm willing to fight
for love.
O.K.
Listen up everybody.
I'm really impressed
with Miss Fio's decision.
We, 'Mamma Aiuto',
are going to back up this fight up!
Yes...
Let the air pirates union do this, too!
Miss Fio! See you soon!
This sucks!
Hey pig, don't run away!
Shut up, get lost!
Bye-bye!
This is ridiculous. Well, you are.....
Don't tell me. I know, I am foolish.
Fio,
I think I have to say thank you.
You gave me a chance to fight Curtis.
Thanks.
We share the same luck.
We are partners, aren't we?
We are going to have a hard time.
I trust you.
Trust me, eh?
I haven't heard that in a long time,
but I'm glad you said that.
What's wrong? You feel sick?
Fio?
I'm fine.
It's just that my heart is pounding.
To be honest, I was really scared.
Hey?
I want to swim.
Porco! I made a mistake!
Are you O.K?
I should have padded the deal.
We have a bad bargain.
HA,HA,HA,HA.
You're right. HA,HA,HA,HA.
Porco....
Hmm?
You can't sleep, can you?
Now, I just saw...
It may have been a dream...
Every thing is all right.
It's too early in the morning to get up.
Porco.
Why did you become a pig?
I don't know.
I know a lot about Captain Marco Pabatto.
My father used to be in the same unit.
I've heard many a story,
in which the captain
saved lives of enemy pilots,
I liked it.
Porco! How about if I kiss you?
You know a fairy tale
where a princess takes off
a curse on a prince,
who was changed to a frog.
You, silly. Save it for your man!
Won't my kiss work?
Huh, you are a nice girl.
You make me feel comfortable
and make me wish
to be a human being again.
Be a nice girl and go to sleep.
Tell me your story and I will.
My story?
Well...
It was the last summer of the war.
We were fly over the Adriatic Sea
on our usual patrol.
Belneldi was flying on my right side.
He was an old friend of mine.
He got married just two days before.
I was the matchmaker.
He didn't have enough leave
to be with his wife for long.
So, he returned to duty.
Everyone was falling down like flies,
whether a friend or a foe.
I was chased by three planes,
and had no time to worry about my friend.
At the end I was the only one
remaining of my unit.
But, they never gave up chasing me.
I made desperate efforts to run away.
My hands and feet went numb,
and I grew dizzy.
I thought I was going to die.
It was at that time that
I saw the white sky.
White?
Yeah, it was like a flash.
Because of the brightness,
it took me a while to realize that I was in a cloud.
I was worn out, and
didn't have any power left to control my plane.
In spite of that my plane continued to fly.
A cloud of planes...
Yeah, it was calm,
and the sky was very clear, too clear.
There was a line of clouds far above me.
Belneldi, you are alive, aren't you!
Belneldi, wait, where are you going!
Belneldi, don't go!
Are you going to leave Gina alone?!
I'll go instead of you!
When I recovered my senses, I was flying
over the sea, almost touching it, alone.
God said it wasn't your time yet,
didn't he?
In my mind I thought he might
let me fly like that forever.
That would not have been right,
because your are a good guy!
Good guys are all dead already.
Besides, there might have been
Hell inside that cloud.
Well, my story is over.
Go to sleep.
Shit, they gave me crap...
I'm glad you came back to live
because I like you.
Good-night!
Hey, hey, which one's gonna win,
a pig or...
08:07
you need ice-cream, telescope?
Fools. They make our fight into a festival.
Are they all air pirates?
Trash of the Mediterranean Sea...
Gangs, pirates, smugglers,
spies and even some ordinary people.
Heh, this makes my fame rise more and more...
Ten minutes till start,
ten minutes till start!
This is the fight between Porco Rosso
and Donald Curtis!
There are no special rules,
but an unfair fight will a
disgrace to their fans.
Shut up and start right now. Back off!
You shut up, or I kill you!
He'd be better off throwing a 10ton bomb...
This is the fight which will determine
the future of Miss Fio Piccolo.
Shut up!
Do you understand?
If you do, clap your hands.
CLAP!
Shut up, that's the routine.
Well, both of you present your bids.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Put it on the chair properly!
None of you have anything to say, do you.
Well shake hands or something before you start!
No way. I'm fond of cleanliness.
He's hard to please.
Fio, as soon as this fight is over,
we will go to the church.
Don't worry.
My mom told me your going to like me soon.
You...
May I take a picture with you?
I took a shower already.
Everybody, smile!
SMILE!
If the flight is over in 3 minutes,
the black plane has the advantage...
This is great.
I want them to do this event every month
15 seconds to go.
They are so cool...
5 seconds to go.
4 , 3, 2, 1, 0!
Curtis took over!
This is going to be a one-sided fight.
Give me that.
Porco, what are you doing! Fly over!
He would be shot if the took off now.
It's very difficult for Curtis
to shoot Porco in this situation.
I know you want me to waste the bullet's.
I know it.
Looping! The pig took Curtis' back!
Looping?
His skill made the pig
an ace of the Adriatic Sea.
Shit!
He's gonna shoot!
He doesn't open fire.
Is his machine-gun broken!?
I got it, I got it!
The pig won't shoot until the end.
The pig doesn't kill anybody.
Now, the American should be fine.
You got it! Go and shoot!
Oh, he didn't shoot yet.... See,
I told you...
If the pig opened fire,
it would kill the American, so, it's going to hit
Curtis' engine a few bullets
after Curtis gets tired.
He said this is not war, but...
Porco...
Are you teasing me or what?
Come on!
Is your gun broken, huh! You,
poor bastard!
They are coming this way!
Come on, pig!
Go away from here and fight over there!
Great! The pig is leaving a cloud trail.
Come on!
Shoot that side!
It's cool! It's the first time
I saw the plance leaving a cloud trail!
I've never seen such an air fight before.
I'm really impressed.
I ready for the flight.
She'd better hurry,
or the fight will be over.
She's in her room, and doesn't come out.
Does she want to go or not?
I want to see that fight...
To G of Heart, for the pig.
The air force found out about the fight.
Stop the silly fight.
Oh, this is must be from Fierrali.
I should hurry.
First of all,
both of them are very tough.
The show isn't over!
Porco, fight!
I'm not going to give Fio to a man
Iike you.
O.K. The pig took Curtis' tail.
It's over!
This is the finish.
Whoops... Jammed, too.
You, idiot! You are out of ammo!
Whoops.
This is broken because of Fio's butt...
I'm not going to finish this fight with a draw.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
This is not a western. You can't hit me.
You...
You really think it will reach here?
You, stinking pig!
Can't throw it!
Bastard!
Throw it finally!
For love!
Shut up! You piggy!
Looks like something is wrong.
Ah... they are coming.
They are coming back!
Wait! Bids don't leave from here.
O.K. Wait, you guys.
You, fat pig!
You, chicken cowboy!
Come on with your bare hands!
Go back to cows!
Porco, hold on!
Stand up, pig.
Go, go!
Bets still stand!
Where's the betting table?
Can't you fly faster, much faster?
It's impossible. Engine would blow.
Pilots are all stupid, aren't they...
Hey, Fio. Did you see my punch?
I'm gonna take him down next round.
I'll take you down this time.
Porco, hang on!
I'll make prosciutto out of you!
Take aim!
Come on, you chicken!
You are the chicken!
You seduce all women around you.
That was my word.
Choose Gina or Fio, either one!
What?
Don't choose both.
Gina is...
Don't say, Gina, Gina...
Gina loves you, pig.
She is...
waiting for you...
at the garden!
Porco!
The sound of drum.
It's over! Look at that!
I can see it.
The ltalian Air Force hasn't arrived, yet.
You are unfair... You're a dirty liar.
Don't you understand, you idiot.
I am not telling a lie...
I don't give Fio to you.
That's Gina's plane.
It's an emergency signal.
1, 2...
The winner is the one who stand up first.
Everybody, let me through.
6, 7, Gina, don't.
8!
Marco, Marco, can you hear me?
Do you want another girl to be unhappy?
9!
Porco!
Porco, thank you!
Well...
This party is over.
The Air Force will be here soon.
Everybody run away quickly, please.
Then stop by my restaurant.
I will serve you all.
Everybody, let's go!
It's over, Mr.
Hey, boss, hurry up!
Shut up!
I don't like the pig, but I like you.
Goodbye!
Thank you.
Take a shower sometimes, will you?
Thank you, too, Mr. Curtis.
Next time I'll propose you formally,
not as a bet.
O.K. But I've made up my mind already.
You, get on Gina's plane.
No! No!
I'm going on Porco's plane.
You said I'm your partner, didn't you.
Gina. Take her home, please.
You always do this.
I'm sorry. Please leave.
Let's go.
The ltalian Air Force is finally coming.
Do you want to help me?
I'm going to lead them astray.
Wait, the face!
Let me see your face!
Your plane is over there, eh?
Let me see it a little bit!
After the flight from the Air Force,
I returned to Milan.
I haven't seen Porco since.
Instead, I have found
a very good friend in Miss Gina.
Since the of the fight,
there have been many wars.
But I still keep in touch with Gina.
After I take over the factory 'Piccolo',
I make it a rule to spend summer vacations
at the Hotel Adriano.
Miss Gina has become more beautiful since.
Old friends still stop
by the Hotel all the time.
Mr. Curtis, now I recall,
writes to me sometimes
though he is not the president of the U.S., yet.
He says he longs for the summer
of Adriatic Sea.
It's only our secret that Gina
won her gamble...
End
Thank you for watching