Still got it.
What's that?
An old friend.
I was rummaging
through a closet
and it was just
sitting there.
It's nice, Paul.
It's got character.
When I wrote my first book, I
used to carry it around in this
while I was looking
for a publisher.
I was a writer then.
You're still a writer.
Haven't been a writer since I
got in the Misery business.
It's not a bad business. And it
would still be growing, too.
The first printing
for Misery's Child
was the most ever.
Over a million.
Marcia, please.
Misery Chastain put braces
on your daughter's teeth
and is putting her
through college,
bought you two houses and
floor seats to the Knicks.
And what thanks does she get?
You go and kill her!
I never meant for it
to become my life.
And if I hadn't
gotten rid of her now,
I'd have ended up
writing her forever.
Now I'm leaving for Colorado
to try to finish the new book.
If I can make this work, I might just
have something I want on my tombstone.
I'm your
number-one fan.
There's nothing
to worry about.
You're gonna be just fine.
I'll take good care of you.
I'm your number-one fan.
Where...
We're just outside
Silver Creek.
How long?
You've been here two days.
You're gonna be okay.
My name is Annie Wilkes.
My number-one fan.
Yes. That's right.
I'm also a nurse.
Here, take these.
Here.
- What are they?
- They're called Novril.
They're for your pain.
Thank you.
How come I'm not
in a hospital?
The blizzard was too strong. I
couldn't risk trying to get you there.
I tried calling, but the
phone lines are down.
You mustn't tire yourself.
You've gotta rest.
You almost died.
Open wide.
Your legs just sing grand opera
when you move, don't they?
It's not gonna hurt forever,
Paul, I promise you.
Will I be able to walk?
Of course you will.
And your arm
will be fine, too.
Your shoulder was
pretty badly dislocated.
It was a little stubborn, but
I finally popped it back in.
What I'm most proud of is the
work I did on those legs.
Considering what
I had around the house,
I don't think there's a doctor
who could've done any better.
It's not nearly
as bad as it looks.
You have a compound fracture
of the tibia in both legs,
and the fibula in the right
leg is fractured, too.
I could hear
the bones moving,
so it's best for your legs
to remain immobile.
And as soon as
the roads open,
I'll take you to a hospital.
Meantime, you've got
a lot of recovering to do,
and I consider it an honor
that you'll do it in my home.
This is Marcia Sindell, I'm
calling from New York City.
I'd like to speak to the Silver
Creek Chief of Police or Sheriff.
Which one
of them do you want?
Whichever one's not busy.
Well, I'm pretty sure they're
both not busy, Miss Sindell,
since they're both me.
I also happen to be president of the
Policeman's Benefit Association,
chairman of the Patrolman's
Retirement Fund,
and if you need a good fishing
guide, you could do a lot worse.
Call me Buster.
Everybody does.
What can I do for you?
I'm a literary agent, and I... I
feel like a fool calling you,
but I think one of my
clients, Paul Sheldon,
might be in some
kind of trouble.
You mean Paul Sheldon
the writer?
He's your client, huh?
Yes, he is.
Everybody sure likes
those Misery books.
I'm sure you know that Paul's been
coming to the Silver Creek Lodge
for years
to finish his books.
I understand he's been up
here the last six weeks.
Well, not quite.
I just called there
and they said he checked
out last Tuesday.
Isn't that
a little strange?
I don't know.
Does he usually phone you
before he checks
out of a hotel?
No, of course not. It's just that
his daughter hasn't heard from him,
and when he has a new book coming
out, he usually keeps in touch.
Now when there wasn't
any word from him, I...
You think he might
be missin', huh?
I hate that I made this call.
Tell me I'm being silly.
A little overprotective, maybe,
but tell you what I'll do.
Nothing's been
reported out here,
but I'll put his name
through our system, and
if anything turns up,
I'll call you right back.
I'd appreciate that.
Thanks a lot.
Goodbye, Miss Sindell.
We got a phone call?
Busy morning.
Yeah. Work, work, work.
Virginia,
when was that blizzard?
Last Tuesday. Why?
No reason.
I guess it was kind of a
miracle, you finding me.
No, it wasn't
a miracle at all.
In a way,
I was following you.
You were following me?
Well, it wasn't any secret to me you
were staying at the Silver Creek,
seeing as how I'm your
number-one fan and all.
Some nights I'd just tool on
down there and sit outside
and look up at
the light in your cabin
and I'd try to imagine what
was goin' on in the room
of the world's
greatest writer.
Say the last part again,
I didn't hear you.
Don't move now.
I wouldn't want
to hurt this neck.
Well, the other afternoon
I was on my way home,
and there you were,
leavin' the lodge.
And I wondered why a literary
genius would go for a drive
when there was
a big storm comin'.
I didn't know there was
a big storm coming.
Well, lucky for you, I did.
And lucky for me, too,
'cause now you're alive and
you can write more books.
Oh, Paul, I've read
everything of yours.
The Misery novels.
I know 'em all by heart.
All eight of 'em.
I love them so.
Well, you're very kind.
And you're very brilliant.
Like a baby. All done.
Thank you.
When do you think the phone lines'll be up?
I have to call my daughter,
and I'd like to call
my agent in New York
and let her know
I'm still breathing.
It shouldn't be
too much longer now.
Once the roads are open, the
phone lines'll be up in no time.
If you give me their numbers,
I'll keep tryin' them for you.
Thank you.
Could I ask you a favor?
I noticed in your case there's
a new Paul Sheldon book, and
I wondered if maybe...
You want to read it?
Well, if you wouldn't mind.
Well, I do have a very
hard-and-fast rule as to
who reads my stuff
at this early stage.
Only my editor, my agent,
and anybody that saves me from
freezing to death in a car wreck.
You'll never realize what a
rare treat you've given me.
Boy, it's like clockwork
the way your pain comes.
I'll get you
your Novril, Paul.
Forgive me for prattling away
and making you feel all oogy.
What's your
new book called?
I don't have a title yet.
What's it about?
I don't know.
I know it sounds crazy, but
I haven't written anything
but Misery for so long.
Why don't you read it,
and you can tell me
what you think it's about?
Maybe you can
come up with a title.
Like I could do that!
There's nothin' unusual about
Mr. Sheldon's leaving, Buster.
You can tell
by the champagne.
Maybe you can, Libby.
No, see, he always orders
a bottle of Dom Pérignon
when he's ready to go.
Then he pays up
and he's out the door.
No long-distance phone calls
or Federal Express packages?
Anything out
of the ordinary?
I don't think
Mr. Sheldon likes
for things to be
out of the ordinary.
Considering who he is
and all, famous and all,
he doesn't put on airs.
Drives up from New York in the
same car each time, a '65 Mustang.
He says it helps him
to think.
He's always
been a good guest.
Never makes a noise,
never bothers a soul.
I sure hope nothing's
happened to him.
So do I.
I bet that old Mustang is pulling
into New York right now.
I'm sure you're right.
Thanks, Libby.
My pleasure.
I know I'm only 40 pages
into your book, but...
But what?
Nothing.
What is it?
Well, it's ridiculous.
Who am I to make a criticism
to someone like you?
It's all right,
I can take it.
Well, it's
brilliantly written.
But then everything
you write is brilliant.
Pretty rough so far?
The swearing, Paul.
There, I said it.
The... The profanity
bothers you?
It has no nobility.
These are slum kids.
I was a slum kid.
Everybody talks like that.
They do not!
What do you think I say when I
go to the feed store in town?
"Now, Wally, give me a bag
of that F-ing pig feed
"and 10 pounds of that
bitchly cow corn"?
And in the bank,
do I tell Mrs. Bollinger,
"Here's one big bastard
of a check,
"give me some of your
Christing money"?
There! Look there!
See what you made me do?
Paul, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Sometimes I get so worked up.
Can you ever forgive me?
It's fine.
I love you, Paul.
Your mind. Your creativity.
That's all I meant.
Well, this sure is fun.
Virginia, when
you're in this car
you're not my wife,
you're my deputy.
Well, this deputy'd
rather be home
under the covers
with the sheriff.
- Stop. Stop.
- What? What?
See that broken limb?
Could've been
the weight of the snow.
Yeah? Could've been a rotten
branch, could've been the wind,
could've been
a lot of things.
Damn!
Need some help?
No, I'm enjoyin' myself!
Thank you.
You really think
Sheldon's out there?
I hope not.
If he is, he's dead.
Let's go to
the newspaper office.
I hope I didn't wake you.
No, that's fine.
Look what I got. They had
it at the store, Paul.
There was a whole batch
of 'em there,
and as soon as I saw it I slammed my
money down. I got the first copy.
Then the roads are open.
Well, the one to town is,
but that's about it.
I called the hospital and I talked
to the head orthopedic surgeon
and I told him who you were
and what had happened.
He said as long as there's no
infection you're not in any danger,
and as soon as the road
to the hospital is open,
they'll send
an ambulance for you.
The phone's working?
Well, mine's still out, but the ones
in town were working just fine.
I called that
agent of yours.
Paul, I peeked at
the very beginning.
What a wonderful
first page.
Just to read the name
Misery Chastain...
My daughter's gotta
be goin' nuts.
It's like a visit from my
oldest, dearest friend.
I mean, I'm supposed to be home
for her birthday. It's today.
The agent said she would
tell her you were okay,
but I'm afraid you'll have
to wait till tomorrow
if you want to talk
to her yourself.
Oh, Paul.
What a poet you are.
I made you my specialty,
scrambled eggs à la Wilkes.
And I'm on Page 75.
I guess that means
it's okay.
No.
No, it isn't, it's...
Pooh. I can't think
of any words.
Would "great" be insulting?
I can live with great.
No. It's not just great,
it's
perfect.
A perfect, perfect thing.
I thought it was time
you two should meet.
Paul, say hello to my favorite
beast in the whole world,
my sow Misery.
Misery?
Yes. I told you I was
your number-one fan.
Yeah, I'm... I'm
starting to believe you.
This farm was
kind of dreary,
what with just a few cows
and chickens and me.
But when I got Misery
here, everything changed.
She just makes me smile so.
She's a fine pig,
is what she is.
I'm on Page 300 now, Paul, and it's
better than perfect. It's divine.
What's the ceiling
that dago painted?
The Sistine Chapel?
Yeah!
That and Misery's Child.
Those are the only two divine
things ever in this world!
When my husband left me,
I wasn't prepared.
It wasn't an easy time.
For a while I thought
I might go crazy.
I know how that can be.
I don't know about you, but
what I did to get through it
was I dove into work.
Days, nights.
Night shifts can be lonely
at a hospital.
I did a lot of reading.
That was when I first
discovered Misery.
She made me so happy. She made
me forget all my problems.
Course, I suppose you had a little
something to do with that, too.
Yeah, well...
I just kept reading
them over and over.
I've only got two chapters
to go on this one,
and I know when I finish I'll
just turn right to the first page
and start reading it
all over again.
I'm...
- Done?
- Yeah.
No problem.
Thanks.
Don't get me wrong. I'm not
against marriage per se,
but it'd take a pretty
special guy to make me
want to walk down
that aisle again.
Yeah, it's not something you
should enter into lightly.
It boils down to respect.
People just don't respect the
institution of marriage anymore.
They have no sense
of real commitment.
Well, I'd love to
stay here and chat,
but I'm right at the end, and I
gotta find out what happens.
You...
You dirty bird.
How could you?
She can't be dead! Misery
Chastain cannot be dead!
Annie, in 1871, women
often died in childbirth.
But her spirit
is the important thing,
and Misery's spirit
is still alive.
I don't want her spirit!
I want her!
And you murdered her!
No. I didn't.
Who did?
No one. She died,
she just slipped away.
Slipped away? Slipped away?
She didn't just slip away!
You did it!
You did it! You did it!
You murdered my Misery!
Annie!
I thought
you were good, Paul.
But you're not good. You're just
another lying old dirty birdie.
And I don't think I better
be around you for a while.
And don't even think about
anybody coming for you.
Not the doctors, not your
agent, not your family,
because I never called them.
Nobody knows you're here.
And you better hope
nothing happens to me.
Because if I die,
you die.
No, Miss Sindell, there's
no point in comin' up here now.
Everything that
can be done is.
Yes, we're working close
with the state police
and the FBI's
been informed.
Right. Right. As soon as we know
anything, we'll let you know.
No bother at all. Call anytime.
Bye, Miss Sindell.
All right. Well, I sure
appreciate it. Thank you.
According to the check on
Sheldon's credit charges,
there's nothing
after the Silver Creek.
And no calls about
the article, either.
You poor, dear thing. What
are you doing on the floor?
It's all my fault.
If I'd had a proper hospital bed
this never would've happened.
Here, let me
help you back in.
I know this hurts, but it'll
only take a few seconds.
Upsy-daisy!
Please, wait.
You're such a crybaby.
There you go. Comfy?
Perfect.
You're such a kidder.
I have a big surprise
for you.
But first there's
something you must do.
You don't suppose
I could have a little snack
while I'm waiting
for the surprise?
I'll get you everything you want,
but you must listen first.
Sometimes my thinking is a
little muddy, I accept that.
That's why
I couldn't remember
all the things
they were asking me
on the witness stand
in Denver.
But this time
I thought clearly.
I asked God about you,
and God said,
"I delivered him unto you
"so that you may
show him the way."
Show me the way?
Yes.
When I mentioned a snack,
I was thinking
more along the lines
of cheese and crackers
kind of thing.
Paul, this is
no time for jokes.
You must rid the world
of this filth.
You want me to burn my book?
I know this may be difficult for
you, but it's for the best.
It's really
not difficult at all.
My agent made
dozens of copies.
There's gonna be
an auction in New York.
Every publishing house in
New York is reading it now.
So if you want me
to burn my book, fine.
You're not really ridding
the world of anything.
Then light the match, Paul.
It's no big deal.
So you've indicated. Do it.
I know this is
the only copy, Paul.
When you were 24 you wrote your first
book, and you didn't make a copy
because you didn't think anybody
would take it seriously.
But they did. And ever since
you've never made any copies
because you're
superstitious.
It's why you always come back
to the Silver Creek Lodge.
You told that story to Merv
Griffin 11 years ago.
Merv Griffin.
I'll tell you what. It doesn't
ever have to be published.
No one ever has to read it.
I'll just keep it for myself.
No one will even
know it exists.
As long as it does exist,
your mind won't ever be free.
I think you should
light the match, Paul.
Can't you see
it's what God wants?
You're so brilliant,
I would think you'd certainly
be able to see that.
We're put on this earth
to help people, Paul.
Like I'm trying
to help you.
Please. Help me help you.
You're doing the right thing.
My goodness! Goodness gracious!
Oh, my.
Goodness!
Heavens to Betsy!
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, goodness!
Well, isn't that
an oogy mess?
That's the Steadman place
down there.
And that's the Wilkes farm
straight ahead.
That's no '65 Mustang.
There's nothing else out this way.
Let's... Let's circle back.
I do believe
the winters are getting
shorter and shorter
every year.
People say it has something
to do with the ozone layer.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Yeah, well, it's a theory.
Here's your Novril.
All right. We're back.
Now, you're gonna have to remind
us who the audience chose.
- They chose Kevin.
- Hi, Kevin.
- Hi. How you doin', Chuck?
Fine. Make yourself
at home back there,
and Sheree will tell us
about the date.
Okay. First of all, I picked
out a very classy restaurant.
It was so classy, and he
shows up without no tie...
See, isn't this nice?
Great. I always wanted to visit
the other side of the room.
And look what
I got for you.
An electric razor, so you
can shave yourself now.
If I knew this was gonna be the
surprise, I'd have burned all my books.
Now, don't poke fun!
This is a very big
day for you, Paul.
You just sit tight and
I'll set everything up.
Set what up?
That's the
big surprise.
Your new studio.
After all, writers
do need a place to work.
Work? You mean write?
What in the world
do you think I'd write?
Paul, I don't think.
I know.
Now that you've gotten rid
of that nasty manuscript,
you can go back to doing
what you're great at.
You're gonna write
a new novel,
your greatest
achievement ever.
Misery's Return.
Misery's Return?
I know you didn't mean it
when you killed her,
and now
you'll make it right.
It'll be a book
in my honor,
for saving your life and
nursing you back to health.
Paul, you're gonna make me
the envy of the whole world!
You just expect me to whip
something off, is that it?
I expect nothing less
than your masterpiece.
You do understand that this
is not the ordinary way
in which books get written.
I mean, some people might actually
consider this an oddball situation.
I have total confidence
in your brilliance.
Besides, the view
will inspire you.
You just inhale that.
I'll be right back.
I guess you don't get
bothered by neighbors much.
Don't you
worry about that,
you'll have total solitude so you
can concentrate on your work.
Great.
I got you this expensive
paper to type on,
and I got a great deal
on this 50-pound clunker,
on account of
its missing an "N."
I told the saleslady
"N" was one of the letters
in my favorite writer's name.
It's two of the letters in my
favorite nurse's name, A-nn-ie.
You fooler! Did I do good?
You did great.
There is just
one little thing.
I can't work on this paper. See,
it's Corrasable Bond. It smudges.
So I thought maybe,
if you went back into town,
you could bring me
some white long-grain mimeo.
But mine cost the most, so I
don't see how it can smudge.
Come here, I'll show you.
It does smudge, after all.
Isn't that fascinating.
I thought
you'd be interested.
I'd like for you to be
in on everything, Annie.
Not just the finished book,
but how it's written.
Thank you
for thinking of me.
Anything else I can get
while I'm in town?
Any other crucial requirements
that need satisfying?
Would you like
a tiny tape recorder?
Or how about a handmade set
of writing slippers?
No, just the paper
will be fine.
Are you sure?
'Cause if you want, I'll bring
back the whole store for you.
Annie, what's the matter?
What's the matter? I'll
tell you what's the matter!
I go out of my way for you!
I do everything to try
and make you happy!
I feed you, I clean you, I dress
you, and what thanks do I get?
"You bought
the wrong paper, Annie.
"I can't write on
this paper, Annie!"
Well, I'll get
your stupid paper,
but you just better
start showing me
a little more appreciation
around here, Mister Man!
Shit.
Come on, you've written
about this, now do it.
What do you know?
It actually works.
What a surprise.
You crazy bitch.
Paul, I've got your paper.
I hope it's enough. It's three
reams of long-grain mimeo.
Just the kind you asked for.
Paul, you're dripping
with perspiration.
Your color is very hectic.
What have you been doing?
You know damn well
what I've been doing.
I've been
sitting here suffering.
I need my pills.
Poor dear. Let's get you back in
bed and I'll get them for you.
I want my pills now!
It'll only take a second.
No!
I want my pain
to go away, Annie.
Please, make it go away.
Please, Annie. Please.
It just breaks my heart
to see you like this.
I've done a lot
of thinking on the drive.
Here you go.
And I'm absolutely certain the main
reason I've never been more popular
is because of my temper.
You must be so mad at me.
The truth, now.
Well... Who doesn't let off a
little steam every once in a while?
My genius needs his rest
before he writes.
Footsies up.
There you go.
Here. In case you think
of any ideas.
Well, I wouldn't
expect too much.
Don't be silly!
You'll be brilliant.
Think of me as
your inspiration.
I have faith in you,
my darling.
Catch this.
"My darling."
The presumption must now be
that Paul Sheldon is dead.
We know that he somehow managed
to crawl outside his vehicle,
but we have been unable
to find his body
anywhere in the vicinity
of the accident.
We also know that
if anyone had found him
they would have taken him
to an area hospital.
Undoubtedly he is buried
somewhere out there in the snow.
We'll find him
after the first thaw.
That is, unless the animals
didn't get to him first,
which is
a distinct possibility.
Local papers...
That was a statement from Colorado
Police Chief Sherman Douglas.
The whereabouts of famed
novelist Paul Sheldon is...
We will be updating
you with the latest...
You don't think
he's dead, do you?
Well, he might well be,
but not the way they say.
He never crawled out of
that car by himself.
You can see the dents
on the door there.
Someone pulled him out.
I'm sorry, Paul.
This is all wrong.
What?
You'll have to
do it over again.
It's not worthy of you.
Throw it all out.
Except for that part of naming
the gravedigger after me.
You can leave that in.
I really value
your criticism,
but maybe we're being
a little hasty here.
Paul, what you've written
just isn't fair.
Not fair?
That's right.
When I was growing
up in Bakersfield,
my favorite thing
in all the world
was to go to the movies on Saturday
afternoons for the chapter plays.
Cliffhangers.
I know that, Mister Man!
They also call them serials.
I'm not stupid, you know!
Anyway, my favorite
was Rocketman,
and once it was
a no-brakes chapter,
and the bad guys stuck him
in a car on a mountain road,
and knocked him out
and welded the doors shut
and tore out the brakes
and started him to his death.
And he woke up and tried to
steer and tried to get out,
but the car went off a cliff
before he could escape,
and it crashed and burned
and I was so upset
and excited!
And the next week, you better
believe I was first in line.
And they always start with
the end of the last week,
and there was Rocketman,
trying to get out,
and here comes the cliff,
and just before the car went
off the cliff he jumped free,
and all the kids cheered!
But I didn't cheer. I stood
right up and started shouting,
"This isn't what
happened last week!
Have you all got amnesia?
"They just cheated us!
This isn't fair!
"He didn't get out
of the cockadoodie car!"
They always cheated like
that in chapter plays.
But not you.
Not with my Misery.
Remember Ian did ride
for Dr. Cleary
at the end of the last book, but
his horse fell jumping that fence,
and Ian broke his shoulder and his
ribs and lay all night in the ditch
and he never reached
the doctor,
so there couldn't have been any
experimental blood transfusion
that saved her life.
Misery was buried in the
ground at the end, Paul,
so you'll have
to start there.
Is it fair?
Should I continue?
You better!
Oh, Paul!
When Ian realized that
the reason they'd
buried Misery alive
was because the bee sting had
put her in that temporary coma!
And when Gravedigger Wilkes
remembered how 30 years earlier
the same thing had happened
to Lady Evelyn-Hyde!
And then old Dr. Cleary
deduced that Misery
must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde's
long-lost daughter
because of the rarity of deadly
bee stings, my heart just leapt!
I've known from
the very first book
that Misery had to
be born of nobility
and I was right!
Yeah.
Paul, can I read each chapter
when you're finished?
I can fill in the "N's."
Will she be her old self
now that Ian has dug her out,
or will she have amnesia?
Have to wait.
Will she still love him with
that special, perfect love?
You'll have to wait.
Not even a hint?
Uh-uh.
Misery's alive, Misery's alive!
It's so romantic!
This whole house is gonna
be filled with romance!
I'm gonna put on
my Liberace records!
You do like Liberace,
don't you?
Whenever he played
Radio City,
who do you think was right
there in the front row?
I'm gonna play my records
all day long, to inspire you.
He's my all-time favorite.
Annie.
Would you have
dinner with me tonight?
To celebrate Misery's Return.
I couldn't have
done it without you.
Paul.
It would be an honor.
No, he's not here.
I don't know where he is.
He never tells me
anything anymore.
He's probably out
havin' an affair somewhere.
Wait a minute.
He's comin' in now.
It's Jim Taylor.
He wants to know who you're
havin' an affair with.
Hello, Jim.
What's doin'?
Jim, we've been
through this before.
If you're gonna have benches
out in front of your store,
people are gonna want
to sit on 'em.
Well, I don't like him,
either,
but I'm not gonna
come over there
and tell him to move.
Give my best to
Denise. Bye.
Well, whoever she is,
she sure likes to read a lot.
Virginia, I'm flattered that you
think I've got that much energy.
I figured that if
I can't find Paul Sheldon,
at least I can find out
what he wrote about.
What do you expect to find?
A story about a guy who drove his
car off a cliff in a snowstorm?
You see, it's just
that kind of sarcasm
that's given our marriage
real spice.
I hope you like it.
It looks wonderful.
So do you.
I've never had meatloaf this good.
What do you do to it?
My secret is I only use fresh
tomatoes, never canned.
And to give it
that little extra zip,
I mix in some Spam
with the ground beef.
Can't get this in a
restaurant in New York.
Let's have a toast.
A toast?
Yes. To Misery.
Let me pour you some wine.
To Misery.
Wait. Let's do this right.
Do you have any candles?
I don't know.
I think so.
I'll go look.
Did you study decorating
or do you just have a flair?
Oh, you!
I just picked things up
over the years.
Well,
it certainly says you.
You really think so?
Absolutely.
Listen, if you can't
find any, it's okay.
I just thought it'd be nice.
Are you kidding? If anyone had
ever told me that one day
I'd be having
a candlelit dinner
with Paul Sheldon
in my own house,
I would have checked
both legs
to see which one
was bein' pulled!
Will this do?
It's perfect.
To Misery and to Annie Wilkes,
who brought her back to life.
Paul, I get goose bumps
every time I think about it!
My God, what have I done?
I'm so sorry, Paul!
I ruined your
beautiful toast!
Will you ever forgive me?
Here, let me
pour another one.
Can we pretend
this never happened?
To Misery.
Paul, this is positively the
best Misery you've ever written.
Here's your pills.
Annie?
Annie, what is it?
The rain.
Sometimes it
gives me the blues.
When you first came here,
I only loved the writer
part of Paul Sheldon.
But now I know I love
the rest of him, too.
I know you don't love me.
Don't say you do.
You're a beautiful, brilliant,
famous man of the world
and I'm not
a movie-star type.
You'll never know the fear
of losing someone like you,
if you're someone like me.
Why would you lose me?
The book's almost finished.
Your legs are getting better.
Soon you'll be
wanting to leave.
Why would I leave?
I like it here.
That's very kind of you, but I'll
bet it's not altogether true.
I have this gun.
Sometimes I think
about using it.
I better go now.
I might put bullets in it.
"There is a justice
higher than that of man.
"I will be judged by Him."
What?
They're haulin'
Misery into court.
That's nice.
There is a justice
higher than that of man.
I will be judged by Him.
See you in the morning.
I'm supposed to lead to
the finale of my show right now,
but I'm having such a
wonderful time that I have...
Paul.
Hmm?
I know you've been out.
What?
You've been out of your room.
No, I haven't.
Paul, my little
ceramic penguin
in the study
always faces due south.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Ceramic penguin?
Is this what
you're looking for?
I know you've
been out twice, Paul.
At first I couldn't
figure out how you did it,
but last night
I found your key.
I know I left
my scrapbook out.
I can imagine what you
might be thinking of me.
But you see, Paul,
it's all okay.
Last night it came so clear.
I realize you just
need more time.
Eventually you'll come to
accept the idea of being here.
Paul, do you know
about the early days
at the Kimberley
diamond mines?
Do you know what they did to the
native workers who stole diamonds?
Don't worry.
They didn't kill them.
That would be like
junking a Mercedes
just because it had
a broken spring.
No, if they caught them
they had to make sure
they could go on working,
but they also had to make sure
they could never run away.
The operation
was called "hobbling."
Annie, whatever you're
thinking about doing,
please don't do it.
Annie, for God's...
Darling. Trust me.
God's sake!
It's for the best.
Annie, please!
Almost done.
Just one more.
God, I love you.
You cockadoodie!
Turn on this!
You poop!
Just leave it, all right?
I like that tone!
How many times do I
have to tell you?
I have a system here! Where
the hell is that thing?
What thing?
The thing!
Here it is, right where
it's supposed to be.
What is it?
I'm not sure.
Maybe nothin'.
Well, I'm glad you found it.
There's that spice again.
Come on, Misie.
Come on.
Hi, pumpkin.
Such a kidder!
Come on, Misery.
Hey, Pete.
Buster.
Answer me a couple things.
If I can.
Do you have any new
Paul Sheldon books?
Well, we had a batch.
Sold 'em all out
in three days.
You wouldn't happen to know if Miss
Wilkes bought one of them, would you?
Are you kiddin'? Every time
that fella writes a new book,
she has me set aside
the first copy.
Has she been buyin'
anything odd lately?
Miss Wilkes?
Same old stuff.
Lest you call paper odd.
Newspaper?
No. The typin' kind.
That kind.
Nothin' odd about that.
Miss Wilkes done somethin'?
Not a thing.
I don't think I'll ever understand you.
I cook your meals,
I tend to you practically
24 hours a day,
and you continue
to fight me.
When are we going to
develop a sense of trust?
Oh, my.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to startle you,
but you didn't give me
a chance to knock.
I guess you can tell
from my reaction
I'm not all that used
to visitors out here.
What can I do for you?
Well, I was wonderin', do
you happen to know anything
about Paul Sheldon?
What do you want to know?
Well, anything you
could tell me might help.
Well, he was born in Worcester,
Massachusetts, 45 years ago,
the only child of Franklin
and Helene Sheldon,
mediocre student,
majored in History...
Well that... That isn't exactly the
kind of information I'm after.
You see, he's been missin'
for quite some time now...
I know. It's so upsetting.
I'm his number-one fan.
I've got all his books. Every
sentence he ever put down.
I'm so proud of my
Paul Sheldon collection.
Well, here I am,
prattling on,
and my manners
have just flown away.
I haven't invited you in.
Please.
Thank you.
Of course, you must know all
about that horrible accident.
Mind if I take a look around?
Of course not.
That accident almost
killed me, too.
I prayed when
I heard the news.
I got down on my knees and I
begged for it not to be true.
You're gonna laugh
at what I'm about to say,
but go ahead,
I don't care.
When I was praying,
God told me to get ready.
Get ready
for what?
To be his replacement.
He gave so much pleasure
to so many people,
and there's a shortage of pleasure
on the planet these days,
in case you
hadn't noticed.
God told me, since I was
his number-one fan,
that I should make up new stories
as if I was Paul Sheldon.
So I went to town, and
I bought a typewriter,
and paper to type on,
the same kind
Paul Sheldon used.
And I turned the guest bedroom
into a writing studio.
Would you like to see it?
Sure.
It's right this way.
I know how he wrote. The
kinds of words he used,
the wonderful stories
he told.
I've spent the last
four weeks
trying to write
like Paul Sheldon,
but I can't do it right.
I try and I try, and I know all the
words, but it's just not the same.
Well, maybe it takes a while
to get the hang of it.
I could give you a couple
of hundred pages of mine
and you could tell
me what you think.
I'm not much of a critic.
Well, I just thought...
Oh, look at me. You'd think
I'd never had a guest before!
Would you like a nice
hot cup of cocoa?
No, really, I don't...
It's no trouble.
There's some already made.
Must get lonely, livin'
out here all by yourself.
Well, I always say, if you
can't enjoy your own company,
you're not fit company
for anyone else.
Well, you've got
a point there.
Here you are.
Well, thanks, Miss Wilkes,
but I don't want to take up
any more of your time.
I best be goin'.
But you didn't even
taste your cocoa.
I'm sure it's wonderful, but I
really should be gettin' back.
If you wouldn't mind,
perhaps I could
pay you another
visit sometime.
I'd be delighted,
now that you know the way.
Miss Wilkes?
Miss Wilkes,
are you all right?
Here!
Here! I'm down here!
I'm down here!
Mr. Sheldon?
Don't feel bad, Paul.
It was bound to happen
sooner or later.
It's a sign.
You see, I've known for some time
why I was chosen to save you.
You and I were meant
to be together forever.
But now our time
in this world must end.
But don't worry, Paul.
I've prepared
for what must be done.
I put two bullets in my gun,
one for you and one for me.
Darling,
it'll be so beautiful.
Now don't be afraid.
I love you.
I love you, too.
And you're right.
We are meant to be together.
And I know we must die.
But it must be
so that Misery can live.
We have the power
to give Misery eternal life.
We must finish the book.
But the time is now.
Soon others will come.
It's almost finished.
By dawn
we'll be able to give Misery
back to the world.
I'll fix you
something to eat.
Paul, I'm dying!
Does she wind up
with Ian or Windthorne?
You'll know very soon.
I've just started
the last chapter.
You know, when I finish, I'd
like everything to be perfect.
I'll need three things.
What things?
You mean you don't know?
I was foolin', silly.
You need a cigarette, because
you used to smoke but you quit,
except when you finish a
book, and you have just one.
And the match
is to light it,
and you need one glass of
champagne, Dom Perignon.
Dom Perignon it is.
Annie, Annie?
Yes, Paul?
I'm almost done.
Oh, Paul,
this is so romantic!
Ian and Windthorne dueling for
the right to Misery's hand.
Does Ian win?
Don't tell me.
It's Windthorne, right?
You'll know everything
in a minute.
Get the champagne.
Did I do good?
You did perfect.
Except for one thing.
This time we'll need
two glasses.
Oh, Paul.
Remember how,
for all those years,
nobody knew who
Misery's real father was?
Or if they'd
ever be reunited?
It's all right here.
Does she finally marry Ian,
or will it be Windthorne?
It's all right here.
Paul, you can't!
Why not?
I learned it from you.
No, no, no! Not Misery!
Not my Misery!
No! Not my Misery!
I'm gonna kill you,
you lying cocksucker!
Here, you want it?
You want it? Eat it!
Eat it till you choke,
you sick, twisted fuck!
This is it.
The very first copy.
The word I'm getting is the Times
review is gonna be a love letter.
That'll be a first.
And my contacts at Time and Newsweek
tell me they're both raves.
And don't laugh,
but for the first time
I think you've got
a shot at some prizes.
Great.
I thought you'd be thrilled.
You're being taken seriously.
I'm delighted
the critics are liking it
and I hope the people
like it, too.
But I wrote it for me.
Now, don't think
I'm completely nuts, but...
In some way, Annie Wilkes,
that whole experience,
helped me.
Paul, since you
brought her up,
I have to ask you this or I'll be
drummed out of the agents' union.
How would you feel
about a non-fiction book
about what went on
in that house?
Gee, Marcia, if I didn't know you
better, I'd think you were suggesting
I dredge up the worst
horror of my life
just so we can make
a few bucks.
I thought you
were over it.
I don't know if anyone could ever
totally get over something like that.
It's weird.
Even though I know
she's dead,
I still think about
her once in a while.
Excuse me. I don't mean to bother
you, but are you Paul Sheldon?
Yes.
I just want to tell you
I'm your number-one fan.
That's very sweet of you.