"Dearest dream which is
inflicted with violence in soul"
"On one's lap it is carried, that is life"
"Confronted with dense
woods as proceeded fonlvard"
"Challenging great paths of destiny"
"My beloved is on the march to
succeed for a cherished victory"
asmnma 213mm.“
Parameshwara!
(Lord Shiva!)
For the sins that I've committed, if
death is the solution, you may take it.
But he should remain alive!
He should remain alive for the sake
of his mother, who is waiting for him!
To adorn the throne of 'Mahishmathi'
he should remain alive!
'Mahendra Bahubali' must be alive!
My God!
Cheera, without just watching
you go and save that child.
Hey fellow, you go fast, make it fast!
Give the baby, give.
Hey fellow, who is this?
Don't know, on seeing the
bangle in the mother's hand...
...looks like she is a princess.
During the moment of death,
the finger was pointed towards mountain!
My God, two corpses are lying here.
Fellow, you are these people?
Looks like they had come to kill her.
It seems, that lady
had killed these people.
Hey chief!
My heavens! A cave, was not
aware of such a thing over here.
Hey chief! They are steps
inside this oneto climb up.
That lady after giving the baby
and pointing to mountains.
Does it mean that he will
be taken towards sky?
Are you out ofyour mind? Has
send men to slain a new born baby.
Saying sending towards sky.
Ganga, it's not like that. I...
He is my son. As I was in deep pain
for not being able to bear children.
He is a blessing that this
'mother river' has given to me.
If at all anyone's talks opposing
I'll pluck out that tongue and throw!
Hey you fellow! What are you
gawking at? Close that cave!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Shiva...Boy what are
you doing here?
Mother, what is there on top?
Out there, there is ghosts and
devils, all sort of things like that.
If you go there, you will
be torn into pieces!
I'm going to climb on top. - My God,
always saying the same thing, come!
How many times have I told,
not to climb that mountain?
Why are you repeatedly
climbing that mountain?
Aren't you my dear son, again you
must not climb, did you hear?
Hey man, it seems this time
he'll climb. -Where to climb!
Did you see that 'neermala' (mountain)?
It's somewhere in the sky.
While climbing on that
how many times he had fallen?
Hundred times!
Then what? Just like before
he'll fall down for sure.
Hey man, Shiva, overthere
your mother is doing something.
Shiva, Shiva!
(Salutations to Lord Shiva)
Only fifteen!
If you pourthousand and one times,
may be your prayers will bear results.
Swamy!(tutor) lfl do this does
my son listen to what I say?
Will he stop climbing that mountain?
By all means, what have you
thought of Lord Shiva?
You surrender your soul
to Shiva and cool that deity.
Perhaps your son
may come to right path.
All right Swamy.
Mother, do you think that you
are young? - Move away boy!
Always if you climb up and
down won't you be ill?
My dear mother,
just listen to what I say.
Go man, have you ever
listened to my words?
Father, you may
advise her something.
Ganga!
What is it?
Where did you keep that 'Vibhuti'?
(sacred ash) where and all I searched.
Leave me boy! - Mother, then
I'll go instead of mother.
Did you agree?
That's not possible.
Shiva won't accept that.
One who has prayed, they
themselves should fulfill it.
Swam Boy. give m
y. you may do only yourjob!
Nama Shivaya!
My mother, mother.
What is it?
I'll carry you like this and go, mother
you yourself can pour water on idol.
Agreed?
That's not possible,
Shiva won't accept that.
One who has prayed, they
themselves should fulfill it.
For mother's hunger, is
it possible when son feeds?
Swamy! You and your
Shiva will slain my mother!
Who knows? What is there in
Shiva's mind, how'll Iknowthat?
Hey girl Ganga! Come and see
what your son is doing, overthere.
(Shiva!)
Shiva!
Stop it, stop it I say!
Stop it. boy stop m
This is Lord, this is Lord!
Shiva!
Hey you, Shiva, stop it!
(The hymn in praise of Lord Shiva)
asmnma 213mm.“
"Who is he, who is he? One
who lifts the deity and goes"
"One who carries you on the
shoulders, just like a child"
"No one has seen
nor no one has heard"
"By searching for
Ganga, one carries oneself"
"Shiva Linga (symbol)
moves by walking"
(The hymn in praise of Lord Shiva)
Mother, for your Shiva
it is not thousand times.
Here after every minute the idol of
Shiva will get cooled. Take a look!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Swamy! Things took place
just the way you predicted.
Ever since last
'Amavasi'(new moon)-
- my son has not paid attention
to that 'Neerm ala'(mountain)
Then what? What have
you thought of Shiva?
However, he is always talking to
that mask, which fell from 'Shiva Linga'
Why is that?
Who knows? How can I
know what Shiva may offer'?
That should be asked to Shiva, is it?
Swamy, I've a doubt.
Our Shiva has poured water
on top of 'Linga'(symbol)
So, will Parameshwaran (Shiva)
hear his prayers or her prayers?
This tongue will be
struck by a thunder bolt!
My son has done it for me, no?
Swamy, will my prayers be fulfilled?
What Shiva has intended,
that will take place.
What is he saying?
Hey Shiva, how long can
you look at this wooden face?
There is someone on top.
Let it be there, mother is calling.
Come, lets go.
You go, I'll come.
Come man.
Who are you?
Why did you come to me?
Asmnma 213mm.“
"As a moonlight in the
sky, I have called you"
"l'm the beauty in the assembly
of Indra, I'm born for you"
"Are you in slumber or in playfulness?
Cometo my lap, I'll sing"
"On your paths to lead you,
I'll become a companion"
"l'm coming by destroying hurdles
I come by crumbling mountains"
"For you, I caress this speeding
Brooke, like the hair knot of Shiva"
"l'll posses your beautiful face to see
that I'll tear apart this earth into two"
"Sprout out to grow high, will you
grant me the boon that you will come?"
"Pierce the spear and come,
I'll set gaze on pathsfor you"
"Brave will conquerthis world
In life, strength of heart is your own"
asmnma 213mm.“
Kashi!
We are betrayed, attack!
My mother!
How did you get this?
One person among you was caught
when he trespassed to our country.
Our men had killed him, this
was..This was on his neck.
I'm not the one who
killed him. No, don't kill me.
Upon mercy, please leave me.
Burry the corpses, without
leaving behind any clues.
Chief, Dileepan has also
succumbed to victorious death.
Stop it. From the eyes
a drop of tears shouldn't fall.
That demon in his country.
Our 'beacon of clan' is
locked up in iron chains.
Our queen 'Devasena' is
tied up like slaughter cows.
Our respect is
belittled and humiliated.
It is being hanged
with the head down.
It is not tears on our
eyes the fire should burn.
What have you forgotten
the pledge that is done?
Chief, won't forget that
till the life ends.
Even if thunder bolt
strikes on paths of our goal.
Never will desist from the
path, the absolute truth!
Even ifthe body splits into two...
...Never will there be fear!
Even if the life is taken...
...Only one aim, the
release of Devasena.
How to attain the goal?
No time for smiles and laughter.
There is no place for
relationships and love.
The body is for the nation.
The life is for Devasena.
My goodness, my mother!
Chief, we've heard several tales of
great warrior Kattappa of Mahishmathi.
What I have come to know is,
he is a good person.
Why don't we approach him?
'Karikala Kattapanakar' is
a very generous person.
He owns a high spirit.
But he will not do it.
Kattappa, is a slave of the throne.
Karrappa!
From the North, the arms
trader has come to meet you.
Asmnma 213mm.“
The iron taken from Bagdad tunnel.
Purified at Turkey.
Designed by Persian experts.
Double headed sword.
Ifthis sword is swinged by a kid
even the palm tree will be chopped off.
Very impressive sword!
But kindly pardon dearAslam, this
sword can't replace our swiftness.
Kattappa, when blood and word
falls out, it can't be taken back.
If your swiftness is
higherthan my sword.
Prove and show!
Now, did you
understand, Kattappa?
I've traveled a lot to countries
like China, Persia, Mongolia.
But I've never seen a
warrior like you, anywhere.
It is a pride forthis
Aslam to dine with you.
Come Kattappa!
Pardon Aslamji.
Slaves sitting along with
royal family is never acceptable.
Slave!
The head of this army.
You, a slave?
Yes Aslamji.
Before the war, weapons
should be made ready.
During the time of war, to save
the king's life must sacrifice life.
Afterthe war must lie down
under the feet of the king.
Tell, to release you ask your king
how much gold he wants? Ask and tell.
Higher than that in 10, 50,100
times, tell him Aslam will free you.
Aslamji, this slave
doesn't posses a price.
Everybody who is born in my caste.
Shall be the slaves
of Mahishmathi throne.
My ancestors at some point of
time, had already promised.
On a promise that is given by
dead people at some point of time.
Do you still have to"? -Let the
people who gave the promise die.
But the promised word doesn't die!
In this birth, my life and soul
is dedicated to Mahishmathi.
If the trust has a
form, that is you Kattappa
Whenever you need any
help at any time
Don't forget this dear friend
is always there to help you
asmnma 213mm.“
Wshau!
Where are you going?
Aren't you sleeping?
I'll come now.
We've received a golden
opportunity to fulfill our goal.
On the forth coming
day of 'Chathurthi'
Preparations had started to
celebrate the Palvaldeva's birthday -
- on a grand scale through
out the country
All the people in the country will
arrive to participate in the function
This is the righttime to bring
queen Devasena, the pride in it
Send me, send me!
I'm ready.
This time I give
chance to Avanthika
Avanthika, what is this?
How did this appear?
Your heart forgot the goal and went
in search of beauty, that is why.
A girl who loves her own beauty,
how can she fight for the goal?
You are not deserving
forthis title. I say you go!
Do not find this tear drop
as a symbol of weakness!
It has not sprouted
out of timidness.
The revenge in my heart
gets boiled and becomes vapor.
They are the fire balls
ejected out through the eyes.
Ifthe heat of that has touched you.
Please permit me for
the journey of my goal.
Now within two days you
should get ready to start.
You must execute the
things in utmost attention.
If you execute it carelessly,
you may end up in danger.
That Bhalvaldevan will tear
you apart and kill you!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Highness, that she-buffalo was brought
from woods, two days back only
Still now it is not calm.
Kindly be careful
Hey great minister, to defeat
Bhalvaldeva not one...
...not one she-buffalo, may
require ten wild she-buffalos
You just come here
Kill Bhalva...
Grandpa.
Long live great king!
Long live Bhalvaldevan!
Hey father, has killed it.
Did you see the courage
of my father, did you see?
Asmnma 213mm.“
When I see your trust,
I always feel amazed, Kattappa.
Within your inner soul, I can
find the fire burning to kill me.
But still you gave your
life and saved me.
How is it Kattappa, how
could you do this?
Well, you may ask
whatever boon you want.
Will give anything you want.
Highness, I've got only one request.
End that punishment which that
mother is suffering for 25 years.
Kindly free Devasena
Well, I here by give my word
Go and kill Devasena and free her!
Kattappa, is there higher
liberation than death?
Go!
Does it mean no? If so let her suffer!
Should suffertill the last breath!
What lady? Are you sleeping?
Hey get UP!
Get up I 58V!
Aren't you done with sleeping?
Why are sleeping un-conscious?
Get up.
Get up and come out.
Devasena, is there any
short falls in torture?
Says doesn't want me.
Only wants him.
Now where is he?
Where is he? Let me hear.
Devasena, ifl ask one
thing you must tell thetruth.
During these past years, does
anyone from any where...
...at any time, have you
heard telling about him?
In any one ofthe nights,
in any one ofthe loneliness.
On the tickle of this
chain, that lives with you.
Have you heard his name?
Shucks!
No!
Devasena, Mahishmathi
has forgotten it
His name not only
from the lips of citizens...
...have vanished from theirthoughts
Now in this country there are only
two people who thinking about him
You..And me!
For you, in this birth longs
to see one more time
For me, Iwant to slain him one
more time till my anger vents out!
Both are unfulfilled wishes
Mother Devasena!
Kindly agreethis time, if you order
I'm ready to free you
from these chains
Have you decided to be in this
imprisonment through out the life?
No Kattappa, my son will come here
To free me
How can the son come
back, who is dead?
My son is alive
He'll return for me
For a son who is not alive,
still now you are waiting
Also undergoing a punishment
that was not at all required
I don't know when I'll
get a chance like this
Before the night guards reach
here, kindly accept princess
Please allow
I'm only asking a permission
for the liberation
At that time how is it possible, when
you pick up the twigs like this!
Kattappa, did you think that I'm a
mere lunatic that picks up twigs?
I'm preparing a 'fire bed'
To burn that Bhalvaldeva's
blood, body and soul
I'm preparing a fire bed forthat
My son will come here, he will come
and drag Bhalvaldeva into this fire bed
Will give that animal
into my hands to burn
Out of fear of death,
Bhalvaldeva's withering cry of pain...
...that will be echoed in the
walls of the fort of Mahishmathi
My son will come back for me
asmnma 213mm.“
Avanthika, what had happened?
On that day while I was
sleeping, drew on my hands
Again ifl sleep
here, he'll come again
Avanthika, what is this
on your shoulders?
Avanthi! - You go I'll come.
Did you see what I've drawn
on the shoulders? Isn't it good?
Why is always your face scorn?
Can't you just smile?
Hey why are you shooting arrows
on me? Are you trying to kill me?
Who are you?
It's nice to hear you
talk like this. I'm Shiva.
I hail from Am bili village, I've come to
top climbing mountain to see you
This is what I said,
should obey to words
Now did you see
unnecessarily fell into the hole
How is it?
Avanth ika!
Now tell, who are you?
What I told is true, I climbed
that mountain and... - Stop it!
Only Paramashivan can climb that
That is it, I'm Shivan is it?
Oh, no, no!
Enough, I'll tell everything
I'll tell everything but before
that I need to know one thing
What do you want to know?
Who are you?
Knife in the hand, shields in the
body, red eyes, a face glowing in anger
Not you what is seen outside.
Innerto that, at the
bottom of the mind
Truly, who are you?
Shall I say?
You are a female and I'm a male
I've come, liking you
Yes, how blissful is this pain
This is mine. It was lost
in the mountain brooke
You..Have you actually climbed the
mountains and come on top? - Yes
This far'?
I've come here to see
the smile ofthis masked girl
But still now I was not able to see it
asmnma 213mm.“
"You are a raw fire, I'm a
'Thechipoo' (Ixora flower)"
"While seeing each other,
became one very soon"
"Out of burning rock, haven't
you craved a heavenly beauty?"
"You are the star in
the sky and earth"
"You are the flower casket
that came to my hands"
"While wejoin hands, it transforms
into wings, new world will emerge"
"You are a raw fire, I'm a
'Thechipoo'(lxora flower)"
"While seeing each other,
became one very soon"
"l've seen petals in stag eyes I've
conquered mountains and reached here"
"Upon your arrival, I came to
realize that I have a heart"
"Heart is throbbing,
telling your name"
"You are a star of my land, you are
a virgin who leans on my shoulders"
"As our shouldersjoin meet each
other, peacock flowers within me"
"You are a raw fire, I'm a
'Thechipoo'(lxora flower)"
"While seeing each other,
became one very soon"
"Out of burning rock, haven't
you craved a heavenly beauty?"
Such a thing has never
happened in history
120 feet golden statue
A luck which even
God has not achieved
Yes, yes
After installation of this, the
fame of our king not only here...
...that will be spread
all over the universe
Is all the arrangements over'?
Highness, everything is completed
Tomorrow, the statue will be installed
At the very moment, ourteam of
percussionist will break the sky
asmnma 213mm.“
Examine her.
Catch him!
Bahubali!
Bahubali, highness don't kill me
Pardon me, don't kill me
Please leave me
Shiva!
Shiva, kindly pardon me.
I didn't know what else to do
Can't deny you
For you my goal also...
You are mine Avanthika
Whatever you own,
that belongs to me
Even your goal is also mine
I don't know who that Devasena is
But it is her liberation that you wish
I'll liberate her and bring
This is my promise
"Burning ember as breath,
due to wounds in heart"
"Eyes remain dried
and they remain waiting"
"To show one single sight
these chains stand as witness"
"Hey nation, wake up and come"
Mahishmathi calm
down, my son has come!
Bahubali has conquered death
asmnma 213mm.“
Fast, make it fast
Fast!
While installing king's
statue, all must praise him
Nothing is going to happen
It's a hundred feet statue, no?
At least should sacrifice
hundred heads, no?
Bahubali!
Bahubali?
Bahubali
Bahubali!
Who is that?
Chinna, you also come and pull
It has been 15 days since my son
has left, why is he not coming yet?
He is the one who lifts the Shiva
Lingam, nothing will happen to him
If nothing has happened, why is he
not coming here? -Don't know...
...Whether he has seen his parents
Don't know whether he came
to know we are not his parents
Won't my Shiva come back to here?
Ganga! - Here after won't
he call me mother?
Hey fellows, open that cave fast
Come man
On that day trusted me on
seeing the fire burning in my eyes
Today on those same eyes, trust
on the determination that glares
My Shiva will liberate
queen Devasena
Come with me
O Kay
Who has told that custodian of
righteousness Bahubali is not alive?
All though I'm alive
I'm dead long back
And you, still keeps on living
in the minds ofthe people
Bahubali!
On hearing the sound of Bahubali
still echoing in the breeze again
Not mine, it feels like
his statue is rising up
Is it because what that is suppressed
in the mind of people, has it come out?
Or is it because what is seen
in reality, has it come out?
Shucks! No chance at all
Will call all the guards
Grandpa, will enquire who
has started it first
asmnma 213mm.“
Hey what are you doing
here, king is calling, come
Today who has pronounced the
sound Bahubali among the crowd?
The question is asked to you people
Why are you all silent?
Your tongue, should
it be chopped off?
Your highness, we do
not know who he is
Stop it!
Bunch of donkies, are you saying
none among you has seen?
I've seen
It seems like I've seen
those eyes some where
Badhra, Iwant him alive
All of you come
Hey! Who are you man?
He is over here!
Catch him!
Blow the danger siren!
Mother, I've come to liberate you
Kattappa, one stranger has
entered inside the king's palace
He had escaped by
setting fire to kingdom
You all go to the East
I want him alive, doesn't matter if
legs and hands are broken - As you wish
Somehow, want him alive
Come
Heard the danger siren!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Did you think that
you had escaped?
You old lady!
After all these years of punishment
aren't you done with sexual desire?
At the moment on seeing a male,
longs to flirt without shame isn't it?
Kattappa, save me, he
is going to kill me
Young prince, indeed that is my duty
If he wants to touch you,
before that he should defeat me
Karrappa!
Devasena!
They are coming to catch
Devasena, attack together
Bahubali!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Thinking that he is
dead, you had raised him
Made him into a great warrior,
presented to us and strengthened ourtrust
Towards you, this Mahishmathi
is always indebted
My mother's eyes which
should gaze at me with love
She looks at me
with a sorrowed face
Those eyes which I had not seen
so far now looks at me as if I'm God
Not knowing who she is, on seeing
those un-healed wounds on that mother
My anger is burning!
Why is that?
Who am I?
You arethe blood of
our God Amarendra Bahubali
You are blessing as a result of your
mother Devasena 25 years of penance
You are a tree which is sprouted
out of seeds of 'sacrifice' -
...of mother princess Shivagamidevi
Mahendra, the history
which you should...
...know has started
half a century back
The throne of Mahishmathi was
adorned by your grand father...
...Veerendra Vikrama Devan
King's brother Pingaladeva,
was denied with the throne...
...dueto his handicap
in his own mind
Moreover he misunderstood that it
was because of his defect on his arm
He glazed out of anger!
By disdaining the citizen's of Mahishmathi
whom he loved so much
Disdaining his wife who
was six months pregnant
One day great king Veerendra
Vikrama Devan passed away
For three months, the
Mahishmathi was drenched in sorrow
Sister of king as well
as wife of Pingala...
...Shivagamidevi undertook the great
task of ruling on her own shoulders
With her knowledge
and dexterity, Mahishmathi...
...was awarded with
a good governance
However the throne without a king...
...she soon realized it was
a breeding ground for cheaters
Wicked people's cunning
moves echoed on her ears
During the full moon at
'Kalkidakam' (July-August)
The princess withered
out of labor pain
Couldn't save the great princess
The baby is a boy
Bahubali!
While seeing this throne, it seems
like it's a widow's forehead, isn't it?
I'm going to take over this throne
Bringing light to Mahishmathi,
which is remaining in darkness
Indeed an apt decision
You had taken pledge will remain
with Mahishmathi at all times, didn't you?
At the times of a danger it is not
fair to be against country's interest...
...that is not the symbol of a
'Kshatriya'(Warrior), Marthanda
Great minister, sign of a
'Kshatriya' is to conquer the throne
Shivagamidevi!
Believers of royal family
come and stand on my side
Hey Shivagamidevi, who is
going to align behind a lady?
Kattappa...!
Because of them, honor of
Mahishmathi is tinged with shame
Purify itwith blood!
Hey! Did you all see,
he is attacking our men?
Go, slain that slave
and this Shivagami!
Kill Kattappa!
With my own men, stabbing
on my back is it?
What a wild strategy of war'?
Marthanda, this is not
a wild strategy of war
This is the war strategy of the nation
Mother, have seen your knowledge
and courage face to face
You must head this
throne and rule the nation
No, great minister
that is not my place
Who else is it? -Great minister,
that is an unwanted question
My son, Bhallaladeva is
born for this throne
Shivagami, kindly
order the decree
Both my children has got the
equal rights to head the throne
When they grow up, out of them
one who is stronger in combat...
...one who understands the
feelings of subjects more.
He'll be the king of Mahishmathi
This is my order and this is
the decree ofthe country also
"On the sky as darkness spreads"
"She is the ray of light"
"On this lap..."
"Bahubali was born here"
asmnma 213mm.“
"Churns on this sea of milk"
"ls it the poison orthe nectar?"
"To heirthe Mahishmathi
which leaps to skies"
"Bahubali is that sun"
"Adorns arms and garland
Bahubali is winning hero"
Feed me some
Why standing? Kindly sit
Now, you may feed me
Prince, your visit to
here itself is wrong
And sitting beside us,
that is a bigger offence
To quench hunger asked some food,
forthatwhy telling all this rules?
Over there at the palace,
royal feast is waiting for you
Let it be, what'll happen ifl eat this?
The very smell of it,
makes me long to eat it
Prince, even now haven't you
understood what the mistake is?
You hail from royal family
We are from lower caste
If so, I being the prince of
Mahishmathi orders it
Uncle, kindly feed me
G reat!
Great! When I become the
king, you'll be my army chief
Complete training on education
and war techniques are over
Both of your children are
equally skilled, princess
In such a situation how to
decide who'll be the future king?
I'm putting my children to a test
On the contrary, both of them are
equally blessed and Lord tests me
Chief minister, let the next round
of tests be more severe than this
Before deciding who'll
become the king
Princess, had to
confront a new problem
In the form of Shahithan, who was
one of the most trusted one of princess
Princess, a robber killed our guards
and stole our war strategies
Inform the news to two young prince
As your order
Both young princes, rode outside
the borders of Mahishmathi Kingdom.
Traveled to various countries
in search of insurgent
At last came to know that he is
hiding in a place called 'Shringapuram'
That place was the hiding
place for robbers and terrorists
lf at all any strangers enters to that
place, impossible to return alive
You are not seen here before
I'm new to this place
Why do you want a knife
in the waist, are you an informer?
No, no
Check everyone and
only then let them inside
If our men had guarded like this...
We wouldn't be able to
see these countries
Is it strength or intelligence?
Will use whichever is sharp
Take the spirits
This is not enough
This is also not enough
Do you have the money?
Give as much as my brothers need
Not only this there are several more
asmnma 213mm.“
"Veins gets heated up"
"Body drenched in sugarcanejuice"
"Night has lured, melted
and has casted it"
"Has tamed, tightened,
com pressed the bosom"
"Hey beauty"!
Hey beauty,_!"
"Hey naughty, has kept you inside
golden casket, I had given myself to you"
"Today I've come whirling
your tender body..."
"...l'm a snake which
came in search of it"
"Longing for the treasure that is
hidden, the search is on, is on"
"Veins gets heated up"
"Body drenched in sugarcanejuice"
"Haven't we made
flowers out of clouds?"
"Why searching for other ones?"
"Why not pluck the
flowers and tickle it?"
"Magical charm of him"
"indulging in pleasure with him"
"Come beside to extinguish it"
"Hey beauty"!
Hey beauty,_!"
"Entire body was numbed out of
desire, heart throbbed out of lust"
"Longing for the treasure that is
hidden, the search is on, is on"
"Veins gets heated up"
"Body drenched in sugarcanejuice"
asmnma 213mm.“
Better than being severely
tortured in your hands"
Karrappa!
Tell!
To whom have you
send the secrets?
Come on tell
Kalakeya
Kalakeyar, they are like hunters
Once they trespass inside a city...
...they will come and search for crying
babies and squeeze their necks
They rape females without any
distinction on youth and old
Will kill whatever that has got life
Whatever that shines
will be possessed by them
And the restwill be put to flames
Small countries might
be scared of Kalakeyan
Why should we get scared,
as we've 25,000 soldiers?
What is the strength
of the Kalakeya army?
100,000!
Woods where herd of locust flies
land where Kalakeya army moves
That will be converted
into a burial ground
On one side we should protect
the country and on other side...
...we must continue the war
What is ourwar strategy?
'Trident military array'
That strategy is only in the books
No one has tried it
Do you mean to say with
philosophy can go for war?
If no one knows it,
then Kalakeyar also won't know it
Because of that we
should use that one
That is my opinion
I agree to it
To come inside our country
this is the only entrance
Kattappa, to keep offthe enemies...
...not entering how many
soldiers do you want?
5000 soldiers, with spears and
shields will create an iron fort
A big wall made up of soldiers
I'll take the charge of
the army at the North
I'll undertake the army at the South
From the information
what we have received
Kalakeya army head will deploy
only half of his army to forefront
With our military array and
with other weapons...
...any big army can be
detained forten hours
But before that
Kalakeya head must be killed
When the army head is killed, the
army will get scattered and run
At the middle of the war,
at the right time
Both the princes, along
with horse army battalion...
...will attack Kalakeya head
On understanding this
military array and to counter...
...attack they might need two hours
Mother, that is enough for
me to succeed and return
For me, just one hour will be
enough to chop his head and return
Great! One who wins in
this will get thethrone
In the war who kills the Kalakeya
head, he'll get Mahishmathi throne
That is true highness
Yes
For both ofthe princes,
divide the army and give
Bhalva, Bahu time has
given a good opportunity...
...to show your love
towards your country
Make use of it
Long live Mahishmathi Kingdom!
Bahu, what your uncle has
done towards you is injustice
You are given with only weapons
to destroy the wall ofthe fort
On a wide war front what
is the use of that?
All weapons on arrow shooting
is delegated to Bhalvaldevan
Shucks!
You could have denied that initially
Giving the arrow shooting tools
to our prince that was big cheating
What cheating? I need this much
soldiers, these many weapons...
...one who is not capable of
demanding by asking, over here
What is he going to
do at the war field?
A strong person is
provided with more strength
This is not cheating, this is
the strategy of war in the country
Hey who is that?
Kindly excuse
Prince has told to dismantle
the tents and come
Bhalvaldeva, welcome!
Bahubali welcome!
Bahubali!
No need!
Bahu, this is a ritual that is
followed by us for centuries
When the sacrifice is not conducted
the soldiers will get frightened
Their confidence will get swinged
The blood must be spilled!
Yes prince, if sacrifice
is not done before the war...
...will become a victim of Kali's wrath
To quench the thirst of Kali...
...why an animal sacrifice, that
doesn't know anything?
Let my blood be
spilled, which is boiling
Long live Mahishmathi Kingdom!
There is a limit to
Mahishmathi's patience
Giving you a chance for
the last and final time
Leave yourweapons in
the battle field and return...
...you can be spared from killing
Among the two children
of yours, one who kills me
You had informed that he is the king
Perhaps ifthey die in my hands
Along with the country
I'll also attack you
I'm ready to give you a son!
You make him the king!
He should be there, alive!
Today before sun set, legs
and hands chopped off...
...on the battle field, with blood
flowing he should be alive!
For the vultures to pluck out his
eyes, eagles to dig out his intestines...
...he should very much remain alive!
Kattappa!
As peryour order
Let the war sirens blow!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Long live Bahubali!
Start trident military array
Bhalvaldevan!
Young prince!
Soldiers!
Asmnma 213mm.“
Our military array is destroyed
Forthefirst time, in the soil of
Mahishmathi enemy flag is flying
This is the sign of death
Truly, it's death!
Death!
Brave men!
What is death?
More than our strength, thinking
that number of enemies are more...
...that's death
In the battle field, it's better to die
than living in fear, that is death!
After insulting mother and person
laughs before the eyes, on seeing it...
In stead of chopping his head,
fleeing out of fright, that is death!
To win that death, I'm
going to start my journey
My mother as well as my motherland,
no one who is born to a scoundrel...
...can'tjust touch them!
I'll prove this by killing enemies
Who is going to come with me?
I'm the one...!
Who is ready to die with me?
Who is going to succeed
death and live with me?
I'm the one...!
Long live Mahishmathi!
Vultures must pluck out his eyes!
Eagles must dig out his intestines
With legs and hands chopped off
A river of blood should flow!
Yes, my son, mine...!
Let Bhalvaldeva rule!
Asmnma 213mm.“
My Son!
My blood!
My son killed Kalakeyan!
Won the battle!
From now on the king of
Mahishmathi is Bhalvaldevan
Long live Bhalvaldevan
The courage of Bhalvaldevan...
...should be written in
golden letters in history
This success epic should be
scripted on our temple walls
Afterthousands of years, let his
tale of success sung by this soil!
Today, my son Bhalvaldevan
great warrior...
...is appointed as
army chief of Mahishmathi
And I hereby inform, Bahubali
as your future king!
Hey Shivagami, what
a decision is this?
My Son!
Our son!
It was our son, no?
Who killed Kalakeyan
And haven't you seen that?
Why is he not appointed as king?
Why...?
The qualification to become
the king is not on account...
...of how many enemies he killed
It is based on how
many citizens he had saved
In the battle field Bhalvaldeva's
focus was on killing foes
On the other hand, Bahubali, has
slained enemies with one hand
With the other hand
he saved our citizens
That is the difference
between a warrior and a king
One who kills hundred enemies
is indeed a courageous warrior
Being able to save one life
He is equal to God
If anyone saves lower castes,
that to become a king...
Bahubali, will become
the king of Mahishmathi...
...on an auspicious time,
he'll adorn the crown!
This is my final order!
This is my order and my
proclamation for the country
Bahubali!
Immortal Bahubali!
Was my Shivan's father,
such a great valiant?
On hearing about
him I get goosebumps!
Can I see him once?
No mother
That God demised
No weapons can touch,
no foe can come near!
Can you tell how that
brave warrior died?
There is a deadly weapon
than ordinary weapons
Treacherous killing!
Bahubali, was stabbed from back
Who is that?
Who is that cheat?
That cheater...
...l'm the one!
"Dearest dream which is
inflicted with violence in soul..."
"...on one's lap it is
carried, that is life"
"Confronted with dense
woods as proceeded fonlvard"
"Challenging great paths of destiny"
"My beloved is on the march to
succeed for a cherished victory"