MEN WHO HATE WOMEN
from the book by Stieg Larsson
Today they pass judgment
against the journalist -
and the responsible publisher
from Millennium, Mikael Blomkvist, -
who is accused
for gross slander -
of the successful financier
Hans-Erik Wennerstrm.
Blomkvist accused of Wennerstrm
Illegal arms trafficking and fraud -
over 60 million.
The Swedes have always had
divided opinions on Blomkvist.
His supporters believe he is
the last idealistic journalist.
But now his long career as
journalistic watchdog may be over.
In the case Wennerstrm Vs. Millennium
Is defendants Mikael Blomkvist declared -
guilty in six of
eight allegations.
The accused is sentenced
three months' imprisonment -
and a compensation of 150,000
dollars to Hans-Erik Wennerstrm.
How do you see the ruling?
We must stop
people like Kalle Blomkvist -
Digging in honest peoples cases
simply because do not agree with their views.
- I have no further comment.
- There he comes.
How is it
to be declared guilty?
Will you continue as a journalist
Mikael Blomkvist?
- Cheers, everybody. God Jul
- Cheers. God Jul
- Cheers.
- How do we appeal the ruling?
We're behind you
one hundred percent, Micke.
We must do something. The advertisers
have lost confidence in us.
- We wont regain that with an appeal.
- An appeal would win us the time.
- We will not appeal.
- This is about Millennium's future.
The sooner this is over
the better for Millennium.
Not to act as the
Devil's advocate -
but it is not an idea
if Mikael left Millennium?
Just until the storm is over?
Merry Christmas
Wait Micke.
- They are in shock.
- Only Janne dare speak the truth.
- I am a liability for the magazine.
- It's about finding a way out.
There are empty here.
I have not written a word
for several months.
Do you?
Wennerstrm
Delivers a knockout to Blomkvist
Jail!
God damn!
It is rare that we show
our research for our clients.
But we have a special relationship with
your client, so we make an exception in this case.
- That we appreciate.
- I must warn you.
- Lisbeth is a special little girl.
- What do you mean by special?
But make no mistake. She is
our very best researcher.
Good morning, Lisbeth.
Good morning.
Dirch Frode.
Prints of SMS.
E- mail. Bank account overview.
How do I get access to it?
You order the product.
I will deliver it.
What can you tell me
About Blomkvist?
- Everything is in the report.
- The short version.
Blomkvist got the nickname
Kalle Blomkvist -
when he solved
a bank robbery in the 80s.
A public person with no major
secrets. Read the newspaper articles.
- But then he does have secrets?
- Everyone has secrets.
How hard is he affected by the
crisis on Millennium?
- Financially?
- Maybe you should read the report.
Miss Salander,
Do you have anything to add?
Do you have any thoughts of your own?
There is something odd
about the Wennerstrm case.
How so?
Is there more in the case?
I must examine him,
not do his job.
I would like to hear
your personal opinion.
Blomkvist is clean. Not one single speeding ticket.
I found nothing on him.
I do not think
he has fabricated false evidence.
Someone caught him in a trap.
Why did you not ask me?
- No lawyer could save me.
- I know. I have read the ruling.
I did not want to get you involved.
But you could have asked me.
I am your sister.
I know.
I'm stuck in the shit.
Why drag the family down with me?
And now your going to jail.
That is far out.
The secret of good meatballs is
that you have to moisten your fingers.
And then
rub your hands against each other.
Shit. Could you take this for me?
- Hello, this is Micke Blomkvist.
- Hey hey, your little terrorist.
- It's Mikael.
- Mikael Blomkvist?
- Yes. Who I am talking too?
- My name is Dirch Frode.
I am a lawyer.
My client would like to speak with you.
- It is Christmas! Is it important?
- My client do not want to wait.
- Call Millennium after the New Year.
- My client does not want to wait.
- Who is your client?
- Henrik Vanger.
From The Vanger Concern?
My client would appreciate it
if you came.
It is Christmas Eve.
It has been a horrible week.
I promise
you will find it interesting.
Blomkvist!
Henrik lives on the island Hedeby,
A few kilometers from Hedestad.
The bridge here is the only connection
to the mainland.
Once everyone came from the top of
Swedish business community to this estate.
Now, its only Henrik
and the housekeeper Anna, who lives here.
Thank you for coming, Mikael.
Frodes call
was somewhat unusual.
- Are you hungry? There is lunch.
- Otherwise, thank you. Let's get down to business.
- I go home this afternoon.
- Then we skip lunch.
Do you remember her?
That is Harriet Vanger,
my brother Gottfried's daughter.
You have met her.
The girl here?
Your father worked for me
in summer 1965.
He was a mechanical engineer in the workshop
and lived in one of our cabins.
You and your mother came to visit -
at weekends.
Harriet liked you.
You often played out there by the water.
I remember her.
- Harriet.
- I never got any children himself.
Harriet was my precious.
She was an incredibly smart girl.
I looked at her
like my own daughter.
What happened to her?
- I think she was murdered.
- Murdered?
This is family Vanger, Mikael.
My family.
22. September 1966. That day
the whole family gathered in this house -
to the annual meeting.
30 petty and greedy people -
who fought over who would
have the largest piece of the cake.
One of these people...
...murdered Harriet.
Harriet was 16 years.
It was Children's Day.
She had been inside the Herdestad
to see the parade on the main street.
That image
was printed in the local newspaper.
Around two she came
back to the island.
She wanted to talk to me
about something, but...
...I was busy
with a board meeting.
How was she murdered?
Nobody knows.
She just disappeared.
You are well prepared.
I have thought of that day in 40 years.
That you can call preparation.
Quarter past two, there was a serious
traffic accidents down on Hedeby Bridge.
A tanker full of gasoline
collided with a car.
Truck was across the bridge.
Tank leaked gasoline
All over the place.
Nobody could get past.
All had to stay on the island.
By accident
the photographer captured it here.
See up there at the curtain.
It is the last picture
made by Harriet.
Commissioner Morell from Hot Hedeby
led the investigation.
He took the film here and had made
Enlargements of this image.
Since then, no-one have seen her.
We waited for her at dinner,
but she never showed up.
- Hello?
- Lisbeth Salander?
- Who is it?
- Svensson from the state administration.
- You have a new guardian. Bjurman.
- I already have a guardian.
Your previous guardian was
hospitalized with a stroke, -
- so I had to
find you a new one.
Good we could meet,
though it's Christmas, Sit down.
It is a bit unfortunate -
that Palmgren has had such a lax
approach to guardianship law.
I see
you've managed your own economy.
- It has not been a problem.
- No, it probably is not.
But as your guardian
I am legally and financially responsible.
That means I get the blame if
you suddenly cannot pay rent.
I have work.
I earn my own money.
Yes, you work for
Milton Security, I see...
- What are you there?
- I make coffee and photocopies.
We do it this way:
From now on, your salary goes into
a new account, which I dispose over.
You get some pocket money every month
for personal expenses -
but all other expenses
I will have to accept. Okay?
How do you manage
your personal hygiene?
What do you mean?
With all those rings.
Don't you get inflammation in the holes?
Do you have a girlfriend?
No.
Have you ever had sexual intercourse?
I am 24 years.
I can choose to write
that you are cooperating, -
or that you create problems
and is being troublesome.
And then your life
quickly become very problematic.
So how many
have you had sex with?
- Two.
- Two?
200. No, 2000.
- 200,000. Are we finished?
- What kind of sex do you have?
Any special preferences?
Have you considered
That might just have left?
No, because of the accident.
The bridge was blocked for 24 hours.
And it was the only way off the island.
Harriet disappeared,
while no one could leave the island.
The day after we thought
that it could be a crime.
But then the bridge was open, and the killer
could have gotten rid of the body.
She may have drowned
have committed suicide.
We searched after her. We put dogs out
and divers in the water.
Even today,
when I take a walk, -
I find myself
looking for her.
When Harriet was eight,
She gave me a birthday present.
A bluebell
from 1958.
Then she gave me
a new flower every year.
1966.
The year when Harriet disappeared.
We have to go to the attic.
Incredible.
Every damn year, I get
a flower on my birthday -
from a new spot
on the world map.
- Who do you think you send them?
- Harriet's murderer.
You do not know my family.
You do not know what they are capable of.
I favored Harriet. It did
her an obvious victim for them -
Those who wanted more power
in The Vanger Concern.
They wanted to crush me.
I am 82 years.
The police have since long given up.
I end up going to the grave
without knowing.
Help me
to make one last attempt.
- Why just me?
- I have followed you.
You are a good journalist. Stubborn.
I do not ask you
to solve the puzzle. Just make an attempt.
There are half a year to
you must serve your sentence.
You have devoted 40 years...
I will pay you
a good fee.
You will be wealthy.
You have nothing to lose.
You have nothing
to return to in Stockholm.
"Blomkvist resigns from the Board
and works no longer for Millennium."
Have you written the press release
without talking to me first?
It is me
who must take the decision.
What happens now?
I will work for Henrik Vanger
in Hedeby.
Aha. So now you
work for large capitalists.
It is not for The Vanger Concern.
Are you going to live there?
In Hedeby?
Good trip.
CONNECTING BLOMKVIST
CONNECTION ACHIEVED
FULL ACCESS
NO NEW ACTIVITIES
I'll crush you.
What are you looking at?
What the fuck are you doing, you pussy?
The whore need to lie down.
- Cunt!
- Down with her!
- The bitch is crazy.
- Come again, pig!
Come on.
Shit.
What did you say?
- I can save the hard disk.
- Good.
And the rest?
You need to go on sales hunting.
- How did that happen?
- Nevermind.
- You stink of beer.
- And you just showered?
You can borrow the desktop PC.
I use it for backup,
so it needs to stay here.
Welcome to Hedeby.
Very refreshing
with this cold weather.
You did not want to live in the main building,
so I hope you'll like it here.
If it gets colder,
The water pipes freeze.
Then you must come up to me
and get water.
Yes? Well, it is good.
Just put them here.
It is part of the material
I've collected over the years.
There are pictures.
Police Reports.
Newspaper. In addition
some of Harriet's possessions.
It is a start.
You were a beautiful nanny.
What did you experience?
Defending Sweden's purity:
We are the
Swedish national socialists -
Which the Aryan race
can not do without:
Family Vanger is
a pretty unpleasant bunch.
Most of us detest each other,
but are forced together by the company.
In there lives my brother Harald.
To put it mildly
we do not get along together.
Your brothers Richard and Harald
was in a Nazi group in the 30s.
Well, you know that already.
Gottfried was in the Hitler Jugend.
They were all three Nazis.
Yes. Fanatical.
Richard fell in
The Finnish Winter War.
Harald has been a bitter, old
man. He never goes outside of a door.
Harald's daughter Cecilia
Is in Scotland at the moment.
Cecilia and Harald
are not on speaking terms.
In there lives Martin, Harriet's brother.
He took over The Vanger Concern
after me.
Hello.
There you are. It is
the famous Kalle Blomkvist.
Just call me Mikael.
I am curious to hear
why you want to -
spend six months
in this godforsaken town.
Martin and Harriet's father, Gottfried, -
lived a miserable and
alcoholized life with his Isabella.
I have never seen a woman be
as bad a mother as Isabella.
I intervened
and took care of Harriet and Martin.
That was all the family members
who live here.
On the day itself
there was even more.
Cecilia's sister Anita,
who died of cancer.
- Greger Vanger and Ulrika Vanger.
- Stop just a moment.
Who do you suspect?
None.
And everyone.
That is where you come in...
Dear diary. Today I got this
book by my dear uncle Henrik.
A nice, but busy man.
He has finally come home
from his trip and gave me this book.
I sit alone in my father's summer house
and write. Anita is coming soon.
So that is you
who pry into the family's history?
Shit you scared me!
Cecilia Vanger.
Henrik said you were here.
- Mikael Blomkvist.
- I know you from the newspapers.
- What have you there?
- Harriet's bible.
She was often here
with my sister.
- Anita?
- Yes.
The last summer
before she disappeared.
- Strange, since her father died here.
- Gottfried died here?
He got really drunk and fell in the lake.
They found him the next morning.
Down at by the bridge.
This happened
years before Harriet disappeared.
Henrik said you were abroad.
I had to come home
to hide Harriet's body.
We were not allowed to go here when we were small.
It was forbidden.
Thank you.
Dear diary. It is autumn.
The weather has been colder.
Magda 30112.
Sara 32016.
BJ 32027.
LJ 31208.
32018. Mari
I do not understand why
Henrik hired you.
Me neither, to be honest.
With all due respect: There is nothing
to find. Its almost 40 years ago.
I found Harriet's diary
in her father's cottage.
- Yes, but the journal did not help us.
- What with the five phone numbers?
- The phone numbers was a big mystery.
- But 32 is...
32 can be Hedenstad.
30 is Norrbyns area code.
But the names and numbers
do not match.
- Did you ring the numbers?
- We rang. Tried them backwards.
Swapped them, took numbers out.
We tried everything.
The report describes her as
introverted and religious.
Was that also your impression?
Who is not introvert
as a teenager?
But yes, she stayed for herself.
Anita, her cousin, knew her best.
Anita is Cecilia Vanger's sister.
And Anita is dead.
She died many years ago.
Harriet was my first case.
I have thought about the case
every day for almost 40 years.
I retire this summer. It is
only now I can let it go.
There is no answer.
You gain nothing but
keeping Henrik's obsession alive.
Drop the case
Before you become obsessed with it.
What are you working on?
Plague calling WASP.
Hello.
- Who is this week's victim?
- No one.
Still that journalist?
I thought you were finished with him.
Why do you keep on?
Yes, it is a bit slow.
A new computer?
- Yes, I need 20,000.
- Why do you need a PO for 20.000?
- Game, surf the Internet.
- Do you surf the Internet a lot?
Do you chat?
You know, Lisbeth?
I can not just give you 20,000.
- Not just like that.
- How hard can it be?
Why can I not manage my account?
Hit again. Do it now.
That is what you want, right?
Hit me.
If there are problems with you
I will arrange for -
you are cooped up the
rest of your life.
I know all about your mental
problems and violent background.
Understand me right, Lisbeth...
I would like to give you
the 20.000.
But you know
that any trade -
is based on trust.
I have to feel that I can trust you.
Can I do that, sweetheart?
Can I trust you, Lisbeth?
Can I trust you?
If you're nice to me...
If you're nice to me
I will always be nice to you.
- It's only 7.000.
- More than enough for a computer.
What are you looking at?
You said it was the newspaper's photographer,
who took pictures of the children's parade.
Yes, both that and the traffic accident.
The old part of the archive
is very messy.
We have not scanned it electronically,
so everything is still in negative folders.
20... 30...
...40, 50, 60...
A photographer will take between two and ten
rolls in one day.
Closer to ten,
when we were talking about Children's Day.
Here. September 1966.
I will only need the hour,
of the procession.
- Knock yourself out.
- Is it not sorted?
If you are lucky,
they are roughly chronological.
Do you have a negative scanner
and a light table?
This is the first trace in the case
in 39 years.
It is a start.
It is more than that.
See there.
Thinking about the same as I?
What is it that caught her eye?
What is she afraid of?
Her murderer.
About here
on the other side of the street -
Is Harriet's murderer.
- Coffee, Mikael?
- What have you found out?
I must have read...
...several thousand pages.
People have been on the case for 40 years.
To be quite honest, -
I have not found anything.
Should you not be in Stockholm
and try to appeal your conviction?
- Leave it.
- No you leave it.
- Mikael is old enough to...
- I was lured into a trap.
One of my old classmates
gave me a tip on Wennerstrm's company.
It was a good story.
Good enough to trap him.
You would think.
Yes, for suddenly there was an even
better history of fraud -
and arms trade for 60 million.
Wennerstrm's name appeared everywhere.
So far so good.
So I wrote the story.
The all my sources disappeared.
And all documents and evidence
proved to be fabricated.
Counterfeit?
It was too lure you
away from the real story?
It was too good to be true.
Do you want something, that
is really too good to be true?
Single malt. 21 years old.
To hell with the past
mischief. Cheers to you.
- Cheers.
You...
Should we take one last glass of wine?
I had enough.
- Thank you for a pleasant evening.
- Because of the investigation?
My secretive family?
- What do you mean?
- It could be me. Right?
I am also
on your list of suspects.
- Bjurman.
- It is Lisbeth.
- What do you want?
- I need more money.
- That we can talk about.
- I need them now.
Welcome.
Come in and take off your jacket.
- I just need my money.
- You'll get your money.
Thank you for last time.
I hope you also had a nice time.
I will not suck cock
every time I need the money.
Oh you will not?
What would you want to do then?
Should I call
to social services and say -
you're breaking into my home
and exhibits threatening behavior?
Then we see how fast you can go
back to the psychiatric hospital.
What say you?
That was better.
There you go.
Come here.
Come on.
No!
I have a... rule
you need to learn.
If you resist, then...
Are you sweet? Are you sweet now?
NORSJ carpentry
My husband died many years ago.
There is only me here.
He worked in the carpentry
for 24 years.
They did everything from clothes pegs
to Wardrobes.
He has done the cupboard there.
And the lamp, of course.
More cake?
Do you remember whether you were in Hedeby
in September 1966?
Hedeby...
- In 66...
- Yes, 66
- That was our honeymoon.
- How nice. Do you have pictures from it?
We camped.
It was the latest fashion.
It was our best trip together.
Honeymoons often is.
- But you have some pictures?
- Yes, I have them.
Who does not store images
from their honeymoon?
On the first part of the journey
we walked in the mountains.
My husband had always walked a lot.
So it was some long walks.
He was not exactly
romantic.
Now let's see.
Hedeby...
See there.
How beautiful.
Although the image does not
do the sunset justice.
Now let's see. Here's something.
- There was a parade.
- Did you?
What the hell are you doing here?
I was on the way out.
You have misunderstood the rules. You must
agree with me when you come.
Do you hear me?
Let me go.
Do you hear me? Let me go!
Do you like being tied?
Or does it turn you on
tying others?
Super nice.
Have you chosen that yourself?
You did not chose it?
I think it is nice.
Have you seen the program in which
politicians were filmed with a hidden cameras?
We have those cameras at my work.
I had one in the bag last time.
Welcome.
I thought
I had to blow you.
But you are sicker,
than I thought.
The products a couple of hours. Think about
what the police and the media would say.
Enjoy.
Thanks for last time.
I hope you also had a good time.
I will not suck cock
every time I need the money.
Oh you will not?
What would you like to do?
Now I will tell you,
how we are doing. You nod in response.
I dispose of my own account.
You no longer have access.
I dispose of my own money.
Is that understood?
Every month you write in a report
I behave myself exemplary.
Better than ever.
In exactly a year you apply for
getting my guardianship terminated.
There will be a mail with instructions.
You should never contact me.
If you do, I send copies of the
film to the police and all the newspapers.
The same happens
If I have an accident -
or you break my rules.
Is that understood?
I have never tried it before.
Lie still, otherwise you make a mess.
Lie still.
I am a sadistic PIG
AND A rapist
FIND BLOMKVIST LAPTOP
CONNECTING BLOMKVIST
...the past year or so...
...religious fanaticism.
SEND
This guy in the blue sweater.
I can not get him sharper.
I can not do a damn thing.
It is crazy blurred.
- Are you sure?
- Completely sure. I have tried everything.
Well, thanks for the help.
Talk to you later.
WASP...
Harriet phone numbers.
Read it here and you will cringe,
Kalle Blomkvist...
Leviticus...
"If a woman
comes an animal near..."
...for them to mate, you must
kill both the woman and the animal.
They must suffer death."
32018. Mari
Magda 30112.
Leviticus,
Chapter 1, verse 12
"...she shall take two doves -
- one for burn victim
and the other for a sin sacrifice."
BJ 32027.
"When a man or woman..."
"When a man or woman
have a deadcaller's spirit in themselves -
they shall suffer death.
I will stone them."
They must suffer death.
Frode! What happened?
It is Henrik.
He suddenly fell down.
We return,
when we know more.
It is a heart attack.
They operate on him.
- What are the prospects?
- They talk about bypass. This is serious.
- Want a coffee?
- No.
You must continue the investigation.
- Have you put more on the task?
- No, it is only you.
Then there is someone named WASP who
hacking into my computer.
I have received a mail with a copy of
one of my own documents.
So he has been
on my hard drive.
Do you know anything about it?
No...
No, but I have a guess -
whom it can be.
You just sleep on.
Lisbeth Salander?
- Who are you?
- You know that. Can I come in?
I have read your report.
Exciting reading.
You gained illegally access into my files.
It would interest the police.
Like the fact that you still
hack into my computer.
If you remove that folder
I'll remove the chain.
What do you want?
- Hi.
- All right?
- What do you want?
- Is there coffee in the jug?
How much do you know
about my job?
A 40-year murder
on a 16-year-old girl.
Until today I was not sure that
that she was murdered.
Then you showed me
that it was the bible quotes -
on women
to be killed.
- And?
- It is the main trail so far.
- I need your help.
- You will be well paid.
- I have a job.
You work
as a professional hacker, -
but send me a mail
you know I can track.
Why?
What?
But he survives?
Can he have visitors?
Lisbeth Salander is here.
It is good Frode.
We talk to you. Thank you.
If a woman
an animal comes near...
I assume that you are updated.
We have shared files lately.
Yes.
You... What if the quotations
do not have a thing to do with God?
If it is a kind of code?
"Sara Witt was found found
murdered in the family byre -
outside of Vilhelmina in 1962."
Sara? What else doe sit say?
"Between two and three o'clock
at night the victim was lured out..."
"The young woman's body was mutilate,
possibly after a religious ritual.
Police would not disclose details."
Mutilated, possibly religious...
Was the killer found?
No. The case was never solved.
- It's a shot in the dark.
- I know.
- How far is it to Vilhelmina?
- A bit too far on a motorcycle.
What are we waiting for?
- Do you want to drive?
- Why?
I have not driven
since the divorce.
Then it is about time.
Female Names
always leads to porno sites.
What are you doing?
Sets the computer to search through
some newspaper databases.
We should be in the cowshed.
They could not sell the farm after the
murder. It has stood empty since then.
She was found here?
Yes. Her husband found her.
Terrible for him. Terrible.
It was here she was.
In her crib.
Curbed and beaten.
Animals were also abused?
How did you know?
"If a woman
an animal comes near...
...you must kill
both woman and animal."
- It may be a coincidence.
- Yes.
Damn da, Lisbeth.
If the other also fits...
I have found
an old television program.
A program from 1999
about a murder in Dalarna.
"In the series' Swedish murders 'we have
come to Magda Lovisa Sjberg -
from Dalarna."
Magda...
"A cruel murder mystery, which caused
police problems in November 1954."
- Had we not a Magda-quote?
- Leviticus, Chapter 1, verse 12
"So he cut it out
also head and suet, -
and the priest shall put it on the
wood over a fire on the altar."
That was literally.
It was quoted word by word.