Let The Right One In
Squeal like a pig.
Come on, squeal!
Squeal! Squeal!
Like a pig!
The police have ways of
detecting a criminal...
Do you remember the fire in ngby?
A burnt house and
they found a body inside.
We know that
the fire was started...
... to hide that this person
was murdered before.
So, how did we know this?
- I know.
- Yes, you. Go ahead.
There wasn't smoke in
the body's lungs.
Correct. Have you
heard this before?
No... I just read a lot.
What kind of books would those be?
Just books.
Ok, now I'm going
to talk to you about drugs.
The kind of drugs you might
think are most common--
Hey, Oskar!
What are you looking at?
Are you looking at me?
Eat shit!
Oink!
What a good little pig you are.
- Let's go. It's time for gym.
- I'm not going.
This is the weather report...
Excuse me...
- ... Can you tell me what time it is?
- I don't have a watch.
- What is that?
- This? It's called Halotano.
Get out!
Stupid dog!
What are you looking at?
Are you looking at me?
Eat shit!
What is your problem?
Are you scared?
Squeal, then!
Squeal!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Do you live here?
- Yes...
I live right here in the playground.
Seriously, where do you live?
- Next door to you.
- How do you know where I live?
Just so you know
I can't be your friend.
- What are you trying to say?
- Does there have to be a reason?
That's just how it is.
How do you know I
want to be your friend?
You're supposed to help me!
Should I just
take care of myself?
Say something!
Pardon me.
They don't know
who murdered the boy.
I imagine that
many of you are worried.
The counseler will be here
all day long...
...so you can see him if you like.
Any questions?
Is it ok if we kill the murderer
if we see him?
That is not ok, Conny.
Oskar...
- Where are you, piggy?
- Piggy!
Now you go
directly to the school.
And don't leave the yard
until I get home.
- But I'm going to Vallingby.
- A man that kills children...
...could easily take
the metro for two stations.
Or walk a mile.
No, Oskar, you'll stay with
your father next week.
PUNCTURE MURDER
FOR BLOOD
THE VICTIM'S BLOOD
WAS EXTRACTED
- Hi.
- If not for my sweetheart...
The death penalty isn't right
in a just state.
A just state?
The government wants to sell us
that crap, like the Russians did...
Are you saying that there
aren't any more Russians?
- Of course there are...
- I've never seen one.
But like snakes
they haven't bit anyone.
That guy over there just moved
next door. He's got a daughter.
Where Janne lived.
- Should I invite him to the table?
- Sure...
So long as he
buys us a round.
In that case he's welcome
although he's got cancer.
Bad news?
Yeah, life stinks...
You're in Department 15, right?
You don't have to stay here alone,
come and have a little fun.
No thanks, I'm in a hurry.
Mom, I'm going out for a bit.
You aren't going to watch the show?
No, I don't like it.
Don't leave the yard.
I'll watch it alone then.
Here you are again.
You've returned.
- I want to be alone.
Me too.
Go home, then.
You go home, I
lived here first.
- What's that?
- This?
A Rubik's cube.
Like a puzzle?
Yeah...
You wanna try it?
- You can give it back to me tomorrow.
I don't know if I'll come tomorrow.
The next day, then,
but no later.
How do you do it?
Each side should be
only one color.
Like this...
You smell weird.
- Aren't you cold?
- No.
- Why not?
- I forget.
See you tomorrow.
Thanks for another night
of friendship and happiness.
- See you tomorrow.
- You're the best, Jocke.
Help...
Hello?
Please help me.
Did something bad happen?
Are you alright?
- Can you get up?
- No...
I'll carry you to a phone.
- Careful.
- You're so light.
Son of a bitch!
Never again...
Gosta? My god what a long time.
I think I haven't seen you all year.
Jocke...
Jocke!
I was on the balcony and saw...
...I saw Jocke and that girl.
How old is the girl?
He was here.
Clean it.
What the fuck is that?
Holy shit! It's blood!
Who the fuck did this?
How did you do it?
I just turned it.
Do I smell better now?
What's your name?
Eli.
- And you?
- Eli?
I'm Oskar.
- How old are you?
- 12... more or less.
What about you?
12 years, 8 months, and 9 days.
What do you mean
"more or less"?
When's your birthday?
I don't know.
You don't celebrate your birthday?
Your parents should know.
Then you've never even
gotten a birthday present?
No.
You can keep it if you want.
It's yours.
I don't know how to solve it.
You want me to show you?
- Sure, here.
- Start with the corners.
Then this part. And you put it...
...like this.
No... like this, then this.
"...Dodging in and out of the shadows,
running rapidly and silently...
...and hiding from the sun..."
...They returned quickly, between
moans and curses, to care for the portal..."
...Bilbo had escaped."
Ok... that's all for today.
Did they give you the note
for the field trip on Thursday?
They can go then.
- Oskar, you aren't--
- No, I've got stuff to do.
Hurry up, Conny!
What were you writing?
What do you mean?
Show it to me.
No.
What are you talking about?
Give it to me.
Who's gonna tell
your mommy now?
Wait for me!
Oskar...
Piggy!
I slipped in the park...
- ...and I fell on a rock.
- Oh, sweetie...
You have to look
where you're going.
Short, long, long, short, long...
- Short, long, long, short, long.
- Exactly.
Here...
What happened?
There.
Some classmates...
- What school do you go to.
- Oskar, listen...
Answer me.
You never answer...
... Why not?
So do it.
Answer me...
- There's three of them.
- Louder.
Hit them as hard as you can,
and they'll leave you alone.
- And what if they--
- Then I'll help you.
I can help you.
Come on.
Move.
You're in the way.
Let's go.
Now let's see... short, short...
G...O...O...D
L...U...C...K
Maintain your distance.
Not too close nor too far.
Keep your distance.
With rhythm and without errors.
Yeah?
For the weightlifting program
after school...
... Can  I sign up?
You don't have to sign up,
just come at 7 o'clock.
Are you thinking about doing it?
Sure.
If you practice, you'll get strong.
See ya later.
Just a second...
Assorted candies.
Take em.
No.
What a pain in the ass.
I'll try one.
I'm sorry.
Oskar...
Do you like me?
Yeah, a lot.
If I wasn't a girl...
... Would you like me the same?
I think so.
Why do you ask?
Oskar!
Hello, son.
- You're home early.
- Hi, Dad.
There are people who've seen my face...
...and know that I live here with you.
Maybe you shouldn't.
What else can
I do for you?
Can you do something for me?
Can you not see that boy
tonight? Please.
What--?
Why are you so late, Matte?
Hey, Matte.
You can touch at home.
Hurry up, Matte.
What are you doing?
- Matte!
- Put me down.
Put me down!
Help!
- Matte!
- Help!
- Open the goddam door!
Help!
- Put me down!
- What are you doing here?
Eli.
...according to leader of the Communist
Party, Congressman Brezhnev.
An unidentified man was
arrested yesterday for murder...
...tentatively in Vllingby
on the outskirts of Estocolmo.
The man abused himself
resulting in serious wounds on his face...
...that made it impossible
to identify him. Now, sports--
You can come in. Through that door.
Yeah?
Excuse me. I'm looking for my father.
Is he in this hospital?
What's his name?
He's sick. The police brought him in.
Do you know where he is?
He's on the seventh floor.
But it's a restricted area.
You can call him...
No... that's ok.
Poor creature.
Can I come in?
A child...
What child?
- Why did he kill Jocke?
- I ... I don't know.
Jocke was the best
subject I have found.
I should tear that girl
apart limb from limb.
Oskar!
Can I come in?
Don't look at me.
But you have to let me in.
Ok, come in.
Close your eyes.
How did you get there?
- Flying.
- Yeah, right.
You're not even there.
You're as cold as ice.
I'm sorry...
Do I disgust you?
No.
Eli...
Do you want to go out with me?
What do you mean?
Well...
Will you be my girlfriend?
Oskar...
...I'm not a girl.
But... You want
to go out with me, right?
Why can't we just
leave things as they are?
I guess...
Do you do anything special
when you go out with someone?
No.
So it's the same.
Yeah.
We'll go out together then.
Just you and I.
Seriously?
Yup.
Attention!
The lower grades
will skate with me.
The older kids
can skate alone.
Watch out for her holes.
- Do you understand?
- vila...
- I think you meant THE holes.
- THE holes.
I meant to say THE holes!
You want to be a "diver"?
Watch out for HER holes!
Do you want to swim or not?
No.
Mr. vila, I have to piss.
- Go behind that tree.
- On the ice?
Does it matter? You'll just make
more ice, but yellow.
What's that stick for?
To hit you if you
try anything.
So you're a brave little
piggy all of the sudden?
I'm going to push you
and you won't do anything.
Isn't that right?
Little baby piggy watch where
you walk or I'll catch you...
Look!
Let's go.
Mr. vila will be mad...
Should we stay here
and not do anything?
What happened there?
What are you doing?
Of course they accuse us!
What do you want him to say?
That my son doesn't have a father?
Yeah! That's it!
Here he comes.
The school called.
Better if you talk to your
father rather than me--
Hi.
I'm good.
I don't know.
Does the bike work?
Ok, let's see.
Hi Oskar.
So you finally went swimming?
I'm just kidding.
We shouldn't be here.
But some of the bigger kids
come here anyway.
And you know what? Today...
They tried to push me
on the ice... but I...
...but I had a stick and I hit Conny
so hard they sent him to the hospital.
Oskar...
Yeah?
Well done.
What do you want us to do?
Mix...
It doesn't hurt.
The only thing you have to do
is pinch the finger.
Eli?
Get out!
Get out of here!
They had to use a crane to get
him out. You have to contact the police.
- What's the problem, Gsta?
- They're going to interrogate me.
What are you talking about?
They took me to one of those rooms...
...and they pointed a lamp at my face.
- Jocke and I were like that together.
- I'm sorry, but I can't...
It's your responsibility, you
were a witness to a crime.
Oh god...
You're thinking what a
good guy you were...
Now that it happened, there's nothing left for me.
Nothing.
- Oh, Lacke.
- Stop it!
Don't try that "Oh Lacke Lacke" crap.
You don't understand,
you were so cold.
No one understands.
Very subtle, Lacke.
Ginia, please wait.
Can we at least talk about it?
Let's go...
Let her go!
Wait... you brought my lighter.
That wasn't my intention, Ginia...
I love you.
What the fuck?
No...
- I didn't wait for that.
- You'll never do it.
- But this time I beat you.
- Keep dreaming.
You first.
- Look who's here!
- Good evening everyone.
It seems like she's
getting along very well.
That's true.
Oskar's here...
Ok...
Dad...
-... it's your turn.
- We have visitors.
It's warm and cozy here, right?
So did you have fun?
"I should go and live,
or stay and die" Take it, Eli.
Everything turned out wrong.
It seemed ok, but your
calculations were incorrect.
It was a mistake from the beginning.
And it gets worse. When
you pass those buildings...
Busy night.
Come on in.
Ginia? Where the hell were you?
What happened?
I was so worried about you.
- What happened to you?
- Leave me alone!
No...
Open the door you son of a bitch!
Let me in! No...
Oskar, is that you?
Yeah.
You're a vampire?
I live on blood... if that's what you mean.
You're...
...dead?
No.
Can't you tell?
But...
You're old?
I'm 12.
But I've been 12 for
a very long time.
You're poor?
You see that egg over there?
If you sold it you
could buy a nuclear power plant.
Seriously.
Yeah, right...
Put your finger on it.
Where did those rings come from?
I'm going home.
I have to distribute a
few thrills tomorrow.
For money?
I can give you money.
Here. Take it if you want.
You took this...
...from the people
you killed, isn't that right?
- They gave it to me.
- Who gave it to you?
Different people.
I'm going home now.
Yeah, you're leaving me.
The time has come to sell this.
Dad's stamp collection.
This one, one stamp...
...is worth $80,000.
If we find a good buyer
we won't get less than that...
Then we'll buy this pretty cabin.
The country is so beautiful.
We can both live there.
Listening to the birdsong
and growing vegetables...
Lacke, you have to help me.
Sure...
That girl...
May have infected me somehow.
I don't want to keep on living.
Good morning!
Everything went well.
I think I'll go home today.
Wouldn't he like to?
We'll take this...
And we'll take a blood sample.
There we go.
Listen...
Can I open the blinds?
Sure... no problem.
Give me your hat. Let's go!
What's your problem?
Give it to me.
Are you stupid?
Come on, give it to me.
Give it to him hard, Conny!
- Fight.
- Are you blind as well as deaf?
- Hi.
- What's up?
Can you give me the keys?
I'm going home.
- Sure, here you go.
- Thanks, see ya.
- Who sent you home?
- Good, good...
- What are you laughing at?
- Are you hard of hearing, Conny?
- Hi.
You have to invite me in.
And if I don't?
What happens if you just come in?
Is there something in your way?
No!
Come in!
Who are you?
I'm just like you.
What do you mean?
What are you looking at?
Huh?
Are you looking at me?
Scream then!
Squeal!
Those are the first words
that I heard you say.
I don't kill people.
But you'd like it if you could...
For revenge, right?
Yeah.
I do it because I have to.
I know, Eli, just for a while.
Please, Oskar, I know Eli.
I can give you one of my mom's dresses.
Oskar...
...let me in.
What are you doing?
I'm in the tub, I'm be right there.
Let me in, Oskar.
Hi, I'm in the tub. Please
don't come in. You want to go out tonight?
I'd like that very much. Come in, Eli.
I can't see...
No!
Let me go!
Thanks.
Oskar...
I should go far away.
WHO KILLED THE MAN IN THE ICE?
Hello? Is that you, Oskar?
It's me, Martin. Mr. Avila wants
to know if you're coming tonight.
Why?
Just wants to know, I guess.
I'm sure he wants you to come.
I'm not sure...
That was good...
What you did to Conny.
- He earned it.
- What an actor...
You think so?
Sure. Are you coming tonight?
- Ok, Oskar.
- Hi.
Hi, Oskar.
Hi.
Come on, let's do aerobics in the water.
Hurry up!
Come on, Oskar! Let's go!
Move it.
What? Oh god!
Call the firemen! Fire!
Stop!
Get out!
Do you know who I am?
- Yes.
- Ok, then you should understand.
Let's have a little contest.
You have to stay under the water...
...for three minutes.
If you can do it I'll only cut you a little.
But if you can't...
...I'll take an eye.
An eye for an ear,
does that sound fair?
But it's impossible.
That's your problem.
Three minutes.
You'd better breathe deep.
five, four, three...
...two, one.
- Jimmy...
- Shut up!
- Come on, Conny.
- I said shut up!
Translated by
Black Kbbath