You know, after last year's corporate,
my wife was always encouraging me.
You know, she said: you did fine,
you did fine in the corporate.
I was a bit nervous. This
little guy... hello. Sorry.
That's nice, eh? Nice background
with the people there...
We are here at the... must I look..?
- Just look straight at the lens.
We are here at the... MNU head office,
Department of Alien Affairs.
My name is Wikus Van De Merwe.
And behind me you can see
the Alien Affairs' workers.
And what we do here at
this department is...
we try to engage with the Prawn
on behalf of MNU and
on behalf of humans.
To everyone's surprise, the
ship didn't come to a stop
over Manhattan or Washington or Chicago,
but instead it costed to a halt
directly over the city of Johannesburg.
The doors didn't open for 3 months. It
just hovered there. Nobody could get in.
And they eventually decided,
after much deliberation,
that the best thing to do would
be to physically cut their way in.
We were on the verge of first contact.
The whole world was watching.
Expecting, I don't know...
...music from heaven and
bright shining lights.
Oh my God!
The creatures were
extremely malnourished,
they were very unhealthy,
they seemed to be aimless.
There was a lot of international
pressure on us at the time.
The entire world was
looking at Johannesburg,
so we had to do the right thing.
The government then established
an aid group that started to
ferry the aliens to a temporary
camp set up just beneath the ship.
We didn't have a plan.
There was a million of them.
So, what was a temporary
holding zone soon became fenced,
became militarized. And before
we knew it, it was a slum.
But the truth is, nobody
really knew what this place was.
There's a lot of secrets in District 9.
At first, a lot of
attention was given to...
giving the aliens a proper
status and protection.
They're spending so much
money to keep them here.
When they could be spending
it on other things, but...
...at least they're keeping
them separate from us.
l want to be realistic with everyone.
The aliens will not be able to go home.
The aliens are here to stay.
There were literally
thousands of different theories
as to why the ship seemed inoperable,
and what was speculated was that
the command module had detached
itself from the main ship,
and then somehow
mysteriously became lost.
Did it fall by itself or was
it programmed? I don't know.
Examination of the old video footage
shows very clearly that a
piece falls from the ship.
We look for it. We look everywhere.
This piece that's falling
caused us bloody problems.
More energy weapon caches found.
The Special task force
conducted raids in District 9.
Where there's a weapon, there's
crime. Tensions rose, and rose.
People became more and more fed up,
and eventually the rioting started.
Residents in Tembisa rioted
for the third consecutive night
in an attempt to remove all
the aliens from their township.
I think they must fix
that ship and they must go.
A virus, a selective virus.
Release it near the aliens.
They must just go. I
don't know where, just go.
If they was from another
country we might understand.
But they are not even from this planet.
The government have
enforced a nationwide curfew.
The aliens, prawns,
they take my wife away.
The derogatory term Prawn is used for
the alien, and obviously it implies
something that is a bottom feeder,
that scavenges the leftovers.
I mean, you can't say
they don't look like that.
That's what they look like,
right? They look like prawns.
The aliens made off with an undisclosed
amount of cash. One bystander was hurt.
What for an alien might be
seen as something recreational,
setting fire to a
truck, derailing a train,
is for us obviously an
extremely destructive act.
They can take the sneakers
you are wearing off you.
They take whatever you have on
you. Your cell phone or anything.
After that they kill you.
And now, after 20 years, public
pressure had forced the government
to shift the aliens out of Johannesburg.
They had had enough and they
wanted District 9 to be moved,
and more intensively
policed and controlled.
So, to enforce this mass eviction,
the government turned to MNU.
Welcome all and thank you for coming.
Please listen very
closely to this briefing.
Today we start a very complex
and delicate operation.
This is the largest operation
that MNU has ever undertaken,
and we believe that it is going
to be undertaken successfully.
It is to move 1.8 million prawns
from their present home in District
9 to a safer and better location
200 kilometers outside
of Johannesburg City.
We built a nice new facility
where the prawn can go,
he can be comfortable,
he can stay there...
The people of Johannesburg and
of South Africa are going to live
happily and safely, knowing
that that prawn is very far away.
UIO protocol dictates
that we give the aliens
24 hours notice of our right to evict.
Today, you will serve these notices
getting the aliens to sign I-27 form.
The legality that MNU is using to
evict the aliens is simply a whitewash.
I'm going to appoint a field
officer to take direct command.
Wikus Van De Merwe.
Everybody always said that
Wikus was not a very smart boy,
but he was a wonderful son.
That was my Wikus, just...
Feels like life on the big
stage. Thank you Piet... Mr Smith.
l had to put aside the fact that
my daughter was married to Wikus.
That didn't affect my
decision to promote him.
It's almost as big as my wedding
day. You know... not as big.
Wikus was always making me things.
He said that way they
just mean so much more.
He left this paper-mache
bowl on the sofa one day
and I didn't see it and I sat
down, and I... kinda squashed it.
They took all his stuff away
for the investigation, and...
I made them bring it all back.
Hey, congratulations,
man! -Thanks, man.
Okay, you're gonna go to P7.
- Wikus! -How is it going, man?
Here's the shake. P9 for you. -Thanks.
I'm not saying what he
did was right, but...
he took the choices
that were given to him.
This is Trent. Fundiswa, Trent. -Hi.
Fundiswa is the guy that
I've selected to replace me.
If he can make it
today, eh? -I'll make it.
I just want everyone
watching this right now
to learn from what has
happened. -You would think...
things like this would happen
to somebody else, not to me.
How is it going, man? Long time,
mate. Have you got my stuff?
Hey, boss! -How is it
going? -I'm all right, boss.
Good, good, this is Fundiswa.
He is training with us today.
I think I was disgusted
with the way he worked.
There was always just a hint
of something not quite kosher
with mr Van De Merwe.
- Nobody saw it coming at all.
None of us had any idea
of what he was doing.
l think it is a great
thing to see that...
it's not the military
guys in charge this time.
Not to say that Koobus and
his cowboys are not wanted.
You guys are always wanted.
You see now, these are the cowboys.
They shoot first, and then
they answer the questions.
Sorry, is this above the
allocated amount of ammunition?
Because I see your
pouches are full but...
I think maybe you should
speak to the colonel.
F.A.G. over here says that
we got too much ammunition.
No, all I'm saying,
Koobus, is that, you know...
you should find ways of making
you guys more efficient...
Listen to me, you fuck!
Get him outta my face.
There are rules, we're all
living by rules in this world.
Well, l don't think he can
be forgiven for what he did,
cause it's like a betrayal.
- I've gotta get going, Les.
I think we're gonna have to cut this
interview, cause we're gonna go...
12 KILOMETERS FROM DISTRICT 9
Take your magazines,
people. Come on, lets go.
The Prawn doesn't really understand
the concept of ownership of property.
So, we have to come there and
say: listen, this is our land.
Please, will you go?
It's difficult to put
the vest on by yourself.
Thomas, can you help
me? -All right, boss.
They told me I was gonna get
the vest inside the Casper.
Thomas, just look on the
side if there's a vest there?
I'm just concerned about my family.
- Don't worry about the vest, it'll be fine.
Rights groups have demanded
that mercenaries should comply
with all UYO regulations in District 9.
We're coming to you from
the entrance of District 9
as today, Multi National
United sets out to relocate
approximately 1.8 million alien
residents from their homes.
Human rights groups are
keeping a watchful eye,
as many suspect abuses might occur.
We're seeing heavily armed
private security forces
being deployed into District 9.
Backed up by significant air support.
We'll go shack to shack and
get them to sign the form.
First one EX 247.
We're seeing the convoy stop.
The operation is about to begin.
Just stay focused.
Are you ready,
Thomas? -Yeah. -Okay.
Is that a signal? Okay, fellows.
You stay behind us. Good luck, boy.
Stay low! Where is he going? What is it?
It's clear that security is very high.
This is only the beginning
of a total clamp down.
This is MNU agents. Open
the door please! -Open up!
Hello! Hello, hello...
This is Wikus Van De Merwe from MNU.
We are here to serve
you an eviction notice.
You just put your
scrawl there. -Fuck off!
All right! Thomas, hold it!
We've got his scrawl there.
Because as he hit it,
it counts as a scrawl.
First time we come in, there
will always be a little bit
of tension happening
between us and them.
Hey, you can't eat that, man!
The prawn likes to eat the rubber.
To him it's like a marshmallow.
No, no! Guard! Don't
confront him like that!
Did you see that? Right
in the roost. Stay calm!
This is gonna be a problem cause
now all prawns are coming out,
they wanna see what's
going on. Stop it! Stop it!
Bring my kit. See,
everybody is gathering now.
Don't shoot or you're gonna
turn it into a warzone!
What is that? Is that a
tear gas? -No, it's cat food.
It is cat food. I just distract them.
One of them attacked the
prawn and he's lost his arm.
No it's not my house. I don't live here.
Well, that's a pity
because, you know, this...
This is a nice cat food, you know.
But of course, it's not your house.
So, we'll just have to go and give it
to someone else. -Yes! It's my house!
We need you to sign here.
Now you can take that...
All right. Stop it!
The creatures became incredibly
obsessed with cat food.
Something about it, like catnip
for cats. Only a lot more intense.
Hello? MNU. We are here
to serve eviction notices.
What is eviction?
What we have stranded
on Earth in this colony,
is basically the workers that are
unable to think for themselves.
They will take commands,
they have no initiative.
They've lost all the apt of leadership
through whatever cause.
We presume illness.
I'm holding steady over
Nigerian compound area.
Where there's a slum, there's crime.
And District 9 was no exception.
The nigerians had various scams going.
One of them was the cat food scam.
Where they sold cat food to the
aliens for exorbitant prices.
You put the money here first. You
don't get anything until you pay.
What are you trying to do?
I'll chop your balls off.
Not to mention
interspecies prostitution,
and they also dealt in alien weaponry.
You have a car hijacking,
there's a chop shop there,
you can see that, that's
somebody's car in there.
The nigerians in District 9 are
headed by a man called Obesandjo.
He's a very powerful underground
figure in Johannesburg.
You don't want to play with these boys.
They will cut you into pieces.
That's the boss there. OK, no problem.
Don't look at him! This
is gonna cause problems.
All right, next. 766, all right.
MNU agents. Open the door please!
Whoa! Jesus! What is it?
Check the other side!
Control, this is Wikus Van De Merwe.
I need a population control team
at JV 766 immediately, please.
Check the other side, Thomas!
There is 40 to 50 eggs in here.
Is this normal? -This
is an amazing find.
l can just show you a
little bit how it works.
Basically, a cow is hung from
the ceiling, you can see here.
Very little of it left, of
course, because all these pipes
supply the nutrition to
the little prawn eggs.
You can do one, I can show
you, want to see? -No, I'm fine.
There we go. Okay, no
more nutrition to the guy.
Then finally we take air back.
The little guy is gone to
a nice little sleep now.
You pop him out, there
we go. Pop him out here.
You can take that. You wanna keep it
as a souvenir of your first abortion.
You can feel like you did one
of these here. -Thanks, boss.
Okay, here it comes,
guys. This is the snake.
If we were going to abort
each egg one at the time,
it'd take a very long time.
So, this makes a lot of sense.
You hear that? That's a popping
sound that you're hearing.
It's almost like a popcorn.
What the egg does, it pops up.
The little guy, what's
left of him, pops out there.
So that's the sound that
you're hearing with the popping.
You don't need that, man.
Only sissies wear that.
Been drinking a little bit here, eh?
What are you doing with this
television set, sir? What's this?
Hey, smile for the cameras here.
That's a first day
find. -That's a big find.
You see this? Trent, look at this!
There's weapons all over here.
CK 5, 7572...
Some of the guns are small
but if it shoot you, it make a big mess.
MNU is trying to move the
aliens for humanitarian reasons.
But the real focus, just as it has been
right from the beginning, is weapons.
MNU is the second largest
weapons manufacturer in the world.
We assumed that we'd be able
to pick up the alien laser gun
and just be able to shoot,
but it didn't work like that.
Because, as we discovered,
their technology is actually
engineered in a biological manner to
interact exclusively with their DNA.
It just doesn't work with humans.
And it's as simple as that.
This is basically a guy,
and there's 3 humans here.
Basically trying to
make a warning, you know.
He's saying "I kill 3
humans, watch out for me."
Hey, don't urinate on your own
bloody... get back, get back.
This is Wikus, requesting
First Battalion escort, please.
You want to talk to them
or you want to talk to me?
No, not them!
Okay, guys, thanks very much.
Yeah I know, he had a spade.
Look-I find some!
I tell you before... this is
human technology, it is useless.
Only our technology contains the fluid.
This is not our
technology? -No, it's junk.
Keep looking.
I find something.
Yes. This is what we need.
Good, little one.
Get down!
Careful... wait...
...there.
Why must it take so long?
Because it is very difficult...
...so much can go wrong.
Twenty years of work.
Our plan is ready now?
- Quiet... listen...
...they are coming.
You must hide this.
They must not find it.
Answer the door and be polite.
No! You take it.
You see, this is the problem.
This is the gang sign.
You see this? So again,
looks like we have
more and more gang members.
Fundiswa, you just stay
back. You stay behind Thomas.
This place is swarming with
MNU. I will be searched.
I must get back to my son.
Don't make them angry - be polite!
MNU agents, open the door please.
Hello? We would like you
to... -Nobody is here.
Okay, that's unexceptable.
That is totally unexceptable!
Get out! Get out! You stupid prawn!
- Get outside!
- C'mon! Move! Move!
On your knees! -I'm gonna have a look.
Just stay there! Right there!
Sir, we have to serve
you an eviction notice.
Do you understand it? -No.
This is a classic kind of
gangsta shack, I can tell you.
We're gonna find weapons here.
Watch your head, don't hit the cows.
Just checking for
panels. Ah, you hear that?
Yeah, it's hollow there.
See? Look at that!
I haven't see this type of
setup. It's almost like a...
chemistry type of a set.
It's gotta be something.
l don't know, this has got
the markings there of...
...so it is definitely alien.
But it's not a weapon.
But I don't trust it.
Are you all right?
Wikus, are you all right?
Switch it off, please. Just turn it off.
Are you gonna cut that part
out, Trent, where it sprays me?
- Yeah, don't worry.
- You cut that.
We just found a dangerous object here.
It has a fuel in and I suspect it
might leak onto people or cause damage.
So we just check that in and we
take that down nicely to the lab.
It's not a weapon but it's dangerous.
He's got weapons somewhere here,
my sense is telling me that.
Lets check the other side
here. Thomas! -Yes sir?
Thomas, keep the gun on
him. -OK, I got it sir!
Keep the gun on him,
Thomas, there's weapons here!
Oh, this is Christmas! This
is Christmas, my friends.
This is the biggest
find that I've ever seen.
Control, come in. Wikus Van De Merwe,
requesting First Reaction Battalion.
Stand by, guys!
This gun I've never
seen. Have you seen this?
This is amazing! Look at
this gun. What gun is this?
This is absolutely amazing!
- What are you doing?
- I wanna show this to Thomas.
But I thought you said
you can't handle it.
No, I am not handling it,
I'm just gonna show it.
I'm not gonna use it, man. It
doesn't even work with humans.
Thomas, look at this gun!
- That's not mine.
- You're a dealer, eh? -No.
You hear this, sir? You
see what's happening?
First Battalion, my friend.
You know what that means?
That means that your days of
flaunting the law are over.
Have a look, you see that? What's that?
That's a firing team.
Come here!
Wikus! Are you all right?
Where do you think you're going, eh?
You don't run away from
the chopper. -No, no...
Where do you think you're
going? You wanna piss me off?
Koobus to base, come in!
I've got two people down.
MNU guard, MNU agent.
It's the Foxtrot
Yankee 5-3-0... copy?
And we need a Med Evac ASAP.
No, that's fine, Koobus.
I don't need a Med Evac.
Wikus, you burned your
arm, you need to...
I'll just treat it here, Koobus.
Sir, I really think you must go to
a doctor, a hospital or something.
- No, no.
- You should just get it checked out.
I'll just have it treated
by the medics. Help me up.
Did you see how fast
that prawn was, Trent?
- Yeah, he was fast.
- He was fast, I promise you.
Look, I fix it. I make it work.
I told you not to touch that.
What is wrong?
Nothing. Go outside
and watch for humans.
Where is your friend?
He's gone.
Are you okay? -Yeah,
I'm just a bit hot.
Are you guys hot? Are
you hot, Trent? -No.
Yeah, if you can't stand the
heat get out of the kitchen.
Now you see. There's kids everywhere.
This is what I mean. That's
why we get rid of them.
- The little ones.
- Yeah, that's why we abort.
Lets just shoot the little bastard.
- No, no, don't shoot it now.
MNU agents! Come out!
Hello, little guy.
MNU has sweets for you.
There you go, eat your sweety.
You know, eaty sweety. Works
like a charm every time.
Oh fuck, man!
You almost poked my eye out
with the fokkin' lollypop.
I tried to be fokkin' nice to you, man!
Is this your fokkin' little brat here?
Inside, go! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Teach him some manners.
Thomas, get him out.
Come! Get down! I've had
enough of your stupid games.
What do you want?
We're from MNU. -I know.
We require your scrawl on
this eviction notification.
- Why am I being evicted?
- Yes, it's an eviction notice.
Put your scrawl on the bottom.
See? There's your name at the top.
- Yes! - Christopher Johnson? So, put
your name in the bottom.
It says you must give
me 24 hours notice.
You're going to another place. A nice
new city built especially for prawns.
- A special place! - And we are not
even going to charge you, okay?
This isn't legal. -Sign
the fokkin' paper! -No!
This guy is obviously...
he's a little sharper.
So we are gonna have
to try something else.
All right. Hello... okay.
Seems like we didn't understand
each other there properly, eh?
So, you've got a little one there.
Do you have a licence
for that little one? -Yes.
There's a litter out here. This is
dangerous conditions for your child.
Article 75 says that because
your child is living in dangerous
conditions, I'm gonna take
him down to Child Services.
I'm gonna go and have a
little chat with your son.
You keep away from my child!
Don't point your
fokkin' tentacles at me!
You said you want to stay?
Your boy is coming down
with me to Child Services.
He's gonna spend the rest of
his life in 1 by 1 meter box.
Hello, little guy! It's
the sweety man coming!
Fuck, look at this, Trent! Fuck it!
Thomas, keep the gun on him.
He is definitely a criminal!
He's got a whole
computer shop here, man!
You know, this is amazing.
I mean, this is obviously...
you can see stolen computers now
that he's decorating his place with.
Definitely he doesn't
have the permit for this.
Where is that fokkin' little brat?
Hello! It's the sweety man...
It's the sweety... Hey, I've got this...
- Wikus!
- Trent, turn it off!
Are you okay, boss?
- Fuck off, man! Fuck off!
Shall I leave him? -Just
fuckin' leave him, yeah.
I'll see you tomorrow,
Christopher Johnson.
When dealing with aliens,
try to be polite, but firm.
And always remember that a
smile is cheaper than a bullet.
Are you feeling better?
- What? -How are you feeling?
I'm fine, I'm alright. I'm
just a little bit dizzy.
Can you just pull up there on the side?
I just want to get
something to eat here.
Are you sure you should be having that?
After your whole puking episode?
I feel a lot better... I think I
just needed the fillings, you know.
Boss! Boss!
There's black stuff
coming out of your nose.
Jesus!
It's a silver cylinder. I can't find it.
We must find it. It contains the fluid.
It's not here.
It has to be. Keep looking.
We trade for ten thousand cans.
Certain factions of nigerian gangs
want to try and extract
weaponry from District 9.
And have been trying
to for many many years.
Give them one hundred cans.
- Hundred. -One hundred!
Yes, yes, but we take them all now.
Alright, boys! Get them the catfood
- hurry up.
And they amassed
thousands of these weapons.
Without the ability to use them.
Fuck off! Go! Hey friend,
not you. You stay here.
- What do you want from me?
- I just want to talk.
Talk about what?
Stupid prawn. They'll believe anything.
Muti is a South African word.
Today it's synonymous with
witchdoctory and magic.
You cut it here. This is their heart.
Cures high blood when you boil it,
cures sugar, diabetes, all diseases.
The nigerians were
consuming alien body parts.
They believed that by doing so,
they were ingesting their power
to use alien weaponry.
You must eat them.
And their power will live in you.
Just give me a fucking chance
to go in front of you, man!
Oh, baby! -Hi baby, come in! -I
need to get to the toilet, quickly!
Why? What's the matter?
Baby, listen. I might have
crapped in my pants. -Surprise!
What's this for? -Your promotion.
- All right, my promotion!
Hello, dad. How is it going?
Hi mom. -Good to see you.
What a surprise, man!
- Congratulations. -Thanks.
Congratulations, boss. -Thank you.
- Wikus, what happened?
- I had a small incident, baby.
I'm just gonna go to the toilet,
and then I'll talk to people, okay?
I need to talk to you. Come with
me. -Okay, but I just gotta...
Guys, can you give us a moment, please?
What happened out there?
This prawn wouldn't listen to
me, one really unruly prawn...
and I just had to...
get him in my grasp.
Listen to me, too many
aliens died out there today.
UYO is all over my backside.
Focus! you're not going
to fuck this up for me!
If you can't do the job,
I'll find someone who can!
Hi there! -Nice to see you again.
Does this mean he's in
charge of this new operation?
- Yes.
- That's nice.
Wikus! Baby are you okay?
Okay, let's cut some cake.
Doctor Smith, please come
to room 405, doctor Smith.
Is it badly infected?
- There's a lot of suppuration.
Also you should know on my right hand
some fingernails were coming loose.
And I had a black fluid coming out
of my nose, and sort of a black vomit.
What is happening to my arm, doctor?
What is this thing?
Just breathe deeply.
Calm down. Stay calm.
Sir, please tell my wife.
Attention all medical
containment evacuate ward 11.
Stop right there, madam.
What's going on? What
are you doing to him?
Let me through!
Wikus! Wikus! Where are you taking him?
Okay, got him? Are you ready? -Got him.
We decided not to use the anesthetic,
the reason being we can't know
how the subject will react.
Doctor Fester! -Yes? -I
think you should see this.
I found it in his jacket.
You think this is alien?
Stop, it's freezing! Fuck!
16 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
Where is this?
What?
What are they doing to these prawns?
Pain threshold, test one, DBX 7.
That's a strong pain reaction.
That means the nerves have fused.
I mean, it's almost
completely integrated.
Okay, do it.
B5. Testing AMR-B5.
Clear the range. Now, quickly!
Swing it around.
What are you doing?
- The door is locked.
Can you grip that? -What is this?
- Put it through.
- Why are you doing this?
- Standby for fire. Standby.
- You want me to shoot that?
Stand back... and fire!
That's good!
It worked!
All right, thanks very much.
Do you know where my wife is?
Do you know if my wife
knows where I am, sir?
Pull! Pull!
No sir, I will not pull.
What did you say about
your wife? Fuck your wife!
Pull! -I will not pull.
Fire!
B7. -I can pull it.
- He says he can pull it.
I said I could pull it! You fuckin'...!
B21.
Move, hurry up. Move!
Right, we want him in the center
by the chain. -Get this off me.
Come on! Time, time!
Leave that fucking prawn, man, I
will shoot at pig. I'll shoot, sir!
Listen, I'll shoot at pig again
for you. I'll pull the trigger.
But I'm not shooting at prawn,
you hear me? Untie the fucking gun.
B21 in human hand.
That's good. It worked.
Just untie the gun, sir. -Stand by.
Listen, you can't use the real
guy, he didn't do anything to you.
I want to try this.
Everybody standing by.
Ready to go? Three, two, one, go!
Amazing!
All right! I think that's all we need.
Gentlemen, we are running out of time.
This is the key stage
in the metamorphosis.
His DNA is in perfect balance
between alien and human.
And a problem is, as
the infection spreads,
the transition becomes
permanent and less active.
He's going to turn into
one of them. A prawn!
What happens to him isn't important.
What's important is that we harvest
from him what we can right now.
This body represents
hundreds of millions,
maybe billions of dollars
worth of biotechnology.
There are people out there,
governments, corporations,
who'd kill for this chance.
Will he survive the
procedure? -No, of course not.
We need everything.
Tissue, bone marrow, blood.
The procedure is gonna basically
strip him down to nothing. -Please...
What about next of kin?
Please help me. Don't let them do it.
I'll handle that.
Okay, I say let's go. -Good, thank you.
I don't understand.
None of this makes any sense.
He just hurt his arm, dad.
The doctors are trying, sweetheart.
Doing their best to save him.
We're starting to harvest
material from the specimen.
We'll start with the soft tissue
first. Cut through the chest cavern.
We need to get the heart
out as quickly as possible.
Once it set the
sinuosity, it just spread.
You know Wikus. He
never was very strong.
I'll go through the chest,
go straight into the heart.
Be quiet, please. -Fuck you!
Can I see him?
Not a good idea.
Fuck off! Fuck you!
Fuck you!
Drop the knife!
Move or I'll fuckin' cut his throat!
Okay. All right!
I'll fuckin' kill him!
You need to let go of him now.
It's okay, Tania.
Everything will be okay.
Smith.
When?
Get Koobus.
...Wikus Van De Merwe.
White male, mid thirties. Is
considered highly dangerous.
- Hey baby.
- Wikus, is that you?
- Mrs. Smith?
- How dare you phone us!
What are all these people doing in
my house? -It's none of your business.
I need to speak to Tania straight
away, please. It's my house.
This is my phone that you're
using, mam. I'm fokkin'... what?
He tried calling me.
Anton, it's me! It's
me! Accept the call!
I've been friends with you
for fokkin' 13 years, man!
Fuck off! What are
you watching? Fuck off!
We all thought it was for the
best because he needed help.
A special medical help.
And he wasn't gonna
get that as a fugitive.
He became the most valuable
business artifact on Earth.
He was the only human who had ever...
successfully been combined with
alien genetics and remained alive.
But his real value was that he
could operate alien weaponry.
Hello.
Can I get some cheese burgers
and one large sauerkraut, please.
We interrupt this program
to bring you breaking news.
A patient has escaped from the
isolation ward and is loose in the city.
Wikus Van De Merwe was
recently apprehended
after prolonged sexual activity
with aliens in District 9.
This is nonsense. -I
have to call my manager.
That is totally untrue. You
are legally obliged to serve me!
...is causing bodily disfigurement.
If I could just buy my burger,
please. Don't listen to them!
It's highly contagious
and the police warns people
to stay at least 20
meters away from this man.
Don't look at this
hand! This hand is fine!
If you have any information
regarding the whereabouts
of Mr Van De Merwe, contact us
immediately on 0800-stop-wikus.
Stop!
31 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
Hi, this is Tania. -And Wikus.
We can't come to the phone right now.
Please leave a message. Bye. -Bye bye.
Control, there's no
sign of mr Van De Merwe.
The entire world was watching him.
He was on every radio station,
every image on television,
anything you could
find had his face on it.
So he had nowhere else to go. He
ended up hiding in the one place
he knew no one would
ever come looking for him.
40 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
Pay now,or nothing.
I pay you next week, I promise.
No money - you get nothing. Fucking
prawn, this isn't charity.
Hello, I'd like to
buy some meat, please.
Hey, a man!
Yes, have you got a
hamburger, or a steak roll?
Does it look like a hamburger shop?
Which one do you want? Goat?
Come on, come on, I
don't have the whole day.
Is that a cat food
there? -Yeah, yeah, it is.
I'll have some of that, guys.
Fuck, man!
Hello, hello?
Baby is that you? Tania?
God, please let it be you.
Yes, it's me.
I'm so happy you called me, baby.
Wikus, listen to me. -Okay.
I have something to say to
you, and it's not gonna be easy.
No, no, look... listen baby,
before you say anything...
Your father is working against
me, but he's lying to you.
I did not have sex with one of these...
...fokkin' creatures, man!
I would never have any kind of
pornographic activity
with a fokkin' creature!
They say that you're becoming
one of them. I can't do this...
Baby please, don't give up on me.
Don't give up on me
baby, because I can...
I want to see you again, baby.
I'm gonna fix my arm and
I'm gonna see you again,
and I'm gonna kiss you and
I'm gonna hold you again.
I also want you to hold me again.
Baby?
Hey! Hey man!
Okay...
We are on tracking
directly to the location.
Roger that. I'll send you a
couple of choppers for backup.
You!
What do you want?
Come in, control, there
is our target moving to 66.
- You have to go.
- Please, I need your help.
We're gonna play hide and
seek. -Yes! Yes! -No, get back.
You want me to hide? Show me
your favorite hiding place.
Please, just go. Leave us alone.
No, please, I need to hide.
They wanna kill me.
I just need to hide in here,
sir, for 5 minutes, okay?
What is this? What are you doing here?
I remember you. -Nothing.
You must hide somewhere else.
Sir... please sir, you have to help me.
I'm losing blood,
they're trying to kill me.
Only one thing that
could make that happen...
Quick! We have to hide him.
Now you... get down there.
Where's the fluid?
What did you do with it?
- Please!
- You took it...
I don't know what you're talking about!
...I know you did. I can
see what's happening to you.
Tell me where it is.
Alright, alright.
Was it a black fluid
in a flask container?
Yes, that's it. Yes!
I confiscated it and the
guys at the lab took it.
It will be at the MNU. MNU has it.
What is this?
- You ruined everything.
- Where is this?
Is that your shack?
This whole thing is under your shack?
For 20 years you've... had
this fokking' thing in here?
Jesus, this is very illegal.
I mean, this is a find, you know.
I wish they catch you with this.
Fuel goes in here.
That's enough! Quiet!
Then we fly away.
I said quiet! We cannot trust him.
What is he saying about the fuel?
Are you trying to start this thing?
Are you little fuckers trying
to start this and get away?
Never mind.
Yeah, you sneaky fokkin' prawns.
Too bad. I could've fixed you.
What? What did you
say... about the fixing?
What do you mean you could fix me?
Forget it. It doesn't
matter, it's too late.
No, listen! Listen. Are
you saying that you can...
turn this prawn hand into a human hand?
You can make me human again?
We have medical machines on the
mothership that can fix you. Yes.
We can use this ship to fly up there.
That's fantastic! You
guys are brilliant!
I always thought that prawns
were intelligent. Let's do it.
I don't have fluid.
I could fix you and I could fly
away. But I don't have fluid.
Right, okay.
All right, I tell you
what. Why don't we...
go risk it some more?
Let's go collect some up.
It took twenty years
to collect that amount.
Fuck, man! Fuck!
Fuck! The only one that exists
is the one I confiscated?
Yes.
It's four stories underground.
Why does he keep looking at
me like that? -He likes you.
We are the same.
We're not the same. We're
not the fokkin' same.
There is a way out of this.
We get the fluid back from MNU.
Yeah, and what then?
Then we both die, eh?
Both of us dead. That's
a suicide mission, man.
Can you not fill my head
with that sort of nonsense?
The transformation is accelerating.
You don't have much time.
56 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Hello.
- Wikus?
- Tania! Baby...
- Are you okay?
- Oh God! Thank God...
Where are you?
I'am...
It's not like my father said. I
know he was lying to protect me.
I just don't know what
to believe anymore.
Baby I know, but listen to me.
It's all lies, I swear to you.
Everything he said to you is lies.
- I know.
- What? What?
I believe you, Wikus.
I just want you back.
I want everything back the way it was.
That's... baby, that's what I want.
That's great! That's great news.
I can make it the way it
was. If you take me back.
How? How can we go back?
I have a plan. I know how to fix it.
I know how to fix myself.
And it will be me. And
we'll be back together.
- You promise me?
- I promise you, baby.
Don't give up on me, okay?
Because I haven't given
up on you. All right?
I won't.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Tell me you got a fix on him. -D9.
How many moons does our planet have?
Seven.
This planet only has one.
I can't wait to see our planet.
It's bigger than this one, isn't it?
Enough.
We go home now?
Not home. No.
This is where we must go.
See that tent there? That might be ours.
I want to go home!
We can't go home. Not anymore.
Hi, you don't wanna go to the
tents, they are not better.
They're smaller than the shacks.
Actually, more like
a concentration camp.
If I can get you that black
fluid, what happens then?
We go up to the mothership.
And you can start that thing? -Yes.
Okay, so just to be clear:
this is gonna go back...
This is gonna go back
to human like this.
I can go home and then you can go home.
You can take your boy, you
can take all the prawns,
if I can get you that fluid, right?
You said it was a suicide
mission. Maybe you were right.
We have no weapons.
They'll shoot us on sight.
Look, look... Christopher...
I know where we can get weapons.
Hi guys. Hello.
I would like to buy
some weapons, please.
How did you do this like that?
A doggie style with the demon.
I love it!
One brave white man, eh?
Were you wearing a condom?
I need to buy weapons, please.
You and I both know that there
are illegal weapons inside here.
I have money and I would
like to buy some of those...
Sit!
Thank you sir for your time.
Thank you very much for seeing me.
I would like to buy some weapons.
AK-47, some grenades...
maybe tear gas canisters.
I see you have limpet
mines here aswell, and I..
also see you guys have alien
weapons there, which is great!
If I could have one or two of those.
I have money, okay? Now, I'm...
Sir! Please, sir!
I've heard about you.
Where do you have it? Show me!
Oh, shit!
Come here. Come.
No, no... don't please!
Why are you doing
this? What do you want?
Shut up!
Forget the weapons! Forget the weapons!
I want the arm. Cut it off.
What is he saying?
I'll show you.
Holy shit!
You tell them to stand down!
You tell them to be quiet! To back off!
Tell them to put the
fokkin' weapons in the bag!
Give me the fokkin' weapons, man!
Don't you, sir, look at me.
I said don't fokkin' look at me!
How did you get that hand?
Fokkin' hurry up there!
Look at me when I fuckin' speak
to you. What is your secret?
What did you do? Tell me!
I want that fuckin' arm.
What the fuck did you do?
You fuckin' mazungo, I'm coming for you!
I'm coming for you
and I'm gonna get you!
Drop your fokkin' knife.
Drop your fokkin' knife!
He's useless to us
dead. -Would you relax?
For fuck's sakes, my men have
done this a hundred times before.
Maintaining a visual on the location.
It's gonna be quick.
It's gonna be clean.
Best of all, it's gonna be quiet.
Van De Merwe hasn't got a
clue what's coming his way.
It's empty! -Where are they?
Target is gone. The place is empty.
What do you mean, empty?
Where the fuck is he?
That little shithead has got
no idea what is coming his way.
I'm gonna find him.
There are the guards! At the gate!
Watch the guards at the gate, man!
Move! Get out!
They're going down. Four stories down.
This is alien weaponry.
Give me a status report.
It's Van De Merwe. He's on level four.
Switch to live, and then
we're taking him out.
Colonel, we weren't allowed
to use live ammunition.
They want him alive.
Stay here until I call
you. -I understand.
I need to get the door open.
No! I said stay until I call you!
Fuck!
I thought you said not to kill them?
He shot at me!
Fuck! Get out! Don't fuckin' look at me!
Get out! Get the fuck out!
Get out! Everybody get the fuck out!
Get out! Go!
Move the fuck out! Go!
What is this place?
- Don't worry about that.
What do they do in here?
Check these boxes.
Any type of a box that looks like it
can hold a tube. Just check it out!
These fuckers!
Go, go, go...
Clear.
I got it! I got it!
Chris, I got it. Let's go!
Christopher!
Oh, fuck!
Listen... I promise you, I
didn't know they were doing this.
Until they brought
me here the other day,
I swear to you I did not know
they were doing this to you guys.
But Christopher... look
at me. Listen to me.
We need to leave now. Okay?
The whole of MNU is
gonna come down here.
He's going to destroy us.
We can do this, okay? We're
gonna get out of here...
Fire!
Move, move!
Shoot at the prawn!
Christopher! What the
fuck are you doing?
Think of your boy, for fuck sake!
What the hell are you doing?
Are you out of your fuckin' mind?
You're gonna get us
killed! -What do we do now?
I thought you had a way out?
I didn't say anything about the way out.
I promised you that we'll get
in. We're in! -I have an idea.
- Where are you going?
- Follow me!
What are you doing? -Making a bomb.
Let's go!
Quick! Get in!
Go! Drive!
Okay!
Okay, hold on!
Fuck!
Reports are coming in of
explosion in downtown Johannesburg.
Well, there was a terrorist attack,
but I can assure you that we
dealt with it. Everything is fine.
Droop it down! Droop it down! Decline!
They are really close to us now!
Shit!
Let's go, let's go!
Don't drop that fokkin' thing!
Come on, move! Get down there!
Go down and initiate
the binary commands.
Set it down right now!
When we get up to the mothership,
how long is this gonna take?
- To do what?
- The fixing. To fix me.
It's going to take a bit
longer than I thought.
Okay, that's fine. How long do you need?
Three years.
Sorry, just go slowly
with the clicks there,
it sounded like you said
"three years", like human years.
Yes. Three years.
What? Three fuckin' years?
I will fix you,
but first I must save my people.
The deal was: you go home, I get fixed!
I will not let my people
be medical experiments!
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment!
You hear me, Christopher?
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment, man!
I must go home and get help.
I must use all the
fluid to travel quickly.
I'll just stay here, Christopher?
I'll just stay here in this shack.
And I'll see you in three years
time? -I will come back. I promise.
Christopher!
Where the fuck is he?
Hey, you're hiding
Wikus down there, my boy?
- Father?
- No, no, no.
Your daddy needs to stay here to
sort out a few things, alright?
We're gonna go. We're gonna
come back and fetch him, okay?
In here? -In there.
- Goes in here?
How the fuck do you open this, prawn?
Father.
Show me, you fucker. You
want me to fuckin' kill you?
Is that what you fuckin' want, eh?
Right... there's no buttons.
On!
Activate?
My teachers teach only:
One prawn, one bullet.
I can't believe I get paid to do this.
I love watching you prawns die.
Fuck, man!
Father!
Get out! Get out!
This is remarkable.
It looks like something is
emerging from the ground.
Something is definitely
coming out of the ground.
Okay... steady!
Go sit down, I can't play with ya now.
Uncle Wikus is flying.
Bug off. Bug off!
Lock the weapon at target!
Fire when locked.
It seems to be drifting towards
the center of the territory.
We have a lock on him. -Fire!
Something is fired
upon... it has been hit!
What the fuck is that?
One of the engines is billowing
smoke, it's out of control.
It's going down, boss. Should
I send the boys to fuck him up?
Now... it hit the ground,
the massive impact,
and it's come to a standstill.
My son! My son's in there!
Shut the fuck up! Get
this fucker inside.
We're moving out. Come,
let's go, let's go...
Move!
We're banking around now, trying
to get a better view of the ship
which is absolutely wrecked, waiting
for some of the smoke to clear.
Somebody has been brought
out of the vehicle.
It looks like a human being.
We are getting unconfirmed
reports that this might be
Wikus Van De Merwe, a fugitive
that has been on the run
from MNU for the past 3 days.
They are loading him into a
vehicle now, and heading off.
72 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
What the fuck?
We caught him, boss. -Bring him to me.
Come on! Get back!
Oh, fuck!
Control, we're taking enemy fire!
We need support. Backup, now!
Fuck off! Fuck off, man!
Get you hands off me!
Fuckin' get off me!
Get your fuckin' hands off me!
Didn't I tell you...
that I'm gonna get you?
You came in here and you left
with something that belongs to me.
Fuck you.
Fuck you all!
I told you that the day will come.
You've been running
around with my prize.
All I want is to eat that
hand and become like you.
No! It won't work...
Once I have that power,
no one will stop me.
It was your turn... now it's mine!
Fighting MNU security forces,
this armed faction is doomed...
Now I'm gonna eat, my friend.
We're getting reports claiming that
the alien device is activating...
You see that prawn back
in the Casper? -Yeah.
He knows what the fuck
is up with that ship.
Get that fucker out and
get him talking, now.
Three contractors are closing in
on the nigerian compound, and...
Come, alien!
What's your plan?
How are you doing it?
Who's moving that ship?
All right, that's very clever.
Wait for my command. Make
sure you fuckin' shoot to kill.
Fuck! Move it! Move it!
Bring that fucker down!
Hold you fire! Hold your
fire and keep your positions!
It's Van De Merwe.
Hey, Dickus!
I'll come back for prawn, alright guys?
Do you hear me, now? -Run, Wikus!
- You hear me?
- Run!
And keep on running, you fuckin' coward!
Run! Run!
Get the air support up, and
get on his fuckin' trail, now!
It's not gonna work,
boss. He's a tough one.
He's not gonna talk. -Then
just fuckin' kill him.
Fuck!
He's a tough one. He's not gonna talk.
Then just fuckin' kill him.
Hey, c'mon. Get up! I'm
gonna get you out of here.
- I can't... it's too far.
- It's not too fokkin' far. Get up!
I'm gonna get you there. I'm
gonna get you to your boy!
C'mon, stay behind me!
Go back!
Run, run, run!
Arriving at the location now.
We have a clearance to engage.
Prawns are coming, get down, get down!
There are headed for a drop
site. Knock these fuckers off!
Come to mommy, come...
Fuck!
Shit!
Are you hurt?
We can make it. I was shot in the arm.
We can make it, come on!
Listen, you go ahead. You can make it.
I'm gonna just... hold them off
here, and I'll join you soon.
No, we stick together.
I'm not leaving you here.
Take your boy and go
home. You have to make it.
Don't make me go through
all of this and not make it.
Do you understand? -I
will come back for you.
Go! Go now before I change my mind! Go!
Three years. I promise.
I'm not fuckin' scared of you!
Quit fuckin' with me!
You want me? You want me?
Is that all you got?
Is that all you fuckin' got?
Some kind of quite extraordinary
light from the mothership.
I've never seen anything like
it. It's a beam of light...
Full scan. Okay.
Fire!
Get to the vehicle, now! Get
going. -Yes colonel. -Go, go, go!
Fuck!
Quit playing with me, Koobus!
You fucker!
Go, Chris, go.
Go home.
We go home now?
Yes.
74 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
Unbelievable.
Now I know why everybody
wants a piece of you.
I can't wait for those
med boys to cut you up.
But you know what?
You're not gonna waste
any more of my time.
You half-breed piece of shit!
I'm gonna just fuckin' kill you myself.
Stay back, you fuck! Stay back!
Stay back!
The people everywhere
across Johannesburg
are flooding the streets and
pouring out of their offices
and all eyes are pointed up towards
the sky on this momentous day.
It's the first time, ladies and
gentlemen, in over two decades,
that the mothership has
shown any sign of movement,
and people are tremendously excited.
The city had come to
an absolute standstill.
Everybody wants to know
what's going to happen next.
There's no way of knowing whether or
not Christopher Johnson will return.
We don't know if he was simply escaping,
whether he will effect a rescue plan...
...and, as the so
called free press says,
whether or not he will come
back and declare a war on us.
This is the last known
footage of Wikus Van De Merwe.
And we can only speculate as
to what has happened to him.
The more zany conspiracy
theories state that
he's been captured by MNU
or by another government.
Or by perhaps some
shady government agency
and he's actually
being held in captivity.
If we knew where he was,
we would try and help him,
and that is the most difficult
part, not knowing where he is.
Wikus, sadly, is gone but
I'm the one who stays behind
with all the questions.
I can't give the answers.
He died in my mind a long
time ago. And that's that.
Wikus Van Der Merwe is a name
that will become very widely known
because of this pivotal role that
he played in this whole event.
He was an honest man, and he didn't
deserve any of what happened to him.
I mean, I know. I looked into a
computer system and I found stuff.
I mean, the whole data
was there, you know?
They didn't even do a
good job of hiding it.
Fundiswa Mhlanga is
currently awaiting trial
for exposing MNU's illegal
genetic research program.
District 9 was demolished
after the alien resettlement
operation was completed.
District 10 now houses 2.5 million
aliens and continues to grow...
You guys haven't seen a picture of
my wife. Let me show you my wife.
She's my special angel.
She even looks like an angel
with veil, you want to see that?
Look, you see, with the
white veil over the...
she even looks like an angel.
Everyone says that his wife is angel,
but this is a real angel that
you see there, on the cameras.
They won't put that in
the video, I don't think.
I found this at my front door.
As tho somebody had just left it there.
My friends say that I
should throw it away,
cause it's just a piece of rubbish.
That it couldn't possibly come from him.
I know it's true.