in memory of...
...my grandfather, Nazmi Erdoan
and my brother, Grdal Tosun...
1974 - A small town
in southeastern Turkey
Emin! Emin!
Yeah, what?
Cut it out!
lso, Veysi, you bastards.
Just wait till l catch you!
Stop it!
lf l fucking catch you...!
Sons of bitches!
l'll show you!
Damn!
Missed it again!
lsn't it a bit too close for comfort?
Closeness inspires love,
which leads to Art.
How many girls have you
tried that line on?
Search for the answer
in my eyes.
-What a fucking stupid movie!
-Don't flip out on me!
-lt's bullshit!
-So don't watch it, idiot!
How am l supposed to know it's
bullshit without watching it? ldiot!
Keep it down!
Shut your faces and sit down!
Hello! What a coincidence!
You again.
Well, it's a public beach after all!
l'll tell that lady you stole her car.
That's enough out of you!
Go find yourself another beach!
You've utterly ruined me!
What's the big deal?
Don't cry mother.
l'll do my duty and come back.
The movie made me cry.
What's the matter?
Nothing, just hiccups.
Mother, please don't cry.
l've just been called up, that's all.
Mother, we all did it.
And l served 28 months.
Why so long?
Never mind.
lt's a bit complicated.
Weren't you caught with a woman?
Some broad?
That's no way to talk about
a married woman.
She was married, too?
-Why'd you say she was married?
l didn't. You did!
Cut it out.
Watch the movie! You too.
Mother!
l told you, it's the movie.
What's there to cry about?
They won't live happily ever after.
lt's all over,
and we're together again.
Till death do us part.
lt's these false teeth, Mayor.
Food keeps getting stuck
under them.
You've gotten old, Casim.
We'll be eating helva next year
after your funeral service.
Why me?
Maybe you'll die pimp.
l still have my own teeth, codger!
Pimp!
But there's only a couple of months
between you.
No way! Old Casim was friends
with my late uncle.
Fuck off!
He's been dead for ten years!
See? You've got one foot
in the grave!
You're like a fossil, Casim.
We'll put you in the museum
if we get one.
No hard feelings. l was just
joking along with the others.
Rifat.
lf you've finished eating,
go say goodbye to your friends.
Yes, sir.
Stay away
from their mothers, though.
Don't worry, dad.
So, Rifat's doing his
military service too.
Time sure flies. l was a private in
lzmir and...
...there was this officer who...
Well, dear old Casim.
lzmir was part of the Ottoman
Empire then, wasn't it?
Empire?
Turkey wasn't even
a republic back then!
Asiye!
Hey, Asiye!
Rifat. What are you doing?
Shhh.
Mother's photo!
Go! Quick!
l'm going away.
l know.
You'll wait for me, won't you?
l'll wait.
What should l get you from Ankara?
What do you know about gifts?
Some men even write poetry.
All you do is chase after a ball.
l don't chase after a ball. l'll be
a football player one day. God willing.
Don't start that again.
What's that?
My scab's inside it.
Scab?
Remember how l fell and skinned
my knee when we first met?
l saved the scab
because it was our wound.
l know it's silly, but...
l thought it'd be better than
giving you a picture.
You might get bored of it.
But a scab
is like a piece of my flesh.
lt'll give you a pang
every time you look at it.
ls heart-of-stone Asiye crying?
Why would l cry?
l thing a scab's a silly gift
for a girlfriend, too.
Mom's probably looking for me.
-l'll write the minute l get there.
-Fine.
-What do you mean, fine?
-You know. Fine.
Give me a kiss.
You know, l'm off to the army.
Not like that.
On the lips, like in the movies.
No way.
l won't leave until you do.
Don't then.
Don't eat the food over there.
l won't, mom.
lf she could, she wouldn't let go of
him until he was discharged.
Siti, the bus is leaving!
Don't eat just anything.
You've got a sensitive stomach.
Have someone else try the food
first. Then eat it.
All right, mom.
May God be with you.
Look.
What do you think?
That's what l got up to in Ankara.
The last time l went to the nightclub
the owner said ''Welcome, Fikri''.
Turns out he'd seen my name
on my lD bracelet.
l asked where Feri was.
l've got a babe there. l call her Feri
cause she looks like the actress.
Her real name is Gulsen,
but her friends call her Munevver.
And when we're alone
l call her ''lambchop''.
She's such a sweetie.
Hello, Engin.
Hi, Emin.
l brought your radio.
Does it work now?
What do you mean? Has any radio
escaped my healing hands?
-What kind of answer is that?
-What kind of question was that?
How much do l owe you?
Don't worry about it till later.
ls that scumbag there in the shop?
Where in Ankara is this nightclub?
ln Ulus. Over by that statue.
You should see all the lights and
glitter. Real classy joint...
What do you want, psycho?
l want my money.
What money?
Didn't l fix your radio last year?
And didn't you tell me
to come back later?
-Now fork it over!
-Think you can bully me, dickhead?
-Watch your mouth, Fikri!
-What are you talking about?
Get out of here, fuck-face!
Fikri, what do you want
from the poor orphan?
The bastard's cursing at me.
You started it! l fixed your radio.
Now pay up, faggot!
Who're you calling faggot, pimp!
Pimp yourself, you son of a bitch.
Stop it. That's enough.
Go on, get out of here, Emin.
Maniac...
See you later, Fikri.
Damn! My arm!
Here's a list. Wires, spools and stuff.
Make sure you don't forget anything.
This is no time for joking around.
l feel awful. l'm getting out of here.
''The Gangsters'', showing tonight
at the Lale Cinema.
Welcome, Mr. Mayor.
-Give me your blessings, father.
-Bless you, my son.
Goodbye.
The soldiers are leaving
on the bus.
Our Rifat's on it, too.
They've called up
all the young ones this time.
Why did they take so many
this time around?
You've got the wrong idea
about me. Really.
Try that number on some other girl.
When l'm in love, l feel it here.
And when l do
there are no lies, no tricks.
l feel it with my heart and soul.
That bastard's been showing
the same movie all week.
Cool!
l wish it was an action movie.
Maybe there'll be
some kissing action.
Shut up, you pervert.
That girl sleeps day and night.
Wake up and have some melon.
-Huh?
-Want some melon rinds?
No thanks, mother.
l adore you, l entreat you...
Are you all right? Don't cry sonny.
Get down you little devils!
Are they up on the roof again?
Movies make you forget everything.
Didn't l tell you the kids
shouldn't climb trees at night?
-What happened, dad?
-A lot of crap, that's what!
All right. l'll have some now.
And didn't l say no one could
watch Latif's movies?
We don't go there.
We watch from here.
You may as well have gone on in!
Hey, little devils, have some melon.
Hello.
Come in, Seyhmus.
l noticed you didn't get your melon
tonight, Mayor. This one's on me.
Thanks. They've already bought one.
Oh, really?
Keep this one for tomorrow, then.
Must have bought it from my boy.
Good night!
Where'd you get this?
Do we have to answer
for everything we do?
So you stole it, then?
ls the Mayor's family
a pack of thieves?
lf l stole it was for the child.
l'll be the laughing stock
of the town!
Those you look down on
are people of honor.
Go home! The film's over!
l'm leaving,
but only to return one day.
How's it going, lso, Veysi?
Good night.
You electrocuted me!
What's 'n your hand?
Teasing me'll get you
the shock of your life.
All that kissing
and stuff is phony.
Watch what l'm
gonna do to Crazy Emin.
Crazy Emin!
Cut it out, you bastard!
Maniac!
So your boy's in the army.
lt's no big deal.
He's so young. l wish it'd been
Ahmet, not Rifat. He's so helpless.
l wish they'd take Ahmet forever.
l wish l didn't have a son like him.
Rifat was my father's favorite.
He said Rifat would grow up to be
a village head like him.
He said ''Just like me.''
Nazmi, is Ankara so very far?
Why do you put this flowerpot here?
lt's right in the middle of the road.
Of course l'll bump into it.
ls there another way in?
Stop! l heard something.
Never mind. We're busy.
Slow down. Wait for me!
Cool!
Why do stars shoot?
l asked that once. lt's so crowded
up there that some fall to earth.
Who'd you ask?
A friend.
Why're you farting, you pansy!
We're outside.
What's the big deal?
lt stinks just as much.
Don't cry my boy.
So are you little pests
sleeping up on the roof?
What's so funny?
Don't cry, honey.
Gule! Nafiz!
Go tell your father
to get the bonesetter.
-The poor thing broke his foot.
-OK, mom.
Don't forget to
put on your underwear.
How did you know?
Come on. Get going.
What's all the racket about?
-Ylmaz broke his foot.
-Which Ylmaz?
Remember your son?!
What an idiot!
Get out of my way.
You'd think l broke his foot.
Get up, Gule
and make me breakfast!
Esteemed citizens...
...a surfeit of sand in the
municipal mains...
..may lead to certain unavoidable
obstruction of services.
Thank you for your
restraint and patience.
What's he talking about?
Water isn't running because the pipes
are filled with sand.
What would life be without
your entertaining announcements.
What a great mayor we have.
Water running through the streets...
...but not through the pipes.
What a great job!
lt's not the Mayor's fault.
lt's that bastard contractor.
Watch your mouth!
Fikri's my cousin.
Well, l'm related to the Mayor.
Did l call the Mayor a bastard?
You can't, because he isn't one.
And is Fikri a bastard?
lf he weren't your cousin, he'd be
the biggest bastard around.
Now you're talking.
What's so funny?
Fikri, you haven't done any work.
How can you ask for money?
We all know that contractors
occasionally get down to work.
You don't like the work
but you like the money.
You and your team grab all contracts,
but do nothing.
Mr. Mayor, those words
of yours sure sting.
Can words sting an ox!
What are insults to oxen?
Why couldn't you
lay a pipe in five years?
We never get advances in time.
You waste them carousing around
with women.
lf l've spent so much as a penny
on a woman, l'm no man.
We all know you're no man.
Mayor, you're addressing the
grandson of Village Head Bedri!
Bedri was a muledriver.
So you can't love animals
and be village head?
The late, great lover of mules.
You're wasting my time. Get out!
At least give me my advance.
Fikri!
Don't expect any work
to get done then.
Do you expect my team
to work for free?
Get the money back from your
women and give it to the men, then.
What's this obsession with women?
Have you been paid, Mr. Fikri?
Fat chance! When l campaign
for him, we get along.
When it comes to money, he
starts squirming.
When he needs me it's all praises
for my grandfather,...
...for his wonderful mules.
l need money, not flattery!
Give me a cigarette, Sezgin.
l don't have any.
Come on.
Let's see. Ah!
l thought l'd thrown that pack away.
Must have noticed that only...
one or two were left and made
plans to toss it.
That's how l forgot all about it.
lf l had tossed it,
l'd have forgotten it by now.
You'll have to wait for your kickback,
my friend Sezgin. See you.
Sezgin.
Yes, sir.
You're losing your hair.
lt's just my high forehead.
Mr. Good-looking, huh?
Mind your own business.
-ls my dad in?
-Yeah.
Anyone with him?
Nope.
Sezgin.
What?
Never mind.
Come on, you looked at my head!
You're thinning a bit on top.
Get lost.
Dad, Ylmaz fell off the roof.
What's so funny about that?
Nothing. l was just kidding around
with Sezgin, that's why.
How's Ylmaz?
Mom said he broke his foot.
She wants you
to get the bonesetter.
Okay, you can go.
lf you have an errand for me...
l wouldn't waste one on you.
When do you start work?
Next month, God willing.
God willing.
Mr. Basri, the town administrator,
is here to see you.
-Send him in.
-Yes, sir.
Sezgin, have you heard about
some new shampoo?
No, sir. What is it like?
You rub it on your ass and the hair
there comes out on your head.
Bit wiry, though.
Our Mayor's such a wit.
Welcome, Basri.
Nothing welcome about it.
We're in big trouble!
What happened?
When there's some state job to get
done, they pin it on me.
The governor asked me to oversee
things personally.
Sorry to hear that, Basri.
Anyway, let's have some tea.
l'm sorry too. But for you.
The Governor was so pleased to
hear you'd take charge of it.
Where did he hear that?
l told him.
Great. What is it exactly?
Receiving a delegation
from Ankara.
What delegation?
They're bringing
a vizontele transmitter.
A what?
You know. lt's in all the papers.
So we're finally getting one too?
l knew you'd be thrilled about it.
Good!
Mr. Mayor, what exactly is it?
You know, we've all heard about it.
Radio with pictures.
l'll give you all the help
my official capacity allows me.
What help? lt's your job!
Certainly! Assisting you is my duty!
Goodbye.
Radio with pictures.
Movies in every home.
lt will be the end of Latif.
Attention!
Anyone selling goods on public
property will be in big trouble!
And don't say l didn't warn you first!
Don't cry honey.
lt's dislocated, not broken.
So, he's all right?
Sure. lf he's careful today,
he'll be on his feet tomorrow.
Bless you. Let's bind it.
Many thanks, Saban.
What a great pair of glasses!
They were my father's.
Now they're mine.
-Will your kids wear them after you?
-God willing.
Goodbye.
l caught it! l caught it!
Well, l sliced up the bread!
Musto, Aykut! Let it go!
Let what go?
The bird, of course.
Think l'm an idiot?
Come weed the garden.
What's wrong, Sddk?
lt's my tooth, Mr. Mayor. l'll have
it pulled next month, God willing.
Come here. l'll wash you down.
ls what l heard true?
What did you hear?
Spit it out slowly.
That you're taking a second wife.
Who told you that?
That's not important.
ls it true?
lt's just to help you
with housework.
Help? There's something else
that needs help working...
What do you mean by that?
Damn! There goes another.
You'll ruin me!
Answer me, melon man.
l would, but they won't let me.
Take this melon home.
We'll talk it over tonight.
There's no need for that.
l got my answer!
-Look at that. A perfect melon, too.
-Don't worry. We'll eat it.
Back to work, greedy bastards.
l want it finished by 7:00 this
evening or there'll be...
-...a big crowd at the entrance.
-Finish it by the evening.
Dad, what about my, you know?
l'll take care of it son.
Get in the truck.
Get lost!
''The Gangsters'' is showing tonight!
''The Gangsters'' tonight
at the Lale Cinema.
Turn it down a bit.
So, weeding, are you?
Yeah. Pulling up the bad plants
so the good ones can flourish.
Don't you have any
in your yard?
No.
Right. Yours are in the house.
Some weeds are tough to pull up.
They have deep roots.
So, we pull them out, roots and all.
-l heard something, is it true?
-lf you heard it, it must be false.
l heard vizontele is coming.
Oh, that.
Aren't you happy about it?
No problem. Just checking.
Do you even know what it is?
Sure. l saw one once in lstanbul.
Nothing like the cinema, huh.
Don't get too close.
We don't want any
weeds in our garden.
Let's go, Veli. We'll have a crowd
for the Ylmaz Gney movie tonight.
And keep an eye out for
the rooftop freeloaders.
Nothing like the cinema, huh?
lf he's so worried, this
vizontele must be a good thing.
Stop it. Your mother'll see us.
No, she won't.
Nafiz!
Coming mom.
-What is it?
-Make a phone call for me.
There's no point. They won't
be able to connect us.
Calling Ankara isn't so easy.
Go on. Just do it.
Hello, switchboard.
Hi, Salih. This is Nafiz.
The mayor's son.
You were going to connect us
to Ankara. What happened?
Hello!
We can't even get through to
the operator, let alone Ankara.
Salih! Haven't we helped you over
the years? Connect me to my Rfat!
Dammit!
lt's not Salih's fault.
Hello, Salih. Rifat.
Hello!
lt would be great with pictures.
-Would you like some fruit?
-What's with the fruit?
What are you shouting about?
Just offering.
Don't! l'm pissed off enough as it is.
On the road to nowhere,
heel broken, nails broken.
Hair messed up for 300 km. now!
Did l assign you?
Am l the general director?
lf you're not,
why are you hitting on me?
Hitting on you? Me?
lsn't he after me, Cevat?
Not exactly.
Maybe over interested is all.
Over interested?
Come on, you're overdoing
it a bit with the broad.
Broad? That's it!
Shut up and turn that off.
l swear l'm about to kill myself.
What kind of an assignment
is this for a lady?
That Bnyamin bastard
is responsible for all this.
l'm not about to sleep with just
any old deputy director.
We already spent 4 extra days
because the truck broke down.
By the way, l'm not staying an extra
second in this godforsaken town!
Aren't we going to set it up?
No way! Give them directions
and let them do it themselves.
Being exploited in a place like this!
Pull over. At least let me
have some water.
-What do you mean by ''at least''?
-l mean, God give me patience.
-Cheers.
-Same to you!
-We wanted some water.
-You're in the right place.
A fountain is the place for water.
ls it far to the town center?
Why are you asking? We don't
get many questions like that.
We're from Ankara.
We brought a television transmitter.
Ah? What transmitter?
Here sir. We've got something
better than water.
Not this early in the day.
We can pretend it's evening.
Tekin. What's the hold up?
Pass me that raki, brother.
That woman is such a bitch.
l'm about to kill her.
The guy she mentioned. Bunyamin.
The deputy director.
His wife caught them in bed. Now
she says he's under her control.
More like she's under him
all the time.
l sure feel better now.
Goodbye.
Some drinker.
He is. lsn't he?
Attention!
The delegation expected to
arive from Ankara today...
...is bringing us a
vizontele transmitter.
What's keeping them, Mr. Mayor?
They'll be here any minute, brother.
You should have made a speech.
What are you talking about?
Of course you don't have to.
You can't make a speech
every time a crowd gathers.
You'd have to speak every time
three people got together.
Like you've nothing better to do.
-Bring the microphone.
-Yes, sir.
This is a great day
in our town's history.
Why? Are we driving out
the enemy or something?
A very important delegation from...
...Ankara is bringing us a vizontele,
an example of the latest technology!
-What's coming?
-Vizontele.
-What's that?
-l think l saw one in Ankara.
-What does it do?
-l don't remember.
l was drunk. My eyes were
on the babe next to me.
-Sure. l believe you.
-l swear it's true! She was a singer!
What's this machine Mr. Mayor?
lt's like radio with pictures.
What do you mean?
Zeki Mren sings on the radio. Right?
Right.
With this, you can hear him and
see him at the same time!
Will he see us?
l don't know about that.
What about if you're wearing
your underwear?
You wouldn't want
the great Mr. Mren to see that.
And what if the prime minister
appears on the news?
Will we have to sit around
the house wearing ties?
Don't be ridiculous.
Can actors see you at the cinema?
Can't they?
No. This will be like having a cinema
in your own home. But no tickets.
There they are.
Welcome to our town.
l'm the Mayor, Nazmi Doan.
Go on. Get the sacrificial lamb.
There is no need for that.
Why? Don't you eat meat?
We can't stay long Mayor. We're
returning to Ankara immediately.
Now, if those gentlemen
could just unload the device...
Gentlemen! The device...
At least come up and
have a drink before dinner.
Thank you sir,
but we'll be on our way.
There's no getting out of here
so quickly.
lt takes at least a year to get
the right contacts...
...for re-assignment to Ankara.
What do you mean by that?
Just kidding, nothing personal.
Not my idea of a joke.
l got a bit carried away.
Tekin, cut the yakking!
What yakking?
She's such a maniac.
She may tired, not a maniac.
Would she care for a drink?
Upper Ayranc?
What?
l know Ankara very well.
Are you from Upper Ayranc?
No.
So it is Lower Ayranc?
No!
That place with a park, then?
My name is Fikri.
Must be all the travelling l guess.
What were you talking to her for?
Me? She talked to me first.
Gave me her address in Ankara,
so l could visit her.
Let me just jot it down.
This is how you hook it up.
Understand?
Put the transmitter up
on a high hilltop.
When you get a picture,
set it there. Good luck.
Hey, wait a minute. What? How?
Move over a bit lsmihal.
So l'll be sitting on the driver's lap?
You'd think she never
sat on a lap.
-What was that?
-Nothing. Just a joke.
Don't blow this way.
But you're smoking too.
l want my own smoke, not yours.
-This is all your fault.
-What can l do. lt's the state's job.
We'll find a way out of this.
What do we know about this
vizontele thing? They just dumped it.
We need someone who
understands these things.
Where can we we find
someone like that?
-We've already got one.
-Who?
-Emin.
-Which Emin?
Crazy Emin, the radio guy.
Get real! You can't be serious.
We can't let that maniac near it.
He knows all about radios.
This is just one with pictures.
Do you seriously think
that nutcase can handle this?
He can build
a radio out of a shoe!
Exactly. A nutcase!
Normal people wear shoes.
lf anyone can do it, it's Emin.
There's no way l can help you
with that.
Just take a look, Emin.
How can l help with that?
And you've already got
six daughters.
But she hasn't given me a son.
Just blow on her and pray.
This holy breath thing is just
something people made up.
Your father was a holy man.
People call you crazy but l believe
you're a holy man.
You got Seyid's boy walking.
My father was no holy man.
God forgive you. And you
smote so and Veysi.
That was just an electric shock!
And l just made the boy a crutch.
You want one?
Would you?
Will it help me have a son?
Leave me in peace!
So much for neighborliness.
Come on, woman!
My father a holy man?
He was a bastard!
Back then the governor had
a daughter. Leman.
She had hair clear down to here.
And when the wind blew...
...she looked like a ballerina
with a long cape.
She came to the match one day.
l broke out in a sweat
even before it started.
Anyway, l caught a corner position
and headed the ball into the goal!
Everyone clapped.
l turned.
Leman was on her feet,
cheering me.
How long was she in these parts?
2 years. She told me to visit her
if l was ever in zmir.
And l did. 5 years later.
You found her?
Yeah. We had tea together.
Leman, me and her husband.
Remember what our teacher
said about this place...
Which teacher?
Our literature teacher in high school.
What'd he say?
He called it the capital city
of disappointment.
What is this?
lt's a vizontele.
What does it do?
lt'll bring the world to our home.
What for?
What do you mean?
-How will it do that?
-l don't know.
lt's something like a moviehouse.
-One in each home.
-May God protect us!
Mela Hseyin said
movies were sinful.
He says that about everything.
Repent. You busy yourself with this
but have no time for your son.
l haven't been able
to talk to him even once.
He's in the army. So what?
We all served. l served four years.
Nafiz! Try to call him again.
The whole world right here.
Maybe Emin really is
just the guy for this.
-Mr. Veli, when is the fight film?
-Get lost.
Wh... wh... what is it?
They all call it ''vizontele''.
But it's really called ''television''.
Wh... what is it?
lt's the devil's work. We don't show
blasphemous movies at the cinema.
But this thing will be in everyone's
house. Who knows what it'll show?
Do your religious duty.
Warn the people.
Bye!
Would you like some tea?
Ahmet!
Come to the breakfast table,
you drunk!
l'm here dad. What's the fuss?
With the drinking and all,
it's become a rare honour...
...to see your face around here.
l drink now and then with friends,
that's all.
Now and then?
You don't even go to the office.
After all the strings l pulled.
Don't do this in front of the women!
Oh. So, you do give a damn about
the women of the house?
ls that why we married you?
Did you ask me anything
about it then?
Get up and get out! Now!
Eat your food, child.
-Nafiz.
-Yes, father.
Get me Emin, the radio guy.
Crazy Emin?
Go on, son!
Come on, kids...
Why are you taking them
to religious classes?
Repent, mayor. Do you want them
to grow up heathens?
Your son went, and this devilish
contraption arrived in his place.
lt's a bad omen!
You must get rid of it.
lt will bring harm on us.
God in heaven protect us!
Well, children.
Repeat after me.
All you do is eat, drink and crap.
Some of you never tumble.
Some of you think you're partridges.
You are tumblers!
Some of you get away
with two tumbles a day.
l won't name names here.
But that's finished!
No more feed for non-tumblers.
You think l will tumble for you?
No tumbles, no feed.
Go easy on the guys.
They're just birds after all.
What's up, good-for-nothing?
My father sent for you.
What could the teacher want?
He is the Mayor!
What ever. Mayor then. He was my
teacher once. What does he want?
Quit moping.
Have some more feed.
But l'm expecting tumbles tomorrow!
Turn that wheel a little.
This one?
How did you manage
to build all these gadgets.
l learned from my master.
He asked me to hold a screwdriver
for him one day.
And l never put it down again.
He didn't pay me,
but he was a great man.
Stop, get out of the way!
What's going on?
Where are you going?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Darn, missed it again!
Emin, what are you doing?
That's my mom's favorite song.
l keep running up here...
...to play it for her
on the radio,...
...but either the song is too short...
...or the grave's too far.
Once the song started just as l
was passing by.
But the battery ran out.
Then l made a battery
that never runs out.
A battery that never runs out?
So why does teacher want me?
-For the vizontele.
-What's that?
You haven't heard
about the new gadget?
What gadget?
You should see the look
on your face when l say gadget.
Get to the point?
What gadget?
No one knows for sure.
Radio with pictures.
Radio with pictures!
So they finally made one?
l'd thought of it. Really.
Let's go.
That maniac's running off again!
Where is it?
Where is what?
Vizontele.
Why ask me?
Maybe the kids have it.
Don't try my patience.
l know you took it.
lt's state property.
What are you trying to do to me?
lt's the devil's property!
Says who? Mela?
That's what he says.
What did he say?
''lt's the dd... dd... dddevil's work''?
God preserve us.
Where is it?
lt will bring disaster on us.
Send it back.
My hand's about to cause
an accident.
Hi, Siti!
Welcome, Emin.
What's that thing on your head?
lt's for my eyes.
Where is teacher?
-Welcome, Emin.
-Thanks.
Where's the gadget?
Siti?
ln the pantry, under the oven.
Hush child!
What a beauty.
Just look at it.
l knew they'd made one one day.
So we'll set it up on a high spot?
Can you manage?
l'll have to dismantle it
and take a look.
What?
The vizontele.
What do you mean,
dismantle it?
Take off the cover and
have a look inside.
Open up a gadget like this?
Are you crazy?
Most people say so.
So... the wave hits this at right
angles. Not like the radio.
l should kiss the hand of the guy
who invented this.
Great job! They altered
the radio to...
You're driving me crazy!
Can you do it or not?
We'll put it back together,
and see.
l assume you can do that.
l suppose l can.
Suppose?
Maybe Basri was right.
Dad, can you step out for a minute?
-What is it?
-Look!
One meter higher
should do the trick.
At least one more meter.
Raising the wall so we can't watch.
Shameless bastard.
Worse than shameless. You're
the mayor. Just shut it down.
l can't. lt'd be like
punishing the people.
lf we can set up this
vizontele tomorrow...
...he'll get what he deserves.
Exactly! Who needs moviehouses
if we have vizontele!
We'll have a ceremony.
Put on something decent.
-So, isn't this all right?
-No! Haven't you got a jacket?
Not with long sleeves.
l'll get you one then.
No, thanks teacher.
l'll get one myself.
What's up Yasar?
Nothing.
How can nothing be up?
ls there such a thing as nothing?
ls Fikri around?
Nope.
Fine. l saw him
on my way here anyway.
We had a misunderstanding the
other day, but he's not so bad.
When you said ''nothing''
you reminded me of something.
What's that?
Do you know the tale of the
vizier and the elephant?
Yes.
-The vizier and the ant?
-Yes.
Just the vizier?
You couldn't have heard it,
l just learned it.
l'll tell you about it.
One day the vizier...
So, how are
the great revolutionaries?
Fine Emin. How about you?
You still haven't saved us.
Even we couldn't save you.
Come see the vizontele! We're
having an opening ceremony soon.
lf you're in charge...
Where'd you get this suit?
A friend gave it to me.
On the brink of war and look
what they're busy with.
Which son of a bitch did this?
Dad, they torn down the wall
and smashed the bricks.
lf they's just left us the bricks,
we could have rebuild the wall.
l'm just explaining
about the bricks.
What's up, snow man?
Nice suit. Going to a wedding?
We're testing the vizontele today
up on that hill.
Why spend money on something
that's just going to melt away.
Can l help you?
Mother, talk to me!
About what?
lt was an accident.
All this over a picture?
But it's my only picture.
Mom, l talked to dad.
What about?
l've got good news for you.
He'll take you to the photographer!
Hurry and get ready.
So, how did it happen?
l told him how important
it was for you.
And he went along with it?
Well, l told him there were some
new watches at the studio...
...and that he could put one on
for the picture. He liked that.
l'll get dressed.
Hang these on the line.
l'm going to this vizontele thing.
Tell us when you're going to come.
Rifat, are you well? Do you
have enough money?
Do you have money?
Nafiz, l wonder if you could, well,
take me to the vizontele thing.
l miss you so much Rifat.
Sure, of course we'll go.
Rifat, don't hang up!
Let's go.
-What about the telephone?
-Come with me.
lt's me, Asiye.
We're fine.
My parents are fine too.
How are you?
Yes, me too.
What? Where is that? Where?
So you think Nazmi did it?
Did it or had it done.
lt must be Siti. lt's just like her!
What's the poor woman got
to do with it?
Why do you say that?
What did l say?
That ''poor'' woman.
We're all grandparents now, and
you're still jealous of your sister!
She's no sister of mine!
My own sister asked at my wedding
whose wedding it was!
Made it seem like
you wanted her.
Thirty years later
you're still going on about it!
You loved her too. That's why
you call her ''poor'' woman now.
Go find something better
to do with yourself.
lt still bothers you, doesn't it?
Enough!
Let's go see how the
vizontele thing turns out.
Dad, what about that matter?
You still haven't
aranged things for the boy.
l will in good time!
Levelled my wall, did they?
Testing... testing...
What are the good citizens up to?
Get a load of the suit...
Emin!
-What's the matter, Mr. Goldilocks?
-Give the mike to our Mayor.
Dear citizens. We are gathered here
today for a most historical event.
Someone asked
what was historical about it.
l'll tell you.
Visitors always ask us:
How can you live in a place like this?
That's a tough question.
We have no choice but to love
our homeland...
...and there's no other way
to find true happiness.
lf you love this town it becomes
the most beautiful spot in the world.
lf you don't love the most beautiful
spot in the world...
...it is no longer beautiful.
Newspapers arrive here
two days late.
By the time we hear something
city folk have all forgotten about it.
Vizontele will end all that.
We'll see whatever they see
in lstanbul. And at the same time.
Vizontele will narrow the gap
between our town and the world.
Everything will be closer.
May it be to the best for us all.
We're ready, teacher.
ln the name of God...
Look, it's a movie
about a blizzard.
Emin?
Looks like we'll be climbing
another hill.
May it bring joy to our town.
Still snowing away.
lt was so popular
they made a sequel.
l think you can skip the speech
today. l mean, no one...
Turn it on.
Yes, sir.
Save the vizontele. lt's on fire...
lf only you'd seen it.
Up in flames, smoke pouring out.
The Mayor's a relative of mine.
Now they're ribbing me too.
They call him ''The Vizontele Mayor''.
Has a nice ring to it.
Get me some hot water, would you?
l told him it would never work,
but he wouldn't listen.
And l told him we should get a
technician from Ankara.
He and Crazy Emin set the
state's vizontele on fire.
How can l explain this
to the governor?
We'll probably see some real
fiery shows on that thing.
You'll all vote for him again anyway.
Not a chance.
And two people
were wounded they say.
So what are the two cleanest bears
in town talking about?
The vizontele fire.
lt'll go on burning. l'm a movie man,
myself. lt's something else.
Now, who was that tall actor?
Tark Akan.
That's right. He's not that tall.
Just comes up to here.
l saw him in lstanbul once.
That's movies for you.
There's one more thing.
l was walking in Beyolu... last year.
Who was that guy
with the pencil line mustache.
Ayhan lsk.
Of course you know nothing
about Beyolu.
Who was the guy in ''Tourist Omer''?
-Sadri Alsk.
Right. He's got a thin mustache too.
Anyway, l yelled out ''Tourist Omer''
when l saw Ayhan lsk.
He didn't even turn around.
So if you shout out ''Ayhan lsk''
when you see Sadri Alsk...
...probably won't look back either.
That's the weird thing about movies.
-How are you Necati?
-Fine.
Good evening.
Welcome, Veli. How are you my son?
What the hell do you want?
Dad sent me.
He says you have to buy tickets
to watch the movie from the roof.
No more free loaders, he says.
Veli!
They're my dad's orders.
Get the hell out of here.
No money for you!
Well, l'll tell him that's what you
said, then. Good evening.
What does he want?
He came here to sell tickets.
Oh, really
You want money?
Come and get it...
Emin.
Don't even try it.
Just keep on watching.
l cooked stuffed vegetables
in case you were hungry.
At this hour?
Food's good at any time, darling.
l thought it might be my fault
that you want a second wife.
Your fault? Why?
l've let myself go. l've been wearing
the same bra for two years.
l got a new one today.
Wanna see it?
Your bra? Here?
Yes, it's here.
l mean, you wanna show it
to me here...
What are you rascals up to?
Shame on you! Go on home!
Teacher! Come here for a second!
What is it?
The fire started because
this overheated.
But Emin's got the answer.
-What?
-Watch this...
This fan will keep it cool.
But we need a battery for the fan.
Where can we get one right away?
Turn it off.
What's wrong?
lt's all over.
What do you mean?
l've made a fool of myself. They're
calling me ''The Vizontele Mayor''.
Let's get a technician from Ankara.
We can't quit now.
We'll show them all.
Especially Latif.
l know what to do.
What?
They said to put it high up
on a hill.
We've been up on
every hilltop around.
And it didn't work.
So we have to go higher.
Higher?
The highest hill of all!
The highest of all.
Are you out of your mind?
All we need is a battery.
Look, l haven't gone crazy yet. No
one's ever been up there! Forget it.
l'm sending the vizontele
to Ankara.
We're leaving this with you.
Take care of it!
Father, are you going up
Mount Artos?
Got a problem with that?
Mayor, have you lost your mind? How
can you go up there at your age?
Get down here!
For God's sake, father!
Shut up!
Mr. Mayor, l really must
tell you that you're too old.
And you're not.
What do you mean, sir?
Hop in. You're coming along.
l'm coming too?
Get in, Goldilocks.
Stop it!
May God give you wisdom!
What else can l say?
Going up Mount Artos.
He's really losing it.
What about that matter, dad?
Don't start with me.
l said l'd handle it!
You keep saying that, but...
You didn't sell even one ticket.
Get in and get to work!
The poor guy's lost his mind.
He's not fit to serve his mayor.
What's going on?
The car doesn't work.
Dad, the battery is gone.
You must have left
the headlights on.
lt's really gone, dad!
lt's been stolen!
Someone opened up the hood and
stole it. lf they'd left the battery...
What'd he say?
Crazy Emin told me you said
he could pick out any suit...
...as payment for a radio.
As payment...
That's right.
-And you fell for it...?
-Yes.
Want some tea?
l'll get it to you. Go inside.
Stupid son of a bitch.
Keep your eyes glued to the
vizontele, Semsi! Got that?
lf anything happens
let us know. Got it?
Where did you get the battery?
Never mind.
A friend gave it to me.
Mr. Mayor...
Don't say a word. This is a matter
of honor for me.
l'll go all the way to the Himalayas
if l have to.
What can l say?
May God be with you.
Once we get a picture,
we'll celebrate with a bonfire.
Yes, sir.
The mayor's gone bonkers.
He's going up the mountain.
Emin, you maniac! l'll be seeing you
about the suit.
Actually, it does need some
alterations.
We'll walk the rest of the way.
People keep talking
about my father...
...saying that he was some kind
of holy man,...
...that that makes me
a holy man too.
Half of them think l'm crazy; half
think l'm some kind of a mystic.
Are they the same?
l know the real story.
He came here as a soldier...
...and managed to convince everyone,
including my mother...
...that he had special healing powers.
That's how l was born.
A bit of mystical, heavy breathing
and then off he went.
Being a bastard is not so bad.
Think of all the hassles l'd have
if l had relatives.
lf l had a brother he would
only mean trouble.
You've a point there.
lsn't it time to find
you a girl, Emin?
No, thanks. l've got a sweetheart.
Who?
She's in Denmark.
-Where?
-lt's a foreign country.
-What's she doing over there?
-She's from there.
How'd did you meet this girl?
She came here as a tourist,
l showed her around.
She wanted me to go to Denmark
with her. l asked her...
...who would look after
my birds?
You stayed here for your birds?
They'll die if l go. But when she
insisted, l said...
...l'd try to sort something out...
...so l could go see her
next summer...
We had no idea you were
working on international relations.
l was just showing her around.
Nothing special.
We were eating walnuts.
She loved me, and l loved her.
When did all this happen?
While we were eating walnuts.
lt's not my fault.
l just did what she did.
What are you doing?
No Cristine, no.
When did she come here?
5 years ago.
What's her name?
Cristine. Spelled with a 'c'.
l hope it all works out.
Let's go before it get's too late.
What are you staring at?
lt's turned off.
Get lost! lt's the mayor's orders.
Your hair's thickening with
each mile, Sezgin.
That inimitable sense
of humor, Mr. Mayor...
Dammit!
Gone. You'll have to ask me
about your hair. Yes, it's thinning.
Shut up.
Get a move on, Goldilocks.
Are you ready, Emin?
lt's nightfall.
Ready, teacher.
Help us God. This is our last chance.
Look! A picture!
Just a minute.
What's this?
Persian.
Why?
l think it's lranian vizontele.
They must have one too.
Fuck!
Excuse me, Mr. Mayor.
You took the word right
out of my mouth. Fuck!
Well, Emin? Wasn't it supposed
to work on the highest spot?
l'm not sure.
Maybe if we go to...
Stop it Emin, for God's sake!
That's right, Emin.
lt's your fault we're here.
Shut up, Goldilocks. Or l'll send you
back for the mirror.
l'm sorry, teacher.
What's going on?
ls it a wedding or something?
Put out the fire!
People will think that...
Let it burn...
Otherwise we'll freeze to death.
What happened?
We got lranian vizontele.
-But you built a fire!
-We were cold.
A Traditional Black Sea Wedding...
Mr. Mayor! lt's on!
Turkish vizontele is on!
Look mom, it's on!
Welcome, please come in...
May it be for the best, Mr. Mayor.
Thank you.
There's no business tonight, dad.
They've all gone
to watch the vizontele.
Don't worry. They'll be back in a
couple of days. lt's the novelty of it.
Turn it on, Mayor.
Right. Here, by the grace of God...
Turn it on, Emin.
Good evening.
The Turkish Armed Forces' naval
and air intervention in Cyprus...
...continues with
overwhelming success.
Prime Minister Blent Ecevit
addressed the nation...
...at a press conference
this morning:
''We are in Cyprus
to promote peace,...
...not to forment war.
We hope that our forces will not
encounter resistance...
...that will only lead to bloodshed.
We are there for peace,
not for war.
We're also there
to bring peace to the Greeks.''
The marine corps are successfully
holding Girne, at great cost...
...to enemy ranks. Turkish forces
have suffered 5 fatalities...
2 officers and 3 privates.
Lost in action are...
Where is he?
Who?
My son, where is he?
The general called today. He told us
to be proud of our boy,...
...said he was a true hero.
They built him a tomb...
...at the War Martyrs' Cemetery
in Cyprus.
He said it. One of the top brass.
Would he call just anyone?
-Our boy must have been great.
-Teacher, Mother Siti says to...
Don't do it ma'am.
lt's not the gadget's fault...
Grandfather...
Father.
We're going to my father's house.
Where is everybody?
The Brazil match is on TV.
They'll come after the game.
Shall l put the head facing that way?
And a brand new Phillips television
from the groom's uncle.
Everyone clap!
Upon your feet, everyone!
Turn the antenna some more.
Like this?
Some more.
ls it on?
ls it?
Yes, we've got it.