Distributed by OFFICE KITANO
anb NIPPON HERALD
BANDAI VISUAL, TV TOKYO,
TOKYO FM
anb OFFICE KITANO present
TAKESHI KITANO - VOLUME 7
Probuced by MASAYUKI MORI
YASUSHI TSUGE
TAKIO YOSHIDA
Starring BEAT TAKESHI
and KAYOKO KISHIMOTO
Music by JOE HISAISHI
Written, Directed and Edited by
TAKESHI KITANO
DROP DEAD!
Det. Horibe, were you and Nishi
classmates in junior high?
In senior high, too.
And your wives are friends, too?
That's right.
Do you remember, Nishi?
At the amusement park.
We picked them up, didn't we?
Nishi got the pretty one
and I got the dog.
What are you laughing at?
Hey, stop the car.
Go get some bean cakes.
Yes, sir.
How is your wife?
It's been two years, hasn't it?
My wife is healthy as hell,
but it must be tough for you.
Been to the hospital lately?
The stakeout's near the hospital.
Go see her.
Go on.
We don't have much to do today.
- How much?
- 1,200 yen.
- For bean cakes?
- Yes, just the bean cakes.
Idiot! There's too much
for the 3 of us! You pay for it.
But...
These are the wrong ones.
- Were there any chestnut ones?
- Steamed?
Not the hot spring kind!
It's straight to the amusement park
with no sleep for me tomorrow.
I spoil my daughter.
Smart place to park!
I can't even get out!
I'll go check.
Don't play ball here, you idiots!
Sorry!
Well?
No way he'd come here.
He won't come back to his apartment
after that massacre.
What's the chief thinking of?
I know.
Is that how you dress
for a stakeout?
You're not on a date.
Nishi's going to the hospital.
Can you stay on?
Well, I have a date...
Screw you!
How is Nishi's wife?
Not too good, I hear.
Is it cancer?
Watch what you say.
First their daughter died...
She was only 4 or 5, wasn't she?
That was a bigger shock
than her illness.
I visited his wife a while back.
She didn't say a word.
I'm glad my wife is so healthy.
Must be hard on Nishi.
Daughter dies, wife gets sick,
and he's a damn cop.
So busy he can't even visit her.
I'll stay on.
Not you, Tanaka.
You're a family man.
Come on, stay on for 3 hours.
No, I can't.
OK, I'll stay. You can go.
Can I get a lift?
How's your wife?
I'll go visit her some time.
Hello. It's me.
I'm not coming home tonight.
I know that.
What can I do? It's my job.
Let me talk to Michi.
Michi, it's daddy.
I'm at work.
The amusement park? Another time.
What? You drew a picture?
Where did you draw it?
You shouldn't do that.
Yes, it's very pretty.
- Drive me to Shibuya.
- I can't.
My date's waiting for me there.
No. I have to wait for him.
I'll go by cab then.
Is Nishi's wife really dying?
Dammit! Don't say that.
It's bad luck.
- Leukemia, right?
- Why don't you shut up?
Excuse me.
The doctor wants to speak to you.
Modern medicine
can't work miracles.
We've done all we can.
I think it would be better
to take her home.
The child's death was a real blow.
She'll be better off at home
than in the hospital.
Excuse me. Could you call Mr Nishi?
Just a moment.
Mr Nishi, someone to see you.
Det. Horibe's been shot.
Even when they're married,
people just think about themselves.
When I came home,
my wife and child
couldn't even look at me.
The light wasn't even on.
They just said goodbye.
Now that I'm a wreck
they leave me just like that.
Actually, it may be better this way.
But I've got nothing to do.
My mom says I should
take up a hobby or something.
Haiku.
She wanted me to join
a poetry group.
Give me a break.
Work is all I've ever known.
Since I live by the seaside,
maybe I should try painting.
But I've never painted anything.
I wouldn't know where to start.
And the materials don't come cheap.
Don't get me wrong.
It's not your fault.
Maybe I'll buy a beret.
Don't worry.
You're very kind.
After all, my husband
died in the line of duty.
Because of the recession,
good jobs are hard to come by,
but I'm helping out at a deli.
The hardest part is...
when my son tells me
he misses his dad.
It's so sad...
But I'm sure he'll understand soon.
We'll be OK.
I have to get back to work.
I've decided...
to get married.
Who to?
I really wasn't serious about her,
but when I was injured,
she visited me every day.
I was touched by that.
Can you answer that?
Excuse me.
Kudo speaking.
The other day,
I went to see Mr Horibe.
He seemed so lonely.
They were
such a close-knit family...
but his wife and child left him.
You know,
you really shouldn't feel guilty...
Tanaka's death
isn't your fault either.
He died in the line of duty.
It's nobody's fault.
This way, please.
Shut up!
- Yes, sir?
- Shut up!
Hey, Nishi.
The boss is mad. You haven't paid
the interest this month.
You better pay up!
You know what we yakuza are like!
After all, you were a cop.
Without the badge,
he's just an ordinary guy.
He's less than that - he's a bum.
How's your wife?
Here are her usual pills.
But I don't think
they'll do her much good.
Don't think about it too much.
When you're with her,
talk to her as much as possible.
You could even take her on a trip.
If anything happens, call me.
Here's a shirt for you.
It might be too big for you,
but you can have it.
Please try to be more careful.
Hello.
It's Horibe...
He attempted suicide.
Luckily his landlord found him.
I think he'll make it,
but he took
a lot of sleeping pills.
Are his wife and daughter there?
He's asleep now.
He should be OK
in a couple of days.
Shall we go?
- Let me out here.
- I'll take you home.
It's OK. I'll get out.
Stop the car.
What sort of a detective
was Mr Nishi?
He was a great cop.
Decorated lots of times.
He and Mr Horibe were a great team.
Whenever Mr Horibe got too rough,
Mr Nishi would stop him.
You haven't even paid back your debt
and you want another 4 million!
Why should we lend it to you?
You can't even pay the interest.
You poked my guy's eye out.
Who's going to pay for that?
- Is that a loan, too?
- Forget it!
If he can't pay us back,
he can work for us.
What do you have in mind?
He could be my bodyguard.
Great idea!
He keeps shooting
when the other guy's gun
is empty.
But when Mr Nishi really lost it,
he was more frightening.
Like that time...
when he emptied his gun
into a corpse.
Hello.
How are you?
Doing all right.
Watch out, asshole!
I had the right of way!
On narrow roads,
big cars should yield!
- Are you crazy?
- What?
- Driving such a tiny car!
- What's it to you?
- Fix it yourself.
- Mind your business!
- Want some more?
- What?
Well?
I'm sorry.
Are you done?
- What's going on?
- He's in a coffee shop.
He has a gun and with all
these people, we can't do a thing.
How's Horibe?
Don't know yet.
He's at the hospital.
He got hit in the belly.
What are you doing?
Can you sell me that light?
You mean the police light?
What do you want it for?
I'm thinking of robbing a bank.
Sounds great!
Take it. You can have it.
Good luck.
Do some work,
you glue-sniffing bum!
You want 500,000 for this?
No, not this one.
The other one.
What other one?
This one.
But it's a taxi cab!
It's mine.
How come?
- It belongs to me.
- You didn't steal it?
No, it's mine.
- How old are you?
- 20.
You can't get a cab license at 20!
I'll call the cops!
The fender's a bit dented,
but you can have it for 200,000.
This car is hot.
How about 50,000?
What happened at the bar?
Like I said, the waiter apologized
for spilling soy sauce on my jacket.
And gave you 100,000 yen!
It was an Armani suit and...
Armani? You're kidding!
Genuine Armani.
And?
And I needed
some money for the taxi and...
For the taxi?
100,000 yen for the taxi! Where to?
Oita, on the southern isle.
Don't bullshit me.
Do you take us for fools?
- He offered it to me.
- That's extortion!
Not at all.
Cut the crap!
I'll throw this in, too.
Hi!
Can I help you?
METROPOLITAN POLICE
You're just a yakuza loan shark!
An expert at dirty tricks.
You borrow money off me
and call me a loan shark!
Well, aren't you? You don't
respect the terms of the contract.
Your interest rate's outrageous.
You can wait a while!
You've been saying that
for months, you bastard!
We're running a business!
You can't get blood from a stone.
Want a bullet in your head?
I dare you, you two-bit punk!
Hey!
What do you want, boy?
Good luck with the bank robbery.
Miss...
I found it there. How much?
You can have it. It's junk.
Junk, huh? Is the rest junk, too?
- What are you doing?
- Salvaging junk.
What do you mean "junk"?
Isn't this junk?
It's merchandise, asshole!
Hey, I recognize you!
Hey! I've been hit!
Hey, wait!
Stupid cop, wait!
I'm a hit-and-run victim!
You waste of public money!
I should've sold it for 200,000.
Wake up!
8 of hearts.
4 of clubs.
Queen of diamonds.
10 of hearts.
Ace of diamonds.
Queen of clubs.
Crunchy chocolate!
Goodbye.
Thank you very much.
Why don't you keep it?
I'm sure he wants you to.
Mr Nishi was really worried
about you.
Goodbye.
I can't believe it!
He paid back all his debts!
Did he rob a bank?
No, he wouldn't do that!
Right. He's not like you!
To make a fortune,
I'd play the stock market.
- Extort companies?
- Don't use that word!
The boss is a legit businessman.
A businessman packing a piece!
HANDLE WITH CARE
Nobody home.
Did you ask the neighbors?
Go ask them, you fool!
More! A bit more!
More, I said!
Look.
What a big bell!
Look at the size of it!
It goes "gong" when you hit it.
You can't hit it now.
But you'll hear it this evening.
Well, it's time to go home now.
LUCKY CHARM
All this free time is tough.
I paint pictures to kill time,
but I'm only an amateur.
I can't find anything to paint.
Hasn't Mr Nishi been in touch?
Not recently.
But he sent me
some art materials a while ago.
I didn't know what to say.
With his wife sick,
he must be very busy.
To be honest...
I don't think
his wife has long to live.
But in a way,
he's better off than me.
What are you giving them water for?
Those flowers are dead.
Hey, it's no use
watering dead flowers!
Did you get ditched by a guy
and lose your mind?
I'll be right back.
Boss says you forgot the interest.
Hey!
Go on, shoot me, punk.
Go on.
Open your mouth.
Next time, I'll kill you.
There! ltalian-style cooking.
Step on it!
Go on!
No. Forward!
Forward!
Why did you want to see the snow?
It's freezing cold.
You're going to catch a cold.
My hand hurts.
Can't you hold it?
Go over there.
Don't worry. I'll keep watch.
Just you?
Don't you want one
with your husband?
Ready?
Smile.
Cheese!
A souvenir for you.
Enjoy your stay.
SNOW
LIGHT
SUICIDE
Excuse me.
There's someone to see you.
What do you want?
The boss is here. Come with me.
- Where are we going?
- You'll find out.
Come with me.
Sorry about your eye.
How much money do you have left?
Why don't you hand the rest over
to us?
After prison
you'll get it back with interest.
I warned you.
SUICIDE
Shove him in and close the door.
I saw them...
the yakuza corpses...
Can you wait a moment?
Just a moment.
I could never live like that.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Nishi: BEAT TAKESHI
Nishi's wife:
KAYOKO KISHIMOTO
Horibe: REN OSUGI
Nakamura: SUSUMU TERAJIMA
Junkyard owner:
TETSU WATANABE
Yakuza hitman: HAKURYU
Criminal: YASUEI YAKUSHIJI
Kudo: TARO ITSUMI
Tanaka: MAKOTO ASHIKAWA
His widow: YUKO DAIKE
Doctor: KEN'ICHI YAJIMA
Produced by MASAYUKI MORI
YASUSHI TSUGE
TAKIO YOSHIDA
Music: JOE HISAISHI
Paintings: TAKESHI KITANO
Cinematography:
HIDEO YAMAMOTO
Lighting Director:
HITOSHI TAKAYA
Art Dirtector: NORIHIRO ISODA
Sound: SENJI HORIUCHI
Written and Directed by
TAKESHI KITANO