London. The greatest city
in the world.
For 22 years, I've lived here.
Every morning I take a walk
down this street.
Every morning, the street asks me
my name...
Chaudhary Baldev Singh? Who are you?
Where are you from? Why are you here?
Do I have a reply? After half
a lifetime spent here...
this land still remains alien
to me, and I to it.
No one here knows me. None except
these doves. Because they're like me.
Neither do they belong to a country.
Just drop down where you find food.
Have your fill, then fly on.
When shall I fly? I don't know.
Of necessity, my wings are clipped.
I'm shackled to my bread.
But someday I'll surely go...
to my land. To my Punjab
"When the koels sing in spring,
it's time again for memories"
"It's time again for swinging
under the boughs"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your heart beckons"
"The mute soil doesn't
read your letters"
"Come, kiss your soil, bring back
the earth to life"
"Yes, you have your dreams;
but we are yours too, your kin"
"You are so forgetful,
but we miss you so..."
"Come home o'wanderer,
your land beckons".
Glory to The Goddess.
Yes Lajjo, I'm here safe and sound.
- Good.
Why is my little one giggling away?
- Mom! Every day for 20 years...
Dad has been walking down
the very same street...
to his very same destination.
Yet every day, you call him up...
just to ask him, "Have you reached?"
- You won't understand.
Just assume it's a habit.
- Habit left unchanged...
tends to become necessity-like.
- Philosophy, again? You're twelve.
Talk like a 12-year old!
Why all this big talk?
There's no childhood, no adulthood.
One is as grown-up as one feels.
All right! I lose! Now go to school,
chew your teacher's brains, okay?
Why d'you forget
the almonds everyday?
What to do?
Just assume it's habit.
Will you get out?
"This is the first time
it's happening in 18 years"
"Some stranger I have never seen,
comes to my mind".
That's my diary!
- So what...?
Only I can read it.
- That was so funny.
Let me read some more.
- No way! This is a private diary.
Why hide anything from me?
When a girl is grown up...
her mother becomes her friend.
Show that to me.
You won't tell anyone, will you?
- Never.
All right. I'll read. You listen.
- Very well
"This is the first time
it's happening in 18 years"
"Some stranger I have never seen,
comes to my mind..."
"shadow-like before my eyes"
"Someone raps on my heart"
"Deep eyes want me to give myself up"
"When I look at my hands,
there I see a face etched"
"A silken breath brushes my cheeks"
"My hair still smells
of the odour on his hands"
"Yes, it's happening for
the first time in 18 years"
"I've never seen this stranger
who comes to my mind".
Simi, you've begun
writing quite well...
and the boy seems lively.
Who's he?
Ma, I've yet to set my eyes on him.
So there's no one? I was wondering.
One doesn't find such boys nowadays.
And you dream of someone
you haven't even seen! Quite mad.
No Ma. This is no dream.
I may not have met him, seen him.
But he's there. Out there, somewhere
"The one who comes in my dreams..."
"the one who teases me..."
"just ask him to face me, once"
"What's he like? Who is he?
Who knows where is the one..."
"my lips will say yes to?"
"Is he someone I know?
Is he a stranger?"
"Is he for real,
or just a legend?"
"He stares at me,
from far, far away"
"Tell him not to rob me
of my sleep"
"The one who comes in my dreams..."
"the one who teases me..."
"just ask him to face me, once"
"Some kind of spell is overcoming me"
"Oh what do I do?
My heart yearns so"
"My heart tells me it's mad for you.
Then why do you keep hiding from me?"
"He makes me blossom,
it's all his fault"
"Tell him, I'm asking for the Moon"
"The one who comes in my dreams..."
"the one who teases me..."
"just ask him to face me, once".
Raj! This partying all night!
Party all night and you don't sleep.
And how do you get up in the morning?
Late for graduation! Hurry!
Is it a holiday...?
What Raj...?
Late for your graduation?
What to do? Last night...
What's wrong with him?
Has he had one too many beers?
I hear someone has failed.
The Dean has decided...
to announce his name in public.
You've made Dharamveer Malhotra stand
an inch and a half taller in his shoes!
I don't think you heard it right.
- I knew, someday you'd make me proud!
And not only me, the whole dynasty is
proud of you! Look, they smile at you.
My great grandfather Diwan Brijnath
never went to school.
His son, my grandfather
Diwan Dwarkanath failed...
...his fourth standard examinations.
My father, your grandfather...
Diwan Pushkarnath, failed
his eighth standard examinations.
And I, your father,
failed to matriculate.
Not having an education, failing,
are family traditions. I'm happy...
that you have kept tradition alive,
and indeed you're two steps ahead.
We failed back home in India.
You came to London and failed!
Are you really happy?
- Glad.
Education is all useless.
Filling your head with books...
won't fill your pockets.
Look at me. Runaway peasant-boy from
Bhatinda-turned millionaire in London.
So, whatever happens is for the good.
Join my offices from tomorrow.
Offices? From tomorrow?
- Today, if you wish.
I can't attend office now.
- Why not?
Pops, you're a man of experience.
You know what amount of hard work
it takes to fail. And I'm tired, Pops.
I want a little rest, you know,
like a long European holiday.
Long European holiday? How long?
- Month or month and a half.
Will you hold this for me?
And turn around.
Moron! Did I bring you up
to see this day?
No, don't drop that.
Are you all right, Pops?
Pops, you're right. I ought
to take care of your business.
You've become so old.
- You tell your father that?
Pops, I've decided against Europe.
I'm joining the offices from tomorrow.
In this house, only your father
decides. You're going to Europe.
No. I've had enough of a good time.
My years of youth are over for me.
Never say your youth is over.
All my life I've slogged to give
you whatever I couldn't do.
When youth came and went,
I never got to know.
But I wasn't sad, because I knew
that my son will have my years.
If you think you've had enough
of a good time...
if you think the years of youth
are over for you, well no problem.
Just go and live my years for me.
Ajit's letter?
Lajjo! Look, what's here
Letter! From my friend.
From Ajit.
Just smell it, lady!
The fragrance of Punjab!
The flavour of mustard curry
on leavened maize bread.
Those long tailed shirts,
the short knickers
"My dear friend Baldev,
We're fine here"
"We hope to God that you, your wife
and the children are well too"
"You will be pleased to hear that
my son has graduated in arts"
"He has joined my business.
By God's grace, it's time now...
for us to let our childhood
friendship mature into a relationship.
Let's make good the promise we made
to each other 20 years ago. I hope...
you will come here at the soonest
for Simran's wedding to Kuljit.
Read on.
She's shy! See Lajjo?
That's our etiquette, our culture.
My daughter is still so shamefaced.
I'm not a failure.
In the heart of London,
I've kept India alive!
Still staring? Lajjo, your daughter's
wedding! Celebrate it with sweets.
Chutki! I'm so happy today.
Can I say one thing?
- Say four things
lt'd be better to ask Simran once.
- What are you saying?
Ever since she was a baby, she has
known that she is engaged to Kuljit.
That she knows. But 20 years...
- Don't you worry!
Simran is going to be so happy...
you'll pray that she never
gets the evil eye!
I'll write to Ajit right away.
God! At last, comes the day.
Simran, what are you doing?
I had forgotten, Ma. I haven't
even the right to dream.
No my child, of course
you may dream.
But don't expect them
to come true.
And who know, Kuljit might be
the man of your dreams.
I don't care.
I've bought your tickets.
You're coming to Europe with me
- I can't.
Babuji won't let me go to college
alone. Will he let me go away...
touring Europe for a month?
I have lots of work here.
- You've known me for years.
Can't you make up an excuse?
An excuse, I can find. But I don't
feel like lying to Babuji.
You must come. Dolly and Payal
are coming too.
Let me talk to Ma tonight.
Europe?
- Yes.
With friends?
For a month?
- Yes.
Chutki, call the doctor. Tell him
that our Simran has gone stark mad.
Will you at least take a look?
- Check out your brains first.
You talk of travelling by Eurail?
If he hears, he'll bring the roof down.
A lone girl mustn't travel like this.
- Mom, I'm not going to be alone.
My friends are going to be with me.
- No good arguing with me.
I'm not going to object. But you
will need his permission.
Ask him when he's home.
God, please keep Babuji
in a nice mood.
It's just beer. It's over there.
- I told you. The store is shut.
Get out.
Got the beer?
- Didn't find any.
Can't even do such a simple job?
- That was an angry man.
I'll get it.
- You won't.
Can I have an Aspirin?
- The store is shut.
My head is about to crack up!
It's sinusitis.
If I can't find an Aspirin,
I'll faint.
All the other stores are shut.
Please let me have one Aspirin. One
Hindustani ought to help another.
Glory to The Goddess.
- Here you are.
I'm feeling bad about forcing you to
open your store for a small medicine.
I'd like to buy some other things
from you.
I'll pick up some beer.
Not for myself.
My friends out there, they drink.
Put it down.
- Why sir?
Are you trying to con me? You aren't
getting anything. Put it down.
You're getting worked up
over nothing. This is for your profit.
Will you put it down?
- Not that umbrella.
Here you are. A pound extra?
No two. Keep it, okay?
Shameless!
You call yourself a Hindustani?
You give India a bad name.
You're a liar and insolent!
Get out of here.
I'm off. I'll keep this.
Rev up!
Babuji.
What is the matter? You're late.
- Bloody shameless scoundrel.
They call themselves Hindustani! Blot
on India! Ought to drown themselves.
Rascals! No shame, no decency.
How to respect their elders...
they don't even know.
- Have you had a fight?
Scum! He came for beer. I told him
the store is shut. He took it per force.
He even broke the statue of
The Goddess! Bloody half-caste!
I say Lajjo, thank God that
you and your daughters...
haven't been marred
by this Britishness!
Else, you would've been nowhere!
Damn these scoundrels!
Set sail in stormy waters, and
you're in danger of sinking.
You were so little when we brought
you here. And now...
They said that a grown-up daughter
is a burden on a man.
But a daughter like you, makes
a father's chest swell with pride!
You're my good girl.
Will you give something if I ask you?
- Whatever you wish.
I want to take a look at Europe.
Eurail is offering a month's tour.
All my friends are going.
Please don't be cross. I have
never disobeyed you, Babuji.
I'll be going away to a land
I have never seen.
The man I'm going to marry
is a complete stranger. But...
I have no complaints. You must've
considered it in my best interests.
But I won't get a chance
like this ever again.
I don't even know whether
I'll ever come back...
whether I will have
these friends later on.
Besides, it's only for a month. In
a month, I will have lived a lifetime.
For the sake of my happiness, won't
you let me have a month of my life?
Please Babuji, give me one month.
Go. Live it up.
My baby.
Where's Simran?
Where might she be?
- Has she slipped in the loo?
I told you to wake up Raj
Did you?
No.
Open sesame.
Do you have the keys to this?
Anybody home?
No one at home.
Haven't I seen you somewhere?
At Robbie's party, no?
I don't go to parties.
- Great! Nor do I, ever.
Your eyes...
What's wrong with my eyes?
Reminds me of someone.
- Of whom?
My grandmother. Like you, her eyes
too had hues of yellows and blues.
Keep reading. I only wanted to find
out how you read upside-down.
This is the limit!
Simran, you're here?
I heard you've missed the train.
- No, I took it.
I was afraid...
- By the way, what's your name?
Sheena.
Here I am. Shall we...?
- Take it easy.
Pump it up
- It's pumped. Look.
It's nothing.
- Raj, where have you been?
As usual. Caught up with a girl.
Girl...?
- I help her onto the train.
And she falls for me.
- What...?
He bored me. He had me all alone,
and he began flirting.
Same old hat...
haven't I seen you before?
She sidled up to me.
- What?
I was scared! Only so much space,
and there she was with me.
Then?
- Then what? She was lost in my eyes.
He was after my eyes. Wouldn't
shut up. Boys these days...
These girls! I just managed
to come out unscathed.
What's that?
- Invitation to a party.
I told you. It'll be a bore.
- You prophesied a train crash.
And then we'd all be charred alive
after supper in a dinner-hall fire.
Look, boys.
- Where...?
He's the one.
Where have we landed?
Was this your idea?
Us? or the waiters?
- For me.
Rocky shut your trap.
Why did you have to call him?
You know Sheena, haven't
I seen you before?
Me? Really? Where?
- At Robbie's party?
You might've.
I go to so many parties.
You know Sheena...
- What?
Your eyes remind me of someone.
- My eyes? Really? Whom?
My grandmother.
Is she singing or crying?
And I can play better piano.
You know how to play the piano?
I was born on a piano. Been playing
the piano ever since I was a baby.
You know, I've magic in my fingers.
No sooner than I touch the piano...
it starts playing.
Isn't that voice familiar?
Was this necessary?
Doesn't the magic in your fingers
make pianos start playing?
"Stop, my wild lover"
"I've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"Come, let me touch you"
"Wait, my wild love"
"I've got to ask you something"
"Look at me, smiling, unknowing"
"I'm waiting for you,
holding my heart"
"She looks subdued"
"But she has lots to say"
"If you say yes,
I have something to say"
"Wait, my wild love"
"I've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"You aren't the only
pretty woman around"
"Why are you the only one
who's cross?"
"The one I've fallen for,
is someone else"
"If she says yes,
I'll take her in my arms"
"Wait, my wild love"
"I've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"Come, let me touch you".
About last night, I'm ashamed.
I misbehaved with you.
I wanted to tell you something else.
What...?
- This.
Run.
First come, first served.
Hurry! The train is about to leave.
- Where did I keep my money?
One minute, I don't know how to count
this currency... lots of small change.
Can you tell me one,
two's, eighths...?
Stop.
Train's gone?
The train is gone!
Don't cry, Senorita.
But you just stopped crying.
It's raining! Don't cry, please!
I'm with you, I'm here! Look.
Okay, I'm gone... gone!
Here's your bell.
The next train is very late.
To catch up with the train...
at Zurich tomorrow morning, we can
either take a bus or hire a car.
What would be your pleasure?
Bus or car? Where's she?
Ever since you met me,
you've been harassing me.
What are you saying?
- All along the trip...
you've been chewing my brains.
- I...?
Something's always the problem
with you. Today, I've missed...
the train, thanks to you.
- To me...?
I wish to make it to Zurich on time.
So you go your way, I'll go mine.
Strange! We're fellow-travellers,
on the same destination, same train.
Why split up? Besides, a man like me
ought to stay with a girl like you.
Wrong! A girl like me doesn't need
a guy like you. Stop pursuing me.
I'll sew it up. I have a thread and
needle. I'll buy you a new dress.
What have you got yourself into?
I told you not to pursue me!
Who do you think you are?
What do you think of yourself?
I wasn't pursuing you.
And I don't fancy touching you. Thank
your stars I came in the nick of time.
Else, you would've been in jail.
I help her, and she says this.
Hey, take her away.
What did you say?
I got carried away.
Never mind Senorita, never mind. In
big places, such small things happen.
What's about this Senorita?
- My first girl friend was from Spain.
Why did you dump her?
- She hated Indians.
You like Indians, don't you?
- When do we reach Zurich?
What's in Zurich?
This is the real Europe.
So beautiful, so pretty. Sometimes,
I fear, it might become dirty.
Here for the first time?
- Yes.
Will you drive faster?
- What's the hurry Senorita?
Train leaves Zurich at 11:30 tomorrow.
We have a whole night and half a day.
We'll be there on time.
- Still, if we could...
What had to happen, has happened.
Now you're with me.
Nothing can go wrong.
Europe is best done on foot.
Just the four of us.
Chutki is way ahead of her years.
And Ma's more a friend than a mother.
So I never felt the need for a friend.
You can't live the rest of your life
with friends. Sometime or the other...
you will need someone who will
walk by you all your life.
Can't walk anymore. I'm tired.
- Do I pick you up in my arms?
I can't afford a hotel. Let's try
that house. We might find lodgings.
Come. Arrangements for the night
is done.
Which is your room?
Situation is somewhat like this.
There's only one room.
And we spend the night in the same
room? You presume somewhat like that?
How compelling!
- Not quite so compelling.
I'm not staying here one minute.
- You take the bed. I'll take the sofa.
No problems.
- No way. I'm leaving.
I'm not joking. I'm going away.
- And I'll have the bed all to myself?
So nice... so romantic!
And these curtains... so nice!
And the view!
No horses?
It's so warm in here.
There! You have a fire going.
Granted. You have a great sense
of choice.
You couldn't find a better place
to spend the night, right?
We were getting a nice room.
But you'd rather spend the night
with me in the stables. Not in the room.
Eat
- I'm not hungry.
All right. Don't eat.
How am I bothered?
Eat it.
I told you. I'm not hungry.
Come on now. Eat.
What did you say?
I got carried away.
Never mind. In big places,
such small things happen.
You were right, Senorita.
The spirit of adventure in this barn...
you could never enjoy in that room.
- But how do we get to Zurich?
No, not Zurich. Tomorrow evening, we
entrain at Berne. Tomorrow morning...
we take the first bus at eight.
I've found out everything.
Now, nothing can go wrong.
What's that?
- Life.
Aren't you ashamed to drink
in the presence of a lady?
Better than dying before the lady!
If you wish to live on...
you too should have a bit, Senorita.
- Don't you dare come near me.
All right, don't.
I'll see you tomorrow morning if
you're still alive.
Until then, goodnight
"May I have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May I try a pirouette?
"How about a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Let me fly with the wind"
"God! Help me"
"The chill in the breeze
sets my body afire"
"I feel like..."
"making love to you"
"This never happened before"
"I've taken my first step"
"Let me fly with the wind"
"God! Help me"
"May I have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May I try a pirouette?"
"Give me a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Where do you think you're going,
my darling, my love...?"
"You're a pretty girl.
I'm a handsome young man"
"Come into my embrace"
"Let me hold you in my eyes"
"Oh, I'm drunk"
"God! Help me"
"May I have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May I try a pirouette?"
"Give me a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Oh, I'm ecstatic"
"God! Help me".
Up in the mornings,
you look even prettier.
How did I get here?
With me. Last night.
I don't think you've ever
had a drink before.
And you had one too many.
Have this.
What happened last night?
What happened last night,
was bound to happen.
But I didn't imagine
it'd happen this way.
Tell me the truth, Raj!
What happened last night?
How do I answer
this question, Simran?
Look, look into my eyes.
Aren't my eyes telling the truth?
No! This could never have happened.
This could never have happened.
- That's exactly what happened, Simran.
Who can stop what is to happen?
You're lying!
You're lying, aren't you?
No Simran.
- Please tell me you're lying.
Granted! I'm lying,
my eyes are lying.
But are these love-bites lying?
Speak.
Tell me Simran! Are these yours?
Or someone else's?
Don't cry! I was just joking.
Those aren't real! Look!
I used your lipstick.
You only had one too many,
and you were dripping wet.
I had no options. I had to bring
you here. I swear, I'm just joking.
You were all alone on the bed. I slept
out there. I'm just joking! I swear.
Don't cry, don't.
I know what you think of me.
You think I'm a wastrel.
I'm not scum, Simran.
I'm Hindustani.
And I know what honour means
for the Hindustani woman.
Not even in my dreams can I imagine
doing that to you. Trust me, Simran.
I'm saying the truth. Last night,
nothing happened. Just a joke.
Please, never joke about that.
You don't know what I would've done.
Please, no jokes like that.
I promise never to crack
a joke like that.
Get changed. Fast.
We got to catch the bus.
May I have my shirt back?
Fifteen minutes before the bus
leaves. You want to eat something?
No, I'm not hungry.
Come on, let's take a look inside.
- Churches aren't worth a look.
I'm not going.
Go on. Take a look.
What?
- Hurry up. We'll miss the bus.
Shall we?
- Why not leave after tea?
What did you ask for?
- You aren't supposed to speak of it.
Then you must be sure about
being given what you've asked for.
Whatever one seeks with a pure heart,
one is surely given.
Go on. I'll be back in a minute.
- What happened?
Go on. I'll join you.
I'm Raj.
I'm sorry, I don't know how to pray.
But I want nothing for myself.
But that girl Simran, she's nice.
Very good at heart.
Give her whatever she asked for.
Where have you been?
In the church?
Half a teaspoon of sugar, one spoon
of milk, bit of cream. Your coffee.
You want a postcard to send home?
- Postcard? For home?
If that postcard reaches home,
my Pop will give me up for dead.
When were you last serious?
- Till now, never.
If ever, it'll happen only once.
- When?
When I'm in love.
A boy like you was never in love?
- I've had many affairs.
But I was never in love, Senorita.
Never found one.
What kind of girl are
you looking for?
Want me to tell you?
The moment I look at her...
all my heart's desires, all my
dreams will come alive.
Has never happened. But now I hear
a voice, behind the clouds, calling.
She's a stranger, a face I've never
seen before. When will the clouds part?
Has it never happened with you?
- No.
No stranger ever invaded your dreams?
No place for strangers in my dreams.
I am engaged to marry.
Engaged to marry?
- Yes.
Where's the fiance? In London?
- No, in India.
Looks...?
Don't know. Never seen him.
You've never seen the man
you're going to marry?
Not necessary. My father has
seen him. His friend's son.
You'll spend your life with someone
you've never met?
A complete stranger?
That's how it happens with us.
- And you're happy with this decision?
The train is here.
Lovely photographs. Send me a set of
copies. And your wedding photos too.
Won't you be there at my wedding?
- Who's going to travel so far?
Sheena, you must!
- Just joking. Of course, I'll come.
I got to take a look at your groom.
Who knows what idiot she's marrying?
You dropped this.
What happened? Why are you
staring like that?
I have something to tell you Simran.
Go on.
I'm in love with you.
Just look at your face.
You thought I was saying the truth?
Strange Simran!
You've known me for so long...
and you still can't make me out?
Remember? I've never been serious.
All this love etc. is beyond me.
Still haven't been able to make out...
how some men spend a lifetime with one
girl! It's a world full of pretty women.
Someone has beautiful eyes, someone has
good lips, someone has nice hair...
You boys are all the same.
- But you're one up on all of us.
You're about to spend a lifetime
with someone you haven't even seen.
That must be true love.
Forget it. Think for a moment,
what if you're in love with someone?
I mean, imagine you're in love with
someone you've met on this trip...
why someone? Say you're in love
with me, and I'm in love with you too.
Then what will you do? Will you
go back to marry that stranger?
Or, will you have the courage
to have an affair with me?
What will you do?
I don't want to miss the train again.
- I want to miss it again and again.
What...?
- Nothing.
If she's in love with me,
she's going to turn around.
Turn.
Back in London. How a month
passed by, I didn't even notice.
Raj, you haven't given me your address.
I'll send you my wedding invitation.
You'll come, won't you?
No, I won't come
"What's come over..."
"my heart?"
"Have I lost it?"
"What's come over my heart?"
"Where have I lost it?"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"You didn't care to turn around..."
"but I was still waiting"
"By the time I wanted
to stop you..."
"you were too far away"
"What happened?
- I don't even know"
"Why is my heart...
- In love...?"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"Oh time! Stop, tarry..."
"go backwards"
"I've left myself behind..."
"at the crossroads of life"
"Where am I...?
- Where are you?"
"What is this...?
- Magic"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
"Darling, this is love"
"What's come over..."
"my heart?"
"My heart was with me always"
"Have I lost it?"
"I've lost it".
Ma, you remember the dream
I wrote about in my diary?
That face I imagined
holding in my hands?
The one, I wanted to face.
I've found him.
What...?
What are you saying, Simi?
- Yes Ma. When I was leaving...
I was clear about what
I was getting out of life.
For a month, I wanted to be as happy
as I could. Then I'd come back...
and go away to my country to spend
a lifetime with a stranger.
I had come to a compromise with my
destiny, Ma. But little did I know...
this was in store for me.
Like a storm he came...
and he swept me off
like a fallen leaf.
Love's like this, like that,
I had read, I had heard.
But I never understood. When, for the
first time, he offered me his hand...
I still didn't understand.
I was with him for so long...
still I didn't understand anything.
But today, when we were leaving each other...
for the first time I felt
that after this moment...
I'm not going to see him ever again.
I kept looking back. He was going away.
I wanted to stop him, I wanted to say
something, I wanted to hear something.
But he didn't stop. I understood.
This is what love is like.
And to him, I've given all my dreams.
I don't even know whether he loves me.
All I know is that for me, he's life.
I can never be anyone else's, Ma.
You're up? Simi and I
have been talking.
She's back after so long.
I even lost track of time.
I told you, not to betray my trust.
I took a promise from you.
And you've deceived me?
No Babuji...
- Listen, first ask her.
I don't want to listen to anything!
Pack. Tomorrow morning,
we leave for India.
For good.
Let her cry.
She has writ it on her own destiny.
She will have to learn for herself
how to get over it. Let her cry.
What's her name?
- Simran.
What girl, Pops?
The one whose face you see
in the moon.
I'm not one of them...
who will go crazy about a girl.
- Yes, I forgot!
Some have good lips, some have
beautiful eyes...
Lives where?
- Who, Pops?
This... Simran.
Don't know
- How is she?
Very lovable.
Then what's the problem?
Problem is, she's about to marry.
- How about stopping the wedding?
In your time, it was different.
Times have changed.
Love is still called "love". That has
never changed, nor will it ever change.
She's going to be someone else's.
- The bride goes to the man...
who brings her home. I didn't sire
you to play that fiddle. We aren't...
those who stare at the moon. You
reach out to the moon...
you bring her home. Go.
And come home only
with your bride. Get it?
Gone. The daughter is
getting married.
They've sold out and moved to Punjab.
I'm coming, Simran.
I'm coming
"When the girls go to the riverbank,
you'll hear their anklets chime"
"When the ripe mustard sways
in the farms..."
"you'll know a year
has come to pass"
"Come today, come with a smile,
bring me a song, I've been waiting..."
"for the whistle
of the chugging train"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your mate beckons"
"Come home o'wanderer"
"Your land beckons".
Bless me, Ma-ji.
No Ma-ji.
Son, 20 years I've held back
these tears.
Today, they won't stop, son.
Not today.
Simran, my child.
My baby doll.
How have you been?
- I haven't changed a bit!
You're the bride's aunt now!
Time to find a good groom for yourself.
Lajjo, I've been ready all these years!
But in this village...
there isn't one who's a match for me.
So what do I do? For me, I think...
it'll have to be a foreigner!
- You haven't changed a bit.
Not a bit!
You did keep us waiting.
Anyway, better late than never.
Wife, will you excuse us a moment?
- Get lost.
Come on. Baldev, who's this?
Go on...
You don't know?
My daughter Preeti.
Kuljit's sister.
- May you live long.
Wonderful, isn't it? In 20 years,
the whole generation has come of age.
She's beautiful.
- Father's daughter, right?
Get lost.
Where's Kuljit?
- Yes, where's Kuljit?
Bhaiyya (Brother) is out for a hunt.
He should be back soon.
My respects.
- May you live long, son.
That's a strong lad from Punjab.
- Whose son is he anyway?
Get lost.
Come, breakfast is ready.
- Yes hurry. I'm famished.
Come on kids.
For you, for you and for you.
You must take me out
tomorrow morning.
Sure Didi (Sister).
Kids, Grannie wants
everyone downstairs.
You know Simi, when I was a kid,
my father would tell me...
there's no difference between
man and woman. All have equal rights.
All my childhood, I lived believing
it's true. But as I grew up...
I realised what a lie that is.
I wasn't given an education,
because it was more important...
that my brothers be educated.
That was my first sacrifice.
Then, at every step, sometimes
as daughter, sometimes as sister...
sometimes as wife... I went on
sacrificing my own happiness.
But once you were born...
when I held you in my hands
for the first time...
I made a promise, never to let happen
to my daughter, what happened to me.
No more sacrifices at every step
as daughter, as sister, as wife.
So what if she's a girl?
She'd live her life as she wishes.
She'd have her share of happiness.
But I was wrong, Simran.
I had even forgotten that a woman
hasn't even the right to make promises.
She is born to be sacrificed for
their men. For their women...
men will never make sacrifices,
nor will they ever make sacrifices.
Therefore I, your mother, come to
take from you, your own happiness.
Forget him, my child. Forget. Because
your father won't care for your tears.
For the happiness of everyone...
I beg of you. Forget him, my child.
You're right, Ma.
So naive of me. I don't even know
whether he loves me.
And after all, Babuji is my father.
He has always cared for my happiness.
For the sake of his happiness,
can I not make this little sacrifice?
Go Ma, go and tell Babuji that
I'm ready for the wedding.
He won't have any problems
from my end.
Your girl is beautiful.
Not the girl. Kuljit is plain lucky.
And my name is Rajeshwari.
Miss Rajeshwari Singh.
If the little one is like this,
what will the older one be like?
I'll tell you, after the wedding.
Listen.
The day after tomorrow is the
engagement.
The wedding is on the 25th.
Sweets.
I'm worried about something.
I don't know why I see this
sadness in Simran's eyes.
Even her smile is hesitant.
Is everything all right?
It's nothing, Ma.
It's a new place, it's a change.
In a few days, she'll adjust.
Don't worry for nothing.
Here you are, kheer.
Simran hasn't forgotten him yet?
- She has agreed to get married.
By and by she will forget everything.
- If she remembers, she'll regret it
"When I saw you, I realised..."
"what madness love is"
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
"My eyes...
dream of you"
"My heart holds memories of you"
"Nothing's mine.
It's all yours"
"My life, my breath is yours"
"When I weep for you, your tears..."
"my sorrows begin to smile"
"I saw you, I realised..."
"what madness love is"
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
"I don't feel like anything"
"What do I say, what do I do?"
"In front of me...
just keep sitting"
"Just let me look at you"
"You called out to me,
and look, here I am"
"What greater than
the promise to love?"
"When I saw you, I realised..."
"what madness love is"
"I saw you, I realised..."
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms".
Take me away from here, Raj.
Take me away from here!
What...?
- You don't know...
what's going on in there!
Day after tomorrow is the engagement.
The wedding is after a fortnight.
All arrangements are in place.
Babuji gave his word to his friend.
And he lives by his word.
He can do anything, but he can't
go back on his word.
We have to run from here. We must!
- No Simran. I'm not eloping.
I haven't come here to steal you.
I might have been born in England.
But I am Hindustani. I've come here
to take you as my bride.
I'll take you only when
your Babuji gives me your hand.
You don't know my Babuji!
We have to get away from here, Raj.
Please Raj, take me away from here.
Do you love me?
- More than anyone else.
Do you trust me?
- More than I trust myself.
Then listen carefully to what
I'm going to say. From now on...
we're strangers. I don't know you
and you don't know me. Go back.
Let things happen as they're happening.
Leave the rest to me.
What I'm upto is daunting. But I have
complete faith in our love.
But alone... I cannot tread upon
this path.
You will have to be my strength.
You must co-operate. Tell me,
will you stand by me?
Remember one more thing.
I'm here only for your sake.
Till I have you for lifetime's
sakes, I am not leaving.
Listen, what's the name
of the one you're marrying?
Kuljit Singh.
Help!
Anybody here?
Somebody, help me!
Where's everyone? Help!
Anybody around?
Had Raj not arrived in the nick
of time, I would've been the prey.
Raj, I'm sold out!
- What are you saying?
- Where are you from?
I've never seen you before
- I'm from London.
Our guest from London!
What have you come here for?
- To achieve something.
To achieve what? Do tell us.
Land... land.
- Land...?
Yes, if I could find a good stretch
of land, I want to set up a factory.
Factory, making what?
- Beer.
Tell me something, Kuljit.
Will 8-10 million pounds...
be enough to set up a factory?
What happened?
- 8-10 million pounds?
Too less? I can get more.
- No! That's a lot. Enough.
God is great! He makes us meet.
We'll get along fine together.
You want to set up a factory?
As good as done.
Done, my man.
By the way Raj...
where are you staying?
- You see, I don't know anyone around.
So I'm putting up at
the Circuit House.
Strange! Now you know me.
I have a palatial house! And you'll
stay at the circuit house? No way!
Binda, go and get his luggage from
the circuit house. Drop it home.
What are you doing, Kuljit?
- Not a word.
You've saved my life, saved Kuljit!
Can't I do as much for you?
I know, you're from London.
Here in Punjab, we're lions.
You're going to enjoy yourselves.
- Well, if you're forcing me...
as you wish.
- That's like it!
What about babes?
We'll have a blast!
You haven't gone yet?
Go on Binda, hurry up.
Get a Black Label for Raj.
I'm going to have a scotch with Raj.
Show me a cigarette, man. Strange!
The lighter too.
You have done us a great favour
in saving Kuljit's life.
No, it was my duty.
- May you live long, son.
Preeti, give Raj some sweets.
Enough
10 million pounds! Why didn't
you tell me before?
I was about to...
- Raj! My son!
The sweets.
- I have some.
Let me feed you. That's like it!
You want to set up a factory, no?
We'll set it up for you.
- What was I telling you?
Get dressed fast. We're going
to Baldev's for lunch.
Who's Baldev?
- He's my friend, man!
His daughter is marrying my Kuljit.
What am I going to do over there?
- That's true. What will he do there?
But if you insist, I'll come along.
- That's like it!
Baldev is a bit British.
He'll mind it if we're late.
Let's make it on time.
- That's like it!
You get dressed fast. We're always
getting late because of you.
Kuljit, I have something to tell you.
- Don't worry about the factory.
I have...
I'll take all of it.
Compliments.
My compliments.
Listen...
- I...?
How did the shopkeeper get here?
I've seen you somewhere before.
- Not me. I never step out of the house.
In London...?
- But I haven't been beyond Ludhiana.
Have you met my friend Raj?
He has just arrived from London.
What are you saying?
- Balli, the doctor...
Raj is the one who saved
Kuljit's life yesterday.
You know who this is? The oldest
of my friends. My kinsman to-be.
What are you staring at?
Touch his feet.
My respects.
Hurry! The doctor has been
asking for you for ages.
This doctor is a wonderful fellow.
Come on, man.
Old foggie has quite a memory.
- What happened?
Nothing. This is great! Lovely house!
- I told you.
This is Raj. My friend.
He has come from London.
This is Simran.
Namaste, Simran-ji.
Were it not for him yesterday,
you and I wouldn't be here together.
What a thing to say...
Very glad to meet you, Ms Rajeshwari.
What is this?
- A little gift. For a little bride.
Mr Raj, folks I like
can call me Chutki.
And folks who like me,
call me Raj. Only Raj.
Namaste, Simran-ji.
- Namaste.
Come on now.
This is Raj, my British friend.
The one I told you about.
- My respects.
May you live long, son.
- Coming.
Have some.
- Thanks Ma-ji (Mother).
Let me do the rest for you.
- No, you belong to the groomspeople.
You're our guest.
- How strange of you.
A moment ago you called me your son.
The next moment, you disown me?
Allow me.
Just try this lassi. I made it with
my own hands! Here you are, Aunt.
Here you are Parjai-ji (Aunt).
This is for you, Aunt.
That's a lovely dress.
Excuse me...
After you.
Why are you taking all this trouble?
We kids can manage. Allow me.
That's what I've been saying all
along. But no one will listen to me.
I've been given all the work.
- That's my point.
Hey... who are you?
- I...? I'm Raj.
Raj, who...?
- Your son-in-law to-be.
Kuljit is your son-in-law to-be, no?
I'm his friend.
Darling boy! Put the glasses there.
- Sure.
Such a darling!
Today I see the best sign!
For the first time...
I'm seeing Simran laughing
with such mirth!
Give that to me.
- I won't.
True, Ma-ji. Simran looks
very cheerful.
Sweet? Salted?
Nothing's happening for Raj here!
Get ready to leave.
Son of an Englishman! Get up!
Hurry! We're going hunting.
Look at him
Aren't you coming? Get up.
I'm sick. I have high fever.
Caught such a chill last night,
I slept in my shoes, you know.
You're wearing only one shoe.
- That's the leg that caught the chill.
Sorry friend, I just can't
go hunting with you.
You British are so feeble.
I'll send medicines for you.
Make sure you're fine
by this evening.
We're having fowl for dinner.
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Hey Kuljit...
Come on Raj, get started.
What's this?
- Keep moving.
What's all this Raj?
- Wonderful thing happened today.
Met a minister on my way. Turns out
to be my Daddy's childhood friend.
He gave me all this. Let me take care
of that. Don't tire yourself.
I'm a lone fellow you know. What use
this sugar, rice and wheat for me?
So I thought I'd bring it over.
There's a wedding in the offing here.
Could be useful, no?
- Maybe so, son.
But we're the bridespeople.
Can't take anything from you.
Not again. Once and for all,
decide what you take me for.
Either you don't call me a son,
or you treat me like a son.
How do you treat sons?
- You don't argue with sons.
All right. I won't argue.
- That's like it.
Now listen to the real thing, Ma-ji.
My mother used to say...
one who helps out with a wedding,
gets a pretty bride.
All this, for a pretty bride?
- What else? Only lucky ones...
find good brides nowadays.
- What kind of a bride d'you want?
Say, someone like you.
Don't say that.
Give me your blessings.
Granted. You'll get a bride you want.
All right, I'm off.
- Will you please open this?
It's going to open.
Aunt, don't keep looking,
don't even think. Just take it.
Stuff like this is hard to find
even in Delhi or Bombay.
Just wear it and step out,
and you'll make the girls stare.
Don't even ask me about the boys
- It's nice.
Not special.
You show me that one.
- Okay. Here you are.
Superb stuff. Just take a look at
the borders. On you, resplendent.
Such bad ones! If you have
something special, show me.
I have to wear it for the wedding.
- Here you are.
This is for weddings. If you aren't
pleased, I'm no connoisseur.
Pure gold thread.
On you, looks exotic!
Don't talk rot! It's not that good.
Not that bad either.
I'll keep it.
Pack it. And put a good price.
You've worn me out.
Raj, let's have a song from you.
- I can't sing.
Coy like a girl? Sing.
- Oh no Grannie...
Sing... please.
I'm in love, why am I afraid?
I've loved,
I haven't stolen anything.
Why should I weep secretly?
I'll live for love,
I'll die for love.
What else have I to do?
- I'm in love, why am I afraid?
You've got your aim all wrong.
Forget it, you can't even sing.
The lover will carry his bride away.
The bridespeople will be left gaping.
What are you doing?
Everyone's out there! Let go!
On one condition.
- What?
Give me a kiss Senorita.
- Are you crazy?
One kiss
- Ma might see!
Let her see.
Chutki might see!
- Let her see.
Aunt might come by.
- Let her come.
This Babuji is going to
get me killed!
What are you wondering Baldev?
There's no countermove.
First time in 20 years,
I have you checkmated.
Good move, indeed.
This once l'm checkmated.
That's check. And mate.
- Wonderful!
Yes Babuji, I'm wonderful.
How did he checkmate?
No, I'll put it back.
- No, let me take a look.
What happened?
You know what's about
to happen tomorrow?
What?
Tomorrow, I'm going
to be engaged to Kuljit.
Tomorrow, Kuljit will put
a ring on this finger.
You know why the engagement ring
is worn on this finger?
Because the artery from this finger
leads straight to the heart.
I can't wear anyone else's ring
but yours, Raj.
If you want me to walk up in front
of everyone with a ring...
and put it on you, I'll do it.
No problem.
All this is a great joke for you,
isn't it? What I'm going through...
you can never imagine
- Look at me.
Look.
I feel everything Simran, the way
you're pining, your pain, your tears.
But why don't you understand?
This is just the beginning.
These people haven't even gotten
to know me properly.
I need more time, Simran.
And I need your support.
I want you to smile. And listen,
no son of a gun can take you...
away from me, using just a ring.
You're mine, only mine.
Chutki might wake up. Go away.
Listen.
Didi...
Can I say something?
- Go on.
I don't like this Kuljit one bit.
Don't marry him.
It's very late. Go to sleep.
Didi, I like the one
who was on the roof.
What did you say?
Didi, isn't Raj the one
you met in Europe?
Yes.
I like him a lot! You marry him.
- Don't you worry.
He's the one I'm marrying.
Yes Grannie?
- Pistachios for the sherbet.
Done.
Raj, where are the flowers?
- You put them beside the staircase.
Oh I forgot! Were it not for you,
everything would be topsy-turvy.
That's what I'm saying.
The lover will take his bride away.
Raj, weren't you with the
groomspeople? Have you switched...
over to the bridespeople?
- Someday I'll have a bride too, no?
Just putting in some practice. Get it?
- Never mind. Get lost.
Son of a gun.
Kuljit is so lucky!
- Really.
Now give her yours.
Simran, offer your hand.
Simran, put your hand out.
Come on.
What's this?
Last night, while taking off
my bangles, I hurt my finger.
Never mind. The other hand
"These girls are poison pills"
"These boys are rogues"
"Poison pills.
- Rogues"
"Make sure you're painted
with henna"
"Make sure the bride's palanquin
is ready"
"To take you away, o'beauty,
your lover is coming"
"Make sure you come with your face
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra"
"It's a matter of hearts.
Keep it in your heart"
"For a signal
from your flying tresses..."
"with bated breath,
the bachelors await your suit"
"The maidens will go into hiding
out of shame..."
"for these are all madmen from town
come to our village"
"Keep your eyes downcast;
keep yourself chaste"
"To take you away, o'beauty,
your lover is coming"
"I'm a young boy;
you're a pretty girl"
"If our hearts are swayed,
what's my crime?"
"You should've held your heart.
This beauty is magic"
"If the magic is working,
what's my crime?"
"Keep up for me,
leave the door ajar"
"To take you away, o'beauty,
your lover is coming"
"Say no more now,
do no more now"
"It's a matter of hearts.
Keep it in your heart"
"Make sure you're painted with henna;
make sure your palanquin is ready"
"Make sure you come with your face
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra"
"O'my precious one..."
"O'my precious one...
you know not..."
"you're still pretty,
and I'm still young"
"I could still die for you, my love"
"Make sure you're painted with henna;
make sure your palanquin is ready"
"Make sure you come with your face
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra".
Babuji, yesterday you were wonderful!
What a dance! Bested all the others.
No Babuji, just a speck of dirt.
Now it's clean.
Too few doves, don't you think?
The whites ones...
Iook... one, two, three.
No, maybe same like yesterday.
I've decided. Today I'm talking
it over with Raj.
Is it something to be ashamed of?
- Raj is here.
Back? So early?
Raj! My precious son! Come here.
We were just talking of you.
I've something important to tell you.
- Sure, go on.
This ought to be discussed by elders.
But since you're so close to us...
I thought, why not talk to you?
- Tell me.
I wish this friendship
to become a relationship.
Why not, why not?
- For my daughter, Preeti...
I seek your hand.
Raj! Better think up something fast!
Else, they have you trussed!
Raj, have you any objections?
- What...? Oh no. How could I?
My son!
- But I can't take...
such a big decision all by myself.
So you will have to talk to Pops.
Pops...?
- Father.
See? What a good boy!
- I never do anything...
against my father's wishes.
- No problem. Give me his number.
I'll talk to him over telephone.
He's away in America on business.
- Great! Gone to America!
Let ask him to come over.
- No problem.
My country, my soil, my Raj!
Here I come, son.
Step out of the country,
and you'll find everything...
but the matthri your wife serves up.
- Compliments, lady.
Neither the language, nor the culture.
For one who loves the Ganga...
what's a Thames? So I told Raj
to return only with his bride.
That's like it!
- Such conviction.
What do you do in London?
- Back in London...
London...?
- Forget London. All I know is...
Go East, go West,
Punjab is the best!
Son!
Don't you worry.
I've got it all tied up.
You don't even introduce me
to your Daddy.
What a wonder! Just this morning,
we were talking about him...
and I find him in the marketplace,
armed with a photo, asking about you.
Whatever anyone says, this marriage
was made in Heaven! Right, lady?
Right.
- Right...?
You're strange! You don't need
my permission for a good deed.
What do you mean no? Have I ever
refused you anything.
How about sweets?
Your son-in-law is waiting.
Right away!
- Go on!
The wedding must be done right away!
A good deed can't wait.
I was thinking of Kuljit and Raj
getting married at the same time.
What was that?
It's final!
- Raj, are you happy?
Give me a sweet! Quick!
My son is happy!
Now you're marrying Preeti.
Her brother is Kuljit...
the one who's about to marry Simran.
And you love Simran. Not Preeti.
What was Preeti doing in London?
- Not Preeti. In London, it was Simran.
Yes, Simran... who's this Simran?
- Pops! Just give up thinking! Please.
Can anything be done without
giving it a thought?
I'm here. Everything will be alright.
- By now, it's done already!
Wedding must be done right away!
Good deed can't wait! Why did you come?
It was a mistake! Won't happen again.
I'll tell them that I forgot...
about your mother's death
anniversary.
Matter laid to rest for a month.
May I come in?
- Sure, come right in.
You're going to live very long.
Raj and I were just talking of you.
Sit.
You sit too. Milk for me?
Thank you!
Tomorrow's Karwa Chauth.
- What's Karwa Chauth?
I'd like to keep fast for
Raj's well-being. May I...?
Sure, no problem!
- Karwa Chauth, Pops...?
Karwa Chauth...? No! Never!
Why...?
- We consider it a bad omen...
for a girl to observe the ritual
for her husband before her marriage.
Besides my child, we can't discuss
the liaison for a month.
It was during this month
that Raj's mother passed away.
We have to fix another date for the
wedding. Let's talk to your father.
Ajit...
Raj, you know what day
it is tomorrow?
What's it now?
- My first Karwa Chauth.
I want you to give me water and
food after my fast.
Hands off.
- What?
I told you. Hands off.
Simran, if you don't love me, just
tell me straight. I'll go away.
Then you can marry Kuljit. It's going
to save me this everyday melodrama.
Is it something I said?
- But you never say anything, no?
I want you to give me water and
feed me the first morsel...
of food after my fast.
Are you out of your mind? You expect
me to make a grand entry saying...
"Hi Simran! I'm your husband-to-be!
Here, take a drink of water".
I don't care!
I'll even die of hunger!
But the first drink of water,
and the first morsel of food...
you will feed me! Get it?
Just like her father.
So why should I be
the butt of the joke?
You're unique, Mr Malhotra.
Your dress doesn't indicate...
your affinity to Hindustan.
- The dress has fooled even you?
I keep Hindustan in my heart.
- Wonderful!
Wonderful...?
Ajit was saying you're here
to set up a factory?
The factory is just an excuse.
If you ask me the truth...
I'm here to choose a bride for Raj.
Then men are all out
in the outhouse.
They say, they don't want
to disturb us on Ladies' Day.
Are you keeping a fast too?
- Yes.
May you live long, my child.
My Kuljit is lucky to get...
a bride like you. Come.
Ma-ji, this is my Pops. Father.
Your son has cast a spell
over everyone here.
That's my son.
I'll join you.
Pops, this is...
- I know.
She can only be Simran.
May you live long.
No one even watches his step.
Hold this. The flowers...!
"Let it rain flowers!"
"My beloved is here".
Kammo, where are the flowers?
Hurry up.
I'm Raj's father. From London.
- From London...?
Actually from Bhatinda. But I've
been in London for many years. You?
I'm Simran's Aunt.
- You can't be!
What...?
- You could be her sister.
Listen... aren't you keeping fast?
- No. I'm still a maiden.
Nothing could've been better.
- What...?
One of your flowers.
- Maybe it's for you. Keep it.
When is the moon going to rise?
I'm starving.
I hope it kills you.
Did I ask you to fast?
Eat this on the sly.
No one's looking.
Don't.
The moon is up.
- Where?
There
"On this night of prayer
for the wedded woman..."
"I look at the moon,
I pray with folded hands"
"Then I break my fast"
"Give me the water, take your slave
for your queen"
"Tonight, give me what I desire"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your beloved beckons".
What happened?
- Water.
Simi, my child
- Drink water.
What happened? What happened to her?
- She swooned.
Get up. Come, my child.
What happened?
- It's all right. She just swooned.
It's nothing. Come on, let's eat.
She's so fragile, no?
Why are you anxious?
Are you fasting too?
No...
- Then come along.
It isn't easy for him to get away.
Everyone's asking for Raj all the time.
He won't be able to come, Didi.
Please, eat something.
I won't! I'd rather die starving.
- Very well, kill yourself.
I'm sorry, I'm late. But what to do?
They weren't about to leave me.
It was tough getting away.
Here, eat.
Eat it.
I said I'm sorry. Now eat.
Else, you'll swoon for real.
Chutki, tell him there's no need
for him to worry for me.
I was about to faint of hunger.
And there he was, filling his stomach.
Anyway, it's my first Karwa Chauth.
Why should he get so worked up?
Whether I live or die,
is he bothered?
You don't know this. But Raj hasn't
eaten anything all day either.
He wanted to break fast with you.
And he told me not to tell you.
Sorry Raj, but I couldn't
keep shut any longer.
Come here.
Talking to me?
- Come here.
I got carried away.
- No matter, Senorita.
In big places,
such small things happen.
My turn Senorita. Feed me.
I told you, not to betray my trust.
Simran hasn't forgotten him yet?
If she remembers,
she'll regret it.
What happened to me won't
happen to my daughter.
No more sacrifices at every step
as daughter, as sister, as wife.
She'll live life as she wishes.
She'll have her share of happiness.
Come in.
Keep this.
Ma, this...?
- Not a word! I know everything.
I've seen everything. Raj is the one
you met in Europe. I know.
I also know, the two of you
love each other dearly.
I was wrong Simran! My daughter
won't sacrifice her happiness.
She isn't going to sacrifice
her love.
I know Raj, you'll make my daughter
very happy. You have my blessings.
Take my daughter away.
Leave.
No one here cares for your love.
Take her away from here.
I'll take care of everything.
- No Ma-ji.
I don't want to hear anything! No!
Please go away from here!
I beg of you, son!
-I will Ma-ji. I'll take her away.
Come... sit here.
Keep this.
Ma-ji, I was a little boy
when my mother passed away.
But whatever I am today,
is because of her.
To this day I haven't forgotten
something she said. She'd say...
"Son, at every turn in life, you'll
find two roads. One right, one wrong"
"The wrong route will be easy, it
will draw you. But the right path..."
"will be hard, with lots of hazards,
a lot many troubles"
"On the wrong road, initially, you
might find success, happiness"
"But in the end, you will lose.
Upon the right path, initially..."
"you may trip at every step, you may
face hazards, difficulties.".
But... in the end,
you will always win".
Now you tell me, Ma-ji. Am I
on the right, or on the wrong?
Your way is absolutely right, son.
But you don't know my husband.
And Ma-ji, your husband
doesn't know me.
If I wanted to elope with Simran,
I could've done it already.
But I want to be given Simran.
I don't want to steal her.
I don't want to take her away
on the sly. I want to do it openly.
If I have come, I'll surely
carry my bride away.
But only when Babuji gives me
her hand, of his own volition.
Now Simran isn't your problem.
She's my headache.
As for you, you have given
your daughter away.
Just a matter of time now
before the bride is carried away.
Is this crying illness
in the genes?
How strange Uncle-ji! Tell me.
- The girl... what's her name...?
Yes Simran. I don't approve
of the match.
Why Uncle-ji?
- Girl's fine. But no match for you.
You're a strong young Jatt d'Punjab!
And this girl is frail, subdued.
Is this any match? Match for you
is a girl like a sparkler!
Just come with me to London.
The girls I'll introduce you to...
will drive you crazy!
What's the problem, Uncle-ji?
After the wedding, Simran stays here.
And we're going to be in London,
meeting your sparklers!
Pull out all the stops!
- You son of a gun.
As a little boy, I'd ride out to
the fields on my father's shoulders.
Ever since, I struck up a friendship
with these doves. I find it...
so peaceful out here.
I love spending time with the doves.
Tell me Babuji, are the doves here
different from the doves in London?
Difference there is. The doves here
know me, they recognise me.
They belong to my land.
Even the doves out there are alien.
Could it be that you perceive it
differently? Maybe a dove out there...
took to wings from here, from your
land... one who knows you...
one who recognises you.
Maybe you don't recognise him?
What happened?
What are you doing?
- My Ma used to say...
the soil of our land is very
powerful. It's going to be fine.
But this is outrageous!
Who might've done this?
Babuji, look.
Let's go.
- Babuji...
Are you still angry about
my beer act?
I was childish.
Won't you forgive me?
I forgot that long ago.
I was wrong about you.
You're right.
I didn't recognise.
Come, let's go.
Ma-ji, what is the matter?
You asked for me?
Son, whatever the doctor might say,
I know my time's up.
Speak of nice things, Ma-ji.
What a thing to say?
Not to be anxious. I'm of the age
when one leaves.
I've had a wonderful life.
Son, I have nothing to
complain about.
But now that I see Simran...
after years a desire
wells up in my heart.
I want to see Simran married.
Before she marries, I wish I don't...
- How can you talk of such things?
Listen son.
The bride's palanquin has just got
to cross over from one house to another.
Now that everyone is here, what
difference would it make if...
the wedding is pre-poned to tomorrow?
- Absolutely correct!
The wedding happens tomorrow.
Yes Baldev? Right tomorrow.
Yes Ma-ji. Tomorrow.
We will have to take Simran away
on the sly.
Nothing else is going to work.
Don't worry. I have it all worked out.
We're taking the morning train out.
I'll wait for you at the station.
Somehow or the other,
just get there with Simran.
Whatever happens next, we'll see.
Are you listening?
I know this isn't your way. You don't
want to take Simran away like this.
But son, it's too late now.
If you love her...
if you want to spend a lifetime with
her, you must elope. Understand?
Please Raj, take me away from here!
You don't know my Babuji!
We have to run from here. We must!
- I've come to take you as my bride.
I'll take you only when
your Babuji gives me your hand.
What is to happen tomorrow,
I don't know.
What I'm going to do tomorrow,
But you must trust me.
Whatever I do tomorrow,
is going to be for both of us.
Do you love me?
Do you trust me?
Then it's just a matter of time
before the bride is carried away, no?
"Oh heart's love"
"Oh my love"
"I give you..."
"to God to keep"
"So strange are the ways
of the world"
"The heart is crazed,
yet so helpless"
"What's left to be heard?
What's left to be said?"
"Just let it lie between us"
"The hide-n-seek is over.
I'm getting married"
"How I wish it doesn't kill you".
Simi, come down, quick! Time for
the ritual body-painting with henna
"Oh my love"
"Oh my Moon"
"You are my life..."
"my beloved".
I wanted to tell you.
You were right.
I failed to recognise.
You enter my house,
and before my family...
you play with my honour?
You have deceived me! You have
taken advantage of our trust!
You made a joke out of
our cordiality?
How dare you have an affair
with Simran?
Did you imagine you'd marry Simran?
You aren't even worthy of yourself.
How can you be worthy of Simran?
I was right about you.
Liars, wastrels like you never improve.
They only become worse.
No Babuji! No!
Didn't I tell you to take me away?
No one cares for our love!
Didn't I say, let's elope?
- No Simran, don't.
You can only run from strangers.
From the ones we call our own
Our elders are our parents.
All our lives, they've brought us up.
They gave us so much love.
About our lives, they can
decide better than we can.
We have no right to make them sad
for the sake of our happiness.
Babuji is right.
I am a liar, a cheat.
Even if I lied for your sake,
a lie is always a lie.
Babuji is right.
I'm not worthy of you.
And so what if I can see nothing
beyond you?
And so what if I can remember
no one but you?
Babuji is right. I'm a wastrel.
How did I think of marrying you?
So what if this wastrel
loves you like a madman?
Love isn't everything, is it?
Babuji is right, Simran.
Babuji is right.
Here you are Babuji.
Take your daughter.
I didn't come here
to break anyone's heart.
I just wanted to win hearts.
Maybe I fall short of expectations.
Maybe that's why
I couldn't win you over.
If you think Kuljit will make
Simran happier...
then you're right.
What's best for Simran,
you know best.
Forgive me.
Forgive me Preeti.
I know I have hurt you.
Where's Simran, Raj?
Raj, where is Simran?
She will come, Pops.
She'll come.
Babuji will bring her. Personally.
He will have to.
I wish to hear no more.
Go away from here.
Your son has deceived all of us.
He has shown us where he belongs.
I won't let my daughter marry a liar!
- Enough!
I am proud of my son.
Don't incite me to passion.
Kuljit and Raj are fighting
at the station.
We must go there!
One might kill the other!
Come on.
Come with me Simran.
Stop.
Let me go, Babuji!
Please let me go.
Raj means all my life!
Without him, I can't live.
Let me go to my Raj.
Please let me go to my Raj.
Go Simran.
No one can love you more than him.
Go my child. Go to your Raj.
Go on Simran.
Live your life.
Go my child, go
ln big places,
such small things happen.
The lover will carry his bride away.