* This subtitle is translated from sinhala .Thanks the guy from sinhala. *
Yashoda who got the logistical Please save conversion rights
Do know how many stars the sky.
Have you ever tried to count right?
From now on, prices start adding,
To count the stars in our galaxy, at least'll have at least 6,000 years.
If you ask how many such galaxies have?
Scientists say it is more like two billion or more that is right.
Therefore,
The stars in the universe at this ...
We live in any kind of a planet is ..
Like them, we look to the moon and Mars will be the world ...
They do not we find a topic to be here ...
Rajasthan - India
The thief was taken, the spacecraft is summoned to the machine
The remote controller can not go back to his house without him ..
He does not know our language ..
That his friend casts here.
Alone, helpless, he thought about just one thing .. SL
How can I go home now?
Life goes. I also following up.
New building new roads.
To go somewhere far away ..
Heart dreams ..
Who knew otherwise anticipated what was ... ..
Says the visitor will find ..
Touched my heart ..
I raise a smile .. .. හඬවයි
Sorry, but I'm the first hand earlier.
Oh, sorry, but I first have to ask .. After that you came.
I'm a big fan of Raleigh හරීවන්ෂ් Rai Bachchan.
But I am a big fan of Amitabh Bachchan.
I have read all the poems he's written since 10 years ..
From the age of five when I say that all of his dialogue, without ලියාගන්නෙත් ..
Who should decide exactly ..? .. She did not work for me.
100 euros.
40's tickets, 100 ...
B .. forgery sell? Since it took over 6 hours of queue is.
Time is money.
If you take no mess ..
Do not take yourself first female to be created anyway ..
Wait, what do you say, we have access to the Passport half half crazy?
Free time before you hear poetry ..
After free time, I see Amitabh sir .. please ..
It's nice idea!
10..20..30..40
50..6 ... - 96
There are 96.
We are not all the same .. .. .. small discount to a friend?
Bharatha Mother .. Cheers! Bro .. - .. u mother down! 100 euros.
Oh .. Euro 4 Can you lend?
The watch will come to you to keep your money back ..'ll give.
Oh .. Uncle, last ticket.
Boy, Full House .. what happened. Tickets will not bring back.
Got a hero .. selling forged tickets.
Shoving one.
He is like the name is ugly.
Boy, you stay here, I'll get you tickets.
THX.
Uncle ..
Who? - Who you ask? .. Where are my tickets?
B .. paper tickets?
Euro 100 million.
Thief they ve heard .. ..
Hide .. .. Liar liar.
- You're more than aware of. - Tell you shut my mouth ..
- Guards. - Now go look inside .. old man.
.. Go go go.
නාකියෝ .. I'll take care of you.
Go go go go. - Shoving the girl.
The control is not going to run right. Ll b ..
Today, when ..
The very strange for generations.
Just put it eliminated.
What was the last.
How did give up ..?
A good poem asks the guy sitting there. I'm from here .. - දාන්නකෝ eliminated.
Our memories are often hurt the moment .. why.
The future, we waved his hand.
We go forward with.
So .. you write me a little here and there.
That's good. Tell the rest from them.
.. Can not say the rest.
If the rest of you ..
Proposals will marry me.
Are you crazy b ..
Oh .. really .. did you like හරිවන්ෂ් Rai Bachchan.
Woman found in the morning ..
She sang the words of my poems ..
By evening she died.
I've read it. - Really.
If not. Twelve waiting ...
Birth trades.
Amitabh Bachchan.
Clenching.
Clenching ..
My name.
've Put a lot of long name father.
International holiday.
Everyone made fun of the school.
So I was short. - Clenching.
Located in Mumbai come ..
No delhi. Television production woodworking course.
- Are you? - I Architecture pick here. Also, additional to a job.
Here, the Pakistani embassy.
Why Pakistan Embassy ..?
What do you say .. I'm.
The Indian embassy is coming, do not you ..?
Whats happened ..?
.. No nothing.
And so, Pakistan ...
Smile was gone ..?
Well then .. God bless you.
My name without asking the village ..
Aside from the customs ..
Several steps, just a few steps ..
Come walk with me.
My name without asking the village ..
Aside from the customs ..
Several steps, just a few steps ..
Come walk with me.
Nothing gives us nothing unless .. ..
My hand ..
Several steps, just a few steps ..
Come walk with me.
Nothing gives us nothing unless .. ..
My hand ..
Several steps, just a few steps ..
Come walk with me.
If the sun's rays are blocked your way ..
I'll cover it ..
If you from the darkness threatening ..
I සරසන්නම් sky the moon ..
When feeling sad and funny .. ..
Add your mouth smiles ..
Buraq, a smile growing ...
We walk a few steps ..
Happy partner like you to meet ..
Who is afraid of the world ..
But only a few steps, the entire life ..
You will travel with ...
Nothing gives us hear ... nothing ..
My hand ..
Only a few steps a few steps .. ..
Walk with me ...
THX.
Mom, Dad ... ..
She has been in love.
Love has said.
He is so cute.
Where's the picture show.
Boy doing ..? Not a family all together, right ..?
Before calmly say. I tell you everything. - What are the name.
Sarfaraaz
Muslim personality?
Yes, Dad, architecture pick.
Family live in Pakistan.
Pakistan pakistan ... what?
Mom ... it's Pakistan.
.. If you're going to get dressed covered evolved your head b ..
Do not turn off. Do not move. Hold on. Go quickly.
Lord will be a catastrophe ...
To help.
.. I knew where I was going, Dad.
Ever since we saw the image of a little more than your parents ..
රූපේ lifestyle presides ....
Mom, I'll ...
School bag from home bathroom wall standing ..
Minor lifestyle was evident everywhere.
Good time for him to get lost. Not protect the tooth.
Minor lifestyle father was given a box of God.
It was the Lord of each task.
Dad, when stock transactions, Lakshmi computer screen showing.
Tres Mil one run, curl up in front of God pair.
Close eyes  Internet, linked Appearances, no sugar
All these things made for enabling lifestyle.
Clenching, lifestyle enjoyed begging, get blessings.
Why global holiday ...
Why make suicide ..
taken down.
O ...
Be impartial help ...
Ok.
Well ..
God ... what you say.
Look at the World Future .. holiday.
The Pakistani youth.
called.
you.
no kidding me.
Boy, bear witness to history.
These people, who do we turn to fraud possible.
The one you take advantage of the benefits.
Stand together with you. But not if you want to marry this guy. Am not find us.
Clenching you want to come home immediately.
You'd imagine so one night, our relationship is over.
Sahani, women
I'll talk with the children.
Son ...
Press the delete button.
And get him off your system.
Hello ...
Whats happened ..?
Do you love me?
Without .. I love that. Why do you ask? ..
Marry me?
But what happened ..? - Do not tell ඔව්ද සර්ෆරාස්.
Yes .. but .. - tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow we will get married.
තාපසතුමන්ගේ prophecy was wrong.
I will prove it.
Sir James හෙරික් bras and Ophrah Miss, you are next
James is not yet come.
Ah .. talk to the Registrar.
Can you keep a little Am ..
This is for you ..
I .. - Yes.
THX.
It sent a letter සර්ෆරාස්.
... I had not written anything else between marriage between two families.
Our countries, religions, people change everything.
Who gave their pain, how happy we live ..?
Do not try to contact me.
Oh sorry.
Where to go to the young lady ..
New Delhi.
After six months in New Delhi ..
I returned to my city ..
But my father did not place my home.
I got the news channel added.
Boss, stress being laid take-dog.
Go to breaking news.
Sometimes tuned.
Sometimes had to make some news.
Shelter do not know.
Has disappeared.
Contact the මුණගැහුනොත් Picquet.
The man, a good story.
You go to the office. I'll talk.
Good would come quickly.
Listen.
Why do you like this leaves divide ..
My case is not solved yet whimsical.
කරගන්නෙත් not contact me, do not meet ගැහෙන්නෙත්
My life has been destroyed.
Do not know what world you go to sit.
Have you ever got in there somewhere?
No.
Why are you wearing a helmet is ..? - Saw walking in darkness.
To know even from distant yellow.
Despite how hard bypass, far from the taxi to know.
- So? - So far so god who can find me.
Or, to know how much I was among the people?
Yes, to the left side. OK OK. Nice nice.
Background ..
Clenching right.
If the animals do not commit suicide is.
These requirements.
Delhi, Ramesh city for building the dog Sweetie.
He is last month, there have been suicide three times.
Jump off the roof to try, made to drink sleeping pills,
The gas fireplace made blow.
Why did Inspection ..
Inspection something like වැළඳිලාද mental illness?
Or Inspection ...
Clenching .. What happened?
So did this film නීතූ ..
We hope to talk more with the millionaire නතානිවාලා gold. It is the usual interval.
Wow. Drinking coffee ..
The husband brought coffee to b ...
Jerry .. ..
- Oh done. - What do you think the caller is depression b b .. ..?
Psychopathological conditions, schizophrenia can not control their own conditions.
What I guess what I have?
That's what others say ..?
So why do people like this makes no show.
Show what you are saying ..?
Come on. Am a little catch.
Look at this. Today, I met someone.
This leaves the road බෙද බෙද.
A man looking for God. - Tivo'd God ..?
- No.
God is not found in religion.
That's news to earn God's.
I get to meet God bring him ගැහුනොත්. I'll give him a program.
You know its procedure.
News about God and religion is not even. That's all.
What is wrong with you ..?
Is that why individual ago දඟලපු to former Revolution?
You're looking for the විප්ලවකාරයාවද?
Show? Look at this.
There are three signs here. Show ..?
They are not born spots.
Your father අදරණීය friend, that lifestyle is not it?
I have news program against him.
It was because of his devotees came to my ass holes.
From then on, I decided, is to live in this country ..
Do not mess with religion. That's all.
I have a program. You can go.
After the truce again, we were talking businessman with gold නතානිවාලා.
Find more about the story, do not ever given the opportunity.
But two weeks later, it came back to my life story.
... ... A thief thief thief.
Catch him. Ping steal money from the box.
Hey ... Where හොරෝ?
Catch him.
Get away.
Do you idiot .. stealing from God?
Pandit .. This is not a thief.
Grant money box when I ping my wallet fell through.
He's helped me get it all.
I'm telling the truth.
Check to see if you manage to. Wallet had Rs 5,000.
Pandit .. Those are mine.
Once, when he was named in his hands.
Now they are his.
Go to her.
You get up ..
What did the b .. The money was given back.
Money was no exploration work done. - No, no wait, guys.
I saw you first begin to get some money, and then put some money back.
I just buried here, 200, take the rest of the figure is put back.
Before you necklaces, rings, was not wearing it ..? - It's all up. They do not hit back.
This gets face stickers are you ..?
My security.
Picture walls repeat the loose, right?
Everyone does not get wet walls. I අලවාගත්තා here. And not one beat.
නීතූ .. where are you?
Oh yes, my hand did not have to go home.
I tell you what happened after.
I'm quite all, that is .. That is a temple.
Come quickly .. Thanks .. bye.
Take this. Keep.
What the ..? - This should go home.
The normal somebody could not go home.
My mind's not right.
The listen. - Not again. That's all I owned was
Can not. I can not take this.
That's because ..? ඕනනේ not you go home?
Not your money too.
Honestly, I ..
Do not make it home.
What the hell ..? Where do you live? ..
Usually are not,
... Boarding.
But these days, there rent or සැරයිනේ ..
So tonight I'm gonna release imprisoned.
.. Imprisoned?
You said the police imprisoned. - 122 of them here in Delhi's.
This is one. - Are They So you stay? Like a hotel.
Come on. I'll understand.
You're here to stay.
Hey, look at this idiot ...
I'll take care of you.
Clenching
You sit behind. That car to go along.
Who's car ..? - Our story.
Get your wallet. .. Need some pocket money.
Hurry නිතූ.
Thank you, bye.
Listen.
Say yes. - I want to go into the lock up.
What is it?
To meet that guy.
Ladies, you look like Hall restaurants this school?
Go inside to eat and drink tea, as much fun to go with friends.
This lock up.
Only someone who is able to go in error.
Ma'am, payoffs to ban.
So give prohibited.
Therefore, you can even put in. - Oh So දාන්නකෝ.
Thank you, Mr. Pandya. - Or just an hour.
Hi.
Want to know your story.
Tell me.
What is it?
I වාර්තාකාරිනියක් television. These are what I do.
Listen.
If they hear something like whisker.
So ..
What's your name? ..
I did not name.
But all she could talk to PK, PK.
What's the job?
අභ්යාවකාශගාමියෙක්.
අභ්යාවකාශගාමියෙක් ..
That means that the moon did අයනේ.
Moon miner .. do not work. Do not newsworthy.
OK .. not what's your favorite planet?
Our world. - Not good earth himself without it ..?
They came to this earth is කෙළවිලා ..?
I said in my world.
The normal night, that's up there in my house .. see.
ඉන්ඳැද්දී there .. we learned.
We also know there are more people world.
He sent me here, research.
But just got here.
I ran away, waved a remote control.
I do not leave home without a way to send remote control signals.
A signal coming, he visits one to take me a homeland.
They might think. It's a dangerous world that. I lived out here to die.
Hey ... Listen.
What ..? - Open the door a bit. I want to go home.
The ladies, we are determined to be someone out there that whirring going home.
Look I'm not a thief. - This is what is always steals.
Where Mr. Pandya? You talk to him. - Mr. Pandya go on patrol.
Pandya all.
- Pandya all. - Hey girl, shut up. Or give ear ..
You think I'm crazy, crazy to do ..?
Or else what?
Your planet බෝජ්පූරිද official language?
Our world ...
What did our first language in the world. Talk to your mind. No problem.
Here is one. Means another one.
This means that for four months ... ..
Says this is good .. that good.
Never mind everything else not so good
Big eyes told them,
Like wonder what that means ...
"Your mother accident ... good / right ...." Qur'an like.
.. When someone angry tone sound more.
"But ... but ... I come to teach"
Some thinking while continuing to paint word.
"But ......"
Pay attention to your feelings by preaching's young.
Then the point is that one can realize that.
Escape the chaos. I understand went to six hours.
It is learned completely බෝජ්පූරී're six hours. Nobody did not catch up.
One girl, who gave her support.
So I exchanged her to complete my move.
You're going to have a brain like that one laughing.
Making a false kind of stuff you have cherished.
Like an USB cable .. if your hands?
B transfer files to another computer is a computer ...?
And your clothes ..?
Like you are wearing a pair of your planet b ..
No no no .. .. Our world, our world who are not අඳින්නෙම clothes.
As soon as I got homesick, came here ..
Our world different from those of the skin, the skin here.
Some of the other co-equal bright .. කළුම black look.
Someone's skin color, cataracts another person a while.
He sticks the skin of her body .. someone hanging down.
Then one day I saw a car.
Dancing car.
As I understood, that is capable of and we're here.
The difference here is all they are wearing something that fashion over her body.
Then I realized how does the mix with here.
Oh, that is it, people are laughing.
After that, I understood little, men women විලාසිතාවනුයි විලාසිතාවනුයි to change.
One night .. one fashion style lunch.
One one hand playing style dining style ..
One of my clothes catch, a picture.
I went slowly realize, is that to live in this world to survive in the picture.
This brings the picture will eat.
So I started to collect pictures of this old man.
What man ...
Why do I have these ..?
What this book to my store.
B .. .... you have to take carrots.
I realize that this picture is only one nation that is useful paper.
The other does not make the paper.
The need for clothes like the car was able to complete with dancing.
He did the same to my bank, I had the same clothes were coming hard
Once it got kind of a strange uniform,
The suit, because that has no picture,
The food comes to their own kind.
Mr. take this.
I realized that if I find a remote control that other people in the world to learn the language.
Language can not or do not work here any.
Just like he could not say that even if Mr. style ..
I thought I was bad in his style that persists.
So I tried again, as you put it.
Am I met ඉන්ඳැද්දී down the road.
Am right to confront someone put some Douchebag go away.
If the mind is not as nice.
Nothing has not responded.
Deaf ears do not know.
The catch ........
Hear. No answers.
Firm's shot in the head like.
Memory lost.
Memory gone.
Do you remember who hits you?
Remember අංකේ car?
Remember what is right?
Let's brother.
Go with me.
As long as you come back to your memory of my guests.
Take your head nails ටොක said.
Head somewhere fought memory lose.
Also, you can head reminded fought right back.
Films that I've seen it.
If you want to know what this husband and I discovered that I need to work hand in his language exchange.
The name of the car is ...
Oh, I lost .. .. Ask men to know the difference forgot now ...?
Hold on a sec.
Look at my driver's license.
Gender.
Men. Man.
Anything.
If I go back in the house ..
Was definitely one that should catch someone's hand.
Mate, friend has had a colorful ..
He බලාවි at all strange men without changing ...
You've been hard for us ... boy.
Do not do it .. so ..
The boy has come true, my guest ..
The five-color dress are you wearing come from ..?
Where in Patna, where the පාටන් or පටියාලා complaints ..
You name of Shakespeare or something, brother ...
School Shakespeare write your name ..
Something not address the ration card පතකවත් .. ..
You come දෙබෑකරගෙනද sky or the ground split .. Are
You've been hard for us ... boy.
Do not do it .. so ..
The boy has come true, my guest ..
Lost your memory is good .. But this is not an argument ..
Somebody did not pay no transaction .. .. ණයකුත්
You are very pretty .. you innocent.
Do not do it .. so ..
The boy left the land of my guests have come true ..
My colorful guest has arrived ..
The boy jumps down to everyone ..
The boy had been a true visitor ..
I can understand your pain, brother.
But do not say openly hold hands.
Although beautiful red floor, it can be life threatening.
Brother, do not hurt you.
Go. We now.
You're here, whose corpse someone else right hand grips,
No one else do not think you come here, come on ...
It's a real place.
There are very nice. And pretty.
Everyone was willing to take me home, take my hand.
I've got many girls had a decent peace of mind.
පුල්ගඩියා.
පුල්ගඩියා, she did not take a honeymoon room.
පුල්ගඩියා a patient was sitting.
In the meantime, I ..
Over six hours ...
Took her to draw on in my body.
Progress of ... health ... X / J
I took everything that had pulled her inside.
The first path, useless Echo ..
Were you in love before the start ...?
Too.
Where are you ..?
I came from very far away.
You have not heard the name, I stay at.
But if we talk about how we talk.
Just what you have learned is ..
I spoke to his sister.
Hey .. your mother, sister glitch .. .. going to go from here.
Brother ..
Brother .. brother up.
Get brother.
Brother.
You're talking brother.
I want to help your brother.
What did මායාවක්ද b .. පුල්ගඩියා?
Go with me now.
This memory has a direct connection to something.
The point is to tell the doctor's brother.
Boil the mixture .. pill cure.
There is a very important job. Brother .. we'll go.
Stop here. Stop here.
Brother ..
This guy right here is my Marley was down.
I want .. I Male to Male.
It's very worth it? - Very much.
Listen brother.
The thief is in our own interest. But the message must Male Delhi.
Because it is so precious caught selling the chain neat.
So I go there, brother. - Where?
Delhi.
This one .. - .. why?
My remote control has been stolen.
Sven's b .. The two of their remote control to find the police who are b ..
It's not a TV remote control.
So of what? - I can not say that.
But it was fenced fixed elevation hanging neck. And it's worth much more.
Where did the theft .. - Neat as well.
She ...? One of the neat stolen ..
They come to Delhi to find b ..
But Delhi thief far. - So?
So where can you find cheats, then?
There are two million people in this city .. weird.
Police are men. Not without gods.
Only God can help you.
God hold two legs. Him means the only people able to help you.
Oh do know is how we know?
Oh know, here මකබෑවෙනවකෝ.
Have faith in the Son of God.
Who is god? I can say to help.
-Yes, He is asking questions and not recite ..
After what I saw, I was freaked out.
Those who know this world
Who made them ...
They themselves made them one place to be.
At least there are street street to his house.
Hundreds of thousands of people to their questions before he goes ..
He took everyone's problems and a small amount of solution.
He did not have this kind of a wonder of the world.
I could not believe you. Just thought I tried two or three times.
Let me know god.
20 .. 50 .. This is what this .. and worthy to it .. 100 500 .. Then it
What is the difference between the 20 to 50 drilling drilling?
- The size of the difference is no difference .. else. - And the 20's work is so deceptive ..
15 to Rs.
Lord, I am very hungry.
Give me something to eat.
I can not imagine anything happened.
The program argued that god.
Now I can go to my home.
I took a good remote.
I brought it back දෙන්නකෝ. I want to go home.
Know, this is it down to God battery.
It does not work then we went to a little work.
What do you mean ..? - I mean, to put a new battery put කොතෙන්ටද ...?
Do not put the battery call. - Then why this does not work ..?
Where this kind of damage happened. - I'm not going to do it no harm happened to work.
You're the God created ..?
Yes, from my hands.
God did not create you did God create you?
God created us all is that?
His sculptures we make it.
Why create his sculptures?
And we can offer to hold Him.
Tell Him about our joys and sorrows.
There have been installed communication device?
How do we hear God say?
God does not need communication.
Hear Him directly.
If you hear directly what the sculpture?
I do not understand what the man.
Trying to end our business, huh?
What is Your problem?
Conductor steal my remote control. I ask God ..
That's where I tell you.
B .. not a good head? - What does that mean?
Little to someone that you bear all know.
Thief Leaves can do the little legs ..?
Go inside temple. There was a big God.
Catch his bare feet. Run very fast.
The nuts, and some money to him. Your job will have.
200 gonna give you.
Everyone was waiting for their turn carrying swords and money.
To their work.
Two hours later, there was my turn.
Oh my god .. ..
Gosh .. Give me back my remote control.
B ... Where is it? - Move a bit.
Hold on my remote control not yet received.
This one .. She's not my job. I like money.
You're going to be your job. - When will b ..
Who can say that my son would one day? Your job is.
- We may දෙන්නකෝ. - But when my product is b ..
Do not clamp silence. Go ahead. - So if someone else then I went to my product?
- Sven's b .. - Hold on, ma'am. What are you doing ..?
But කොහෙන්ම I get my product .. - Will find a mental hospital.
How do huh? What money we paid, a mental hospital would go over, huh?
The man was pulled down. So give me the bill mean.
දෙන්නකෝ brother Bill. I asked the man what shows .. come to accept the product?
Go on. Please go. - But .. but my remote control.
I know .. coming, find two sandals.
Anyone wearing going.
You two will be wearing somebody else.
The temples are you doing anyway.
අයකරගත්තා full fees. But I did not have work.
Say his name.
Divinity (God) - say the full name.
Do not know the full name.
Where you live?
That's in front of the temples.
You gave her the money repaid?
No, put his charity box.
He'll say that your job? - He does not speak.
That's because ..? ගොළුවෙක්ද? - May be ...
Absolutely. - Right?
Tell her appearance.
This looks like.
But size is too large.
Come here Come here ... ..
Picquet you ..? (You're drunk?)
Yup. But you know how it all. - I think we're assholes b ..
20 years of police work from. Who can not tell who's gonna walk drunk.
ක්රිපාල් Singh, to search his.
Millicent is what? Give here.
Dr. ද'මෙලෝ.
Incomplete, so why drink to forget their difficulties?
Muses a church temple.
Go to your church.
Your God is near.
Church ..
.. Going to come out here. But my stuff.
Beat it. Going out.
Their sins because God put කුරුසෙට nailed.
කුරුසෙට nailed leave.
When? - 2000 years ago.
For their sins.
I think I deserve this? I came here alone.
They're drunk b ..
Yup. - God is watching. You're looking at how he behaves.
Where are? Where are? Where?
What does that cup? - Wine.
Wine ...
At that time, he took me to understand the thing.
Coconut water has been God ..
Now he's having fun with wine.
I can give wine.
So I started to collect money.
Found that some of the money from the car dance.
Found some more,
Every bridge on the stand who මනුස්සයාගෙන්.
Can take many would like someone.
Conductor, the storing of God itself matter? Yup. That is not forward.
Hold on.
ඕවායේ what happened? - Wine.
Give God. Where is?
This lady is very sad like.
So I thought to know that the hand hold.
A thing that someone hurt women widowed Asshole.
How do you know this guy who I'm a widow. - You've seen wearing a white saree b ..
Everything all right?
Very sorry about the death of your husband. - What? When?
How do I know when dead? You're wearing a white light.
Married to wear white matter. - No. මැරුණමයි wear white.
Dirge to wear black. මූසලයෝ. - Now you understand. Get out of here.
You දෙනාගෙම husband died three b ..
I'm coming here to live. You will ..
After eating, I understood why a lot of hurt,
One of the world is not
God, that many people.
Each is different and one way is legal wavered.
Is open to all companies that own god.
It is known that people doctrine.
There are separate briefings every manager ධර්මයකටම.
Everyone in this world to be, something one of nature ..
The company is one belongs.
It's God who is pursuing his own, not those of others.
I'm a member of what is now owned company?
Lord, how I hold sacred?
If you want to know about the remote control.
What are you doing?
Where are marked?
What sign?
That religion is marked.
How do you know what that company, owned this?
God, where does it run?
Guards.
It's getting hard to find out what happened to my religion.
Now you can do the same thing?
I hold sacred gods every governor ධර්මයකටම.
One of them will be right, my God.
I would like to hear the story.
The World තලයම rule that you heard ..
Listen to my case this my home so I come ..
My goodness ..
Whither are you ..?
Whither are you .. god ..?
You've heard that leads to lost heart ..
Who has been delayed lost ..
I come back to my house to tell ..
Whither are you .. god ..?
I hold sacred ..
Besides you day and night ..
You can find දෙවොලෙත් ..
Can not find the church ..
You have to find my tired eyes ...
I will do all customs properly ..
You meant the Tana were delayed නවමි head.
Whither are you .. god ..?
You have many names ..
You have many faces ..
You will find many ways to ..
I walked all the way to the ...
.. But you could not be found
I can not understand what you want ..
I think without trying to keep ..
I garrenty ගෞරවපූර්වකම what you want ...
My goodness ..
Whither are you ..?
Whither are you .. god ..?
My head is good mess.
I will have done something wrong,
This is my story you have not heard him.
Please call to tell me.
Show me the way.
Oh ..
I'm asking you, begging Him ..
I knelt down on his forehead revamped site will tell ..
ඝන්ටාරය sounds to you ඇහැරවන්නද,
If you call the loudspeaker,
Gita ශ්ලෝක read ..
If the Koran is right ..
Bible and read ..
You were one kind of Managers,
What is one to say ..
Says he sacrifices Monday ..
Another says he sacrifices Tuesday ..
Before I get to say the sun is food.
Then another man waded into the sun so do you.
Says he offered to hold cattle ..
Another person was killed, I tell them ..
Shoes go without saying a temple, another says to go to church wearing boots ..
This is Eve කෝවද right කෝවද wrong.
I do not understand anything.
Then the Lord came here probably.
I want to go home.
I do want to say is you.
Send me my house.
... Oh!
What to tell.
If someone is hiding
Something answer.
Please ..
Hey, why lock it .. Oh ..? - Does not go so today.
Yeah, you ඇරහන් door, and I now have to apply for the story ..
Shiva, destroyed the existing ..
No fear not.
Guard.
Who are you? - Do not recognize me?
I Picquet. (Drunk)
Guards.
B .. not one out there? People come to drink. I held වැසිකිළියෙද display.
Release the door.
I will bring my remote control.
What remote administrators b .. - I spacecraft remote control.
The spacecraft.
Did she forget .. I asked if once a b ..
I'm not a world, far from the world you come from.
This way you. Do you find my remote control? Then I can go home. You see.
Oh brother .. I go beating.
I have small children. - I know.
කාර්තිකුයි දෙවියොයිනේ genera. They're talking about a small difference.
They can live alone. My remote control and also to find out where to go.
Lord save me.
B .. god who are above you?
Where is ..?
Now that the Shiva dancing.
No fear. - බේරගනියෝ me.
බේරගනියෝ.
I Himalayas and mountains ..
Remembering that God was ධ්යානගතවයි.
Suddenly a light.
Great light of nowhere.
The light was raised, a small pointed down to earth.
I looked at it.
Remember that God is about.
It quickly became a relationship.
God. Come to me.
What is light?
The cold winter කඳුරකරයෙත් Heating feel makes plenty.
God said.
The god Shiva, drum break down priceless. This will bring.
It had taken appropriate to this shrine built there.
This is only appearance devotees,
All that pain out of.
Do you see it?
Shiva drum break down the part.
Bola Bola බෝලෝ බම් බම්.
බම් බම් Bola Bola thanks God ... Let බම් බම් ..
Do not stop, do not stop, let him come.
Come on, son, come on ...
Boy, you're not .. come here.
From here to say something to say.
බම් බම් appears. Thank God.
Where are you God?
Come on stage. I want to thank you Lord.
He is here.
I met Him toilet. My request for a product, run ago.
But I thought, I'll run.
But it is not, he took me back here.
My product goes, thank God, whether .. Thank God, whether ..
This is not a piece of Shiva displease God,
This one belongs to me. Accidentally sent optimistic.
Doubtful that displease have a piece of someone else.
Just ask him. Near the පාතම. If god came forward.
All right, I'll take it.
Oh .. I know it belongs.
Travelers dreaming ..
බැතිමතෙක්වත් මිථ්යාදෘෂ්ටිකයෙක්වත් not ..
If I say it ..
What I have come to the emulated ..
What kind of හැංඟි grandfathers playing this ..?
Go home with me, my friend ..
My heart wants a thing ..
Since when did you feel, you're someone else came to planet?
Listen ..
You had a mental doctor ගැහුනොත් met.
Now go ma'am.
500 is able to give so much punishment. Wait a minute.
This is my card.
Enlistments have written my number.
If you like, I can prepare you for a session.
And found time to talk to me. OK?
Thank you Mr. Pandya.
Do you think my story is not a lie.
That had not gone wrong දිවිනහගන්න බල්ලවම television show.
Inspection ....
It is your destiny.
Mr. Pandit, Mr. Pandya ..
I want to go back in two minutes.
What is going to fall threw the wine b ..
Do it. Take another 500 paper given මිනිහවම.
Inspection ... දිවිනහගන්න dog in ..
When you have time off, I did.
Do not say. - How do you know.
When you got my hand.
When he met someone who said you can shake me.
You were thinking, if this story went awry. My destiny is left is issued it.
Do not lie. I have to tell you about it. Tell the truth.
I'm not okay to lie නොනේ. Lying mouth.
Our world is so attracted to men holding hands ..
Where to hand. - I can not.
Where දෙන්නකෝ.
Boy, I need help. I swallowed hard enough.
Ask 1,000 people who are hospitalized for drugs.
Another Rs. 500 is not enough ...
If you can give 500 children, නෝනගේ my life ... - I'll. I'll.
Here's one. - If you give me your address written. I send money Curacao.
Uncle did not come to our house and money orders, you keep it.
Thanks son.
Uncle ..
Keep to 100. Go give it a try as a tip.
Boy, I'll come.
.. Saw AHMAzwar realized.
You can not read anyone's mind.
Do not you understand? A man took the money to fool you.
There is no hospital in the nearby foothills. - I know.
He and his wife take a meal to bring my five-star hotel.
Today, his wife of 75 th birthday.
Everyone 75 years and his wife were not at a five-star hotel.
A little at least one month to collect their pension from that little figure is making.
Wife to bring ice cream, it has to pay more than the thought homey.
The money is going to come here to mate නානකාමරේට.
Do please feel anything ..
නෝනේ our world do not lie.
You would imagine that.
Wait, wait, hold on.
Give it your hand.
Today birthday, happy to have an opportunity.
I told no lies one of our world.
The.UNHCR.helps.people.who.can did not .....
You do not tell anyone you know .. you පිටසක්වළයෙක්.
If I said I was in a laboratory put out.
Dalrymple's what's inside our බලාවි cut.
So why did I do?
On this one, I came from, everyone just took the money from me.
None of the money was not given.
You're the first one I put in the box for charity in 5000.
I felt inside, and I can not believe you're someone important.
I will find your remote control, PK
How's that?
This time do not tell.
But you must go back to your house.
That I promise you.
What will you like ඔරව ඔරව ..
At you.
පිටසක්වළයින් not come to my house every day.
Really .. it's your world, you hear everyone out of the way .. Which is?
The same. - Then there all walks nude.
Do not feel strange?
That music and naked.
It feel strange?
If'd wear looks strange.
PK
I did not sleep at night until lights.
How do you get a remote control තාපසතුමන්ගෙන් was thinking about that.
Hello. - Connect බුල්වීර්සිංව. Room No. 4
Wrong number.
Is not this ෆෝටීස් hospital?
Husband, you get a wrong number, you say I'm from yesterday.
How did the wrong number? I have stored phone number.
Okay, so what did?
Hello. - Connect බුල්වීර්සිංව. Room No. 4
Oh .. you said you'm late.
බල්වීර් Singh died this morning. - What do you mean ..?
How did the surgery haemorrhage die?
That sad fact is. But that does not matter.
Let's write a death certificate, a heart that. Not on a family name to be ugly.
So come on, OK, take the body.
Oh .... - right there, then bye.
Why do you say? Happy people.
Now he'll hospital. He saw how well their parents feel happy friend
His little fun lesser offenses since it?
Fun ..? - PK I was joking?
I understood. I saw the whole game. They're kidding.
තාපසතුමන් hard and call God,
This kind of head still is, God would appear.
All of it going wrong number.
A person who answered the call Him kidding.
Or how God, my remote control Laminating with his broken Drums existence itself?
Looks to me ..
Those who speak of God in this world with the telecommunications network, mess up.
Every call going the wrong number.
- What do you mean? - I always thought ..
Why do not fit into God's answer to our questions.
Mourning scroll down to come to my house to give it says.
Tell me. We are all children of God, right?
So what dad, tell their children ..
Scroll down everything will be fine if you give.
Have it your dad ever? Scroll down if you get my daughter to have a new outfit that she attends.
I do not always mommy milk.
The calls go to PK or lesser God
He is what process?
What is he? Say, every day millions of children are on the road in my sleep.
Let them drink milk. I am not from me mommy milk.
I'm sure someone who took us fun. Now that you like.
PK guy I thought was important lifestyle.
I did not have this issue to untie his head.
What would be a good idea came to my head.
PK's remote control back to a better kind of idea.
Who is the PK? - Who? Where is home? It does not do anything.
But he can not see anyone as we see in this world.
What does that mean? - Means ..
You see, he smokes, police spoke to say, you're trying to දිවිනහගන්න
What is it? - Pack has more hit one, that smoking is cancer.
What do you think?
War.
I would like to face the joys of PK with තාපසතුමන්.
They want to talk about the other show on television.
Evaluation is looking more ඉන්ඳැද්දී values.
Clenching already back to my right side, there are three signs.
But it has brought you to the left, both sides are balanced, what?
No Jerry, what's most important in this war is not fought with PK තාපසතුමන්.
He will explain to him in love, he does not go to God's call that number is incorrect.
තාපසතුමන්ට can not imagine how we want to deal with is the PK.
Jerry, Jerry.
That are sitting out there. See once met.
I challenge you, you will not answer his questions. Trust me.
Know, this is your hand down. - Oh, thank you.
This is not mine.
කාමසූත්ර ස්ට්රොබෙරි taste.
I'm sick of strawberries, ask me? අහනවකෝ others.
Madam, this is yours? - What do you unsuccessful?
Just check your wallet. Do not lose the mall. Who are they, shoving one.
Uncle, this is yours, then? - No, I was not.
PK It has done.
It's come to ask anything about her.
Come in.
What is this?
Give condoms.
What is this? - Blows are controlled population.
How's that? - There it is dressed.
Add up with someone else sexually cases.
How are you this ඇඳගත්තම world population is?
I'm not ඇඳගත්තාම.
Millions of people wear those things. - All these and get yours?
Everybody's got those things.
I have this problem. Listen, PK, to ask a question.
Money from the pockets of the people fall down, they all take it in my rush to do it my.
But you're in all cases උපත්පාලන mine that I was not afraid to run.
This is, adding that sex is a private matter.
What is it? -'ve Entered the world just do not want to say, today I am going to have sex together.
But then married ..
Crackers made, the orchestra players to teams ..
Why is everybody city, today I going to have sex together.
What's this?
I do not have an answer to your question.
But I have a job for you near.
Let's go, this guy before change your mind.
තාපසතුමෝ careful to keep their booty,
Now my turn.
PK තාපසතුමන් here every day pilgrims meet you there. They're talking about God.
We go in, give ear to listen to his phone calls.
You start to do something even if the other side, you have to be submitted soon.
It has to realize that his phone calls තාපසතුමන්ට going the wrong number.
That would be obliterated, he returned my remote control?
He තේරුනොත් someone kidding him that, he'll understand that part of the one that displease fell.
He returned Devi your remote control. - Yes, I do understand him.
Built a house for someone who is meritorious.
God will build a house is meritorious.
The length of her arm, but to donate.
Do we get rid of their suffering.
Tell Carols. Because what you are affected ..
තාපසතුමනි,
My wife is six months from the paralysis.
Doctors ඔසවව්වා hand. I could easily ..
O ..
Be resort.
Too.
Tell God Hour.
Where?
God of your choice.
Have heard රෝහ්තන්ග් glaciers? - No.
Himalayas are. Go to සෙනෙගුඩි train.
From there, the bus ..
රැන්ග්ටොප් from ..
Foot boat from there ..
8 days to be ...
God's divine House warmly ගන්චන් චන්ඟාගේ seen ...
.. Going to go with mother loved.
Wrong number, it wrong number.
What is?
Wrong number.
තාපසතුමනි, God spoke to you the use of technology to break up ..
Everyone's going to call you .. Incorrect
From there you call to get stolen .. kidding.
What are you trying to say?
I understand that we all God's children, right?
So yes. - So, what do you get your child to you for your help ?.
Does he carry out justice? Or tell him ..
4000 km away from my house there are some that come ..
Submit this problem again in detail. Then I'll answer.
If this was a real call to God, he says, his wife, son .. Even if,
.. I do not care to find why she walks will.
I always come to one dead,
Now, she says to spend time with. Ah .. I do not listen?
I can prove it, someone took a joke for you.
තාපසතුමනි, you get to hear him call once again ..
Can you be sure that you are sick aunt ..
Uncle, written guarantee trades, do not leave your aunt.
See අමතලා you, can you find out.
තාපසතුමන් take lunch time came,
තාපසතුමනි, that thief ..
Jewel told my handheld remote ..
A liar ..
Liar, liar .. ..
God does not see a spurt received until now no ordinary mud.
God does what we expect ..
We say, God Manager.
PK Many important issues presented. - What is? -
Managers call God has spoken to go?
No. - Because we think it makes,
The call will be answered, God is If con is about.
They're the wrong numbers. - So tell us, PK How can people like this situation?
The call to the right person and miles,
Joined together to find answers to their questions. Need to help each other.
PK Tell a story so much. Well, as long as we can connect with God කළමනාකාරවරුන්ට God
We do not look to their aid. We'll help each other.
PK says not to build the temple.
The gem that belongs to him to tell. - What is in your pocket?
Do you smoking?
Yes drink. - Drug-hop drink, right?
Yes, occasionally drink from. - You're a smoker. Drink alcohol.
But knowing that both the poison.
The government gives permission.
Factory produced from the poison.
The shops are open poison sale. And one question will not come.
But God Rama generated latest ..
This is a sacred site to build a temple of God born Krishna obsessed ready ..
Why are these questions as?
If you want to question, go ask greater ..
Try to stop building the temple.
Who is the PK? Khan did not exactly lateral.
If you did not send sequence is lowered.
Sorry, you need to SGR ..
Listen to go from that PK is to ask questions.
What's his religion?
What's his religion, his religion?
In came a long time ago, මෙහෙමූද් Gasnawa ...
Put our temples destroyed.
Today, there came another history to be remembered.
Yes, but ...
තාපසතුමෝ, little that you get a call from God. I want to know Him religion voyage,
First, he believes his religion arbitrary, we know what the children ..
What the hell are you doing here b ..? - OK, here you speak drove number.
Listen .. I do not know what it wants to hear from God. I can say it.
The Hindu man, the Catholic, the Sikh warrior, one of the Jains,
And this guy is your nation ..
If you were told their names තාපසතුමන්ට.
Hello, my name .. සුක්වින්දර් Singh Powell.
අස්සලාම් American directors, my name is Ali Abbas යාකූබ්.
Cheers .. I have great Veer Jain.
Hi. I'm Christopher D. Souza.
Citizens have a .. I Jagath holiday.
Now you understand the job ..
I was transferred to the bad. Yakutia.JPG your right?
Buddhism is determined fashion.
I know everything. Come on. I'll show you.
A beard, ජටාවයි. Sikh man.
ජටාව ගැලෙව්වාම Hindu.
ගැලවුනාම mustache Muslim.
The change was designed, that number belongs to the wrong god fake.
If god is right, what is karma body marks belong to. Have doubtful marked body?
Maybe? - What are turned back again? See you there removed the clothes.
Why be shy?
Removed all of his clothes, තාපසතුමන්ට show signs that religion is what they have done.
Why be shy? ගලවන්නම්කෝ me right. Hold question.
Look at this.
Have marked huh?
Is there? Coming, replaced ..
B have a sign?
Hey .. put this man out.
What is this, huh? I'm going to prove it?
Gaot cast eyes.
Clenching.
The jokes stopped.
You're born 40 days, you get a name තාපසතුමන් When you hips.
.. Can remember the name of your partner.
The name is not to say it can.
Dad, the name given to the World holiday.
Do not do it again? - They?
How much money themselves want, huh?
Money trying to scare you into තාපසතුමන්ව huh?
- No. - They පිළිස්සේවි hell fire. Protest worry about his emotions.
THX. THX. Father. THX.
I had බාගෙටයි වැටහිලා. You understand and gave everything.
This fear has been playing. The one that we were wrong to be treated, not just kidding.
He's taking over our fear exploited. Do you understand?
PK Can you understand what you saw my father?
Yup. I can understand you. I can prove it.
Let's go.
I do not have time to spend on this nonsense.
Dad, this is nonsense, if I stop the program.
Papa, College weird place. Students here are pretty scared.
Now I'm afraid to use to business here. I'll show you.
Go.
This is the factory machine.
So initially invested.
Now officially start.
Now wait. 15 minutes to double investments.
Look. Look.
He was arrested.
Hot hot tea. - Look man selling tea,
How invested. Green tea, sugar, water, glass, anything.
There is ගලකුයි red, green තිලකයකුයි.
Hot tea, hot tea.
There are customers out there who could bring that guy.
And there, consumers are unable to එලවගන්න.
Alright, come on. You'll have the rest of the pilgrims.
There will bow down in front of the customer.
Here the customer in front of the stone, washed down shakes.
More people got scared ගාගෙනම belly shakes.
The business man speaking lesser offenses. Afraid to do business.
Afraid of going to the temple of gaining one.
You're pretty scared. These are removed from it.
Not a question about religion.
It's something to believe in.
God does not like people questioning ..
He argued that we do not allow you to ask why.
The use of resources, the buyers, attacked and could not answer.
Afraid to, mouths shut. Still, we do not shut up.
Until now the only one who questioned the PK, PK from today, thousands of questions will light.
So guys, .. take up their phones
We heard that something was wrong in their detect low numbers, we have to send the cases recorded.
Our station will broadcast what you're recording.
Telephone hands, to question.
Baba, Baba ... ..
If there is one thing that can make gold wind .. your ..
Why does not end poverty in our country, b ..
Now to answer.
If you manage to make gold
What is to aid us? Answer.
Om writes. Om writes.
The wrong number. The wrong number.
Clenching .. go with me.
Come with me.
Come in.
Then we work.
Greatest country that sends the wrong numbers.
If you did a terrible job.
Look now.
He says, getting a job in this bull කැව්වාම grass.
The cow in my curriculum vitae b .. Do not even get companies?
Or biological data on monster.com note published?
This number deadline. - There is more. There is more.
He's saying, Christian, be. If you go to hell.
If Christian, God wants me, I became උපද්දවනවනේ Christian family.
Now why does not switch religion. Again, wrong number.
Everybody who wants to go to school.
If schools are girls, I'll shoot.
Our God is so low one can be.
The children learn enough to be angry about. Again, wrong number.
That is what our book is written.
He created the whole universe is like a plan.
If you want to accept it. - Outside the temple Rs. At least 10 book sales.
I have a page four. Read all members.
And will have a son.
This is a guy who, Rs. 10 a book ..
That plan is to destroy okay.
PK Your program has been quite popular. SMS around the world is coming.
Look, another one.
Whats happened?
Father arrived a short message.
ලැජ්ජයිලු him about his daughter.
Know?
I was ten years old ...
First, write a poem.
For my father.
Everyone says I look like my mother ..
Everyone is real.
But I'm my father's daughter ..
I was told this poem ..
Everyone got clap.
The populations amid applause, someone started to play very loud whistling.
Applause end up hitting one,
One said, by not නැවැතුනේ.
It's my dad.
He was very proud of me.
But the message sent today ..
I would be embarrassed.
Your father's shoulders,
The bad has happened අංකේ walks.
It feels wrong number laid off the day,
He thrash so much whistling, no one stopped.
The day will never come no PK
Do not worry, where up.
Come up, you know what to do with our world to commit sad?
What is PK? - To me.
Batteries will automatically charge. - What is PK?
I do the same thing. - Picquet.
What we are doing PK?
- Close your eyes. - How do you take care of what වහගත්තොත් eyes?
And never mind, eyes and wait.
.. You continue to wait at
Read hear your stay ...
Forget also benefit from ...
When you come right ..
This waste of time ..
Love is a waste of time ..
But when I looked back inside, thinking ..
Once in this life ..
Ate away the time ..
Time to eat away ..
I want to devour the time ..
I'd like to eat at this time ...
Several times the mirror will look ..
Many times will make hair ..
Threw need to change clothes ..
Big bottles of perfume will be embalmed ..
This is the sister realized .. wasting time and love that ..
Think again looked into the heart ..
Once in this life ..
Devour time ..
Time should be eaten ..
I want to devour the time ..
I'd eat up time ..
Heart strange strange thoughts come ..
And what does this tell whether they feel that if ..
Sitting, sitting as the greatest laughter ..
I do not understand what it is ..
I cried ඉගිලෙන්නට mind ..
This is the time to get Sister Love .. Massey said ..
Think again looked ඇතුළිත් heart ..
The life of this once ..
Devour time ..
Time should be eaten ..
I want to devour the time ..
I'd like to put time consuming ..
Questions have come over to the charity money box.
Doubtful pictures, books, medicines oil has stopped selling everything.
මුහුණුපොතට also account for a very negative views are expressed tweet happened.
- 35 million. - It came to them while your appeal.
There are shouted at them.
What if you were good.
One can no longer be shut due to our disadvantage.
Talk to him.
She's not a lot of questions?
I ask him one question asking.
- Hey Clenching. - What?
What happened?
තාපසතුමන්ට wants to be a part of our program.
He wants to talk with PK.
That's great. PK Devi job. - It would be amazing work schedule.
You're ready to PK. නීතු you start advertising.
Do not forget. "One more question?"
O'clock Sunday afternoon.
So our boy has a star b. The බලහල්ලා, my friend has a star.
Again .. walked naked naked.
I did ඕකව star.
Television is well seated.
.. This shit, I do not newsworthy village Simone sit down to drink alcohol with an idiot like you.
A big star ..
When the star. Ha ha ..
PK Rajinikanth Singh that he had to speak.
- Rajinikanth ... - Get There.
- Brother. - Oh, boy.
So .. if you got a star?
- Where are you brother .. brother. - This is the time of the MRS.
Will come to your downtown. Get a present from coming back.
I'm gravely who steals your remote control.
He sold your product at 40,000.
Who would listen to you? - To whom?
තාපසතුමන්ට.
God said ..
The god Shiva priceless Berets broke down.
It had taken a suitable house built.
.. .. This is because only appearance
Hi .. .. whats happened?
Who steals my remote ...
Holding. - What?
Really? - Brother as saying ..
තාපසතුමන්ට thief is given a remote control.
The game is already so තාපසතුමන්ගේ.
Horace's go take her home.
Let's go, you get a moment jerky remote control gives us. We'll get stolen or television before.
තාපසතුමන්ට have not got my remote control in the Himalayas apartment.
It is තාපසතුමන් lies.
That means ..
God does not call the wrong fake ...
තාපසතුමාමයි.
Clenching that you know?
Remember when you first told about the PK wrong numbers?
තාපසතුමන් God calls ..
Everything going wrong number.
I immediately realized that you're misunderstanding.
But I did not untie your mess. If you told තාපසතුමන්ට liar, everybody would have laughed at you.
People want to do something new every day.
It's the wrong number.
They are deeply touched talk about your wrong number.
They always have with you today. - This is the wrong number.
My plan worked, PK. Imagine that you have the remote control.
But ..
If you go here.
Gonna go ..
Never owned one impressed.
A missing friend ..
I would remind you, too.
Stop?
How it stop?
I really say.
Has more work. Others can share everything.
You can stay here.
If someone wants to pay me a time to meet ගැහේවිනේ.
To marry him. I do not ask ..?
Who can I marry you?
Why is that?
Your trouble is starved to introduce you to go.
This is my husband.
She's PK (Drunk)
That's not my name. Basically all I did. Ridiculous.
PK (Drunk ..) - I changed my name.
Something you name ...
Proposed testimony. To you ..
I feel ..හොඳයි name. - Look.
The person's name and his පෞර්ෂ්යත්වය ..
To fit. - Yes, he's right.
So .. how my පෞර්ෂ්යත්වය? - I have a little පෙන්නන්නම්කෝ.
I have හාත්රසී Kaka ..
The name and image, the difference ..
I do not want to hear poetry. Let me say something else.
Damn. How do understand him?
Got another name ..
Behave another way ..
Fire has completely cooled ..
Thank you very much're great .. There is a lot of work there is one.
You choose any name. If you have a good look inside.
ඩන්ග්රූ ටට්ටේ Ram.
Indeed, no secrets.
Oh .. multinational Singh.
සර්ෆරාස්.
See, they are more good there.
Clenching What happened?
Nothing.
How brother ..
One terrorist organization has claimed responsibility for the attack.
They say this is only one small attack.
This is what happens to those who attacked us.
We will defend our God.
Where PK?
Program. - No, do not want to go.
Must go.
"One more question."
This special program, all your welcome.
When you connect to the PK .. .. - Hold.
Wait a bit.
Where to.
What is this?
God is a ..
His drum break down a ..
Okay ..
It belongs to him.
God is ..
Temples to create.
Okay ..
Temples to get it done. Mean that we are asking ..?
God .. that thing?
Or .. thing is this guy?
Wearing a yellow helmet, the green Sudan.Even.
To see. To see.
Said first ..
God never find it.
Then he asked God a liar.
Tomorrow should say ..
God has died.
Boy, what do you expect?
I do not have a world of God?
To you ..
Understand people's feelings?
Some people do not eat bread.
Some head no roof.
People do not talk to a friend.
How many lives that day නහගන්නවාද you know?
Buds take off. Fan hanging die.
Why is that? Because if they do not hope to live.
God came forward ..
Tilak is kept forehead ..
ගැටගහගත්තාම hand thread ..
If we want to live in them, they do it ..
Who are you to seize?
And ..
The hard and tried to corrupt people say ..
Instead, do what you tell them.
Every day you read this the wrong number .. .. wrong number.
We tell everyone, you tell me what the correct number.
Exactly what you say තාපසතුමනි.
At one time, was ..
I could not find food to eat.
I was not home.
I cried a lot.
I let this one coming, friends.
I only had one of ...
God ...
I always thought that would be good tomorrow.
What is the right way to point to God.
I accept.
Faith in God that spending ..
Hope for the heart.
The difficulties that befell .. courageous, heart gives strength.
But I have one question.
I want to believe in God, and how.
You say that God'm drilling.
I do not say ..
There are two ..
One was the one who created us all.
The other one is the one made by you.
We do not know anything about the man made us all.
But you're the one who made ..
You seem entirely.
Pretend play act,
Giving false promises.
Rich ones soon meet you there.
Letting the poor people there.
When praised happy.
People are afraid to even word for word.
I have the right number is very simple.
We are all made in God count ..
Put faith.
And you made that fake god ..
Get it done.
You hand, because our God ..
I'm gonna shut up and wait I think ..
Boy, we know how to protect our God.
You can protect God ..?
You ..?
The world is very small.
In the world there is a big difference in the universe.
You're a little world, a little safer, a little street, so sit ..
I made Him to protect the universe ..
Him you do not care.
Him can protect themselves.
Today, one of my friends died because he tried to make his දෙවියන්වආරක්ෂා ...
I was just left her the shoe.
Stop trying to defend God.
Or in the world ..
People will not only save up shoes.
One Muslim bomb blast ..
Hindu man ..
Sitting here asking your speech.
Well .. - Who's Who Hindu and Muslim ..
Where is marked show.
The difference was not like you were God.
And it is ..
The world's most dangerous, wrong number.
More than anything serious wrong number.
Most people would die. Apart from each other.
The wrong number, you ..
ජග්ගූගේ ඔළුටත් to enter, සර්ෆරාස්ව allocated to him.
What hotline wrong? - සර්ෆරාස් to entice her ..
Who said that Muslims are hypocrites ..
So .. he is deceived her.
It's not a lie.
Hold on. What is this ..?
- Look. - You wait here.
You're saying ..
I said in the prophecy සර්ෆරාස් ..
True?
Yes, that's what I say.
So to prove. I want to prove that the sentences.
If you can not prove ..
You have to forgive me, my foot slipped feet to the beginning ..
And I must admit in front of everybody, you know, I was raised an ..
I offer unless .. - Do not PK.
That would be my son, it's yours.
Agree to the conditions.
If you have to be turned towards the camera UN holiday.
International holiday .. I hope that,
I would have said you are asking about things.
Belgium and you've been in love with Pakistani boy.
Really? Or false?
Why is there talk about my personal life?
Friday day ..
I told one of the potential sentence to twenty minutes to three point .. After
The boy that you රවට්ටාවි.
The next day,
Did you get married
But boy did not come.
Really? Or false?
Yes, he did not is, please stop this?
Now ...
You come to my foot waterfall? I'm not where you are?
සර්ෆරාස් not tricked you.
This is just going to put PK. Please. - No, tell everyone what happened that day.
Please PK. - Only once.
For me.
I was put in the marriage.
I got a letter. - සර්ෆරාස්ද take it from?
No.
The hand of a little boy was sent. - Was the letter was written a name?
So how do you think it sent a letter සර්ෆරාස්.
It is ...
Another girl, boy you can be sent a letter?
There were not other girls?
Former girl was carrying a cat, right?
He is holding your hand gave you love this?
අඳුනනවාද child taken from you a letter?
No. - අඳුනනවාද him to you?
No. - So how did he know ..
Do you want to give a letter.
Sent a letter to his daughter one ..
Cat person stay ..
I go to the letter.
He gave you a letter.
You read it.
Then you did not ඇමතුමක්වත් සර්ෆරාස්ට phones.
සර්ෆරාස්ට spoke to existence?
It did this lifestyle ..
It's your head that did enter the wrong number.
Muslims who are deceivers.
Clenching සර්ෆරාස් not tricked you.
What's going on here b ..
.. .. Cats to dogs in the heart when the heart speaks about hell,
I want to stay here since they are listening, b ..
Do we know now htaccess. Clenching, සර්ෆරාස්ට phone call away.
Clenching Hurry,
"If you do not use the requested number."
Something else right number? Friend, college, somebody does not matter.
Clenching say.
Belgian university.
Hello.
Hello, I need to contact your student graduating from the University.
සර්ෆරාස් Yusuf. - He went to Pakistan last year.
You can ask for the number.
Number can connect him to leave? Sorry, the information you give us will not be allowed.
Ma'am, it's very important. - E-mail request to you. I can look at the team's student affairs.
You have a nice day.
Pakistan's number? His home number? - No.
Clenching think, think.
I have a half-time job to Pakistan Embassy.
Part-time job that she Pakistan Embassy.
නීතූ, Pakistan's ambassador to Belgium, to the office.
On loudspeakers to call here.
Hello! Pakistan Embassy.
Hello.
Did the student working there came from Lahore?
Yusuf සර්ෆරාස් it. - Your name ජග්ගූද?
Hello, your name ජග්ගූද?
Well, how do you know?
That call came.
That call came from Delhi girl phones. ජග්ගූගෙන් call came.
Come on everyone. ජග්ගූගෙන් call came.
India got a call, come all.
Ma'am,
We talk every morning from 9.00 සර්ෆරාස් Yousuf in Lahore.
By far, the only one asking the question with respect us ..
I call someone to come Clenching India.
We are not told him, he got the phone.
We knocked everyone crazy.
You hang in there, I'll contact him.
Hello.
සර්ෆරාස් Yusuf, sir - yes, hello!
Where are you supposed to do this?
The Lahore from, and why?
When you're talking sense into this?
I'm in my house, and why?
Your storing, chair or something you can sit there?
If there is, please sit down. - If you are going to drop the worst bout.
Oh sorry. I do not understand what is said.
You delhi call came.
Now to talk with him.
Hello. - සර්ෆරාස්.
Clenching.
Hello.
Hello, you're not Clenching?
You came from the registration of marriage then? - Yes arrived.
When you go there, but I am.
Why did not I ඇමතුමක්වත්?
How to do? I got your letter.
It was written, I do not try to contact me.
I knew you would have affected family.
But is it .. Oh Clenching, I thought ..
Do you ever do will try to contact me.
You got a lot of time Clenching, talk.
What to do?
Your wrong number, but I have.
Now is a friend, got right number.
Thank you, son.
You're not අල්ලගන්නකෝ.
PK're going to take the battery b ..
There are not on him.
But so are you going to keep a lot of battery do?
The tape recordings of these has been quiet.
I ask them. Then, later on. - What's the time?
That everyone in the world ...
Animals, music and traffic noise.
You're gonna go to the traffic noise and hear.
Adding to remind all world of ..
Go there and pick one asks.
The Wait ..!
Download other items I have.
PK will open.
How about to happen? ඒකෙත් battery is full.
Listen ...
Which is right out of your world as you listen to everyone?
Then there all walks nude?
Do you have a place to stay?
Know?
I was ten year.
My first poem le'mon.
It is written for the father.
Everyone says I look like my mother.
Everyone is real.
Poetry that is ..
Ensuring sound a few big story.
You're so cute.
A friend is one of the more ..
සද්දයක්වත් raven ..
There was no traffic සද්දයක්වත් been recorded.
Every sound clip was just my voice.
It was found.
I was very දුවවව්වා.
PK has been recording what mom?
I mean, Kaputu noise, traffic congestion, noise and hear.
Earth seems sometimes ..
I listen to the piano.
From there, you waved his hand, said.
Fast ..
Cristina wave you hand ..
Get the time ..
Millicent has not on record my voice would not it?
Will see ...
B .. put him.
You say that rhyme, have it.
It is the only poem?
I love කරනවායැ ..
I totally devoted to waste thinking about you ..
He did not back any one time.
Sometimes a glitch in his tears හංඟගන්න.
He did something about position ..
It also teaches something ..
Learned to lie.
Was taught ..
Love is the word meaning.
"I would love to be able to go too."
The world as children come ..
She is naked here today.
Like a lot of kids asking questions ..
Also asked a lot of questions.
Then one day ..
Go away.
We want them very far ..
The way I was given a very nice gift.
සර්ෆරාස්.
And my father.
පීවත් is long ..
He's in every night and look at the star ..
Waved his hand.
Sure ..
It also makes.
I miss him.
After a year ...
We are brothers and sisters .. one hour disembark Earth.
Do not forget that I'm given. Have four points.
First, banned from walking naked on Earth.
They do u kiss මනං ..
Every one who is naked here හැංඟිලයි.
Trees that raise everything else is open.
Second, the big issue here is the language.
You would then ask කඩමණ්ඩියකදී,
I love chickens, fish .. I love you ..
Not much to say here, that means those animals.
It means that, today, the chickens eat, or one that will take fish.
They think about the difference between what we say and what research is.
Third, we need to collect clothes from the car down, quit walking and dancing.
You put everyone in their underwear kicked remote control.
Nobody steals failed to hit the nail.
Fourth, and most important point.
Needing to meet someone who can connect to God ගැහුනොත්,
Left side of the research, on the other side of the back, you can come back fast.
Brothers go. Oh, do not worry.
What will keep ඔරව ඔරව huh?
I have a question. - What is?
When the time came before you,
Were you how to eat cheeks roads?
Why these?
Self. B .. safety? - Yup.
Go. - Go.
Where are you going? මෙහේටයි go.
| Created by prashanth |
* * Yashoda warrant
*This is translated subtitle from sinhala*
*Thanks the guy from sinhala*