There is a meadow..
in my perfect world.
Where wind..
dances the branches of the tree...
... casting leopards spots of light
across the face of pond.
The tree stands tall...
and.. grand and alone,
... shading the world beneath it.
There will come a day when I rest
against its spine...
... and look out over a valley where
the sun warms, but never burns.
I will watch leaves turn..
Green, then amber,
then crimson.
Then no
leaves at all...
But the tree will not die.
For in this place,
winter never comes...
It is here,
in the cradle of all I hold dear,
... I guard every memory of
you.
And when I find myself frozen in
the mud of the real
... far from
your loving eyes...
... I will return to
this place, close mine,...
... and take solace in the simple
perfection of knowing you.
Subtitled by Clarity.
Did you see Wyman's sheep dogs near
the flock?
Nope.
Told me he had six dogs watching
over it.
No. I am not to tell you..
I got a call from Tribal Police,
chief was asking for you.
There was a mountain lion working through
the flocks east of Boulder Flats.
You'd think folks would realize this
isn't sheep country.
Yeah, tore up a horse and some weanlings
too.
That sounds like wolves.
Chief says it's a cat, and they
ain't had no luck getting it.
I'll give him a call.
Yeah. Drop those off at Fish and Game.
Hey.
- You got blood on your shirt..
- Just getting for work..
Who was the victim today?
Looks like it's gonna be me.
Want some coffee?
Sure...
Great.
So, I gotta go to the Rez tomorrow,.
thought I'd take Casey by
to see your folks..
Something killed a yearling in the pasture
behind their house.
Yeah... That's why I'm going.
Don't let Casey out of your sight
on the Rez, okay?
Like I said, I'm gonna leave him
with your folks while I scout.
- You know what I mean.
- Yeah, I do. I won't.
- Case.
- Dad?
- Come on, bun... time to go.
- Okay, I am coming.
Whoa, whoa, whoa..!
Where is your bb gun
pointing at right now?
- Come here, come down here.
- Sorry, Dad.
Hey, where's the rule bud?
Okay, guns are always loaded,
even if it ain't.. Right?
Okay, come on buddy.
Put that in the truck. Hurry up.
- Okay.
- Don't run.
- I'll be back Monday afternoon.
- Okay.
I don't need him to be missing school
to go chasing coyotes with you.
Yeah.. alright.
Is this it?
- No, no. Let him, let him.
- Yeah. I know.
He's still learning to
do things for himself.
I agreed, but I've stood here..
as long as I need to stand here.
Thanks for the coffee.
Good luck on that interview in Jackson.
Yeah.
Take Togwotee Pass.
And don't go through Pinedale.
This storm's coming
from the south so...
Yeah, you can drag me through
Pinedale with a rope.
Okay?
Well, good luck.
You hear that?
Cause it's hungry.
Chats on boys.
- You okay?
- Fine.
Gotta push his nose back
when he rubs it on you like that.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Look.
Told'ya I'd get that hat dirty..
They got the height advantage
on me is the deal..
Is that right?
Let's fix that. Come on.
- Close the gate for me, would you?
- Okay.
Hey zed.
- You want zed to be your horse, don't you?
- Yeah.
You are gonna have to prove it. Not to me,
you gotta prove it to him.
Come over here.
You gotta earn his respect from him.
When you do that,
he would be standing on your ground.
Who's got the height advantage now?
Who's got the height advantage?
Just back him up.
Gentle.. so you chose you not to be.
Take him around.
That's it. Press her up by his foots.
Keep on going.
There you go.
You show him who's boss.
You are side passing over this way?
There you go.
Keep coming.
Back him up.
Look at that.
Atta boy.
How about that?
Good job come over here.
Put your hand upon his nose.
Let him smell you and breath you.
Let him know you.
He will love you forever.
- Hey.. so what do you think of that, son?
- That was pretty cowboy, huh..
No, son.
That was Arapahoe.
Entering Wind River,
Indian Reservation
Hey, grandson.
Grandma's making you fried bread.
- Had breakfast?
- Just eggs.
Go ahead. Get you some.
- Horses sense a storm.. huh?
- Yeah.
So.. Police chief called you
to hunt the lion, eh?
He called me to hunt something.
Heard you
lost a steer?
Yeah, I'll show you where.
It's a lion.
- Is the right?
- Come on.
- How Wilma?
- She got a job interview.
Jackson, some hotel I think.
- Jackson Hole?
- Ya.
Gonna live with the millionaires, eh?
Haven't heard about that, I think..
..the billionaires chased out
the millionaires years ago.
Ah, save your money.
When the wolves start eating
their Golden Retrievers...
...that land's gonna go
for pennies on the dollar.
Yes sir.
Tell me what that is.
That's a lion alright?
There's two.
Three.
She's got both of last
year's kits with her..
They chased your steer around for a while,
it seems.
That's what the tracks say..
Momma's teaching her kits how to hunt.
she's teaching 'em on livestock.
Mother just got her
whole family killed.
Got gas in your slate?
I need emergency assistance.
Repeat. Emergency assistance
requested... Come back?
Fremont County Sheriff's office.
What's your location?
The Wind River Indian Reservation,
east of Boulder Flats.
FBI's taking a while, eh?
Eh..and the road out of Riverton's bad.
I don't want to move her
until they have a look.
but I'm not gonna try to pull
her out after dark.
We gotta get
this show on the road.
We're losing the tracks.. Ben.
Now, it is coming down pretty good.
Should let me follow 'em while I
still can.
Can't let you do that.
Until it's all cleaned by the FBI.
Called her folks yet?
No, I want to take the body to Lander.
I know, it looks like Natalie, but...
It's Natalie.
There's your Feds.
What are these fools doing?
- Can't see the road..
- We don't have time for this.
I'll get 'em.
- Your destination is on the left.
- Where?
Turn left.
Where do you want me to turn left?
FBI?
Are you Tribal Police?
No, I am here to take you to him.
- Look very close. Just follow me, ok?
- Yeah.
I'm Jane Banner.
- You're by yourself?
- Yeah, it's just me.
I'm Ben Shoyo,
I'm the Indian Tribal police chief.
He's Cory Lambert,
with Fish and Wildlife.
He's the one who found the body.
And this is his father-in-law,
Dan.
He don't do nothing.
We got the same job eh?
I'm sorry to meet under these circumstances.
So. Do You wanna
show me the body?
I don't mean to be rude, but I'm
freezing my ass up here, so...
The quicker the better.
Yeah, that's gonna get a lot worse
if you go out there dressed like that.
I'm a big girl, thank you.
Body's 5 miles on a snowmobile.
You'd be dead by the time we
got there.
I got the call when
I was in the court in Riverton.
So this is.. this is what I've got.
You should have a winter-gear bag
in that truck.
No, it's not a government vehicle,
it's a rental, actually I'm from Vegas.
So I'm just the closest agent
to the scene...
You don't think I
can make it..?
- You're from Vegas?
- No, I'm not from Vegas,
I'm stationed there.
I'm from Fort Lauderdale.
Sorry, if we're gonna keep
having this conversation...
Let's get you fixed up inside.
It's gonna be great - Thanks.
Sorry excuse me. Thanks.
See what they send us?
Thermals can make underwear wedge
up your bottom,
but I guess yours
are already there.
Here, these should fit.
You're skinny.
Thank you.
- You got gloves?
- No.
Goodness. What were they thinking
sending you here?
Thank you.
You bring them back the minute you're done.
They ain't a gift.
- You hear me?
- Yes, of course.
Hey.
I'm... bundled.
Let's go.
Okay.
Hey, buddy.
I'm gonna need a couple more hours,
for work.
A couple.
This is our day.
I promise.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Hang with Grandpa.
- Sweeten up. Let's go.
God, there was blizzard
here 20 minutes ago.
Comes in waves. Could be sunny for an hour.
Then you're right back in hell again.
Storm will come back.
- That's something to look forward to.
- Yeah.
Over here.
- You Got a positive ID?
- Not positive, no.
Natalie Hanson.
We'll call that positive for now.
Does she lives close by?
Yeah, Fort Wakashie.
- North a ways.
- What's a ways'?
About a 30 minutes drive.
Ok, well, she didn't run from home then.
She's frozen solid.
No one reported her missing?
Her parents?
No.
Yeah, that's why we called you.
How experienced is your medical examiner?
Just to say... He stays busy.
Order a rape kit,
When he's done with his prelim,
I want her body sent to Lovelind.
Make sure her belongings
go with her... they need to get tested too.
I'm listing this as a homicide.
How well do you know this land?
Like it's my job. Which it is.
Well is there anywhere she could be
running from? Is there anything close by?
Nearest houses..
3.5 miles from here southeast.
- Sam Little feathers place is over there..
- Yep.
Those boys could use some
serious looking into.
There's no structures closer?
There are drill rigs five miles from here..
They got trailers for the workers., but...
That's closed for the winter.
So why would a teenage girl be out here?
Well kids come out here on their
snow machines.
And have a big party in the snow.
Not barefoot.. they don't.
- What do you think?
- I know what the tracks say.
- Okay, That's all we got.
- Come here, I'll show you.
Come right here. See this one..
See how the toes turned out?
..the front is much deeper than the back.
That says she was running.
Come here, let me show you.
She ran until she dropped.. here.
See the pool of blood
where her face hit the snow.?
Now it gets twenty below here
at night.
So if you fill your lungs up
with that cold air.
when you're running..
it could freeze em up.
Your lungs fill up with blood,
you start coughing it up
So.. wherever she came from,
she ran all the way here.
Her lungs burst here.
She curled up in that tree line
drowned up in her own blood.
How far do you think someone
can run barefoot out here?
Oh.. I don't know.
How to gauge someone's will to live...
... especially in these conditions?
But I knew that girl.
She was a fighter.
So no matter how far you think she ran...
... I can guarantee you she ran farther.
I got to get back to my son.
Hey, um.. Would you be willing to help me?
I can't.. I couldn't find the way
back to my car if I drive.
I really don't know how
to investigate this in...
Hey.. Can I borrow him for a few days?
What? He doesn't work for me.
You got a lion to kill, don't forget.
There's three o 'em. And I didn't.
Sorry.. what is it..
what is it that you to again?
- Hunter.
- You are a lion hunter?
I hunt predators.
Good. Why don't you
come hunt one for me then?
Okay.
Dad?
Hey, bud.
You happen to can't sleep?
I had a nightmare.
Is that right?
What is it about?
Who was she?
Come over here.
- Want some milk?
- No.
She's a girl
who's lost her way in the snow.. that's all.
What's all this?
That's work buddy.
Did she die like Emily?
She died in the cold.
So she died like Emily?
Yes, so...
I'm afraid she did.
I am sorry.
- I see you found town okay.
- Yeah.. barely.
Do the family identified the body?
Yeah.
Did they give you a reason for
not reporting her missing?
Well she stayed with a boyfriend some...
didn't think anything of it.
She was eighteen.
Free to do what she wanted.
Have you done this before?
- Observed an autopsy?
- Yeah?
Ah.. no.
Anyone who tells you it gets easy
is a goddamn liar.
Let's get
it over with.
Okay Randy, you're on the clock.
I've got about five minutes of this with me,
so let's go.
I'll be quick
Good morning, Randy Whitehurst,
the medical examiner.
- I'm Agent Banner.
- She's FBI.
Thank you, yes. I'm FBI.
- This your first autopsy?
- Yes.
Hey, gotta have a first.
Yes, it's my first on an investigation,
but... I am trained for this, so..
- if we can just get to this. Please.
- Yes, ma'am.
As you see here, she suffered a deep
laceration along her brow line.
Two separated ribs.
Frost bite in
both feet up through her ankles.
Circumstances is your field, not mine.
- Let me show you.
- No I don't need it explained
I need to find whoever...
... chased her to death in this
snow and put him in prison.
and not calling it...
Sorry.
This is very prosecutable
as a murder..
Clearly she wouldn't have been
running through the snow
if she hadn't been attacked,
but I can't list the cause
of death as a homicide.
And I can't get an FBI team
to the reservation...
... unless it's listed as a homicide.
I'm not here to solve this..
I'm here to obtain a
cause of death...
... and send a team here that can.
Look, present the rape, present the
assault and I'm sure...
Those aren't under
the jurisdiction of the FBI.
Those fall to the Bureau of Indian Affairs.
Sorry.
You keep saying sorry,
but you keep doing it.
Don't look at me.
Hey, I'm used to no help.
You have six officers on your
entire force...
... to cover an area
the size of Rhode Island.
Yes I know that.
No offense, but this will have to curl
up in your lap in order for you to solve it.
- I know that too.
- We all know it's a murder.
You can have a US attorney to sign off on it
I'm happy to corroborate that,
But I just can't put it
on the death certificate.
Okay.
Thank you.
I appreciate your passion.
It's not the Fed's usual response.
But Randy is on our side
My supervisor sees this report,
he's gonna want me back in Vegas.
Not that I'm much help or anything..
... but I'm all you've got.
Hey.. What's that
hunter's phone number?
Ya?
So you never met him.
No
- And she never talked about him?
- Not to me.
Why would you let your daughter stay with a
guy that you've never met?
whose name you don't even know.?
Cause I look around, I see your photos...
- She was an adult..
- Barely.
Wyuksa psi wasichu.
- What does that mean?
- It ain't good.
Um.. look.
I don't mean to offend you.
I'm trying to understand the dynamic here,
Mr. Hanson
I'm trying to help.
Why is it whenever you people try
to help, it starts with insults.
I don't know why she didn't tell me.
But she was eighteen.
And I chose to trust her..
I chose wrong.
Ok. Well.. um how about your wife,
did your daughter talk to her?
- Do you talk to your mother?
- Her name is Annie? Is she here?
- She's in the bedroom..
- I'd like to speak to her.
Be my guest.
Thank you.
Bedroom's just this way?
- Jane.
- yeah?
You don't mind, right?
Hey, you don't need my permission.
You're an adult.
Barely..
I'm really sorry.
Hey.
I'd like to tell you it gets
easier...
... doesn't.
If there's
any comfort...
...it's getting used to the pain I suppose.
I went to a grief seminar in Casper.
You know that?
Don't know why...
I just wanted the bad to go away.
Wanted answers
to questions that couldn't be answered.
The counselor came up to me
after the seminar.. sat down next to me.
He said something that stuck with me.
I don't know of it's what he said.
Or it's how he said...
He says, "I got some good news
and I got some bad news."
The bad news is
you're never gonna be the same.
"You'll never be whole. Not ever again."
You lost your daughter.
Nothing's ever going to replace that.
"The good news is
as soon as you accept that...
... and you let yourself suffer. "
"You'll allow yourself
to visit her in your mind."
"You remember all the love that she gave."
"All the joy she knew."
The point is, Martin
you can't steer from the pain.
If you do
you'll rob yourself.
You'll rob yourself of every memory of her.
Every last one.
From the first step...
to her last smile.
You kill 'em all.
Just take the pain, Martin.
Do you hear me? You take it.
It's the only way to keep her with you.
I'm just tired, Cory.
I'm just.. so tired
of fighting this life.
What you do now you is for your boy.
Drugs is his family now.
He's gone too.
Lives right down the damn
road, but it's...
He's gone.
I expect they'll find he's involved
in this somehow.
He is staying with the Little feather
boys, that it?
Yeah.
You're driving this Fed around
so she don't get lost, is that it?
They asked me to do,
Not what I'm doing.
What are you doing?
I'm a hunter.. Martin.
What do you think I'm doing?
If you find out who did this...
I don't care who it is.
You understand me?
Right where they stand.
Then get off my porch
and go do it.
Natalie's brother lives here with
Sam and Bart Little feather.
And a real piece of work named Frank Walker.
Hanson's kid is bad... but
the others are stone evil.
So.. watch yourself.
Shouldn't we just..
maybe wait for some backup?
Well, this ain't the land of back-up, Jane.
This is the land of you're on your own.
Listen to this shit.
Ya?
We are looking for Chip Hanson. He around?
- Not here, brah..
- Who are you?
Who the fuck are you?
I'm the FBI, dickhead.
Are you Sam?
No.
You high right now Sam?
How many times have I arrested you?
- Chief, wazzup Brah?
- Where's your brother?
- He's in prison. Where you put him..
- What no parole?
Look at that,
the justice system at work.
Reminds me, my PO told me to give you some..
- Wait, I got it, I got it right here.
- Wait.. Let me see your hands!
Cory watch the back!
Fuck!
Heros have always killed cowboys.
The other two's outside with Cory.
Let's go.
He's still alive.
We need to call EMS.
EMS is an hour away.
- Just leave him.
- He's not dead, Ben.
Like I said.
Let's go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Skinny one's Natalie's brother..
- Who's the other one?
That is Frank Walker.
Won't your daddy be proud?
- My dad's in prison, asshole..
- I know, I put him there.
Tell me what happened to your sister, Chip.
What?
- Don't play dumb.
- About what? What happened to her?
What that cracker do?
What crackers?
Was she seeing a white guy?
Do you know him?
- Do you know who he is?
- Do you know his name, Chip?
You said was.
Why did you say
was?
Why would she say was?
She just said was.
Because I found her raped and
killed right over there, son.
That's why.
No...
What?
No!
You go. I'm going to get
Chip over to Lander.
See if he give me the
name of this boyfriend.
I tell you..this is how we find him?
No. We go to where he works or
where he lives.
Yeah.. where does he work
where does he live.
You think this asshole's
gonna tell you anything? I don't.
Look, I know you're looking for clues,
but you're missing all the signs.
Come here, let me show you.
See this here?
This is snow track.. right?
- Okay.
- Is he out here on the ridge?
Here... use these.
Okay.
- You see at the end of the ridge here?
- Where?
- Follow my hand. Can you see my hand?
- Hand's all I can see.
When I take it away.. now look.
- You see that? You see the shadow there?
- I think so.
Snow's starting to cover.
Look up at the base of the mountain.
There you see. Go up the ridge there.
You'll see it a lot of easy there.
You see the tracks go up..
that mountain there?
- Yes, I see it.
- Alright.
Now his body was found just past there.
But someone unloaded the sledge right here,
to go all the way out there.
There is no tracks coming back. Why's that?
I'm telling you.
The answer is out there.
Hey look... um..
I don't know how to do this. Okay?
I'm not a tracker.
That's okay, it's all I do.
- You asked to help you, right?
- Yeah.
We should go while I still can.
Okay.
Why are we stopping?
About the storm now...
The trees are too thick to drive.
Gotta walk from here.
Come on.
- Put this on.
- Okay.
Clap them up real tight ok?
Now what?
We walk.
Follow these sledge tracks heading south.
- you ready?
- Yeah.
Follow me.
Oh my god.
We went on foot the last half mile of it.
but we blazed a pretty good trail
on the snow.. so,
I could take the boys back up
there if you want.
III talk to the BIA Supervisor,
he just might want you to do that.
The security team over at the rig
got the cameras around their perimeter.
Im gonna head up there in
the morning,
we might get lucky to find
something on the tape.
The two we have in custody
say anything?
They ain't the talking kind,
Jane.
These kids... they expect to
go to prison.
Hell, I think they look
forward to it. You know?
Three hoots, and a cot,
and free cable?
Anything better being here...
the way they see it.
Lets r their DNA against the
semen, see what that tells us.
- Can I talk to him?
- No.
Cory, anything they might tell you
would be inadmissible in court,
and anything you tell us would render
everything that resulted
inadmissible as well.
What if don't tell you.
If I just knew it.
Yeah, agent Banner.
Ben.
Ive known this kid since he could walk.
I gotta canvas the house.
The back doors are only locked
from the inside...
Look at you.
I didnt do shit.
All you been doing is shit for
the last few years.
... Its this place. Look what it
takes from us.
What it took from you.
Im not going to stand here
and tell you that life's fair,
Cause it ain't.
To either of us.
But you know, what do we go?
This land is all we got left.
What is this we shit...?
Only thing native about you is your ex-wife
and a daughter you couldnt protect
Maybe if
youd played detective back then...
That's not something you get to talk about.
You hear me?
Over there.
You gonna lecture me about
protecting people?
While you deal the shit thats killing em?
Unlike most people...
... You had every chance to
get the hell out if thats what you wanted.
You got the Army. You got College.
Whatever is your choice.
Look what you choose.
Look what you chose.
God damn you.
I met him.
Ya?
Yeah, the motherfucker was
almost as old as you.
I wanted to fight
his ass.
Natalie wouldnt let me.
Guess love really is blind huh?
He works security on one of them drill site.
This boyfriend have a name?
Matt... Matt something...
- Who does?
- Sam knew. Why dont you ask him?
I think you'll be talking to Sam
long before I do.
You think this is who I wanted to be?
I get so mad..
I want to fight the whole world.
You got any idea what's that feel like.
I do.
I decided to fight the
feeling instead. Know why?
Because I fear that the world would win.
What did I tell you...
Did he say anything?
No. Fuck it..
I don't. I don't wanna know.
Youre heading for the rigs
tomorrow ain't you? yeah.
- Natalies boyfriend worked there.
- What?
- No, you are not to tell me.
- The thing's solve when it will solve.
Cory.
I want you at the rig with us tomorrow.
We don't catch wolves
looking at where they might be.
Head for where they've been.
They've been right here.
Hey.
You okay?
Been better.
What do you want?
I don't know.
Brings all back, doesnt it.
Maybe.
You and Ben and this little FBI girl formed
your own posse to go solve it all, I hear.
- Just trying to help.
- You won't get the answers..
..you're looking for.
No matter what you find.
This is not about Emily.
Good bye, Cory.
Matt Rayburn.
Did you know him?
- That's the guy we found in the snow?
- Yes, fingerprints from the database.
He was a security contractor
for one of the drill stations.
Alright.
Is that it?
Am I fired now?
- Why don't you come inside? Warm up.
- Okay.
- You.. want something to drink?
- Sure.
You got the..
milk and coffee and well water.
- Water is good.
- Okay.
Right, um.. make yourself at home.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
That's my daughter Emily.
She passed three years ago.
I'm sorry.
You want to know how.. do you?
I do, but...
Let's do this.
I was working as an outfitter in Pinedale.
And there was a big snow,
so I found myself with a rare night off.
So I got a motel called the wife,
she can come up stay for the night.
I mean you got 2 kids and when you're
at the mountain for half of the years.
You don't get much time together.
So we had Emily look after Casey
who was 5 at that time.
She was 16.
I guess that word got out that
we are out of town.
So some school friends came over
and some more friends.
Then...
And then some people came
that weren't friends.
So a little gathering
turned into a quite the party I guess.
Then...
I don't know.
You know there is a lot I don't know.
We got that phone call the next morning.
From Natalie.
Said that Emily was missing.
She was worried, naturally,
they were best friends.
Yeah.. We tried to be
very careful with Emily.
Tried to plan for everything.
She was such a good girl.
But we let our guard down.
Yeah. Let me tell you.
Maybe you'll have kids one day.
You cannot blink.
Not once, not ever.
Then there was a guy moving sheep
over by the wind river.
He is the one who found her.
Some 20 miles from our house.
I don't know how she got there
or what happened.
Autopsy couldn't tell us much
cause the Coyotes got at her pretty good.
No, I'm sorry...
- Sorry.
- Could you point me...
towards your bathroom?
- Straight up there.
- Thanks.
A Meadow in My perfect world.
Emily wrote that.
It's what got her accepted into the
summer writing program in Colorado state.
Did she write it to you?
Doesn't matter who it's to.
Just matters who it's from.
Look I'm sorry about..
earlier tonight.
I'm just trying to do the right thing here.
I don't really know
what the Hanson boy told you but...
I don't wanna stumble onto something
like today if I can help it.
So you know, if he said something
that I should know...
... I would appreciate if you share it.
He only said.. he said,
Natalie's boyfriend was named Matt.
And you've already figured out
who that is, so...
You get a call for that information, huh?
I wanted to know why you're helping me.
Now I do. So..
Tomorrow...
Do you think we could not ride
the snowmobile 80 miles an hour?
Yeah, if you wanna end up in a ditch,
we could have jumped over..
Great.
Okay.
- Have a good night.
- All right.
- See you tomorrow.
Shaking more than she is.
That's cold enough to freeze
a gold digger's ass out here.
Yeah, below zero, I bet.
Yes, six below,
it's lot colder up here.
Hey, bud.
- Hey, how are you doing?
- What are you doing here?
These track lead from the
little feather' house to your body.
I'm gonna follow them.
See where they go?
Yeah, well, Jane's the only one with
jurisdiction out there.
Just wanted a few extra badges along.
- You wanna walk 'em through this?
- Oh sure yeah.
The drill station has
cameras along its perimeter.
We're hoping one of the cameras
caught something.
And we'll also canvas
Matt Rayburn's trailer.
See if there is anything
that links him to the assault.
- You have a warrant?
- I'm going to ask real nice.
Can't get that from
little feather house?
Now that's a real tough slade
right through two canyons.
And I ain't looking to dig you out so...
I won't recommend it.
We'll take the refinery road around.
See you gotta drive 50 miles to go 5.
Welcome to Wyoming.
Then you people can get to my mothers.
It's spring.
If you find anything,
you call me on the radio.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
Can I help you?
- Yeah does Matt Rayburn work here?
- Yeah. You know where he is?
I was about to ask you the same thing.
No. he got in a fight with his girlfriend
a couple of days ago.
She took off, he took her back.
Then we have not seen 'em since.
- When was that?
- Three days ago.
Heck, we didn't know what to do.
We've been waiting
on the corp. ever since...
tell us whether or not fill his
termination papers, or call you guys.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah yeah, they are here for Matt.
You find him? Is he okay?
- What happened to you two?
- What's that?
You look little torn up.
He hit one of the pine branch doing 60.
see what happens to you.
We run the property line twice daily.
Comes with the territory.
You should try using a face shield.
I requested helmets.. our supervisor said,
"Snow's soft, ain't it?"
Corporate in Texas,
what can I tell you.
- Does Matt bunk here on the property?
- Yeah, yeah, we all do.
- Can we see his trailer?
- Yeah, sure come on. I'll walk you up.
- What's going on boss?
- They're here about Matt.
End of line for you.
So did.. did something happen to him?
You know where he is?
That's what we are trying to find out.
His girlfriend filed a
missing person's report..
Well how can that be?
Thought you guys found her in a snow drifter
right before the storm.
Excuse me?
I heard her name go out over the radio
when you guys found her.
I don't remember using her name.
Maybe you weren't listening.
- The fuck are you doing?
- What?
- Why are you flanking me?
- What are you talking about?
What the fuck you think I'm talking' about?
You got us on three sides.
Get your hand off that weapon,
this is private property.
Put the fucking gun down right now!
Put it down!
Do it!
- Turn away from me, drop to your knees.
- Right now! Evan!
Fuck you! This is private BIA issued lease
on reservation land, assholes.
You are breaking the law by being here.
This is a lease land on reservation, Deputy.
You got no authority.
You think I don't know what are you doing?
Fucking do it assholes,
see what happens.
- Hoka he, white boy. Let's go.
- What are we doing?
Deputy, You have got no authority,
you are in violation of Federal law,
- Lower your weapons.
- Fuck, you got us in the cross fire!
Talk to me!
What do I do?
Hold your ground.
County Sheriff have no authority.
- Get them to holster those goddamn weapon.
- Alright everybody, just take it easy.
FBI! Hey, FBI.
This is federal land and
I have the only authority, ok?
Right now all of you stand down.
Okay, everyone.
If we're all working
towards the same goal here...
... and I need you to back down,
and take your hands away
from your weapons.
Look?
Dylan, holster your weapon.
Fucking decaf man.
Jesus fucking Christ.
You keep these assholes in check lady,
we're just doing our fucking job here.
Yeah, when we show up
your job is over, asshole.
Evan, holster your weapon now!
All right, everyone of you
step to my left. Let's go.
- Nobody behind me, you understand?
- You got it. asshole.
Guys step my way.
Everybody take a
big deep breath here please.
Deputy, holster your weapon.
- You didn't see it?
- Now or you're under arrest..
You understand me?
You didn't see it.
Take us to Matt's trailer fucking now.
Yes, ma'am.
Ben, do you copy?
Ben!
This is it.
Right here.
- Did he bunk with anybody?
- Yeah.. me and Pete Mickens.
- Pete in there now?
- Yeah, he's sleeping,
he's got the night shift.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm looking for my
knight in shining armor..
I think this is his trailer.
Shit.. I am little short on armor.
- I don't mind.
- You don't mind?
Do you have any idea
how good it is to see you?
Like any idea?
Man o' man.
How did you get here?
I din't hear your carriage pull out.
Yes, well... My carriage wanted to
catch the eight oclock show in Lander.
So she dropped me off at the turn-out.
You did walk in that snow huh?
Like super woman?
- I think you're worth it.
- You think I'm worth it, yeah?
Would you get your ass in here like..
the baddest woman in the planet..
you know that?
I love you..
- Ah..
Feet never touch anything but cement.
Okay how about Chicago?
Baby it's the same thing as New York,
just colder.
More crime,
if you're into that kind of thing.
You think that's funny?
Alright. How about Los Angeles?
Hey, listen to me, do never ever say
that word around me again.
- It's warm there.
- I would rather be in Iraq.
Iraq's warm.
I tell you what..
I got one..
I got one...
I remember I was stationed up at this place
called Point Mugu right..
... It's about an hour north of LA.
It's Christmas, I woke up, I'm all alone,
You know. I don't have anybody..
But the navy does a Christmas time,
see there's dumb little kids
at the mess hall
you know for the guys without family.
I wasn't gonna stick around
for that bull shit.
So I just.. I got my truck
and a high ** out of there..
... and I wound up in a
little mountain town called Ojai.
I get there and it's like.. fruit farms.
Vineyards...
And there is this mountain surrounding it
you know like protecting the town.
And the people there...
like everybody smiles at each other.
They say hello... it's like
I remember thinking they were all like..
I don't know.
They had these looks in their eyes
Like they ran on some sort of secret
like they had all figured it out.
There is this mission, the Spanish mission
right there in the middle of the town.
They are having Christmas mass.
They're celebrating Christmas.
70 degrees where you know..
I just land there pick me
an orange of the tree...
... and sat down on a bench, to listen that
choir singing, eating my orange.
You know that was the best Christmas
I've ever had.
You wanna live there?
Okay.
Let's go live in Ojai.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
What time is it?
I thought they were
staying in town tonight?
I did too.
I'm sorry, Nat.
Just shut the.. uh.
It smells like sex in here.
What are you guys..
fucking honeymoon suit?
What have you two been doing huh?
What have they been doing?
Well.. Hello lady.
- Hi, Pete.
- Hello.
Just kind of wonder,
who you got under them sheets there?
- Hey Kurt, do you mind getting him in?
- Come on, Pete.
I asked the lady a question.
What does she got underneath them sheets?
It's a fluffy downcast Pete, not very sexy.
Well, fluffy sounds good to me.
Kurt, you're gonna get him
or not man?
Mattie, wait a second,
are you naked too?
Are you naked too?
What have you two been doing?
Hey Kurt, mind getting him
out of my room please?
Are you naked to?
What have you two been doing?
Hey Kurt, could you get him in?
- Hey. Come on, Pete!
- I just want a little peek.
Kurt, why don't you come in here.
And get him out of here.
I don't see why you aren't gonna do that.
The fuck is your problem?
Why are you doing that?
- Come on, Pete.
- Do not be bullshit to me girl.
You've been showing
your little ass like flag
I've been seeing it and
all I want is a little...
All I want is a little peek.
What are you gonna do, big boy?
Come on, Pete.
What are you gonna do, come on?
What are you gonna do, big boy?
What the fuck?
You're such a pussy
over this Prairie nigger.
Pete!
Nat!
Hold her!
FBI! Open up.
Are you sure someone's in there?
- Hey, Pete, It's Curtis.
- Ben do you copy?
The FBI is standing
in front of the door, open up.
Jane, get away from the door!
Fuck you, let's go.
- Pete, you okay?
- I'm hit..
Who is hit?
- Pete you good?
- We're good.
How many we got down?
- Two that won't get up.
- No, I'm getting up.
Goddamn it, the woman out here are spunky.
Anyone seen where that came from?
- Could you stand?
- I don't know.
We better figure it out,
cause we're not done yet.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Coming in!
Mike!
- Hey, Curtis!
- Out there... trailer 3.
You're okay?
Let's get you inside.
- How bad are you hit?
- I don't know.
I guess couple of rounds
went through here.
But just pieces.
You'll be okay.
Let me see.
Okay.
- Hold that. Press it tight.
- Yeah, okay.
Give me your radio.
My best chance out of here...
is a helicopter.
You don't have one of those.. do you?
No.
Give me your radio.
Go get him.
I won't bring him back.
You have to know that.
I do.
Go get him.
- Do you know where we are?
- No.
The Gannet Peak.
Highest mountain in Wyoming.
On the hottest day in August,
still there's a feet of snow.
Today, too cold to snow.
Look man, Let's just talk for a bit,
alright?
- Let's just talk, please.
- Sure.
What the fuck?
Where are my boots?
You know..I got all the time in the
world here, can't say the same for you.
So you're gonna talk?
Or you keep whining?
Look I've had made mistakes ok?
So what did you do?
Hey look,
I am not the law here
I'm just the guy
sitting in front of you.
So you can tell me the truth.
You tell me the truth
I give you a chance.
Alright just listen to me!
You know what it's like
out here in this frozen hell?
Ain't there nothing to do..
No nothing.
Aint no women, no fun.
This is fucking snow and
the fucking silence, that's all!
My family's people were forced here.
Stuck here for a century.
That's snow and silence...
... is the only thing
that hasn't been taken from them.
So what did you take?
I don't know what you mean.
You take something too?
No.
Hey, I need you to be
honest with me, right?
You get drunk,
get lonely...
Then what you get?
You did it.
Just be man and say it.
Say, "I raped her."
I raped her.
I raped her.. yeah!
Her boyfriend.. where he get in your way
You beat him to death?
Look a nod's not gonna cut it, ok?
- I need you to say it.
- I beat him.
We made him dead.
Okay.
Please don't.
I'm gonna cut you lose.
You're free to go.
- Where.. where I gonna go?
- I'm a man of my word.
You have told the truth.
Let me give you a chance.
Let me give you the same chance
that she got.
What chance did she get?
If you can make it to that highway,
you're free man.
Where is the highway?
You know how far that drill camp was
from where I found Natalie's body?
6 miles, bare foot.
That's a warrior.
You.. you may make 600 feet.
But you better get going.
I don't understand.
What do you want me to do?!
I want you to run.
How you feeling?
I feel okay.
Got you something.
Thought maybe it give you a little
taste of home.
- Crocodile.
- Please don't make me laugh.
It's an alligator.
I hope it protects you
better than bullet-proof vests right?
I should not joke about that,
it saved your life.
You saved my life.
No.
Jane, you're a tough woman.
You saved your own life.
We both should be honest.
I got lucky.
Ah. well, luck don't live out here.
Luck lives in the city.
Don't live out here.
It lives where you get hit by a bus or not.
Where your bank is robbed or not.
At someone's damn cell phone
when he come up to a crosswalk.
That's luck, that's winning or losing.
Out here you survive or you surrender.
That's determined by your strength
and bare spirit.
Wolves don't kill the unlucky deer.
They kill the weak ones.
You fought for your life Jane.
And now you get to walk away with it.
You'll get to go home.
I know what you're doing.
Will read to you from a magazine.
"10 Signs that He's Into You."
"He looks you in the eye when he speaks."
Is it supposed to be?
She ran 6 miles in the snow.
Yes, she did.
Hello?
Martin?
Martin!
Hey..
Martin?
Annie?
Hey.
What's with the paint?
It's my death face.
Is that right?
How would you know what that it is?
I don't.
Just made it up.
Guess no one left to teach her.
That's right as..
Then the phone rang...
... which is never good.
But today it was.
First time Chip's called me in over a year.
Where is he?
Police station.
Just gonna go pick him up...
... as soon as I wipe this shit of my face.
I heard about what happened.
I heard there's one still missing.
No.
No one's missing.
How did he go out?
With a whimper.
You better go easy on Chip.
I should go get him.
I just need to sit here...
... You gonna sit for a minute?
You got time to sit with me?
Well, I ain't going nowhere.
Subtitled by Clarity.