M-Mr. Cash?
Mr. Cash?
J.R...
J.R., turn it off
and get to sleep!
Change it, J.R.
Turn it off.
Guess which Carter that is.
Anita?
- That's fine.
- Nope. June.
That was little ten-year-old
June singing for you.
And what was the name
of that number now?
Turn it off!
Do I have to come in there?!
Let's get to bed.
It's hot.
It's going to be hotter
tomorrow.
Maybe Daddy will
quit us early
and we can
go fishin'.
We'll go fishin'
Saturday.
Daddy needs a good day from us
tomorrow, J.R.
I know.
Jack?
Mm-hmm?
How come you're so good?
I ain't.
You pick five times
more than me.
Well, I'm bigger than you are.
You know every story
in Scripture.
You know every song
in Mama's hymnal.
Songs are easy.
They ain't for me.
There's more words in the Bible
than in Heavenly Highway Hymns.
Look, J.R., if I'm gonna be
a preacher one day...
I got to know the Bible
front to back.
I mean, you can't help nobody
if you can't tell them
the right story.
Said by noon
it's gonna be 104.
Them radio stations
will say anything
to get
them niggers off.
Ray, why don't you let J.R.
Take the babies in?
I told Roz we'd have a crop
yesterday.
What do I say when he pulls up
here and we're shy?
You ready to unload that piano?
We're not selling Daddy's piano.
And I'm not the one in Bartstown
drinking every
Saturday.
Eh, what's up, Doc?
Whoa!
What, what did
that rooster say
when he was all
blown up by the TNT
and picking his feathers
up outside that henhouse?
"F-Fortunately, boy,
I keep my feathers numbered
for just such an emergency."
I got it, I got it.
Can we go soon?
Mr. Coles gave me a dollar
to cut the whole pile...
and not half.
Go on ahead, J.R.
Catch a fish.
The worm on a hook.
Drop it in a brook.
If things go right...
you'll fry some fish tonight.
Where you been?
Throw that pole down.
Get in the car! In the car!
J.R.
You hear them, J.R.?
You hear them angels?
I can hear 'em, Jack.
They're so beautiful.
Beautiful.
Jack?
Do something!
You know what that is, J.R.?
You know that is
coming out of there?
Stop it, Ray.
Nothing!
Nothing, that's what that is.
That's what that's worth.
And that's what you are.
Leave it alone, Ray.
He didn't do this.
The devil did this!
He took the wrong son!
- Stop it, Ray.
He was my best, and now he's gone!
Jack, please,
don't leave me alone.
- Ray!
- Quiet! Quiet!
Everybody quiet!
You're going to miss your bus.
Communist troops have been driven out of Seoul, Korea...
by U.S. Forces led
by General Douglas MacArthur.
What's that?
Anybody seen Tommy?
He's leaving, Ray. Come on.
Don't start crying, Mama.
Be careful
with that rifle, J.R.
Yeah, I will, Mama.
Last month, that Pervis boy
got confused and shot himself.
Ain't going to be no battles, Carrie.
He's going to Germany.
The war is in Korea.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Take this.
Thanks, Mama.
Take care of yourself,
Donzil.
Take care
of my sister, too.
I will.
Hey, Tommy, be a good boy.
You're gonna miss your bus.
Yeah.
I saw this church in Dusseldorf...
made of limestone,
big as a train station.
We could get married there
and go to Venice.
That's in Italy, Viv.
The streets are made
of water, I ain't kiddin'.
Johnny, I haven't seen you for two years.
We only dated for a month.
My daddy says there's
something wrong with you.
Well... what do you say, Viv?
I mean...
I thought you said you loved me.
I do.
Oh, I do.
Then don't be scared.
You tell him that.
You tell him I love you, too.
He says that's impossible.
He says that you hardly know me.
Well, I know perfect
when I meet it.
Let's go, Cash!
Viv, listen, baby...
you tell your daddy
I'm your man.
Tell him we're
gonna make a family
and I'm gonna be on the radio,
'cause I am.
You tell him we're
gonna have a nice house
and we're gonna be happy.
And we're gonna live in Memphis.
And you tell him I'm
gonna love you forever.
- Do you promise?
- That's a promise, Viv.
Do you hear me?
That's a pro...
Five minutes was up
five minutes ago.
I am Folsom Prison.
At one time they called me
"Bloody Folsom."
And I earned the name.
My own prisoners built me.
Every block of my granite
is cemented by
the blood of many men.
Is it any wonder a man
sometimes went berserk
and fought the hated walls
that shut him in?
Knock it off!
You knock it off
and get to sleep!
This was a common thing in those old days.
I had so little work for them to do...
You gonna try
today, John?
Really try to sell something?
What does that mean?
I cleaned out
your case last night,
and, baby, all I found
were peanut bags
and music magazines.
I need you
to think about
what my daddy offered.
Viv, I'm trying.
I mean, I'm really
trying to sell stuff.
Hello, ma'am.
I'm from Home Equipment Company
over on Summer,
and we have a lot of...
...enamel colors
that you can choose from
that we can...
Hello. I'm John Cash
and I'm from the Home Equipment
Company on Summer.
LaQuisha!
LaQuisha, who is it!?
You are late, man.
Little higher.
A little...
yeah, a little higher.
Now play the chord.
Let's hear your E, Marshal.
There's my E.
Lulubelle, time to come in!
Jack! Jack, get in here!
- Let's go.
- Jack!
Let's go, John.
Viv?
- Viv, open the door.
Viv.
Viv, don't embarrass me.
You know who's out there
watching.
I want to see my daddy.
I want to go
home, John.
Please.
He's just got a job,
sitting in there in San Anton...
just waiting for us.
It's just sitting there...
it's just sitting there
waiting...
Viv, the guys are here.
My band is here in Memphis.
Your band?
John, your band?
Your band is two mechanics
who can't hardly play.
Baby, can't you hear the
difference between you and that?
You have your wife
and your baby in a dump, John...
and another one on the way...
and we can't even
make rent, John.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you the owner
of this place?
That's me.
Hello, I'm J.R. Cash.
Sam Phillips.
Well, good to meet
you, Mr. Phillips.
I'm a singer
and I've got a band...
and we've been
working on some songs.
You want to cut a record, son?
It's four dollars.
What about the guys there
on the wall in the pictures?
I mean, they pay four dollars?
They're on my label.
How do I get
on there?
You audition.
Right now?
Call my secretary, Marion,
when she comes back.
She's at the salon.
She'll set you up
an appointment next month.
I can't wait that long,
Mr. Phillips.
Excuse me?
I can't wait that long.
What about this one?
I can iron it.
John, you can't
wear that one.
It's black.
It's the only color shirt
we all have.
Nothing wrong with black.
It looks like you're
going to a funeral.
Maybe I am.
Hold on.
I hate to interrupt...
but do you guys
got something else?
I'm sorry.
I can't market gospel.
No more.
So that's it?
I don't record material
that doesn't sell, Mr. Cash...
and gospel like that
doesn't sell.
Was it the gospel
or the way I sing it?
Both.
Well, what's wrong with
the way I sing it?
I don't believe you.
You saying
I don't believe in God?
J.R., come on,
let's go.
No.
I want to understand.
I mean, we come down here,
we play for a minute...
and he tells me
I don't believe in God.
You know exactly
what I'm telling you.
We've already heard that song
a hundred times...
just like that,
just like how you sang it.
Well, you didn't let us
bring it home.
Bring... bring it home?
All right, let's bring it home.
If you was hit by a truck
and you were lying out
in that gutter dying...
and you had time to sing
one song, huh, one song...
people would remember
before you're dirt...
one song that would let
God know what you felt about
your time here on earth...
one song that would sum you up...
you telling me
that's the song you'd sing?
That same Jimmie Davis tune
we hear on the radio all day?
About your peace within
and how it's real
and how you're
gonna shout it?
Or would you sing
something different?
Something real,
something you felt?
Because I'm telling you
right now...
that's the kind of song
people want to hear.
That's the kind of song
that truly saves people.
It ain't got nothing to do with
believing in God, Mr. Cash.
It has to do with
believing in yourself.
Well, I've got a couple songs
I wrote in the Air Force.
You got anything against
the Air Force?
No.
I do.
J.R., whatever
you're about to play...
we ain't never heard it.
Where you been?
Are you drunk?
What happened?
He didn't like our gospel.
So I played him some
songs that I wrote.
We made a record, Viv.
I mean, a real,
real record.
We did it like,
like six times.
I had to sing the song
over and over again.
And, uh, and playin' it.
And you should have
seen Marshall.
He was so nervous.
But I mean, we made
a real record
- of my song.
- Oh, baby.
- Of my song.
Never seen nobody
play like that.
Ladies and gentlemen...
The Killer Jerry Lee Lewis!
Get yourselves
a pine box, boys...
nobody follows The Killer.
These next boys have just put out
their first record
called "Cry, Cry, Cry"
- and it is selling like hotcakes.
- Shoot, now I'm late.
Oh, my gosh!
Excuse me.
That's my cue.
Oh, no, you...
oh, that's stuck...
right on my dress.
Hey, Bill!
- Let me get...
- Hold on, Bill... I'm comin'!
- Uh... Oh, my.
I think I hear June Carter's
voice, ladies and gentlemen.
I'll be right there, Bill,
I'll be right there.
- Uh, reckon when, June?
Well, Bill,
I got tangled.
- Yeah, in what, June Bug?
Johnny Cash's
guitar strap.
Don't worry,
I can keep this funny
for at least two minutes.
And I tell you what, Bill.
He's a strapping boy,
that Johnny Cash.
And his guitar strap is
pretty strappin', too.
Here. I love that
Cry song by the way.
Thanks.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss June Carter.
- Bill!
Bill, I had to come
and tell you.
I had to tell you...
I had to tell you
I just can't
sing tonight.
You best be getting out here.
Well, Bill...
I got the laryngitis.
- June, we...
- I do!
Y'all laughing,
but I do.
We all just heard you
hollering up a storm backstage.
Well, I didn't have it then,
Bill.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss June Carter.
All right.
June's going to be back
to sing later.
Her family is also
with us tonight.
But like I was saying,
these boys up next
are hotter than a pistol.
They are burning up the radio
with their new hit,
"Cry, Cry, Cry."
We want to make sure we
give them
a big Texarkana welcome.
So here they are, folks.
New passengers on
the Sun Rocking Railway-
Johnny Cash
and the Tennessee Two.
Hello.
I'm Johnny Cash.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Viv, I'm telling you...
I think this is the best show
we've ever done.
Hell, it might be the best show
I've ever seen.
No kidding!
Where are you?
Texarkana.
Baby, I miss you.
Hey, do you hear Orbison
doing our song?
He turned it into
a two-step, listen.
You hear that?
Oh, damn it!
- What's the matter?
Damn it!
Oh, it's Roseanne.
She just ran her head
into the table.
Roseanne!
Roseanne, here, talk to Daddy.
Hey, Roseanne.
Hey, it's Daddy.
Honey, don't, don't cry.
Daddy's going to be home real soon.
- John, I have to go.
- Huh?
I have to go, John.
Bye.
You're sounding
good tonight, Cash.
Real tight.
Oh, thanks, man.
You want some chili fries?
Oh, no, that's all right.
She's been in the spotlight
since you and me
was bitin' ankles.
They say Maybelle
had a crib at the Ryman...
so she could pull her out
and let her whoop and holler
and pop her back in
to go to sleep.
We're leaving
in an hour, John.
All right.
Aw, that's a sweet story, honey.
No.
Within, like, five minutes.
All right.
Everything else
all right?
Okay.
I love you, too.
Bye-bye.
How you doing?
Bye.
Coffee?
Yeah, and some toast, please.
Hey.
- Hey, how are you?
- Good. Do you mind?
No, not at all.
Did you lose your voice?
I did.
I was just singing my
heart out up there.
I've got to ask you how
you came up with that sound.
What sound?
That sound everybody's
talking about.
Steady like a train,
sharp like a razor.
Well, we'd play
faster if we could.
I guess it just...
come out like that.
I got to close my register.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Here's a picture
of my wife, Viv...
- my baby, Roseanne.
- Oh, look at her.
She's beautiful.
Thanks. Got another one
on the way.
- I got a little girl, too.
- Yeah?
Her name's Carlene, yeah.
She's about the same age.
You know when I was
in the service...
I used to look at
pictures of you...
you know, in magazines.
Oh.
No... no, it
wasn't like that.
I mean, I... I liked
your music, you know?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I mean, I... you were,
well, you are...
I mean, l-I kept
track of you.
You and
your family.
I listened to your voice
my whole life, you know?
Me and my brother, Jack...
we always listened
to your songs.
Like "Swallerin' Place."
- Yeah.
We liked it when
you'd sing one alone.
Well, you and Jack
are the only ones.
What do you mean?
I'm not really much
of a singer, Johnny.
I mean, I got a lot
of personality, I got sass...
I give it my all,
but my sister Anita's
really the one
who's got the pipes.
Well, who said that?
Everybody.
My mama, my daddy.
That's how come I learned
to be funny...
so I'd have something
to offer.
Well... parents
aren't always
the best judge
of things...
if you want
my opinion.
So how long you on the tour?
Another couple
of weeks.
We just got
on board, but...
I tell you it feels
like a lot longer.
I'm sure.
I'm headed off,
I'm going to the Ryman.
Why don't you tell
your brother, Jack, to tune in...
and I'll
sing him something.
What does he like?
Oh, that's-that's sweet,
but, uh, he passed.
I'm sorry.
Were y'all real close?
Yeah.
Yeah, he's, uh...
It's funny, I ain't talked about
Jack in a long time, you know?
After he died, I...
I talked about him all the time...
but, uh... I guess people
grew tired of it.
So I just stopped.
John?
You're tired,
aren't you?
Yeah.
It'll slow down.
It will.
I better get going.
It's good to talk to you.
You, too.
Take care.
I'll see you soon.
You better tune in...
I'm going to sing you
that "Swallerin' Place."
I will, I
really will.
Okay.
That's fine, that's perfect.
Yes, ma'am.
When was the last time you heard him
moving around in there?
I don't know.
Thought you were going
to help me today, John.
You head out tomorrow.
Yeah.
Better start living life
here with us when you come home...
before you have to leave again.
Hey, you know, I was thinking.
You know, maybe I could get Bob
to push my dates.
I'm happy
when I'm here.
I like waking up
and seeing your face.
John, those bags over there?
Hmm.
Those letters in there
are ten to one from girls.
Ten to one, and they're obscene.
Reba's been trying
to answer some of them...
but, you know,
half of them ain't even 15...
and they are sending pictures
of themselves in bathing suits.
Pictures for you to look at
while you're doing time
at Folsom.
Oh, Viv.
This one girl,
she sent you...
Viv, you know, don't even read
those letters, you know...
It's just crazy right now,
that's all.
You know?
Hell, you should have seen
last week.
We was at the fair, and, uh...
this bus full of 4H girls
pulls up, you know...
and they come piling
out of there...
and they go running
and screaming
after Carl and Roy,
I mean running.
John... I have a casserole
in the oven and your sister
in the kitchen, and I don't want
to talk about the tour.
Viv, you're the one who brought it up.
In fact,
that's my new rule.
When you come home,
I want to get
right down to talking
about regular things.
Viv, don't give
me no rules.
All I got are rules.
All I got is to be at this place
at this time.
I'm trying to go there,
and I'm trying to be back here
and spend time
with you and the kids...
and write songs, do this-
I mean, what do you want
from me, all right?
I got you your dream house,
all of your things...
all the pretty little things.
I got you your car.
What do you want from me?!
I want you, John, I want you!
And I want everything
that you promised to me.
Well, what if I can't do that?
Got your mind on something?
What are you doing up there, man?
I'm building a bomb.
Where we going again?
Tyler. The
George Jones show.
Where was it we just was?
Have another one, Carl.
Austin, Carl.
That's where
y'all picked me up.
Hey, Johnny, you see
the new charts?
"Cry, Cry, Cry"
was 14, I think.
Yeah, I heard that.
I haven't seen it.
Wherever we been, I can
tell you where we're going.
Everybody in this car
is going to hell.
What about the
car up there?
We're all going to hell
for the songs we sing.
People that listen to them,
they're going to hell, too.
Shut up with that.
God gave us a great
big apple, see, and He said...
"Don't touch it."
He didn't say
touch it once in a while.
He didn't say take a nibble
when you're hungry.
He said, "Don't touch it.
Don't think
about touching it.
Don't sing about touching it.
Don't think about singing
about touching it."
Well, what about me,
Jerry Lee?
Am I going to hell?
No, June, you're beautiful.
Sleepy is what I am.
She's making me fall
in love with her.
Feel my heart. Come here.
Sincerely.
Feel my heart, baby.
It's just a-beating for you.
Stop it, Jerry.
Come on, I'm falling
for you, June.
Hey. Jerry Lee.
Jerry Lee, stop it.
Jerry Lee, just sit your ass down.
Just sit down.
The 1957 Chevrolet...
- Looks like we're here.
Oh, thank goodness.
Get me out of this car
and all these boys.
Let's go,
home sweet home, boys.
If you could just put those
right there, that'd be great.
Oh, wait.
I wanted
to give you that Billboard.
Oh, right.
It's in here somewhere.
You got a library
in there, June.
Here it is.
I circled it for you.
- Hmm.
- It's right there.
Yeah.
Fourteen.
- I don't believe it.
Um, I wanted to
give you this.
Yeah, I just finished it.
It's really amazing.
The Prophet?
Yeah.
Keep it.
Oh, no, you don't want to...
Whenever I finish a book,
I give it away to somebody.
Just lightens my load.
John.
I just went through
a terrible divorce.
I got a world of
judgment on me right now.
And, um...
it's really none
of my business...
but you seem like
you have a nice family.
I'm sorry.
It just happened.
Just happened?
Yeah.
You wear black 'cause you can't
find anything else to wear?
You found your sound
'cause you can't play no better?
You just tried to kiss me,
because...
it just happened?
You should try taking credit
for something
every once in a while.
John.
Hey, Lou.
Hey, John.
You okay?
I'll let you know
in a few minutes.
How you doing?
Okay.
That boy Elvis sure likes
to talk poon.
That's all I heard
since Lubbock.
Ease off, ease off.
Do you want some?
What is it?
Well, it'll just make you want
to drive all the way
to Jacksonville
and enjoy yourself
once you get there.
Elvis takes 'em.
Yeah.
Yes, sir...
Be careful.
Here comes Marshall
with his bomb.
Hey, you got your
lighter, J.R.?
Yeah.
All right, you help
me get up in there.
- Grab that fuse.
- All right.
How long we got us
after we light it?
About 30 seconds
a foot.
All right.
Does your wife know how much
you like to blow stuff up?
Sure she does.
That's why
I married her, John.
Did you light it?
There's a bomb up here,
ladies and gentlemen.
It'll go...
Way to go, Johnny boy.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
How about them boys, huh?
Johnny Cash
and the Tennessee Three.
You kicked it good
tonight, John.
Thanks, man.
That's right,
kiss his ass.
Hey, Jerry Lee, your
mama know you're out?
She knows.
How about that Johnny Cash,
everybody?
- Johnny Cash!
Okay, now.
Mr. Cash?
Yeah?
There's a Miss Audrey
Parks here to see you.
Who?
Audrey Parks.
Well, hey.
Oh, get it now.!
Ray, why don't you say grace?
Mama, it's J.R.'s table.
Why don't you say grace, J.R.?
No, go ahead.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.!
Hi.
You're June Carter,
ain't ya?
Oh, my.
Betsy Pervis.
Hi, Betsy.
So nice to meet you.
Well, we're coming
to see the show tonight.
Oh, wonderful.
This is my husband, Lloyd.
Hi, Lloyd. So
nice to meet you.
Y'all wouldn't know
where the fishin' tackle is,
would you?
Back of... back
of them footballs on the corner.
Oh. All
right, great.
Well, y'all enjoy the show,
and if you have any requests...
just holler 'em out.
- Morning.
- Hey.
Oh, can I help you?
Oh, um, I'm looking
for some lace.
Oh, the sewing store
on Saticoy's got lace.
Thank you.
You know, your ma and pa
are good Christians
in a world gone to pot.
Well, I'll tell 'em
you said that.
I'm surprised
they still speak to you
after that stunt
with Carl Smith.
Divorce is an abomination.
Marriage is for life.
I'm sorry I let you down, ma'am.
Hey.
What's funny?
Well, you've just been standing
in that same spot
for about ten minutes staring
at that Polly Pepper book.
Well... well, I can't...
I can't figure out which one
Roseanne would like more.
She got brown hair, which
makes me think this one.
- Right.
- But this is baby sister's...
and she got a baby
sister, and...
Well, I got that one
for Carlene, and she liked it.
Oh, yeah?
I missed her birthday.
- Oh.
- So I wanted to get her something more...
you know,
like one of these dollhouses.
But I don't know how
to get it out to her.
You want me to help you?
I think there's a lake
right up around the corner.
- Got a hitch in your giddy-up?
- Yeah.
Forgot how much
I like this.
Hey, June?
I never used one of these
fancy reels before.
Well, what'd you
use, a sapling?
- Yeah.
Okay, hold on,
I'll help you.
- It's like there's some kind of a lock on it or...
- No.
My daddy taught me how to do this;
I'll show you.
Keep your thumb down
on the button.
That loosens the line.
And then you're gonna
bring it back...
and then you're gonna
throw it out there...
and then when you're ready...
if you got a good spot for it,
you let go of the button.
- All right?
- Side-arm?
Yeah, side-arm.
All right.
See? There you go.
Hey, folks, what do you say
we get June Carter out here again?
Maybe she'll, uh,
sing with me.
- No, no, no, no.
Now, come on, June,
I never sing with you.
I have my slippers on.
I'm not coming out there.
Well, they don't care
if you got your slippers on.
Come on, it's for the sake of the evening.
Folks, let's hear it: June, June...
June, June, June, June...
- June, June, June, June...
- Come on, June.
Prove Elvis wrong.
He says you can't do nothing that ain't
written in your calendar.
- June, June, June, June, June, June...
June, June, June...
June, June, June, June,
June, June, June, June...
- You see, June?
- They want to see us together.
- All right, well...
quit that clutching on me,
and I'll sing with you...
but you got to quit
clutching on me.
Hi, folks.
How y'all doing again?
I hope y'all don't mind
my bare feet.
So, what are we
gonna sing, Johnny?
You got me out here.
Is that where
your plan ends?
- Well, uh... I always liked
that song of yours,
"Time's a Wastin'."
- Let's do that one.
Oh, come on,
I don't know about that.
How about your hit song,
"Big River"?
- That's a good song.
Well, "Big River"
ain't a duet.
Uh, let's do
"Time's a Wastin"'.
John, I am not
gonna sing that song.
It's inappropriate.
I recorded it with
my ex-husband.
- I'm not going to sing it.
There's no better way
to put it behind you.
I'm not gonna do it.
June, let's sing.
Don't do that!
Hey, June.
June?
Open up.
June, open the door.
Just leave me be,
John, all right?
What?
W-What did I do?
June, it's a song.
Just please get away from me.
I think I hear Johnny Cash and the Tennessee Three.
They'll be playing
all weekend long at the Malco.
Matinees and evening shows,
along with Jerry Lee Lewis...
June Carter and Carl Perkins.
It's the candy man.
Is the candy man
like Jerry Lee, there?
How come you don't never try
this brand of picking, Luther?
What you're looking for,
Waylon, I already found.
Well, hey, June.
Hey, Jerry Lee.
How you doin', John?
Uh...
Well, okay, June.
How you doing?
I surmise you've
never been to bed.
Surmise...
We've got a show at 2:00, a matinee.
- You remember that?
We were just practicing.
Oh, come on,
June, sit down.
It's slick here.
Not today, Jerry Lee.
Why not?
'Cause you're drunk.
Uh-oh!
- Whoo!
Come on, Junie,
just come have a beer with us.
I'm going home tonight
after the show.
I'm not here
to look after y'all.
You're not?
You got somebody
to do that for you, John.
You got a wife somewhere,
you remember that?
Ooh!
What if I didn't?
There's too many "ifs"
in that sentence.
Only one, actually.
There's only one "if"
in that sentence, June.
L-I thought it
was a good point.
There is only one.
Really?
How dare you
talk to me like that!
We surrender!
What was I thinking?
I must have been crazy.
Y'all are gonna blow this tour.
You can't walk no line.
June, we ain't blowing the tour.
I am not gonna be
that little Dutch boy with my
finger in the dam no more!
You're lying to yourself
if you think
this is about a tour, honey.
This isn't about a tour!
This isn't about a song!
John.
Honey, let's take a picture
of Roseanne.
C'mon, say cheese!
What do you think of California, Mr. Cash?
We like it. We just
bought a house.
Lunch time!
Come on in, everybody.
What is this?
I've been looking for that.
That's the letter I wrote
to Bob Dylan on a plane.
Hey, Mama, that's
that folk singer
I was telling you about.
You wrote it on
an air sickness bag, honey.
So what?
What's so funny?
I was thinking
maybe you ought
to try sleeping
at night.
Maybe eating,
maybe both.
Hey, uh, Viv, have you made
your mind up about tonight?
You coming?
Okay- 'cause you're asking
so nice.
I got it.
- Hello?
- Music awards.
We got a British Invasion...
a beautiful girl from Brazil,
a matchmaker from New York.
We even had a flying nanny.
In 1964...
Hey, Johnny.
Hey, Randy, how are you?
June? Hey.
Hi, John.
Been a long time.
Yeah.
Hi, Vivian, how are you?
Hello, June.
I saw you got married.
Uh, yes, I did.
Congratulations, June.
- Thank you, I appreciate that.
- You're welcome.
So you think
this one will stick?
John!
What is this, your second or your third?
- John!
- I'm just asking a question.
Do not do this to me.
John!
Oh!
Hey! June, wait up.
I need to talk to you.
I don't want
to talk to you, John.
Hey, excuse me, fella,
do you mind?
You don't look good, John.
Well, you look real nice.
So where's
your truck driver?
Stock car driver.
And you'll be happy to know
that things aren't really
working out between us.
It doesn't make me happy.
Well, a little it does.
I want to tour
with you again, June.
I miss the tour.
I mi... I miss the music.
I got two grown girls, John.
I can't tour.
So you're just going
to do a comedy act
the rest of your life?
You've got a voice,
June, use it.
One week a month,
that's all, all right?
You'll work for me.
You don't have to worry
about bookings
or agents, or publicists
or anything.
All right, one of
your girls gets sick...
you stay home,
and I pay you, anyways.
You stay home,
Thank you.
That's my mama's favorite song.
So y'all sit down,
squat down, or lie down...
but make yourselves at home.
'Cause here's
the one and only...
Mr. Johnny Cash!
Hello, I'm Johnny Cash.
Thank you.
Good to see y'all.
It's all June.
Thank you.
Hi, good to see you.
Thanks for coming.
What's next?
Vegas, we're booked in Vegas.
Hey, June?
Yeah?
I want you to meet my parents.
Oh!
This is my mama
and my daddy.
Hi!
How you doing?
It's so nice
to meet you, finally.
Hi, I'm June Carter.
Miss Carter.
Nice to meet you.
And you haven't met
my little girls, have you?
This is Roseanne
and...
- Oh, they're asleep...
Ain't they sweet?
Oh, you girls are
all dressed alike.
I love those yellow ribbons.
June?
Yeah?
Stay clear
of my children.
Vivian, I...
I was just
saying hello.
You heard me.
Viv.
- Vivian, please.
- No.
Oh, wait, catch it.
Come on, y'all.
I got these
cookies...
you're going
to love 'em, man.
Highfalutin'
high rollers out there.
Say, Officer...
how do you get your shirts
to stay that way?
So stiff?
Just starch.
Huh.
It's real nice.
What?
Are you out of
your rabid-ass mind?
All right, boys,
good night.
Good night, y'all.
- God night.
- Let me take one.
I am
so sleepy...
That was a fun show
tonight.
Yeah, it was.
- This is my room.
- Yeah.
Hey, you want to have
one of these with me?
Uh...
I don't know.
Can I have one?
John!
John, that's mean!
All right.
Wait, wait, wait, here.
I'll get
a good one.
- You are...
You know what?
You're just mean.
That's what you are.
You're mean!
Here, here.
You're a mean man.
- Don't say that.
- And I knew it.
I've known it
all along.
Wait a minute.
Here.
Come on, open your mouth.
No.
I don't trust you.
Don't say that.
I don't,
I don't trust you.
Yes, you do.
Open your mouth.
You are so evil!
- Terrible!
Oh...
I best better answer it.
Hello?
Oh, hey, Carlene,
what's wrong?
Okay, sweetie...
I can't understand
what you're saying...
you're crying so hard.
I know, but you got
to calm down, honey.
All right.
But everything's okay?
Yeah, I know,
sweetie...
sometimes
that happens.
- Sweetie, little sisters
do stuff like that,
sometimes.
You got to learn
to be patient with her.
Um...
okay, well, um...
tell Linda that Mommy said
it's all right for you
to have pancakes
on Saturdays.
- Hey, June... I'm gonna go to my room.
- All right?
Yeah, I know,
sweetie.
I'm going
to come home soon.
Yeah, so please don't cry.
Front desk.
Hi, could I have
June Carter's room, please?
Certainly.
One moment, sir.
June?
It's not wrong, June.
This ain't wrong.
June!
I'm not gonna
do this, John.
I'm not gonna do this.
Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
Where's Johnny?!
Well, Johnny Cash will be
out in just a minute.
He's been detained
for just a minute.
But we're gonna keep you
entertained till then.
And we're gonna play, uh...
a wonderful song...
Wait, hold on, hold on. Johnny's here.
Here he is!
Mr. Johnny Cash!
Hi, folks, I'm Johnny Cash.
What about that June Carter?
Ain't she a sweetheart.
How ya'll doing?
Get it on, man!
Play the fucking thing!
I'm okay.
Oh, my God, John?
Close the curtain.
- Get a doctor!
- John! John!
Pull the curtain back!
Come on, pull it back!
- Pull it back.
- Are you okay?
- Here, here, look at me.
- John? John?
Look at me.
Fortunately, I was keeping
my feathers numbered
for just such an emergency.
- Let's get some help!
Well, get him some help!
The tour's been canceled.
Who says?
We got your ticket
home, John, tomorrow.
See where I'm putting it?
Right here
by the phone.
Take care of yourself, John.
You're burning up.
Got hotter places
than my forehead.
Tell me you don't love me.
I don't love you.
You're a liar.
Well, then I guess you ain't
got no problems, do you?
Where's my pills?
Flushed them all.
June.
Junie, don't say that.
Hold on, all right?
L-I need those.
I need those pills!
Listen, that's just...
baby, it's just...
Th-Those are my prescriptions,
from the doctor, okay?
L-I nee...
I need those.
It burns.
It burns, it burns.
Mommy!
Few more minutes, pal.
There you go.
Mr. Cash.
You want to take these strings
off or you want us to break it?
Your mama was here...
your daddy, too.
What'd he say?
He said now you won't
have to work so hard
to make people think
you've been to jail.
Hey, Daddy.
Hey, baby.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine...
I'll see you in the morning.
Cindy doesn't
like mustard.
The pills were legal, Viv.
You know, I got prescriptions,
it's just...
You're not supposed to buy them
across the border, that's all.
Other than that, it's... fine.
So the radio's lying?
Yeah.
The TV's lying?
Baby, they'll say
anything to...
Your lawyer's lying?
Luther's lying, Marsh is
lying, your manager...
Viv, I don't want to fight.
What about June?
Does she think it's fine
her new boy's a drug addict?
She left the tour,
Viv, in Vegas.
Well, that explains
everything, doesn't it?
John!
John, what are you doing?
It's 7:00 a.m.
The kids are getting
ready for school.
I was hanging pictures.
John, please don't hang these.
Viv, they're pictures
of my band.
Don't hang these.
No, I don't want you
to hang these.
Viv, let go
- of the damn picture.
- No.
- No, I said, please don't hang these, John.
- Viv!
No!
Viv, get back here!
Viv?
Viv, get back here.
Viv, I ain't kidding!
Vivian, give me
the damn picture.
Viv.
Give me the...
No!
Viv. Wai...
Don't...
- You! You!
- Now, stop it. Baby, stop it!
- You pathetic excuse for a man!
- All right, ba...
She will find out,
you liar...
She'll find out!
She'll find out, John!
You liar!
- Stop it!
- No!
You think you're perfect?!
You think you're perfect? Huh?!
- Huh?!
No!
No.
Shut the door.
Hey, you leaving all this?
Viv?
You leaving all this?
Girls!
Girls! No!
- Girls!
- Hey, did June call?
Waylon!
Did June call?
Woman won't return
my damn calls.
They disconnected it
yesterday.
Insufficient
fundulation.
Now, come on, man,
I gave you money for that.
Well, that was last month.
This is this month.
You see, I'm...
I'm a little behind
right now,
and-and I need this
to turn my
phone back on...
because I need to
talk to my woman.
See, I'm-I'm in love
with a woman...
and I need to talk
to her, you understand?
I need this
to get my car
out of the shop.
She lives way, way out
on the edge of town.
It's the Bataan death
march to get there.
You see? So, if you just go
ahead and-and-and cash this.
Um, I'm sorry, Mr. Cash.
- You know who I am?
- I...
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
Then just please cash
the check for me.
The bank puts an automatic hold
on checks like this.
It's a large amount.
Well, if you
can't cash it...
- then it's just a piece of paper. See?
- Oh, don't do that.
- Please, don't.
- Why, you can't cash it, it ain't nothing.
It ain't nothing.
Just a damn piece of paper.
Mama, Johnny Cash is here!
Hey, girls.
Hey, Carlene, you
look real look nice.
Hey, Johnny.
Mama, Johnny Cash
is here!
Hi, Mother Maybelle.
Hey, John.
How are you doing?
I'm doing all right.
Hi, June.
Hi, John.
Hey, girls...
can you go inside the living
room and clean up that mess?
All right, honey.
I tried to call, June, but I
think there's something wrong
with your phone.
Look at you.
Have you looked
in a mirror lately?
How are you gonna sing,
when you can't even talk?
I got the laryngitis.
Remember?
Marry me, June.
Oh, please.
Get up off your knees.
You look pathetic.
Come on.
I don't want my girls
seeing somebody like this.
Come on, baby.
Where's my friend John?
What, did he get high?
Or is he incognito?
Is he gone?
'Cause I don't like
this guy, Cash.
I ain't incognito.
I'm right here.
You see?
I'm here.
Fine, where's your car?
Kiss and make up.
You walked here?
Yeah.
You walked here all
the way from Nashville?
Yeah, walking's
good for you.
See, I'm trying to
get into shape, June.
It cleans out your system.
Well, it's a spiritual thing.
I'm on a love walk.
The June Carter Love Walk.
- And memorial.
- You know what?
I'm supporting
more than myself right now.
Please, do not blow
another tour.
Aw, June, love's more
important than a tour.
- Is that right?
- Yes, it is.
Well, then start
loving yourself...
so we can go
back to work.
All right, June.
Hey, you keep your phone on,
and I will, too.
I'll call.
I'll call you.
When you're feeling better,
I'll call.
Hey, that's a beautiful house!
Hey, man.
Beautiful place, man.
- Yeah? Thanks.
- Uh-huh.
Hello.
June? Hey, it's John.
Hey.
How you doing?
I'm fine, John,
how are you?
Uh, yeah, doing a lot better
than the last time you saw me.
Well, that's good.
I'm glad to hear that.
You still taking those pills?
No, that was...
no, that was
a rough patch, uh, June.
I just needed to, uh,
you know, get some time.
I'm doing better, though, now,
you know?
I, uh, got out of that apartment
and got this place
out in Hendersonville
on a lake.
Big spread.
I heard that.
Yeah, I'm...
trying to get things together.
Mm-hmm.
Are you alone
on Thanksgiving, John?
Yeah.
My folks are coming down
with Reba and Roseanne...
and, uh, I got this big bird...
but I don't know
when to put it in the oven
or really what temperature
to set it at or...
Uh-huh.
It is beautiful.
Really lucky.
I'm really
proud of you.
- You see, it goes from right up there...
- Mm-hmm.
Clear across
halfway around the lake.
Yeah.
What's going on down
there with that tractor?
Uh, I got it stuck.
I was trying to pull out
that stump, and I couldn't...
- Doing something dangerous.
- Yeah, but...
That's a fine
piece of equipment
to leave sinking
in that mud.
Is that the way you
take care of your things?
Well...
Hey.
- Hey!
- There's John.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
- Oh!
Here, Carlene.
- Happy Thanksgiving!
- Hello, John.
- Hi.
- I like this place out here.
Oh, thanks.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
- Hey, Rosie.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- Let's go over and meet John's...
House is beautiful.
Thanks. Thanks for coming.
Hey, how you folks doing?
- John, how are you doing?
- Let me help you out.
- All right.
- Oh, thank you, Carrie.
Mother Maybelle,
that's my mama, Carrie.
Maybelle Carter,
happy to meet you.
This is my daddy...
- Ray.
- Ray, how you doing?
- How are you doing?
- Good to meet you.
- My mama, Carrie.
- How are you doing?
Carrie was going to cook
for y'all, but, uh...
J.R., he doesn't have
a pot or a pan, so...
Well, we're more than happy to
share our food with you folks.
I just moved in, you know?
- Okay, thanks, Carrie.
- Come on inside.
If you're gonna get out
on some big water
like the lakes or river,
you're gonna need something
that you can cast out there
a pretty good ways.
Now if you haven't gotten one
yet, what I want to tell you is...
you need to get you
a Zebco 33.
That's about the best
reel that you can get.
They don't tangle up
very much, and you
can cast 'em
about as far
as you want to throw 'em.
Of course, around the house
there, them little farm ponds...
you don't need nothing
but a cane pole and a float...
and maybe some crickets or
worms, if you can dig them up.
That's all we ever had.
Zebco 33 is probably
your best bet.
I bought June one
when she was about 12 years old.
You remember that?
- That's right, I caught a lot of fish with that.
- Mm-hmm.
You sure did.
So wha...
what do you think, Daddy?
About what?
About the house.
It's a fine,
big house, John.
It's not as big
as Jack Benny's.
You been to Jack Benny's, Ray?
Saw it on the TV.
Carrie, I was meaning to ask you...
did you teach the boys
to play?
Well, J.R.
Always sang pretty...
but I don't think
I could take credit for it.
I bet you did.
I bet you learned
the same way I did.
- Oh, out of the hymnals, sure.
- Hymnals.
I knew you'd
say that.
But you know,
you'd be surprised
how many musicians
can't read
shaped notes nowadays.
I can't imagine.
I know, I know, but my husband's uncle...
E.M. Bays, he taught me
with hymnals, too.
How about you, John?
You know how to read
shaped notes?
John?
Mama asked you
a question, John.
I'm really glad
y'all could be here today...
especially you, Daddy.
I'm glad you came.
To dinner, and
Thanksgiving and all.
Not everybody's here.
Jack's not here, is he?
Huh?
"Where you been?"
That's what you said to me.
Remember?
And I was 12 years old.
You's got Jack's
bloody clothes...
And you said to me,
"Where you been?"
Well?
Where were you?
I quit drinking
a long time ago, J.R.
What about you?
You still taking them pills?
That'll kill you, ya know.
Yeah, well, so will a car wreck.
You're sitting
on a high horse, boy.
I never had talent;
I did the best I could
with what I had.
Can you say that?
Mr. Big Shot.
Mr. Pill-popping rock star?
Ray.
Who are you
to judge?
You ain't got nothin'.
Big, empty house.
Nothin'.
Children
you don't see.
Nothing.
Big old, expensive tractor
stuck in the mud.
Ray...
Nothin'.
Come on!
Do it!
Come on...
You son of a bitch, you.
Come on!
Do it!
Sit in the middle this time.
Come on, you son of a bitch!
John?
Oh, here's a fine
piece of equipment!
John!
You should go down there to him, June.
Mama.
He's mixed up.
I am not going down there.
If I go down...
You already are
down there, honey.
Do it!
More, more, more!
John!
Ah!
John.
June?
Come on.
You should have left me.
John?
Go on ahead, J.R.
You know what that is, J.R.?
Just please, get away from me.!
Daddy?
John?
Hey, John?
Oh, shit! Jesus!
Hey! What?
Hey, John?
Get your ass
out of here, boy!
Hey, John!
Get out of here!
Take your poison with you!
Okay!
Hey.
Mama and I picked these up
down the road.
They're good.
It's good to see you again.
Can I get you
something else?
Just stay.
Okay.
You're an angel.
No, I'm not.
You been here with me.
I had a friend
who needed help.
You're my friend.
But I done so many bad things.
You done a few.
That's true.
My daddy's right.
Should have been me on that saw.
Jack was so good.
He would have done
so many good things.
What have I done?
Just hurt everybody I know.
I know
I've hurt you.
I'm nothing.
You're not nothing.
You are not nothing.
You're a good man.
And God has
given you
a second chance
to make things right, John.
This is your chance, honey.
This is your chance.
Morning.
Hi, how are y'all?
Hey, June?
It's okay.
Come on.
What about the Tropicana?
What's wrong with the Opry?
He was banned after
he smashed up the footlights.
Well, if he smashes
lights at Folsom...
they're going
to keep him there.
Look, Frank.
While Johnny was
out recuperating...
the world changed.
Dylan's gone electric.
The Byrds
are electric.
The Beatles
Hell, everybody's
electric.
He needs a fresh sound...
and all he wants to do is
cut a live album
with the same old pickers
at a maximum-security
penitentiary!
You can talk to me,
you know.
I'm standing
right here.
And what's with
the black?
It's depressing.
Looks like
you're going to a funeral.
Maybe I am.
Your fans are
church folk, Johnny.
Christians.
They don't want
to hear you singing
to a bunch of murderers
and rapists...
trying to cheer
them up.
Well, they're
not Christians, then.
I'm fine with you
doing a live record.
Just not at a prison.
That's my compromise.
January 13...
I'll be at Folsom Prison
with June and the boys.
You listen to the tapes.
You don't like 'em...
you can toss 'em.
Pardon me, Mr. Cash?
M-Mr. Cash?
Mr. Cash?
Might I suggest you refrain
from playing any more tunes
that remind them- the, uh,
the-the inmates, that is-
well, that they're in prison?
You think they forgot?
Perhaps you and your wife
could do another spiritual.
That's not my wife, Warden.
Keep asking her, and
she keeps saying no.
You ever drink this water,
Warden?
No.
I'm a Coca-Cola man.
All right!
I want to remind you,
we're recording live here today...
so you can't say "hell" or
"shit" or anything like that.
I got to tell you,
I can't tell you
how many shows we done...
but this is the best audience
we ever had.
I want to thank you for that.
You know...
standing back there in your
shop, catching my breath...
I come to admire
you even more.
Yeah!
You see, I never had
to do hard time like you...
Yeah!
...although I have on occasion...
gotten myself busted.
Once in El Paso,
I had this bag of... Oh...
you heard about that?
You been in El Paso, too?
Well, anyways...
I felt tough, you know?
Like I'd seen a thing or two,
you know?
Well, that was
till a moment ago...
'cause I got to tell you,
my hat's off to you now.
'Cause I ain't never had
to drink this yellow water
you got here at Folsom.
- All right.
This song's for your warden.
Boom!
In the back.
Hey, June.
June.
What's wrong, John?
Oh...
bad dreams, memories.
Well, you need
to get some rest, sweetie.
You did good tonight.
Well, we got another show
tomorrow.
Yeah.
Hey, listen.
The thing is...
I think it's time
now, you know?
I think it's
about time.
Time for what?
For you and me
to get married.
Go to sleep, John.
I don't want to sleep.
I want to marry you...
and I'm telling you,
it's the time.
Well, I am telling you,
with 100% certainty...
that it is not the time.
It's not about time.
It's not the right time.
It's not even quarter
to the right time.
June.
How do you know? I mean...
You haven't been clean
even six months.
Come on.
Except for a honeymoon,
you have not even thought
about what you're asking me.
Yes, I have.
I have. That's all
I've thought about.
Well, how's it going to work,
John?
Where we going to live?
What about my girls?
- What about your girls?
- Well...
What about
your parents, John?
Your daddy won't
even look at me.
June, that stuff will just
work itself out.
No, it does not work itself out.
People work it out for you...
and you think
it works itself out.
You're scared.
What?
You're scared of being in love.
You're scared of losing control.
And you know what, June Carter?
I think you're scared of living
in my big fat shadow.
- That's your problem.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah. Yeah, it is.
- Is that my problem?
My problem is it's 2:00 a.m.
My problem is I'm asleep.
I'm on a tour bus
with eight stinking men.
Rule number one- don't propose
to a girl on a bus.
You got that?
Rule number two-
don't tell her
it's because
you had a bad dream.
June?
What?
Marry me.
Okay.
Well, that's...
that's the last time I'm asking.
Well, good.
I hate reruns.
Hey, June?
June?
What's that, dear?
I said...
What, you're not talking to me?
You are not allowed
to speak to me tonight.
After that stunt you
pulled on the bus...
the only place you're allowed
to speak to me is on stage.
- Do you understand?
- What did I do?
I don't know.
Why don't you ask your big fat shadow?
Come on, baby.
Baby, baby, baby,
baby, baby.
All right, thank you.
I don't know if y'all know
who wrote that song...
but it's this long-legged gal
standing right here...
Miss June Carter.
Thanks, ya'll.
Thank you very much.
So, uh, June, you going
to stand over there all night...
or you want to come over here
and sing with me?
I'll sing with you,
Mr. Cash.
You sure
that's what you want?
Yeah.
All right. Okay.
Well, folks, what do you say?
You want to hear, uh, "Jackson"?
All right.
Thought you was gonna
wax poetic a little bit longer.
No, I'm done with that, June.
Oh, okay, good.
Sorry for
the interruption, folks...
but, uh, I got to ask
June here a question
before we finish this song.
What's that, John?
Will you marry me?
Why don't we just
sing the song, John?
No, darling.
Come on, finish the song.
People want to hear us sing.
Sorry folks, but, uh...
I just can't do
this song anymore...
unless she's
gonna marry me.
It'd just be like
we're lying.
You got these people
all revved up, John.
- Now come on, let's sing "Jackson" for 'em.
- You got me all revved up.
I've asked you 40 different ways
and it's time you come
up with a fresh answer.
Please, sing.
I'm asking you to marry me.
I love you, June.
Now I know I said
and done a lot of things...
that I hurt you, but I promise
I'll never do that again.
I only want to take care of you.
I will not leave you
like that Dutch boy
with your finger in the dam.
You're my best friend.
Marry me.
All right.
Yeah?
In case none of y'all
heard, she said "yes"!
She's finally said "yes".
Grandpa, here,
let's talk on this.
What do you want me
to do with it?
Well, you... you
listen and you talk.
It's a tin can telephone.
And the sound goes
up the string.
Hello, grandgirls.
Can you hear us?
Hello, Roseanne.
Hello, Carlene.
You got to pull
it tight, Daddy.
Come on, Grandpa.
Talk.
Speak, Grandpa.
- Tell us a story.
- Speak.
- Grandpa!
- Tell us a story.
Here, you take it,
talk to them.
No, they want to talk
to their grandpa.
I don't got no stories.
You got all the stories, Shooter.
Why don't you tell
them about the flood?
Tell them about how you made
a boat out of the front door
and got us all
out of there.
They'll like that.
Tell us!
Come on, tell 'em.
You got to pull
the string tight.
It was 1937...
There was a flood.