After you.
Is this 348?
Yes, it is.
I've got a special delivery
here. That sounds interesting.
It's for Dowd. Dowd's my name. Elwood P.
Here, sir. Let me give you one of my cards.
That won't be necessary.
Just sign right here. Uh-huh.
Beautiful day. Every day's a beautiful day.
Thank you.
He was a nice man.
Come on.
Thank heavens
he's gone!
Oh, Myrtle, it's
a wonderful feeling...
to have your relative out of the
house before the company comes.
You're sure Uncle Elwood won't
come back and spoil everything?
Of course not, dear. Your uncle
always spends the afternoon...
downtown at those filthy bars
and taverns, you know that.
I'll go tell the cateress
to get started.
Why, Miss Johnson, what
are you doing? Leaving.
Miss Johnson, you were hired
to serve as well as cater.
Our guests will be here any
minute. Now, Miss Johnson...
Myrtle, let me handle this,
dear. Miss Johnson, what's wrong?
There was a man here a minute ago
and he stopped and he spoke to me.
You didn't tell him anything about our
party, did you? I didn't tell him nothin'!
He gave me his card. Here. And
then he introduced me to somebody.
To whom? Do you think I'd
stay in this house after that?
Um, well...
Oh!
People get run over by trucks every day.
Why can't that happen to Uncle Elwood?
Myrtle Mae Simmons,
I'm ashamed of you!
Even if people do call your uncle
peculiar, he is still my baby brother...
and this is not his
fault. Whose fault is it?
We'll get the cook to do the
serving. Come and lend me a hand.
We haven't got much time.
Elvira!
If it isn't his fault,
whose fault is it?
I know whose fault it is, but I'm
not telling. You're not telling?
Elvira?
Elvira, you can bring
those things in now.
Mother, why can't we live
like other people?
Do I have
to keep reminding you...
your Uncle Elwood is not living
with us, we're living with him?
Living with him and his pal! You promised!
- His pal Harvey!
- Oh, you said that name.
You promised you wouldn't say
that name and you said it!
Mother, why did grandmother leave
all her property to Uncle Elwood?
I suppose it was because
she died in his arms.
People are sentimental
about things like that.
You always say that
and it doesn't make sense.
She couldn't make out a will after
she died, could she? Don't be didactic.
It's not becoming in a young
girl. Besides, men loathe it.
Men! A fine chance
I've got!
Dear, the whole idea of this
party this afternoon is to...
Is to get you started socially, so
that you can meet some nice young men.
What's the use?
Myrtle Mae Simmons,
her uncle, Elwood P. Dowd,
is the biggest screw...
Screwball in town!
Who'd want me?
Myrtle, dear, you're sweet
and you have so much to offer.
I don't care what anyone says, there's
something sweet about every young girl.
And a man takes that sweetness
and look what he does with it!
Oh, show some poise, dear. I
want you to charm Mrs. Chauvenet.
She has a grandson
just about your age.
A lot of good that'll do if Uncle Elwood
comes home. Uncle Elwood won't be home.
Or will he? I'm going to telephone
Judge Gaffney. We can't take any chances.
Mother,
you better hurry!
Mrs. Halsey and Miss
Tewksbury are here already.
Oh, dear.
Yes, dear, I am hurrying.
Hurry, Mother. They're
getting out of the car.
Oh...
Judge Gaffney, please.
Mrs. Veta Simmons calling.
Yes?
Oh, put her on.
Veta, my girl,
this is a pleasure.
Judge, we haven't got
a moment to lose.
I'm having the Wednesday Forum over
for a program tea for Ethel Chauvenet.
Elwood has just gone out, but
I'm so afraid he may come back.
You can understand why.
Oh!
Hello, Miss Tewksbury,
Mrs. Halsey.
Go right into the drawing room.
Myrtle, take their things.
Yes, you've got to help me,
Judge.
You've got to help me.
I can't...
Speak up, Veta!
What? I can't make out...
Is that so?
Oh, yoo-hoo, Mrs. Streickelberger.
Hello, Mrs. Simmons.
Oh, no, no, no.
Yes, that'll be all right.
You can depend on me.
All right.
Minninger, in a few minutes, a
man will be crossing the square.
He'll be wearing a hat and coat and
carrying another one over his arms.
I want you to follow him. If necessary,
even confront him, quietly, of course.
But at all events, I want you to
prevent him from returning to his house.
His sister is giving a party. He wouldn't
fit in. His name is Elwood P. Dowd.
Elwood Dowd, sir! Couldn't
you get someone else?
Kratke maybe or Beck?
They're bigger than I am.
You'll be able to hide better. Hurry and
stick with him all afternoon. Quickly, boy.
Yes, sir.
Oh, elevator!
Come in.
Yes?
Who is it?
Oh! The doctor
will see you in a minute.
Good afternoon, Mr. Dowd. Howdy do?
We must be
more careful.
After you.
How do, Mr. Dowd? Afternoon, Mr. Cracker.
Excuse me.
How is he? Oh, he's just
fine, fine. How are you?
Oh, can't complain.
That's good.
Is this all right?
You sure, hmm?
Well, all right. Give you a hand
there. Whoop, don't slip! There.
You sure this is all right? You
wouldn't rather sit in a booth?
Well, all right. Would he prefer a booth?
Thank you, Mr. Cracker. He
seems to prefer the bar today.
Good afternoon
to you, sir.
Mr. Meegles is back. Oh!
Well!
You...
Excuse me a minute.
Mr. Meegles, this is a
pleasure! We've missed you.
How are you, Mr. Dowd? Fine.
And how is he? Oh, he's
splendid, thank you. Splendid.
He decided he wanted to come over
here this afternoon, so here we are.
Sit down. Oh, thank you. You've been away.
For 90 days. Been doin' a job for
the state. Makin' license plates.
Oh, is that so?
Interesting work?
I can take it or leave it alone. Oh, I see.
I did a job for 'em last year
too. Helpin' 'em build a road.
Oh. Well, Mr. Meegles, we'll just
have to do something about your return.
Would you like to come to
my house for dinner tonight?
Oh, thanks, Mr. Dowd,
but I couldn't make it tonight.
Ah, tomorrow night?
Would that suit you?
Yes, yes! But you know,
the last time I was there...
I kinda got the impression your sister held
it against me because I did a little time.
Oh, no. My sister loves to
entertain. She's very social.
Yes, I see by the papers. You know
I never miss the society column.
You don't? No. She's giving
a clambake this afternoon.
This afternoon?
Yeah.
"Reception, program and tea,"
it says here,
"for the members of the Wednesday Afternoon
Forum," for that rich Mrs. "Shuvanut."
Cheva... Yes,
that's Aunt Ethel.
Is this today's paper?
Veta didn't tell me anything about
this. Must've slipped her mind.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow
night at 7:00, Mr. Meegles, huh?
Thanks, Mr. Dowd. Very glad
to have seen you. Good-bye.
Harvey,
I just found out...
Now, what can I do for you?
What did you have in mind?
What's your order?
Two martinis.
Harvey, it seems that Veta is
having a party this afternoon.
And l...
Hmm? Oh, you knew?
Well, I just thought she might
be offended if we weren't there.
After all, she's the only sister
I have and l... How's that?
And the only one I'm ever likely to
have. Yes, you're absolutely right.
We'd better hurry, huh?
That'll be
four bits.
The one at the end will pay
for it. Oh, he'd be delighted.
He'd be delighted.
Well...
let's drink up.
My love
Will take me flying
to the sky
On a steed
with golden wings
And then
we'll ride away
Forever high
on the moon
On a star
on a cloud
In his arms
I will stay
Ahh-ahh-ahh-ahh
Ahh
Hop, hop, hop, hop hippity
hop on a golden steed
hop Love is all I need
Ahh-ah, ahh-ah
Hop, hop, hop, hop hippity
hop on a golden steed
hop Love is all I need
Mother.
Shh-shh.
Mrs. Chauvenet is here.
Mrs. Chauvenet is here? Oh.
Aunt Ethel! Veta Louise
Simmons, I thought you were dead.
Oh, no! I'm very much alive, thank you.
And this is my daughter
Myrtle Mae.
My dear, you're your grandmother
all over again. I was at her funeral.
And now, where is Elwood?
Elwood couldn't be home.
That's Miss Tewksbury singing.
She'll be through in a minute.
Oh, shame on him! That was the main
reason I came. I want to see Elwood.
Do you realize, Veta,
I haven't seen Elwood in years?
I was saying to Mr. Chauvenet...
What do you want, my dear?
Just the other night, "What on earth
do you think happened to Elwood Dowd?
"He never comes to
the Yale Alumni Dances anymore.
I haven't seen him at the club
or the horse show in years."
Does Elwood see anybody
these days?
Yes, Aunt Ethel, Elwood sees
somebody. Yes, Aunt Ethel, he does.
Is Elwood happy,
Veta Louise?
Oh, yes, Aunt Ethel, Elwood's
very happy. You mustn't worry.
There's Mrs. Cummings.
She's waving at you.
Is that Mrs. Frank Cummings? Doesn't
she look ghastly? I thought she was dead.
I must get a closer look.
We can go in now. What did I do with my...
Oh, there it is.
Oh, no!
Elwood! Elwood Dowd!
Bless your heart!
Aunt Ethel.
What a pleasure...
to find a beautiful woman waiting
for me. Elwood, you haven't changed.
Elwood!
Well, you both
look lovely.
Some mail came for you. It looked
important so I put it up in your room.
Did you, Veta?
That was nice of you.
Aunt Ethel, I'd like to have
you meet a very dear...
Aunt Ethel, don't you want some
tea? Not just now, thank you.
There's punch if you don't
like tea. But I do like tea.
Stop pulling me,
you two.
Elwood, what night next week can you come
to dinner? You and Veta and Myrtle Mae?
I'll have Ordway there.
Ordway is my grandson.
Any night at all, I'd be
delighted. I'd like to meet Ordway.
And now, Aunt Ethel,
I'd like you to meet Harvey!
Harvey, you've heard me speak of Aunt
Ethel Chauvenet. One of my dearest friends.
She's the one who...
Hmm?
Th-That's right. Well, this
is the one. No, she's the one!
She... He says he would've
known you anywhere.
Well, now we must go in and
greet the rest of our friends.
Come along, Harvey.
Oh, Aunt Ethel,
will you pardon me?
You're standing
in his way.
There we are.
I'll see you in a minute.
I can see that you're disturbed
about Harvey. Please don't be.
He stares that way at
everybody. It's his way.
But he likes you, I can
tell. He likes you very much.
I'm, I'm coming, Harvey.
Well, I... I think
I'll be running along.
No tea? Or punch? No, no. Thank you.
Perhaps a nice lemon fizz...
I'll be going. Good-bye.
with a turkey wing
and some walnut dressing?
Oh, no!
Elwood.
Oh, no.
Not Mrs. Halsey.
She has a nephew. He's a little bit
old, but he would have done in a pinch.
Oh, Mother, I can't face
those people. I just can't!
Your uncle has disgraced us for the last
time in this house. I'm going to see to that.
You're no match for him.
He always gets the best of you.
Where are you going? Upstairs to pack.
I'm going to lose myself in some strange
city. I'm going to change my name!
Don't do that yet,
dear!
Wait until I telephone
Judge Gaff... Judge Gaffney.
I'm going to do something
I should've done long ago.
I don't understand it, Veta. Mr.
Minninger is as trustworthy as the Bible.
I don't know anything about
your Mr. Minninger.
But I do know Elwood Dowd when I see
him and he's here. He's here, I tell you.
If you insist he's there, then I must
act on the assumption that he's there.
Minninger!
You failed!
I didn't fail, Judge.
I haven't tried yet.
I've been in
the doctor's office.
Oh, excuse me.
Hold on, Judge.
Mrs. Halsey, Mrs. Krausmeyer.
You're not leaving, are you?
I just remembered the horse show
is today. Good-bye. It's been jolly.
Won't you join us
tomorrow night?
Harvey and I are having a
few people in for Mr. Meegles.
Forgive me, Mrs. Simmons. One of my
stupid headaches. Such a lovely party.
Good-bye, good-bye.
Elwood, I'd like to talk...
W-W-W...
There.
There we are.
I'd like to talk to you, Elwood.
I like to talk to you too.
This is very important. Would
you mind coming into the library?
Oh, of course, Veta.
Elwood, I want
to talk to you.
Oh!
I want you to wait here.
Don't move. I'll be right back.
Certainly, sister. I happen
to have a little free time now.
You're welcome to all of it,
Veta. Want Harvey to wait too?
Oh, yes! Yes, Elwood.
I certainly do.
Hello! Speak up, I say.
Did you say something,
Harvey? Who said that?
Veta Louise, are you there?
Are you there, girl?
Hello? Veta?
Hello.
Who is it please?
Oh, Judge, I'm so glad you
called. I was going to call you.
Oh, um... Omar,
we've got to take those steps
we discussed once.
Yes. I want you to make
all the arrangements.
Yes.
By all means, yes.
That was Omar. We've been
neglecting the Judge lately.
Veta, do you know that it's been weeks
since Harvey and I've been up to his office?
Let's go tomorrow, shall we?
Elwood, you and I may take a ride.
Oh, I'd like that! Only
the other day Harvey said,
"It's certainly been a long time
since we've been for a drive."
You're sweet and thoughtful. Don't
forget to wait for me. I'll be right back.
Make yourself comfortable,
Harvey.
There.
All right?
Veta wants to talk to us.
She, uh,
says it's very important.
I think she wants
to congratulate us...
on the impression we made
at her party.
Jane Austin.
Sense and Sensibility.
Hmm?
Oh...
Random House.
No, deluxe edition.
Usual acknowledgments.
Chapter One.
"The family of Dashwood had
been long settled in Sussex..."
Will you wait here for me,
Elwood, dear?
You want both of us to
wait? Oh, yes, both of you.
I won't be long.
Driver, driver, will you
keep an eye on him, please?
I won't be but a minute.
Charming place, isn't
it, Harvey? Name's Henry.
It's Henry, Harvey.
No, just plain Henry.
Hmm, oh!
My name's Dowd, Elwood P.
Let me give you one
of my cards.
If you should ever want to
call me, call me at this number.
Don't call me at that one.
That's the old one.
If you happen to lose the card,
don't worry, I have plenty more.
Mrs. O.R. Simmons. 348
Temple Drive. Is that right?
Yes. We were born
and raised there.
It's old, but we love it.
It's our home.
And you wish to enter your brother
at the sanitarium for treatment?
What is your brother's
name? It's... Oh, dear.
Mrs. Simmons,
what is your brother's name?
I'm sorry. Life is
not easy for any of us.
It's Dowd.
Elwood P. Dowd.
His age?
Forty-two
the 24th of last April.
He's Taurus,
Taurus the bull.
I'm Leo, and Myrtle's on the
cusp. You have him with you now?
Oh, yes. He's outside
waiting in a taxi cab.
I told him to wait. He
always does what I tell him.
I see. Is he married?
No, Elwood never married.
He always stayed with
Mother. He loved his home.
Yeah? Wilson, there's a
Mr. Dowd outside in a cab.
Will you ask him if he'll be good enough
to step up to room 24 South Wing "G"?
Ask him? Wilson, this is
his sister, Mrs. Simmons.
Oh, how do?
Why certainly.
I'll be glad to escort him.
I'll see if Dr. Sanderson
can see you, Mrs. Simmons.
Dr. Sanderson? I want to
see Dr. Chumley himself.
Dr. Sanderson is the one who sees
everybody. Dr. Chumley sees no one.
I'll tell him
you're here.
l-lsn't this wonderful, Veta? Okay, buddy!
Oh, you startled me!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Simmons.
I am Dr. Sanderson. Oh.
Miss Kelly tells me you're concerned
about your brother, Mister, uh, Mister...
The card, Miss Kelly.
Miss Kelly!
The card, please.
Mr. Dowd? Elwood P. Dowd. This way.
I'm sorry if I awakened you,
Miss Kelly.
I'm so...
I do hope you don't think
I'm always as jumpy as this.
This is not easy for me,
Doctor.
These things aren't easy
for the family. I understand.
Won't you sit down,
Miss Simmons? Thank you.
How long has it been since you first noticed
any peculiarity in your brother's actions?
As a baby,
he was perfectly normal.
I know. I was his big sister
and I had to change him.
Babies do need changing,
you know.
I noticed that he seemed
to be different...
after we came back
after Mother had died.
Myrtle Mae and I came back from
Des Moines to live with Elwood.
I could see that he...
That he...
That he what?
Take your time.
Don't strain.
Just, just let it come.
I'll wait for it.
Doctor, everything I say to
you is confidential, isn't it?
I am not a gossip. I am
a psychiatrist. Of course.
For one thing, he
drinks. Mm-hmm. To excess?
To excess?
Don't you call it excess when
a man never lets a day go by...
without stepping
into some cheap tavern,
bringing home a lot of riffraff,
people you never heard of?
If you don't call that excess, Doctor,
I'm sure I don't know what excess is.
I didn't doubt
your statement.
I merely wanted to know
if your brother drinks.
Yes, I say definitely
Elwood drinks. Mm-hmm.
I want him committed
out here permanently...
because I cannot stand
another day of that Harvey!
Don't you think it would have been
a little bit kinder of Mother...
if she'd written us about
him. Now, be honest. Don't you?
I really couldn't answer
that question. I can!
Yes, it certainly
would have.
This person
that you call Harvey,
who is he?
He's a rabbit.
Yes, perhaps.
But just who is he?
Someone your brother picked up
in one of these bars?
I've been telling you,
Harvey is a rabbit!
A big white rabbit six feet high,
or is it six feet, three and a half?
Heaven knows, I ought to know. He's
been around the house long enough!
Mrs. Simmons, if I'm not
mistaken... Don't you understand?
The rabbit's name
is Harvey.
Harvey lives
at our house.
Elwood buys theater tickets and
railroad tickets for both of them.
He's lost interest
in everything else.
And here I am trying to get
Myrtle Mae started...
with a nice group
of young people.
That's my daughter.
Doctor,
I'm going to tell you something
I've never told anyone in this world.
Not even Myrtle Mae.
Every once in a while, I see
this big white rabbit myself!
Isn't that terrible!
And what's more, he's every
bit as big as Elwood says he is!
Don't ever tell that to anybody,
Doctor. I'm ashamed of it.
I can see that you've been under
a great nervous strain lately.
You just try living with those two
and see how much of a strain it is.
Your mother's death, it
depressed you considerably.
Nobody knows how much.
Don't you worry. I'm going
to help you. Oh, Doctor!
Miss Kelly. Miss Kelly!
Wilson? Wilson!
Don't you move. You just sit there
and make yourself comfortable.
I'll only be a minute. Yes.
Wilson? Wilson!
Hello?
Lady, you told me to keep an eye on that
fella, but a big guy in a white coat came...
That's quite all right.
You just wait.
Do you want I should do
something about his suitcase?
Oh, Elwood's things. Yes, I
better come get them, I guess.
He might need them. Oh dear, it would
be awful if he should get hurt and...
She picked a fine time to leave her desk
just when I've got a new patient in my office.
Mrs. Simmons?
Mrs. Simmons!
Sound the gong. That poor woman mustn't
leave the grounds. Made a getaway, huh, Doc?
Her condition is serious. Go after her
and take her to 13 Upper West "R." Right.
Where is she? That little dame
that just came out, where'd she go?
She's picking some posies. She wants
to bring 'em to somebody inside.
Mac, is it safe for me
to wait around?
I don't see no bars on these
windows. Don't need 'em.
Anybody tries to climb through those
windows will sound like a three-alarm fire.
Hello, sweetheart.
Well, well. Those for me?
For you? I should say not.
They're for my brother Elwood.
He's devoted to ranunculus. Sure.
Wouldn't you like to come inside
and pick some off the wallpaper?
No, thank you. These
will do nicely. Good day.
Lady. Come, lady. Now, really, l...
There's a man inside wants to
talk to you. No, I don't... No!
No! You let me go! Help. Help! Police!
What do we want with the police,
love boat? They're no fun.
You let me go! I'm a respectable
woman! That's for sure.
Come on, lady, be nice or I'll
have to pick you up and carry you.
Help!
Oh, Dr. Sanderson!
Judge Gaffney!
How about giving me a hand,
beautiful?
I'll sit on her.
You can strip her clothes off.
You'll have to wait. I've got
to give some guy a bubble bath.
Okay, honey,
but make it snappy.
Somebody help me!
Doc, that Simmons dame's all
set. Yeah, no trouble at all.
That's fine. I'll be right up and
prescribe some preliminary treatment.
Don't you ever stay in your office?
I needed you! I had to give a hypo.
Telephone this Elwood P. Dowd right
away. His sister's condition is serious.
But, Doctor, l... He'll have to
sign these commitment papers for her.
I didn't know the woman needed the
treatment. She said it was her brother.
Of course she did! That's
the oldest dodge in the world.
Always used by
a cunning type of psychopath.
She knew her brother was about to commit
her, so she came here to discredit him.
Get him on the phone, please. I
thought the woman was all right...
so I had Wilson take the
brother up to 24 South Wing "G."
He's there now. You had
Wilson take the brother in?
Come on, no gags, please.
You're not serious, are you?
I did, Doctor. I did.
Doctor, I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, you're terribly sorry! Well,
that's fine! That fixes everything!
That's just wonderful!
Oh, no! Kelly! Kelly, do
you realize what you've done?
This man Dowd can sue us for false
commitment! He can own the sanitarium!
And I'll be kicked outta here faster than you
can say "stupid, incompetent and inefficient."
I'll tell Dr. Chumley you had nothing
to do with it. It was all my fault.
You're the last person I'd ever
want anything like this to happen to.
You know that,
don't you?
This is hardly the time or place to go into
the balcony scene from Romeo and Juliet.
Lately, Doctor, there's
never any time or place!
Jeepers! They may be putting him in
the hydro room right now. Get him down!
I'll break the news to Dr.
Chumley. He may want to handle this.
What shall I say to Mr. Dowd?
What'll I do?
He'll probably be so furious
he'll refuse to come down.
He's probably fit to be tied,
but he's a man, isn't he?
I guess so.
His name is "Mister."
Then go into your routine. You
know, the eyes, the swish, the works!
I'm immune to it, but I've seen it work
on some people. Some of the patients!
You get him down here
if you have to do a striptease.
Dr. Chumley, I'm afraid
there's been a serious error.
Dr. Sanderson, we don't permit
errors in this institution.
Mr. Dowd?
Elwood P. Here, let me
give you one of my cards.
Mr. Dowd, I'm Miss Kelly. I'm
at the reception desk downstairs.
I'm happy to know you, Miss
Kelly. Thank you, Mr. Dowd.
I was wondering if you would come
downstairs with me to Dr. Sanderson's office.
There's something he'd like to
explain to you. Uh-huh. I'd be glad to.
But there was another very charming
girl in here. And she asked me to wait.
She said something
about a bath.
I don't like to disappoint her. She
seemed to have her heart set on it.
That was Miss Dunphy.
It's quite all right, Mr. Dowd.
Dr. Sanderson will explain everything
in his office. Well, here we are.
Tsk-tsk. Mr. Dowd,
you haven't peeled yet.
And I regret this, but Miss Kelly
seems to want me to go with her.
Miss Kelly, you've met
Miss Dunphy? Yes, of course.
I want you to meet a very dear... There's
been a mistake. Just forget everything.
I have a suggestion. Why don't I do
what she wants, and then go with you?
That won't be necessary, Mr.
Dowd. All right. Good-bye, my dear.
You could've had
a bath too.
I've already had a bath. Oh, I wasn't
speaking to you. I was speaking to my fr...
Mr. Dowd, I take a bath every
morning just before I go on duty.
It's always such a pleasant way
to start the day.
Oh, after you.
Mr. Dowd?
Elwood P.
Let me give you one
of my cards.
I am Dr. Lyman Sanderson, Dr.
Chumley's assistant. And l...
Good for you! Happy to know you. Yes.
I asked Miss Kelly to bring you
down here... Isn't she lovely?
You're very lovely,
my dear.
Why thank you! Some people
don't seem to think so.
Well, some people are blind. That's
very often brought to my attention.
I'd like both of you to meet a very dear
friend of mine... Why can't we sit down?
Won't you have a chair?
Well, thank you very much.
There we are.
Please, sit down.
After Miss Kelly.
No, really, Mr. Dowd. I couldn't. I'm
in and out. But you sit down, please.
After you.
Sit down, Kelly!
Anything we can do for you, Mr.
Dowd? What did you have in mind?
Is your chair comfortable? Is the
chair quite comfortable, Mr. Dowd?
Yes. Care to try it? No, no, no,
thank you. How 'bout a cigarette?
No, thank you.
Yes, a cigarette...
Mr. Dowd, you have us
at a disadvantage here.
You know it and we know it, so
let's lay our cards on the table.
That appeals
to me, Doctor.
Best thing in the long run. People
are people no matter where you go.
That is very often
the case.
And being human,
are liable to make mistakes.
Miss Kelly and I, we've made a mistake
this afternoon and we'd like to explain it.
The truth is... You and Miss Kelly here?
Yes.
Out here this afternoon? Yes, Mr. Dowd.
We hope you'll understand. Oh, yes, yes.
These things are often the basis
of a very long, warm friendship.
It wasn't Dr. Sanderson's
fault. It was mine.
No, the responsibility
is all mine!
Your attitude may be old-fashioned,
but I like it very much.
Of course, If I had seen
your sister first,
this would've been
an entirely different story.
There you surprise me.
I think the world and all of Veta,
but I had supposed she'd seen her day.
You mustn't attach too much blame
to her. She's a very sick woman.
She came in here insisting that you needed
treatment. That's perfectly ridiculous.
Veta shouldn't be upset
about me. I get along fine.
She was extremely upset and plunged right
away into a heated tirade about your drinking.
Ahh!
That was Veta.
I tell Veta not to worry about
that. I'll take care of that.
Exactly! Oh, I suppose that you take a
drink now and then like the rest of us.
M-M-M-M...
Yes, yes I do, Doctor.
As a matter of fact,
I'd like one right now.
so would I.
But her reaction to the whole
matter was entirely too intense.
Does she drink, Mr. Dowd?
Oh, no, oh, no. I don't think
Veta's ever taken a drink.
I am going to surprise you. I
think she has and does constantly.
She... Is that...
Well, I certainly
am surprised at that.
Her alcoholism isn't
the basis for my diagnosis.
It was when she became so emotional
about this big white rabbit Harvey.
Yes, I believe she called
him Harvey. Harvey's his name!
Doctor, before we go any
further, I must insist...
that you and Miss Kelly allow me
to introduce you to a friend...
Let me make my point.
I think your sister's condition
stems from trauma.
From what? Trauma.
Spelled T-R-A-U-M-A.
It means shock. There's
nothing unusual about it.
There's the birth trauma,
or the shock of being born.
That's the one
we never get over.
You have a very nice sense of humor.
Hasn't he, Miss Kelly? Oh, he certainly has!
May I say the same
for both of you?
Your sister's condition is
serious, but I can help her.
She must, however, remain
out here temporarily.
Uh-huh. Well, I've always wanted Veta
to have everything she needs. Exactly!
But I wouldn't want her to stay here
unless she likes it and wants to stay here.
If this were an ordinary delusion on the
memory picture, that would be one thing.
But this is
much more serious.
It stands to reason no one has ever
seen a white rabbit six feet high.
Not very often,
Doctor.
So she must be committed
here temporarily.
Under the circumstances, I'd
commit my own grandmother.
Does your grandmother
drink too?
That's just an expression.
Here are the commitment papers for you
to sign, and here's a visitor's pass.
You can come and see her
whenever you like.
I think you better
have Veta do this.
She always does all the signing and
managing for our family. She's good at it.
I'll have your family lawyer
take care of it. Judge Gaffney.
He's already telephoned us in
connection with this matter.
Is that so?
Yes.
I like you, Dowd. Well,
I like you too, Doctor.
And Miss Kelly here.
I certainly do like you.
Why, thank you,
Mr. Dowd.
You two have been so pleasant,
why don't we keep on going?
I'd like to invite you
to come downtown with me...
and we'll go to this charming little place
called Charlie's and we'll have a drink.
Oh, I'm sorry,
but we're on duty now.
Give us a rain check. Some
other time, we'd be glad to.
When? Well, I can't say offhand.
Miss Kelly and I are
on duty until 10:00 tonight.
10:00 will be fine. I'll be waiting
for you. It's at Twelfth and Main.
If we can make it.
I'll be waiting.
The four of us will spend a
very pleasant evening together.
I want both of you to become friends
with a very dear friend of mine.
But you said later on,
didn't you? Yes, yes.
Later on it'll be.
Good-bye. Good-bye, Mr. Dowd.
Boy, that was
a close shave!
But he seemed like a
reasonable sort of a fellow.
You handled him beautifully,
Doctor. You were wonderful.
Psychology. Specialized
training. Takes years of it.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Chumley.
Good afternoon, Herman.
Oh, stop the car
a moment, Wesley.
Yoo-hoo!
Is there something I can do for
you? What did you have in mind?
You were walking on my husband's
prized dahlias. I'm Dr. Chumley's wife.
Oh, Dowd's my name. Elwood
P. Let me give you...
Looking for someone over
there? Yes. My friend Harvey.
I turned my back for an instant
and he seems to have wandered off.
I wish you could meet him,
Mrs. Chumley.
I'm sure he'd be quite taken
with you. Oh, thank you!
You're very nice to say so. Oh, not at all.
Mrs. Chumley, would you care to come downtown
with me? I'd be happy to buy you a drink.
Oh, I can't. My husband and I
are going to a cocktail party.
Dr. McClure is giving a party
for his sister from Wichita.
Oh! I didn't know Dr. McClure
had a sister in Wichita.
You know Dr. McClure?
No.
But you... But are you sure you wouldn't
have time to come with me and have a drink?
No, I can't. I'll tell
you what I'll do, however.
What will you do, however?
I'm interested.
If I meet your friend inside, I'll
be glad to give him a message for you.
Would you do that for me? I
certainly would appreciate that.
Just tell him to meet me
downtown if he has no other plans.
Any particular place
downtown? No, he knows where.
Harvey knows this town like a book.
How will I recognize your friend?
Oh, you can't miss him,
Mrs. Chumley. He's a "pooka."
A pooka?
Is that something new?
No, no. As I understand it,
that's something very old.
But Harvey's not only a pooka,
he's also my best friend.
Oh, if Harvey's said to me once, I'll
bet he's said probably a million times.
He said, "Mr. Dowd,
I would do anything for you."
How sweet.
Yeah. He's also very fond
of my sister Veta.
But Veta doesn't seem
to care for Harvey.
Don't you think that's rather
too bad, Mrs. Chumley?
I don't know. I gave up long ago
expecting my family to like my friends.
It's useless! We must
keep on trying, mustn't we?
Oh, yes.
Well, good-bye.
Good-bye.
Leslie, did he say
"pooka"?
Yes, ma'am.
That's what the man said.
Your pass? Oh! Yes, sir.
There you are.
Dowd.
Elwood P.
Isn't that interesting! Yes,
I constructed this myself.
Is that so? Well, I'll
declare! It's very simple. See?
Closed.
Opened.
You're a very brilliant man. Thank you.
My name is Herman Shimelplatzer,
but everybody calls me Herman.
You're to be congratulated,
Mr. Shimelplatzer. Thank you.
Would you care to come over to my
house for dinner tomorrow night?
I'm having a few friends in,
just informally.
I certainly would. That's
very nice of you, Mr. Dowd.
Let me give you one
of my cards.
If you should want to call me,
call me at this number.
Don't call me at that one.
That's the old one. Good-bye.
That's remarkable.
I hate to take you away, Willie, but we
did promise Dr. McClure we'd be there early.
One moment, angel. My hat and
coat, Miss Kelly. Yes, Dr. Chumley.
Dr. Sanderson. I'm leaving
for the day. Yes, Doctor?
About the difficulty of this woman with the
big white rabbit. Has it been smoothed over?
Yes, Doctor.
Good.
I've had many patients out here with
animals, but never an animal that large.
Yes, Doctor. She called him
Harvey. Unusual name for an animal.
I want her to have a hypo at
6:00, with another one at 9:00.
Willie... Yes, I'm
coming. My formula 9-7-7.
Listen, Willie...
Somebody's gonna have to give me a hand
with that Simmons dame. She's terrible!
I had to take her corset off
all by myself!
Hiya, Dr. Chumley.
How's every little...
Hey, what's with you and that hat? Hat?
Here's your hat.
I'm wearing my hat.
There was something... This
isn't my hat. Must be yours.
No, mine is... Of course it's not yours.
I'd like to say... No, dear,
of course it's not yours.
But whose hat is it?
He won't let me talk.
Look at this!
Two holes cut in the crown.
It's probably some new fad.
Perhaps Mr. Dowd left it here, sir. Dowd?
Yes, that's what I was... That's Mrs.
Simmons' brother. I gave him a pass.
I've been trying to tell you. I met a
gentleman at the gate. His name was Dowd.
He said he was looking for
a friend of his named Harvey.
Harvey?
Yes! Yes, Harvey.
Holy smoke! I left the water running
on that Simmons dame in a hydro tub!
Why are you looking at me like that,
Willie? He was a nice, polite man.
He said his friend was a
pooka. Whatever that is.
Gimme Upper West "R."
Where did he go, Mrs.
Chumley? He went downtown.
Dunphy, I left that
Simmons dame soakin' in 13.
Do me a favor.
Turn off thejuice.
So you gave him a pass!
Perhaps they neglected to tell you at
medical school that a rabbit has pointed ears!
Do you know what
you've done?
You've allowed a psychopathic case to
roam around with an overgrown white rabbit!
You've laid me open
to a lawsuit!
I shall have to do something
I haven't done for 15 years.
I'll have to go after this
man, Dowd, and bring him back!
But when I do, Dr. Sanderson, your connection
with this institution will have ended.
Wilson, get the car. You'll have
to go to the McClure's without me.
Take a cab. You two, get
that woman out of the tub!
Willie? I'm going to call my attorney.
Wilson, what's a pooka? What's a what?
A pooka.
A pooka?
You could search me,
Mrs. Chumley!
"P." "O."
Poo... Pooka!
Oh dear, I'm already late
for the McClure's.
I did promise them
I'd be on time.
P-O-O-K-A.
"Pooka.
From old Celtic mythology.
"A fairy spirit
in animal form.
"Always very large.
"The pooka appears
here and there,
"now and then,
"to this one and that one.
"A benign but
mischievous creature.
"Very fond of rumpots,
crackpots...
and 'How are you,
Mr. Wilson?"'
"How are you,
Mr. Wilson?"
Who in the encyclopedia
wants to know?
Wilson, let's go. Dr. Chumley,
the screwiest thing just hap...
I know, and believe me, heads
will roll. But I was looking...
Quick, downtown.
Step on it.
Oh. Where's your mother? Where is she?
She took Uncle Elwood out to the
sanitarium. I thought you knew.
She just called me on the phone
at the club. She's hysterical.
Where's your phone? In the library.
What was Mother hysterical about?
I don't know. I couldn't make
out what she was talking about.
She was carrying on something fierce.
Where's the number of that sanitarium?
I'll look it up. I don't know
what Mother had to carry on about.
All she had to do was have Uncle
Elwood locked up. Maybe that's it.
I feel bad about havin' Elwood
locked up. I always liked that boy.
He could've done anything, been anything,
made a place for himself in the community.
And all he did was get a
big rabbit. Yeah, I know.
He's had that rabbit in my office many
a time. I'm old, but I don't miss much.
What's the name of this place?
Chumley's what? Chumley's Rest.
Yeah, Elwood had everything.
Brains, personality and friends.
Men liked him. Women
liked him. I liked him!
Women liked him?
Uncle Elwood? Mother!
Myrtle!
Veta Louise!
What's wrong, girl? I thought
I'd never see either of you again.
Take hold of her. She looks like
she's going to faint. Not so fast.
Don't rush her. Ease her in.
Get me where I can sit down.
There you are. Get her some
tea. Let me sit down somewhere.
You want some tea? Oh,
no. I don't want any tea.
The minute their backs were turned,
I ran like a frightened rabbit.
Oh, I didn't mean to say that!
I don't know what I'm saying.
Just let me sit here. Let me get
my breath. Let her get her breath.
Let me get my breath and then let me get
upstairs to my own bed where I can let go.
Mother,
what happened?
I want you to sue them. They
put me in and let Elwood out.
What's this? As I was going to the
taxi cab to get Elwood's things,
this awful man stepped out, he
was a white slaver, I know he was.
He was wearing one of those white
suits. That's how they advertise.
What did he do? He grabbed hold of
me and took me in there, and he...
Oh!
Go on, Veta. Go on,
Mother. Was he a young man?
Myrtle Mae, perhaps you'd better
leave the room. Now? I should say not.
Go on, Mother.
What'd he do, Veta?
He took me upstairs
and tore my clothes off.
Did you hear that?
Go on, Mother.
And then he dumped me
down in a tub of water.
Oh, for heaven's sake! By
Godfrey, I'll sue them for this!
I always thought that what
you were showed in your face.
Don't you believe it, Judge,
Myrtle Mae.
That man grabbed hold of me as
though I was a woman of the streets.
But I fought. I always said that
if a man jumped at me, I'd fight.
Haven't I always said that,
Myrtle Mae?
She's always said that. That's
what Mother's always told me to do.
He hustled me into the sanitarium
and dumped me in that tub of water...
and treated me as though I was a... A what?
A crazy woman. But he
did that just for spite.
Well, I'll be swizzled!
Then one of those doctors...
came upstairs and asked me
a lot of questions.
All about sex urges
and all that filthy stuff.
That place ought to be
cleaned up, Judge.
You ought to get the authorities
to clean it up.
Don't you ever go out there.
You hear me, Myrtle Mae?
This stinks to high heaven.
By Godfrey, it stinks!
Is that all those doctors do in
places like that, think about sex?
I don't know. Because if it is, they
ought to be ashamed of themselves.
It's all
in their heads anyway.
Why don't they take long
walks in the fresh air?
Judge Gaffney walked everywhere
for years, didn't you, Judge?
Did you? I better take some notes on this.
You said one of the doctors
came up to talk to you?
Yes. Dr. Sanderson. But don't pay
any attention to anything he says.
He's a liar. Close-set
eyes. They're always liars.
Besides, I told him something in
strictest confidence and he blabbed it.
You can't trust anyone!
What did you tell him? What
difference does it make?
I don't want to think about it.
I don't want to talk about it.
Anything you told Dr. Sanderson,
you can tell us.
This is your daughter, and I'm
your lawyer. I know which is which.
I don't want to talk about
it. I want to sue them.
And I want to get upstairs
to my own bed.
I should never have tried
to do anything about Elwood.
Something protects him.
That awful pooka.
Where is Uncle Elwood? How
should I know? They let him go!
They're not interested
in men at places like that.
You ought to know that,
Myrtle Mae. Don't be so naive.
Mother, no matter who jumped at you, we still
have to find Uncle Elwood and lock him up.
The next time,
you take him, Judge.
Oh, wait 'til Elwood hears what they
did to me. He won't stand for it.
You've got to sue them.
Myrtle Mae, I hope that
never, as long as you live,
a man tears the clothes off you
and sets you down in a tub of water.
Oh, there he is now! He's
after me! Stay where you are!
Knock him down, Judge. Kick
him! Don't let him get me!
Veta, please. I want you to
confront this man with your charges.
I don't want no part of that wacky dame.
I'm looking for that other screwball.
He's gotta go back to
Chumley's Rest. Kick him, Judge!
Veta, did you hear that?
Where is he? Where is
this guy, Elwood P. Dowd?
That screwball
with a rabbit.
What's the matter, you goofy too?
You a member of this cockeyed family?
I'm Mrs. Simmons' daughter.
Uncle Elwood is my uncle.
Look, kid, I've been to four fires and
14 gin mills lookin' for that crackpot.
A bartender give me a tip he
was here. Came with a bundle.
Now, where is he? What'd you
do with him? You hidin' him?
No...
I'm not hiding him.
Hey, my name's Marvin
Wilson, honey. What's yours?
Myrtle Mae. And I'm not
afraid of you. Myrtle Mae, huh?
If we grab your uncle, you'll be comin'
to the sanitarium on visitin' days.
Really, I don't know.
If you do, I'll be there.
You will? If you don't see me right
away, stick around. I'll show up.
Won't you sit down?
I got no time, kid.
I gotta find that uncle of yours
and be on my way. Now, where is he?
Where'd you put him? I
didn't put him anywhere.
I want you to catch him just as
much as you want to catch him.
I can't even have any callers
when he's around.
You shouldn't have any trouble about
callers, honey. Thank you very much.
I'll tell you something, Myrt. Yeah?
You not only got a nice build,
but you got something else too.
Really? What?
You got the screwiest uncle that ever
stuck his puss inside our nuthouse.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
I can't, kid. Dr. Chumley's
checking all the police stations.
I better catch up with him. You look
awfully hungry. How about a sandwich?
Yeah, but I don't want that crazy dame
on my neck. Don't worry about Mother.
She won't come down.
She's too frightened.
Would you like a ham and rye?
How about an egg and onion?
I'd love to make you one. The eggs
and onions are waiting in the kitchen.
Suppose we go in the kitchen.
You can relax and be yourself.
Do you like your work?
Oh, I do now, Myrtle!
Charlie's Place?
Oh, Mr. Cracker.
Mr. Cracker, this is
Elwood P. Dowd speaking.
Tell me,
have you seen Harvey?
Uh-huh. Well, don't worry. I'll find him.
Mr. Cracker, I'm entertaining some
friends there tonight at 10:00.
May I have
my regular booth?
Oh, fine. Thank you.
Good-bye.
Harvey!
Harvey?
Hello?
Come on. Don't you wanna come back
in the kitchen and get acquainted?
I thought I heard voices.
What kind of voices?
Come on, I wanna talk to you. It
sounded something like "Harvey."
Harvey? I'd better get goin'. You
haven't finished your egg and onion.
Business before pleasure, even
if it's a pleasure bein' with you.
You make a great egg and
onion. Don't you want more?
I'll see you tomorrow out at the
nuthouse. You didn't finish your sandwich.
Wilson! What happened to
you? He's not here, Doctor.
Then what are you doing
here? I was just having...
What are you eating? An
egg and onion sandwich.
How can you think of food at a time
like this? Get over to Union Station.
I'm told Dowd goes down there to
watch trains. All right, Doctor.
Why did you send him away? Some
people pick the best times...
to keep other people from becoming
acquainted. My, dear... Judge Gaffney!
Chumley, just the man
I want to see.
Mrs. Simmons has retained me to file
suit against you. I've been searching...
File suit? I'm on my way to the
office to draw up the necessary papers.
What happened this afternoon was an unfortunate
mistake, but I've dismissed my assistant...
We shall see what we shall
see. There must be some way...
You'll hear from me in the morning.
Good-bye. But surely, Judge...
This is
most unfortunate.
Most unfortunate.
Judge Gaffney?
Judge Gaffney, I want...
You're not Judge Gaffney.
You have much more hair
than he has.
Besides, I never forget
a face. I'm Dr. Chumley.
You're Mrs. Simmons. Yes, of course.
I'm glad to know you, Dr. Chumley.
Would you mind asking Judge
Gaffney to come back? Certainly.
I want to tell him to sue you for $
100,000. I don't think $50,000 is enough.
Mrs. Simmons,
can't we talk this matter over?
After what happened to me today in the
bathtub? I don't want to talk it over!
Then will you please
just listen?
I don't want to listen to you.
I'm suing you.
Please listen to me, I beg of
you. I'll listen, all right.
But I'm warning you, it
won't do you any good. Hello.
No, I am not listening to my radio.
I am listening to Dr. Chumley.
Mrs. Simmons, that picture
over the mantle?
That portrait of my mother happens
to be the pride of this house.
Who painted it? Some
man. I forget his name.
He was around for the sittings.
Then we paid him and he went away.
I suppose if you have the money, you
can persuade people to do anything.
You brought this up. You might
as well learn something quickly.
I took a course in art last winter.
I learned the difference between...
a fine oil painting and a
mechanical thing, like a photograph.
The photograph shows
only the reality.
The painting shows not only the
reality, but the dream behind it.
It's our dreams
that carry us on.
They separate us
from the beasts.
I wouldn't want to go on living if I
thought it was all just eating and sleeping.
And taking my clothes off.
I mean, putting them on.
Ooh, ooh!
Oh, Doctor!
Mrs. Simmons, steady now,
steady. Don't upset yourself.
Everything's going to be
all right. What's the matter?
Doctor, that is not
my mother!
I'm very glad
to hear that.
Elwood's been here. He's been here,
Doctor! Now, now, better be quiet.
I'll take it.
Hello? Yes?
Who's calling?
He's here! It's your
brother! Let me talk to him.
Be careful. Don't let him
know that I'm here. Be casual.
Yes, I'll be casual.
Yes.
Hello, Elwood.
Where are you, dear?
I'm here, Veta.
l-ls Harvey there?
He won't say where he is. He
wants to know if Harvey's here.
Tell him Harvey is here. But he isn't!
I know that, but pretend he
is. We've got to humor him.
Hello, Elwood.
Yes, dear, Harvey's here.
Why don't you come home?
It won't work. He wants us
to call Harvey to the telephone.
Well, say Harvey's here but he can't come
to the phone because he's in the bathtub.
Oh, Doctor! You've got
to do it, Mrs. Simmons.
Yes, dear, Harvey is here, but he can't
come to the telephone. He's in the bathtub.
I'll send him over as soon as
he's dry. Where are you, dear?
I-I-I'm...
Never mind. Harvey just
walked in the door down here.
Oh... Mr. Cracker,
two martinis.
Good-bye, Veta.
You'd better look in the
bathtub. It must be a stranger.
He says Harvey just walked through the
door. It must be a stranger in the bathtub.
But I know where he is.
He's at Charlie's Place.
That's a bar at 12th and Main.
That's two over and one down.
Where are you going? I'm going to
get your brother and bring him back,
take him to the sanitarium
where he belongs.
I want to observe the expression on
his face when he talks to this rabbit.
He does talk to the rabbit?
They tell each other everything.
What? Yes, he talks to
him, but don't go out there.
You'll regret it if you do.
Nonsense. You underestimate me
No, you underestimate my brother.
Don't worry. I can handle him.
You can handle him?
That's what you think.
Myrtle Mae, see who the
stranger is in the bathtub.
Sounds funny,
but I'll miss this place.
I guess I'll miss
a lot of things around here.
You will?
You won't laugh?
Of course not.
You know how it is working around people
day after day. You get attached to them.
I know, Lyman. It may be
ridiculous, but I'm gonna miss...
every one of the psychos and
neuros and schizos in the place.
I guess I'll even miss
Dr. Chumley.
In spite of the fact that he fired me,
I have a genuine admiration for him.
You can miss your psychos
and schizos, Dr. Sanderson!
You can miss whomever you
please. But after you leave here,
I won't miss a thing,
not a single, solitary thing!
Now what's wrong? Nothing. I
came down to say good-bye to you.
So good-bye, good luck
and good riddance!
You can't even say good-bye without
putting it on a personal basis.
Don't flatter yourself. There's
nothing personal about this.
I think you've been working too
hard. You're getting neurotic.
Don't start analyzing me. Save
your psychiatry for your next job!
I'm not using psychiatry. And let
me give you a little friendly advice.
That chip on your shoulder stems from a
persecution complex that goes back to childhood.
Thanks so much for
the case history, Doctor.
Could you tell me what an overinflated
ego stems from? Now, listen here!
Hiya, Kelly.
Hiya, Doc.
I'm glad I caught you
before you left.
I'm sorry you got bounced. We're
all gonna miss ya. Thanks, Wilson.
Any of the patients been acting
up? Everything's just peachy!
That's good. When are
you takin' off? Right now.
I was waiting
for Dr. Chumley to get back.
Wait a second. Didn't Dr. Chumley
come back with that pyscho?
We thought he was with you. No.
I left him with that Simmons dame.
When I called back later to check with him,
she told me the Doctor went to bring her bro...
That was four hours ago! Have
you any idea where he went?
Yeah. No!
Come on, come on.
I don't know. I can't think. Poor Dr. Chumley
may be layin' in an alley in a pool of blood.
Mr. Dowd seemed harmless
this afternoon.
I've been wrestling these guys for
years, and they're pretty tricky.
One minute they're sweet, and the
next minute... they give you the knife.
The name of the place? It was
a barroom and a guy's name.
Charlie! Charlie's Place.
That's a lead. We'll start there.
Never mind. I'll go with
Wilson. You needn't bother.
Until Dr. Chumley comes back,
I'm still in charge here!
Let's get goin'. Let's not
stand and argue about it.
Yeah,
this is the place.
What'll it be, folks? We're
looking for someone, two men.
A tall, short one and a thin, fat one. I'm
so nervous, I don't know what I'm sayin'.
One man is short and middle-aged.
The other is much taller and younger.
They might have been here about
four hours ago. No, can't say I have.
We've been running
medium sizes all evenin'.
The tall man was soft-spoken and
sort of polite. His name is Dowd.
Dowd? Why didn't you say so?
He's here now in the back booth.
Is he alone? Well, there's
two schools of thought, sir.
If that crackpot did anything to
Dr. Chumley, I'll knock his teeth...
No rough stuff. Psychology.
I'll do the talking.
Well, I've been expecting
you. Where's the Doctor?
Wilson! Why don't you
take a look around the place?
Why don't you do that? Although
I don't believe it's for sale.
Miss Kelly,
these are for you.
Why, thank you, Mr.
Dowd! A pleasure, my dear.
You know, after what happened this afternoon,
these flowers really should be from you.
Now, won't you join me? Mr.
Dowd, I'm afraid we can't do that.
The situation has changed since this
afternoon, but I urge you to have no resentment.
Dr. Chumley is your friend and he only
wants to help you. Isn't that nice!
I'd be glad to help him. We all must
face reality, Dowd, sooner or later.
Uh-huh. Well, I wrestled with
reality for 35 years, Doctor.
And I'm happy to state
I finally won out over it.
Mr. Dowd,
where is Dr. Chumley?
Not knowing, I cannot say. Wish I could.
Miss Kelly, I don't like to see
you standing. Sit down, Kelly.
There we are. Now, let's all have a drink.
Dr. Chumley did come in here
to get you earlier this evening?
Yes, he did. And I was
delighted to see him.
What'll it be, Mr. Dowd? Martinis?
- But that was four hours ago.
- Where has the evening gone?
Four... Three martinis, Mr. Cracker.
I've looked all over this joint. There's
no sign of the Doctor. What'd you do to him?
We're trying to find out.
What happened then?
I introduced Harvey to the
Doctor, and he sat down with us.
Harvey was sitting here,
and the Doctor sat opposite
Harvey so he could look at him.
Who's Harvey? A white
rabbit, six feet tall.
- Six feet?
- Six feet, three and a half inches. Let's stick to facts.
What happened after you
introduced Dr. Chumley to Harvey?
Harvey suggested that
I buy him a drink.
Knowing that he doesn't like to drink alone,
I suggested to Dr. Chumley we join him.
We joined him.
Go on.
Wejoined him again.
- Then what?
- Then the other matter came up.
Now we're gettin' somewhere.
What other matter?
Eh... Mr. Wilson, I don't
like to see you standing.
Wouldn't you join us here? Who, me?
Sit down, will you, Wilson? Sit right down.
You say this other matter
came up, Mr. Dowd.
Yes. There was a beautiful blonde
woman name of Mrs. Smethills...
and her escort seated in the
booth directly across from us.
Dr. Chumley went over to sit
next to her, explaining to her...
that they had once met...
in Chicago.
Then her escort
escorted Dr. Chumley...
back here
to Harvey and me,
and tried to point out that it
would be better for Dr. Chumley...
to mind
his own affairs.
Does he have any? Does he have any what?
Any affairs? How would I know? Shut up!
Go on, Mr. Dowd. Well...
Thank you, Mr. Cracker.
Mrs. Smethills' escort seemed to get more
depressed as he kept looking at Dr. Chumley.
So Harvey and I felt we should
take the Doctor somewhere else.
Harvey suggested
Blondie's Chicken Inn,
but the Doctor
wanted to go to Eddie's.
And while they were arguing about it, I
went up to the bar to order another drink.
When I came back here,
they were gone.
You don't believe that story about the
Doctor talking to a big white rabbit, do you?
Why not?
Harvey was here.
At first Dr. Chumley seemed
frightened of Harvey,
but that gave way to admiration
as the evening wore on.
"The evening wore on."
That's a very nice expression, isn't it?
With your permission,
I'll say it again.
"The evening wore on."
And with your permission
I'm gonna knock your brains out.
Look, you did something to Dr. Chumley,
and I'm gonna find out what it is.
Stop! Lyman! Wilson!
For heaven's sake!
Get outside!
Mr. Cracker?
Sure, Mr. Dowd. Mr. Cracker,
may I intercede for my friends?
Youth and high spirits. Time will
take care of that. Sure, Mr. Dowd.
Okay, boys,
let 'em go.
If Mr. Dowd vouches for you, okay. One more
peep out of you and I'll butter your necktie.
Yeah, fine. Get back to your dancing.
Stimulating as all this is, I
think we all should have our drinks.
Here, Miss Kelly,
sit down.
Here we are.
Dr. Sanderson.
You keep your eye on him. I'm gonna
check in those other two joints.
And Dr. Chumley better
be there, pal... or else!
Mr. Wilson?
Yeah?
Good-bye, Mr. Wilson. My regards to you
and anybody else you happen to run into.
Ah, you...
Mr. Dowd, can't you think of anything
else that might help us to find the Doctor?
Miss Kelly, may I
take hold of your hand?
Yes, Mr. Dowd,
if you want to.
We're all so worried.
Please try to think. Please?
For you I'd do anything. I'd almost
be willing to live my life over again.
Almost.
But I've told it all.
You're sure?
I'm quite sure.
But ask me again anyway,
won't you?
I liked that warm tone you
had in your voice just then.
So did I.
Maybe we better go someplace else.
Miss Kelly seems to be unhappy.
No, let's stay here.
Kelly's all right.
Perhaps you'd like
to dance, Miss Kelly.
All right, Mr. Dowd, if
you'd like to. Oh, not I! No.
I used to dance.
I haven't danced in years.
I'm sure Dr. Sanderson would love to
dance with somebody as lovely as you.
Hmm? Would you, Miss Kelly?
All right.
There we are.
It's been a long time
since we've danced together.
Yes, a long time.
I'd forgotten what
a wonderful dancer you were.
If we didn't have to humor Mr. Dowd,
you wouldn't have remembered at all.
I'm not dancing with you
to humor Mr. Dowd, Ruth.
We shouldn't
have left him alone!
Where are you goin',
Mr. Dowd?
I was just looking
for someone.
Why don't you come back inside?
All right, if you want me to.
It seemed to be so pleasant
out here.
You know, you two look
very nice dancing together.
I used to know
a whole lot of dances.
The Flea Hop.
And what's the...
The Black Bottom.
The Varsity Drag.
I don't know. I just don't
seem to have any time anymore.
I have so many things
to do.
What is it you do,
Mr. Dowd?
Harvey and I
sit in the bars...
and have a drink or two,
play the jukebox.
And soon the faces
of all the other people,
they turn toward mine
and they smile.
They're saying, "We don't know your name,
mister, but you're a very nice fellow."
Harvey and I...
warm ourselves
in all these golden moments.
We've entered as strangers.
Soon we have friends.
And they come over
and they sit with us,
they drink with us
they talk to us.
And they tell about the big,
terrible things they've done...
and the big, wonderful things
they'll do.
Their hopes
and their regrets,
and their loves and their
hates, all very large...
because nobody ever brings
anything small into a bar.
And then...
I introduce them
to Harvey.
And he's bigger and grander
than anything they offer me.
And...
and when they leave,
they leave impressed.
The same people
seldom come back,
but that's...
that's envy, my dear.
There's a little bit of envy
in the best of us.
And that's too bad,
isn't it?
How did you happen
to call him Harvey?
Well, Harvey's
his name.
How do you
know that?
There was a rather interesting
coincidence on that, Doctor.
One night several years ago I was walking
early in the evening along Fairfax Street.
It was between 18th and 19th.
Do you know the block?
Yes, yes.
I'd just put Ed Hickey
into a taxi.
Ed had been mixing his
rye with his gin, and he...
I just felt that
he needed conveying.
Anyway, I was walking along the
street and I heard this voice saying,
"Good evening, Mr. Dowd."
Well, I turned around...
and here was this big six-foot
rabbit leaning up against a lamppost.
I thought nothing of that because
when you've lived in a town...
as long as I've lived in this one, you get
used to the fact that everybody knows your name.
Naturally, I went over
to chat with him.
And he said to me,
he said,
"Ed Hickey was a little spiffed this
evening. Or could I be mistaken?"
Of course
he was not mistaken.
I think the world and all
of Ed, but he was spiffed.
We talked like that for a
while and then I said to him,
"You have the advantage
on me.
You know my name
and I don't know yours."
And right back at me
he said,
"What name do you like?"
Well, I didn't even have
to think twice about that.
Harvey's always been
my favorite name.
So I said to him,
I said, "Harvey."
And, uh...
Th-This is the interesting thing
about the whole thing.
He said,
"What a coincidence.
My name happens
to be Harvey."
Dowd,
what was
your father's name?
John.
John Stuyvesant.
Tell me, Dowd,
when you were a child,
didn't you have a playmate?
Someone with whom
you spent many happy hours?
Yes. Yes,
I did, Doctor.
Didn't you?
Yes.
What was his name?
Vern.
Vern McElhinney.
You ever know the McElhinneys, Doctor? No.
That's too bad. There were a
lot of them and they circulated.
Very nice people.
Just wonderful people.
Think carefully,
Dowd.
Didn't you know somebody sometime,
someplace by the name of Harvey?
Didn't you ever know anybody
by that name?
No. No,
not one, Doctor.
Maybe that's why I always
had such hopes for it.
We looked in both of those joints, and
Dr. Chumley ain't in either one of'em.
I brought help.
What're you doin' out here?
Come on. We're going back
to the sanitarium. Wh...
Come, Elwood. Very well, Lyman.
I'm afraid I won't be able to
stay very long. I must find Harvey.
Which one is Dowd? My
name's Dowd, Elwood P.
Here, let me give you one of
my cards. Never mind the card!
Wilson,
what did I tell you?
Coming, coming.
Who is it? It's me. Open the gates quickly.
Oh, it's you, Doctor!
I thought you'd gone for the
night. I thought you'd gone.
Close them, Herman.
Close the gates.
Are you all right,
Doctor? I'm being followed.
Who's following you? None of your business.
Ahh! Ahh!
You called me,
Doctor?
No. No, I didn't.
No.
Everything's fine.
What's wrong? What happened,
Herman? What's goin' on?
The alarm went off. Somebody
must've come through a window.
Yes, Doctor. Sanderson, he's after me.
Who's after you, Doctor?
I don't see anyone.
I saw him. He came through
the window. Who was it?
Who came through
the window, Doctor?
I won't tell you. What's he talkin' about?
Forget it.
I'm going to my office and
I don't wish to be disturbed.
Forget it, he says.
Not me.
I'm takin' a look around this
joint. I'm gonna see what's goin' on.
It's locked.
Locked?
Have you any
extra keys, Miss?
Yes, we have.
I'll get them.
Dr. Chumley, I went around the
house and climbed through the window.
I didn't see anybody. Thank you,
Wilson. It's quite all right.
Everything's in order,
thank you. I'll be all right.
Dr. Chumley,
if you need me, I'll...
Holy smoke! We forgot about that crackpot.
He's probably roamin' around loose.
Excuse me.
I got 'im, Doctor.
Let's go upstairs.
I wanna do your fingernails for
you. That's thoughtful of you.
Just a second. I'll take
him. Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, Miss Kelly.
Perhaps you'd like this flower. I
seem to have misplaced my buttonhole.
Thank you, Mr. Dowd. Okay, let's go.
One moment, please.
Ah, Dr. Chumley. How nice
to run into you again.
How are you getting along
with Harvey? Oh, well, uh...
Mr. Dowd, I'd like to speak to
you in my office alone, please.
I'd like that, too, but I just promised
this gentleman he could give me a manicure.
Of course, if you wouldn't mind waiting
a few minutes. Not at all, Mr. Dowd.
Oh, excuse me.
You first. Go ahead. Oh...
Mr. Dowd, won't you have a seat? Thank you.
Will you have a cigar?
No, thank you, Doctor.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
What did you
have in mind?
Mr. Dowd, what kind
of a man are you?
Where do you
come from?
Why, didn't l... Didn't
I give you one of my cards?
And where on the face of this tired
old earth did you find a thing like him?
You mean, Harvey the Pooka? Yes, it's
true, the things you told me tonight.
I know it now.
Yes, yes.
Yes, Harvey has several
very interesting facets.
Did I tell you about Mrs. McElhinney? No.
She lives right next door
to us. Wonderful woman.
Harvey told me last night that
Mrs. McElhinney's Aunt Rose...
was going to drop in
on her unexpectedly...
this morning from Cleveland. And did she?
Did she what?
Aunt Rose. Did she come,
just as Harvey said she would?
Oh, yes, yes.
These things always work out just
the way Harvey says they will.
He's very,
very versatile.
Did I tell you
he could stop clocks?
To what purpose?
You've heard the expression,
"His face would stop a clock."
Well, Harvey
can look at your clock...
and stop it.
And you can go anywhere you
like with anyone you like...
and stay as long
as you like.
And when you get back, not
one minute will have ticked by.
You mean that he...
You see...
He can... Science has
overcome time and space.
Well, Harvey has overcome
not only time and space,
but any objections.
Flyspecks!
I've been spending my life
among flyspects...
while miracles have been leaning
on lampposts at 18th and Fairfax.
Tell me, Mr. Dowd,
will he do this for you?
Oh, he'd be willing
at any time.
But so far I haven't been able to
think of anyplace I'd rather be.
I always have a wonderful time
wherever I am, whomever I'm with.
I'm having a fine time
right here with you, Doctor.
Oh.
Oh, l...
I know where I'd go.
Where?
I'd go to Akron. Akron! Oh, yes.
There's a cottage camp
just outside Akron...
in a grove
of maple trees.
Green, cool, beautiful.
That's my favorite tree.
And I'd go there with a pretty woman. Oh.
A strange woman,
a quiet woman.
Oh, under a tree. I wouldn't
even want to know her name,
while I would be just...
Mr. Smith.
Then I would send out
for cold beer.
No whiskey, huh?
No.
Then I would
tell her things.
Things that I've never told
to anyone.
Things that are locked deep...
in here.
And as I talked
to her,
I would want her to hold out
her soft white hand and say,
"Poor thing.
You poor, poor thing."
How long would you want
this to go on, Doctor?
Two weeks.
Two weeks?
Wouldn't that get
a little monotonous,
just Akron, cold beer and
"poor, poor thing" for two weeks?
No!
It would be wonderful.
Well, I can't help feeling,
Doctor,
that you're making a mistake
not allowing the woman to talk.
If she'd been around at all, she might've
picked up some interesting news items.
And I'm sure you're making a mistake
about all that beer and no whiskey,
but it's
your two weeks.
Mr. Dowd, could he...
Would he do this for me?
Oh, he could
and might.
I've never heard Harvey
say a word against Akron.
By the way, Doctor,
where is Harvey?
Don't you know?
The last time I saw him
he was with you.
He's probably waiting for me
down at Charlie's.
Yes, that's it. He's
down at Charlie's. Uh-huh.
In that case, I'll go down
and join him for a nightcap.
Fortunately, Charlie's
stays open rather late.
Excuse me, Doctor. I want to say good-bye
to some of my friends before I leave.
Mr. Dowd, none of those people
are your friends.
But I want you to know that I am
your friend. Thank you. And I'm yours.
They underestimate you,
as I did.
This sister of yours is at the
bottom of a conspiracy against you.
She's trying to persuade me to lock you up.
Today she had commitment papers drawn up.
She has your power of attorney
and the key to your safety box.
And she brought
you here!
My sister did all that in one afternoon?
That Veta certainly is a whirlwind, isn't she?
Good heavens, man! Haven't
you any righteous indignation?
Oh, Doctor, l...
Years ago my mother used
to say to me, she'd say,
"In this world, Elwood,
you must be..."
She always
called me Elwood.
"In this world, Elwood,
you must be oh, so smart...
or oh, so pleasant."
Well, for years
I was smart.
I recommend pleasant.
And you may quote me.
This is it.
Here we are.
Okay, thank you.
Come on, Myrtle.
I'll come... You wait
right here, Veta girl.
I will not wait here.
I'm going in with you.
You're a very high-strung girl.
This may be an ordeal.
Then let Myrtle Mae
stay here too.
Mother, you know it isn't right to put Uncle
Elwood away without some blood relative present.
Hey, you're not gonna leave
the lady here. I thought...
See, Omar? Even strangers
think I should go in with you.
I wish to see
Dr. Chumley.
I'm sorry, sir. He's in
conference. You'll have to wait.
After dragging me out of bed at this
hour? Tell him Judge Omar Gaffney's here.
I telephoned you right after we
picked up Mr. Dowd. I'm Dr. Sanderson.
I demand that this matter
be settled right now!
Oh, good, nobody here
but people.
You promised to wait in the car.
You forgot Elwood's bathrobe.
Why are you all standing
around? I thought you'd be...
How do you do, Doctor? Committing
Elwood. Hello, Mrs. Simmons.
He's the one
I told you about.
Girl. Doctor,
what's your opinion?
How are you feeling, Mrs.
Simmons? Better, thank you.
In my opinion, Elwood P. Dowd is suffering
from a third-degree hallucination.
I recommend formula
number 9-7-7.
That's a powerful serum which
will shock him back to reality.
Nothing will do that.
Lock him up.
If this shock formula brings people back
to reality, that's where we want Elwood.
Yes. If he won't see the
rabbit anymore, give it to him.
Then when Harvey comes
to the door, I'll deal with him.
Please stop talking about Harvey
as if there were such a thing!
Myrtle Mae, you have a lot to
learn, and I hope you never learn it.
Oh, Mother... Marvin! Myrtle Mae, baby!
Myrtle Mae, come back here.
The idea of that terrible man...
Let's get on with this, Doctor. I'm sorry, but
you'll have to take that up with Dr. Chumley.
Then why waste my time?
Young lady,
will you inform Dr. Chumley
of my presence or must I do it?
I'll attend to it
immediately, sir.
Oh.
Oh, Miss Kelly.
Isn't Dr. Chumley there?
How nice to see you.
Where's the Doctor?
What'd you...
Are you all right, Doctor? Yes,
thanks. I'm quite all right.
Well, Veta and Myrtle Mae!
What a delightful surprise.
Good evening, Elwood. I brought
your bathrobe. Thank you, Veta.
Well, Dr. Chumley, are we gonna
settle this matter or are we not?
I, uh... I've turned
this case over...
to Dr. Sanderson. Oh, no. You forget
I don't work here anymore, Dr. Chumley.
Dr. Sanderson, please disregard
what I said this afternoon.
I want you to head my staff. I think
you're a very capable young man.
Oh, Lyman,
did you hear that?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some work to do.
Well, I think this calls
for a celebration.
Why don't we all go down to
Charlie's Place and have a drink?
You're not going anywhere,
Elwood. You're staying right there.
Yes, Uncle Elwood.
Stay here, son.
I plan to leave,
you want me to stay.
An element of conflict in any
discussion is a very good thing.
Shows everybody's taking part,
and nobody left out. I like that.
Ah, Miss Kelly.
Miss Kelly, you know,
when you wear my flower...
you make it beautiful.
"A diviner grace has never
brightened this enchanting face."
Ovid's Fifth Elegy. Ovid's
always been my favorite poet.
My dear,
you'll never look lovelier.
I'll never be happier,
Mr. Dowd. I know it.
Hey, this rabbit gag
must be a good one.
Mr. Dowd, I have a formula, 9-7-7, that
will be good for you. Will you take it?
9-7-7, huh? Yes.
It's a serum.
Oh. You won't see this rabbit anymore.
But you will see your responsibilities
and your duties. Uh-huh.
Well, Doctor,
if you thought of this,
I'm sure it must be
a very fine thing.
And if I happen to run into anybody who
needs it, I'd be glad to recommend it.
But as for myself, I don't
think I'd care for it.
You hear that, Judge?
You hear that, Doctor?
That's what we put up with.
Veta, do you want me to take this?
Oh, Elwood, I'm only
thinking of you.
You're my brother and I've known you
for years. I'd do anything for you.
Harvey wouldn't do anything for
you. He's making a fool of you.
Elwood, don't be a fool. I won't.
Why, you could amount
to something.
You could be sitting on the Western
Slope Water Board right now...
if you'd only go over
and ask them.
If that's what you want, Harvey and
I'll go over tomorrow and ask them.
Tomorrow! I wish there might
never be another tomorrow!
Not if Myrtle Mae and I have to
go on living with that rabbit!
Our friends never come to see us
anymore. We have no social life whatever!
We've no life
at all.
We're both
perfectly miserable.
But perhaps you don't
care. All right, now, Veta.
Well, l...
I've always felt Veta should
have everything she wants, but...
Veta,
are you sure?
Yes.
I-I'll take it. Where do I go,
Doctor? In my office, Mr. Dowd.
This will only take a few
minutes. Why don't you wait?
Veta, you tell Dr. Chumley to say good-bye
to the old fellow for me, will you?
Dr. Sanderson,
couldn't we...
Yes, Kelly?
Nothing.
I'll need you
to give me a hand, Miss Kelly.
Right in here. No, no. After you.
No, after you.
Miss Kelly. No, after you. Here we go.
Dr. Sanderson said
it wouldn't take long.
Ooh, ooh!
Sit down, girl. Thank you, Judge.
He said it wouldn't take...
long.
Relax, girl.
Take it easy.
Thank you.
I'll try to, but...
Oh, there you are. Lady jumped out
of my cab, left without payin' me.
She didn't say anything, and a
fellow gets nervous after a while.
Well, there's no cause for
concern, man. How much is it?
All the way out there
from town? $2.75.
Why, I must've forgotten
my wallet.
I was dragged out of bed in such a hurry,
it's a wonder I didn't forget my pants.
Beg your pardon,
Veta.
Uh, would you take a
check? We don't take checks.
Yeah, I know, but...
Would you mind, Veta?
Oh, of course.
Yes, I, uh...
Well, I could've sworn
I brought my coin purse.
Where is it?
Oh, the idea!
Well, I never!
Oh, I know. I'll get it
for you from my brother.
But I can't go in just now. He's
in there getting an injection.
It won't take long.
You'll have to wait.
You're gonna get my money from
your brother who's in there...
getting some of that stuff
they shoot out here?
Yes. It'll only take
a few minutes.
Lady, I want my money now. I told
you it'll only take a few minutes.
We want you to drive us
back to town.
I told you I want my money now or I'm nosin'
the cab back to town and you can wait for a bus.
Well, of all the pigheaded,
stubborn things!
What's the matter with you?
Nothing that $2.75 won't fix.
You heard me.
Take it or leave it.
I never heard of anything so
unreasonable in all my life.
Would you please let my
brother step out here a moment?
This cab driver won't wait.
Oh, Elwood.
I'll be right back.
Elwood, I came off
without my coin purse.
Would you please give
this man $2.75?
But don't give him any more.
He's been very rude.
Howdy do. Dowd's my name, Elwood P.
Mine's Lofgren, E.J. Glad
to know you, Mr. Lofgren.
This is my sister Mrs. Simmons. My
good friend Judge Gaffney, back there.
Hi. Hi.
Hi.
Have you lived around
here long? All my life.
Enjoy your work?
It's okay.
I've been driving
for Apex Cabs for 15 years.
My brother Joe's been driving
for Brown Cabs for near 12.
Is that so? You drive for Apex
and your brother Joe for Brown.
That's interesting, isn't it, Veta? Yes.
Mr. Lofgren, let me give you
one of my cards.
My sister and my charming niece
live at that address with me.
Wouldn't you and your brother like to
come and have dinner with us sometime?
Sure,
be glad to.
When? When would you
be glad to?
I couldn't come any night but tomorrow.
I'm on duty all the rest of the week.
Tomorrow would be perfect. We'll be
expecting you and delighted to see you.
Won't we, Veta? Elwood, I'm sure
this man has friends of his own.
Can't have
too many friends.
Don't keep the Doctor waiting.
It's rude.
There you are. Keep the change. I'm
glad to have met you, Mr. Lofgren.
I'll expect you and your brother tomorrow
night. Now, you'll have to excuse me. l...
A sweet guy.
Certainly.
You could just as well have waited. Ah, no.
Lady, I've been drivin'
this route for 15 years.
I've brought 'em out here to get that stuff,
and I've drove 'em home after they had it.
It changes them.
I certainly hope so.
You ain't kiddin'.
On the way out here,
they sit back and enjoy
the ride, they talk to me.
Sometimes we stop and watch the
sunsets and look at the birds.
birds when there ain't no birds,
and look at the sunsets
when it's rainin'.
We have a swell time.
And I always get a big tip.
But afterwards...
ooh-ooh.
"Afterwards, ooh-ooh." What do
you mean, "Afterwards, ooh-ooh"?
They crab, crab, crab.
They yell at me,
"Watch the lights! Watch the
breaks! Watch the intersections!"
They scream at me to hurry. They
got no faith in me and my buggy.
Yet, it's the same cab, same driver, and
we're going back over the very same road.
It's no fun.
And, no tips.
My brother would've tipped
you anyway. He's very generous.
He always has been. Not
after this he won't be.
After this he'll be
a perfectly normal human being.
And you know what stinkers
they are.
Glad I met ya.
I'll wait.
Oh, no! No!
Elwood, come out.
Don't give it to him! Stop
it! Stop it! Elwood, come out.
Don't do that, girl. Dr.
Sanderson's giving the injection.
I don't want him to have it.
I don't like people like that.
I don't want my brother
to be like that. Elwood!
Oh, you haven't given him the
injection already, have you?
No, but we're all ready,
Mrs. Simmons. Oh, Elwood!
What's the trouble?
What's goin' on?
What's wrong?
She wants to stop the
injection. She does, huh?
Come on, you. Take your hands off me!
Don't you touch me,
you white slaver, you!
Marvin, please! All right,
honey. Anything you say.
You don't know what you want. You
didn't want that rabbit either.
What's wrong with Harvey?
If Elwood and Myrtle Mae and I want
to live with Harvey, what is it to you?
You don't even have to
come around. It's our house.
Elwood! Oh, Elwood. Veta, that's all right.
Veta's all tired out.
She's done a lot today.
Have it your own way, but I'm
gonna take that cab back to town.
I'm not giving up another night's sleep
again no matter how big the animal is!
Elwood,
let us go too.
I hate this place.
I wish I'd never seen it.
All right, Veta. Wait
'til I get my hat and coat.
Why...
Why look at that!
It's my coin purse.
It must've been in there
all the time.
I could've paid
that cab driver myself.
Harvey!
Thank you, Doctor.
Ooh!
Myrtle Mae and that man!
They make a beautiful couple,
don't they?
Mr. Wilson has such a dynamic
personality. That man...
Myrtle Mae...
Mr. Wilson, may we have...
the pleasure of your company
tomorrow night for dinner?
We're having a few friends in.
Very informal.
Certainly, Mr. Dowd. I'd
be glad to. Thank you.
A very nice couple.
And you make
a very beautiful couple too.
Well,
I must find Harvey.
Good-bye, Mrs. Simmons.
I'll see you tomorrow night.
Yes. Good-bye,
Mr. Wilson.
Myrtle Mae!
Come, Myrtle Mae. Please try to forget
all about that dreadful Mr. Wilson.
Wha... Wha...
Well, there you are!
I've been looking
all over for you.
Oh. Wasn't it cold
out here?
Hmm? l...
I don't mind if I do.
That'd warm us up,
wouldn't it?
No, Charlie's would be
fine. Yeah, just fine.
Here.
Oh, Mr. Dowd?
Mr. Dowd, don't take him
away. Let him stay with me.
Doctor, whatever he wants to do
is perfectly all right with me.
He knows that.
It's up to you.
Would you like to stay
with the doctor? Hmm?
No, I-I don't mind.
Have you ever been
to Akron?
Hmm? Akron.
Now, where is Elwood? Elwood,
we've been waiting for you.
I'm sorry, Veta. We've lost
the car. The Judge took it.
We'll have to go to the
corner and wait for a bus.
Hurry up, dear.
Good night, Mr. Shimelplatzer. Good night.
Was anything
the matter?
No, I, I thought you decided
to stay with Dr. Chumley.
You... Huh?
You...
Well, thank you,
Harvey.
I prefer you too.