[Saxophone Plays
"Lift EveryVoice And Sing"]
[Rap Music Plays]
# Come on, now, get down #
# 1989 #
#The number, another summer #
# Get down #
# Sound of the funky drummer #
# Music hittir your heart #
# 'Cause I know you got soul #
# Brothers and sisters #
# Hey, listen
ifyou're missir y'all #
# Swingir while I'm singir #
#Givir whatyou're gettir #
# Knowir what I'm knowir #
#While the black band's sweatir #
# In the rhythm rhymes rollir #
#Got to give us whatwewant #
# Ugh #
#Got to give us whatwe need #
# Hey #
# Our freedom of speech
is freedom or death #
#We got to fight
the powers that be #
# Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be #
# As the rhythm's designed
to bounce what counts #
# Is that the rhyme's
designed to fill your mind #
# Now thatyou've realized
the pride's arrived #
#We've got to pump the stuff
that makeyou tough #
# From the heart
it's a start #
# A work of art to revolutionize #
# Make a change, nothirs strange #
# People, people we are the same #
# No, we're not the same #
# 'Cause we don't know the game #
#What we need is awareness #
#We can't get careless #
#You saywhat is this? #
# My beloved,
let's get down to business #
# Mental self-defense offitness #
# Bum rush the show #
#You got to go
forwhatyou know #
#To make everybody see #
# In order to fight
the powers that be #
# Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be #
# Come on, get down #
# Come on,
come on, come on #
# Come on, get down #
# Come on,
come on, come on #
# Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be #
# Elvis was a hero to most #
# But he never meant shit to me #
#Ya see,
straight out racist #
#The sucka
was simple and plain #
# Motherfuck him
and John Wayne #
# 'Cause I'm black
and I'm proud, I'm ready #
# I'm hyped,
plus I'm amped #
# Most ofmy heroes
don't appear on no stamp #
#Sample a look backyou look#
# And find nothir but rednecks #
# For 400 years ifyou check#
# Don't worry, be happy #
#Was a number one jam #
# Damn ifl say it,
you can slap me right here #
# Get it #
# Let's get this party started right #
# Right on #
# Come on #
#What we got to say #
# Power to the people, no delay #
# Make everybody see #
# In order to fight
the powers that be #
# Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be ##
[Ring]
Wake up?
Wake up,
wake up, wake up?
Upya wake, upya wake,
upya wake?
This is Mister Seor Love Daddy?
Yourvoice of choice?
The world's only 12-hour
strong man on the air,
Here on We-Love radio, 108 FM?
The last on your dial,
but first in your hearts,
and that's the truth, Ruth?
Here I am?
Am I here?
Ya know it? Itya know?
This is Mister Seor Love Daddy
doing the nasty toya ears,
ya ears to the nasty?
I's only play
da platters dat matter
the matters dey platter,
and that's the truth, Ruth?
From the heart of Bed-Stuy,
you're listening to We-Love radio?
Doing the ying and the yang,
the hip and the hop,
the stupid fresh thing,
the flippity-flop?
Awoo!?
I have today's forecast foryou?
Hot! Sss!
The color for today is black?
That's right, black?
So absorb these rays
and save that heat forwinter?
So wear that black
and be involved?
Also today's temperature
is rising over 100 degrees?
So that's aJheri-curl alert.
That's right, Jheri-curl alert.
Lfyou have one, stay inside,
oryou'll have
a permanent plastic helmet.
All right, we're going to
say hello to Mister and Missus,
that's Mister and Missus.
Happy birthday to Big Red
and Miss Annie Mae, 100 today.
Stay out ofthis heat,
andyou might live that long.
There's a water shortage,
so keep those showers
to one minute.
Two, ifyou're with a friend.
Get on out there.
Dam n! Whoo!
I t is hot!
Get that pink slip.
So get up, get out!
That's what I'm talking about.
We don't want to see
anybody lose theirjob
'cause nobody
got no money as it is.
All right. Now we're
going to talk about it.
We're going
to rock 'n ' roll...
Good m-m-morni ng?
M-M-My name is Smiley?
This is M-M-M-M-Malcolm??
X?
And this is
M-M-M-M-Martin K-K-King?
Now,
th-they are d-d-dead??
But w-we still
h-h-have to f-f-f-fight
a-against ap-apartheid?
10, 15, 20, 30, 40, 50,
60, 70, 80, 100?
20, 40, 60, shit!
80?? 300?
20, 40, 60, 80??
Wait, that's 300?
300, 350, 450??
Cash dollar bills?
Mookie? Why areyou always
bothering me when I'm sleeping...
Wake up, wake up?
Stop breathing
down my neck?
Why should I wake up?
It's going to be hot, Jade?
Saturday's the only day
I get to sleep late?
Damn?
Stop, Mookie?
That's not funny?
Leave me alone
when I'm sleeping?
You don't love
Brother Mookie anymore?
I loves you, Jade?
I'll get a lock
and keepyour ass out ofhere?
Why don'tyou go to work, man,
and leave me alone?
Later, got to get paid?
Yeah, brush your teeth?
I brushed my teeth?
Your breath stinks?
It's your upper lip?
What's up, Sal?
Howyou doir there, boy?
Man, I got to get me
a Cadillac like that?
I'm getting a car
just like that?
Oh, it's hot?
Sonny, how's the vegetables, huh?
Good morning, Sal? Vito? Pino?
Pop, you talk to that
air-condition guy?
I been calling him all week?
He won't come around
unless he has a police escort?
Pino, get a broom
and sweep up front?
[Yawns]
Vito, get a broom
and sweep up front?
Huh?
Sweep up the front?
What?
Get a broom
and sweep out front!
See? Every time
you tell Pino what to do,
he tells me what to do?
He's brain-dead, Pop, foryears?
Both ofyou, shut up?
Tell Pino!
Am I talking to myself?
I didn't want to come anyway?
I hate this friggir place?
I detest it like a sickness?
You, you detest this place
like a sickness?
That's like really hate, you know?
That's hate?
I didn't say that?
Oh, you didn't say that?
I just heard it?
Am I going crazy?
Did I just hear that, Vito?
I mean, doyou think
you can do better?
No, I didn't think so?
This is a respectable business,
and there's nothing wrong with that?
I mean, ifthere's
something wrong with that, tell me?
Is there something
wrong with that?
There's nothing wrong? OK?
Do me a favor?
Get a broom and sweep up?
Tell Vito?
What areyou... deaf?
Pop asked you?
I'm going to kill somebody today?
I can't believe it?
What?
That you like her?
I don't like her?
Yeah?
Hell no?
Hey?
Hi, Mookie?
Mookie?
Hey, Mook?
Mornir, Mookie?
Morning, Miss Mother Sister?
Mookie, don't work
too hard today?
It's going to be hot as the devil?
I don't wantyou falling out,
you hear me?
I hearyou, Mother Sister?
Good?
All right?
I'll be watching you, son?
Mother Sister always watches?
Mookie??
You're late again?
You live up the block, what?
Your Cadillac broke?
Hello, Sal, Vito?
Yo, Mook? What up?
Just coolir?
You're still late?
Relax, Pino?
Take it easy?
You'll live longer?
Take the broom?
The front needs sweeping?
Wait? You sweep?
I bet Sal asked you first anyway?
That's right?
Vito, sti cazzi.
Fuck that?
I get paid for delivering pizzas?
You're paid
to do what we say?
What we say?
Did you hear Sal?
Sal didn't say nothing?
Who's working forwho?
Shh?
Come on in, Mayor?
Morning, gentlemen?
Pino, Mookie, Vito, Sal?
How are you?
Ooh-whee? It's going to be
a scorcher today?
That's for sure?
Need any work done here?
Daddy, perch tu dai
questo azupep soldi per niente affatto.
Why don't you
leave him alone?
He's a good man?
Leave him alone?
Choose your weapon, Mayor?
You dropped something, Mayor?
You are going to have
the cleanest sidewalk in Brooklyn?
Clean as the Board
of Health? Ha-ha!
All right, Mayor?
Pop, I don't believe
this shit?
You running welfare
or something?
Every dayyou give
this azupep a dollar?
What's azupep?
Areyou Italian?
The Mayor ain't no azupep.
You give this azupep a dollar
for sweeping our sidewalk?
What's Mookie for, huh?
He don't even work?
I work harder,
and I'm your son?
Let's see you carry
six large pies up six flights,
no elevator either and shit?
Shut up, you two?
Yeah, Pop?
Why don'tyou shut up, too, Vito?
We're going to talk?
Says who?
Says me?
What did I just say?
Don't start that
"Mookie don't work" shit?
Yo, Ahmad!
I coulda done that?
Man, shut up?
Yo, Ahmad!
Shit? Look, stop?
Punchy, you want to do
any more screaming,
be my guest?
Yo, who's yelling my name?
Well, Punchy told me to?
Punchy told me to?
Don't listen to this knothead?
It'll getyou in trouble?
Heard that, Punchy?
Yo, Ella? Ella?
What?
You got a brain?
Use it?
[Rap Music Blares]
Peace, y'all?
Peace, Radio Raheem?
Peace, man?
You the man?
I'm just visiting?
It's yourworld, G?
For real,
in a big motherfuckir way?
That boy's livir very large?
Even walks in stereo?
Ha-ha-ha?
Yo, P. E? 's in full effect??
Boyee!
Radio Raheem
like a motherfucker?
Radio Raheem?
Blastir that big box?
Cold rockir the scene?
Where's the Miller High Life?
Where is the Miller High Life?
No more High Life?
You lookwhatwe have?
What kind ofa joint is this?
How come no more High Life?
Look, doctor,
this ain't Korea or China
orwhereveryou're from?
You get some Miller High Life
in this fuckir joint?
You buy another beer?
Da Mayor??
Don't drink this Lite shit?
Tastes like cold pot liquor?
All right, all right?
Butyou're askir a lot
to make a man change
his beer? A lot, doctor?
Hey! You old drunk!
What did I tell you
about drinkir
in front of my stoop?
Move on?
You're blockir myview?
You are ugly enough?
Don't stare at me?
The evil eye doesn't work on me?
Mother Sister, you been
talkir about me for 18 years?
What I ever done toyou?
You a drunk fool?
Besides that?
The Mayor don't bother nobody,
and nobody don't bother
the Mayor but you?
The Mayorjust tend
to his own business?
I love everybody?
I even love you?
Hold your tongue?
You don't have that much love?
One dayyou gonna be nice to me?
We may both be dead and buried,
but you gonna be nice?
At least civil?
I told you, I'm not going
to baby-sit foryou,
and that's it!
What areyou
talking about?
Yesterdayyou said you would?
Now today
you're changing your mind?
No, I'm not changing...
Ay, Mommy,
que muchojota?
Get off of me, please!
I do everything foryou?
You can't do shit for me!
Yo tengo
el derecho de salirte.
Right, right?
You know it's not like that, Mommy?
I can do everything foryou,
but you won't do shit for me?
Stop it!
That lady makes me sick!
Your father makes me sick, too?
Everybody makes me sick?
Shit?
Your father ain't no real father?
He's a bum?
Chump change, to-the-curb,
pulling no major pub, bum!
Mike?
Fuck Mike Tyson!
I rememberwhen he mugged
that woman on Lexington?
I remember that shit?
You're going to tell him?
I'll tell him?
Fuck MikeTyson!
To his face?
You goddamn right!
He'll knock
your goddamn ass off?
You talk shit now?
I'll drop him like a bad habit?
LfTyson dream aboutwhippir my ass,
he betterwake up and apologize?
Well, gentlemen, theway I see it,
ifthis hotweather continues,
it's going to melt the polar caps
and thewholewideworld?
And all those parts
that ain'twater already
will surely be flooded?
You dumb ass, simple motherfucker!
Whereyou read that shit, eh?
The polar caps?
Don't worry about it?
When it happens,
and I'm in my boat
and you black asses are drowning,
don't call for me
to throwyou no rope,
no lifesaver, or no nothing?
You 30 cent away from a quarter?
How the fuck
you gonna get a boat?
Here, boy?
Don't worry about it?
Goddamn right?
Look at you?
You're raggedy as a roach,
eat the holes out of doughnuts?
Raggedy motherfucker!
Don't worry about it?
I'm in good shape?
I will be?
I'll be back on my feet
soon enough?
Look, raggedy-ass shoes!
So run over, you gotta
lay down to put 'em on?
So, ML, ML, ML, tell me?
When is all this goddamn ice
supposed to melt?
[Vito]
Hello? Sal's Pizza?
Yep?
Meatball hero,
eggplant parmesan?
You got it?
Yeah, we deliver?
Of course, we deliver?
All right? Where is that?
You going to pay now
or on layaway?
How much?
You been coming here
three times a day?
What areyou, a retard?
It's $1? 50?
Put some cheese
on that motherfucker?
Extra cheese is $2? 00?
$2? 00?
Yeah, $2? 00?
Hey, forget that shit?
Damn, Sal, you're cheap, man?
Yo, Mook!
Mookie! How come
ain't no brothers
up on the wall?
Man, ask Sal, all right?
Hey, Sal, how come
ain't no brothers there?
You want brothers on the wall?
Getyour own place?
You can putyour brothers and uncles,
nieces and nephews,
your stepfather, stepmother,
whoeveryou want?
But this is my pizzeria?
American-Italians
on the wall only?
Take it easy, Pop?
And you, hey, don't start
with me today?
What?
Yeah, that might be fine, Sal,
butyou own this?
Rarely do I see
any American-Italians eating in here?
All I see is black folks?
Since we spend much money here,
we do have some say?
You lookir for trouble?
Areyou a troublemaker,
is that whatyou are?
Yeah, I'm a troublemaker?
I'm making trouble?
You're a ball-breaker?
You're always coming in here
looking for trouble, aren'tyou?
Suppose I busted your head?
How would you??
Mookie, you want to get
your friend out ofhere?
What, you gonna
kick me out now?
I'm not?
You're kicking yourself out?
We want some brothers
up on the wall...
You know, Malcolm X,
Nelson Mandela,
Michael Jordan!
Tomorrow!
Mookie, get him out?
I'm trying! Takeyour slice?
I knowyou paid for it?
All right, you're kicking me out?
Beat me on the head
and kick me out?
I paid for my...
Look, boycott Sal's!
Boycott Sal's?
I got your boycott swinging?
Yo, what you laughir at?
Mookie, I paid for my slice?
I spend much money in there!
What areyou trying to do?
I want brothers on the wall?
You're fucking my shit up?
It's between me and Sal?
You're fucking me up?
I ain't trying to fuckyou up?
I'm sorry?
You're sorry?
In a week, it'll be squashed?
A week?
Yeah? Yeah?
All right?
Bet?
Mook??
Stay black!
This guy's your friend, right?
If I'm wrong, tell me?
He's my friend?
Lfhe don't behave,
I don't want him here anymore?
I can't do nothing?
Talk brother talk to him?
Brothertalk?
People are free to do
whatever the hell theywant?
Free? What the hell
areyou talking about?
Free? There's no free here?
I'm the boss?
No freedom?
You want freedom?
There, that's free?
Take that order out?
He's got an order?
Let's go? Come on!
Get to work!
You're standing here doing nothing?
You're afraid of the goddamn oven?
Hit the oven!
Is this the address?
Is that the address?
Is that what he just asked me?
Mookie?
Come here, doctor?
Mayor, I got to go?
I'm working?
Come here, doctor?
This is the Mayor talking?
All right?
Doctor?
What?
Always do the right thing?
That's it?
I got it?
I'm gone?
M-M-Mookie??
Howyou doir, Smiley?
P-P-Pay??
2... 2 d-d-dollars?
The other one?
The other one, Smiley?
1... 1 d-dollar?
That one?
Tonight, when I get paid?
When...
When you get p-p??
Bye, M-Mookie?
M-M-M-M-Malcolm?
M-M-M-M-Martin?
Shit?
Seen your brother this morning?
Yeah, on his way to work, I hope?
This might take
a little bit oftime, MotherSister?
I got nowhere to go?
We haven't had a good sit-down
for a long while?
Tender-headed runs in my family?
Areyou tender-headed?
Yeah? Me, too?
I don't fool with it?
That's why onlyyou can touch it?
Ouch!
I'm sorry?
The comb got caught?
Be gentle, child?
Mother Sister's old?
Yes, Mother Sister?
Ooh-whee!
I didn't knowyou had
such beautiful hair?
There's a lotyou don't know?
I'm not stopping?
I'm on myway?
Mother Sister,
why areyou so cruel to the Mayor?
It isn't right?
I ain't studying no Mayor?
He reminds me
of my least favorite peoples...
my tenant and my ex-husband?
Goddamn!
Bless his soul?
Whew!
# Ooh yeah #
# All right #
#You can't stand it #
# I knowyou can't stand it #
#You can't stand the heat #
Salud!
[Speaking Spanish]
# Is the weather #
# I know the times
is just screwir upyour mind #
# But we must
stick together #
# No work foryou
for miles around #
#The family's on the verge
ofbreakir down #
#The rent is due #
#The landlord makir threats #
#The pressure's buildir up #
#The moreyou sweat #
# I knowyou can't stand it #
#You can't stand it #
#You can't stand the heat #
#You're burning?? ##
What areyou doing?
Ahmad, put me down!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey?
It's Radio?
Radio, man?
Hey, what's up, Radio?
Radio!
Don't! Stop!
[Honk Honk]
Hey, yo! Don't be
fucking with the water now?
Oh, man, go ahead?
You got it!
There's going to be
a lot offucking trouble
ifthis car gets wet?
Ain't nobody
fucking around, man?
Why don'tyou just go ahead?
This is an antique here, hotshot?
Man, go ahead!
It's what?
Hey, man, I'm...
I'm serious, man!
All right?
OK, you won't get wet?
Make sure I don't?
Go ahead! Go ahead!
Drive the car!
All right,
I'm driving it?
Get out!
Get out, motherfucker!
Fuckyou back!
Turn the fucking water?
Go!
Those son of a bitches!
They got me fucking soaked!
Officer!
Wait a minute?
Hold it!
I want an arrest made now!
Right now!
What's the matter?
Calm down?
Sir, tell us what happened?
Two black kids soaked me
with the fire hydrant?
They ruined my car!
It's an antique!
They got me soaked!
So where are they?
Brilliant fucking question!
They ran away!
What do you think?
Do you wish
to file a complaint, sir?
Yeah? I want 'em locked
under the fucking jail?
I'm going to turn offthe water?
Whereyou going?
Where's he going?
Did you catch their names?
Officer, what the fuck
areyou doing?
Just calm down?
Did you catch their names?
Fuckyou, their names!
Moe and Joe!
Moe and Joe what, sir?
Moe and Joe what?
Moe and Joe Black?
How's that?
They're brothers, sir?
Brothers? Yeah,
they're fucking brothers?
This hydrant
better not come back on again,
or there's going to be hell to pay!
Come answer to me, goddamn it!
Ask him? He knows?
He witnessed
the whole fucking thing!
Tell him what happened?
Let us do the questioning, sir?
Fucking bullshit?
Know anything about this?
Who were the punks?
Doctors, those that'll tell
don't know,
and those that know won't tell?
What the fuck is that, voodoo shit?
Hey, the Mayor don't
know nothir, all right?
Hey! He's leaving?
Keep this hydrant off?
Go swim at Coney Island?
I'm talking toyou!
He's leaving?
What about me?
I suggestyou get toyour car
before these people
strip it clean?
Have a nice day, sir?
He left there
about a halfhour ago?
No, no problem?
Thankyou?
Mookie left...
Where the hell you been?
I got a business to run?
Run it then, OK?
That's for the station?
Love Daddy?
Yeah? Love Daddy?
Hey, Pop, I'm going
to go with Mookie, OK?
Yeah? You make sure
Mookie don't jerk around?
Wait up, Mook!
You ain't going anywhere?
Howyou doing?
Vito, I know Pino's
your brother and shit,
butyou should kick his ass
the next time he touches you?
The next time he hits you,
fuck him up!
Whoa! Whoa!
Yo, hey, Mook?
I appreciate this concern,
but I don't think
it's any ofyour business, Mook?
Yeah, butyou need
to kick his ass?
Smiley, not now?
Lfl had a brother like him,
we'd fight all the time?
Smiley!
Mook, you don't got
a brother like him?
Smiley, get out ofhere!
Lfyou did, you wouldn't know
what to do with him?
He's my brother?
I'm not going to hit him?
I got a sister?
You never clocked your sister?
Does she bug you?
You don't hit girls
likeyou hit guys?
Just fuckyour brother up once,
it'll be overwith?
We'll be out
ofthis fucking conversation?
It might do some good?
Yes, all right?
A lot of good?
Let's give...
Love Daddy!
Peoples, my stomach's
been grumbling,
but help has arrived?
My main man Mookie
has saved the day!
Straight from Sal's
Famous Pizzeria up the block?
Step up to the mike, Mookie?
Come on? Come on!
Don't be shy?
Mmm, this smells good?
Go ahead?
This is your Love Daddy talking,
Starvir like Marvin?
Say something?
All right, Love Daddy?
I'd like to dedicate this record
with all my heart and soul??
To Tina?
All right!
Let me put this song on
while I go to work
on this chicken
parmigiana hero
with extra cheese
and extra s-sauce?
[Salsa Music Plays]
Salsa. Musica latina.
El sonido de mi pais,
el pais mas bello,
Puerto Rico.
Chill, man?
Shut up?
I 'm trying to read?
Have some fucking respect, huh?
[Rap Music Plays]
Not so loud!
I want to listen
to my salsa music!
Chill! Chill! Chill!
You thinkyou got it
like that, bro? Chocolate?
[Laughter]
Let's go, motherfucker!
Turn it up, Stevie!
Blow it away!
Blow it!
Yeah, blow it away!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Turn up the bongos!
Oh, yeah!
Yo, Steve!
Put it up loud?
Yeah, man!
You got it, bro?
Hey, pendejo!
Qupasa, la neta?
Come on, Steve, man?
Rafael, suba el volumen.
You're dead, choco-man?
He's a punk anyway, man?
Yo! Hey? Pendejo!
Hey, pendejo! What's up?
Pendejo!
He's a sucker, man?
A punk?
See last night's game?
Uh-huh? I saw it?
Best pitcher in the game...
Dwight Gooden?
I knewyou'd bring that up?
Who's better?
Roger Clemens?
Clemens sucks?
He can't carry Dwight's jock?
Dwight's best in the game?
What's up, Buggir Out?
You the man?
No, you the man?
I'm a struggling black
trying to keep my dick hard
in a cruel world?
What's with the white boy?
Don't start no shit?
Vito's down?
Vito's down, all right?
Yeah, right?
Vito's down?
Yeah?
Phew?
Yo!
Damn?
Yeah?
You almost knocked me down?
The word is "excuse me?"
Excuse me?
I'm sorry?
You stepped on
my brand-new white AirJordans?
That's all you can say?
You're serious?
Yeah! I'll fuck
your prick two times!
Two times!
Who told you to be
in my neighborhood?
I own this brownstone?
Who told you to buy a brownstone
in my neighborhood?
What do you want to live
in a black neighborhood for,
anyway?
I understand this is
a free country?
A man can live
wherever he wants?
Free country?
I should fuckyou up for saying that?
Yo, man?
YourJordans are fucked up!
Might as well throw them shits out?
They're broke?
They looked good
before he messed them up?
He was even talking
aboutyour mama...
Shit, you used
to be so fine!
How much they cost?
$100!
$108 with tax?
You're lucky
I got a loving heart?
Next time, cross the street quick?
I'm out ofhere?
Break his feet!
You should buy me another pair!
Black Panther'd whip his ass!
You're lucky I'm
a righteous black man!
Otherwiseyou'd be
in serious trouble! Serious!
Let's fuck him up?
Move back to Massachusetts!
I was born in Brooklyn?
- No!
- Oh!
- Man!
Get outta here!
I should send Vito
with you all the time?
Yeah? No more
90-minute deliveries
Around the corner?
I work hard like
everybody else here, OK?
You know that's true, Pino?
Vito, come here?
Come here?
What's going on
between you two?
You boyfriend and girlfriend?
What did we just talk about?
What?
What you talking about?
Smack him?
Any smacking
around here, I'll do?
You going to listen to him
tell you to smack me,
your older brother?
Rememberwhoyou are?
Your name is Vito Frangone,
not Vito Muhammad?
OK?
I'd love foryou
to stay out of my business?
Stop putting these thoughts
into my brother's head, OK?
Look, I don't play
that Muhammad shit, all right?
What Muhammad shit?
Look?? Don't fuck me, all right?
Oh, man?
Fuck, man?
I hate this place?
What a waste?
As I was saying
before we were
so rudely interrupted
by New York City's finest...
What was you saying?
The motherfucker
wasrt saying shit?
Yeah?
Look at that?
Look at what?
It's a goddamn shame?
What's a goddamn shame?
Sweet DickWillie?
That's my name?
Do I have to spell it out?
Make it plain?
OK, but listen up?
I'm going to break it down?
Let it be broke?
Can you dig it?
It's dug?
Look at those Korean motherfuckers
across the street?
Bet they haven't been
offthe boat a year
before they opened
their own place?
Right? It's been about a year?
A motherfuckir year
off the motherfuckir boat,
and they got a business
in our neighborhood?
A good business,
occupying a building
that had been boarded up
for longer than
I care to remember,
and I've been here a long time?
Yeah, a long time?
Hear, boy?
Now, for the life of me??
You know, I can't
figure this out?
Either them Korean motherfuckers
are geniuses??
Oryou black asses
are just plain dumb?
Fuckyou?
It's got to be
because we're black?
Ain't no other explanation?
You know it's true?
They're always keeping
the black man to about shit!
Oh, oh! You motherfuckers
hold that shit down?
I'm tired ofthat
old excuse, that shit?
I swear, man,
I will be one happy fool
when we open
our own business
right here in our neighborhood?
I swear to God,
I'll be first to spend
what little money I got?
You motherfuckers
are always talking
that old Keith Sweat shit...
"I'm gonna do this,
I'm gonna do that?"
You ain't gonna do nothing?
You're gonna sit on this corner?
When you going
to getyour business?
Just like I thought?
You ain't going to do
a goddamn thing?
But I'm going
to go give them Koreans
more ofmy money?
Out ofmyway?
It's Millertime, motherfuckers?
Old Moosehead fuckers
telling mewhat to do?
Coconut, you got nerve?
You got offthe boat, too?
Leave me alone?
Kung Fu, give me
one of them damn beers?
No more free beer?
Don't push me, baby?
Don't start no shit?
Mr? Sweet DickWillie?
Right? That's my name?
It's a motherfuckir shame?
Man, ain't that a bitch?
Here, Doctor?
What's your name?
Eddie?
How old areyou?
10?
What makes Sammy run?
My name is Eddie?
My name is Eddie Lovell?
Relax? I wantyou
to go to the store for me?
What'll it cost?
How would I know?
What am I buying?
Eddie, you're too smart
foryour own britches?
How much doyou want
to go to the store
for the man?
50 cents?
You got a deal?
I wantyou to get me
a quart ofbeer?
Miller High Life?
Say it's foryour bedridden,
old granddad?
Now, go? Go?
What is wrong with him?
He ain't got no money for nobody?
Look at this here, man?
Cut this shit out?
What makes you the Mayor
ofthis block?
Shit, he's self-appointed?
Leave the man alone?
Shut up!
Look, you all leave me
the hell alone?
I ain't going out
like that, man?
You walk around this block
likeyou own it?
For real?
You're so old,
you're like a fossil?
You're a bum?
You're an old drunk zero?
Now what doyou got to say?
Whatyou know about me?
Can't even pee straight,
nary a one ofyou?
Whatyou know about anything?
Unless you...
Unless you done stood
in the door??
And listened toyour
five hungry children
crying for bread,
and you can't do
anything about it?
Yourwoman standing there...
You can't even look
her in the eye?
Unless you done that,
you don't know my pain,
my hurt, my feelings?
You don't know shit!
Don't call me bum?
Don't call me a drunk?
You don't got the sense
God give a billy goat!
Don't call me nothing!
It's disrespectful?
Your mamas and papas
raised you better?
I hopeyou finished
your little soliloquy
'cause I been peeing straight
foryears?
Understand what I'm saying?
And you're right?
I wouldn't stand around
listening to my children
go hungry?
I'd be getting a job,
anything to feed them?
You're right?
I don't want to knowyour pain?
I don't care?
You did this toyourself?
Every day I seeyou walk
up and down this block, inebriated?
Never sober, but that's
what D-A stands for...
Da Mayor... drunk ass?
Come on!
This mars getting me mad!
He don't get no respect!
You'll never get
respect here, boy!
I respect those
who respect themselves!
Ahmad!
Come on, man!
Tina, I know it's been four days?
I'm a working man?
I work, too,
and I seem to make time?
What do you want me
to do, huh?
Spend some time
with me and Hector!
I wantyou to try and make
this relationship work?
If not, I'd rather not
be bothered with your ass?
Mookie, you're too, too tired?
OK, all right, damn?
I'll be over sometime today?
You always say later!
Laterwhen I get offwork?
Bring some ice cream?
I'm burning up?
Mookie, doyou love me?
Do I loveyou?
Mookie, get offthe phone!
Be offin a second,
all right, Sal?
Do I loveyou?
I dedicated a record
on Love Daddy's show to you?
So what?
How's anybody going
to call in, Mookie?
All right!
One time?
You probablywasted??
Lfthat ain't love, you're crazy?
Areyou deaf orwhat?
Pino, I'm talking on the phone?
I think I see that?
Tina, I got to go?
Yeah, Pino's an asshole?
Seeyou later today?
Later!
Everybody happy?
[Ring]
Sal's Famous?
Yeah? Yeah, hold it?
OK, two large anchovy
and pepperoni?
OK? Just hold on one second?
See, Daddy? Mookie's
fucking talking on the phone,
people are trying
to call in orders?
He's making us lose business?
Mookie!
20 minutes?
How come niggers
are so stupid?
Lfyou see a nigger,
kick his ass?
Fuckyou?
Stay offthe phone?
Hey, Mookie?
Forget about it?
Can I talk toyou for a second?
What?
Who's your favorite
basketball player?
Magic Johnson?
Who's your favorite movie star?
Eddie Murphy?
Who's your favorite rock star?
Prince?
You're a Prince freak?
Boss? Bruce?
Prince?
All you talk about is
nigger this and nigger that?
Your favorite people are niggers?
It's different?
Magic, Eddie, Prince??
Are not niggers?
I mean, they're not black,
I mean...
Let me explain myself?
They're...
They're not really black?
I mean, they're black,
but not really?
They're more than black?
It's different?
Yeah? To me,
it's different?
Deep down you wish
you were black?
Get the fuck out ofhere?
Go ahead, laugh?
Your hair's kinkier than mine?
What does that mean?
And you know what they say
about dark Italians?
You know, I been listening??
And reading...
You been reading now?
I read?
I've been reading
aboutyour leaders?
Reverend Al
"Mister 'Do" Sharpton?
Jesse "Keep hope alive"??
That's fucked up?
"Keep hope alive?"
That's fucked?
Don't talk about Jesse?
And even the other guy,
what's his name?
Faraman, Fairakan...
Minister Farakhan?
Right? Sorry?
Anyway, Minister Farakhan
always talks about the so-called day??
When the black man will rise?
What does he say?
"We will one day rule the earth
as we did in our glorious past"?
That's right?
What past?
What did I miss?
We started civilization?
Man, keep dreaming, man?
Then you woke up!
Pino, fuckyou?
Fuckyour fucking pizza,
and fuck Frank Sinatra?
Yeah? Well, fuckyou, too,
and fuck Michael Jackson?
You dago, wop, guinea,
garlic-breath,
pizza-slinging,
spaghetti-bending,
Vic Damone, Perry Como,
Luciano Pavarotti,
solo mio,
nonsinging motherfucker?
You gold-teeth,
gold-chain-wearing,
fried-chicken
and biscuit-eating monkey,
ape, baboon, big thigh,
fast-running,
high-jumping,
spear-chucking,
360-degree basketball-dunking,
tit, soon, spade, moulan, yan?
Takeyourfucking pizza piece
and go the fuck back to Africa?
You little slanty-eyed,
me-no-speaky-American,
own every fruit and vegetable stand
in New York,
bullshit,
Reverend Sun Yung Moon,
Summer Olympic '88,
Korean kick-boxing,
son-of-a-bitch?
You Goya bean-eating,
15-in-a-car,
30-in-an-apartment,
pointy shoes, red-wearing,
menudo, mira-mira,
Puerto Rican cocksucker?
Yeah, you!
It's cheap?
I got good price foryou,
Mayor Kochie,
"How I'm doing?"
Chocolate-egg-cream drinking,
bagel-and-lox,
B'nai B'rith, Jew asshole?
Yo! Hold up!
Time out!
Y'all, take a chill!
Ya need to cool
that shit out!
And that's the double truth, Ruth!
Sal, can you do me a favor?
That depends, Mookie?
Can you pay me now?
I can't do that?
Sal, just this once?
Can'tyou do me a solid, man?
Not till tonight when we close?
Sal, I want to get paid now?
You knowyou get paid
tonight when we close?
We're still open, OK?
Lfl payyou now,
you won't show tonight?
That's a bet?
Yeah, that's a bet?
I'm going to remember that?
You got to do
whatyou got to do?
I'll remember that?
I wantyou to?
Please do me a favor, hey, Mook?
Remember that?
Come on, Sal?
I can't?
Radio Raheem!
Mook?
What's happening?
It's yourworld?
Whereyou headed to?
I'm going to get a slice?
You going to Sal's?
I'll checkyou back there?
On the rebound?
You bet?
All right?
Oh, shit!
Let me check it out?
That's the hype!
Newest latest?
Let me tell you the story
of right hand/left hand?
It's a tale of good and evil?
Hate?
It was with this hand
that Cain iced his brother?
Love?
These five fingers,
they go straight
to the soul of man?
The right hand...
the hand oflove?
The story oflife is this??
Static?
One hand is always
fighting the other hand,
and the left hand
is kicking much ass?
I mean, it looks like the right hand...
love... is finished?
But hold on?
Stop the presses?
The right hand's coming back?
He got the left hand
on the ropes now?
That's right?
Yeah? Ooh!
It's a devastating right,
and hate is hurt?
Down! Ooh! Ooh!
Left hand, hate,
K? O? 'd by love?
If I love you, I love you?
But if I hate you??
There it is...
love and hate?
I love you, brother?
Bet?
Radio Raheem,
checkyou later?
Peace?
# Fight the power #
# We've got to fight
the powers that be #
Two slices?
No service till you
turn that shit off!?
Two slices?
Turn it off!?
Mr? Radio Raheem??
I can't even hear myself think!
You are disturbing me!
You are disturbing my customers!
# Fight the power #
# Fight the power... ##
[Click]
Two slices?
You come into Sal's??
There's no music?
No rap, no music,
no music, no music?
Capisci?
Understand?
Yo, put some extra mozzarella
on that motherfuckir shit?
Extra cheese is $2? 00?
[Doorbell Rings]
Pizza delivery!
All right? Later?
Mousie, what's up?
Watch out? Move!
People are in the same shit!
What's up, buddy?
Howyou livir, man?
Here come Mookie?
Mookie!
Give me some ofthat!
Get a job?
Don't need no job?
Get a job, man?
Shut up!
Buggir?
Where are the females?
You don't do nothir
with them anyway?
Hey, I've got it like that?
M-M-M-Mookie?
All right?
Hereyou go?
Stop bothering me?
Th-Th-Thankyou,
b-b-b-black man?
All right?
Leave me alone?
Jade!
What?
Mookie, how come
you're not at Sal's?
I'm working?
What's this... Another ofyour
patented two-hour lunch breaks?
I wanted to come home
and take a quick shower?
Sal's going to be mad?
Sometimes I thinkyou're more
concerned about him than me,
and I'm your brother?
That's real smart?
Sal pays you?
That's whyyou should work?
I work?
Slavery's over?
My name ain't Kunta Kinte?
I just don't wantyou
to lose the one job
you've kept over a month?
I'm carrying you as it is?
I'll always get paid?
Yeah? You always get paid?
What about
your responsibilities?
Why don'tyou
take better care ofthose?
What responsibilities?
What areyou, deaf?
You know what
I'm talking about?
Take care ofyour responsibilities,
all right?
Whoyou yelling at, anyway?
I'm yelling atyou?
I'm going to take care
ofthis shower?
I'm your big brother?
Don't beyelling at me?
You're a bum?
Don't call me no bum?
Whew!
Lfl want to shower
in the middle of the day,
it's OK?
Fuck Sal?
We love roll call, y'all?
Boogie Down Productions,
Rob Base, Dana Dane??
Marley Marl, Olatunji,
Chuck D., Ray Charles,
EPMD, EU, Alberta Hunter,
Run DMC, Stetsasonic,
Sugar Bear, John Coltrane,
Big Daddy Kane,
Salt 'n ' Pepa,
Luther Vandross,
McCoy Tyner,
Biz Markie,
New Edition, Otis Redding,
Anita Baker,
Thelonious Monk,
Marcus Miller,
Branford Marsalis,
James Brown, Wayne Shorter,
Tracy Chapman,
Miles Davis,
Force MD's,
Oliver Nelson,
Fred Wesley, Maceo,
JanetJackson,
Louis Armstrong,
Duke Ellington,
JimmyJam,
Terry Lewis,
George Clinton,
Count Basie, Mtume,
Stevie Wonder,
Bobby McFerrin,
Dexter Gordon,
Sam Cooke,
Parliament Funkadelic,
AIJarreau,
Teddy Pendergrass,
Joe Williams,
Wynton Marsalis,
Phyllis Hyman, Sade,
Sarah Vaughn,
Roland Kirk,
Keith Sweat,
Kool Moe D,
Prince,
Ella Fitzgerald,
Diana Reeves,
Aretha Franklin,
Bob Marley,
Bessie Smith,
Whitney Houston,
Dionne Warwick,
Steel Pulse,
Little Richard,
Mahalia Jackson,
Jackie Wilson,
Cannonball and Nat Adderly,
QuincyJones,
Marvin Gaye,
Charles Mingus,
and Mary Lou Williams.
We want to thank you all
for making our lives
just a little brighter
here on We-Love radio.
I t's hot as a motherfucker?
Fan me with your ears?
Stop playir!
Leave it alone?
Why don't he leave me alone?
Shut up?
It's too hot for that?
That's why I asked you?
We don't have money for anything?
I'm beat?
Daddy, you know,
I've been thinking?
Maybe we should sell this place?
Get out while we're still ahead??
And alive?
You really thinkyou know
what's best for us, Pino?
I mean, couldn't we sell this
and open up a new one
in our own neighborhood?
There's too many pizzerias
already there?
Maybe we could try
something different?
What am I going to do?
That's all I know?
I been here 25 years?
Where am I going?
I'm sick of niggers?
It's like I come to work??
It's "Planet of the Apes?"
I don't like being around them?
They're animals?
Whyyou got so much anger in you?
Why? I'll tell you why?
My friends...
They laugh at me?
They laugh right in my face?
They tell me,
"Go to Bed-Stuy?
Go feed the moulies?"
Doyour friends put money
in your pocket, Pino?
Food on your table?
They payyour rent,
a roof overyour head?
Huh?
They're not your friends?
Lftheywere your friends,
theywouldn't laugh atyou?
Pop, what can I say?
I don't want to be here?
They don't want us here?
We should stay
in our own neighborhood,
in Bensonurst,
and niggers in theirs?
I never had no trouble
with these people?
I sat in this window??
All I see is
little kids get old?
And I seen
the old people get older?
Yeah, sure,
some of them don't like us,
but most of them do?
I mean, for chrissake, Pino,
they grew up on my food?
On my food?
I'm very proud ofthat?
You may think it's funny,
but I'm very proud ofthat?
Look, what I'm trying
to say, son, is, uh??
Sal's Famous Pizzeria
is here to stay?
I'm sorry?
I'm your father,
and I loveyou?
I'm sorry, but??
But that's the way it is?
Hey, S-S-Sal?
How you doing?
These are $2? 00?
Get out?
Get the fuck out ofhere, man!
Get the fuck out ofhere!
$2? 00?
S-S-Sal?
Come on?
Get out ofhere?
Get the fuck out ofhere!
Every day it's the same shit?
Hey, leave that boy alone!
Get a fucking job?
Why don'tyou get a fucking job?
Go to fucking work!
S-S-Sal?
Get out? Get out!
See what I'm saying?
Leave that boy alone?
You know he ain't right!
Get a fucking job, man!
I'm sick ofthis shit?
You get a job!
I got a job?
Bring your ass here, punk!
I ain't going over there?
I ain't got no reason
to go over there?
F-F-F-Fuckyou!
Fuckyou!
Get the fuck out ofhere!
F-F-F-Fuckyou!
Go inside?
Smiley, here? Here?
Smiley, here?
Here's a couple of dollars?
Come on? Come on? Here?
Fuckir asshole!
Hey, Willie,
take it easy?
He didn't mean nothir?
[Door Slams]
OK?
Motherfucker!
This is what I'm talking about?
Whoo!
Let's go, Jade!
Da Mayor,
we need your leadership?
Doctor, what areyou talking about?
I'm organizing a boycott
ofSal's Famous?
Shit?
Keep walking, Doctor?
I don't want to hear
none ofyour damn black foolishness?
Damn? No juice?
No, man, no?
No!
Hell, no, goddamn it?
Sal ain't never
done nothir toyou before?
Whatyou ought to boycott
is that barber
that fucked upyour head?
Yeah!
Shit?
Come out here fuckir
with Sweet DickWillie?
Get the fuck away?
Would you sign a petition
to boycott Sal's Famous Pizzeria?
I ain't boycottir jack,
string-cheese
head motherfucker?
I'm going for a slice now?
I was raised on Sal's pizza?
Whatyou talkir about?
You crazy, man?
Good as them
motherfuckir pizzas is?
Black Panther eat pizza,
we eat pizza?
I'll do it withoutyour help?
That's 75 cents?
Thanks?
Thanks, honey?
Sal, we're going to boycott
your fat pasta ass?
You're going...
You're going to boycott me?
You haven't got the balls
to boycott me?
He's going to boycott me?
Are you kidding?
Here...
Here's your boycott?
Up your ass?
You're going to boycott?
Where you going?
I'm talking toyou, Pino!
I'm right here?
Go inside?
I can take care of myself?
Take it easy, OK?
No? Go inside?
Here's your boycott!
Messed up myJordans with muck?
Damn!
Get this thing
straightened out, man?
White guy/black man?
I can't believe this crap?
Ah, yourJordans are dogged?
Oh, man, you, too? Stop?
Yeah, me, too?
Hangir out with baby sis?
We're not hangir out?
She's escortir me back to Sal's?
I'm just goir to get a slice?
You can't? Not today?
I'm organizing a boycott
ofSal's Famous?
What did he do?
You know them pictures
he got on the wall offame?
So?
Notice somethir about them?
No, Buggir Out,
I haven't?
You're wasting my time?
Leave that shit alone?
You really should?
I'm gone?
I'll seeyou there?
Buggir Out, howyou been?
Every single one of them pictures
is somebody Italian?
And??
Wewant black people?
Did you ask Sal?
Yeah, I asked him?
Wewant nobody in there,
nobody spending
good money in Sal's,
until we get black pictures
on the wall?
What good will that do?
Lfyou tried hard,
you could direct
your energies more usefully?
You got to be down?
You ain't?
I'm down, but I'm down for something
positive in the community?
Areyou down for that?
Jade??
Jade, I still
loveyou anyway?
Yeah, I still loveyou,
too, Buggir Out?
Later?
Man?
You're pushing it, Mookie?
You're really pushing it?
I don't pay good money
to haveyou jerk me around?
Keep it up,
you'll be in the street
with your other homeboys?
About time, Pop?
Jade?
Howyou doir, Jade?
Whereyou been?
Just working hard?
Keeping busy?
How's business?
Business is great?
We were wondering
when you'd stop by?
How's Mookie doing?
He's, uh?? Mookie is??
He's great?
A good kid?
Hey, Pop?
Stop lying?
He's kidding?
I know?
What'll it be?
Regular slice?
No, I'm going to makeyou
something special,
ifyou don't mind?
No, that'll be great?
OK? What doyou
want to drink?
Cream soda?
Used to be root beer?
Tell me ifl'm wrong?
I want a change ofpace?
Vito, clean the table forJade?
All right, Pop?
Come here, Jade?
Sit here?
# Fight thepower#
[Music Slows]
# Fight the power #
# Fight the pow... ##
20 "D" Energizers?
20 "C" Energizers?
"D?" Not "C?" "D?"
"C" Energizers?
"D," motherfucker? "D!!"
Learn to speak English first,
all right? "D!"
How manyyou say?
20, motherfucker? 20?
[Speaking Korean]
Motherfuckyou!
Motherfuck??
Motherfucker, you,
you all right, man?
Just give me
the motherfuckir batteries?
20 "D" fuckir batteries?
Hey, yo? Yo, wait?
What's the date on them?
The date!
The fuckir date!
What?
Can you fuckir speak English?
The date!
The date?
Marcha!
Marcha?
Whatyou talkir about... Marcha?
1991?
Oh, March?
That's March, motherfucker,
March?
Yo, man,
you sure that's 20?
20?
No? No? Take them out?
Count them again?
Count the shits again, man?
Motherfucker?
May I helpyou?
I want some flowers?
The whole thing?
It's very expensive?
I know? I'll pay?
I thoughtyou might like these?
I guess not?
There is nothing
like the smell offresh flowers?
Don'tyou agree,
Mother Sister?
Summertime...
All you can smell is the garbage?
Smell overpowers everything,
especially the soft,
sweet smell offlowers?
You don't mind,
I'll sit right here,
catch a breeze or two,
then be on myway?
Thank the Lord,
the sun is going down?
It is hot as blazes?
Yes, Jesus?
Well, guess I'll be on myway?
[Boom Box Blares]
Oh!
Oh, goddamn, man!
Cut that shit down!
A person go deaf
or something?
Fucker!
Man, I don't know
how he does it?
Oh, man!
Goddamn?
That is shit?
ML, come here?
What?
Come hold this fucker, baby?
Hold what, sucker?
You know what I'm talkir about?
That's OK?
At least my moms
didn't name me??
Sweet DickWillie?
Uh-huh?
I told you about that mama shit?
Nobody talkir aboutyour moms?
I ain't say nobody?
I said you!
Just squash that shit?
I didn't mean it like that?
You did, too?
I justwanted to know
who named you
Sweet DickWillie?
Man, it's just a name?
Goddamn? Shit?
How'd you get the name ML?
ML stands for ML?
Now that's some stupid shit?
Hear me?
That's some stupid shit?
'Cause everybody know
why they call me
Sweet DickWillie?
You Negroes kill me?
Always holding on to??
Always talking
aboutyour dicks?
It's too hot to fuck?
Man, you out
your fuckir mind?
It ain't never too hot
or never too cold for fuckir?
I had my best piece ofwoman
on a humid day?
Over in the projects?
Close to yourwoman?
Get out!
Oh, Lord, have mercy?
I better not see her
naked on payday?
Piraguero!
Everybody out!
The icee, icee man is here?
Hey hey!
Looking good?
Here we are?
Look at these beautiful people?
The icee man is here?
I want coconut?
Give me lemon?
Tell me whatyou need?
Thereyou go, my love?
That's your color?
That's your flavor?
I want more syrup on mine?
He's always drinking, man?
[Ice Cream Truck
Music Chimes]
Hey, hey!
Where's everybody going?
Ice cream!
Doctor!
Doctor, don'tyou
know no better
than to run out
in front of a car?
You trying to kill yourself?
Come on?
Let's get up?
You gonna be all right?
You gonna be all right, my boy?
You gonna be just fine?
Eddie, what's wrong?
Mayor knocked me down?
You ought to be
shamed ofyourself?
Ha ha? That boy's
just scared to death?
What happened...
I was walking,
minding my business?
I seen your son
about to get hit by the car,
so I dashed out?
I knocked him down
to keep us both
from getting hit?
I saved two lives today...
his and mine?
Eddie, is that the truth?
Eddie, you hear me
talking to you?
I'm talking toyou, boy?
He gonna be fine, miss?
Mommy, Mommy!
I'm sorry!
Get upstairs now!
Your father gonna
wear outyour behind?
Miss, you didn't have
to hityour boy like that?
He's already scared to death?
I appreciateyou
helping my Eddie,
but I'll have nobody question
how I raise him?
You're right, miss?
You're right?
I don't want to sound like a jerk,
but can I say something, Jade?
Yeah, Sal?
You got the biggest eyes
I've ever seen?
Theyjump out ofyour head?
I feel embarrassed
even saying that?
Thanks, Sal?
Don't even mention it?
It was delicious?
I got to talk toyou?
Come on?
Let's go?
Jade, don't forget
to come back soon, OK?
Hey, Mookie?
Take it easy?
You're going to bust her arm?
I don't wantyou
in Sal's no more?
Mookie, what?
Stop tripping?
Read my lips?
Don't see Sal?
What areyou worked up about?
The way Sal looks atyou?
- He's being nice?
- Nice?
- He's completely innocent?
- Innocent?
You heard me?
Sal just wants
to hide the salami?
You're really crude, Mookie?
Do not come in Sal's anymore?
You are not welcome?
You got a lot of nerve?
I'll tell you one last time?
Stop playing
big brother to me?
I'm a grown woman!
You can't payyour rent,
and you're lecturing me?
That makes no sense?
Oh, it doesn't, huh?
You got $250 a week?
I'm getting paid?
Peanuts?
In a while,
I'll be making a move?
Yeah, when?
Don't worry?
When, Mookie?
Don't worry about it?
Don't come here no more?
We're not talking about that?
I'm tired ofsupporting
a grown woman, OK?
a grown man, OK?
When areyou going
to pack up and go?
Don't come in Sal's no more?
And no more pizza, either?
I don't care ifyou fire me
this exact fucking moment?
Lfyou're saying
what I'm thinking
you're saying,
you better not say it?
You hear this?
Do me a favor?
LeaveJade alone?
You know, Mookie,
not for nothir,
but ifyou were
just a little taller,
I'd kickyour ass
forwhatyou're thinking?
As a matter offact,
I should kickyour ass
on principle alone?
Here?
You got a delivery?
This the right address?
What is this??
Yeah? It's the right address?
That's the right address?
I wrote it myself?
Sometimes you make mistakes,
and I deliver fucking pizzas
to the wrong fucking address?
I don't make mistakes?
You don't make mistakes?
Hurry back, OK?
Don't get lost?
We're still open?
Make a pizza, huh?
Mr? Mayor?
I saw whatyou did?
That was foolish but brave?
That child owes you his life?
Wasrt trying to be a hero?
I just seen what was happening,
and I reacted... didn't even think?
Probablywouldn't have done it
ifl had thought?
Da Mayor's getting old?
Ain't run like that in years?
Went from first to home
on a bunt single?
Scored the winning run?
Two outs?
Bottom of the ninth?
August 1, 1939?
Snow Hill, Alabama?
Mud Cat Bones
was the pitcher?
He hated my guts?
He come down offthat mound,
and I took off
like white lightning
up a black snake's ass?
Maybe I, uh??
Maybe I ought to be
a hero more often?
Maybeyou shouldn't?
Don't get happy?
This changes nothing
between you and me?
You did a good thing?
Mother Sisterjust thanks you?
I want to thankyou?
You're welcome?
Delivery from
Sal's Famous Pizzeria?
Is it hot?
I've never delivered a cold pizza?
Come here?
You thinkyou're slick, Tina?
How else could
I getyou up here?
I haven't seen you all week?
I'm working?
Making money?
You forgot the ice cream again?
I forgot?
Your memory's getting ridiculous?
I got things on my mind?
I reallywanted some ice cream?
I'll run out and get some?
No, no? That's out?
You won't come back?
I can't be staying long?
How long?
Long enough to do the nasty?
Come on, Mookie?
That's out?
First of all, it's too hot?
Lfyou think
I'll letyou get some,
putyour clothes on and leave,
and I won't seeyou again,
you're bugging?
I'll seeyou tomorrow?
Yeah, right?
So no nasty, huh?
No?
Something else?
What?
Trust me?
Last time I trusted you,
we got a son?
Remember him?
His name's Hector?
You saying I'm a bad father?
On the strength?
Let me talk toyou?
What? What?
Over here?
Tina, takeyour clothes off?
I already told you
it's too fucking hot
to make love?
It's too fucking hot?
Why are you always cursing?
I don't fucking curse that much?
What the hell you mean?
All you do is curse?
Anyway, no rawness
is jumping offtonight?
All right?
That's it?
No rawness?
No? No rawness?
Why's it always like that
when you come over?
It's not always like that?
It's always...
What areyou doing?
I'm not cursing?
Mookie? Come on?
I mean it?
I'm not playing?
Don't be so anxious?
That's right?
Take it off?
You're sweating?
Of course I'm sweating?
It's only 100 degrees in here?
Look, freeze?
Don't move?
I'll be right back?
What doyou mean
you'll be right back?
Where areyou going?
I'll be right back?
Whyyou got me
standing on the bed?
Whereyou going?
How's my son, Hector?
Honey, doyou hear that?
He wants to know
howyou are doing?
And he has the straight face
of asking about it?
Sinverguenza.
Good for nothing?
Callejero.
Que se la pasa por la calle... -
English! English!
I want my son speaking English?
Get out of my kitchen?
Bad enough his name's Hector?
I don't want to hear anything?
Out, I said?
Yes, children?
This is the cool-out corner?
We're slowing it down
for all the lovers in the house?
I'll be giving you
all the helpyou need?
Musically, that is?
This shit is cold?
Supposed to be cold?
It's an ice cube?
Later foryour shit?
Mira.
What?
You don't got a forehead?
You got a eight-head?
Mookie, you're full of shit?
You got one of them
Sade foreheads?
Fuckyou?
Goddamn?
Big-ass forehead?
I need an iceberg??
Rather than this ice cube?
Thank God for lips?
Thank God for the neck?
Thank God for kneecaps?
Thank God for elbows?
Thank God for thighs?
Thank God
for the right nipple?
for the left nipple?
Feels good?
Ah? You likes?
You likes?
Amen?
I got to be going?
You better come back?
I'll be back tonight?
You better,
'cause I'll kickyour ass?
Oops? I got to be back then?
All right?
Get out ofhere?
I got to go?
Bye?
I'm not leaving yet?
Get out ofhere?
All right? Later?
Later?
Just out of curiosity,
how long you
sticking around here?
You mean tonight?
I mean the neighborhood?
I figure about 50 years?
'Cause I'm going into real estate?
I'll put up a high-rise
in the neighborhood?
Yeah? Lot ofpeople
want to move here?
Why not?
You want a condominium?
A couple ofstraws, Mr? Trump?
Trump's Pizza?
I heard ofthat?
That's Trump's Plaza?
Get out ofhere?
Take care, Salvatore?
Pino, take the soft drinks
from the back
and load up here?
OK, Pop?
You want me to deliver faster,
I need a rocket?? Something?
I can't be running?
The cheese lands on one side?
Mookie, I didn't say nothing?
You must have a guilty conscience?
I'm not guilty ofanything?
You're guilty ofsomething?
Otherwiseyou wouldn't be saying that?
Come on, Sal?
Wherewe going?
Oh, shit?
Vito, give me a hand?
Come on?
What the fuck's the matter?
Vito, I wantyou to listen to me?
I'm your brother?
I smackyou around
once in a while,
but I'm still?? Your brother?
So what, Pino?
So fucking what?
I loveyou, man?
I'm listening?
I wantyou to listen?
Jesus Christ, Pino?
I said I'm listening?
Vito, black?? White? No?
No, no, no? No?
What the hell
you talking about?
Areyou listening to me?
Stop busting my balls?
I said I'm listening?
Mookie's not to be trusted?
I trust him, Pino?
They can't be trusted?
First timeyou turn your back??
Boom? Aah!
The spear in the back?
How doyou know this?
How doyou know, man?
I know? I read?
I never seen you read nothing
in your fucking life?
Read your history?
It's historical?
He, them??
They're not to be trusted?
What do you want me to do?
Be on fucking guard?
Mookie has Pop conned,
so we got to look out for him?
You don't know
whatyou're saying?
That's exactlywhat I'm saying?
[Sal]
Vito! Pino! Let's go!
We'll be right there, Pop?
One minute?
You better listen to what I say?
I'll ripyou?
I'll fuckyou up?
You know something, Pino?
You don't know everything
you thinkyou know?
You thinkyou know,
butyou don't know?
Mookie, he listens to me?
You don't, man?
You fucking don't?
You'll fucking stab me
in the back, man?
[Rap Music Blares]
Radio!
Buggir, what's up?
Howyou been, man?
Living large, bro?
Yo, that the only tapeyou gots?
You don't like
Public Enemy, man?
The shit's dope?
I'm down, butyou don't be
playing nothing else?
I don't like nothing else?
Yo, check this?
You know Sal?
Yeah, I know
that motherfucker?
I've been trying
to organize a boycott
ofSal's Famous?
I almost had to bust him
in the head today?
Gonna tell me...
Tell me, Radio Raheem...
to turn down my box
and shit, man,
and didn't even say "please!"
Who the fuck he think
he is, Don Corleone?
He make much money
off us black people,
and all he got on the wall
is Italians...
Sylvester Stallone,
okey-doke-lookir motherfuckers?
On the strength?
We shouldn't buy one slice,
spend one penny in there
till he put folks of color
on that wall?
That's what I'm saying!
You got my back?
Your back is got?
My bro?
Yo, Smiley?
Come here, man?
Whatyou listening to?
M-M-M-Malcolm?
M-M-M-Malcolm, huh?
Cut offthat rap music!
I'm in here trying to get me
some motherfucking...
I'll fuckyou up quick!
Two times!
Th-Th-Th-Three t-times!
Th...
Sal, start counting
my money tonight
'cause I gots to get paid?
Come on, Vito?
Come on?
This is terrific?
I mean we had
a great, great day?
You know something?
There's nothing like a family
in business working together?
I'm going to rename the place?
I'm going to call it
Sal and Sons'
Famous Pizzeria?
Why not?
You guys are going to
take it over someday, right?
And, Mookie??
Mookie, I want to tell you
that there's always
going to be a place foryou
right here
at Sal's Famous Pizzeria
becauseyou've always
been like a son to me?
Sal! Can we get some pizza?
We're closed!
Shut up!
You shut up!
Shut the fuck up, man!
All right, let them in?
They love my pizza?
Four slices, and I'm gone?
Sal, we're trying to go home!
Shut up!
You're a delivery boy, bitch!
Man, you don't know shit!
Shut the fuck up!
Sityour black ass down!
Shut up! Fuckyou!
Yo, Sal?
Four slices, man, regular?
To go, all right?
Whyyou gotta curse?
Looking good?
Looking real good, man?
Come on?
Move it, man!
# Fight the power #
# We got to fight
the powers that be #
# Elvis was a hero to most#
# But he never meant shit to me #
# Ya see straight out
racist the sucka... ##
I told you about that noise!
What about them pictures?
What the fuck, are you deaf?
No! Are you?
Fuckyou!
We want some black people
on that motherfucking
wall offame now!
We're trying
to go fucking home!
We've been here all day!
Turn that jungle music off!?
This ain't Africa!
Why it got to be
about jungle music?
Why it got to be about Africa?
It's about them fucking pictures!
It's about turning that shit off
and getting out of my place!
Radio Raheem!
Fuckyou!
And fuckyou, too!
Kick ass, Sal!
Get in there, Pino!
This is music!
My music!
Fuckyour music!
Well, turn it off, then!
Get the fuck out ofhere!
We're closed!
Fuckyou!
We're closing you
guinea bastards for good!
For good, motherfucker!
Until you get some black people
on that motherfucking
wall offame!
You're gonna fucking close me?
You're goddamn right!
You black cocksucker!
I'll fucking tear
your fucking nigger ass!
Oh, we're niggers now?
We niggers now?
Fuck them up!
You fucking white trash!
I'll fuckyou up!
Sal, put the fucking bat down!
Come on,
you fucking guinea trash!
Open the motherfucking counter!
You black cocksucker!
You nigger motherfucker!
[Music Stops]
I just killed your fucking radio?
My music!
You motherfucking...
Aah!
Get offhim!
Get the fuck offhim!
Get off!?
You fucked up my eye!
Ahmad, stop!
Please, stop it!
Stop it!
You fucked with my box, man!
Get the fuck up!
I'll kickyour ass some more!
Come on!
Somebody got it at Sal's, brother!
Fight!
Mookie!
Hey!
Break it up!
Hey! Hey!
You're gonna kill him!
- Stop it!
- Break it up!
Stop it!
Stop! Break it up!
You're gonna kill him!
Let me at 'em?
Let me at 'em!
Get...
Get the fuck out
of the way, man!
Move it!
Get off!?
Let me through!
Get the big guy!
Get off me!
I'll kill you, you motherfucker!
Just take him off me!
Get away!
What are you doing? Sal!
Get the fuck off me!
Get off of me!
You're taking me to jail, huh?
You're not taking Vito
or Pino or Sal out!
Get the fuck off me!
Aah!
Get his other arm!
Take him down!
Just take him down, man!
Let him go, goddamn it!
You're killing him!
Give it up, asshole!
Aah! Aah!
Just take him down!
Come on!
Aah!
Let him go!
Stop it, goddamn it!
Stop it!
Aah!
Get his arm!
Gary, that's enough!
Shut up?
Gary, that's enough, man!
[Chokes]
Gary, that's enough!
Shut the fuck up!
Radio Raheem!
No!
Radio!
Radio Raheem!
Get up!
You ain't dead!
Get up, asshole!
Qit faking it!
Get the fuck up!
Let's get him out ofhere?
Goddamn it!
I'm a black man!
You can't kill us all!
You can't fucking
kill us all, goddamn it!
Motherfucker!
Let's get him out ofhere!
Come on!
Get him to the car?
Let's go?
Back off, assholes!
You pig-fucking murderers!
You can't kill us all, man!
You can't fucking kill us all!
Back off!?
Back off!? Back off!?
Everybody, back off!?
Get back!
Fucking bastards!
Shut up, man?
Fuck off, you fucking...
Damn it!
I told you to shut up!
Back off!?
Radio!
[Sobbing]
Mookie, they killed him?
They killed Radio Raheem!
It's murder?
They did it again,
just like Michael Stewart?
Murder!
Eleanor Bumpers! Murder!
Damn, man!
It ain't safe
in our own fucking neighborhood!
Neverwas?
Neverwill be?
We ain't gonna stand
for this shit no more, Sal?
Ain't gonna stand for
no fucking police, punk!
It's as plain as day?
They didn't have
to kill the boy?
[Smiley Sobbing]
You do whatyou gotta do?
Fuck that, man!
Listen, listen, listen?
Good people, please?
Let's all go home?
Somebody's gonna get hurt?
Yeah? You, boy!
Lfwe don't stop this now,
we gonna do something
we're gonna regret
for the rest of our lives?
Sal had nothing to do
with what the cops did?
One of the police was black!
Leave him alone?
We'll getyou
and them three stooges, Sal?
Go on, Mr? Sal?
You see how they had him
in a choke hold?
I knew that choke hold
would kill him!
You might have saved him!
A fucking radio!
He died because ofa fucking radio!
He wanted pictures
on the wall, and he died!
Whatyou got to say, Sal?
Your son called the cops!
Get the fuck out ofhere, man!
Somebody's getting hurt!
Fuck that, man!
Hate!
Ohh!
Whoo!
What are they doing?
Sal, come on?
Come on, quick?
Get them out of there!
Get...
That's my place!
That's my fucking place!
Sal!
Fucking niggers?
Radio! Radio!
Burn it down!
Come on?
Let's clean house?
Shit? Come on?
I no white?
I no white!
It's your turn, sucker!
I'm black!
What?
I black!
Me black!
Whereyou black at?
I'm black!
You, me... same!
We same?
Same?
Me black!
Open your eyes, motherfucker!
ML, leave the Korean alone, man?
He's all right?
Yeah? He's all right?
He's black?
Shit?
[Sirens Blaring]
Oh, fuckyou, man!
Howard Beach!
People, please disperse!
Please disperse!
Howard Beach!
We're giving you
one more warning
to please go home!
This is our home!
OK, you've had yourwarning!
Hose that black sucker down!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Get off of me!
Yo!
Well, come on! Come on!
Come on, asshole?
Come on!
Come on? Move it?
Motherfucker, come on!
What you think this is, Birmingham?
Fucking Alabama?
Yo, where's Bull Connor?
Son ofa bitch!
Oh, no!
No!
# Fight the power #
- # Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be #
- # Fight the power #
# Fight the power #
#We got to fight
the powers that be ##
My people, my people??
What can I say?
Saywhat I can?
I saw it, but I didn't believe it?
I didn't believe it, what I saw?
Are we going to live together?
Together are we going to live?
This is your
Mister Seor Love Daddy
talking toyou
from We-Love radio,
108 FM on your dial,
and that's the triple truth, Ruth?
Today's weather?
Hot!
Wake up!
Fuck!
My money? Shit!
Where are you going?
To get my money?
Don't try that shit, OK?
You're going to run out,
and I won't see your ass
for anotherweek?
It's not like that?
You don't give
a fucking shit about me,
and you don't
give a shit aboutyour son?
I care aboutyou and my son?
Why don'tyou be a man?
I am a man?
Then act like a man?
Why don'tyou be
a fucking man, Mookie?
I'm so tired ofyour shit?
Why do we have to
go over this again?
Becauseyou don't
fucking listen, Mookie!
Lfyou listen to me,
I wouldn't have to repeat myself
like a fucking radio!
What kind of motheryou are
using fucking language like that?
What kind of mother am I?
Your ass isn't even here!
Get anothervocabulary, right?
Get a fucking life?
Yeah? Look??
Lookwhat?
I'll be back?
Don't leave, Mookie?
Don't leave?
I'm tired ofthis shit?
You walk out that door, that's it?
All right?
I have to get my money from Sal?
I'll be back?
Your shit's to the curb,
and I'm tired ofit?
You need to step off
with your stupid-ass self?
You need to get
a fucking life, Mookie,
because the oneyou got
is not working!
I ain't going to deal
with this shit no more!
Shit?
Fucking ass, stupid ass,
fucking pendejo.
Shit? Fuck?
Fucking shit?
Good morning?
Is it a good morning?
Yes, indeed?
You almost gotyourself
killed last night?
I've done that before?
Where did you sleep?
I didn't?
I hope the block is still standing?
We're still standing?
What doyou want?
I want my money?
I want to get paid?
You don't work here no more?
I want my money?
Your money couldn't begin to pay
for the windowyou broke?
Motherfuck a window?
Radio Raheem is dead?
I know he's dead?
I was here, remember?
He's dead because ofhis buddy?
That cocksucker started this shit?
He's responsible
for that kid's death?
He wanted to close me,
and you stood there like a fuck
and watched them
burn me down!
I also watched the cops
murder Radio Raheem?
You'll get it all
from the insurance anyway, Sal?
What the fuck's
wrong with you?
This ain't about money?
I could give a fuck
about money?
You see this place?
I built this fucking place!
With my bare fucking hands!
Every light socket,
every piece oftile?
Me! With these fucking hands!
You know what that means?
It means pay me
my motherfucking money?
That's what it means, Sal?
OK, Mookie?
How much do I oweyou?
My salary is 250?
250 a week?
1??
That's 2??
That's 3??
That's 4??
And that's 5?
You got $500?
You're a rich fucking man?
Are you happy?
You happy?
He's got 500 fucking dollars!
He's a big man!
He's a rich fucking man!
He's never going to have
any more trouble!
Not Mookie!
He's fucking rich!
Who the fuckyou yelling at?
You're wealthy, Mookie?
You're a real fucking Rockefeller?
You gotyour fucking pay?
Now leave me alone?
Sal, my salary's 250 a week,
all right?
I oweyou 50 bucks?
Keep it?
You keep it?
No, you keep it?
I don't believe this shit?
Believe it?
Areyou sick?
I'm hot as a motherfucker?
I'm all right, though?
Well, they say it's even going
to get hotter today?
What areyou going
to do with yourself?
Make that money?
Get paid?
Sal, I got to go see my son
ifit's all right with you?
Hey, Mook.
It's the Mook man.
I seeyou walking.
Go home toyour kid.
Now the news and weather.
Our mayor has commissioned
a blue-ribbon panel...
"to get to the bottom
oflast night's disturbance.
The City ofNew York
will not let property
be destroyed by anyone."
His Honor plans to visit
our block today.
He should hook up
with our own Da Mayor,
buy him a beer.
Your Love Daddy
says register to vote.
The election is coming up.
There 's no end in sight
from this heat wave,
so today,
the cash money word is chill.
That's right. C-h-i-l-I.
When you hear "chill,"
call in at 555-L OVE,
andyou'll win
cash money, honey.
This is Mister Seor Love Daddy
coming atyou from
what's last on your dial
but first in your hearts,
and that's
the quintessential truth, Ruth.
The next record goes out
to Radio Raheem.
We love you, brother.
# From the heart ofBed-Stuy #
# W-e-L -o-v-e ##
# I was looki ng through
a wi ndow at my I ife today #
# And for the first time #
# I saw things in a different way #
# I n the middle of my mind #
# It was there all the time #
# Never explain love #
# It's not like anything
you've ever done #
# lfit is there,
it's yours to keep #
# And the boundaries, they grow deep #
# Never explain love #
# Let the experience take overyou #
# And when you do #
# Never explain love #
# I was looking for an answer #
# And I was searching for a sign #
#To try and understand
this relationship of mine #
# But I didn't need to go far #
# I was reading it all wrong #
# Never explain love #
# It's not like anything
you've ever done #
# lfit is there, it's yours to keep #
# And the boundaries, they grow deep #
# Never explain love #
# Let the experience take overyou #
# And when you do #
# Never explain love #
# Before I knew #
# I almost knew it all #
#Who needs to be rational #
#When love isn't practical #
# Oh, I knew this was inside #
# And it's so wrong #
# It's so right #
#Whoa-oh-ho ahh #
# Never explain love #
# It's not like anything
you've ever done #
# lfit is there,
it's yours to keep #
# And the boundaries, they grow deep #
# Never explain love #
# Let the experience take overyou #
# And when you do #
# Never explain love #
# It's not like anything
you've ever done #
# If it is there, it's yours to keep #
# And the boundaries, they grow deep #
# Never explain love #
# Let the experience take overyou #
# Forwhen you do #
#Yeah, yeah #
# Never explain love #
# Never explain love ##