Say, it's only a paper moon
Sailing over a cardboard sea
But it wouldn't be make-believe
If you believed in me
Yes, it's only a canvas sky
Hanging over a cotton tree
But it wouldn't be make-believe
If you believed in me
Without your love
It's a honky-tonk parade
It's a melody played in a penny arcade
It's a Barnum and Bailey world
Just as hollow as it can be
But it wouldn't be make-believe
If you believed in me
Rock of ages, cleft for me
Let me hide myself in thee
Let the water and the blood
From thy wounded side which flowed
Be of sin the double cure
Safe from wrath and make me pure
"Judge me, oh Lord,
"for I have lost in mine integrity.
"I have trusted also in the Lord,
"therefore I shall not slide.
"Examine me, oh Lord, and prove me.
"Try my reins and my heart,
"for Thy loving kindness
is before mine eyes
"and I have walked in Thy truth.
"I have not sat with evil persons.
"Neither will I go in with dissemblers.
"I will wash mine hands
"in innocency.
"So will I compass Thine altar, O Lord,
"that I may publish
with the voice of thanksgiving
"and tell of all Thy wondrous works..."
Howdy.
Loggins' funeral.
Yes, ma'am.
- You ain't related, are ya?
- Related, ma'am?
We're looking for the child's kin.
Thought I saw some resemblance.
No kin, huh?
None we know of,
'cept out in Missouri someplace.
- Missouri...
- Seems you got the child's jaw.
No, ma'am, just a friend of her mama's,
just passing through town.
If ever a child needed a friend.
"...will I bless the Lord.
"Amen."
Amen.
Amen, Essie Maye.
I just know your ass is still warm.
Would you like some water, Addie?
We'll get the child some water.
Bless you child, I just want to pay
my respects to your mama.
Well, I'm going to have to be going.
It's a long way to St. Louis.
- St. Louis? You mean in Missouri?
- Yes, ma'am.
I... I sell the good book, ma'am.
Just moving through the country
with the Lord's good news.
Addie, child, don't you have
your Aunt Billie living in St. Joseph?
St. Joseph, Missouri.
It's her poor mother's sister.
- The child's only known relative.
- That so?
You're driving your chariot to Missouri, sir.
You could deliver this child to her kin folk.
Well, I wouldn't exactly
call it a chariot, Reverend.
- I'll write the women a letter tonight.
- Hold it, hold it.
I have to think upon this,
you know, uh...
I mean, I may have to make
a few stops along the way.
I never travelled with no child before.
- But you're going that way.
- The child's got no place to go.
Well...
The eyes of the Lord...
Expect I have no choice, do I?
- Hallelujah!
- God works in mysterious ways.
Don't he now?
Come on, Addie.
Better get your things together.
This nice man's going to take
you to your aunt.
- How come you're taking me?
- Huh?
How come you're taking me?
Because I'm going that way, honey.
Although, I do want to make just one stop
before we leave town.
Got a little business to take care of.
- You know my mama real good?
- Oh, pretty good.
You just stay out here
till I come for you.
Don't you say a word
unless I ask you to.
Mr Robertson?
- That's right.
- I'd like a minute of your time.
- Not buying today.
- Oh, not selling.
Just want you to meet somebody,
Mr Robertson. Only take a second.
So what?
- Tell him your name, honey.
- Addie.
- Addie what, honey?
- Addie Loggins.
You done real fine.
I'll be out in a minute.
Ain't she a sweet child?
No, she ain't a sweet child.
Well, maybe she don't seem sweet right now.
That's because she's sad.
That is with her mama being dead,
what with your brother getting drunk
and driving into that tree like that.
What are you trying to pull?
Get out of here!
All right, I'm going, but let me tell you
where I'm going to go.
I don't care where you're going to go.
I'm going to go see Mr J.T. Faraday.
Now, you know who Mr J.T. Faraday is?
He's one of the biggest lawyers
in Kansas.
And he don't favour the man with the money,
he favours the man without it.
And you know what's gonna happen
to your brother?
There's gonna be a lawsuit against him.
You know what happens then?
Everything's gonna be just tied up
in knots, just sitting there.
That's his banking money,
his house, everything he owns.
Including half this plant.
Now, don't think that poor child
ain't entitled, 'cause she is.
I was thinking...
couple a thousand dollars
would be acceptable.
Couple of thou? I'll give you 200.
$200?
$200.
It's a deal.
There you are.
That'll be, uh, $67.54.
You sure these tyres are new?
$67.54.
Now, we'll have you
to St. Jo in no time.
What time's the next train
to St. Joseph?
St. Joseph? Let's see here.
That'll be the 4:14.
Change trains in Kansas City,
and that'll put you into St. Jo at 9:52am.
I want one child's price ticket.
That will be $11.45.
I want you to send this here telegram
to Mrs Billie Roy Griggs,
Cosmo Road, St. Joseph.
Train arriving 9:52am,
and bringing love,
affection and $20 cash.
Oh, make that $25 cash.
And sign it just Addie Loggins.
Ten words, that will be 85 cents more.
That will be 12 and 30.
12 and 30, huh?
Uh, you better say
in that message there,
love, affection and $20 cash.
Love, affection and $20 cash.
Now, here's your ticket,
and here's $20 for your Aunt Billie.
Well, we got till 4:15.
I don't suppose you can wait
here by yourself, can you?
You hungry?
You want a Nehi and a Coney Island?
- Ain't you gonna eat it?
- I ain't hungry.
D'you worry about going on the train?
You'll like the train. Don't worry about it.
Before you know it, you'll be asleep in your
aunt's house, all your troubles will be over.
- So eat your Coney Island.
- She don't even know me.
- She's going to know you now.
- She ain't gonna want me.
What are you making trouble for?
She ain't even seen you, yet.
- She never even cared for my mama.
- Nobody didn't care for your mama.
- And she was her sister.
- Your mama was a fine woman.
Everybody said she weren't.
Well everybody don't know
your mama, do they?
How good you know my mama?
Good enough to know you can be real proud
of the happiness she give to people.
Now, eat your Coney Island.
You meet my mama in a bar room?
Where would you get
a question like that?
I hear Miss Ollie talking, the neighbour
lady. Says one of you's my pa.
Well, don't the world
have a wild imagination?
Eat your Coney Island.
You my pa?
Of course I ain't your pa.
I'll get you some relish.
A Coney Island ain't no good
without relish.
Look, I know how you feel.
I lost my ma, too. I even lost my pa.
I don't even know where my sister is.
I wish I could tell you I'm your pa,
but it just ain't like that.
You met her in a bar room.
Just because a man meets a woman
in a bar room don't mean he's your pa.
Eat your Coney Island.
Well, then, if you ain't my pa,
I want my $200.
What's that?
I heard you through the door
talking to that man.
It's my money you got, and I want it.
Now, you... you just hold on a second.
I want my money. You took my $200!
- Will you quiet down, you hear?
- I want my $200!
Hold on, now, just hold on.
Let me explain something to you.
It ain't as if you was my pa.
That'd be different.
Well, I ain't your pa,
so just get that out of your head.
I don't care
what those neighbour ladies said.
- I look like that.
- You don't look nothing like me.
You don't look any more like me
than you do that Coney Island.
Eat that damn thing, you hear?
- We got the same jaw.
- Lots of people got the same jaw.
- It's possible.
- No, no, it ain't possible.
- Then I want my $200!
- All right!
All right, maybe we got the same jaw,
but same jaw don't mean same blood.
I know a woman looks like a bullfrog,
but that don't mean she's its mother.
- You met my mum in a bar room.
- For God's sakes, child!
You think everybody gets met
in a bar room gets a baby?
It's possible.
Anything is possible,
but possible don't make it true.
Then I want my money!
Will you quiet down?
You know what the trouble is with you?
You got no appreciation.
All right.
Maybe I did get a little money from that man,
and you're entitled to that,
but I'm entitled to my share
for getting it for you, ain't I?
And where do you think
you'd be without me?
You think them folks would spend a penny
to send you east? No, sir.
But who got you a ticket to St. Jo?
Who got you a Nehi and a Coney Island?
And threw in $20 extra,
not to mention 85 cents
for that telegram.
You wouldn't have had
any of that without me.
Now, I didn't have to take you,
but I took you, didn't I?
All right, I think that's fair enough.
We're both a little better off.
You get to St. Jo,
I get myself a little better car.
Fair is fair.
Now, drink your Nehi,
and eat your Coney Island.
I want my $200.
I don't have your $200 no more,
and you know it.
If you don't give me my $200,
I'm going to tell a policeman how you got it,
and he'll make you give it to me,
'cause it's mine.
But I don't have it.
Then get it.
How we doing, Angel Pie?
We going to have a little dessert
when we finish up our hot dog?
I don't know.
What do you say, Daddy?
Why don't we get Precious
a little dessert if she eats her dog?
Her name ain't Precious.
I want my money back on this here ticket,
and I want you to send this here telegram.
Trip delayed, but I'm coming real soon!
You just lie down in the seat
and be quiet.
Folks don't take to children
when they're doing business.
- Yes?
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
- Is Mr Rudolf Morgan at home, please?
- Mr Morgan?
Yes, ma'am. My name is Pray, Moses Pray,
Kansas Bible Company. He'll know.
Oh, I'm sorry. Mr Morgan has passed on.
Oh, ma'am, I'm... I just...
I don't know what to say.
Uh, what was it you
were seeing him about?
- Well, he ordered this here bible from...
- Bible?
Rudolph ordered a bible?
Yeah, he ordered this here deluxe edition
with the lady's name in the corner.
Lady's name?
Oh, I expect some special gift
for a family friend.
But under the circumstances,
I'll just give you back
Mr Morgan's dollar deposit,
and there won't be
no further obligation.
Ma'am, I just don't know how to put
into words the sense of sorrow that I feel.
What, what...
what name is in the corner?
I don't really know what name
Mr Morgan had put in the corner, ma'am.
Let's see, now.
It's here somewhere. I've got it. Uh...
Here it is.
- Pearl...
- Pearl.
I'm Pearl.
Well, he must have got
this here good book for you, ma'am.
Yes. Yes, he bought it for me.
Of course, now,
you're not obliged to take it.
Of course I'll take it.
There's just one thing. You see, I...
I told him that I could sell him
a cheaper bible,
but no, naturally he wanted the best,
the best, of course, being the deluxe edition
with the lady's name printed
in child-in-the-manger gold letters.
Oh, he would.
Bringing a balance due of, uh...
$8.00? $8.00.
$8.00?
Well, that's, uh, $8.00
minus the dollar deposit,
making it $7.00.
Um, I'll go get my purse.
- Well, you're not obliged to take it, now.
- Of course I'm obliged!
He ordered the deluxe!
'But cold or no cold, it's good
to be back in old Manhattan.
'Well, tell me, Jack, you've been
in town now since Thursday.
- 'What have you been doing with yourself?'
- 'Oh, I've had a lot of fun, Don.
'I saw some shows,
went to a couple of nightclubs,
'and last night, I was invited over
to Fred Allen's apartment for dinner.'
- 'Oh, Fred Allen, eh?'
- 'Yeah, he and I are pretty good friends now.'
'Well, I'm glad to hear it.
Has Fred got a nice apartment?'
'Oh, how could I tell, Don,
'with all that laundry
hanging in the living room?'
Ain't you gonna go to sleep?
Don't you want to hear Jack Benny?
No.
'I don't want to sound catty...'
You're too young to smoke.
You're going to set this whole place on fire.
I now owe you $103.72.
Seventy-four.
I always knew
Someday I'd accompany you
Along Flirtation Walk
A dream foretold
A story that you would unfold
That lives forever and never grows old
I always felt
That your little heart would melt
Along Flirtation Walk...
Frank D. Roosevelt said
we're all feeling a lot better.
He did, did he?
Made me feel good when he said that.
Better than I've felt in a long time.
Bet old Frank sure does wish he was 21.
You don't like me, do you?
No, I don't like you.
Yes?
Afternoon, ma'am. I was wondering
if Mr Bates might be at home.
Mr Bates is dead.
He died over a week ago.
Oh, you mean he passed over, ma'am?
Why, I was just talking to him
not less than a month ago.
- What was it you wanted?
- Well...
My name is Pray, Kansas Bible Company.
I'm just here to deliver this bible
that Mr Bates ordered.
Bible?
Who is it? What's the trouble?
Something about Benjamin buying a bible.
Bible? What kind of bible?
He said he talked to Benjamin,
less than a month ago.
Well, I'm... I'm not exactly sure
of the dates, ma'am.
Well, I don't see how.
Benjamin didn't go nowheres near that shop
for more than a month before he died.
Well, I may be a little
mixed up on the dates.
What company you say you're from?
The Kansas Bible Company,
out of Wichita.
Kansas Bible Company?
I ain't never heard of
no Kansas Bible Company.
Daddy...
Can't we go now? I want to get to church
and pray for Mama.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Sure we can, honey.
Daddy was just fixin' to leave.
This here is my little girl.
It's just the two of us now.
- My Mama's gone to the Lord.
- Oh, so has poor Mr Bates, honey.
I'll just, uh, give you back
his dollar deposit,
and you let us know if
there's anything we can do.
Hold on, there. Wait one damn minute.
He actually done ordered a bible, huh?
Uh, he sure did. Here it is, right here
in gold for somebody named "Marie".
- That's her. She's Marie.
- Oh, she sure did mean a lot to him.
He especially had me get
the deluxe edition.
- How much to keep this here book?
- Oh, well, that one is the...
It's the $12 one, Daddy.
- $12?
Uh, yeah, well, honey, we have
to have a little goodness in our hearts,
- I mean, considering the circumstances.
- Never mind the circumstances.
And if it'll make that woman happy,
I'll take it.
You owe me $85.74.
'I mean, we're going
to Washington on the QT.
'Molly, she says we can't go on the QT,
we've got to take the Pennsylvania.
'Hey, I'd better get going.
'Hey, Molly, where's my suitcase?
Do you know?'
'Uh, I'm sure I don't know, McGee.
You had it last night.'
'Oh, I know where it is.
It's right here in the hall...'
He's going to open the closet!
Now he's going to say how he's got to
straighten the closet out!
'Got to straighten out that
closet one of these days.'
How'd you like to do
a little business with me?
You mean instead of paying me back?
Now, don't get nervous. I'll pay you back.
I'm just saying, while we're heading east,
how'd you like to do a little business
together, that's all?
Well, you're looking at me
like I'm out to cheat you or something.
I am offering you a business proposition.
Take it or leave it.
And turn off that radio! You're like
to drive us all deaf with that radio.
'...in an average way, of course.'
OK, I want you to remember one thing:
I decide on the price.
Maybe you don't know French, but there's
something in this world called "fine-esse".
$12! I never sold no bible for $12.
That man was a law officer.
You could've had me put me in jail.
We got it, didn't we?
I don't care if we got it.
Don't you go making the decisions.
I make the decisions. All you got
to do is look like a pretty little girl.
You ain't got something like a ribbon
in that cigar box, do you?
I got my mum's kimono in my suitcase,
Chinamen with umbrellas.
That ain't quite what I had in mind.
You look real nice in that ribbon.
First off, I didn't know
was she a boy or a girl?
I'm a girl.
Well, it makes all the difference.
Ain't she got a sweet
little face, somehow.
Well, seeing how I just got paid today,
we'll take a ribbon in each colour.
How much that going to set me back?
Well, that'll be 15 cents.
Bought my grandchildren
ribbons just like this last holiday time.
Grandchildren? I don't believe it.
- You break a five?
- Well, you can believe it, all right.
I'm just as old as I look.
Well, now, here you be.
That's one, two, three, four, five.
This old wallet of mine
is about to bust its sides.
I'll give you five ones back,
you give me that $5 bill.
How many grandchildren
you got altogether?
Well, I got two little granddaughters,
a nine-year-old, a ten-year-old,
two grandsons near 16,
and I got a grandson 35 years old.
Come on, you're pulling my leg.
Why don't you just give me a $10 bill?
Here's the $5, and five ones, there.
That way I won't be so quick
to see it break apart.
- Six children, huh? My, my, my...
- I've got a daughter, 51.
Oh, now, I don't mean
to be handing you no line,
but that's just pretty hard to believe
you got a 51-year-old child.
You can believe it, all right.
Well, I'm afraid I'd have to see it
to believe it. Much obliged.
- See you again.
- Y'all come back!
That just don't seem quite right...
somehow.
- Yes?
- I'm looking for Mr Stanley, ma'am.
Mr Stanley's dead.
Oh, well, I'm looking for
Mr Warren M. Stanley, ma'am.
Warren's passed on, sir.
Oh, that's hard to believe.
I was just talking to Warren
not more than two weeks back.
He ordered this here bible from me.
Warren spent money on a bible?
Yes, ma'am, with the name Elvira
in the corner.
Why would Warren spend money on a bible?
He took fast to the idea, ma'am.
Only thing is, he left a balance due of,
well, let's see,
not counting the dollar deposit...
Daddy, this one's already paid for.
Mr Stanley paid for the whole thing,
don't you remember?
Afternoon, ma'am. Mr Huff at home?
Mr Huff passed away,
young man, a week ago.
Oh, gee, I'm sorry. I was just talking to
Mr Huff not more than a month ago.
What was it you wanted?
Oh, well, my name is Pray,
Kansas Bible Company.
Mr Huff ordered this bible
as a gift for someone named Edna.
Oh, that's my name.
You don't have to take it
if you don't want to.
I'll just give you back
Amos's dollar deposit and then...
Of course I want to keep it.
He bought me a bible.
Yes, ma'am. Now, I told Amos
I could sell him a cheaper one,
but no, naturally, he wanted the best,
the best, of course,
being the deluxe edition
with the name printed
in child-in-the-manger gold letters,
- bringing up a balance due of...
- ...of $24!
$24. I'll get my purse.
What's your name, honey?
- Addie.
- Addie. What a sweet little name.
Addie Pray, ma'am.
Well, Addie Pray,
I'm going to give you $24,
and an extra $5
for just coming to my door.
- Praise the Lord.
Keep your sunny side up, up
Hide the side that gets blue...
- Moze, let's give him some money.
- No.
Just a little bit. We got $305.16.
Whole 'nother business giving it away.
- It's bad enough you give away bibles.
- But they're poorly.
The whole country's poorly,
I told you before.
But Frank D. Roosevelt says
we got to look out for one another.
I don't care about Frank D. Roosevelt.
- But he says it.
- That so?
Why don't you ask Frank D. Roosevelt
what he thinks about taking care of himself?
You think he don't eat off silver trays?
He could eat off table tops like the rest
of us, but he don't. You know why?
Because that would make him look common.
And besides, Frank D. Roosevelt
ain't running this thing - I'm running it!
So don't you make up no rules
about what we're going to give away.
It's my money too, you know.
$200 belong to me,
- and don't you forget that.
- You want it?
Well, just put my share in my pocket,
and I'll take you to a train station.
How do you like that?
Get the map.
Find out where the nearest depot is.
Nothing but trouble, anyway.
First you charge too much,
then you want to give it away.
- Where are we now?
- We just left Plainville.
$12 for a bible, then it's up to $24.
If I stay with you,
I'll spend the rest of my life in jail.
There's a depot in Lincoln.
You can take me to Lincoln.
You bet I will!
- Where's Lincoln?
- Clear over there.
Oh, boy, you think
I'm going to take you clear over there
just to get you to some depot?
Then keep going east.
We'll hit one in Sylvan Grove.
- Where's Sylvan Grove?
- Right here.
Well, that'll take us
down through Lucas.
We got to go through something
to get to Sylvan Grove.
I'm not complaining. I'm just saying
that'll take you through Lucas.
You got to go through Paradox and Waldo
and Lorraine and Lucas
if you want to get to Sylvan Grove.
Those are pretty good towns in there.
We could do some business in there.
Well, it won't matter much.
We're near out of bibles anyway.
What do you mean, we're out of bibles?
Why didn't you tell me we're out of bibles?
You look in the box too, don't you?
- Well, you've got an excuse for everything.
- 'Cause you blame me for everything.
If we were running out of bibles,
you should have told me.
- We're running out of bibles!
- Well, then we got to get new ones!
- Then let's get new ones!
- We can pick some up in Great Bend.
- Great Bend's the other way.
- Well, we gotta have bibles, don't we?
Let's see, now, we can veer down to Lucas,
and we'll veer over to Wilson.
Veer off to Lorraine and Bushton.
And we could veer off to Hoisington.
We'll just have to keep on veering,
that's all.
- I'm getting hungry. You getting hungry?
- Uh-huh.
Just one more chance
To prove it's you alone I care for
Each night I say a little prayer for...
You sweet thing.
Don't you tell me that. Ooh!
Sometimes I just don't know,
with all the old doodly-doo.
Doodly-doo, doodly-doo.
OK, now, you go on back, now.
I'll see you another time.
- Don't send me back.
- Oh, you got to go on back.
- I'll see you another time, I promise.
- I want to go in your place.
No, no.
You trying to keep secrets from me?
You got diamonds and rubies in there?
Go on, go on.
Oh, Fido... Night-night, old Fido.
- Woof-woof.
Woof-woof.
Still I'm holding on awhile
You'll give me just one more word
There it is.
- Much obliged.
- Thank you, sir.
All right, boy, you're next.
I ain't a boy.
- Aw, don't let it bother you.
- It ain't funny.
No reason to get that sore.
- He called me a boy, didn't he?
- He just got mixed up, that's all.
He did not.
He looked me straight in the eye.
Yeah, well, I'm looking you straight
in the eye, and I think you're beautiful.
- Oh, you're just saying that.
- Would I make that up?
You're as beautiful as your mama, and she
put all the flowers in the world to shame.
You know, they wouldn't even let her come
to Holland for fear she'd droop the tulips,
and you got all the good looks
she ever had.
Then how come that man called me a boy?
I don't know, maybe it's...
Maybe it's 'cause of what you got on,
or something.
What's wrong with what I got on?
Oh, nothing wrong with it, just...
don't exactly make you look feminine.
Maybe it wouldn't be a bad idea
we get you fixed up a little bit,
get you a new dress,
a fancy new hat, or something.
Come to think of it,
it wouldn't exactly hurt business, either.
You really think I'm
as pretty as my mama?
Of course I do.
- How much money we got in the box?
- $405.16.
Give me a $20.
- What for?
- Give me a $20!
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
We're going to get us
some fancy new outfits
with this money you got
from your Aunt Helen.
- I don't have no Aunt Helen.
- Oh, sure you do, honey.
Come on, let me explain it to you.
Yes, sir?
I'd like an Ipana toothpaste
and a pack of Sen-Sen.
- Uh, twenty and five.
- Twenty-five.
- Yes, sir.
- Here you go.
75 makes one,
four makes five, and 15 makes 20.
Thank you very much. I don't need a bag.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you. Bye now.
Hello. How much is this?
That'll be 35 cents.
65 cents makes a dollar.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Yes?
May I have a bottle
of purple toilet water, please?
That'll be 25 cents.
There you go.
Lady, you made a mistake.
Huh? I give you $4.75.
But I gave you a $20 bill.
Uh-uh. You give me a $5.
No, ma'am, it was a $20 bill.
You give me a $5, and I give you $4.75.
It was a $20 bill.
Got no $20s in with no $5s.
What's all the turmoil?
What's going on here?
This little girl give me a $5 bill,
and I give her change.
I gave her a $20 bill - I know I did.
It was a birthday present
from my Aunt Helen in Wichita,
and she wrote "Happy Birthday, Addie"
on the end of it.
You just go look and see.
That's it right there!
That's my $20 bill I got
from my Aunt Helen in Wichita.
- Give the child her $20 bill.
- I'm giving it.
- Give the child her $20 bill, Miss Brownwell.
- Yes, sir.
- And give her a piece of candy.
- And pay attention to things, Miss Brownwell.
- Yes, sir.
Come on in, get your cotton candy.
Sweetheart, Cotton Candy.
- Five cents.
- Do you have change for this five?
There you are, little girl.
Cotton candy, get your cotton candy.
Mister, this purse is sure full.
If you give me the five back,
I'll give you five ones.
Cotton candy,
get your cotton candy right here.
Mister, if you got a ten dollar bill
I'll give you the five back
with the five ones you have.
Would you give me a ten dollar bill?
There, now don't bother me anymore,
you understand?
Cotton candy!
Step up and get your cotton candy.
Come and get it.
Get your tickets.
Only one fourth of a dollar.
The show goes on in five minutes.
Six unusual little ladies
unveiling the secrets of passion.
Found only a few years back
in the actual Egyptian
tomb of Queen Nefereti.
And featuring the luscious
Miss Trixie Delight.
- I had my photo took, Moze.
- You did, huh? Ain't that fine.
Moze, can you come have
your photo took with me?
- Can't right now, sweetheart.
- Only take a minute.
- Not now, you hear me?
- But it's almost down here tonight.
- It wouldn't be here after...
- I can't help that.
- Now excuse me, you understand?
- How many times you going to see it?
As many times as I like,
that's how many times.
- You seen it half a dozen times.
- And I might see it a half dozen more.
Now why don't you go play bingo
or something?
I don't want to play bingo.
Well, then why don't you go write
another love note to St. Roosevelt?
Maybe I will.
And stop standing around here
checking on me. You don't have to worry.
I ain't about to leave some poor little child
stranded in the middle of nowhere.
I got scruples, too, you know.
You know what that is, "scruples"?
No, I don't know what it is,
but if you got them, I sure bet
they belong to somebody else.
And his name ain't Frank, it's Franklin.
Hey there, my little turtle-dee.
I wondered where you got to.
Where's your pa?
- Is my picture ready?
- Sure, it's...
Excuse me, folks, come right back.
Sit back in the moon there,
I'll be right with you.
Let's see.
Here it is, here.
Hey, now, I thought you were
gonna sit in the moon with your pa.
He ain't my pa.
Hi, folks. Get ready.
Smile. Hold it.
Hold it.
Beautiful.
I don't want you smoking
in the car tomorrow.
- What?
- I didn't say nothing. I'm just listening to you.
Well, there are going to be
a couple extra people riding with us,
and this particular person
don't like cigarette smoke.
- What extra person?
- What?
I said "what extra person"?
A lady and her maid.
I'm giving them a ride to Topeka.
I didn't know we was going to Topeka.
Well, that's because
you don't know everything.
What's the lady's name?
Miss Delight. Miss Trixie Delight.
She's a real lady.
She comes from a good family.
I'm just giving her a ride, that's all.
Well, that's what you're always talking
about, ain't it? Helping other people out.
Now don't you drop nothing, Imogene.
You take care of those breakables,
understand?
Yes, Miss Trixie.
Morning. Car is right over here.
You better ride in the backseat a while.
And then I danced in Tuscaloosa.
And the mayor was there,
and he just said the nicest things about me.
The newspaper ran
a whole big photo on me.
I got a scrap book telling stories on me
from towns all over.
Tell him 'bout the time that man
tried to crack your head open
with the bottle, Miss Trixie.
Why, Imogene, you silly old thing.
You know that's not true.
That old country boy wasn't going to hit me
over the head with no bottle.
He was just horsing around.
Ask me real nice, maybe I'll tell you
about that sometime.
Well, tell him about the time you almost got
thrown in jail, Miss Trixie.
I just don't understand it, Daddy,
but this little baby has to go
winky-tinky all the time.
Well, don't you worry none.
We'll just plan on stopping here for dinner.
But we just stopped for her
to winky-tink at lunch.
That's right, and now
we're stopping for dinner.
- Come on.
- I ain't hungry.
- Want one?
- OK.
- How old are you?
- I don't know, 15. Why?
Just asking, that's all.
- Where are you from?
- Nowhere.
Well, you got to be from somewhere.
Down by Troy, I guess.
How long have you worked for her?
Ain't kept count.
A year, maybe. How old you be?
Nine.
She really do all that dancing?
Well, if you want to call it "dancing".
All she do is wag her hips
and shake her old behind a little.
How come she'd leave
that job back there?
'Cause the boss man tried to make her
put out for his friends.
And she don't believe
in putting out for free.
She put out much?
Just like a gum machine.
You drop something in
and she'll put something out.
How much she charge?
Most she can get.
But she always asks for $5.00.
She ain't putting out
for your pa, though.
Says she's going to wait and get all she can
before she put out for him.
He tell her he was my pa?
Well, not exactly.
I heard him mumbling something
like he didn't want to talk about it.
- Ain't he?
- I'm with him, ain't I?
And how do you come to be with her?
'Cause she promised to give me
$4.00 every week.
She ain't gave me nothing.
'Cept a nickel or dime, sometimes.
- Why don't you quit?
- Quit?
How am I going to quit?
And what if I do quit?
Ain't got no money to get home to Mum.
And what if I do get home?
They got hard times as it is.
My mama say,
"You go work for a white lady,
"she'll take good care of you."
- You want to know what I think?
- Yeah.
You know the little white speck
on top of chicken doo-doo?
Yeah.
Well, that's the kind of white
I think Miss Trixie is.
She's just like that little white speck
on top of old chicken shit.
Oh, I just love it, love it, love it.
All this white.
It is absolutely the proper thing
for my particular kind of appearance.
You know, it wouldn't be bad
for you to have a new dress, too.
The right kind of dress makes
all the difference in the face.
Especially since you got
the right kind of bone structure.
Oh...
Oh, my, oh, my.
Daddy, but wouldn't you look handsome sitting
behind the wheel of a thing like that?
'Course, you know, everything
is in the bone structure.
You know, a person can tell his whole life
on what his bone structure is.
I tried pushing her out
a window once in Little Rock.
Oh...
Oh, I think there's bugs all over the...
I just hope there's
no snakes around here.
You know, I think we ought to go now.
Thank you so much.
Now hurry... oh.
Come on, hurry up.
Get those things in there, now.
Don't break anything, either.
Let's go.
Hurry up, doctor,
this baby's got to go winky-tinky.
Don't worry.
Hey!
Come on, we're ready.
- Come on, now.
- I ain't ready.
Well, you don't look real busy with nothing,
so you just come on down.
I ain't coming.
- Now you listen here, child.
- No, I won't listen here.
What the heck's up with you, then?
I want to sit in front.
And how come we ain't working no more?
'Cause we're on vacation, that's why.
And Miss Delight and me are sitting in front
because we are two grown-ups,
and that's where grown-ups
do the sitting.
And little children
do not tell grown-ups
what to do with their lives,
you understand that?
Well, she ain't my grown-up, and I ain't
planning no more to sit in the back.
Not for no cow.
Will you keep your voice down?
And Miss Delight ain't no cow.
She's a proper woman.
She has a high school diploma,
and right now she's gotta go to the bathroom,
so you just get on down to the car.
She always has to go to the bathroom.
She must have a bladder
the size of a peanut.
Well, I ain't getting back in that car.
Not till she gets out of it.
Hey, what's up, kiddo?
Daddy says you're wearing a sad face.
Ain't good to have a sad face.
Hey, how would you like a colouring book?
Would you like that?
You like Mickey the Mouse?
Oh, son of a bitch!
Ooh... oh.
Now come on down to the car
and let's all be friends.
You see me smile? Come on,
let's see you smile like Aunt Trixie.
Now, come on!
Come on down to the car
with mademoiselle.
Kiddo, I understand how you feel.
Well, you don't have to worry.
One of these days, you're going to be
just as pretty as mademoiselle,
maybe prettier.
You already got bone structure.
When I was your age,
I didn't have no bone structure.
Took me years to get bone structure.
And don't think bone structure's
not important.
Nobody started to call me mademoiselle
till I was 17
and getting a little bone structure.
When I was your age,
I was skinnier than a pole.
I never thought
I'd have nothing up here.
You're going to have them up there, too.
Look, I'll tell you what.
Want me to show you how to use cosmetics?
Look, I'll let you put on my earrings.
You can see how pretty you're going to be.
And I'll show you how to
make up your eyes.
And your lips.
And I'll see to it you get
a little bra or something.
But right now you're gonna
pick your little ass up,
you're gonna drop it in the backseat
and you're gonna cut out the crap,
you understand?
You're going to ruin it, ain't you?
Look, I don't want to wipe you out,
and I don't want you
wiping me out, you know?
So, I'm going to level with you, OK?
Now, you see, with me,
it's just a matter of time.
I don't know why, but somehow
I just don't manage to hold on real long.
So, if you wait it out a little,
it'll be over, you know?
I mean, even if I want a fella,
somehow or other
I manage to get it screwed up.
Maybe I'll get a new pair of shoes,
nice dress, a few laughs.
Times are hard.
Now, if you fool around
on the hill up here,
then you don't get nothing,
I don't get nothing,
he don't get nothing.
So how 'bout it, honey?
Just for a little while,
let old Trixie sit up front
with her big tits.
Hey, come on.
We're coming, baby doll.
And if you don't find me
some old gas station soon,
this little old snowflake's
going to wet her pantaloons.
Oh, my, I almost fell down.
Yoo-hoo! Look what we got!
Ain't she the sweetest little thing,
and don't he look
like a prince on that wheel?
Now, come on, Imogene.
Now, get everything in here.
We got more room than
the whole state of Kansas.
And listen to the horn.
Blow the horn, Daddy.
Oh, go ahead.
Do it again.
Sticks his tongue into the water,
and there's an alligator in the river...
Very funny.
This girl's sitting on the trolley,
and she reaches in her bag,
and she takes out this magazine,
and she starts to read it.
Well, she ain't read more than
a couple of pages.
And real slow and careful now,
she takes her stockings down
and takes off her shoes.
Now, she turns the stockings wrong side out,
and she puts them back on.
She puts her shoes back on.
Well, all the passengers are watching.
They wonder what's going on.
This old guy, he leans over to her,
and he asks her, he says, "What's...?
"I saw you indulge in a strange procedure,
ma'am. What were you doing?"
And she said, "Well, I was reading
this here magazine, you know?
"And I found it to be
such hot stuff that I...
"Well, I felt compelled
to turn the hose on myself."
Oh, turn the hose on!
When you said that, I...
They wouldn't have a room
with a canopy bed, would they?
You wouldn't have a room
with a canopy bed, would you?
Uh, no. But I got one with a fireplace.
Oh, I'd like that one, Daddy.
It ain't no canopy bed,
but it sure do open up
a whole new can of peas, don't it?
Can of peas.
- Ain't that cute?
- Huh? How's that?
Come on, Imogene.
Now, help the boy with these things.
Give them 234, 235, and 236.
They're working
on the elevator right now,
and it's the first flight up,
if you don't mind.
- It's all right. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- "Can of peas". Did you hear that?
- Yeah, what was that all about?
Well, you know,
Canopy... can of pea...
They rhyme, you know?
- Oh, I see! Can of peas, canopy!
- Yeah.
I get it now.
I knew you'd get it
if I explained it to you.
Picture Henry Ford without a car
Picture heaven's firmament
without a star
Picture Grigsby Chrysler
without a fiddle
Picture poor Philadelphia
without a Biddle
Picture Central Park without a sailor
Picture Mr Lord minus his detailer
Mix 'em all together,
and what have you got?
Just a picture of me without you
Now there's a rip in the seam
of that dress, Imogene.
You get it sewed up good, you hear?
- And wash these hose.
- Yes, Miss Trixie.
- Got my bath ready?
Hope the water's not too hot.
You've been making that water
awful hot lately, Imogene.
I knows you like it hot, Miss Trixie.
Well, not that hot.
Now, you go on, finish up all these things
and come back in an hour and dry me off.
Yes, Miss Trixie.
What you doing up there?
I got us an idea. Come on.
- What kind of idea?
- Come on in here, and I'll tell you.
Go on.
Imogene, what do you suppose
Miss Trixie would do
if somebody offered her $25 to put out?
Oh-wee, you crazy.
For that much money,
that woman would drop her pants down
- in the middle of the road.
- That's what I figured.
What you got in mind?
You want to get away
from Miss Trixie, don't you?
Well, if you help me, I'll give you
enough money to get home to your mama.
- How much money?
- $30.
- When do we start?
- Tomorrow morning.
Miss Trixie,
you know that man down at the desk
who checked us in yesterday?
Yeah, I know him. What about him?
Well, he tell me, he'd pay $25
just to have a good time with you.
What?
Well, that little two-bit bum
nerve of that guy.
$25. I bet that little John
don't make that much in a week.
Where would he get 25 bucks?
I don't know.
All I know is what he told me.
25 bucks, huh?
Sure have to see the money
to believe it.
Here you go. You come back
and see us again real soon.
I'll have a Juicy Fruit gum, please.
Here you go, my little beauty.
Want I should chew it for you?
Say, you know that redheaded lady
that comes down here
named Miss Trixie Delight?
Well, she thinks you're real cute.
Oh, yeah? Says you and who else?
No, honest. She says you're better looking
than Dick Powell.
She did, eh?
Well, the lady's got good taste, don't she?
- Well, just thought you'd like to know.
- Hey, just a minute.
Give these here to the lady, and tell her
they're with Floyd's compliments.
Oh. She'll like that.
Maybe you should write her a note.
- Yeah. What kind of a note?
- Oh, I don't know.
I thought men always wrote ladies notes
when they send them presents.
Maybe you should ask her for a date.
That will sure tickle her.
Yeah. Maybe I ought to.
Say, she's not married up
or anything like that, is she?
Of course not. She don't even have
a regular boyfriend.
That man who come in here
yesterday with her is my daddy.
He's her manager. She's a dancer.
A dancer?
You know, I figured
she was something like that.
Whereabouts she dance?
Oh, lots of big places. She's a star.
Well, how about that!
Why don't you print it?
She like men who prints.
Print it, huh?
"Some sweets for the sweet. Ha, ha.
"Some girls say I'm a pretty
smooth dancer myself.
- "How about trying me out sometime?"
- You sure this is going to work?
I don't know, but we're sure
going to give it a try.
Throw this in the drawer, will you?
And keep your fingers crossed.
- Who is it?
- It's me, Addie.
Oh. What do you want?
I got a message from Moze.
He asked me to tell you he had
to run over to Hainesville today.
He won't be back until suppertime.
I think he had to get something
fixed on his car.
- He'll be gone all day.
- Oh.
Well... OK.
OK!
- Howdy.
- What you having?
- Waffles.
I already ate. I had waffles, too.
They sure are good, ain't they?
They ain't bad for waffles.
Mr Moze, Miss Trixie don't feel so good.
She say she's going
to stay in bed today.
She say she'll see you
around suppertime.
She sick? Sick in bed?
I... I better go up there.
Oh, she ain't real sick.
Ain't nothing to worry about.
She's just having her lady's time.
Oh.
Well, you tell her
I'll see her this evening.
Well, just wanted to say good morning.
I think I'll go upstairs
and polish my shoes.
- Somebody at the door, Imogene.
- Yes, Miss Trixie.
It's something for you, Miss Trixie.
- Oh, what is it?
- It was outside the door.
What is that?
Imogene, let all that go now.
You can run along.
I'll call you when I need you.
Yes, Miss Trixie.
Well, hello, cupid.
Miss Trixie wants to see you.
She says it's real important. Room 235.
Oh, she does, does she? When?
- Right now.
- Well, I can't get off right now.
But she says it's real important.
Well, you tell her I'll come up later
tonight... when the moon is full.
But you can't come tonight.
She won't even be here after tonight.
Matter of fact,
she won't even be here after today.
She won't, huh? Well...
You won't be sorry.
I guess I could go up for a few minutes.
What's that room number again?
Room 235. She's waiting for ya.
OK. You tell her
I'm on my way up, sweetheart.
He's coming! He's coming!
- Who is it?
- Sheik of Araby.
Well, then, don't you look pretty?
Well, come on in, honey.
Come on.
...you don't give a girl much time.
Oh, I manage to get around.
Say, you're not one of these fellows
goes around babbling, are you, honey?
What do you mean?
Well, you know,
now most of the time I don't mind,
but it's important to me right now
not to get talked about.
Hey, now do I look like
that kind of fellow?
Say... oh, say you are a wild one,
aren't you?
Hold it, hold it! Now, wait a minute,
you're going to tear it!
Now, now, just let me slip it off.
Hey, there.
Well, now, ain't you a show dog?
Ooh... ooh!
I'm going.
The key... Give me the key!
Mr Moze's going to kill that man. He's
going to kill them both, I just knows it.
- Wait for me here.
- OK.
- Moze!
- What's the trouble?
Better go up to Trixie's room
right away.
Why? What? She sick?
No, she's not sick.
Just do what I tell you.
And take the elevator.
Don't knock. Use the key.
Your daddy going
to kill that man, I reckon.
I expect he cut him up pretty bad.
Moze wouldn't do a thing like that.
Well, down home,
when a man come in from work,
and hear a man inside house
in bed with his wife,
he just walk around to the woodpile
and get his double-blade axe, and go inside,
chop 'em both up to little pieces.
Folks say he cut 'em up
just like kindling wood.
Get your things, Addie. We're leaving.
- Now?
- Right this minute.
I swan, I don't know why that girl
did such a thing to me.
I'd have done almost anything
for that girl.
Just ain't fair.
I reckon she's been...
carrying on a long time.
- From the start.
- You mean, there were other men?
Lots of 'em.
Well, dadblammit,
why didn't you tell me?
I just knew you wouldn't believe me.
- I want you to promise me just one thing.
- What, Moze?
When you grow up,
don't you be the kind of woman
who goes around deceiving men.
- Promise me that.
- I promise, Moze.
Oh, my love, let's take a walk
Just a little ways away
While we walk along, we'll talk
Talk about our wedding day
Only say that you'll be mine
And in our home, we'll happy be
Down beside where the waters flow
Down on the banks...
- Moze?
- Hmm?
Moze, pay attention.
- What's the trouble?
- I seen something peculiar.
- What's that?
- That man in there.
- What man?
- Standing by the door.
What's peculiar about him?
He's got a roll of money
could choke us both to death.
Well, I'm not up to anything right now.
But he's got a black book for making
notes in, and all that money,
and he keeps going outside
and then coming back in again.
- Bootlegger.
- Bootlegger?
No question about it.
You think we might do
some business with him?
Maybe drop a wad or something?
We ain't done nothing in two months,
ever since Trixie.
And we only have $212 left.
Better ways of doing
business with bootleggers.
What ways?
Oh, heaps of ways.
Look, he's going out again!
Follow him.
- Should I, Moze?
- I told you, didn't I?
Follow him. Find out where he goes.
Thinking,
"Lord, what a deed I have done!"
Killed the girl I loved, you see
'Cause she would not marry me
Only say that you'll be mine
And in our home, we'll happy be
Down beside where the waters flow
Down on the banks of the Ohio
Thank you.
Big brown eyes and curly hair...
What'd you find out?
He's got a lot of bottles
he keeps in some kind of bin out back.
- How big's the bin?
- About as big as our car trunk, maybe.
- What you plan to do?
- Find out where he keeps his goods.
Well, there was a little shack
out there, too, but he didn't go in it.
Well, honey... how about a little walk
before Daddy puts you in the bed?
Oh, goody.
Our friend's name is Jess Hardin.
He's a bootlegger, all right.
Wholesales pretty near
everybody in the county.
His brother's some sort of a big shot, too,
but the girl couldn't tell me about him.
Some Romeo walked up, and I had to beat it.
Now, where is it?
- Right over there.
- OK, come on.
OK, now, you watch the hotel.
You see anybody coming, you cough real low.
I'm going inside.
- It may be locked.
- Shucks, honey.
Folks in the country never lock anything.
Don't you know that?
Come sit by my side, little darling
Come lay your cool hand on my brow
Promise me that you will never
- Be nobody's darlin' but mine
- Your name Hardin?
That's right.
Conrad's the name.
Jack said I ought to look you up.
Jack who?
Oh, just Jack's good enough, I reckon.
Don't know no Jack.
Well, maybe you ought to get acquainted.
He's running the biggest
wholesale business in the state.
- You selling?
- That's right.
Ain't interested in no shiney.
I ain't selling no shiney,
I only deal in bonded goods.
- What kind?
- All kinds.
I can let you have a pretty good deal
on some Three Feathers.
How much?
Well, it depends. You take 20 cases,
I'll let 'em go for $25 per.
- That's too much.
- Ain't too much.
You can't get it that cheap
where they sell it legal.
Ain't legal here.
That's all the more reason
you're getting a bargain.
Give you just $20.
Can't do it.
Price is set down in Wichita.
How long before delivery?
Oh... how's early in the morning?
You got it in the county?
That's right.
My mother is dead and in heaven...
Where do I pick it up?
My daddy...
- That'll do it.
- Did you leave some?
Plenty. He'll never miss it.
Moze?
Moze, we better get.
- Here.
- It's all filled up, I told you.
Them's for me.
Get going!
Hurry.
Get up there!
Now hold on.
And make sure nothing spills off.
Well, you'd better go slow.
And hurry.
- Easy!
- Well, I got to turn corners, don't I?
Moze, ain't he going to miss his whisky?
Oh, maybe in about a week,
but by the time he's figured it out,
we'll be in Missouri
and he can't do nothing
once we're in Missouri.
Come on.
Where is it?
Scoot over!
- How much you get?
- $625.
$625, and he bought his own whisky!
That's $625 plus the $212
we already got.
And if we drop some wallets
and do some 20s, we'll...
- What's that?
- Where?
Behind us.
I don't see nothin'.
- There's something back there.
- Nothin' but pitch black.
- I thought I seen something flicker.
- Nothin' there.
- You put the money in the box?
- Uh-huh.
I'll be glad to get out of this town,
I'll tell you that.
There it is again.
Dadblammit!
Somethin' flickered, sure as hell.
Nothin' behind us, Moze.
- Uh-oh.
- I told ya!
- Who could it be?
- Christ!
- Don't stop, keep going!
- I can't keep going.
The damn car's in front of me.
Everything's going to be all right.
You just let me do the talking.
- You playin' games with us, Mister?
- Oh, I... I didn't know who was back there.
It's a risky thing to do.
Might get your tyres shot off.
Where you headin'?
Me and my little girl
are going to Saint Jo.
- Oh. Live there?
- Nearby.
- What's your business?
- Uh...
Livestock, mostly...
mules and horses. Some cattle.
That's funny.
I heard you was a bootlegger.
Oh, no, sir, not me, friend.
Must be some mistake.
Maybe... Maybe not.
The way I hear it...
you just had a transaction
by the old barn.
Where'd you hear a thing like that?
Oh, a... friend of the family.
No, I'm sorry, I...
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I'm talkin' about bootleggin'.
I'm talkin' about $625.
Now, just where might that be?
I don't have no $625.
I... I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't even know where the old barn is.
Well...
I reckon we'll just have to explain
a little more thoroughly, won't we?
Come on, Beau, you take a ride
with these nice people.
- Love to.
- We're all goin' back to town.
Damn.
Just when you think you got it made...
just ain't made, is it?
- You pretty good at this little thing?
- Not too good.
Not too good, huh?
Old bootlegger's sittin' there
with his own little game,
and he ain't even good at his own game.
Yes, sir, that is some good joke.
I found these on the front seat.
Wasn't any money in the car.
Went all through it, inside and out.
Livestock business, huh?
That whisky's for a friend.
Hold out your hands.
- Huh?
- I said, hold out your hands. You heard me.
I didn't say put 'em down, did I?
Mighty clean hands for livestock.
Them hands don't look like
they do nothin' much
except play a little casino
every now and then.
I told you, that whisky's for a friend.
I didn't see no harm...
Didn't see no harm?
Hear that, Beau? Big bootlegger claims
he don't know the law.
Well, Mr Bootlegger, I don't need no
couple of bottles to make a case against you.
Law says all I need
is just one little ol' drop.
And... law says you use a vehicle
to transport alcoholic beverages,
and said vehicle is confiscated
to be sold at public auctions, so...
you can just kiss that pretty
little ol' car of yours goodbye.
Hey, hold on! That seems
pretty rough just because...
Don't lower your hands.
I didn't tell you to lower your hands.
I tell you to lower your hands,
then you lower your hands.
You don't do nothin' till I tell you to.
Understand?
Answer me. You understand?
Yes, sir.
Ah, I already done that.
Ain't nothin' in his clothes 'cept him.
He ain't worth five cents.
No, she ain't got
nothin' on her, either.
You don't know what kind
of real bad trouble you're in.
You better start thinking on it.
I've got a case against you
for possession and transportin' whisky,
and I reckon if I try,
I can think of a few other things.
Better face it, you're going to be
up in these parts for quite a while,
working on the county roads.
Maybe you're lucky,
you get out in six months.
Six more months, influencing a child -
maybe get six years for that.
Maybe we could work something out.
What's there to work out?
'...while I rustle one up,
'you all listen to this little goodie
'from a couple of years ago...'
Ah, I sure don't like to send a man
to a road gang. Never have.
Always felt sorry for them poor devils.
But I can't overlook the fact
that you've been paid $625,
and you ain't tellin' me where it is.
Now, I know you're a bootlegger,
so what's there for me to work out?
All right. Let's cut this
ring-around-the-rosy.
Where's that... money?
You think I'm foolin' around?
I ain't foolin' around.
Maybe you'll come around in time.
Get a little thirsty
and get a little hungry.
Time sure does have a way
with criminals, don't it, Beau?
Sure do.
Well, it's gettin' on to 5:00.
Somebody ought to be
stirring over at the café.
I think I'll step over there a while.
See if that friend
of the family's there.
I'll be on back 'fore long.
I got all day, you know?
I got all the time in the world.
Trouble's just a bubble
And the clouds will soon roll by
So let's have another cup of coffee
And let's have another piece of pie
Let a smile be your umbrella
For it's just an April shower
Even John D. Rockefeller...
Sir, may I get my things, please?
Mr Herbert Hoover...
OK.
So let's have another cup of coffee
And let's have another piece of pie
Daddy...
I need to go to the shithouse.
Well, uh, there's a place down the hall.
Daddy, I'm scared.
I want you to come stand by the door.
All right if I go with her?
Down there.
- Run!
- You crazy?
Hey!
Where are we running? Oh, my God.
Stop them people!
Hey, there's bootleggers!
Jesus Christ, this is the craziest...
- Hurry!
- I'm hurrying!
- Stop!
- Oh, Jesus!
- I'm going to hit him!
- Make him jump! Don't slow down!
I could have killed him!
They're going to have me up for murder!
- They're shooting at us!
- But they're missin'! Keep going!
- We ain't gonna make it.
- Yes, we will.
Not in this car, we ain't. Every lawman in
Kansas is going to be looking for this car.
We got to get across the river
to Missouri.
Where's the bridge?
- Oh, Jesus!
- What's the matter?
- Damn bridge is the other way!
- What?
Hang on.
Ah, this ain't no good.
We're gonna make it too easy for 'em.
We got to get off this road. Hang on!
Holy smoke!
Blow your horn!
Won't do no good.
He can't pull off the road.
Ain't we got all the luck,
selling whisky to a sheriff's brother?
Hang onto your hat.
- What?
- Hold on, I said.
Oh, God!
- You all right?
- Uh-huh.
OK, we threw a hobble on 'em for a while,
but we got to get off this road,
or we're going to end up
in a town for sure.
And take that money out of there.
You like to give me heart failure.
We made it, didn't we?
Anybody 't home?
Howdy.
Need to get rid of my car here.
I need to get rid of my car!
Sheriff wants to take away my little girl,
put her in an orphanage.
You know anybody who might want to swap?
How about that truck over there?
Well, we'll just let him
chew on it a while.
Well, the rear tyres look new, anyway.
- The radio looks OK.
- Think this thing runs?
It better. We got to have
some way of travelling.
- Where we going to go?
- Out of Kansas, across the river to Saint Jo.
That's where.
Here he comes.
Look at 'em all.
All I'm looking for is a swap
and three days' head start
before you take it out on the highway.
It's all legal.
Got the papers right here to prove it.
Just have to fill out that form
on the back, and you own it.
Ain't gonna swap.
Well, it's brand-new.
That car ain't no good.
What's the matter with it?
Can't haul nothing in it.
Oh, well, if that's all
that's bothering you,
you can sell the car and get two trucks
to do your hauling in.
I ain't gonna swap.
Wrassle you for it.
- Are you crazy?
- If I win, we swap.
You win, you can keep the car
and the truck both.
- Moze...
- Quiet down.
- What kind of wrassling?
- You name it.
- Catch as can?
- Shoes or barefoot?
Makes no never mind to me.
Barefoot.
You're gonna get killed
just to give something away.
I ain't got no choice.
Get that city boy.
Get the city boy.
Let's go.
Make him say "calf rope", Leroy.
Come on, Leroy. Get him, Leroy.
Get him!
That ain't fair! You stop that!
You make him fight fair!
Look out for that rake, Leroy.
Watch out, Leroy.
- Let's go in the car. Come on!
- Yee-haw!
Woo-hoo! Yoo-hoo! Woo-hoo!
- Are you pushing?
- Of course I'm pushing!
OK, it'll go now.
Put your foot on the brake.
- The brake! The brake!
- It don't work!
The brake, goddamn it! The brake!
Don't you even know
where the damn brake is?
It don't work.
Oh...
Well, it figures.
Well, we're in Missouri anyway.
What'll we do now, drop some 20s?
- How much money we got?
- $837 and some change.
42 cents, I think.
Well, we're just outside of St. Jo,
ain't we?
- So what?
- So...
It's a big town, ain't it?
We can do better than 20s.
'Y'all know that one.
"'Let's have another cup of coffee,
let's have another piece of pie."
'Well, it's 10:30,
and it's Sunday morning in St. Jo,
'and y'all get to church now, OK?
'Here's the news:
'In Omaha, President Roosevelt
told the nation last night...'
- Moze?
- Yeah?
- What if that old man don't believe ya?
- He'll believe me, all right.
He's in the market for making a killing,
just like we are.
Maybe he don't even have a silver mine.
I had him checked out real thorough.
Where's the money?
And he's just what people say he is -
rich and greedy.
'The independent candidate
for Senate this year...'
- Pull up your socks.
- Moze...
If we get a silver mine, we could get a house
and everything, couldn't we?
Everything, just... everything.
Just around the corner,
there's a rainbow in the sky
So let's have another cup of coffee
OK, you got it straight?
Corner of East Warring and Burlington,
11 o'clock.
Just show there with tears in your eyes.
That's all.
Moze, don't forget the money.
Of course I won't forget the money.
I'll see you in 30 minutes.
Moze, could we get a piano, too?
A piano? We'll have a whole factory.
Just around the corner
There's a rainbow in the sky
I guess you just didn't make
a good enough swap.
My brother's real sore at ya.
Seems you sold him
some of his own whisky.
You can't arrest me now.
We're in Missouri.
And your damn brother's a bootlegger!
You got an awful big mouth, Mister.
Maybe I can't arrest you in Missouri,
and maybe I don't want to.
But I sure can make sure that you ain't gonna
feel real good while you're here.
Let's go!
Addie...
Moze.
Moze...
I sw...
I swallowed my gold tooth.
- Aw, Moze.
- They took it all.
- Oh, Moze, you're all beat up.
- Ain't nothing left.
Don't worry none. I've been keeping
ten dollars for emergencies.
What the hell we do with ten dollars?
We could buy some bibles,
do a little widow business.
Must be lots of good towns around here.
Do some 20s, drop some wallets...
before you know it,
we'll be real good again.
I'll bet in no time we could have
a whole new car and everything.
You're going to take me
to Aunt Billie's now, ain't ya?
- Aw, Moze...
- Don't start crying.
- I won't.
- That's where we set out for, ain't it?
Looks nice.
Yeah, it looks real fine.
- That must be your uncle Daniel.
- He looks nice, too, don't he?
Yup. Real nice.
Maybe if Frank D. Roosevelt comes,
he'll tell him to take me
to the station to see him.
Maybe you write, ol' Frankie'll
have a place to write you back now.
Yeah, he might, at that.
'Course he will.
Ain't no question but he will.
All this talk's just wasting time.
Here's your...
here, your skates, your radio.
- Where you gonna go?
- Don't worry about me.
I got plans.
New ideas coming in every day.
Get going.
You know, if I knew for sure
you wasn't my pa...
It's for sure I ain't your pa.
Although sometimes I used to figure
Mr Connors could have been my pa,
the way he touched my shoulder, get me
things from the candy counter for free.
And Mr Pritchard,
he smiled at me once real nice.
Except they don't have my jaw
or nothing.
So long.
Ain't you coming to the door with me?
There it is, right there.
How much closer am I supposed to bring you?
They'll wonder how I got here.
Tell 'em a family friend brung you,
and you had a little trouble on the way
with your car and with finances.
Now, get going.
Yes?
I'm Addie.
Addie?
Addie!
I've been worried sick about you.
Addie... come on in, child.
I been writing letters,
and your Uncle Daniel's been trying
to call those people down there
to see where you've been.
You're just the spitting image
of your mother, pretty as a picture.
I don't know why I go on like this.
What you need is some ice-cold lemonade.
Now you just sit right there,
and I'll be right back.
Everybody's going to be
so happy to see you.
We're going to get
those clothes off of you.
You're going to get into
a nice, fresh, bath...
and then you're going to sleep
in your own little bed,
alongside your cousin, Edna.
I just near give up on you, child.
I bet you're starving to death.
I'm going to cut you a big piece of pie.
We got those telegrams,
and then we never did hear from ya.
I told you, I don't want you
riding with me no more.
You still owe me $200.
Moze, look!
Come on.
Hurry up.
Keep your sunny side up
Keep it up high,
the side that gets blue
If you have nine sons in a row
Start a baseball team,
they make money, you know
Keep your funny side up, don't let up
Let your laughter come through,
doodley-doo
Stand up on your legs
Be like two fried eggs
Keep your sunny side up