I, Olof Henrik Edvard Vergerus...
take thee,
Elisabet Emilie Josefin Ekdahl...
to be my wedded wife...
to love you for better and for worse...
and as a symbol of this love
I give you this ring.
I, Elisabet Emilie Josefin Ekdahl...
take thee,
Olof Henrik Edvard Vergerus,
to be my wedded husband...
to love you for better and for worse...
and as a symbol of this love
I take this ring.
In the name of the Father,
and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
As well as they have consented
in sacred marriage...
I wonder if this is a good thing.
You saw how happy she was.
- I'm thinking of the children.
- They'll get used to it, dear mama.
He's a devil of a lady killer,
the Bishop is.
You don't know that for sure, Carl.
I don't know
why I just want to cry.
They should have taken a honeymoon.
I invited them to our house in Provence,
but Emilie refused.
That's not so strange.
She has great respect
for her new husband.
He's a handsome man,
whatever you say.
- I expect he has false teeth.
- Petra, don't be silly.
His mother was nice.
They say his sister's a bitch.
I've a feeling we'll have Emilie back...
quite soon.
the children don't appear
to have an appetite.
Everything's new and strange to them.
You must understand, Henrietta.
Perhaps they're turning up
their noses at the food.
Let's be happy
on our first evening together.
I have no desire to spoil it,
but in the future -
yes, I might as well mention it now.
In the future no one may leave the table
without having eaten up -
Dearest Henrietta,
Ill tell my children what to do.
There's a basic rule in this house
which no one must break,
not even you, dear Emilie,
and that is respect
for the temporal gifts.
I think you've misunderstood
an essential point, dearest Henrietta.
But I suggest we postpone this discussion
to a more suitable time.
Forgive me, dear Emilie.
I am forgetting myself.
I'm sure you're a more capable
housewife than I.
I'll ask your advice in all things.
Edvard has admonished me
a hundred times.
It's not easy to realize
one has become superfluous!
That will do, Henrietta.
Perhaps I may be allowed to share
that we are early risers in this house,
both weekdays and Sundays.
At 6:00 we gather
for morning prayers in Edvard's study.
I'd also like to mention that we make
our own beds and tidy our rooms.
In this house, punctuality,
cleanliness and order are the rule.
Don't be alarmed, children.
My sister makes it sound
worse than it actually is.
We'll start out very gently.
I'm not sure I understand.
If you mean to apply
a new method of upbringing -
Not at all, dear Emilie.
I'm convinced that the children
will soon realize
how fun it is to perform
one's duties conscientiously.
It's all to be like a game.
My children don't care
for that sort of game,
and neither do I.
Time will tell, dear Emilie.
They're coming now.
Into bed, both of you!
Now we'll say our prayers.
Thank you, God, for this day.
Please make me good.
May your angel stay by me
through the night.
God bless papa and mama
and grandpapa and grand -
and uncle Edvard.
myself and my brothers and sisters
and cousins, uncles and aunts,
Vega, Ester, Maj,
Siri, Berta, Alida, Lisen.
and uncle Isak
and everybody else. Amen.
Good night, Alexander.
Justina, Id like to speak to you
about tomorrow.
What's that book you're reading,
Alexander?
Good night, my boy.
Good night, my child.
God bless you.
Good night, uncle Edvard.
My dearest wish is for us to live
at peace with one another.
Love cannot be commanded,
but we can show respect
and consideration.
You go ahead, my dear.
I'll come later.
Whose doll house is this?
Fifteen years ago,
two little girls lived in this room.
They drowned in the river
with their mother.
- Perhaps the house is haunted.
- There are no such things as ghosts.
- Did they live in this room?
- I think this was the nursery.
Good night. Sleep well.
I think we've got
a terrible stepfather.
And the sister is crazy.
And that tub of lard
that has to be fed.
I don't want to live here.
You have to give me time.
Much has to be changed.
Some things will go quickly,
others will take time.
The main thing is not to lose heart.
Why did you marry the Bishop?
Because I love him.
Now let us sleep. Things will seem
better when we're not so tired.
Don't play Hamlet, my son.
I'm not queen Gertrude,
your kind stepfather
isn't the king of Denmark,
and this is not Elsinore castle,
even if it does look rather gloomy.
Hell and damnation.
Come, Fanny.
I'll show you something.
The windows are barred.
They can't be opened.
Yes, Oscar, that's how it is.
One is old and a child
at the same time.
What became
of those long years in between
that seemed so important
at the time?
May I take your hand?
I remember your hand as a child.
It was small and firm and dry.
And your wrist
was so awfully slender.
I enjoyed being a mother.
I enjoyed being an actress, too,
but I preferred being a mother.
I liked having a big belly,
and I didn't give two shakes
about the theatre then.
It's all acting anyway.
Some roles are nice,
others not so nice.
I played a mother.
I played Juliet and Margareta.
Then suddenly I played a widow
or a grandmother.
One role follows the other.
The thing is
not to shrink from them.
But what became of it all?
Can you tell me that, my boy?
You're a good boy
to listen to your old mother's soliloquies,
as Isak calls them.
Yes, you're a good boy, Oscar...
and I grieved terribly
when you passed away.
That was a strange role to play.
My feelings came
from deep in my body.
Even though I could control them...
they shattered reality,
if you know what I mean.
Reality has remained broken
ever since...
and, oddly enough,
it feels more real that way.
So I don't bother to mend it.
I just don't care anymore
if nothing makes sense.
Oscar, my dear boy?
- Yes, mama.
- Are you sad?
I'm worried.
About the children?
Supper time.
Then you are to go straight to bed.
The tray can be left until tomorrow.
Mrs. Tander sent some cookies for you.
I'll be upset if miss Vergerus
finds out I gave these to you.
Hasn't mother returned?
No, your mother has not returned.
She said she'd be back this evening.
Oh, dear, I don't know what to say.
Why do you keep sighing like that?
I haven't been in this house long,
thank goodness...
but Mrs. Tander,
who's been here since the first wife,
could tell you a thing or two.
Would you like a cookie?
- Yes, thank you.
- What does Mrs. Tander say?
That it was the same
in the first wife's day.
Only worse.
- Poor children.
- You mean us?
No, I don't mean you.
I mean the poor little ones who found
their grave in the dark river outside.
Their mother tried to save them,
but she was pulled down
by the current.
They found them later by the bridge.
They clung tightly to each other
as if they were one big body.
The arms had to be sawn off
to get the bodies into separate coffins.
Mrs. Tander says that since then,
it has never been quiet in this house.
There are no ghosts.
I don't mean to frighten you...
but this house
does funny things to you.
Look at my hand.
Skin's been completely ripped off,
stripped down to the flesh.
I was taking his grace his coffee.
When I grabbed the doorknob,
the skin stuck and ripped off.
Someone laughed behind me.
I heard it clearly and turned around..
But there was no one there.
I feel sorry for anyone who -
I shouldn't chatter on like this.
I'll keep quiet.
I'll close the door now.
Don't worry.
Your mother will probably
be back tomorrow,
and his grace will personally
release you from captivity.
- I've seen them.
- Who?
The woman and the children.
Is that the truth?
Are you telling the truth, Alexander?
Word of honour as a Swedish citizen.
Where did you see them?
I had been in the library
with that man who married my mother.
He'd been lecturing me.
I don't remember why.
I was passing through
the dining room...
and it was unusually bright.
Then I saw a little girl
in the doorway.
She ran past me without a sound.
Then I saw the older girl,
with the dark hair and big eyes.
She stopped and looked at me
and motioned to me to turn around.
And there in the bright sunlight...
stood the woman in her black dress.
She said in a faint,
almost inaudible voice...
not to be afraid,
that she had something to tell me.
What did she say?
I don't want to frighten anyone,
but these were her very words:
"I want you to know our secret.
Your stepfather, my husband,
locked me and my children
in the bedchamber.
For five days and nights
he kept us without food and water.
In our misery
we decided to escape.
We tied sheets together
and tried to climb down
to the finger of land sticking out
into the deep, swirling water.
My daughters went first,
but they fell headfirst into the water
and were dragged under.
I tried to save them..
but was sucked down into a black whirlpool
that grabbed my clothes.
Underwater I grasped
my children's hands
and drew them to me."
Maj! How nice.
Come in, dear child.
I hope Im not disturbing you.
Not at all.
Give me a kiss.
That's nice.
Very pretty.
Did you make it yourself?
Yes.
A pretty pattern.
So you didn't go on the excursion?
No, I wouldn't fit in the boat
with my big belly.
Nonsense.
- Is something wrong?
- I'm silly to worry.
Let's sit here.
Are you worried about the children?
Alexander and I agreed to write.
I've written seven letters.
And you've received no reply?
One postcard three weeks ago.
"Dear Maj. We are well.
Uncle Edvard took us to..."
the botanical gardens.
"We learned about rare flowers."
"Thank you for your letters.
I'll write when I get some time.
Love from Alexander.
Fanny sends her love."
We mustn't underestimate Emilie.
She's perfectly capable
of looking after her children.
We're worrying for no reason.
I came to the family
before Fanny was born.
They're my children too.
You're going already?
I wanted to speak with you,
since I knew you were alone.
Stay a moment.
Thank you for your kindness,
but I promised to have dinner ready
when they came home.
I haven't put the steak
in the oven yet.
Dear child, are things that bad?
Yes.
- Is it the cafe?
- That too.
Has Gustav Adolf been pestering you?
I don't want to hurt him.
He's so kind.
What worries me most
is the children.
I'm sorry to be crying.
I'm behaving badly.
Forgive me.
Mrs. Tander wants to know
if your grace will have supper alone.
Tell her I don't want any supper.
A glass of milk and a sandwich
in my room will be sufficient.
Thank you, sir. I'll tell her.
Was there something else?
I don't know.
I don't know how to say it.
It's so unpleasant. It might seem -
Well?
Sir, I can't stand here
in the doorway.
Come in, then, and close the door.
You said I was to keep an eye
on the children,
listen to their conversation
and tell you of anything unusual.
Well?
Alexander made up a terrible story.
Really?
It was about -
Oh, it's so awful
I don't know how to get it out.
He says you locked
your first wife up,
and she was drowned with her children
when they tried to escape.
- That's all, sir.
- You can go.
Who's there?
It's just me.
Get up. Your stepfather
wants to talk to you.
Get dressed.
Your stepfather wants to talk to you.
Hurry up!
Alexander, my boy.
In the presence of your sister
and Justina you have accused me
of having murdered
my wife and children.
What?
Justina, please repeat
what you told me.
Alexander said he had seen
your first wife and children.
She spoke to him
and said that the bishop
had locked them all up
without food and water.
On the fifth day they tried to escape
but drowned in the attempt.
- Do you recognize the story?
- No.
- So Justina has given false testimony?
- She could have dreamt it.
Justina, are you prepared to confirm
your statement under oath?
Yes, your grace.
Good, Justina.
Fanny, did you hear
Alexander's story?
No.
So you maintain that Justina
was either lying or dreaming?
yes.
Please come here, Alexander.
Are you prepared to swear to it?
Of course.
It's a mortal sin to swear falsely.
It's called perjury
and is severely punished.
Really?
Lay your hand on the bible
and say after me:
"I, Alexander Ekdahl...
swear by holy writ
and by the living God...
that all I have said,
say and will say...
is the whole truth
and nothing but the truth."
Alexander, my boy.
You remember that the two of us
had an important conversation
about a year ago.
It concerned certain moral questions.
It wasn't really a conversation.
What do you mean?
The bishop spoke
and Alexander said nothing.
And felt ashamed, perhaps,
on account of your lies.
I've grown wiser since then.
You mean you lie better.
More or less.
I don't know what you imagine.
Do you think you can besmirch
another person's honour with impunity?
I think the bishop hates Alexander.
That's what I think.
Oh, so that's what you think.
I'll tell you something
that may come as a surprise.
I don't hate you.
I love you.
But the love I feel for you
and your mother and sister
is not blind and sloppy.
It is strong and harsh.
- Do you hear what I say?
- No.
You're hardening your heart.
Moreover, you misjudge the situation.
- I am much stronger than you are.
- I don't doubt it.
I mean stronger spiritually.
Because I have truth and justice
on my side.
I know you'll confess
in a little while.
Your confession and punishment
will be a relief to you.
You're a wise little man, Alexander.
You realize that the game is up...
but you are proud and stubborn...
and of course you are ashamed.
I've forgotten what Im to confess.
Have you now.
What does the bishop want
Alexander to confess?
You know I have means at my disposal.
I didn't, but I do now.
In my childhood,
parents were not so soft-hearted.
They had the cane.
I have one too.
It's an ordinary carpet beater,
but it can dance a fine step!
If that didn't work, we had other
effective means, namely castor oil.
There you see the bottle and a glass.
A few mouthfuls of this
and you're more docile.
If that didn't help,
there was a dark and cold cubby-hole
where you sat for a few hours until
the rats started sniffing at your face.
Why must I be punished?
That is obvious, my boy.
You have a weakness in your character.
You can't distinguish lies from truth.
So far they are just child's lies,
however dreadful they may be.
But soon you will be
a grown man, Alexander,
and life punishes liars
ruthlessly and indiscriminately.
The punishment is to teach you
a love of truth.
I confess I made it up about locking
your wife and children in.
- Do you also confess to perjury?
- I suppose so.
Now you've won a great victory,
a victory over yourself.
Which punishment do you choose?
Cane, castor oil
or the dark cubby-hole?
- How many strokes of the cane?
- Ten.
Then I choose the cane.
Take two cushions
and put them on the table.
Pull your pants down.
Bend over.
Stand up.
- You have something to say to me.
- No.
You must ask my forgiveness.
I won't.
Then I must cane you
until you think better of it.
Can't you spare us both
that unpleasant experience?
I'll never apologize.
You won't apologize?
No.
Bend over.
No more, please!
Will you ask forgiveness now?
Yes.
Button your pants and blow your nose.
Lend him a handkerchief, Justina.
What do you have to say now?
Alexander asks the bishop
for forgiveness.
Speak up.
I want everyone to hear your regret.
Alexander asks the bishop
for forgiveness.
For the lies and the perjury.
You do understand
that I punished you out of love?
Yes!
Kiss my hand, Alexander.
- May I go to bed now?
- Yes, you may.
But so that you may contemplate
the day's events in peace and quiet...
you're to sleep in the attic.
Justina will provide
a mattress and a blanket.
At 6:00 in the morning
you will be let out. Understood?
Yes, your grace!
I must go.
A carriage is waiting at the gate.
I'm afraid something might have
happened while Ive been here.
I'm in constant fear that Alexander
will say something to displease him.
Alexander is so foolhardy.
I've tried to warn him,
but he can't see that his stepfather
is a dangerous opponent
who's just waiting
for the right opportunity to crush him.
You must leave him, Emilie.
I'm pregnant.
Nevertheless, you must -
forgive me for interrupting.
I've asked him for a divorce.
He refuses.
I tell him that Ill leave
just the same.
Then he explains in detail
what will happen.
In a court of law, Ill lose on grounds
of "desertion," as it's called.
The children will be taken from me,
to be brought up by him.
I've written in secret
to a friend of mine who's a lawyer.
He's confirmed what Edvard says.
I am shut in
and can no longer breathe.
I'm dying, Helena!
I hate that man so violently
that I could -
Don't mention that Ive been here.
To anybody.
- Give me the key!
- Edvard has forbidden it.
Give me the key now!
Edvard has forbidden it!
You're hurting me!
Emilie, you can't!
Take your damn paint box!
Listen to me.
I told you, there's none left.
- Alma, we're to go up to see grandmama.
- What are you shouting about?
I'm just shouting!
Punch will do just as well!
The old girl's not here.
She's probably in the dining room.
Good evening, mama.
We came to see how you are.
I am very well.
I hope you aren't lonely.
Lonely? I love being alone.
Vega was bitten by a wasp.
A wasp stings, my dear.
It has a stinger
just like your old man.
Don't pinch me.
And Petra fell in the lake
and got soaked.
Where shall I serve supper?
I don't want any.
- How's the wasp sting?
- Not worth talking about
And mama is busy
with the old man's photographs.
How many thousands
have you sorted by now?
Here's one of you and your brothers.
You couldn't have been
more than five years old.
- You can already tell which brother -
- who is this beautiful woman?
Did it rain on you the whole time?
No, not at all, dearest mama.
Not a cloud over the outer islands,
but we saw the rain over the mainland,
and heard the thunder
it's rained all day here.
This woman with the low neckline
was one of papa's lady friends.
You're mistaken.
We were at school together.
She married a count, had 12 children
and became as big as a house.
I always admired your skilful way
of handling papa's little adventures.
We must be going.
Mr. Ohman and his lovely wife
are going to stop by.
I'm going into town tomorrow.
Anything I can do for you?
Thank you, Gusten.
I don't need anything.
But I'd like to talk
to you about Maj.
What the hell is it now?
She's got it good.
Now I'm damned angry -
if you'll excuse me, mama.
Calm down, Gusten!
He loses his temper
at the mention of Maj's name.
I just want to say -
you have to realize
Maj is not your private plaything.
Thanks to Alma's broad-mindedness,
she's a member of our family,
and she's expecting my grandchild.
In your dictatorial way,
you've decided her future.
I don't give a damn -
I don't like it when you swear
in your mother's presence.
You hear me, Gusten?
I like the girl. I wish her well.
I want to ensure her future.
I don't want her to be dependent
on the family's benevolence if I die.
She's accepted my suggestions.
She doesn't need any protectors,
especially against me.
Stop your twaddle!
Don't make me out as a dictator!
Maj has decided it all herself!
I like her.
I'm kind to her.
Alma's kind to her.
Now I'm hurt, let me tell you.
Damned hurt!
There's no reason
to side with Maj against me!
I'm fond of her.
Alma's fond of her.
She is loved in the same way
as Jenny, Petra and Putte.
Well, not exactly in the same way,
but almost.
She's good to me.
She doesn't think
I'm fat and old and disgusting.
Nobody thinks that, by the -
Ive a soft spot for the ladies.
What's to be done about it?
That's nothing to giggle at.
Maj is to go her own way through life,
and I'm going to give her
solid ground to stand on.
That's enough said about that.
The opera singer said he would stop by
with his wife and children. Come now.
Good-bye, mama. Give me a kiss.
I don't want you and alma
to sit gossiping about Maj's future.
I'll see to that!
Or rather, she will.
Good night, mama.
Come, Alma.
- I'll be back in a couple of hours.
- Like hell you will! Come on!
Calm down or you'll have a stroke.
I am calm.
You're the one who's shouting.
I want an end to all that gossip
between you and mama!
Good day, Mr. Jacobi.
Good day, miss Vergerus.
What is it?
Is His Grace -
he is not to be disturbed.
May I speak to his wife?
She is indisposed,
resting in her room -
and not to be disturbed.
My mother is out and I am busy.
His Grace might be annoyed if -
What is this concerning?
Some months ago,
His Grace proposed a business deal.
Really? I don't recall.
Of course not, miss Vergerus.
His grace is careful to spare
his family such trivial worries.
What worries of his
could concern you?
Please don't force me to be vulgar.
To be candid, Mr. Jacobi,
I find you unpleasant.
I've neither the time
nor the inclination to speak with you.
- Good-bye, Mr. Jacobi.
- A pecuniary predicament.
I beg your pardon?
Your brother, His Grace,
was in a pecuniary predicament.
- May I sit down?
- Not there! There.
In a peculiar way -
I don't know why -
I appreciate your straightforwardness.
And I do not appreciate
your fawning.
What business do you have
with my brother?
None at all, as far as I know.
I'm tired of your riddles.
Tell me what's on your mind and go.
I must speak to His Grace first.
It's a matter of money.
A lot of money.
Does my brother owe you money?
On the contrary.
It's like this:
In November
His Grace wanted to borrow money.
Regrettably, Jews have certain principles,
like never lending money to the clergy.
He suggested I should buy that chest
for a reasonable sum.
I declined.
So you declined.
Foolishly so,
since Ive now changed my mind.
I'd like to buy that chest,
and at almost any price.
Almost.
I will get my brother.
I told you not to disturb me.
Mr. Jacobi wants to buy the chest.
That man hangs on like vermin!
Stay where you are.
I'll come get you in a few minutes.
Take your shoes off.
Forgive an old man's
unfortunate weakness, your grace.
- You wish to buy the chest?
- Yes.
For how much?
Here is the sum.
It seems you've changed your mind.
I may have an interested buyer.
- I'm being cheated, of course.
- You're free to say no.
- Do you have the money with you?
- The money?
The money!
Of course, your grace.
I have large bills right here.
Let me see.
Yes, here they are.
- Give me the money.
- Of course.
If I may have your grace's name
on the contract?
Forgive me if I retire.
I shall miss you, miss Vergerus.
Do not take anything
that is not your due.
Suspicions recoil
on those who harbour them.
Your grace will want to ensure
that Im not taking more than my due.
That's quite all right.
I just wanted to return
the signed contract.
Please have a seat.
What would you say
about that painting?
A beautiful and valuable work.
Would it interest you?
My resources are regrettably
a bit strained at present.
- How is your wife?
- It's kind of you to inquire.
She is indisposed.
This sudden heat disagrees with her.
- May I pay my respects?
- Unfortunately not.
I understand.
Here is a letter for her
from old Mrs. Ekdahl.
- I shall give it to her.
- You're too kind.
Filthy Jewish swine!
You damned, filthy Jewish swine!
You thought you could cheat me.
You'll regret this,
you repulsive, hook-nosed bastard!
Calm down!
That swine is trying
to steal my children!
He can't.
I have the key to the nursery.
Don't touch them!
Come here.
First and foremost,
let's have something to eat.
This is my nephew, Aron.
Let's go to the table.
I'd like to sleep.
Our guests are tired.
Have you tidied the room
and made the beds?
I've done all you asked, uncle.
This is Aron's puppet theatre.
If you ask him nicely,
he may give a performance.
Behind this door lives
my nephew Ismael. He's sick.
The door must always be kept shut.
Remember that, both of you.
Sometimes he sings, even at night.
It's nothing to worry about.
You'll get used to it.
This will be your home
for the time being.
I hope you'll like it.
Go to bed now.
Good night, Fanny.
Good night, Alexander.
Lock the door at night
and don't open it for anyone.
- Don't forget to say your prayers.
- Don't go.
You want me to stay?
Then I'll sit here.
I'll go and see to Ismael.
My name is Aron.
Ismael is my brother.
Our parents died
when we were small.
I have to pee.
Damn, there's no chamber pot.
It won't be easy
to find the toilet in the dark.
I hope there aren't any ghosts.
Damn, I think I've lost my way.
Now Im lost for sure.
It's not my fault
it's all gone wrong.
I can't leave you.
I just can't.
It would be better
if you'd take off for heaven.
You can't help us anyway.
I lived my whole life
with you children and Emilie.
Death makes no difference.
What is it, Alexander?
Why can't you go to God
and tell him to kill the Bishop?
Or doesn't God give a damn about you,
or any of us?
Have you even seen God
on the other side?
Not a bastard
has a thought in his head.
Idiots, the whole bunch of 'em.
You must be gentle with people.
Aren't you coming to bed?
The clock has struck 4:00.
I can't sleep.
Neither can I.
Elsa's very sick.
We ought to send for the doctor.
He's coming in the morning.
- What are you drinking?
- Hot broth.
- It helps against insomnia.
- May I?
Be my guest.
Can't you forgive me?
I'm staying with you, aren't I?
I don't understand
this sudden yielding.
Drink while it's hot.
- You insist that the children return?
- Yes.
In that case, it's hopeless.
I don't care if it's hopeless.
I care only for what is right.
Isn't that Elsa calling?
Stay here. I'll see to her.
Can I help you, aunt?
It's so dark.
What time is it?
Almost half past 4:00.
It's been a long night.
Try to get some sleep.
My legs hurt.
They're swollen and aching.
You once said
you were always changing masks...
until finally
you didn't know who you were.
I have only one mask.
But it's branded into my flesh.
If I tried to tear it off -
I always thought people liked me.
I saw myself as wise,
broad-minded and fair.
I had no idea...
that anyone could hate me.
I don't hate you.
No, but your son does.
I'm afraid of him.
Who's behind the door?
It is God behind the door.
- Can't you come out?
- No living being may see God's face.
- What do you want?
- To prove that I exist.
This is the end of me.
Shall I show myself?
Now you will see me.
- Admit you were scared.
- I wasn't a damned bit scared.
"This is the end of me."
Ouch! That hurts.
Don't cry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
At least not that much.
I've been working all night
on this puppet.
A rich circus owner in England
is mad about our puppets.
I heard you tiptoeing around.
Hear that?
My brother Ismael is awake.
He's singing.
Poor Ismael.
Human beings are more
than he can bear.
Sometimes he gets furious.
Then he's dangerous.
You said you'd been up all night,
but I saw you asleep.
There are many strange things
that can't be explained.
You realize that
when you dabble in magic.
- Have you seen our mummy?
- No.
Come.
Look carefully, Alexander.
Can you see it breathing?
It's been dead 4,000 years,
but it breathes.
I'll make the room dark.
- What do you see?
- It's shining.
Exactly.
No one knows why it's luminous.
No one can explain why.
The unknown makes people angry.
It's better to blame it on mirrors,
machines and projections.
Then people laugh,
and that's healthier from all viewpoints,
especially financially.
Watch carefully now.
Uncle Isak says we're surrounded
by different realities,
one on top of the other.
There are swarms
of ghosts, spirits, phantoms,
souls, poltergeists,
angels and demons.
He says the smallest pebble
has a life of its own.
- More coffee?
- Yes, please.
Everything is alive,
and everything
is God or God's thought.
Not only good things,
but the cruellest too.
What do you think?
If there is a God,
then he's a shit,
and I'd like to kick him in the butt.
Your theory is very interesting
and appears to be justified.
Shall we take Ismael his breakfast?
I've brought your breakfast.
Your sister gave me sleeping pills
for my insomnia.
I had put three in the broth.
I didn't mean for you to drink it.
When you went to see Elsa,
I put in three more.
You will sleep soundly.
When you wake up, I will be gone.
I'm going back to my children...
to my home...
and my family.
I'll change and you'll come back.
I'll never come back!
I'll poison your life!
I'll follow you from town to town!
I'll ruin your children's future!
Poor Edvard, you don't know
what you're saying!
I am awake!
I'm horribly awake.
Help me into bed at least.
I can't see anymore...
and I feel dizzy.
Are you there? I can't see.
Ismael, I've brought your breakfast.
Good morning, Ismael.
This is Alexander Ekdahl, a friend.
Leave us alone, Aron.
Don't worry. I won't eat him...
even if he does look appetizing.
You can come back in half an hour.
- Go now, Aron.
- Uncle Isak -
uncle Isak is an old goat
and needn't know of Alexander's visit.
Go now.
No, thank you.
My name is Ismael,
but you already know that.
"And he will be a wild man.
His hand will be against every man,
and every man's hand against him."
I'm considered dangerous.
That's why Im locked up.
Dangerous in what way?
Write your name here.
The pencil's pretty dull,
but it should still serve.
There, Alexander Ekdahl.
Now read what you've written.
It says "Ismael Retzinsky."
Perhaps we're the same person,
with no boundaries.
Perhaps we flow through each other,
stream through each other
boundlessly and magnificently.
You bear such terrible thoughts...
it's almost painful to be near you.
Yet it's also enticing.
- Do you know why?
- I don't think I want to know.
You've heard of making an image
of someone you dislike
and sticking pins in it?
It's a rather clumsy method
when you think of the swift paths
an evil thought can travel.
You're a strange little person.
You won't speak of that
which is constantly in your thoughts.
You're thinking of a man's death.
Wait a moment.
I know who you're thinking of:
A tall man with fair, greying hair.
Correct me if Im wrong.
He has clear blue eyes
and a boyish face.
Correct me if Im wrong.
He's asleep and dreams
he's kneeling at the altar.
Above the altar
hangs the crucified prophet.
In his dream he gets up
and cries out,
"my God, my God,
why hast thou forsaken me?"
There is no answer,
not even a laugh.
Don't talk like that.
It is not I talking.
It is yourself.
You are not to hesitate.
He's sound asleep,
plagued by nightmares.
Give me your hands.
It isn't really necessary,
but it's safer.
The doors will be thrown open.
A scream will echo through the house.
- I don't want to.
- It's too late.
You have only one way to go,
and I am with you.
I obliterate myself.
I merge into you, my child.
Don't be afraid.
I am with you.
I am your guardian angel.
It is 5:00 in the morning,
and the sun has just risen.
The doors are thrown open.
No, wait.
First a horrible scream
echoes through the house.
A shapeless burning figure
moves across the floor,
...screaming.
I don't want to.
Let me go! Let me go!
The police are here
and insist on speaking to you.
Your husband,
His Grace the Bishop,
lost his life this morning
under terrible circumstances.
May I, madam?
We think we've been able to determine
the course of events.
Miss Elsa Bergius,
who was gravely ill, lay in bed.
On her bedside table stood a lamp.
By some unfortunate accident,
the lamp fell on the bed
igniting her nightgown,
hair and bed linens.
Blazing like a torch,
she ran through the house
and by chance made it
into the Bishop's bedchamber.
According to His Grace's sister,
miss Henrietta Vergerus,
he was in a heavy sleep
from a soporific
you had given him earlier that night.
Miss Bergius flung herself on him,
igniting his bedclothes
and nightshirt.
His grace woke up
and succeeded in freeing himself
from the dying woman
who was still ablaze.
But he could not
extinguish the flames
that were now engulfing him.
Old Mrs. Vergerus found her son
with his body burnt
and face charred.
He showed faint signs of life
and said he was in unbearable agony.
Although I can't overlook the fact
that the sleeping aid you gave him
possibly made the disaster worse,
I also cannot attach
any serious importance to it.
Therefore, I must characterize the event
as an ill-fated coincidence
of extremely unfortunate
circumstances.
My dear, dear friends.
I am more moved than I can say.
My wisdom is simple.
There are those who despise it,
but I don't give a damn -
forgive me, mama.
I noticed you raised your right eyebrow.
You think your son is talking too much.
Don't worry. I will be brief.
Therefore... and consequently...
we Ekdahls have not come
into the world to see through it.
Never think that.
We are not equipped
for such excursions.
We might just as well ignore
the big things.
We must live in the little world.
We will be content with that
and cultivate it
and make the best of it.
Suddenly death strikes.
Suddenly the abyss opens.
Suddenly the storm howls,
and disaster is upon us.
All that we know.
But let us not think
of all that unpleasantness.
We Ekdahls love our subterfuges.
Rob a man of his subterfuges
and he goes mad and begins lashing out.
Damn it all,
people must be intelligible!
Otherwise we don't dare to love them
or speak ill of them.
We must be able to grasp
the world and reality
so we can complain of their monotony
with a clear conscience.
Don't be sad, dear splendid artists.
Actors and actresses,
we need you all the same.
It is you who must give us
our supernatural shivers,
or better yet,
our innermost diversions.
The world is a den of thieves
and night is falling.
Evil breaks its chains
and runs through the world like a mad dog.
The poison affects us all,
us Ekdahls and everyone else.
No one escapes, not even
Helena Viktoria or little Aurora.
So it shall be.
Therefore let us be happy
while we are happy.
Let us be kind, generous,
affectionate and good.
It is necessary,
and not at all shameful...
to take pleasure in the little world.
Good food...
gentle smiles...
fruit trees in bloom, waltzes.
My dearest friends,
Im done talking,
and you can take it as you like:
The sentimental ramblings
of an uneducated restaurateur
or the pitiful babbling of an old man.
I don't care.
I hold a little empress in my arms.
It's tangible yet immeasurable.
One day she will prove
everything I just said wrong.
One day she will not only rule
the little world,
but everything.
Everything.
Be a good girl now,
so that mama can go to bed.
I think you've finished eating,
in any case.
- I'll take her.
- Thank you, Rosa.
- How do you like it here?
- Everyone's so kind.
Especially Mr. Ekdahl.
He must be a real friend of humanity.
That he certainly is.
He's particularly kind to young girls,
so you watch out, Rosa.
Oh, my!
- Good night, madam.
- Good night, Rosa.
Come on, you're tired.
- Oh no, let's stay.
- Let's go to bed.
We're going to have champagne.
If you're a good boy, I'll bring you
a beer and sandwich in bed.
I'm sure Emilie will want
a glass of champagne.
We'll raise a toast to our daughters.
Go to bed now, Gusten.
I'm so damned happy!
That's nice, Gusten,
but you'll have a headache tomorrow.
Imagine: We're together again.
I'm going to the country tomorrow
to speak with the workmen.
Do you need anything taken care of?
- I'll be there until Thursday.
- I'll come on Tuesday.
Don't you think I have
the best wife in the world?
Much better than you deserve.
And the world's
prettiest little mistress.
A real darling.
- Are you going in the morning?
- Not until 2:00.
When I see you,
I want to weep with joy.
To think you're back with us again!
- Good night, Gusten.
- Good night.
Be a good boy now, and remember
that Alma needs her sleep.
I know what Alma needs.
Aunt Emilie.
- What do you two want at this hour?
- We want to move to Stockholm.
Marianne Egerman is opening
a boutique and wants us to help.
- And we'd like to.
- We'd very much like to.
But we have a big problem.
Papa insists on that cafe for Maj.
He's so kind.
- Maj's had enough of his tutelage.
- He's so kind.
She wants to live her own life
and decide for herself and her baby.
I don't know what to do.
We've spoken to mama.
She was awfully upset at first
and said we couldn't do that to papa.
Then she calmed down and said
that life must take its course...
and that one shouldn't force
one's children.
Though she felt sorry
for papa's sake.
It's awful.
You must think of yourself.
After all, papa's an old man.
Isn't that true, aunt Emilie?
Go to bed now.
I'll have a word with grandmama.
Emilie, how nice to see you!
Welcome!
I need to speak with you.
- Would you like a cognac?
- No, thank you.
Is it anything serious?
Oh, yes. Maj and Petra
want to move to Stockholm.
What do you think?
You can't escape me.
One other thing.
You're right.
On his deathbed, Oscar asked you
to take charge of the theatre.
I was there.
I remember it well.
Gustav Adolf will be awfully hurt.
Why all this concern
for Gustav Adolf?
He has a good head for business,
but he doesn't know
a thing about theatre.
It's your theatre, my dear Emilie.
It's about time we explain
to our backwoods Napoleon
that he's facing his Waterloo.
I'd like you to read a new play
by August Strindberg.
That nasty misogynist!
No, thank you.
It's called a dream play.
I thought we'd both perform in it.
Not on your life.
I haven't appeared on stage in -
all the more reason.
I won't disturb you any longer.
You never disturb me.
What are you laughing at?
Now we're the ones in charge,
aren't we?
Do you think so?
- Good night, dearest.
- Good night, my dear.
"Everything can happen.
Everything is possible and probable.
Time and space do not exist.
On a flimsy framework of reality,
the imagination spins,
weaving new patterns."