Hi, Toybull.
Hey, your pal just drove
into town, Mr. McCarthy.
I'll have one more, Toybull.
I'm afraid I'll have to pay
my bar bill tomorrow.
You're good with me, Mr. McCarthy.
Thank you, Toybull.
Good night, Toybull.
Good night, Mr. McCarthy.
Operator.
Operator, I want...
489 Thunder Bay.
I want to speak to Mrs. Manion.
M-A-N-I-O-N.
This is Paul Biegler speaking.
Iron City 7 00.
- Do they know when she'll be there?
- No, they don't.
I see.Just leave a message.
Tell her to call this number.
Thank you.
- What do you say there, counselor?
- Save your money.
What's in the brown paper bag?
It might be a cabbage head.
Bet it wouldn't be.
You're a very suspicious man.
True, I'm everlastingly
suspicious of...
and/or fascinated by...
the contents of brown paper bags.
- Shall I sneak a peek?
- You do that, counselor.
You do that.
After you sneak a peek, why, you...
uncork whatever you find.
- Shall I pour?
- Be a privilege.
My pleasure, sir.
You fought this soldier by yourself.
You've been drinking alone, Paulie.
I don't like that.
Drop the stone, counselor.
You live in a glass house.
My windows have been busted long ago,
so I can say as I please.
Have an Italian cigar?
No, thanks.
Those stinkweeds are another sign
of your decadence.
Paulie, it's a fact.
Since Mitch Lodwick beat you out of
the office of public prosecutor...
you haven't been worth
salt for peanuts.
Not that I don't understand
how you feel.
A man gets beat out of an office
he's held for a long time...
he feels his community
has deserted him.
The finger of scorn is pointed at him.
None but the lonely hearts
shall know my anguish.
Paulie, you're a good lawyer.
You ought to make like one.
Be here ready for clients,
not out fishing and playing that...
rooty-tooty jazz.
Oh, I'm making a living.
I run a few abstracts--
how to divorceJane Doe
from John Doe every once in a while.
Threaten a few deadbeats.
And in the evening,
I sit around and drink bourbon whisky...
and read law
with Parnell Emmitt McCarthy...
one of the world's great men.
That was a kind word, Paulie.
You know...
I might have been.
That's one of the reasons I hate to see
your talent pushed aside by lesser men.
I look at you, and I see myself
years ago...
with the same love for the smell
of the old brown books...
and the dusty office.
Here's the rose.
A lily.
A sweet lupine.
The United States
Supreme Court reports.
Well...
what shall we read
this evening, counselor?
How about a little
ChiefJustice Holmes?
Keep ChiefJustice on hold for a moment.
I might have a client.
- Waiting for a call. Hello?
- Mr. Biegler?
- This is Paul Biegler speaking.
- It's your party.
- Hello? Mrs. Manion?
- What?
Mr. Biegler?
I'm sorry I missed you a while ago.
Did you get my message?
- Who is that? What is that name?
-Just a minute, please.
We seem to have a bad connection.
Hold on.
It's a woman, name of Manion.
Maida took a message from her.
- In Thunder Bay?
- Uh-huh.
If she wants you to represent
her husband, say yes.
- I don't know what it's all about.
- Pretend you do and say yes.
- Hello?
- Mr. Biegler?
Oh, yes. This is much better now.
Yes, I can hear you fine.
I've waited for your call
all afternoon.
Yes, well, I just got in
a few moments ago.
You've read about my husband?
Muffy, please.
Yes.
Mr. Biegler, have you read
about my husband? Muffy, please.
Well, uh, yes, I have, a little.
- Will you defend him?
- I don't know.
- I'd have to know more about it.
- Will you talk to him?
Mr. Biegler, he's in the county jail.
Will you see him in the morning?
He's very anxious to see you.
You've been so highly recommended.
I have?
Yes, someone told him about you.
Will you see him?
I suppose I could.
I'll see him tomorrow morning.
- Would you want me there too?
- I think that'd be fine.
Let's make it about 1 0:00.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Yes, you're quite welcome.
Bye.
Now, what's this all about?
A man named Barney Quill
raped Mrs. Manion.
Her husband, he's a lieutenant
in the army--
there's a temporary base in Thunder Bay,
a gunnery or something--
The lieutenant goes to Quill's place
and plugs Mr. Quill about five times...
which causes Mr. Quill to promptly die
of lead poisoning.
- When did this happen?
- A couple of nights ago.
If you hadn't been out fishing
in some godforsaken backwater...
you'd have known about it.
- Morning, Maida.
- Oh, there it is.
- What?
- The newspaper.
I thought maybe they didn't bring it.
We haven't paid the bill.
- Did you get my note?
- Uh-huh. We may be on the case.
I'm just reading up on it now
before talking to Lt. Manion.
Doesn't he ever go home?
Oh, you mean Parnell?
We were up late last night.
Is that a fact?
I think maybe you better cancel
all my appointments for today.
What appointments? People think
you've migrated into the woods.
If this refrigerator gets any more
fish in it, it'll swim upstream...
and spawn all by itself.
May I have your attention
for a moment, please?
I was going over
your checkbook yesterday.
I can't pay me my salary.
What did you do with the fee
for the Walkers' divorce?
Help salt a uranium mine
or something?
- Bought a few bare necessities.
- Like a new outboard motor.
I wish I could be classed
as a necessity.
- Aren't you gonna have your toast?
- No, no, I'll, uh--
I'll call you,
let you know how things are going.
Don't let him pay you off
in Purple Hearts.
Those professional soldiers
never have a dime.
I ought to know.
I was married to one.
Beg your pardon.
Are you Mrs. Manion?
- Hi.
- I'm Paul Biegler.
- I'm Laura.
- How do you do?
- This is Muff.
- Oh, Muff.
The jail's right here.
You're tall.
- Hello, Paulie!
- Hi, Sulo.
You wait here, Muffy.
- Good to see you, Paulie.
- How you feeling?
Fine. I guess you come
for the soldier boy.
Yeah. Do you think it'd be all right
if we talk in the sheriff's office?
Oh, sure, Paulie.
I'll bring him down.
Would you mind taking
your glasses off, Mrs. Manion?
Did Barney Quill do that to you?
Mm-hmm. More than that.
You should see. All over.
You can put them back on
if it's more comfortable for you.
This is Paulie Biegler.
This is the bucko, Paulie.
- Hello, there.
- Hi, Manny.
Hello, Laura.
Mrs. Manion, can you meet me down in
my office about 2:00 this afternoon?
It's 305 West Barnham.
- Of course.
- Fine.
Is there anything
I can get you, hon?
I'm all right, hon.
Right in here.
Wanted. The big ten.
They got the ten best-dressed dames...
the ten top teams,
the ten top tunes...
and now the ten most wanted.
Don't knock it. That's the American
dream. Those boys made the grade.
You were the...
district attorney around here,
weren't you?
Ten years.
What's your experience
as a defense lawyer?
- Not very much.
- How do I know you can handle my case?
I guess you don't know.
Shall we talk about it?
I suppose so.
Come on, Lieutenant.
Don't be so bored.
It might very well be that no lawyer
can handle your case...
if you mean
getting you off scot-free.
You seemed to be forgetting
Barney Quill raped my wife.
I have the unwritten law
on my side.
The unwritten law's a myth,
Lieutenant.
There is no such thing
as the unwritten law.
And anyone who commits a murder
on the theory that it does exist...
has just bought himself room and board
in the state penitentiary.
Maybe for life.
Now, with that in mind,
perhaps we can proceed with a...
few questions and answers that--
That, uh--
Can I borrow your lighter?
We can proceed with a few questions and
answers that might help your defense.
But it probably won't be.
Yes. Nice lighter.
- Okay.
- How old are you?
- Twenty-eight.
- How long have you been in the service?
Since '50.
- You see any action?
- Korea.
- Have any decorations?
- Plenty.
- Is this your first marriage?
- No.
You're not on the witness stand.
You don't have to answer yes or no.
Just give me the matrimonial rundown.
- Is this necessary?
- I'll be the judge of that.
My first wife divorced me.
Charged cruelty.
Eating crackers in bed.
You know, the usual stuff.
Truth was...
she found another guy
when I was in Korea.
I met Laura four years ago
in Georgia.
We were married
right after her divorce.
Did you know the husband?
- He was in my outfit down there.
- You mean, you were buddies?
I'll withdraw the question.
It's a little old-fashioned.
Have there been any children
by or from any of these marriages?
- No.
- Any present prospects?
Not unless Barney Quill
started something.
What kind of a gun did you use?
War souvenir. A Luger.
The police have it now.
I suppose you've read the newspapers,
the stories about your case.
- Some of them.
- Are they substantially correct?
And you didn't see Quill rape
and beat your wife?
No. No.
When she got back...
to the trailer,
she told me what had happened.
And how long was it before you went
over to Quill's and killed him?
I don't know exactly.
Maybe an hour.
That long, huh?
The newspapers say that your wife
volunteered to take a lie detector test.
- Do you know anything about this?
- Only what I read and what she told me.
Do you know how
the lie detector test turned out?
They didn't tell her.
- Yes, Sulo?
- We got lunch served for the jail.
- You want to eat with us?
- Your sister still cook for the jail?
Oh, sure. She cooks.
Well, you give her
my compliments, Sulo.
I've got a luncheon date downtown.
- Nice going, Mr. Biegler.
- I'll be back after lunch.
Look, I'm sorry
if I offended you a while ago.
No, you're not.
Come on, bucko.
Thank you.
Pass the salt, Paulie.
Did you give the lieutenant
the well known lecture?
If you mean, did I coach him into
a phony story, no.
Maybe you're too pure, Paul.
Too pure for the natural impurities
of the law.
Could be that you owe the lieutenant
the chance to find a defense.
Could also be that you might guide him
a little, show him the way...
and let him decide
if he wants to take it.
- Want some salt?
- No, I'm not ready.
Anyway, I'm not the right lawyer
for this fellow.
He's insolent, hostile--
You don't have to love him.
Just defend him.
What's the matter?
Don't you need a fee?
You know something? I think
you might be a little bit afraid.
- Afraid of what?
- That you might get licked.
You know, there's only one thing more
devious than a Philadelphia lawyer...
and that's an Irish lawyer.
Pass the salt.
Put it down.
- Hello there.
- I usually answer to the name Paul.
You gonna have some more jokes?
Not unless you want to be
the comic.
Oh, I brought you some cigarettes.
- Oh, thanks.
- Peace?
- Sure.
- Fine, fine. Now, Lieutenant...
there are four ways
I can defend murder.
Number one, it wasn't murder.
It was suicide or accidental.
Number two, you didn't do it. Number
three, you were legally justified...
like the protection of your home
or self-defense.
Number four,
the killing was excusable.
Where do I fit in
to this rosy picture?
I'll tell you where you don't fit in.
You don't fit in any of the first three.
Why? Why wouldn't I be legally justified
in killing the man who raped my wife?
Time element.
If you'd caught him in the act, the
shooting might have been justified...
but you didn't catch him in the act,
and you had time to bring the police...
and you didn't do that either.
You're guilty of murder--
premeditated and with vengeance.
That's first-degree murder
in any court of law.
- Are you telling me to plead guilty?
- When I advise a cop out, you'll know.
- Cop out?
- That's plead guilty and ask for mercy.
If you're not telling me to cop out,
what are you telling me to do?
I'm not telling you to do anything.
I just want you to understand
the letter of the law.
- Go on.
- Go on with what?
Whatever it is you're getting at.
You know, you're very bright,
Lieutenant.
Now let's see how really bright
you can be.
Well, I'm working at it.
All right.
Now, because your wife was raped...
you'll have a favorable atmosphere
in the courtroom.
The sympathy will be with you
if all the facts are true.
What you need is a legal peg so the jury
can hang their sympathy in your behalf.
You follow me?
What's your legal excuse, Lieutenant?
What's your legal excuse
for killing Barney Quill?
Not justification?
Not justification.
Excuse.
Just excuse.
What excuses are there?
How should I know?
You're the one that plugged Quill.
- I must've been mad.
- How's that?
I said I must've been mad.
No, bad temper's no excuse.
I mean,
I must've been crazy.
Am I getting warmer?
Okay. See you around.
I'll tell you that
after I talk to your wife.
In the meantime, see if you can
remember just how crazy you were.
Is Mrs. Manion here yet?
She's been waiting quite a while.
She's been through all your albums,
from Dixieland to Brubeck.
What do you think of her?
Soft. Easy. The kind men like
to take advantage of...
and do.
Did you get any money?
- Money.
- Oh. Oh, no.
I haven't decided
to take the case yet.
You know, you surprise me sometimes.
Why? I've been around.
I, uh...
hope you don't mind.
I think we'd better talk.
You're a funny kind of a lawyer.
The music, I mean.
Aren't lawyers supposed
to like music?
Well, not that kind of music.
Oh. I guess that settles it.
I'm a funny kind of lawyer.
Where's your home, Mrs. Manion?
Where did you go to school?
Where did you live when you were young?
No place in particular.
We sort of moved around.
My father was a construction boomer.
Building dams, mostly.
You can call me Laura.
Is your family still alive, Laura?
No.
I don't know. I have
some cigarettes around here someplace.
- Do you want a cigarette?
- No, I want to offer you one.
- You could light it for me.
- Oh, yes.
Here.
That's just like your husband's.
He gave me this because I liked
the one he had.
He's like that.
He gives me presents all the time.
Do you have a happy marriage?
What went wrong
with the first marriage?
Well, what when wrong is
when I went for Manny.
Well, that's honest enough.
It was more than just that. Like I said,
I grew up on the move, and...
Jack-- that was my first husband--
Jack didn't like to move.
He wouldn't even take a transfer
when he had the chance.
I was really bored.
Manny likes to go. We're always going
whenever we get the chance.
We've been all over.
I'm thirsty.
Water, or would a beer do?
I think a beer would do fine.
Maida, bring me
a bottle of beer, will you?
- Are you married?
- No.
That's nice.
What do you do alone in this house
if you aren't married?
Well, it's a family home,
and I'm the last of the family.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- Aren't you having one?
- No, not right now.
There you are.
Could Muff have a little
in that ashtray? He loves beer.
You want a beer for the dog?
Well, here we are.
He'll go to sleep now.
- Isn't he cute?
- Yeah.
How about it?
Are you ready?
I mean, are you ready
to tell me the story?
I know what you mean.
Now, suppose you tell me everything
you told the state police...
plus everything you didn't tell
the state police.
- Where should I begin?
- When did you leave for Quill's bar?
Right after dinner.
About 8:30, I guess.
Manny was late getting home
from the firing range...
so we had dinner,
he laid down and went to sleep.
I hadn't been out of the trailer
all day, so...
I took Muff and a flashlight
and walked over to the bar.
I bought a drink
and played the pinball machine.
- Many people in the bar?
- Mm-mm. Not many.
Barney came over
and challenged me to a game.
- For drinks, you know?
- How well did you know Barney?
Well, he owned this bar where
Manny and I went sometimes, that's all.
Had he ever made a pass at you?
No. Nothing like that at all.
Was he drinking heavily that night?
Didn't seem to be. At least
not when we were playing pinball.
Were you with him
the whole time you were there?
No, there were other people
playing too.
And what time did you leave the bar?
Oh, about 1 1 :00, I guess.
I left by the side door.
Muff was carrying the flashlight.
He carries it in his mouth.
He's so cute...
running along ahead
with the light shining.
- Was he sober?
- Muff? Of course he was sober.
Oh, you're joking now,
aren't you?
Yes, I'm joking.
Go on.
Well, Barney came from somewhere.
Not the door I left by.
And he said he was going my way
and he could drive me home.
He said the bears had been prowling
around, and I oughtn't to walk home.
The bears come out of the woods
at night to scavenge.
They're harmless enough,
aren't they?
Yeah, I suppose I wouldn't have been
afraid in the daylight...
but the dark isn't the same.
Yes, I know. I know.
Now, you got into Barney's car--
I got in and he drove
straight to the trailer park.
- He made overtures?
- No, nothing.
When we got to the trailer park,
the auto gate was closed.
Mr. Lemon closes it
about 1 1 :00 or a little after.
So I thanked Barney
and started to get out of the car...
but he said that there wasn't
any need for me to walk...
that he could drive me into the park
on another road.
I didn't know
there was another road, but...
he drove on before
I could say yes or no.
- Were you alarmed?
- No.
I'm not usually afraid of men.
And anyway, he hadn't touched me
or even said anything out of the way.
Well, doesn't a woman sort of
instinctively know...
when a fellow's on the make?
Oh, sure,
but that's only usual with me.
With men, I mean. Almost all men.
Ever since I was a kid.
You, for instance.
You're interested...
but there's no reason
to be afraid of you.
It was like that with Barney.
Well, Mrs. Manion, believe me,
I'm not in the least--
Call me Laura.
Laura, I'm only interested
in helping your husband. Nothing more.
I don't mean you'd try anything.
I just mean it's--
it's the way you look at me.
It would be very difficult
not to look at you.
Oh, the way I dress, you mean?
You don't like it?
Oh, I love it.
I just love it.
Now, we'd better keep moving along
with this thing.
Now, how were you dressed that night?
Oh, in a sweater like this
and a skirt.
And the rest-- what about that?
Underneath? I had on a slip
and panties and a bra.
- No girdle?
- I don't need a girdle.
Do you think I do?
I don't know. I don't know.
How should I--
Look, I'm only concerned
with a few facts...
that might be of help to me
in the defense of your husband.
- That's all.
- Well, I don't wear one.
Okay. No girdle. Okay.
All right. Go on.
Well, he turned off the highway
into a lane in the woods...
and he stopped the car
and turned off the lights.
And then he grabbed me,
and he said...
" I'm going to rape you,"
just like that.
- Did he use those words?
- Exactly those words.
Muff began to bark,
so he threw him out the window.
I could hear little Muffy whining
outside the car all through it.
And Barney began to try
to get at me...
and I fought him off as best I could,
but he was terribly strong.
Did you cry out?
Did you scream?
Didn't seem to be much use
out there in the woods.
He began to shout names at me, like...
" Army slut" and other names.
And then he drew back
and hit me with his fist.
He hit me again,
and I didn't fight anymore.
I must have been only
half-conscious, but...
I know that he tore my panties off
and did what he wanted.
Now, the newspaper said
that a doctor examined you...
and said that he didn't think
you'd been raped.
I don't care what the doctor thought.
A woman doesn't mistake these things.
All right. All right.
Now, go ahead.
Well, I--
I don't know exactly what happened then.
I must've fainted. But...
the next thing I remember,
the car was moving.
Barney was driving very fast...
and he was breathing hard...
an ugly, gasping sound.
We were on the main road
to the trailer park...
and he swung in by the gate
and stopped.
I opened the door to get out. Muffy
jumped out first with a flashlight.
Now, wait a minute.
I thought you said he'd thrown Muff
out of the car back in the woods.
Well, he did, but Muff was in the car
when we got back.
He must've let him back in.
I don't remember.
All right. You opened the door,
and Muff got out first. All right.
Before I could get out...
Barney grabbed me and said he was gonna
tear all my clothes off...
and attacked me again.
I got away and ran. I could see Muff
through an opening in the fence.
He was scooting back and forth
with a flashlight.
Barney caught me from behind,
and I fell to the ground.
He fell on top of me and began
to beat me again with his fists.
I thought he was going to kill me.
I screamed and somehow got
to my feet again and ran.
I went through the opening
in the fence...
and followed Muffy, who was running
along ahead with the flashlight.
And I kept following the light
until he led me to our trailer.
And you didn't see Barney again?
Never laid eyes on him again,
dead or alive.
Well, I, uh--
I think that's enough for now.
I've got lots of time.
All you want.
- Where can I reach you?
- I'm still in Thunder Bay...
but I can drive down again
in the morning.
- Was there something else?
- No.
-Thanks for letting me play the records.
-Oh, you're very welcome.
Thanks a lot.
Bye.
- Who's that?
- The lady in the case.
- You're not going to take the case?
- I don't know.
That depends on what Manion
has to tell me tomorrow.
He's thinking things out.
Oh, well, that's more like it.
Now, if I take the case,
I want you in it.
Me, in a big murder case?
The sight of this whisky-drinking man
at the lawyer's table would ruin you.
I need you.
You mean that?
Why else would he say it?
I'd be glad to work with you
outside of the courtroom, but...
- not in the courtroom.
- Suit yourself about that.
Either way, I'm gonna have
to be able to depend on you.
Will you lay off the booze?
I don't know.
I don't know about that, Paulie.
Why don't you know?
Do you think I couldn't
lay off the booze?
Ever tried it?
Try it.
I never been on
a big murder case.
Not once in all my life.
It's up to you, Parn.
Will you be around tonight?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll be around.
You know, Maida, darling...
I might manage it.
I might manage to be
a real lawyer again.
For a little while, anyway.
I tried remembering.
There were still some pieces missing.
I remember...
going to Quill's bar with a gun...
and I remember Quill's face
behind the bar...
but I don't remember anything else,
not even going home.
Don't you remember firing the gun? Five
shots, that's a lot of noise to forget.
Yeah, I remember hearing shots,
but they don't seem connected with me.
They seemed far away, like
somebody else was doing the shooting.
Lt. Manion, I'll take your case.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks, Mr. Biegler.
All right. Now, there's
the little matter of the fee.
Three thousand dollars.
That's reasonable enough, isn't it?
Oh, sure. More than reasonable. I'll
have to pay later. Right now I'm broke.
- You're what?
- I'm broke. I'm flat busted.
I don't have three dollars,
much less 3,000.
- Can you raise it?
- Oh, yes, as soon as I get out of jail.
But next week's payday.
I'll be able to give you $1 50...
and if you get me off, I'll give you
a promissory note for the rest.
All right, now suppose I don't go along
with you unless you pay me half the fee?
Well, I'll have to take a lawyer
the court appoints.
I got my defense now, right?
Insanity.
I think I'll stick around,
make damn sure you get off.
- Where do we start?
- We're going to need a psychiatrist.
Neither of us has any money. Do you
think the army'll stir one up for you?
I know a colonel in the Pentagon.
I'll write a letter.
Good. Do that. Sulo.
Where are you going now?
I'm going to see your wife,
for one thing.
Why? Didn't you see her yesterday?
That's right. I did.
She's a very pretty woman,
your wife.
A man gets used to
the way his wife looks.
I guess he does.
I'll see you.
Come on in, Paulie.
Come on in.
You haven't been in here
since you vacated, have you?
Hardly recognize the old place, huh?
Mary did it for me. She just finished
her decorators' course.
Smart girl. Very smart girl.
Look at this.
- A real, genuine Picasso print.
- That's very nice.
And here. Try this chair.
It sort of does things for you.
Sit right down.
Great, isn't it?
Good for the nerves, they say.
- How do you shut it off?
- Here.
Here we are. Feel better?
I feel all shook up.
Mitch, I just dropped in to tell you
I've got both feet in the Manion case.
- You're going to cop out, aren't you?
- No.
That's a mistake.
It's open and shut.
Well, maybe. We'll see.
Judge Maitland's still in the hospital.
Maybe you'd like to agree...
to a continuance
until he gets back.
If we go with the case now,
we'll have to try before...
some grab-bag judge they'll send in.
- Me, I'd rather have Maitland.
- So would I.
But that'd also mean my client
would lie around in jail...
for another two, three months
before the trial.
Now, if you'll drop the charge
down to manslaughter...
so I can get him out on bail,
we'll agree to a continuance.
You wouldn't do that
if you were still D.A.
I don't know. I might.
I might, since a big, fat
lie detector test on his wife...
is giving proof to the rape story.
- He'd have the jury with him.
- How did you know what the lie--
- I bit, didn't I?
- Yeah, you did.
Anyway, the result of a lie detector
test isn't admissible evidence.
- You can't use it.
- No, but it carries moral weight.
Mitch, I wouldn't sit
in that chair too much.
It could shake a fellow's brains loose.
I'll see you later.
He remembers you, Paul.
He likes you.
He likes the beer in my icebox.
What's the occasion today.
A buffalo hunt?
I bought these in Arizona
when we were stationed there.
Aren't they smart?
I think they're very smart.
Here, we can sit in my car.
Here you are.
Here you go, Muff.
Several things have occurred to me.
The, uh--
The undergarments
Barney Quill tore off--
Who has them now?
The police?
You mean my panties?
All right. Your panties.
I haven't seen them since.
I gave the torn skirt and sweater
to the police, and then...
I went with them up that lane into
the woods to look for the panties...
but we couldn't find anything
but my glasses.
Your glasses? You mean you were
wearing glasses through all that?
No, I had them
in a case in my hand.
I wear them for reading,
playing pinball, things like that.
I must have tried to get
out of the car and dropped them.
You might be interested to know...
that your lie detector test
turned out in your favor.
Of course it did.
I could've told you it would.
- You weren't worried about it?
- No.
Why should I be?
Would you like to have something
to worry about?
Silly.
Like your husband watching us
from his cell window?
All right.
All right, let's have it.
- Did he say something to you?
-Just enough.
Are you afraid of him?
Is that why you volunteered
for a lie detector test? For him?
Does he have reason to be jealous?
He was jealous
even before we were married.
I should've known how it would be.
It's funny, though.
He likes to show me off.
He likes me to dress
the way I do.
And then he gets furious
if a man pays any attention to me.
I've tried to leave him,
but I can't.
He begs, I give in.
Now, if you think I've forgotten
my question, I haven't.
- I have.
- All right.
Then I'll ask it again.
Does your husband have
any reason to be jealous?
No.
Not once. Not ever.
Hi. Like the place all right?
I was just looking
at these pictures.
- That was Barney Quill, wasn't it?
- That's right. Barney Quill.
- I'm Paul Biegler. I'm--
- I know who you are.
I've seen you around Iron City.
You didn't tell me your name.
Paquette.
We don't open till 5:00.
That's all right.
I can wait.
I don't have the shakes yet.
You were on the job that night,
weren't you...
the night Barney Quill was killed.
Like the newspaper said,
I was present.
You were the fellow who stopped
Lt. Manion outside.
That's right.
He pointed the gun at me and said,
"You want some too, buster?"
And you said no,
because your name isn't buster.
- Wasn't anything funny about it.
- No, there wasn't. I'm sorry.
Where were you when Barney Quill
was killed, Mr. Paquette?
I gather you don't want
to talk about that night, huh?
That's right.
I don't want to talk about it.
You'll have to talk to me
about it in court. Why not now?
'Cause I don't have to now.
Reason enough, okay?
Okay.
Boy, old Barney, he was kind of
a rugged character, wasn't he?
Ex-prizefighter, muscle man,
fancy with guns, and--
He paid his debts.
Ran a clean place.
- Me, I liked him.
- You run the place now?
No, I just work here.
Mary's running things.
Mary? Was that Barney's wife?
No, he didn't have a wife.
Mary was his manager.
Oh. All right.
I wonder who's gonna inherit the place?
- Mary, I guess.
- Mary again.
What's the matter with that?
You mean, what's the matter with Mary?
I don't know what's the matter with her.
Mary what?
Pilant. Mary Pilant.
She's in the back booth.
We don't talk about our customers here.
But if we did--
which we don't--
That's her.
That's Mary Pilant.
- Do you know Lt. Manion's wife?
- Sure. I know the lieutenant too.
He's a good officer.
She's all right too.
Friendly. Good kid.
What do you know about it?
Knock it off.
I didn't mean anything. She's a dish.
What's the matter with that?
Do you want this lawyer
to get wrong ideas?
What chance has the lieutenant got,
Mr. McCarthy?
Pretty good, I'd say, with a couple
of character witnesses like you.
I'd like to help him out. I sure would.
But we're moving out.
The whole outfit . Berlin.
Tell me, who is this babe
at the hotel?
Name's Mary Pilant.
She was Quill's private property.
- Would you like a table, sir?
- Yes, please.
- Will you be alone?
- I'll be joined by two others.
- May I take your hat?
- Thank you very much.
- How was the manicure?
- Ask me any questions about anybody.
- I've got all the dope.
- Can you tell me about Mary Pilant?
Easy. Mary Pilant may
or may not have been...
the mistress of the late B. Quill.
The manicurist is in favor
of the mistress theory...
but the hairdresser's against it.
However, they both agree that some sort
of hanky-panky must have been going on.
- To be continued.
- Menu?
Thank you.
- Pretty, huh?
- Yes, very pretty.
What? What?
Anyway, there's one story
that says that...
Barney's wild night with Mrs. Manion
was somehow...
triggered by Mary Pilant.
Seems she'd been running around with
some soldier, and Barney blew his stack.
- He got tanked up and exploded.
- Is Mary Pilant local?
No, she's a Canadian.
Barney brought her in here...
to sort of dress up the place,
and she stayed on to manage it for him.
- Looks like she's done all right.
- Better than all right.
- She's in for the estate.
- Oh?
She doesn't look like a bad sort,
does she?
Hmm? Where?
What do you mean, " where" ?
The pretty one with the menus.
This girl right here?
Miss Pilant, may I introduce myself?
I'm Paul Biegler,
attorney for Lt. Manion...
and this is Miss Rutledge
and Mr. McCarthy, my associates.
- How do you do.
- Could you sit with us for a minute?
- Yes, I can take a minute.
- Thank you.
I'd like to ask you a few things,
if you don't mind.
What sort of things,
Mr. Biegler?
Well, like what kind of a man
your employer was, Mr. Quill.
- A very nice man.
- If that's true, how do you explain...
what happened with Lt. Manion's wife?
I don't know what happened
with Lt. Manion's wife...
so there really isn't anything
for me to explain, is there?
Your loyalty to the dead Mr. Quill
is very touching, Miss Pilant.
Barney was well liked here
by everyone, Mr. Biegler.
It's very generous of everyone
to overlook his faults...
like raping other men's wives.
If you'll pardon me.
The waitress will take your order
when you're ready.
Nice to have met you,
Mr. Biegler...
Mr. McCarthy, Mrs. Rutledge.
You just drew gin, Lieutenant.
- Twenty.
- Manion?
- Any word, Lieutenant?
- Yeah.
This, from Washington.
They'll let a doctor come and testify,
but there's a string on it.
They want me to go to an army hospital
in Detroit for an examination.
Doesn't the army understand that you're
in jail on a non-bailable offense?
That's it, as far as
the army's concerned.
I don't know how I can get around this.
I'll try and think of something.
Look, my wife hasn't been here
in two days. Have you seen her?
- No, not for a while.
- Where the hell is she?
You've got other things
to worry about, Lieutenant.
I'll get in touch with your wife.
I'll tell her you miss her.
Yeah, you tell her that.
- Thanks, Sulo.
- Okay, Paulie.
I know just how you feel, Lieutenant.
I'd be tearing my hair out too
if I had something like that outside.
Something like what outside?
You know what I mean. Something like
that running around on the loose.
Now, what's the big noise, buckos?
It's me, dummy. I hit my elbow
on this lousy iron bar.
You want some rubbing alcohol maybe?
A little bourbon might help.
Knock it off, buckos.
Let's finish the game, Lieutenant.
Hey, what a crazy lawyer we got.
Hiya, Paulie. That's what
they call you, isn't it? Paulie?
That's a crazy name
for a crazy lawyer.
- Thanks for letting me sit in, Pie-Eye.
- Hey, you're not splitting the scene?
- I mean, you're not cuttin' out?
- No, I'll be back.
Hi, Paulie.
Fellows, this is Manny's lawyer.
- Hi. How are you?
- Sit down, won't you?
I'm sorry, I can't right now.
Mrs. Manion...
may I talk to you
for a moment outside?
Mrs. Manion? I thought we dropped
the formalities a long time ago.
I think maybe we'd better pick 'em
up again. It's important.
- All right. I'll go with you.
- All right. Come on.
Hey. You're coming back,
aren't you?
What do you think?
See you later, Pie-Eye.
Okay.
- Did you get my phone message?
- Yeah, but I got busy.
Why haven't you been
to see your husband?
I don't see why I have
to see him every day.
I think it would be
a very good idea if you did.
All right, I'll see him every day.
Okay?
- No, not okay. Where's your car?
- I came with them.
- Mine's right over here. Come on.
- Wait. I've got friends inside.
- Friends or not, you're going home.
- Who do you think you are?
I'm the lawyer trying to beat a rap
for your husband, remember?
- What's that got to do with--
- You listen to me.
Until this trial's over, you're
going to be a meek little housewife...
with horn-rimmed spectacles...
and you're going to stay away
from men and juke joints...
and booze and pinball machines...
and you're going to wear a skirt
and low-heeled shoes and a girdle.
And especially a girdle.
Look, Laura...
believe me, I don't usually
complain of an attractive jiggle...
but you save that jiggle
for your husband to look at...
if and when
I get him out of jail.
Come on. Let's go.
I'm sorry. I really am. I wouldn't
hurt Manny's chances for anything.
Come on.
Is this about where
Barney knocked you down?
Yeah, right over here.
Over there's the opening in the fence
where Muffy was running...
back and forth with the flashlight.
Where's your trailer?
Up there on the hill.
This is my favorite place.
Sometimes when Manny was sleeping
I'd come out here and just sit.
I had to get out of that trailer.
I couldn't stand being cooped up.
I'm-- I'm lonely, Paul.
I'm awful lonely.
I wouldn't have gone to that roadhouse
if it weren't for that, you know.
Maybe you were getting in
some good practice being lonely.
You mean you think maybe
Manny won't get off?
That'll be up to the jury,
and you can never tell about them.
If he didn't,
it'd be one way to end it.
No, I don't mean that.
I may think it sometimes,
but I don't really want it.
Hello, sweetie.
Did you miss me?
Of course you missed me.
You wanna come in, Paul?
You can if you want to,
you know.
No thank you, Laura.
I'm sorry I had to spoil your fun
over at that place.
Good night, Laura.
Good night.
Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye.
The circuit court for the county
of Iron Cliffs is now in session.
You can be seated.
For those of you I haven't met,
my name is Weaver.
I'm from downstate,
and I'm sitting temporarily...
while your good Judge Maitland
is recovering from a severe illness.
There's no need to dwell
at length upon my methods.
One judge is quite like another.
The only difference is maybe
in the state of their digestions...
or their proclivities
for sleeping on the bench.
For myself,
I can digest pig iron.
And while I might appear
to doze occasionally...
you'll find that
I'm easily awakened...
particularly if shaken gently
by a good lawyer...
with a nice point of law.
We will now take up
the criminal docket.
Case number one--
The People v. Clarence Madigan--
breaking and entering
in the nighttime.
Will the defendant rise
and come forward?
That's me, Your Honor.
State of Michigan,
court of Iron Cliffs...
I, Mitchell Lodwick, prosecuting
attorney, come into Iron Cliffs...
and give the court to understand
that one Clarence Madigan...
alias " One-Shot" Madigan,
alias " Smoky" Madigan...
did break and enter the dwelling house
of Casper Katz...
and did there commit the felony
of larceny on said premises.
Does Mr. Madigan have an attorney?
No. A man's gotta have money to ask
them fellas the time of day.
Mr. Madigan,
if you're impoverished...
it's my duty to appoint an attorney
on your behalf.
I wouldn't bother, Your Honor.
I stole the whisky.
I'm guilty as hell.
It was a full case of
expensive bourbon, Your Honor.
Did you sell this whisky?
No. I drank it.
- All of it?
- You bet,Judge.
Are you aware that it will be
necessary to punish you for this crime?
It was worth it.
Well, I'll accept your plea
of guilty, Mr. Madigan.
You'll be sentenced later.
You may now return to your place.
Thanks, Your Honor.
Case number two--
The People v. Frederick Manion.
The charge-- murder.
Paul Biegler for the defendant.
My formal appearance is already on file.
Which of these men
is your client, Mr. Biegler?
None of them.
Sheriff, will you produce
the prisoner?
Well, I-- I'm afraid
I can't do that, Your Honor.
Perhaps someone should explain.
I'm not clairvoyant.
The defendant is in Detroit
being examined by a psychiatrist.
Shouldn't the court
have been consulted...
before the defendant
was allowed to leave its jurisdiction?
Your Honor, we're dealing
with the army in this matter.
This is the only crack they would
give us at one of their psychiatrists.
The court was not present. It was urgent
we get the defendant to a psychiatrist.
What does the attorney for the people
say to this?
It was done with my knowledge.
I've always heard this Upper Pennisula
of our fair state was a queer place.
If it's customary here to allow a man
charged with first degree murder...
to wander about at will, I don't suppose
it behooves an outsider to point out...
that the law makes no provision
for such quaint liberalism.
The defendant is in the care of a deputy
and will be returned this afternoon.
We'll formally arraign the defendant
on his return.
For the sake of the docket,
can you give me a clue to his plea?
The defendant will waive reading
of the information and stand mute.
A plea of" not guilty"
will be entered.
The case of Frederick Manion will be
placed first on the trial docket.
Can you hurry it up, Paulie?
If somebody tells that judge...
the prisoner was lounging around the
rail station, he'll give me the works.
This will just take a minute.
Come on over here.
Well, Lieutenant,
how'd things turn out?
- I was temporarily insane.
- Did he tell you that?
Yeah. Says he's gonna
write you a letter.
I took some notes on my own.
The doctor's name is Smith.
Anatole Ludwig Smith
or Ludwig von Smith, I hope.
A name like that
would impress the jury.
Just plain Matthew Smith.
He said that when I shot Quill...
I was suffering from
"dissociative reaction."
- Sounds pretty good, doesn't it?
- What does it mean?
It means " I had an irresistible
impulse to shoot Quill."
That's okay, isn't it?
What did he say about your knowing
the difference between right and wrong?
I don't think he said anything.
Why, is that important?
We'd better not keep
the sheriff waiting. You'd better go.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Ever heard of a Michigan court accepting
"irresistible impulse" as insanity?
No. Maybe we'd better
switch to self-defense.
Even Mitch Lodwick would make
a monkey out of us then.
- Damn strawberry soda.
- Want a peanut?
No thanks.
Well, tomorrow's Saturday.
We just have a weekend before the trial.
When do you want to start working?
Tomorrow morning, early.
- Paulie.
- Hey, listen to this, Parn.
Never mind that.
Just find...
People v. Durfee, 622,
Michigan, 486, Year 1 886.
That's it. I have it right here
in the A.L.R. Listen.
" The right and wrong test,
though deemed unscientific ...
is adhered to by most states but--"
Now listen to this " but" --
"but the fact that one accused...
of committing a crime
may have been able to comprehend...
the nature and the consequences
of this act...
and to know that it was wrong.
- Nevertheless--''
- Sweet enduring word " Nevertheless."
" Nevertheless, if he was forced
to its execution...
by an impulse-- by an impulse
which he was powerless to control...
he will be excused from punishment.''
The Michigan Supreme Court
did accept irresistible impulse.
This is precedent.
Boy, I think we've got
a hold of something here.
Good old Durfee, 1 886.
How about that?
Give me a pad.
This strawberry soda is beginning
to taste like real bourbon whisky.
Well, don't get drunk yet.
We've got to convince a jury...
that our client was
irresistibly impulsed.
Remember that.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
before we proceed further...
it will be necessary for me
to examine you on your qualifications...
to sit as jurors.
Will you please remember
that you are under oath?
Are all of you citizens?
Will you please
raise your hand if you are not?
Are there any justices of the peace
or law enforcement officers among you?
No.
Are any of you related
by blood or marriage...
to any law enforcement officer?
So much for qualifications.
I will now examine for cause.
Do any of you have
any business pending...
with the prosecuting attorney,
Mitchell Lodwick?
Do any of you have any business pending
with Paul Biegler...
attorney for the defense?
Are any of you acquainted
with the defendant...
sitting there on Mr. Biegler's left?
Will Mrs. Laura Manion,
the defendant's wife, please stand?
Do any of you know Mrs. Manion?
Thank you, Mrs. Manion.
You may be seated.
Counsel may challenge the jury
for cause.
Before counsel's challenge, may I
introduce Claude Dancer to the court?
Mr. Dancer is an assistant
attorney general from Lansing.
Because of the peculiar nature
of this case...
I requested the attorney general to let
Mr. Dancer sit in with the prosecution.
Your reputation precedes you,
Mr. Dancer.
It's a privilege to have you
in my court.
Thank you.
I'm sure it'll be instructive.
Do any of you have
any business pending...
before the
attorney general's office?
I must apologize for
my disparaging remarks...
about the Upper Pennisula
and its customs.
I've seldom seen a murder jury selected
and sworn in less than half a day.
You have won my heart
completely, gentlemen.
Mr. Dancer, you asked for the recess.
What's your problem?
It was a little suggestion
I wanted to make.
- By all means.
- Since the defense plea is insanity...
the prosecution has retained
a psychiatrist.
Under the statute, we have a right
to petition for a mental exam...
of the defendant
by our own doctor.
- Are you familiar with that statute?
- Uh-huh. Moderately.
I think it would only delay things
to file a formal petition...
so why don't we informally agree
to ask His Honor for an adjournment...
only a day or so, and our doctor
can visit with the defendant.
It would save everyone time.
Don't you think so?
- I'm sure it will.
- Good.
Suppose you just go ahead
and file that formal petition anyway.
Of course, you're a little late.
Maybe His Honor will overlook that.
Then I'd like the jury to see that you
think our insanity plea has some merit.
There really won't be any need
for our doctor to examine your client.
Naturally, I was only following
the usual procedure.
Naturally, I'm all for it.
- Do you wish to file the petition?
- Yes, Your Honor--
- That won't be necessary.
- That's right.
Skirmish over. Shall we join now
on the field of battle?
The body of Quill had sustained
five gunshot wounds.
One of the bullets had passed
through the heart.
Death, in my opinion,
was almost instantaneous...
and was directly caused
by this wound.
Dr. Raschid, may I have
your detailed report?
Certainly.
I ask that this report be marked
People's Exhibit One for identification.
So received and marked.
The people hand the defense
a copy of the report.
Counsel may cross-examine.
Dr. Raschid, your primary purpose
was to ascertain the cause of death.
- Was it not?
- Yes.
And yet I read in your report here
that you checked to determine...
whether spermatogenesis was occurring
in the body of the deceased.
Objection.
The people call this witness
only to show the cause of death.
Your Honor, the entire report
was offered as evidence...
and the report contains this information
about spermatogenesis.
Overruled, Mr. Lodwick.
The witness may answer.
Yes, I made that examination
on the deceased.
And now would you tell
the court your findings.
Spermatogenesis was occurring
at the time of death.
In other words, the deceased in life
was not sterile.
- He could produce children.
- That is correct.
Now, Doctor, if a woman says
that she has had intercourse...
with a certain man
and the man is proved fertile...
even though no evidence
is found in the woman's body...
could a lawyer--
say a prosecuting attorney--
could he use this as evidence
that the woman is lying?
Your Honor, I object
to this line of questioning.
We're not concerned with if there has
been relations with a man and a woman.
As long as an examination
for spermatogenesis has been made...
at least we're entitled
to know why.
Overruled. You may answer.
Yes, prosecution could use that...
though it certainly would not be
conclusive that she was lying.
Why not?
There could be several reasons
why the test on her was negative.
The use of a contraceptive...
or possibly there was no completion
on the part of the man.
Now this postmortem,
were you also asked to determine...
if the deceased had reached a
sexual climax shortly before his death?
-No, sir.
-Could you have made this determination?
Oh, yes.
So, you were only asked to make
such an examination...
that might be useful to the prosecution,
none that might help the defense?
I object, Your Honor.
The question is argumentative.
Counsel is trying to impugn the intent
of the representatives of the people.
Mr. Biegler, you must be aware
that the question is improper.
I withdraw the question
and apologize.
The question and answer
will be stricken...
and the jury will disregard
both the question and the answer.
That's all.
No redirect.
The people now call
Lloyd Burke.
Will the witness
step forward, please?
How can a jury disregard
what it's already heard?
- They can't, Lieutenant.
- Do you solemnly swear...
the testimony you shall give
shall be the truth...
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
- Will you state your profession?
- I'm a commercial photographer.
Were you called upon
by the police...
to take photographs of the body
of the deceased Bernard Quill...
before and after he was removed
from the scene of death?
Yes, sir.
Were these photographs
of the deceased made by you?
They were.
The recorder will please mark
these People's Exhibit 282-D.
Photos are tendered to the defense
for examination.
And the people move their admission
as evidence. Your witness.
No questions. No objections.
Paul, he took pictures
of me that night too.
Just a minute, Mr. Burke.
These photos offered as evidence, are
they the only ones you took that night?
Why, no.
I suppose the others
didn't turn out?
All my pictures turn out.
Of course.
I beg your pardon.
Did you give the other pictures
to the police?
I did.
What were they?
Were they side shots
or a shot of the moon perhaps...
or a black bear scavenging
the Thunder Bay dump?
I object. I can't see how
other photographs are relevant.
The photos were introduced to show
the deceased met with a violent death.
I should think any photo pertaining
to the case would be relevant.
The point is good, Mr. Biegler.
Continue.
What were these
other photographs of?
Lieutenant Manion's wife.
You mean they showed how she looked
after Barney Quill was killed?
- Yes.
- How she looked is irrelevant.
There's no evidence to connect
Mrs. Manion's appearance to this murder.
- Sustained.
- I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make sure prosecution
wasn't withholding evidence.
Now look here!
I protest to the defense attorney's
persistent attacks...
on the motives
of the prosecution.
The jury will disregard the mark
made by the defense attorney.
There's no reason to believe
that the prosecution...
has not acted in good faith.
My apologies to the prosecution
and to the court.
But Your Honor,
as long as protests are being made...
I'd like to make a protest myself.
I'm perfectly willing to take on these
two legal giants anytime, anyplace...
but in all fairness
it ought to be one at a time.
I don't want these two fellas pitching
knuckleballs at me at the same time.
It seems to me you're batting
close to a thousand...
but your point is well taken.
Whichever attorney opens
with the witness...
he alone shall continue with that
witness until the witness is excused.
Thank you, Your Honor.
No more questions.
No questions.
- My, we're drawing well, aren't we?
- Where's Parnell?
Parnell? Isn't he here?
No, he's not here, not in his rooming
house and hasn't been there all night.
You were the last to see him.
Where is he?
- I promised not to tell, so don't ask.
- He hasn't fallen off the wagon?
- No, he was sober.
- Has he gone somewhere?
He did borrow my car
for something or other.
Your car? That was smart.
He hasn't driven a car in 20 years.
He'll kill himself.
Now where's he gone?
My word is my bond.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
You may proceed.
Your Honor...
the defense notices a third person
at the prosecution's table.
We're wondering if the court shares
our curiosity as to just who he is?
I was about to introduce him.
Your Honor, this gentlemen
is Dr. W. Gregory Harcourt.
Dr. Harcourt is the people's
psychiatrist in this case.
We ask that Dr. Harcourt be allowed
to sit at our table as an observer.
What are you going to
have him observe--
the constellation ofTaurus
or the life and times of a bumblebee?
To observe the defendant, of course.
That's fine.
The defense has no objection.
I just wish to express my relief...
that the new recruit is not additional
legal reinforcements from Lansing.
Call Alphonse Paquette.
Raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear the testimony
you give in this case...
shall be the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Take a seat, please.
- Will you state your name?
- Alphonse Paquette.
- You work at the Thunder Bay Inn?
- I'm bartender there.
Were you working the night that Barney
Quill was shot by Frederick Manion?
- I was.
- Were you witness to the shooting?
I was.
Will you tell us in your own words
what happened?
I was at a table by the door
when Lt. Manion came in.
Did you know Lt. Manion
by sight and name?
Go ahead.
Well, he came in and walked
over to the bar and began to shoot.
He shot Barney when he came
up to the bar...
and when Barney fell he kept on shooting
at Barney behind the bar.
Then he turned around and walked out.
When Lt. Manion entered the bar,
how did he appear to you?
Well, he walked slow, kind of deliberate
I guess you could say.
Did he speak to Barney Quill?
Not a word.Just walked over
and pulled out his gun...
and bang.
- And then he walked out?
- Yes.
When he walked out,
how did he appear to you?
He seemed just like he did
when he walked in--
like he was the mailman
delivering the mail.
When Lt. Manion walked
out of the bar, what did you do?
Well, it happened so fast,
I guess I was stunned.
- But then I ran out after him.
- Did you find him outside?
- Yes, sir. He was walking away.
- Did you speak to him?
Yes, sir. I said, " Lieutenant,
you'd better not run away from this."
Did he reply to you?
He said,
"Do you want some too, buster?"
Was he pointing the gun at you?
He was holding the gun in my direction,
but the muzzle was low.
When he said,
"Do you want some too, buster?" ...
how was that expressed?
Did he shout it?
Was it hysterical?
Was he hoarse?
Did his voice tremble?
No, sir. He just said it
cool and hard and looked right at me.
Did he appear to you,
as far as you could tell...
to be in complete possession
of his faculties?
- Yes, sir, as far as I could tell.
- Your witness.
Mr. Paquette, did you see Laura Manion
in the bar that night?
There he goes again.
This is immaterial and irrelevant.
I don't see why the prosecution's
so jumpy. I haven't gone anyplace yet.
Let's see where he's going
before we start objecting.
You may proceed.
Did you see Mrs. Manion
in the bar that night?
- She was there.
- Did Barney Quill leave that night?
- Yes.
- Do you remember when he returned?
I think he came back around midnight.
Now from which entrance did he come?
Did he come from the lobby entrance...
or come from that outside entrance?
It was from the lobby.
- And how did he appear to you then?
- How do you mean?
You understood the prosecution well
when he asked you that question...
about Lt. Manion's appearance.
Oh, well, he was just
old Barney, like usual.
You mean he was just good old sober,
reliable, gentle...
salt-of-the-earth,
friend-to-man Barney.
Your Honor, what kind
of a question is that?
I withdraw the question, Your Honor.
Had Barney changed his clothes
since he left the bar?
I don't remember.
Might his clothing have been different
when he returned--
that is, might he
have changed his clothes?
I didn't notice.
Was Barney drinking that night?
Well, he always had a few shots
while he was talking to the customers.
- He's friendly.
- Oh, sure, he was. Good old Barney.
Now how many shots would you say
good old Barney usually had?
I don't know.
Wasn't he in fact pretty loaded
that night?
Objection. Even if the deceased
was dead drunk...
it's no defense to this charge.
Sustained.
I suggest you get off this.
What would you call a man with
an insatiable penchant for women?
A what?
A penchant, a desire,
taste, passion.
Well, a ladies man, I guess.
Or maybe just a damn fool.
Just answer the questions.
The attorneys will provide
the wisecracks.
Well, what else would you call
a man like that?
- We can't see the drift of this.
- You mean you do see.
You may answer.
Can you think of another name?
Woman chaser.
- Try again.
- Masher?
Oh, come now.
Mashers went out with whalebone corsets
and hairnets.
Did you ever hear
the expression " wolf" ?
Sure, I heard that.
It just slipped my mind.
Well, naturally, it would...
clanking around in there
with all those rusty old " mashers."
Have you ever known a man
you could call a wolf?
- I'm not sure.
- Was Barney Quill a wolf?
- I couldn't say.
- Or wouldn't?
- Objection.
- Sustained.
The question was answered.
He said he couldn't tell you.
Mr. Paquette, when Barney returned
from wherever he had gone...
- did he relieve you at the bar?
- Yes.
- And what did he say then?
- He said, " I'll take over."
When you came out from behind the bar,
where did you go?
I went over to the table
where the Pedersons were sitting.
Now you testified that you were
by the door when Lt. Manion came in.
Is that the reason you were by the door,
because the Pedersons' table was there?
Yes.
And how long was it
before Lt. Manion came in?
I don't know exactly.
Maybe 30 minutes.
And you remained at
the Pedersons' table all that time?
- Yes, they're friends of mine.
- Is there a window beside that table?
- I think so.
- You think so.
How long have you worked
at the Thunder Bay Inn?
About six, seven years.
Does this window beside the table...
suddenly vanish and reappear and
come and go in a ghostly fashion?
It's there all the time.
While you were talking to your friends
there, did you look out of the window?
-I might have.
-Were you looking for something special?
No, I wasn't looking for anything.
Didn't Barney Quill tell you to go to
that window and look out for Lt. Manion?
Did he tell you to look out
for Lt. Manion?
He did not.
Barney was quite a marksmen,
wasn't he, with guns?
He won a lot of prizes.
Did he keep any guns
behind the bar?
He might have.
Isn't it a fact there are three
concealed pistol racks behind the bar?
The defendant's plea is one of insanity,
not self-defense.
I'm sure Mr. Biegler hasn't forgotten
that fact, Mr. Lodwick.
You may answer.
Are there concealed gun racks
behind the bar?
Yes.
And how many people know
about these gun racks?
- I couldn't say.
- Isn't it a fact...
that Barney would take the guns out
of the racks and twirl them...
to demonstrate his skill
to the patrons?
- I don't remember.
- Come on.
Try and remember.
Did you ever see him do that yourself?
- Once or twice he did.
- That's all.
- No further questions.
- The witness may step down.
Call George Lemon.
Biegler's going off
in all directions.
What's he getting at?
I have a feeling he's afraid
of what we'll get at.
Mr. Biegler's putting up
a smoke screen for some reason.
- I do.
- Take a seat please.
- Will you state your name, please?
- George Lemon.
What kind of work do you do?
I'm caretaker of the tourist park
in Thunder Bay.
I see the place is clean
and orderly.
I check people in and out
and lock the gate at night.
And what is your authority
for these duties?
I'm paid by Madison Township
and I'm also a deputy sheriff.
Just courtesy, sort of.
Did you see Lt. Manion
on the night of the 1 5th?
- The night Barney Quill was killed?
- Yes, sir.
Will you tell the court
about how and when...
you saw Lt. Manion.
About 1 :00 a.m. a knock on my door
waked me up.
I went to the door and Lt. Manion
was standing there.
He said, " You better take me, Mr. Lemon,
because I just shot Barney Quill."
I told him to go back to his trailer
and that I would call the state police.
How did Lt. Manion appear to you
when he asked you to take him?
He said what he had to say
and did what I told him. No fuss.
Did he appear to you to be--
as far as you could tell--
in complete possession
of his faculties?
As far as I could tell,
yes, sir.
Take the witness.
Mr. Lemon, did you go
to the Manions' trailer?
-Yes, sir.
-Did you see Mrs. Manion at the trailer?
- Yes, sir.
- What was her appearance?
She was a mess.
Objection.
No evidence has been introduced to make
Mrs. Manion's appearance relevant.
Barney Quill's appearance relevant...
but you didn't object
to the question then.
Is that because you know Barney Quill
bathed and changed...
after he raped and beat hell
out of this poor woman?
Your Honor, everybody in this court
is being tried except Mr. Manion.
Now listen, this is a cross-examination
murder case, not a high school debate!
What are you trying to do,
railroad this soldier into the clink?
Mr. Biegler, you are
an experienced attorney...
and you know better
than to make such an outburst.
I will not tolerate intemperance
of this sort.
If you once again try the patience
of this court...
I shall hold you in contempt.
Sorry.
Your Honor...
I apologize and
it won't happen again.
The witness's answer
will be stricken...
and the jury will disregard
the answer.
Now you may proceed,
Mr. Biegler.
Yes, sir.
On the night when Lt. Manion
awakened you and turned himself in...
had you been awakened before-- had
anything else disturbed your slumbers?
- No, sir.
- There were no soldiers singing?
No, sir. Not in my park
after 1 0:00.
- There were no women screaming?
- Those screams were down by the gate.
Objection!
I see no reason for objecting yet.
Tell us about those screams.
I didn't hear them myself. There were
tourists from Ohio in the park...
and they heard them
and told me about it the next day.
- Now, Mr. Lodwick.
- This testimony is incompetent...
hearsay, irrelevant,
immaterial, inconclusive--
Well, that's too much for me.
The witness is yours, Mr. Lodwick.
Huh?
No questions.
The witness may step down.
Call your next witness.
Detective SergeantJames Durgo.
- Hi, Paulie.
- Hi,Jim. Come here.
As soon as we break, you'd better phone
that army psychiatrist.
-Tell him to be here day after tomorrow.
-Will do.
Will you please tell me
where Parnell has gone?
Won't do.
Well, you're fired.
You can't fire me
till you pay me.
Detective SergeantJames Durgo
of the state police.
Were you called to Thunder Bay by
Deputy Sheriff Lemon ofThunder Bay...
on the night Barney Quill
was killed?
Yes, sir. My companion officer and I
were the first to be called in.
When you arrived at the Manion trailer,
who was there?
Lt. Manion and his wife were there.
What did Lt. Manion say to you?
He said that his wife had had
some trouble with Barney Quill.
He had gone to the tavern
and shot Quill.
He asked us whether Quill was dead
or not. We told him he was.
How did Lt. Manion
take this information?
He didn't seem surprised.
What did you do then?
I asked for the gun he'd used.
Did you take Lt. Manion to the county
jail here in Iron City that same night?
Yes, sir. We drove the Lieutenant
down with his wife.
On the drive to Iron City, did Manion
talk further about the shooting?
He remarked that if he had the whole
thing to do over, he'd still do it.
During all this, at the trailer,
the drive to Iron City...
how did Lt. Manion appear to you?
He was very quiet most of the time.
Seemed clearheaded.
Would you say he was in complete
possession of his faculties?
- Seemed so to me.
- Your witness.
Sergeant Durgo, you testified
that Lt. Manion told you...
he shot Barney Quill after he learned
his wife had some trouble with Quill.
Were these the words Lt. Manion
used, " some trouble" ?
No, sir. Those were my words,
not his.
And was it your notion to come here
and use your own words?
No, sir.
And was the suggestion to call it
"some trouble" ...
made by somebody here
in the courtroom?
Yes, sir.
Sergeant, would you tell the court
what words Lt. Manion actually used...
to describe the trouble
his wife had had.
Objection.
We've been over this before.
This information would not be relevant
to any issues before the court.
This statement concerning some trouble
was brought out...
during the direct examination
of Sergeant Durgo.
Up to now, you've adroitly restricted
all testimony...
as far as Laura Manion's concerned.
All right, the cat's out of the bag.
It's fair game for me to chase it.
This is a sore point, Mr. Biegler,
and it's getting sorer.
I'd like to hear
from the prosecution.
Burden is on defense to prove temporary
insanity at the time of the shooting.
Now, if the reason for the alleged
insanity is important to this case...
then that is a matter
for a competent witness--
an expert on the subject
of the human mind.
What the defense is trying to do...
is introduce
some sensational material...
for the purposes of obscuring
the real issues.
How can the jury accurately estimate
the testimony being given here...
unless they first know the reason
behind this whole trial--
why Lt. Manion shot Barney Quill?
The prosecution would like to separate
the motive from the act.
That's like trying to take the core
from an apple without breaking the skin.
Now the core of our defense is that
the defendant's temporary insanity...
was triggered by the so-called trouble
with Quill.
And I beg the court--
I-- I beg the court
to let me cut into the apple.
Our objection still stands,
Your Honor.
Objection overruled.
Sergeant Durgo,
tell the court...
how Lt. Manion described
the trouble his wife had with Quill.
He told us that Quill
had raped his wife.
Now, can you recall generally what
Lt. Manion told you about this rape?
Yes, sir. He said he'd been asleep
right after dinner.
He was waked up by some noise--
screams he thought.
He got up, opened the trailer door
and went outside.
His wife came running out of the dark
and fell into his arms.
As you saw his wife in the trailer,
how did she look?
She was a little hysterical.
She'd been pretty badly beaten up.
She had big black bruises
all over her face and arms.
Did Mrs. Manion tell you
about this rape and beating?
- She did.
- Did she take you to where it happened?
Yes, the next morning.
Did you find anything there pertaining
to the story Mrs. Manion told you?
On the lane in the woods we found
some tire tracks and some dog tracks...
and a leather case with
some horn-rimmed glasses inside.
We also looked for...
a certain undergarment of Mrs. Manion's,
but we didn't find it.
Will the attorneys for both sides
approach the bench?
Mr. Biegler, you've finally got
your rape into the case.
I think all the details should now
be made clear to the jury.
- Do you agree, Mr. Lodwick?
- Absolutely.
What exactly was the undergarment
just referred to?
Panties, Your Honor.
- Do you expect this to come up again?
- Yes, sir.
There's a certain light connotation
attached to the word " panties."
Can we find another name for them?
I never heard my wife
call them anything else.
- Mr. Biegler.
- I'm a bachelor, Your Honor.
That's a great help.
Mr. Dancer?
I was overseas during the war.
I learned a French word.
I'm afraid that might be
slightly suggestive.
Most French words are.
All right, gentlemen,
back to your places.
For the benefit of the jury, but more
especially for the spectators...
the undergarment referred to
in the testimony was, to be exact...
Mrs. Manion's panties.
I wanted you to get your snickering
over and done with.
This pair of panties will be mentioned
again in the course of this trial.
And when it happens, there will not be
one laugh, one snicker...
one giggle or even one smirk
in my courtroom.
There isn't anything comic
about a pair of panties...
which figure in the violent death
of one man...
and the possible incarceration
of another.
Proceed, Mr. Biegler.
Did you give Mrs. Manion
a lie detector test?
Objection. A polygraph test is
inadmissible evidence in our courts.
I only asked if he gave the test.
I didn't ask the results.
He may answer that.
I gave her a lie detector test
at her request.
Now after all this investigation,
did you believe Mrs. Manion?
- I did.
- Even after the lie detector test?
That question constitutes flagrant
subterfuge on part of the defense.
Objection sustained.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
a polygraph or lie detector test...
is not admissible in evidence...
because no one
has ever been quite sure...
that some people couldn't lie
to a lie detector and get away with it.
Go ahead.
In any case, you yourself
in your own heart and mind...
are quite convinced
of Mrs. Manion's honesty?
- Yes, sir.
- That's all.
Just a moment.
Did you look for the panties elsewhere
other than the lane in the woods?
We looked in Barney Quill's car,
his room in the hotel.
We didn't find them.
Do you know why Mrs. Manion
requested a lie detector test?
- I know what she said.
- What?
She wanted everyone to believe her story
because she knew it'd help her husband.
Was that the only reason she gave?
Said she swore to her husband. Said she
wanted everyone else to believe it too.
One moment, please.
Ask him in what manner she swore.
Did Mrs. Manion say how
she had sworn to her husband?
Yes, sir. She said
she had sworn on a rosary.
This lane in the woods,
what's it used for, where does it go?
It used to be a logging road.
It doesn't go anyplace,just stops.
Who uses it now?
I think it's a road
kids drive down to park.
- You mean it's a lovers' lane?
- I think so.
- The witness is yours.
- No more questions.
- The witness may step down.
- In view of evidence concerning rape...
which Your Honor
has ruled admissible...
the prosecution asks for
a 30-minute recess...
in order to bring in another witness
we had not anticipated using?
All right.
We'll take a 30-minute recess.
Recess.
Why didn't you tell me
about that rosary?
I forgot it.
We didn't forget it. Manny said maybe
we shouldn't tell that again.
It might have looked like something
else-- like I didn't believe her.
- How much more didn't you tell me?
- We told you everything else.
Is that right, Laura?
Oh, yes, everything else.
Now get this, both of you.
When you get up on that stand,
I want you to tell the truth.
I don't want you to tell anything
but the truth.
Don't try and lie or conceal anything
or you get skinned alive.
This fellow Dancer's gonna move in.
Dr. Dompierre, did you have occasion
to come to the county jail...
on the night of August 1 5 this year?
- I did.
- Who called you to the jail?
- The police authorities.
- What did they want you to do?
They wanted me to make a test
for the presence of sperm...
on the person
of a Mrs. Frederick Manion.
- I made the test.
- What was your conclusion?
- Negative. There was none.
- Your witness.
In making these tests, did you notice
any bruises or marks on Mrs. Manion?
I did.
Were you asked to determine
the reason for these bruises?
- I was not.
- Where did you do the lab work?
St. Margaret's Hospital
in the city.
- Who worked up the slides for you?
- Technician at the hospital.
Wouldn't it have been better...
to have these slides worked up by
a pathologist or expert in this field?
Yes, but the police
were in a hurry.
I happened to know this young fella
came on at 7:00 in the morning.
Wouldn't it have been especially better
to wait for the expert...
if the possible question of rape
hung on the result?
- It would have been.
- In the newspaper of August 1 6...
it was stated that you found
no evidence of rape, is that true?
It is not true.
I made no such statement.
But did you form an opinion as to
whether Mrs. Manion had been raped?
- No.
- Why didn't you form an opinion?
It's impossible to tell if a mature
married woman has been raped.
That's all.
Did you have an opinion about whether
she had any recent relations with a man?
Well, as far as no sperm
was present...
it didn't appear she had
a recent relation with a man.
- That's all.
-Just one more question, Doctor.
The fact that no evidence was present
in her body...
does not mean that
she was not raped, does it?
No.
Do you know what constitutes rape
under the law?
Yes, sir.
Violation is sufficient for rape.
There need not be a completion.
- No further questions.
- The witness may step down.
The people recall Alphonse Paquette
to the stand.
Since counsel for the defense
has forced the question of rape...
it becomes necessary to take this
additional testimony from Mr. Paquette.
You're still under oath, Mr. Paquette.
Mr. Paquette...
would you take a look at Mrs. Manion
seated there behind the defense table.
Was she dressed in this manner
the night of the shooting?
- No.
- How was she dressed?
She had on a real tight skirt and
sweater kind of thing, sort of glued on.
She was wearing red shoes
with high heels.
- Was she wearing hose?
- No, she was bare-legged.
- Was she wearing a hat?
- No.
What kind of hair does Mrs. Manion
have under that hat?
We'd be very happy to show the court
Mrs. Manion's hair.
Mrs. Manion, would you
take off your hat, please?
Thank you, Mr. Biegler.
Was she wearing glasses
that night?
I think she was
when she played pinball.
Considering the tight skirt and
the tight sweater and the bare legs...
what was the result
in her appearance?
Would you say her appearance was
deliberately voluptuous and enticing?
You could see everything she had.
The defense will concede that
Mrs. Manion when dressed informally...
is an astonishingly beautiful woman
and we--
Mrs. Manion, stand up, please,
will you?
As a matter of fact--
Take your glasses off.
It's pretty easy to understand why her
husband became temporarily deranged...
when he saw such beauty bruised
and torn by a beast!
Your Honor, I protest.
Mr. Biegler is perhaps
the least disciplined...
and the most completely out of order
attorney I've ever seen in a courtroom.
The jury will ignore
Mr. Biegler's oration.
Was Mrs. Manion drinking heavily
that night?
I sold her six drinks myself and
Barney came over and got more for her.
- I don't remember how many.
- Would you say she was tight?
-She was high, all right.
-What did she do to make you think that?
She took off her shoes
and went barefooted.
When she played pinball, she'd swish
around to give the machine English.
You mean she was flipping
her hips around?
- Yeah.
- Anything else?
When she made a good score, she jumped
up and down and squealed like women do.
She was playing pinball
with Barney Quill that night.
- Wasn't she?
- Yes.
What was her attitude
toward Barney Quill?
- Friendly.
- More than friendly, would you say?
- I thought so.
- Why did you think so?
She'd kind of lean on him.
A couple of times she bumped him
with her hip.
Would you say that Mrs. Manion
was making a play for Barney Quill?
Objection. That calls for an assumption
on the part of the witness.
I withdraw the question.
Would you say...
Mrs. Manion was free and easy
with Barney Quill?
- I would.
- Your witness.
Mr. Paquette...
the attorney for the people
asked you if Mrs. Manion was " tight" ...
and you said
that she was " high."
Now, speaking as a bartender,
what's the distinction between the two?
- I don't understand.
- When we say a person's " tight" ...
we usually mean they're a little stupid
with the drink, isn't that so?
I guess so.
And if they're " high"
they're gay and enjoying themselves.
In other words,
Mrs. Manion was happy.
Is there anything wrong with being happy
in Thunder Bay Inn?
No.
Thunder Bay itself is a resort,
isn't it?
- Swimming, fishing, that sort of thing.
- Yes.
Is there anything unusual about seeing
a barefooted woman in Thunder Bay?
No.
So Mrs. Manion's taking her shoes off
in Thunder Bay...
that doesn't mean
she's being unladylike, does it?
- I guess not.
- Yes or no?
No!
Now, you testified that
Mrs. Manion was squealing...
and jumping up and down...
and swishing her-- I think that
was the expression you used--
swishing her hips
around the pinball machine.
Now, was she creating a disturbance?
Was she attracting a crowd?
Were the men at the bar all
standing around watching Mrs. Manion?
- No.
- But you were very conscious of her.
Conscious enough so that you can tell us
all about her actions?
- Yes.
- And certainly Barney Quill...
he was conscious of her because
he was playing pinball with her, right?
So it seems that only you
and Barney Quill were acutely aware...
of Mrs. Manion and her actions
and her appearance.
Maybe good old Barney when he came up
to get some drinks from you...
maybe he winked and said, " Alphonse,
I'm gonna take this babe and rape her."
- No, he didn't.
- Maybe you said...
" Do it once for me, boss."
Objection.
No more questions!
The court's had about all of this
dogfight it can take for one day.
And I'm sure the jury
is equally tired and hungry.
Tomorrow the defense takes over
and with expedition, prayer...
and a little self-discipline
on the part of counsel...
perhaps we can reach an end
by Saturday night.
Will you adjourn court?
Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye.
This court stands adjourned
until 9:00 tomorrow morning.
He's banged up a little, but there
doesn't seem to be anything else.
We'd like to watch him
for a day or so.
How much damage did he do?
Wrecked a gate and a barn door.
He hasn't got a driver's license.
He'll have to appear
in theJ.P. court when he's able...
the old fool.
Speak kindly of the dead.
Mind if I have a minute
with the corpse?
Sure.
Now, was it worth trying
to kill yourself...
for whatever it is
you've been up to?
How is the trial going?
I'm making a lot of noise
and Dancer's racking up all the points.
But come on.
Where have you been?
Quill hired Mary Pilant up north
of Sault St. Marie.
Struck me funny he'd go all the way up
there to hire somebody to work for him.
I've been up there nosing around.
Did you find anything useful?
Not until I looked up
her birth certificate.
Born Blind River, Ontario, 1 934...
out of wedlock.
Mother was a waitress,
Simone Pilant.
Father was a lumberjack
named Barney Quill.
- I'd like to see Miss Mary Pilant.
- It's late, mister.
I know. This is important.
- Real important?
- Real important.
- Yes?
- Miss Pilant, sorry if I woke you.
There's a guy to see you.
Says it's real important.
- What's your--
- Paul Biegler.
- I don't wish to see him.
- Okay.
She said it's not important enough.
Call her back and tell her I mentioned
Blind River, Ontario.
I'll be in the bar.
Good evening, Alphonse.
Drinking or just snooping?
I think I'll try a little of both.
What do you say we start with a beer.
On the house.
And that's all you get-- a beer.
No questions, no answers.
I'm just a lawyer
trying to do my job.
What are you so afraid of?
Let's sit over there, please.
Miss Pilant, I owe you an apology.
I was rough when I was here before.
I didn't know Barney Quill
was your father.
You didn't come here
just to apologize.
No, but the apology was part of it.
To tell you the truth, I was hoping
it would thaw you out a little bit.
All I want you to do is listen to me,
just for a few minutes.
I need some strong evidence to back up
Laura Manion's story about the rape.
The prosecution's gonna attack
that story pretty hard.
And if the jury thinks she's lying...
that could turn the decision
against Manion.
Isn't she lying?
Barney didn't do what she said he did.
He couldn't have.
- What did you know about your father?
- All I needed to know.
He took care of me and my mother
for as long as she lived.
He was always there
when I needed him.
That's what I know about my father,
Mr. Biegler.
Will that back up
Laura Manion's story?
I don't want to get at you,
hurt you.
I appreciate your affection
for your father.
But as a lawyer I've had to learn
that people aren't just good or bad...
but people are many things.
And I kind of have a feeling
Barney Quill was many things.
- I don't want to hear any more.
- No, please. Hear me out.
I believe that Barney told Al Paquette
what happened that night.
And he told him to go to this window
and wait for Manion.
Barney stayed behind the bar
next to a gun rack,just waiting.
Manion came in and fired
the minute he got inside that door...
and the first shot
went right through Barney's heart.
Now here's what I want you to do.
I want you to try to persuade Al
to come to the court...
as a defense witness and tell the court
what Barney told him that night--
that he raped and assaulted
Mrs. Manion.
Al wouldn't conceal a thing like that.
Why wouldn't he tell it if it were true?
I don't know.
But I know this.
Everybody loves something
or someone.
Me, I love fishing
and an old guy by the name of Parnell.
Manion loves his freedom.
He'd like to have a little more of it.
Barney loved you.
Maybe so does Al.
I wouldn't blame him.
But he doesn't want to hurt you or
for you to know the truth about Barney--
that he could be dangerous
and brutal.
Now, if you just ask Al--
if you just ask him right straight out.
Al, Mr. Biegler knows
that Barney was my father.
He thinks you know something
about the night my father was killed--
something you won't tell.
Lawyer, I told you once and I'll tell
you again-- No questions, no answers.
Wait.
Did my father rape Mrs. Manion?
Barney wouldn't hurt a woman.
Is there any reason you wouldn't
tell me the truth about that?
What reason?
Anything else?
I'm going to leave a pass
for you and Al at the trial.
You might like to watch
Lt. Manion get convicted.
You going to spread it around
about Mary being Barney's kid?
No, I'm not going to spread it
around, Al. Thank you for the beer.
Good night, Miss Pilant.
All right. Let's get at
this rosary thing.
It's been testified that your wife
swore to you on a rosary...
that she'd been raped
by Barney Quill.
Did you ask your wife
to swear on a rosary?
My wife was hysterical.
She wasn't making much sense.
I thought if I asked her to take
an oath on a rosary...
it might serve to calm her,
make her think more clearly.
Did the rosary help?
She was able to tell me
in detail what had happened.
All right. Go on from there.
What did you do then, Lieutenant?
Well, I--
I had her lie on the bed,
and I got some cold cloths...
for her head.
And, uh--
Oh, yes. I gave her a drink of brandy.
After a while, she became calm,
seemed to go to sleep.
Then I went to the closet...
I got my gun,
and I loaded it.
Was it in your mind
to kill Barney Quill?
No.
Then why did you go to the closet
and get your gun and load it?
I knew I had to go to Quill's place.
I thought I might need it.
Why?
I knew Mr. Quill kept guns
behind the bar.
I was afraid he might shoot me.
Might shoot you if you did what?
What were you going to do?
I'm not sure.
I remember having some idea...
of finding him...
and holding him
while I call the police.
Well, that Mr. Whatshisname--
Mr. Lemon at the tourist court there,
he was a deputy sheriff.
Why didn't you get him
to go with you?
Maybe because he always
seemed to be just...
the old caretaker of the park.
Maybe because I wasn't thinking
about anything too clearly...
except finding Barney Quill.
Why didn't you go to a phone, call
the police before you went to the bar?
I don't know.
I was in sort of a daze.
It was a horrible thing to see
what had been done to my wife.
Now, you say you were in
sort of a daze.
When you got to the bar,
did you see that the bar was crowded?
I didn't see anyone at the bar...
except Barney Quill.
- He was the only person I saw.
- What was he doing?
I think he was just standing there
behind the bar.
Now, did he make a threatening move
to get a gun?
I don't know.
May have. I don't know.
All right. Now, you say
you went there to find him...
to hold him for the police.
Why did you shoot him?
I don't remember shooting him.
Now, when you left the bar,
do you remember Alphonse Paquette...
coming up to you
and stopping you and saying...
" You'd better not run away from this,"
and you replied...
" You want some too, buster?"
Remember that?
I seem to have a vague recollection
of somebody speaking to me...
but I don't remember what I said
or what was said to me.
When did you realize
that you'd shot Quill?
I was getting a drink of water.
I remember my throat was so dry
it hurt.
And when I put the glass down,
I saw the gun on the kitchen sink...
beside the tap.
I noticed the gun was empty.
Now, I'd like you to show
the court and jury...
just how you knew
this gun was empty.
Well, this gadget here...
when it sticks up,
you know the last round's been fired.
On the night of the shooting,
did you love your wife?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you still love her?
Very much.
The witness is yours, Mr. Dancer.
How many men have you killed?
Now, wait a minute!
Your Honor, a man's war record--
in Lt. Manion's case, a great record--
certainly shouldn't be used
against him.
I'm as patriotic as the next man...
but the simple truth is,
war can condition a man...
to killing other men.
I simply want to determine
how conditioned the lieutenant may be...
to the use of firearms
on other human beings.
I don't like the question, Mr. Biegler,
but I don't see how I can exclude it.
Let him answer.
I know I killed
at least four men in Korea--
three with a hand grenade...
and one with my service automatic.
I may have killed others.
A soldier doesn't always know.
Now, Lieutenant,
in these acts of killing...
did you ever have a lapse of memory such
as you had when you killed Barney Quill?
- No, sir.
- Did you ever have one during battle?
- Were you ever submitted...
to a constant barrage,
constantly in a sweat for many hours...
- constantly under attack or attacking?
- Many times.
Were you ever treated for shell shock,
battle fatigue, neuroses or psychoses?
- No, sir.
- Did you ever experience...
any unusual mental state
during the war?
Well, I do remember having
one great urge.
- What was that?
- To get the hell out and go home.
You would do well to consider
the seriousness...
of the situation you're in.
- I'm sorry, Your Honor.
- I sympathize with the lieutenant.
I expect he has the same feeling
about getting out of jail.
But the main point here
is that at no time...
during your war service did you have
a record of mental disturbance.
You were always in complete possession
of your faculties.
Yes, sir. That's right.
- No more questions.
- No redirect, Your Honor.
Step down, please.
Call your next witness.
We call Laura Manion
to the stand.
- Up these stairs and to the right.
- Thanks.
How long after you told
your husband what had happened...
did he leave the trailer?
I don't know exactly.
Everything was kind of fuzzy.
I was faint,
and I laid down on the bed.
He sat beside me.
I vaguely remember
his getting up and going out.
I remember wondering
if he was going for a doctor...
and then he came back in.
It seemed like just a few seconds,
but it must have been longer.
I must've gone to sleep.
When he came back in,
he sat on the bed...
and he had a gun in his hand.
And I said, " What are you going to do?"
And he said,
"I think I've already done it.
I think I've killed Barney Quill.''
Are you sure he didn't say,
"I've killed Barney Quill" ?
No, I remember distinctly.
" I think I've killed Barney Quill."
Then what did you do?
I put my arms around him
and began to cry...
and I said,
"You'd better go to Mr. Lemon."
And my husband said,
"I forgot about that."
What did he mean?
Forgot about what?
He meant he'd forgotten
Mr. Lemon was a deputy sheriff.
And he said, " Yes,
I'll go turn myself in to Mr. Lemon."
Yes, I see.
Your Honor, I have no other
direct questions at this time.
But since I'm sure it's difficult
to visualize the part...
a little dog played on this night...
I should like a few minutes to show
the court this remarkable little animal.
Do the people object?
I'm sure that if we raise
an objection, Your Honor...
Mr. Biegler will declare that we are
haters of all small, furry animals.
A creature that cannot talk
will be a welcome relief.
Bring in the dog.
Thank you, sir. Will the deputy
bring in the dog, please?
You can put him right there.
Hey, Muff! Come on!
That's a boy.
And now I'll ask Mrs. Manion
to bring a flashlight for the dog.
I'll ask the court to notice
that the dog turned on the light.
It's easy to see that Muff doesn't know
who his enemies are.
- Remove the dog, please.
- Yes, sir.
- The witness will resume the stand.
- There we go, Muff.
May I congratulate you
on your well trained pet.
May I also say I'm pleased to see
you're not today...
hiding your lovely hair
under a hat.
Your Honor, is the assistant attorney
general from Lansing pitching woo...
- or is he going to cross-examine?
- Let's get on with it.
Mrs. Manion, what was your occupation
before you were married?
- Housewife.
- Then you've been married before?
- Yes, once.
- I suppose your first husband died?
No.
Did you divorce your first husband
to marry Lt. Manion?
Your Honor, if counsel wants
to know the grounds...
for Mrs. Manion's divorce,
let him ask that question.
What were the grounds
for divorce?
- Mental cruelty.
- Naturally. And how long after...
your divorce was it
that you married Lt. Manion?
I'm not sure.
May I refresh the witness' memory
for Mr. Dancer?
- By all means.
- I believe she told me...
that they were married
three days after the divorce.
Thank you, Mr. Biegler.
Is that correct, Mrs. Manion?
Then unless yours was
a whirlwind courtship...
you must have known Lt. Manion
before your divorce.
- Did you?
- Yes.
Mrs. Manion, what is your...
religious affiliation?
- I'm a Catholic.
- Catholic in good standing?
Well, no. The divorce, you know.
You mean you were excommunicated
because of the divorce and remarriage.
Yes.
Mrs. Manion, wouldn't you say
that a Catholic...
who can blithely ignore one of
the cardinal rules of her church...
could also easily ignore an oath
taken on one of its artifacts...
say, an oath taken on a rosary?
I don't think that's true.
Wouldn't you think there'd be some doubt
about the integrity of such a person?
I don't know.
All I know is the rosary
means something to me.
I see.
Well, I'll pass on to something else.
Mrs. Manion, you testified
that your husband...
came home late from his work
on the night of the shooting.
Were you a little angry
about his being late?
- I guess I was a little put out.
- Did you have an argument?
Not much. A little.
When you left the trailer
to go to the inn...
- did your husband know you were going?
- He was asleep.
Was part of your reason for going
without his knowledge...
because you were vexed?
Well, I'd been ironing all day,
and I--
- Yes, I guess that's true.
- Your Honor, the counsel...
has deliberately
cut off my view of the witness.
I'm sorry, Mr. Biegler. I wouldn't want
to interfere with your signals to her.
I object to the implication
I was signaling the witness.
This is the shabbiest courtroom trick
I've ever seen.
- You haven't lived, Mr. Biegler.
- I ask for a rule on my objection.
Mr. Dancer, will you be careful
not to place yourself...
between Mr. Biegler and his witness?
Of course, Your Honor.
- Anything else, Mr. Biegler?
- You do it once more...
I'll punch you all the way out
into the middle of Lake Superior.
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
This rowing has got to stop.
The next one of you that speaks
out of turn will have me to deal with.
Get on with your cross-examination.
Would you have gone to the inn
if your husband had been awake?
- He probably would have gone with me.
- But would you have gone alone?
- Not if he didn't want me to.
- Would he have not wanted you to?
I'm not sure.
I don't know how to answer that.
Had you ever gone
to the Thunder Bay Inn, or...
elsewhere in Thunder Bay alone
at night?
- Yes, sometimes.
- Did your husband know you were going?
Not always.
He goes to sleep early...
and sometimes I'm restless.
- Where did you go on these occasions?
- I'd take a walk by the lake, or...
go into the bingo place,
maybe to the inn.
You ever go to meet another man?
No, I didn't.
I never did that.
You mean to say, Mrs. Manion,
a lovely women like yourself...
attractive to men, lonely, restless,
that you never once met--
Objection, Your Honor. The witness has
answered the question about other men.
The counsel is now making
a veiled suggestion to the jury.
I withdraw the question.
Mrs. Manion, on these occasional
excursions into the night...
did you always go
and return home alone?
Of course.
Mrs. Manion, you testified
that the reason you got...
into Barney Quill's car was because
you were afraid to go home alone.
Why were you so frightened
on this night?
I said that it was because he told me
bears had been seen around.
Was this the first time
you heard that...
bears came around Thunder Bay
for scraps?
- No.
- Had you seen the bears before?
Yes.
Oh, this was just the first time
you were afraid of them.
No, I was always afraid of them.
Oh, this was just the first time
you were enough afraid to allow...
a man to take you home
from one of your evening prowls.
Objection. Use of the word " prowls."
Meant to mislead the jury.
- Sustained.
- I apologize, Mrs. Manion.
I didn't mean to imply
that you were a huntress.
Was this the first time that
you were enough afraid to allow a man...
to take you home
from one of your evening walks?
Well, it wasn't just that.
- It was--
- Oh, come now, Mrs. Manion.
You should be able to answer that
straight off. That's a simple question.
Your Honor, how can the witness
answer straight off...
when the counsel keeps interrupting
the answer?
The witness seemed
a little slow to me, Mr. Biegler.
However, let her complete her answers
before you interrupt.
Of course, Your Honor. In any case,
Mr. Biegler's objection...
has given Mr. Manion sufficient time
to think of an answer to my question.
You've thought of one, haven't you?
What I was going to say was that
I didn't want to offend Mr. Quill...
by making him think that I was
afraid of him or didn't like him.
He's been very pleasant to my husband
and me when we'd been in his bar.
That's very good, Mrs. Manion.
Very good, indeed.
- Your Honor, please.
- The attorney for the people...
will reserve his comments
for the arguments.
I will ask you this question,
Mrs. Manion.
Was this the first time you had been
in Barney Quill's car at night?
Mrs. Manion, did you hear the question?
Yes, I heard.
Yes, it was the first time.
Would you raise your voice
a little, Mrs. Manion?
I said it was the first time.
Now, Mrs. Manion...
I'm quite concerned
about the lost panties.
Would you describe this article
of clothing to the courtroom?
They were nylon,
and had lace up the sides.
There was a label in them
of the place I got them--
- The Smart Shop in Phoenix, Arizona.
- What was the color of the panties?
- I believe, white.
- You believe?
I have white and pink.
They may have been pink.
You're not sure?
Haven't you checked your lingerie...
to see which pair of panties
is missing?
- No.
- When your husband came home late...
from work, and you had this little spat,
were you already dressed to go out?
- No.
- When did you dress?
After dinner, when he was asleep.
It's been stated here that you were
bare legged in the bar. Is that true?
In your anger at your husband and
your haste to get out of the trailer...
perhaps you didn't put on
any panties either.
Objection. Witness has already testified
of what she was wearing.
- Sustained.
- Do you always wear panties?
Your Honor, I object
to this line of questioning.
It's immaterial what Mrs. Manion
does all the time.
On the night she was attacked,
she was wearing panties...
and that's all we're concerned with.
Mrs. Manion seems a little bit uncertain
about the kind of panties she wore.
And since these panties have not been
found, I submit that it's possible...
she wasn't wearing any
and has forgotten.
- That's all I'm trying to get at.
- You may answer, Mrs. Manion.
You always wear panties?
No.
On what occasions don't you wear them?
When you go out alone at night?
No, no. Objection. He says he's going
after one thing and goes after another.
I'll sustain the objection.
Strike out the last two questions
in Mrs. Manion's answer.
Now, Mr. Dancer, get off the panties.
You've done enough damage.
Yes, Your Honor.
Mrs. Manion,
is your husband a jealous man?
- He loves me.
- I'm sure, but is he overly jealous?
Your Honor, how can the witness
answer that question?
What's the norm of jealousy?
Can you put your question
a little differently, Mr. Dancer?
- Has your husband struck you in a rage?
- No, Your Honor.
I think Mr. Dancer's fishing now.
What's the relevance of this question?
Your Honor, the shoe is squeezing
Mr. Biegler's foot.
In his own words,
this is not a high school debate.
This is a cross-examination
in a murder trial.
Proceed, Mr. Dancer.
Did you ever go out socially
in Thunder Bay?
Yes, a few times.
When your husband's outfit moved
to Thunder Bay, didn't Barney Quill...
throw a cocktail party
for the officers and their wives?
Didn't your husband strike a young
second lieutenant at this party?
There was a little scuffle.
It wasn't much.
- What was it about?
- I'm not sure I remember.
- Were you too drunk to remember?
- No, I was not.
I think it was because...
the lieutenant was cutting in too much
when I was dancing with my husband.
Shortly after on the verandah, didn't
your husband slap you hard enough...
so that you fell against the wall?
- He was drinking.
- Wasn't this a jealous rage?
- I don't know!
- Do you remember why he struck you?
Wasn't he enraged at you because he
thought you'd encouraged the young man?
- He might have thought so.
- There are witnesses to this affair.
I'll ask you again.
Wasn't this a jealous rage?
I guess you could call it that.
Now I'll ask you.
On the night of the shooting...
what did you swear?
What oath did you take on the rosary?
- It was about Barney Quill raping me.
- Why did you swear on the rosary...
that he raped you?
For the reason my husband said--
because I was hysterical!
That was the reason he gave for asking
you to swear. What was it for swearing?
- So he'd believe me.
- Why shouldn't he?
Objection! The reason for the use
of the rosary has been established.
These questions are immaterial.
No, I think I'll take
the answer, Mr. Biegler.
I'll ask you again, Mrs. Manion.
Why shouldn't he believe you?
Because I wasn't making much sense!
Did he think you'd lie
about a thing like that?
Objection, Your Honor! Lt. Manion had
already testified as to what he thought!
-Sustained.
-Did your husband strike you that night?
Did he hit you that night?
Well, he--
He may have slapped me
because I was hysterical.
Didn't you swear to a lie to keep him
from hitting you again?
No, I didn't! I did not!
Hadn't he already beaten you up when he
caught you coming home with Quill?
Objection! The witness has already
testified she was beaten by Quill!
Quiet. Quiet.
No more questions.
I think the witness
has had enough, Your Honor.
The witness may step down.
We'll recess for lunch.
Recess until 1 :00.
I'm sorry, baby.
You were fine.
Dr. Smith.
I've come to meet you.
My name is--
- I'm sorry. You've been mistaken.
- Maybe I'm the one you're looking for.
Are you Mr. Biegler?
No, I'm his associate in the case.
- Don't tell me you're Dr. Smith.
- That's me.
The army psychiatrist?
Maybe you expected me
to be in uniform.
No.
I didn't expect anybody so young.
I'm 40.
I sort of hoped you'd...
have a beard and wear a monocle.
I see.
Is that better?
You're on the stand this afternoon.
Doctor, have you formed an opinion
as to Frederick Manion's...
mental and emotional state
at the time he killed Barney Quill?
- I have.
- And what is that opinion?
He was temporarily insane
at the time of the shooting.
At the time of the shooting,
do you believe he was able...
to distinguish right from wrong?
He may or may not have been.
It doesn't make too much difference.
Now, Doctor,
as clearly as you can...
will you explain
Frederick Manion's temporary insanity?
It is known as dissociative reaction...
a psychic shock which creates...
an almost overwhelming tension...
which the person in shock
must alleviate.
In Lt. Manion's case, a soldier...
it is only natural
that he would turn to action.
Only direct, simple action...
against Barney Quill would relieve
this unbearable tension.
This is not too uncommon. For example,
in combat, some of the more...
remarkable heroics take place
in this state of mind.
Is there another name for dissociative
reaction that we might recognize?
Yes, it has been known
as irresistible impulse.
Now, Doctor, a man in the grip
of irresistible impulse...
would he be likely to go
to his neighbor for advice...
or call up the police
to come to his aid?
- Completely incompatible.
- Yes, but our man...
was able to think of going
and taking out a gun...
and loading it before setting out
to find Quill.
That's his conscious mind working, but
he'd go even if a gun wasn't available.
How would a man look
in the grip of dissociative reaction?
He might appear to be deadly calm,
fiercely deliberate.
Mm-hmm.
Would you describe his behavior...
as being like a mailman
delivering the mail?
That's not bad. Like a mailman, he would
have a job to do, and he would do it.
- Your witness.
- Doctor...
did you find any psychosis
in Frederick Manion?
- I did not.
- Any neuroses?
I found no history of neuroses.
Any history of delusion?
- None.
- Loss of memory?
- Not before this instance.
- Did you find any history--
- Can you spot Mary Pilant?
- She didn't come back after lunch.
I think you'd better give up
on that one.
Doctor, you stated that the defendant
might or might not...
have been able to distinguish...
the difference between right and wrong,
but it wouldn't have made a difference.
- Am I right? Is that what you said?
- Approximately, yes.
Did you mean that at the time
of the shooting...
he could have known the difference
between right and wrong?
He might have, yes.
Dr. Smith...
if the defendant could have known
what he was doing...
and could have known it was wrong,
how can you come here...
and testify that he was legally insane?
I'm not saying
he was legally insane.
I'm saying that
in his mental condition...
it would not have made any difference
whether he knew right from wrong.
He would still have shot Quill.
Are you willing to rest your testimony
in this case on this opinion?
Yes, I am.
Your Honor, I'd like to ask
for a short recess.
The attorneys for the people would like
to meet with Mr. Biegler in chambers.
- Glad to oblige, Your Honor.
- Short recess.
The jury will remain.
Someday, I'm going to
horrify tradition...
and lay a dense, blue cloud...
of tobacco smoke
in that hallowed courtroom.
What's on your mind, Mr. Dancer?
Your Honor, in view of Dr. Smith's
testimony, I thought perhaps...
the defense might like
to change their plea.
- Change it to what?
- Guilty, of course.
No, we'll still go for broke.
Hell, Paulie, you know a guy's
not considered legally nuts...
in Michigan unless
he didn't know right from wrong.
- Why don't you get this over with?
- Your Honor, will you turn to page 486?
- What's that?
- Appears to be a law book, Mr. Lodwick.
Oh, I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I make those things
to help me think sometimes.
- For perch?
- No, it was for frog.
What case is he citing?
We gig frogs
in my part of the country.
It's the same up here.
I'm a trout man, myself...
but this is a new wrinkle
I'm gonna try.
They do it in the Bayou, down South.
The idea, they get a big, long pole...
and about a ten-pound line,
just sort of...
drift along a high bank
in a boat.
Then you see that big, old bullfrog
in the crevice...
and sort of float this along
in front of him.
Pop! That old tongue of his
snaps out, and--
You've got frog legs
for supper.
- I'll be darned.
- Why don't you keep it?
- Try it sometime.
- Thanks. I will.
Four eighty-six.
- What is it, Your Honor?
- People v. Durfee, 1 886.
Looks like a precedent.
Would you like to read it?
No, thank you, Your Honor.
I think I recall the case.
We're hooked...
like the frog.
Dr. Harcourt, where did you receive
your university training?
Johns Hopkins in Baltimore, Maryland.
And where do you practice now?
I'm the medical superintendent of the
Bonder State Hospital for the Insane.
It's been stated here that...
dissociative reaction,
or irresistible impulse...
is not uncommon
among soldiers in combat.
- Do you agree with that statement?
- I do...
but not as it was put
by Dr. Smith.
- Where would you depart from Dr. Smith?
- Dissociative reaction...
is not something that comes out of
the blue and disappears as quickly.
It can only occur,
even among soldiers in combat...
if the individual has a psychoneurotic
condition of long standing.
It's been testified here that
a psychiatric exam of the defendant...
showed no evidence of neuroses...
and no history
of dissociative reaction.
You've further heard it testified...
that the defendant's behavior
on the night of the shooting...
was cool and direct.
As an observer,
do you remember this testimony?
From this, have you formed an opinion
about the defendant's sanity...
on the night of the shooting?
I'm of the opinion that he was in
possession of his faculties...
so that he was not dominated
by his unconscious mind.
In other words, he was not
in the grip of irresistible impulse.
- In my opinion, he was not.
- Thank you. Your witness.
Dr. Harcourt, psychiatry is an effort
to probe into the dark...
undiscovered world of the mind.
And in there, the world
might be round, it could be square.
Your opinion could be wrong, Dr. Smith's
could be right. Is that true?
I'd be a poor doctor
if I didn't agree with that.
But I believe my opinion
to be right.
Do you think you might've changed
your opinion...
if you'd examined the defendant
as Dr. Smith did?
- I don't believe so.
- But Dr. Smith's opinion...
was made under better circumstances,
wasn't it?
If you mean that he was able
to examine the man, yes.
- Yeah. Thank you, Doctor.
- That's all, Dr. Harcourt.
- Is there more rebuttal?
- We're over a barrel, Mitch.
We have to use him.
We call Duane Miller to the stand.
Will the sheriff please
bring in the witness?
What can he tell?
Nothing.
He can't tell anything.
Raise your right hand. Do you swear
the testimony you give in this cause...
shall be the truth, the whole truth, and
nothing but the truth, so help you God?
I do.
- State your name, please.
- Duane Miller. Most folks call me Duke.
Where do you presently reside?
Across the alley in the jail.
You know the defendant,
Frederick Manion?
Yeah, I got to know him in the past
few weeks. His cell's next to mine.
What was the last conversation
you had with the lieutenant?
Except for " hello" this morning,
the last time was last night.
- Did you discuss his trial last night?
- Yeah, some.
Would you tell the court what Lt. Manion
had to say about the trial?
Well, I said,
"Are things looking up, Lieutenant?"
And he said,
"I got it made, buster."
He said,
"I fooled my lawyer...
I fooled that head-shrinker...
and I'm gonna fool
that bunch of corn cobs on the jury.''
Liar!
You're a lousy, stinkin' liar!
Take it easy, now.
I apologize for my client,
Your Honor.
Yet his outburst is almost excusable,
since the prosecution has seen fit ...
to put a felon on the stand to testify
against an officer in the U.S. Army.
Your Honor, I don't know who's the
worse offender, Manion or his lawyer.
We're close to the end.
In the name of heaven,
let's have peace...
and courtesy
for these last few hours.
Mr. Dancer, you will continue
your interrogation without comment.
Mr. Biegler, you will not sound off
at every opportunity.
And the defendant will remain seated
in his chair and keep his mouth shut.
- Now go ahead.
- Mr. Miller...
are you certain
that Lt. Manion said...
" I've got it made, buster" ?
- That's what he said.
- Did Lt. Manion say anything else?
Yes, sir. He said when he got out...
the first thing he was gonna do
was kick that bitch...
from here to kingdom come.
- To whom was he referring?
- To his wife.
Your witness.
- What are you in jail for, Mr. Miller?
- Arson.
I copped out,
and I'm waiting for a sentence.
How many other offenses
have you committed?
I was in reform school as a kid,
but that's all.
Your Honor, I'd like to see
this man's criminal record.
Do you have his record, Mr. Lodwick?
Yes, sir.
Here it is.
Your record shows you've been
in prison six times...
in three different states--
three times for arson, twice for assault
with a deadly weapon...
once for larceny.
Also shows you've done short stretches
in four city jails...
on charges of indecent exposure...
window-peeping, perjury...
and disorderly conduct.
Is this your true record?
Them things are never right.
How did you get the ear
of the prosecution...
in order to tell them about the
conversation you had with Lt. Manion?
-The D.A. was taking us into his office.
-Taking who into his office?
- Us prisoners in the jail.
- All at once, or one at a time?
One at a time.
Him and that other lawyer...
took us to his office and asked us
questions about Lt. Manion.
Were you promised a lighter sentence
if you went on the witness stand?
- Your Honor, the people object to--
- Overruled. Answer the question.
- I wasn't promised anything.
- You thought it'd help your troubles...
if you dreamed up this story
to please the D.A.
- I didn't dream up nothin'.
- You're sure that's what Manion said?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- As sure as you were about your record?
Well, I guess I kind of goofed
on that one.
Your Honor,
I don't feel I can dignify...
this creature with any more questions.
Take the witness away.
Would you like a conference
with your client?
I can see how the last witness
was quite a surprise.
No, Your Honor.
We don't need a conference.
I'll recall Lt. Manion
to the stand right now.
Now, you've heard the testimony
of this Miller.
- Is any part of it true?
- None.
Lieutenant, do you have any idea why he
might come here with a tale like that?
No, sir.
Have you ever talked with this man?
What did you talk about?
Nothing important.
Certainly, nothing about
my personal life or my feelings.
That's all I wanted to know.
Lt. Manion...
have you ever had
any sort of...
trouble with Miller?
I don't know. What do you mean?
An argument? Something like that?
Did you ever attack--
physically attack him?
Your lawyer can't answer
the question for you, Lieutenant.
- Did you ever physically attack Miller?
- I wouldn't call it an attack, exactly.
I pushed his head
against the bars one day.
- Why?
- He said something ugly about my wife.
Do you remember pushing or bumping
his head against the bars?
Sure. I just told you.
Then this was not
dissociative reaction.
The defendant isn't qualified
to answer that.
Lt. Manion...
wasn't your action against Barney Quill
much the same...
as your action against Miller
and against the lieutenant...
that you struck
at the cocktail party?
All in the heat of anger with a willful,
conscious desire to hurt or kill?
I don't remember
my action against Quill.
How long had you known that your wife
was running around with Barney Quill?
I never knew anything like that.
I trust my wife.
I suppose you just beat her up
occasionally for the fun of it.
Nothing has been established
to permit a question like that.
He keeps implying things
without getting to the point.
Let him ask the lieutenant,
did he ever beat his wife?
I'll sustain the objection.
Would you like to rephrase
your question, Mr. Dancer?
No thank you, Your Honor.
I've finished.
Then I'll ask him.
Did you, Lt. Manion...
ever beat your wife on the night
of the shooting or any other time?
- No, sir.
- Is there any doubt in your mind...
that Barney Quill raped Mrs. Manion?
- No, sir.
- That's all.
Step down, Lieutenant.
- We hurt?
- We're hurt bad.
Your Honor, I know time is pressing.
I don't want to ask for a recess.
I would like to leave
the courtroom for a moment.
If it's important,
we can be at ease for a minute.
Thank you, sir.
This is highly irregular,
Your Honor.
There's no reason to make
a federal case out of it.
Thank you very much, Your Honor.
We now have another rebuttal witness.
The defense calls Mary Pilant
to the stand.
We must protest this whole affair.
The noble defense attorney rushes out
to a secret conference...
and now the last-minute witness is being
brought dramatically down the aisle.
The whole thing has obviously been
rigged to unduly excite the jury.
It's another cornball trick.
Your Honor, I don't blame Mr. Dancer
for feeling put-upon.
I'm just a humble country lawyer
trying to do the best I can...
against this brilliant prosecutor
from the big city of Lansing.
Swear the witness.
Raise your right hand. Do you swear
the testimony you shall give...
shall be the truth, the whole truth, and
nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
- Where do you live, Miss Pilant?
- At Thunder Bay Inn in Thunder Bay.
- And how long have you lived there?
- For two years.
- And what's your profession?
- I manage the inn.
Now, Miss Pilant, how is the laundry
handled at Thunder Bay Inn?
It's chuted down to the laundry room.
Where is the location of that chute
on the second floor?
- Between room 42 and 43.
- Who lives in those rooms?
I live in 42.
Mr. Quill lived in 43.
Would Mr. Quill,
coming up from the lobby...
have to pass by the mouth of that chute
on the way to his room?
Would it be very easy for him to drop
something into that chute as he passed?
Have you ever had occasion to go
down into the laundry at any time?
Yes. Part of my job is to sort
various pieces of laundry...
as they come out of
the wash-and-dry machine.
Would you tell the court what you found
among those pieces of laundry...
the day after Mr. Quill was killed?
I found a pair of women's panties.
- And what did you do with them?
- I threw them in the rag bin.
When did you learn the significance
of those panties?
Here.
This morning, in the courtroom.
And then you went home
and got them out of the rag bin?
Did you bring them with you?
I offer this article of lingerie...
as Exhibit Number One
for the defense.
They're white,
they have lace up the side...
and they're badly torn...
as if they've been ripped apart
by powerful hands.
The label reads...
" Smart Shop, Phoenix, Arizona."
If there is no objection, the exhibit
will be received in evidence.
- That's all, Miss Pilant.
- Do you ever talk to Mr. Lodwick...
about the death of Barney Quill?
He came to the hotel several times
after Mr. Quill was killed.
Did you tell Mr. Lodwick that you didn't
believe Barney Quill raped Mrs. Manion?
- Yes, I told him that.
- Did you ever talk to Mr. Biegler?
Was this also in connection
with the shooting of Quill?
Did you tell him you didn't believe
Barney Quill had raped Mrs. Manion?
- How many times did you talk to him?
- Twice.
- When was the last time?
- Last night.
And have you now changed your mind?
Do you now believe...
Barney Quill raped Mrs. Manion?
I don't know now.
I think he might have.
When did you change your mind?
Last night?
- No, it was here, this morning.
- When were you given the panties?
- Was that last night?
-Just wait a minute!
Use the proper form
of objection, Mr. Biegler.
On second thought, I don't object.
I'd like the jury to hear her answer.
- The witness may answer.
- No.
I was not given the panties last night
or at any other time.
- I found them exactly as I said.
- Do you know for a fact...
that Barney Quill dropped the panties
down the chute, or did you assume it?
- I assumed it.
- Had you thought maybe someone else...
might have put the panties there
who wanted them found in the laundry?
I hadn't thought of that.
And in the grip of what Mr. Biegler
might call irresistible impulse...
you rushed in here with the panties
because you wanted to crucify...
the dead Barney Quill,
isn't that true?
- No, I thought it was my duty--
- Your pride was hurt, wasn't it?
- I don't know what you mean.
- He's trying to confuse the witness.
Let him ask her a question
she can understand.
Yes, Mr. Dancer. I myself would like
to know what you're driving at.
Miss Pilant,
when you found the panties...
was your first thought that Barney Quill
might have raped Mrs. Manion...
or was it that he might have been
stepping out with Mrs. Manion?
I don't know what he means.
Mr. Dancer, once again I must ask you to
put straight questions to the witness.
Here is a straight question,
Your Honor.
Miss Pilant, are you
Barney Quill's mistress?
No. No, I was not!
It's common knowledge in Thunder Bay
you were living with Quill.
- That's not true. Barney Quill was--
- Was what, Miss Pilant?
Barney Quill was my father.
No more questions.
That's all for me.
The witness may step down.
We will recess for 1 5 minutes,
after which...
we will hear the closing arguments.
If possible, I would like to charge
the jury before nightfall.
Think they're gonna stay out all night?
Can't somebody say something?
What do you want me
to say, Maida, darling?
Tell me we're gonna win.
I'm counting on getting that
promissory note from the lieutenant.
I hope I can borrow some money on it.
I need a new typewriter.
Half the time, the " p" and the " f"
don't strike on mine.
" Party of the first part"
sometimes comes out...
" arty of the irst art."
Doesn't make sense.
It's embarrassing.
" Arty of the irst art" ?
I kind of like that.
Has a ring to it.
Twelve people go off
into a room.
Twelve different minds,
twelve different hearts...
and twelve different walks of life.
Twelve sets of eyes, ears,
shapes and sizes.
And these twelve people...
are asked to judge
another human being...
as different from them
as they are from each other.
And in their judgment,
they must become of one mind.
Unanimous.
That's one of the miracles of man's
disorganized soul that they can do it.
And most instances,
do it right well.
God bless juries.
I don't know what I'd do
if I were on that jury.
I really don't know.
Do you?
I loved that, Paulie.
I loved that
"humble country lawyer" bit.
You had Mr. Dancer dancing.
I'm afraid he got in the last dance.
That's the best summary I've ever heard
in a courtroom.
I liked yours much better, Paulie.
Do you have to play that stuff?
Can't you play " Danny Boy" ...
or " Sweet Isle of Innisfree" ?
Paul Biegler's office.
Yes, sir. Right away.
They're ready.
Hey, sweetie.
Go on.
- The jury's coming in.
- Yeah, I heard.
You can tell my loving husband
I'll be waiting in the car.
- You're sure he's gonna come out?
- Oh, sure!
He's lucky.
Some people have all the luck.
You can tell him I'm waiting
to get kicked to kingdom come.
Oh! Hey, sweetie...
I have a souvenir for you.
You'd better keep that thing.
You might need it again sometime.
You never know.
No, you don't, do you?
Oh, I like you, Paulie.
I warn all those present not
to interrupt the taking of the verdict.
I will stop the proceedings
and clear the courtroom...
if there is any demonstration.
Proceed, Mr. Clerk.
Members of the jury,
have you agreed upon a verdict...
- and if so, who will speak for you?
- We have. I'm the foreman.
The defendant will rise.
- What is your verdict?
- We find the defendant...
not guilty by reason of insanity.
Maida gave you that promissory note,
didn't she?
Right here, ready to be signed
by our happy client.
You know, I used to think the world
looked better through a glass of whisky.
It doesn't.
I think I'll keep it this way.
Looks nice.
Well, I got one good thing
out of this case--
a new law partner,
if it's all right with him.
He'd be mighty proud to have his name
on a shingle with yours.
I guess you're looking for Lt. Manion,
aren't you, Mr. Biegler?
He gave me this note for you.
I felt real sorry for Mrs. Manion.
She was crying.
Left a mess, didn't they?
Well, we'd better get busy here.
" Dear Mr. Biegler,
so sorry that I had to leave suddenly.
I was seized
by an irresistible impulse.
Frederick Manion.''
How in the world
are we gonna face Maida?
Gin. I knew there was
something wrong with that guy.
Never saw a gin drinker yet
you could trust.
Partner, what do you say
we go and see our first client?
- Who might that be?
- Mary Pilant.
We're gonna administer
Barney Quill's estate.
Now, that's what I call
poetic justice for everybody.