Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
It was good for little David
and it's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
It was good for old Jonah
and it's good enough for me
It was good for the Hebrew children
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
Uh, Good morning, young ladies and gentlemen.
[Door opening]
Good morning, visitors.
For our science lesson for today,
We will continue our discussion of Darwin's theory
of the descent of man.
Now, as I told you yesterday,
Darwin's theory tells us
that man evolved from a lower order of animals,
from the first wiggly protozoa here in the sea
to the ape and finally to man.
Say now some of you fellas out there are probably going to
that's why some of us act like monkeys.
[Laughing]
But what Mr. Charles Darwin
was trying to tell us,
in his own way--
Bertram T. Cates
come off it, Sam.
You've known me all my life.
Bert, you're charged
with violation of public act 31428,
volume 37, statute no. 31428 of the state code,
which makes it unlawful
for any teacher of the public schools
to teach any theory that denies the creation of man
as taught in the bible,
and to teach instead that man has descended
from the lower order of animals.
Bertram Cates, I hereby place you under arrest.
Monkey trial!
Here's another one--
"Monkey shines in Hillsboro."
The whole world's laughing at us.
Look, from Chicago--
"Heavenly Hillsboro--
"does it have a hole in its head."
"or its head in a hole"
I'm telling you, we've gone too far.
Let 'em laugh.
we're fightin' the lord's battle, ain't we, Reverend.
Well, I'd a sight rather have some
heathen a-laughin' at me
than to have my sons a-laughin' at my bible.
Well, they mocked the lord, too, didn't they
and they smote him and they spat upon him,
and he turned to them his other cheek.
Amen.
Look, Reverend, we don't want to smite 'em back.
We just want to make 'em stop.
Tom, you're prosecuting attorney.
Isn't there something we can do?
Well, in view of my position,
I...hardly think it ethical for me
to express my opinion
then you'd better go back to law school.
Gentlemen, I ask you--
what do we care what a bunch of foreigners and city slickers think
Frank, you ever had a frenchman stayin' at your hotel
Now look, you're missing the--
and how long since you sold a pound of grits
to some smart aleck from New York
Heaven has chosen us to show the way,
to light the road for others,
back to the shepherd, back to the fold.
We're not sheep, Reverend.
Well, I'd a sight rather be a sheep than a Judas goat.
Wait a minute.
As mayor of Hillsboro,
I stand to uphold the laws of this community,
No Matter how it may affect my political future.
Now, I shall just ignore these-- these slanders
just like water off a duck's back.
Now look, you only got 2 months more to go as mayor anyway,
and you shouldn't have been elected in the first place.
You've been a lousy mayor.
[Everyone talking at once]
My friends,
as you all know, I deal with figures--
accounts, checks, balances.
My bank operates on the principle of practical reality
and so do I.
Are you aware, my friends,
that the great big universities throughout the country
will consider student applicants from our state
ineligible because of this law
Now, I don't know whose idea it was
to hang a shingle on Hillsboro
spelling "horse-and-buggy,"
but as for me, I won't invest in antiquity.
I want my bank holding credit
with New York, Pennsylvania, Illinois,
and I may want my son to go to Yale.
Now, I believe in--
just as much as anyone in this room--
in a basic fundamentalist interpretation of the bible,
but we can't close our eyes to all progress,
to everything which represents--
Wait a minute!
"Matthew Harrison Brady volunteers to prosecute
in monkey trial."
Matthew Harrison Brady.
the lord has sent us his right hand.
and I'll be working with him.
They'll come pouring out of the hills.
This town will fill up like a rain barrel in a flood.
It'll be bigger than the Chautauqua
at Chattanooga,
And people are gonna have to have
some place to stay...
and they gotta eat.
This'll put Hillsboro on the map of this country.
Let us give thanks to the lord.
Let us pray.
You better start praying, son.
imagine-- Matthew Harrison Brady coming here.
I voted for him for president,
Twice--
once in 1900
and again in 08
I wasn't old enough to vote for him the first time he run,
but my Pa did.
I seen him once at a Chautauqua meeting in Chattanooga.
When he spoke, the tent poles shook.
Who's going to be your lawyer, son
I don't know yet.
I wrote to that newspaper in Baltimore.
they're sending somebody.
well, he better be loud.
[Knocking at door]
Ahh, probably one of
those newspaper reporters.
You're a popular fellow.
Yeah.
Oh, Bert, you don't mind, do you.
Just for the looks of it
Can't tell who it might be.
Sure. Don't worry about it, Mort.
[Knocking]
All right,
All right.
[Knocking]
Who is it
[Woman] Mort
Rachel.
Come on in.
Ahh, you got a present for Bert, huh
Mort, don't let my father know
I came here.
Well, the Reverend don't tell me his business.
I don't see why I should tell him mine
Is Bert all right
Oh, of course he's--
The safest place in the world's in the jail.
Come on in. Come on.
Tell them you're sorry.
Tell them it was all a mistake.
Please te--
tell them if they let my body out of jail
I'd lock up my mind
Could you stand that, Rachel
at least we'd be together.
It wouldn't be the...
It wouldn't be the same.
Rachel, do you remember
those warm, dark nights down by the riverbank,
just watching the water,
wondering about the...the
miracle of it,
wondering what the stars were for...
what's on the other side of the moon
There'd be no more of that, Rach.
We could still have that.
No, we couldn't.
That would be in the locked-off part...
for both of us.
[Man]
Well...
So, this is where the fate of learning
will be decided for the next 10,000 years.
O tempora, o mores.
Well, I see we have
both beauty and biology on our side.
Who are you
This your writing
Yes.
This is mine.
Hornbeck. E.K. Hornbeck,
Baltimore Herald.
I've been waiting to hear from you.
Read it.
My typewriter's been singing
a sweet, sad song about the
Hillsboro heretic--
B. Cates, latter-Day Dreyfus
Ok. Romeo with a biology bo
want a bite
Oh, don't worry.
I'm not the serpent, little eva.
This isn't from the tree of knowledge.
Oh, no.
You won't find one growing
in "Heavenly Hillsboro."
A few ignorance bushes, perhaps,
but no tree of knowledge.
Ask adam.
You make me sound like a martyr.
You could be.
Martyrs always have a point to prove,
and so do you,
but you haven't won your halo yet.
that won't come until they've tossed you
into the arena...
with the lion.
You mean Brady
I don't want Bert to be a martyr.
What are you trying to prove, anyway
Rach, I'm not trying to prove anything.
All I want to do is teach my students
that man just wasn't planted here
like a Geranium in a flowerpot
that life comes from a long miracle.
It just didn't take 7 days.
But it's against the law.
a schoolteacher's a public servant.
He should do what the law and the school board want him to.
Has the accused anything to say in his own defense
If not, I sentence you to life as a public servant,
a silent butler in the service of
your school board.
Wastebaskets for ideas on sale in the outer lobby.
I don't see anything funny in this, Mr. Hornbeck.
Objection sustained.
Neither do I.
Then why don't you just leave us alone
You newspaper people
have stirred up enough trouble for Bert.
what do you want, anyway
I came to tell boy Socrates here
that the Baltimore Herald is opposed to Hemlock,
and will provide a lawyer.
Who
I don't know yet, but what's the difference
A new lawyer with old tricks,
An old lawyer with new tricks.
Wake up, Copernicus.
The law is still on the side of the lawmakers,
and everything revolves around their terra firma.
Then why bother, you and your newspaper
Because I know that the sunrise
is an optical illusion.
My teacher told me so.
You don't seem like the kind of person who'd want to bother.
You seem so--
cynical.
True, true
That's part of my fascination
I do hateful things
for which people love me
and I do lovable things for which they hate me.
I'm admired for my detestability.
Now, don't worry, little Eva.
I may be rancid butter,
but I'm on your side of the bread.
[Choir]
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
It was good for old Jonah
and it's good enough for me
Give me that old time religion
it's good enough for me
it was good for little David
and it's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
Just give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
It was good for little David
and it's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
Just give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
It was good for old Jonah
and it's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
Matthew Harrison Brady...
as mayor of Hillsboro,
may I say that this municipality
is proud to have within its city limits
the warrior who has always fought for us ordinary people.
Why the lady folk of this town would not have the vote
If it hadn't been for you fighting
To give them all that suffrage.
Mr. President Wilson would not have got to the white house
and won the war
If it hadn't been for you supporting him
and being his secretary of state
In conclusion, the governor of our glorious state
has vested in me the authority
to confer upon you a commission
as honorary colonel in the state militia.
[Cheering]
If it's good enough for Brady...
If it's good enough for Brady
then it's good enough for me
[Cheering]
Col. Brady--
I like the sound of that.
[Crowd chuckling]
Friends, Mrs. Brady and I are delighted
to be among you.
We all voted for you-- 3 times!
I trust it was in 3 separate elections.
[Crowd laughing]
I could only wish for one thing--
that you had not given us quite so
warm a welcome.
[Laughing]
[Women's voice]
Mr. Brady
Yes
Here you are.
Oh, bless you, bless you.
And Mrs. Brady.
Thank you.
And now then,
Who, may I ask, is the, uh, spiritual
leader of the community
The Rev.
Jeremiah Brown
Go on,
Reverend.
How are you, Reverend
Will you stand here at my side thank you.
Ahem.
My friends of Hillsboro,
You know why I have come here.
It is not merely to prosecute a lawbreaker,
a young man who has spoken out against the revealed word.
I have come here
because what has happened in a schoolroom in your town
has unloosed a wicked attack
from the big cities of the north.
We did not seek this struggle.
We are simple folk,
who seek only to live in brotherhood and peace,
to cherish our loved ones,
to teach our children the ways of righteousness
and of the lord.
But what would they teach them, these idolaters,
these priests of "evil-ution"
what would they have them do
they would have them measure the distance between the stars
and forget him who holds the
stars in his hands.
they are lost, my friends.
For, I tell you, if man believes he is descended from the beasts,
he must remain a beast!
and as the young wolf turns upon the old,
these innocent ones, corrupted and despairing of salvation,
will turn upon their fathers,
and our land will become a land of sodom and gomorrah
of pestilence, of fire, of hatred and of death.
I disagree.
[Crowd murmuring]
Who are you
Uh, Hornbeck.
E.K. Hornbeck of the Baltimore Herald.
Oh, yeah.
Yes, I know your paper...
and your writings, Sir.
Ladies and gentlemen
my paper is happy to announce
that it is sending two representatives
to, uh, "Heavenly Hillsboro"--
the most gifted reporter in America today--
Myself--
[Crowd laughing]
and the most agile legal mind
of the 20th century--
Henry Drummond.
[Crowd murmuring]
[man]
who's Henry Drummond
We'll send him back to hell!
ride him out on a rail!
Don't let him into town!
Keep him out!
[Everyone yelling]
No, no, no.
I believe we should welcome Henry Drummond.
If the enemy sends his goliath into battle,
it magnifies our cause.
Henry Drummond has stalked the courtrooms of this land
for 40 years.
When he fights, headlines follow.
The whole world will be watching our
victory over Drummond.
If st. george had killed a dragonfly
instead of a dragon,
who would remember him
[Laughing]
We here in Hillsboro have not only the opportunity
to slay the devil's disciple
but the devil himself!
If it's good enough for Brady...
if it's good enough for Brady
then it's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
It's good enough for me
Oh, give me that old time religion
Give me that old time religion
You're the stranger, ain't you
are you looking for a nice, clean place to stay
I had a nice, clean place to stay, madam,
and I left it to come here.
If it's good enough for Brady
if it's good enough for Brady
then it's good enough for me
[Playing organ]
Rachel.
I waited supper for you.
it's on the table
peace will come, my daughter.
God we must thank
that the sinner stands naked and exposed.
Stop preaching, Pa.
I have something to tell you.
You're upset, daughter.
Eat something and we'll talk in the morning.
No. Now. I'm not leaving Bert.
I don't understand.
You heard what Mr. Brady said
I love him, Pa. I love him.
No, no. that is the love of Judas.
This man has nothing to offer you but sin.
I told you that from the beginning.
what's he done
what's he done that's so terrible
Why do you hate him so
Because I love god, and I hate his enemies.
Bert loves God.
Then what is he doing with Henry Drummond
Why is he bringing Henry Drummond here
to spew his atheistic filth into the ears of our people
You're a schoolteacher.
You know how easy it is to mold
minds for good
or to twist them for evil.
Bert didn't twist any minds.
You're infected with the poison of his agnosticism.
Now get down on your knees and pray for forgiveness.
Forgiveness for what
Because you have betrayed me.
You have betrayed your faith.
I'm not betraying anybody.
I'm glad your mother isn't here
to see what's become of you.
Pa, please listen to me.
If she is looking down from heaven,
I ask her to forgive you and to forgive me.
Pa, ever since I was a little girl,
I'd wake up in the middle of the night
afraid of the dark,
like the house was upside down,
and if I didn't hang onto the Mattress,
I'd fall out into the sky--
Forgive her, Mother,
Forgive her, dear God...
I wanted to run to you,
to have you tell me that I was safe,
that everything was all right,
but I was always more afraid of you than of falling.
It's the same way now.
I have failed.
Tell me what to do, dear lord.
Guide my faltering steps.
Pa. Pa.
I love my daughter. how can I save her
Pa, get up. Please get up.
And I will sprinkle clean water upon you,
and you shall be clean.
From all your filthiness and from your idols
Will I cleanse you
and a new heart also will I give you
and a new spirit put within you,
and I will tear out the stony heart of flesh,
and I will give you a heart of flesh.
[Sobbing]
[Band playing that old time religion]
Hello, devil. Welcome to hell.
Hello, Hornbeck.
Hillsboro, Heavenly Hillsboro
The buckle on the bible belt
Come on.
Where are we staying
--we're sharing a room at the mansion house
like everything else
in this town, misnamed
Follow me, and I shall point out
the unplumbed and plumbing-less depths.
Bible
Hot dogs.
Here y'are. Get your red hots.
That poses a pretty problem.
Which is hungrier-- my stomach or my soul
Hot dog.
Yes, sir.
Tell me, uh, what do you think
of all these monkeyshines
Got no opinion, sir. Opinions are bad for business.
Ah.
Are you a evolutionist
A infidel
A sinner
the worst kind.
I write for a newspaper.
Want a hot dog
No, thanks.
Oh, then you, sir, you must be a man of God.
No, no, no. ulcers
Ladies and gentlemen,
devolution is not a theory but a proven fact.
My friends, man
did not evolve from the ape,
but the ape devolved from man.
Now, you take a look at this creature sitting here.
There before you is an example
of the ungrace
to which man can fall because of his own bestiality.
Look at those beady little brows.
Look at those shifting eyes.
For as sure as the good lord
cast out satan from heavenly glory,
so did he devolve this poor beast from man.
Quit looking at me, will you, son
These are the wages of sin, my friends.
You take a lesson.
Look and beware.
I thank you.
Your contributions will be gratefully received.
Grandpa.
Welcome to Hillsboro, sir.
Have you come to testify
for the prosecution or the defense
You.
You Henry Drummond
Yes, I am.
I'm royce mcHenry, farmer hereabouts.
Nice to know you, Mr. mcHenry.
I want to tell you we're just plain folk down here.
We don't need no outsiders to tell us
how or what to think.
Well, that isn't my mission, Mr. McHenry.
Then why don't you go back where you came from
Hmm.
Pretty hot, aren't they
Their Messiah arrived yesterday.
Look, uh, Drummond,
Why don't you give your ulcers a break and go home
You'll win no victories here.
I've been a lawyer long enough
to know there are no total victories anywhere
Hm. there's only one man in this town who thinks at all,
and he's in jail.
That's why I'm here.
Just, uh, plain folk, 2nd generation.
Mr. Drummond
We're all members of Mr. Cates' homeroom and biology class.
..w-we all like Mr. Cates very much.
And we hope you do right by him.
Well, so do i, son. so do i.
Sarah!
It's good to see you, Henry.
I only wish it were under different
circumstances.
Sarah, you look lovelier than ever
Oh, uh, you know Mr. Hornbeck
How do you do, Mrs. Brady
How do you do, Mr. Hornbeck
Ha ha!
Excuse me.
HHenry! Henry Drummond!
How are you, Henry
Hello, Matt.
I see you've made friends among the younger set.
Yes, youth appeals to me these days.
[Concierge]
Room 206, Mr. Drummond.
Thank you.
Neither of us is getting any younger, eh Henry
Matt, you know what the doctor said
about not overeating in this heat.
Don't worry, mother.
We need strength for the fight ahead.
I'll take up your bags, counselor.
Thank you.
Oh, it's you again, Mr. Hornbeck.
I read your article yesterday.
Very biased reporting, I must say.
Mr. Brady, it's the duty of a newspaper
to comfort the afflicted...
and afflict the comfortable.
I don't like that fellow.
Oh. Henry, I'd like for you to meet
some of the good, uh, people
of Hillsboro.
Mr. Carter, the mayor.
Welcome to Hillsboro.
thank you, your honor.
Prosecuting attorney for this, ah, this district,
Mr. Davenport.
We'll be working together.
Mr. Drummond, sir, let me assure you,
while we may not agree with your ideas,
we respect your right to voice them.
Good boy.
[Brady]
Henry Drummond and I have worked side by side
in a good many battles for the rights of the common folk of this country.
Twice he campaigned for me when I ran
for president.
Isn't that right, Henry
That's right, Matt.
Now, after all these years,
We find ourselves on the opposite
side of an issue.
Well, that's evolution for you.
Good day, gentlemen.
Good day, young gentlemen, and--and thank you.
Sarah.
Good-bye,
Henry.
[Band playing that old time religion]
[Crowd cheering]
[Crowd booing]
[Band playing funeral dirge]
I believe we can desist
with the taking of photographs
for the time being.
Mr. drummond, is the defense ready to proceed
with the selecti on of the next juror
Defense is ready, your honor.
Col. Brady, is the prosecution ready?
Prosecution is ready, your honor.
All right, Mort, call a venireman
to fill the 12th and last seat on the jury.
Ap! Jessie H. Dunl
Yes, sir.
You're next, Jessie.
[Crowd cheering]
[Gavel pounding]
[Judge] order in the court!
Order in the court!
I want to warn the spectators
that the court will not tolerate
any undue disturbance at any time.
[Reporter] the 11th juror has been selected...
[Judge] Now, I thought I made myself plain.
I'm not going to warn you again about those photographs,
[Reporter] 11 down and 1 to go...
[Judge] and you reporters have just one more minute
on those telephones.
[Reporters talking]
as you know, for all last night and today,
the legion of the unwashed and holy
have been rivering out of the rustic back ways
to listen to their plump messiah coo and bellow.
Their high priest of mumbo jumbo
Matthew Harrison Brady
has alternately been stuffing himself with fried chicken
and belching platitudes
since his arriva l here 2 days ago.
[Gavel pounding]
[Judge] All right, can we continue, Col. Brady
Your honor, before we continue,
will the court entertain a motion
on a Matter of procedure
Will the learned prosecutor state the motion
It has been called to my attention
that the temperature in this courtroom
is now 97 degrees fahrenheit
and it may get hotter!
[Crowd]
Ha ha! Amen! Amen!
I do not think the dignity of this court will suffer
if we remove a few superfluous outer garments
Does the, uh, defense have any objection
to Col. Brady's motion
Well, I don't know if the dignity of this court can be upheld
with these galluses I've got on.
We'll, uh, take that chance,
uh, Mr. Drummond.
Those who wish to remove their coats may do so.
[Chattering]
Is the, uh, counsel for the defense
showing us the latest fashion
from the great metropolitan city of Chicago
[Laughing]
Glad you asked me that.
I brought these along special.
it just so happens
I bought these in peabody's general store
in your hometown, Mr. Brady--
Weeping Water, Nebraska.
[Laughing]
[Gavel pounding]
Let us proceed
with the selection of the final juror.
Mort.
State your name and occupation, Jess.
Jessie H. Dunlap, farmer.
Mr. Davenport.
You, uh, believe in the bible, Mr. dunlap
I believe in the holy word of God,
and I believe in Matthew Harrison Brady.
[Crowd] Amen!
Hallelujah, brother.
[Gavel pounding]
This man is acceptable to the prosecution.
[Judge]
Mr. Drummond
No questions. Not acceptable.
Does Mr. Drummond refuse this man a place on the jury
simply because he believes in the bible
If you find an evolutionist in this town,
you can refuse him.
I object to the defense attorney
rejecting a worthy citizen
Without so much as asking
him a question
All right, I'll ask him a question.
How are you
Well... kind of hot.
Me, too.
Excused.
[Laughing]
[Gavel pounding]
You are excused from jury duty, Jessie.
You may step down.
Your honor,
I object to the note of levity
which the counsel for the defense
is introducing into these proceedings.
The court agrees with you in spirit, Col. Brady.
And I object to all this Col. Brady talk.
I am not familiar with Mr. Brady's military record.
Well, he was made honorary colonel
in our state militia the day he arrived in Hillsboro.
Well, the use of the title prejudices the case of my client.
It calls up a picture of the prosecution
a stride a white horse
a blaze in the uniform of a military colonel
and with all the forces of right and righteousness
marshaled behind him.
Well, we certainly want to give you
a fair hearing in this courtroom.
We don't want anything prejudicial to your client.
What do you suggest we do, counselor
Break him. Make him a private.
I have no serious objection
to the honorary title of Private Brady.
[Crowd murmuring]
You better do something about this, Jason.
Get him up here.
Oh, Mr. drummond.
You know our mayor, Mr. Drummond.
Yes.
I believe he has a suggestion to make
By, uh, by authority of, uh...
well, I'm sure the governor won't have
any objection--
I hereby appoint you, Mr. Drummond,
a temporary honorary colonel in the state militia.
Well...
Well, gentlemen, what can I say
it certainly is not every day
that a man attains the exalted position
of temporary honorary colonel.
I thank you.
Col. Brady,
Col. Drummond,
You will examine the next venireman.
Mort.
George Sillers!
You're next,
George.
State your name and occupation, George
George Sillers. I work at the feed store.
Tell me, sir, would you call yourself a religious man
Well, I guess I'm as religious as the next fellow.
in Hillsboro, sir, that means a great deal.
[Crowd agreeing]
Tell me, Mr. sillers,
Do you have any children
Uh, not as I know of.
[Laughing]
If you had a son, Mr. Sillers, or a daughter
what would you think if that sweet child
came home from school
and told you that a godless teacher-
Objection! We're supposed to be
selecting jury members.
The prosecution is denouncing the defendant
before the trial has even begun.
Objection sustained.
Mr. Sillers, do you have any personal opinions
with regard to
the defendant
that might prejudice you on his behalf
Cates
Hmm.
I don't hardly know the man.
Though he bought some peat moss from me one time.
H-he paid his bill.
Mr. Sillers impresses me
as an honest, god-fearing man.
I accept him.
Thank you,
Col. Brady.
Col. Drummond
Now, Mr. Sillers,
You, ah, you have just said that, ah, you were a religious man.
Do you work at it very hard
Well, I'm pretty busy down at the feed store
My wife tends the religion for both of us.
Oh, I see, I see.
You take care of this life,
and she takes care of the next
one, is that it
that is objected to as immaterial
and argumentative.
[Judge] objection sustained.
Now, tell me, Mr. Sillers,
While your wife has been taking care of the religion for the family
have you ever heard of a fellow called Charles Darwin
Oh, not till recent.
Well, tell me something.
From what you've heard of this fellow Darwin,
do you think he's the kind of a man
you might invite up for Sunday dinner
Your honor, my worthy opponent from Chicago
is cluttering up the issue with hypothetical questions.
I have already established
that Mr. Sillers is not working very hard at religion.
Now, for your sake
I'm trying to establish
that he is not
working at evolution.
Oh, I'm just working at the feed store.
[Laughing]
[Gavel pounding]
Mr. Sillers, do you think you can render impartial--
Objection! The prosecution has already accepted this man.
But all I want is a fair trial.
So do I.
Unless the state of mind
of the members of the jury
conforms to the laws and patterns of society--
Oh, conform, conform. what
do you want to do
run the jury through a meat grinder
to have them all come out the same
Take a box seat there, Mr. Sillers
Your honor! Your honor! this is ludicrous!
Gentlemen, you are both out of order.
The bench rules that the jury has been selected.
Due to the excessive heat
court is adjourned until 10:00 tomorrow morning.
[Chattering]
Ah, one moment, please. one moment
Order in the court
Rev. Brown has asked me to announce
"Pray for justice and guidance." All are invited.
Your honor, I object to that commercial announcement.
commercial announcement
of the Rev. brown's product.
Why don't you announce
that there's going to be an evolution meeting
I have no knowledge of such a meeting.
That's quite understandable.
It isn't enough
that everybody who comes into this courtroom
has to pass under a sign which says
read your bible.
I want that sign taken down, your honor.
[Crowd]
No! No!
Or else I want another sign put up
just as big with just as big letters
which says read your Darwin.
[Cheering and booing]
That's what I mean about this man.
[Judge] order!
Your honor, your honor, we want the learned counsel from the North
to get every fairness and consideration
in this trial.
We must not forget that he is our guest.
Guest, hell! I'm a lawyer in a courtroom.
Then behave like a lawyer.
Stop using this courtroom
as a platform for your obscene ideas
trying to dirty the minds of our young people here.
You are both out of order. Court is adjourned.
My conduct in this courtroom is not under question,
and certainly not by you!
Well, your language is!
I don't swear just for the hell of it!
Language is a poor enough means of communication.
I think we should use all the words we've got.
Besides, there are damned few words that anybody understands!
Henry Drummond, atheist!
You! what are you going to say in your paper now
"He that sups with the devil must
have a long spoon."
[Chattering]
[Man] Let's go.
Let's go folks, clear the floor.
We'll fix you, Cates. we'll run you out of town.
Well, anyway,
the Baltimore Herald is with you...
right up to the lynching.
Bert...
Bert, you've got to call the whole
thing off now.
who are you, young lady
This is Rachel Brown. We're engaged.
Brown Rev. Brown's daughter
Don't you see what's happening, Bert
They're using you as a weapon against your own people.
What you think or believe isn't the point anymore.
You're helping something bad.
No, young lady, it's not as simple as all that--
good or bad, black or white , day or night.
do you know that at the top of the world
the twilight is 6 months long
Bert and I don't live on top of the world.
We live in Hillsboro.
and when the sun goes down, it's dark.
And why do you have to come here to make it different
I didn't come here to make Hillsboro different.
I came here to defend his right to be different.
And that's the point.
How about it, boy
I don't know what the point is anymore.
I tried to open their kids'
minds...their kids.
I tried to give them knowledge they could use.
they're using it-- as a stranglehold on me.
[Hornbeck]
You're learning, Cates.
Disillusionment is what little heroes are made of
Where do I finish dead with a paper
medal on my chest
"Bert Cates, world's biggest chump-- he died fighting."
Let's face it-- to him, I'm a headline. To you, I'm a cause.
And to yourself
All right, let's face it.
Now, you chose to get into this
by yourself.
You didn't get into it because of his headline
or because of my cause,
or maybe even because of their kids.
You got in to it because of yourself--
Because of something you believed in
for yourself.
I didn't believe it would happen this way.
It can get worse.
Those people are in a lean and hungry mood.
They look at me as if I was a murderer.
[Chuckling] In a way, you are.
You know, you-- you kill one of their fairy-tale notions,
and they'll bring down
the wrath of god, Brady and the state legislature on you every time.
You make a joke out of everything.
Young lady
I know what Bert is going through.
It's the loneliest
feeling in the world.
It's like walking down an empty street
listening to your own footsteps.
But all you have to do is to knock on any door
and say, "if you'll let me in,
"I'll live the way you want me to live,
and I'll think the way "you want me to think,"
and all the blinds will go up,
and all the doors will open,
and you'll never be lonely, ever again.
Now, it's up to you, Cates.
You just say the word, and we'll change the plea--
th-that is, of course, if you honestly believe that the law is right
and you're wrong.
Now, if that's the case, just tell me,
and I'll pack my bag and go back to Chicago
where it's a nice, cool 100
in the shade.
Bert, I've gone to my father's church
every sunday as long as I can remember.
This is where I live.
This is where my children will be born.
What kind of a life could we have
Well, what kind of a life could we have if I gave up now
your father's kind
Hallelujah, and ignorance, here we come
Rach, what goes on in this town is not necessarily
the christian religion everyplace else.
Rach, I can't live the way you want me to
You're the one who's got to decide.
It's his church or our house.
You can't live in both.
[Mort] sorry, Bert.
I have to take you back now.
You ever been in love, Hornbeck
Only with the sound of my own words, thank God.
I have been to their cities
and I have seen the altars upon which they sacrifice
the futures of their children to the gods of science.
And what are their rewards
confusion and self-destruction.
New ways to kill each other in wars
I tell you, gentlemen, the way of scientism is the way of darkness
Now, Mr. Brady, do you, ah, believe
seriously
that the majority of the American people
hold with your views
not just the views
of Matthew Harrison
Brady, Mr. Hornbeck.
There isn't one state in the union
where the evolutionists are in the majority.
It'll be the people themselves of our great land who will speak.
Mr. Brady, how do you account for the unfortunate comment
that your crusade has aroused
the attacks upon me stem from a vociferous minority
which happens to control the press.
I hope you gentlemen--
madam--
will not be influenced by this same negative bias.
Pardon me.
Thank you, O lord, dear father,
from whom all blessings flow, for thy bounty,
make us worthy of thy grace, amen.
Go ahead, Henry. I said grace
for you, too.
God may be a Matter of indifference
to the evolutionists,
and the life beyond hold no charms for them...
[Whispers] Sarah.
[Brady] But the mass of mankind will continue to worship.
Here, sit with me.
Thank you.
He'll be busy for a while.
Well, where is it, where is it
The hat with the little blue feather
Blue feather
You used to wear it to all the conventions. it was much too becoming.
[Chuckling]
Oh, Henry!
And whatever happened
to that skinny black tie you used to wear
Not very attractive... like an old shoelace.
It's back in the shoe.
how are you, Sarah
how are you
a little grayer, Henry. And you
A little grimmer.
I don't believe it. I watched you in court today.
You seemed to be enjoying it as much as ever.
That's Matt. He brings out the worst in me.
We've missed you, Henry.
You don't make many good friends in a lifetime.
I never dreamed our ideas would separate us.
[Brady] I have reason to be.
I have messages of encouragement
from the governors of 22 states.
He still has a loud voice.
He still has something to say, Henry.
You mean about how everybody else should live
Oh, don't be cynical.
I think every man longs to be his brother's keeper
and to be cared for in return.
It sounds more convincing coming from you.
He doesn't have a blue feather in his hat, that's all.
[Chuckling]
You know, looking back,
I don't think Matt would have made a great president,
But I would have voted for him for king..
just to have you for queen.
and what would you have been
Your majesty's loyal opposition.
[Brady] "...of our belief in the written word of the bible.
I believe that Hillsboro..."
Pardon me,
"...will become the shrine
of all" those millions upon millions
"who find a rallying point
"for their expression of God's will."
Now, that's all for today, gentlemen.
Hearken to the word!
The word tells us
that the world was created in 6 days.
In the beginning, the earth
was without form, and void,
and the lord said, "Let there be light."
[Crowd] Yeah! Yeah!
And there was light!
Amen!
And the lord saw the light, and the light saw the lord
And the light said, am I good, lord
And the lord said, thou art good.
[Cheering]
And the evening and the morning
were the 1st day.
and the lord said, "Let there be
a firmament."
And even as he spoke, it was so.
And the evening and the morning were the 2nd day!
On the 3rd day,
Brought he forth the dry land,
and the grass, and the fruit tree,
and on the 4th day, the sun, the moon and the stars,
and he pronounced them good.
The 5th day peopled he the
sea with fish
and the air with fowl,
and made he the great whale,
and he blessed them all!
[Crowd cheering]
But...
on the morning of the 6th day,
the lord rose, and his eye was dark,
and the scowl lay across his face.
Why
Why was the lord troubled
Why tell us!
Tell us the troubles of the lord!
The lord looked around him, did the lord, at all his handiwork
Bowed down before him, and he said,
"It is not good! It is not enough!
It is not finished!"
"I shall make me...
a man!"
[Crowd cheering]
Do we believe
[All]
Yes!
Do we believe the word
Do we believe the truth of the word
Yes!
Do we curse the man who denies the word
Do we call down hellfire
on the man who has sinned against the word
Yes!
Whatever happened to silent prayer
O lord of the tempest and the thunder,
strike down this sinner
as thou did thine enemies of old
in the days of the pharaohs.
Let him know the terror of thy sword!
Let his soul for all eternity
writhe in anguish and damnation!
No!
No, Pa!
Don't pray to destroy Bert!
Lord, we ask the same curse
for those who ask grace for this sinner
though they be blood of my blood
and flesh of my flesh!
Rev. Brown, Rev-
Rev. Brown, I know it's the great zeal of your faith
which makes you utter this prayer,
but it is possible to be overzealous,
to destroy that which you hope to save
so that nothing is left but emptiness.
remember the wisdom of solomon
in the book of proverbs--
"he that troubleth
his own house"
shall inherit the wind."
The bible also tells us that God forgives his children,
and we as children of God should forgive each other
My good friends, return to your homes.
Go home.
The blessings of the lord be with you all.
We'll take you home, my dear.
I can't go home. He hates me.
He doesn't hate you.
He damned me. My own father damned me to hell.
No man has the power to damn.
He's always done it.
He did it to Bert and the little Stebbins boy.
Stebbins boy
That's how the whole thing started.
the Stebbins boy was just an innocent child.
[Mr. Brady] God has no wrath for the innocent, my dear.
That's what Bert said.
He u--he used to say that when we-- when we were together.
I-if I could justexplain it clearly,
then you'd understand.
Mr. Brady, please, I--
We'll do all we can to help you.
Come. Now, let's go home.
I'll be right up, Sarah.
All right, Matt.
Good night, Henry.
[Drummond] good night.
You're up late.
Too hot to sleep.
No use trying to fool ourselves, Henry
We're just not the men we used to be.
Ha ha!
By the size of that meal you packed away tonight,
I'd say you hadn't changed in 40 years.
[Laughing]
Funny how 2 people
can start from the same point and...
drift apart.
It's the nature of the life process.
There used to be a mutuality of understanding and...
admiration between us, Henry.
Why is it, my old friend, that you've...
you've moved so far away from me
Well, all motion is relative, Matt.
Maybe it's you who have moved away by standing still.
Hmm.
If progress means abandoning God
abandoning the faith of our fathers--
I saw a demonstration of that faith tonight.
it's a pretty deadly instrument, I'd say.
What you saw was a reflection
of the violence and hate
in the world around them,
Henry-- your world
But they're driven to it
because their faith was challenged.
These are simple people, Henry, poor people.
they work hard
and they need to believe in something...
something beautiful.
They're seeking for something
more perfect than what they have
Window shopping for heaven.
why do you want to take it away from them, Henry
it's all they have...
like a golden chalice of hope.
[Chuckling] Ah.
Like my golden dancer.
Your what?
Golden dancer.
She stood in the big side window
in the general store in Wakeman, Ohio.
I'd stand out on the street and say to myself,
"if I had golden dancer, I'd have everything in the world I ever wanted."
I was about 7 years old
at the time and a great
judge of rocking horses.
Golden dancer had a bright-red mane, blue eyes,
and she was gold all over with purple spots.
And when the sun hit her stirrups,
She was a dazzling sight to behold.
But she was a week's wages for my father,
So golden dancer and I
always had a big plate-glass window between us.
And then...
Let's see...
It couldn't have been christmas.
It must have been my birthday.
I woke in the morning,
and there was golden dancer
at the foot of my bed.
Mom had skimped on the groceries,
and my father had worked nights for a month.
I jumped into the saddle,
and I started to rock...
and it broke.
No
Split in 2. The wood was rotten.
The whole thing was put together
with spit and sealing wax.
All shine and no substance,
And that's how I feel about that demonstration I saw tonight, Matt--
All glitter and glamour.
You say you're giving the people hope
I think you're stealing their hope.
Oh no, Henry --
[sighing]
As long as the prerequisite for that shining paradise
is ignorance, bigotry, and hate...
I say, "the hell with it."
[Door closing]
We had to keep an open mind on the origin of species.
Very interesting, Howard.
Very interesting.
Now, go on, Howard
tell us what else Mr. Cates told you
in the classroom
Well, he said at first
the earth was too hot for any kind of life.
then it cooled off a mite,
and cells and things began to grow.
cells
Oh...oh!
Mr. McKinnon.
Mr. Galbraith.
I think you know the rest of these gentlemen.
[Gavel pounding]
Ahem.
Cells, Howard.
Little bugs, like in the water.
then the little bugs got to be bigger bugs,
and sprouted legs and crawled up on the land.
How long did this take according to Mr. Cates
Couple million years...maybe longer.
Then comes the fishes and the reptiles and the mammals.
Man's a mammal.
Along with the dogs...
and the cattle in the field
Did he say that
Yes, sir.
Now, Howard,
How does man come out of this slimy mess
of bugs and serpents,
according to your, uh, professor
Well, man was sort of evoluted...
from the old-world monkeys.
Did you hear that, my friends
old-world monkeys!
Ha!
According to Mr. Cates,
you and I aren't even descended
from good American monkeys.
Now Howard, listen, carefully.
in all this talk of bugs and evolution
of slime and ooze,
did Mr. Cates ever make any reference to God
[Sighing] not as I remember.
of the miracle he achieved in 7 days
as described in the beautiful book of genesis
No, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen--
Objection!
I ask the court to remind the learned counsel
that he is not in a Chautauqua tent.
He's supposed to be submitting evidence to a jury.
There are no ladies on the jury.
Your honor...I have no intention of making a speech
there is no need.
I am sure that everyone on the jury,
everyone within the sound of this boy's voice
is moved by his tragic confusion.
He has been taught
that he wriggled up like an animal
from the filth and muck below.
I say that these bible haters,
these evolutionists, are brewers of poison!
and the legislature of this sovereign state
has had the wisdom to demand
that the peddlers of poison, in bottles or in books,
clearly label the product they attempt to sell.
I say that if this law is not upheld,
this boy will become one of a generation
shorn of its faith by the teachings of godless science!
But, if the full penalty of the law
is meted out to Bertram Cates,
the faithful the whole world over
who are watching us here and listening to our every word
will rise up and call this courtroom blessed!
Your witness, Sir.
I sure am glad the colonel didn't make a speech.
[Laughing]
Now, Howard...
I heard you say that the world used to get pretty hot.
Well, that's what Mr. Cates said.
Any hotter than it is right now, do you think
Well, I guess it must have been.
Mr. Cates read it to us from a book.
This the book
Charles Darwin's theory
of the evolution and the descent of man
Yes, sir.
That's right, Howard.
That's the very book
He read to you in your classroom.
Now, Howard, tell me,
do you think there was anything wrong in that
Well, I don't know
Objection, your honor.
The defense is asking that
a 15-year-old boy hand down an opinion
on a question of morality.
I am trying to establish that Howard,
or Col.Brady, or Charles Darwin,
or anyone sitting in this courtroom, or you, sir,
has the right to think.
Col. Drummond, the right to think
is not on trial here.
Well, with all due respect to the court, sir,
I think the right to think
is very much on trial here...
and it is fearfully in danger in
the proceedings of this courtroom.
A man is on trial!
A thinking man!
and he's faced with fine and imprisonment
because he chooses to speak what he thinks.
Col. Drummond,
will you please, ah, rephrase your question
Well now, let's put it this way, Howard--
all this fuss and feathers about evolution--
do you think it hurt you any
Sir
Did it do you any harm
Still feel reasonably fit
what Mr. Cates told you,
Did it, ah, did it hurt your baseball game any
did it affect your pitching arm
No, sir.
I'm a lefty.
A south paw, huh
Still honor your father and your mother
Sure.
Haven't murdered anybody since breakfast, have you
Objection.
This is an absurd piece of jactitation.
Ahem.
Counsel uses a word
with which, ah, the bench is not familiar.
Jactitation--
A specious or false premise.
in this instance,
as to the murder of known or unknown persons.
Objection
Sustained.
Ahem.
Ask him if his faith in the holy scriptures has been shattered.
When I need your help, Col.Brady,
you may rest assured I shall humbly ask for it.
Anytime, Col. Drummond, anytime.
He's the only man I know
who can strut sitting down.
Now, Howard, tell me something--
did you believe everything Mr. Cates told you
I'm not sure.
I gotta think about it.
Good for you.
Now, uh, uh, your Pa's a farmer, isn't he
Yes, sir.
Got a tractor
Brand-new one.
You think there's anything sinful about a tractor
because it isn't mentioned in the bible
No.
You know, Moses never made a phone call.
You figure that makes the telephone
an instrument of the devil
I never thought of it that way.
Neither did anybody else!
Your honor, the defense makes the same old error
of all godless men--
he confuses material things
with the great spiritual value of the revealed word.
Why do you bewilder this child
Does right have no meaning to you, sir
Realizing that I may prejudice the case of my client,
I must tell you
that right has no meaning for me whatsoever.
[Murmuring]
But truth has meaning...as a direction!
But...
it is one of the peculiar imbecilities of our time
that we place a grid of morality upon human behavior
so that the action of every man
must be measured against a...
an arbitrary latitude of right
and a longitude of wrong
in exact minutes, degrees, and seconds, so...
Howard, do you know what the heck...
do you understand what I'm talking about
No, sir.
Maybe someday you will.
That's all, son.
Thank you. you're excused.
This boy may not
understand, but I do.
I've seen what you can do to a jury--
twist and tangle them.
Nobody's forgotten the Endicott publishing case,
where you made the jury believe the obscenity was in their own minds
It was immoral, what you did to the jury.
tricking them, judgment by confusion.
you think you can get away with it here
I'm not trying to get away with anything!
I am simply trying to prevent the clock-stoppers
from dumping a lot of medieval nonsense
into the United States constitution.
this is not a federal court, Col. Drummond.
Well, damn it, you have to start from somewhere!
Your honor, it's obvious what he's trying to do--
he is trying to make us forget the lawbreaker
and put the law on trial
Well, we have the answer for you in our next witness.
Call miss Rachel Brown to the stand.
[Bailiff] Rachel Brown!
[Clerk] Rachel Brown, come to the stand, please!
Did you know about this
He didn't, but we should have.
Rach
Rach, what did you tell him
Take it easy, son.
Sit down, Samson.
You're about to get a haircut.
Rachel, do you solemnly swear
the testimony you're about to give
is the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth,
so help you God
I do.
Now, my dear,
I just want you to repeat
some of the things you told me last night.
Please, Mr. Brady...
Rachel, didn't you say you wanted the people here to understand
Yes.
Then just answer my question.
Now, Miss Brown,
you are an old friend of the efendant, Bertram Cates
We're...we're engaged to be married.
Do you and Mr. Cates attend the same church
Yes...we did.
Do you now
What?
Attend the same church
No.
Did Mr. Cates leave the church
No, not really.
Not the spirit of it.
But the body of it, correct
Mr. Cates left the church
you and he once attended together
Yes.
Why
Because of the Stebbins boy.
The Stebbins boy.
Would you tell us about that, please
It was 2 summers ago.
The little Stebbins boy was 13 years old.
He was one of Bert's students.
He lived right next door to the boarding house,
and he used to come over
And look through
Bert's microscope.
Bert said the boy had a bright mind
and--and he might even be a scientist when he grew up.
Yes
He--he went to the river with the other boys a-and went swimming.
He...
he got a cramp...
and drowned.
Go on.
At the funeral,
Pa preached that tommy didn't die in a state of grace
because... because his father wouldn't allow him
to be baptized.
Tell him what your father really said,
that tommy's soul was damned, writhing in hellfire!
Cates, you sinner!
Religion's supposed to comfort people,
Not frighten them to death!
[Crowd murmuring]
[Gavel pounding]
We will have order, please.
Now, sit down, Bert.
Don't you see
Bert thought it wasn't fair
that a little child couldn't go to heaven!
It wasn't God he abandoned, only the church!
Very well, my dear. It is true, then,
that because of what happened to the Stebbins boy,
Bert Cates left the church!
We've said nothing wrong.
We are merely beginning to gain some insight
into the experiences that sometimes will lead a young man astray.
Objection!
Whether my client went astray
is a Matter of interpretation.
Strike it from the record.
Objection sustained.
The jury is directed
to disregard the remarks of counsel.
Very well.
Now, my dear, will you tell the jury
some more of Mr. Cates' opinions
on the subject of religion
Objection!
Hearsay evidence is not admissible.
The court sees no objection to this line of questioning.
Proceed, Col. Brady.
Just repeat, in your own words, some of the conversations
you had with the defendant.
Rachel, you can't.
The things I said to you
were questions-- questions you ask your own heart.
If you say those things out loud,
he'll make them sound like answers.
I--I can't.
You won't hurt him, Rachel. This
is for his good.
Speak up.
Mr. Brady, I confided in you--
Well, we're here to serve the truth, Rachel, only the truth.
I can't remember.
Rachel, you are testifying under oath.
It is unlawful to withhold pertinent information.
Describe to the court your innermost feelings
when Bert Cates said to you,
"God did not create man. Man created god."
Bert didn't say that!
He was just bitter
because of the little Stebbins boy!
He said man created a vengeful god
out of his own bigotry
and the devil out of his own hell!
And when he wondered what's on the other side of the moon,
did he ever mention the possibility of heaven did he
or did he say there was nothing
but a world of stars, moons, galaxies, and universal dust
Tell us, tell us some more.
What'd he say about the holy state of matrimony
Did he compare it to animal breeding
[Drummond] Objection!
You want the good people of this town
to see what happened to his brain
so they can help bring him back to his senses, don't ya
Tell it! Tell it all!
Tell it! Tell it! Tell it!
Matt!
[Sobbing]
Under the circumstances...
I believe the witness... should be excused.
Col. Drummond, do you have any objection
to excusing the witness
from cross- examination at this time,
subject to later recall
Well, your honor, the defense must have a chance
to challenge the words
put into the mouth of the witness by the prosecutor.
Don't plague her. Let her go.
Uh, may I have a moment
Do you want every word he just put in her mouth
to go in to the record
It's not that important.
Not th-- he just pulled you apart like a plucked chicken.
Please, do as I say. You've got to.
I've got to what
send you to jail
Let her go.
You all-American idiot,
She just handed them your head on a silver platter.
Damn it, stay out of this!
It's none of your business.
Don't tie my hands, son.
Let her go, or I'll change my plea to guilty.
No questions.
For the time being, the witness is excused.
May I have your autograph
[Judge] Does the, uh, prosecution wish to call any further witnesses
Not, uh, not at the present time, your honor.
The prosecution rests.
We shall proceed with the case for the defense,
Col. Drummond.
I'd like to call Dr. Amos Keller...
the head of the department of zoology
at the University of Chicago.
Objection!
On what grounds
I wish to inquire what possible relevance
the testimony of a zoology professor
can have in this trial
Why, it has every relevance.
My client is on trial for teaching evolution.
Certainly any testimony relating to
his so-called infringement of the law
must be admitted.
Irrelevant, immaterial, inadmissible.
But why
if Bertram Cates were on trial for murder,
would it be irrelevant to call in witnesses
to examine the weapon
would it rule out testimony
that the so-called murder weapon
was incapable of firing a bullet
I fail to grasp, ah, the learned counsel's meaning.
Oh.
Uh, well, your honor,
The defense wishes to place Dr. Keller on the stand
so that he can explain to the gentlemen of the jury
ah, the exact meaning of the theory of evolution.
How can they pass judgment if they don't know what it's all about
I hold that the very law we're here to enforce
excludes such testimony!
The people of this state have made it very clear
that they do not want this zoological hogwash
slopping around the schoolrooms,
and I refuse to allow these agnostic scientists
to employ this courtroom as a sounding board
as a platform
from which they can shout their heresies
into the headlines
Col. Drummond,
the bench rules that zoology is irrelevant to the case.
Agnostic scientists
Ahem.
I call Dr. Allen Page,
deacon of the congregational church
and professor of geology and archaeology
at Oberlin College.
Objection.
Objection sustained.
Uh, does your honor deny in one breath
The existence of zoology, geology and archaeology
we do not deny the existence of these sciences,
but they do not relate to this point of law.
[Sighing]
I call Walter Aaronson,
anthropologist, philosopher, author,
and one of the most brilliant minds in the world today. Any objection
Objection!
Your honor, the defense has brought to Hillsboro,
at great expense and great inconvenience, 6 noted scientists.
their testimony is basic
to the defense of my client...
for I intend to show this court
that what Bertram Cates spoke quietly one spring morning
in the Hillsboro high school is no crime.
It is incontrovertible as geometry
to any enlightened community of minds.
in this community, Col. Drummond,
and in this sovereign state,
exactly the opposite is the case.
The language of the law is clear, your honor.
We do not need experts
to question the validity of a law already on the books.
Well, what do you need a gallows to hang him from.
That remark is an insult to this entire community.
And this community is an insult to the world!
[Crowd murmuring]
Your honor, I request permission to withdraw from this case.
Mr. Drummond, you can't quit now!
Why not you were ready to 5 minutes ago!
Col. Drummond,
What reasons canyou possibly have
Well, there are 200 of them!
And if that's not enough, there's one more--
I think my client has already been found guilty.
Is Mr. Drummond saying that this expression of an honest emotion
will in any way influence
the court's impartial
administration of the law
I say that you cannot administer
a wicked law impartially.
You can only destroy.
You can only punish.
And I warn you
that a wicked law, like cholera,
destroys everyone it touches,
its upholders as well as its defiers.
[Judge] Col. Drummond--
Can't you understand...
that if you take a law like evolution
and you make it a crime to
teach it in the public schools,
tomorrow you can make it a crime
to teach it in the private schools
and tomorrow you may make it a
crime to read about it
and soon you may ban
books and newspapers.
and then you may turn
catholic against protestant
and protestant against protestant
and try to foist your own religion
upon the mind of man!
If you can do one, you can do the other!
Because fanaticism and ignorance
is forever busy
and needs feeding.
and soon, your honor...
with banners flying and with drums beating,
we'll be marching backward!
Backward!
Through the glorious ages of that 16th century
when bigots burned the man who dared bring
enlightenment and intelligence to the human mind.
I hope counsel does not mean to imply
that this court is bigoted.
Well, your honor has the right to hope.
I have the right to do more than that.
You have the power to do more than that!
And I exercise that power.
Col. Drummond, I order you to show cause
tomorrow morning at 10:00
Why you should not be held in contempt
of this court.
And in the meanwhile, I order that you be held
in custody of the bailiff.
bail is fixed at $2,000.
$2,000--
Why don't you make it $4,000
It's $4,000, Col. Drummond.
Your honor, my paper will post the bond.
Can you prove legal authorization
to make such a commitment for your employer
Well, I'll wire my paper immediately.
Fine. Until then,
Col. Drummond can avail himself
of our municipal accommodations.
[Crowd murmuring]
Your honor
your honor, sir
I'll put up my farm for Mr. Drummond.
[Judge] We have no way of ascertaining
the value of your farm, sir.
it ought to be worth that much.
The law demands that bond be posted in cash.
Your honor, my bank will honor the offer
on the security of this farm.
He has considerably more equity in it than that.
Ahem.
Very well.
you can make arrangements with the court clerk.
Who are you
my name is John Stebbins.
[Judge] Court will adjourn
and reconvene at 10:00 a.m. tomorrow.
We'll hang Bert Cates
to a sour apple tree
Our god is marching on
glory, glory hallelujah
glory, glory hallelujah...
She'll sleep all right tonight.
Give her these pills tomorrow
and keep her in bed.
Thank you, John.
Rachel
We'll hang Bert Cates
to a sour apple tree
our god is marching on
glory, glory hallelujah
His truth is marching on
We'll hang Bert Cates
to a sour apple tree
our god is marching on
We'll hang Henry Drummond
to a sour apple tree
Our god is...
[Knocking at door]
glory, glory hallelujah
His truth is marching on...
trick or treat.
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Hooligans of the world, unite!
You've got nothing to burn
but your intellectuals.
Well, those are the boobs that make our laws.
It's a democratic process.
Well, I suppos e you have something better to suggest.
We'll hang Henry Drummond
to a sour apple tree...
Looks like you're going out
in a blaze of glory, counselor.
Well...
you were pretty impressive
for a while there today, Henry.
"your honor, after a while
you'll be setting" man against man,
"creed against creed, et cetera, et cetera,
ad nauseam."
Aw, Henry, why don't you wake up
Darwin was wrong.
man's still an ape,
and his creed's still a totem pole
when he first achieved
the upright position,
he took a look at the stars--
thought they were something to eat.
When he couldn't reach them,
he decided they were groceries
belonging to a bigger creature.
that's how Jehovah was born.
I wish I had your worm's-eye view of history.
It would certainly make things a lot easier.
Oh-oh, no! Not for you!
No, no, you--you'd still be spending your time
trying to make sense
out of what is laughingly referred to
as the human race.
Why don't you take your blinders off
Don't you know the future's already obsolete
You think man still has a noble destiny.
Well, I tell you, he's already started
on his backward march
to the salt and stupid sea from which he came.
What about men like Bert Cates
Cates
The monkey who tried to fly
Cates climbed to the top of the totem pole
but...then he jumped,
and there was nobody there to catch him--
not even you.
You were there.
You saw what they did to my witnesses.
What you need is a drink.
What I need is a miracle.
A miracle
Here's a whole bagful--
courtesy Matthew Harrison Brady.
Your honor...
Your honor, I, uh...
I feel I owe you an apology.
Any remarks leading up to the contempt citation
I regret very much.
I realize your honor is trying to be fair and
I, uh... I'm very sorry for any remarks
that were made in the heat of the moment.
My friends...
Col. Drummond...
the man that I believe came into the world
to save mankind from sin
taught that it was godly to forgive.
I believe in those principles.
I accept Col. Drummond's apology.
I withdraw the contempt citation.
Thank you, your honor.
I, too, should like to add
that in the spirit of forgiveness,
I feel no animosity toward learned counsel
from Chicago.
He is well known to have ridden hobbyhorses before
perhaps he'll return to his home
having learned a lesson.
We commend him to learn in his heart
the words of him who said,
"if you thirst, come unto me,
"and I will give you life."
That's why he hasn't an enemy in the world--
only his friends hate him.
Ahem.
Perhaps, ah, there is much to learn
from the learned counsel for the prosecution.
Your honor, there were some remarks I made, ah, yesterday, ah,
namely that I wish to withdraw from the case.
If it please the court,
I shall like to withdraw my withdrawal
and continue as counsel for Bertram Cates.
[Judge] I see no reason why Col.Drummond
should not continue as counsel for the defense.
Proceed, Col. Drummond.
Thank you,
Thank you.
Your honor, the court, ah, has ruled out any evidence
as to scientific knowledge or the Darwinian theory.
would the court admit evidence--
expert evidence--
on a book known as the holy bible
Ahem.
Any objection, Col. Brady
If counsel can advance the case for the defendant
through the use of the holy scriptures,
the prosecution will take no exception.
Good. I call to the stand
one of the world's foremost experts
on the bible and its teachings--
Matthew Harrison Brady.
[Crowd mumbling, judge banging gavel]
Your honor, this is preposterous!
Brother, let us pray.
Well,
it's highly unorthodox
I've never known an instance
where the defense called the prosecuting
attorney as a witness.
Your honor, this entire trial
is unorthodox...
but if the interests
of right and justice will be served,
I will take the stand.
But, Col.Brady...
the court will support you
if you wish to decline to testify
as a witness against your own case.
Your honor,
I shall not testify against anything.
I shall speak out as I have all my life
on behalf of the living truth of the holy scriptures.
Col. Brady--
no, no, no.
That won't be necessary to swear him in.
Oh, I can make affirmation.
I have no objection to swearing to God.
[Chuckling] No. I take it you will tell the truth.
Now, sir, I-I-I am right
in calling upon you
as an authority on-- on the bible, am I not
I believe it is not boastful to say
that I have studied the bible as much as any layman,
and I have tried to live
according to its precepts.
Bully for you.
Now, I suppose you can quote me chapter and verse
Right straight through the King James version.
There are many portions of the holy bible
that I have committed to memory.
I don't suppose there are many portions of this book
you've committed to memory--
the origin of the species.
I am not the least interested
in the pagan hypotheses of that book.
[Drummond] Never read it
and I never will.
Then how in perdition have you got the gall
to whoop up this holy war
about something you don't know anything about
How can you be so cocksure
that the body of scientific knowledge
systematized in the writings of Charles Darwin
is in any way irreconcilable
with the book of genesis
Would you state that question again, please
Well now, let me put it this way.
On page 10 of the origin of the species,
Darwin states--
I object to this, your honor.
Col. Brady has been called
as an authority on the bible.
now the, ah... gentleman from Chicago
is using this opportunity
to read into the record scientific testimony
which you, your honor,
have previously ruled irrelevant.
If he's going to examine Col. Brady on the bible,
let him stick to the bible,
the holy bible and only the bible.
You will, uh, confine your questions to the bible.
All right.
Forget it.
We'll play in your ballpark, Colonel.
[Crowd chuckling]
Now a--a I'd like to get this part clear first.
Th-this is the book...this is the book th-that you're an authority on, isn't it
That is correct.
You believe that-- that every word written in this book
should be taken literally
everything in the bible should be accepted
exactly as
it is given there
now, what about this part right here
Where, uh...
Uh, it talks about, uh,
Jonah being swallowed by the whale
you figure that really happened
The bible do es not say "a whale."
It says "a big fish"
Heh heh heh.
[Chuckling] As a Matter of fact, it says a great fish."""
[Laughter]
But I guess one's pretty much the same as the other.
What do you...what do you think about that business
I believe in a god who can make a whale
and who can make a man
and make both do what he pleases.
God bless you, Matthew Harrison Brady.
[Crowd] Amen.
Hallelujah.
I want those Amen's in the record.
Now, I recollect a--a story about Joshua--
Joshua making the sun stand still.
Uh, as an expert, do you a...tell me
that that's a... as right as the Jonah business
That's a pretty neat trick.
I do not question or scoff
at the miracles of the lord
as do ye of little faith
Have you ever pondered
what would actually happen to the earth
if the sun stood still
You can testify to that if I get you on the stand.
[Laughing]
If, as they say, "the sun stood still,"
they must have had some kind of an idea
that the--that the sun moved around the earth.
Do you think that's the way of things
or don't you believe the earth moves around the sun
I have faith in the bible.
you don't have much faith in the solar system.
The sun stopped.
Good.
Now, if what you say actually happened--
if Joshua stopped the sun in the sky--
the earth stopped spinning on its axis,
continents toppled over one another,
mountains flew into space,
and the earth shriveled to a cinder,
crashed into the sun.
Now, how come they missed that little tidbit of news
they missed it because it didn't happen.
But it had to happen,
It must have happened according to natural law,
or don't you believe in natural law, Mr. Brady
would you--would you ban copernicus from the classroom
along with Charles Darwin
would you pass a law
throwing out all scientific knowledge since Joshua
revelations, period
Natural law was born
in the mind of the heavenly father.
he can change it, cancel it,
use it as he pleases
It constantly amazes me
that you apostles of science,
for all your supposed wisdom,
fail to grasp this simple fact.
Now...ahem.
Now listen to this.
This is genesis, 4 to 16.
"and Cain went out from the presence
of the lord,
and dwelt in" the land of nod,
"on the east of eden.
and Cain knew his wife."
Now, where the hell did she come from
Who
Mrs. Cain. Cain's wife.
If in the beginning there were just
Cain and Abel
and Adam and Eve,
where--where did this extra woman come from
d-did you ever stop to think about that
No, sir.
I leave the agnostics to hunt for her.
Ha ha ha!
[Laughing]
[Gavel pounding]
Never bothered you
Never bothered me.
Never tried to find out
Nope.
You figure somebody else pulled another creation
over in the next county somewhere
the bible satisfies me. It is enough.
It frightens me
to think of the state of learning in the world
if everybody had your driving curiosity.
Now this book goes into a lot of "begats."
"and Arphaxad begat Salah...
and salah begat Eber..."
and so on and so on and so on.
How, are these pretty important people
they are the generations
of the holy men and women
of the bible.
How'd they go about all this begatting
What do you mean
Well, I mean, did they a...
did they begat
in much the same way
as folks get themselves begat today
The process is about the same
I don't think your scientists
have improved it any.
Ha! Ha ha
[Laughing]
[Gavel pounding]
In other words,
all of these folks were conceived and brought forth
by the normal biological function known as sex.
What do you think of sex, Col.Brady
in what spirit is this question asked
[Chuckling] I'm not asking you
what you think of sex
as a father, as a husband,
or even as a presidential candidate.
you're up here as an expert on the bible.
What is the biblical evaluation of sex
It is considered original sin.
and all these holy people got themselves begat
through original sin
Well...
all that sinning make them any less holy
Your honor, where is this leading us
What has it got to do with
the State v. Bertram Cates
Col. Drummond, the court must be satisfied
that this line of questioning
has some bearing on the case.
You've ruled out all of my witnesses.
you must allow me to examine
the one witness you've left to me in my own way.
Your honor
I am willing to sit here
and endure Mr. Drummond's sneering
and his disrespect
for he is pleading
the case of the prosecution
by his contempt for all that is holy.
I object! I object! I object!
On what grounds
Is it possible that something is holy
to the celebrated agnostic
Yes--
The individual human mind.
in a child's power
to master the multiplication table,
there is more sanctity
than in all your shouted "Amens"
and "Holy holies"
and "Hosannas"!
An idea is a greater monument
than a cathedral,
and the advance of man's knowledge
is a greater miracle than all the sticks turned to snakes
or the parting of the waters.
But now,
are we to forgo all this progress
because Mr. Brady now frightens us with a fable
Gentlemen,
Progress has never been a bargain.
you have to pay for it.
sometimes I think there's a man who sits behind a counter
and says, "all right, you can have a telephone,
"but you lose privacy and the charm of distance."
Madam, you may vote, but at a price.
"you lose the right to retreat behind the powder puff"
or your petticoat
"Mister, you may conquer the air," will lose
their wonder...
but the birds
"and the clouds will smell of gasoline."
Darwin took us forward to a hilltop
from where we could look back
and see the way from which we came.
But for this insight and for this knowledge,
we must abandon our faith in the pleasant poetry of Genesis.
We must not abandon faith!
Faith is the most important thing!
Then why did God plague us with the power to think
Mr. Brady, why do you deny the one faculty of man
that raises him above the other creatures of the earth--
the power of his brain to reason
what other merit have we
the elephant is larger,
the horse is swifter and stronger,
the butterfly is far more beautiful,
the mosquito is more prolific,
even the simple sponge is more durable.
Or does a sponge think
I don't know.
I'm a man, not a sponge.
[Laughing]
Well, do you think a sponge thinks
If the lord wishes a sponge to think,
it thinks.
Do you think a man should have
the same privilege as a sponge
Of course.
This man wishes to be accorded
the same privilege as a sponge.
He wishes to think!
But your client is wrong!
He is deluded! he has lost his way!
It's sad that we don't all have
your positive knowledge of what is right and wrong,
Mr. Brady.
How old do you think this rock is
I am more interested in the rock of ages
than I am in the age of rocks.
Ha!
Ha ha
Dr. Page of Oberlin College
tells me this rock is at least 10 million years old.
Well, well ...
Col. Drummond,
you managed to sneak in
some of that scientific testimony after all.
Look, Mr. Brady...
these are the fossil remains
of a marine prehistoric creature
found in this very county
and which lived here millions of years ago
when these very mountain ranges
were submerged in water.
I know.
The bible gives a fine account of the flood.
But your professor's a little mixed-up on his dates.
That rock is not more than 6,000 years old.
How do you know
A fine biblical scholar, Bishop Usher,
has determined for us
the exact date and hour of the creation
it occurred in the year 4004 B.C.
Ah, well,
uh, that...
That's...that's, uh, Bishop Usher's opinion.
It's not an opinion.
It's a literal fact,
which the good Bishop arrived at
through careful computation
of the ages of the prophets
as set down in the old testament.
In fact,
he determined that the Lord began the creation
on the 23rd of october, 4004 B.C.
at, uh, 9 a.m.
At eastern standard time
or rocky mountain time
it wasn't daylight saving time, was it
because the lord didn't make the sun
until the 4th day.
That is correct.
That first day, uh...
Wha-what do you think it was,
24 hours long
Bible says it was a day.
Well, there was no sun
h-how do you know how long it was
The bible says it was a day.
Well, was it a normal day, a literal day, a 24-hour day
I don't know.
[Col. Drummond] what do you think
I do not think about things
that I do not think about.
Do you ever think about things
that you do think about
Isn't it possible
that it could have been 25 hours
there was no way to measure it.
No way to tell.
Could it have been 25 hours
It is possible.
then you interpret that the first day
as recorded in the book of Genesis
could have been a day of indeterminate length
I mean to state
that it is not necessarily a 24-hour day.
It could have been 30 hours,
It could have been a week.
It could have been a month, it could have been a year,
it could have been a hundred years,
or it could have been 10 million years!
I protest!
This is not only irrelevant, immaterial,
it is illegal!
I demand to know the purpose
of Mr. Drummond's examination.
What's he trying to do
I'll tell you what he's trying to do.
He wants to destroy everybody's belief in the bible
and in God.
That's not true, and you know it.
The bible is a book.
It's a good book, but it is not the only book.
It is the revealed word of the almighty God
spake to the men who wrote the bible.
How do you know that god didn't spake to Charles Darwin
I know, because God tells me to oppose
the evil teachings of that man.
Oh, God speaks to you
Yes!
He tells you what is right and wrong,
Yes
and you act accordingly
Yes.
So you, Matthew Harrison Brady,
through oratory or legislature or whatever,
you pass on god's orders
to the rest of the world!
Well, meet the prophet from Nebraska!
Is that the way of things
is that the way of things
God tells Brady what is good.
to be against Brady is to be against God.
No! each man is a free agent!
Then what is Bertram Cates doing in a Hillsboro jail
supposing Mr. Cates had the influence and the lung power
to railroad through the state legislature
a law saying that only Darwin
could be taught in the schools
Ridiculous! Ridiculous!
There is only one great truth in the world.
The gospel--
the gospel according to Brady.
God speaks to Brady, and Brady tells the world!
Brady, Brady, Brady almighty!
The lord--the lord is my strength!
suppose that a lesser human being--
suppose a Cates or a Darwin
had the audacity to think that God might whisper to him,
that an un-Brady thought might still be holy
must a man go to prison because he differs
with the self-appointed prophet
extend the testaments.
Let us have a book of Brady.
We shall hex the Pentateuch
and slip you in neatly
between Numbers and Deuteronomy!
N-now, my friends...
Your honor, my followers..
ladies and gentlemen...
The witness is excused!
All of you know what I stand for.
What I believe...
I believe in the truth of the book of Genesis--
Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy,
Joshua, Judges, Ruth, 1st Samuel,
2nd Samuel, 1st Kings, 2nd Kings,
Isaiah, Jeremiah,
Lamentations,
Ezekiel...
[Judge] Court is adjourned until 10:00 tomorrow morning.
[Judge pounding gavel]
[Chattering]
Matt
Matt, dear
let's go home.
Home
Back to the hotel.
Uh.
[Knocking at door]
Who is it
Where is he
I've got to talk to him.
Not now, Rachel. He isn't feeling well.
Yes, now.
He's got to tell Bert it wasn't my fault
Rachel, please be quiet. He's sleeping.
Why should I be quiet
I want the whole world to know
that Matthew Harrison Brady's a fake.
Rachel!
I'm sorry.
I found myself in bed today,
in the middle of the day.
I-I was dreaming I was in the witness chair--
chained to it.
I kept begging him to let me go.
Oh, Rachel, Rachel, it's been a nightmare for all of us.
But mine was real.
I turned to your husband for help.
he encouraged me to open up my heart to him,
and then he twisted my words.
He tricked me.
Why why did he do it
I don't know.
I don't know why he did it.
Maybe it meant too much to him.
Maybe he was tired or afraid.
I taught my pupils
that Matthew Harrison Brady was a great man--
next to God, almost.
What do you want me to teach them now
He's still the same man.
No, if he could do such an evil thing,
then he must be an evil man,
and everything he stands for
must be evil, too.
Oh, stop it! stop it!
Youth can be so pure.
What do you know of good or evil
what do you understand
of the sum of a man's life
He betrayed me.
You betrayed yourself.
You see my husband as a saint,
and so he must be right in everything he says and does.
and then you see him as a devil,
and everything he says and does must be wrong.
Well, my husband's neither a saint nor a devil.
He's just a human being...
and he makes mistakes.
How can you defend him
it's not he I'm defending.
I'm defending the 40 years I've lived with this man
and watched him carry the burdens
of people like you.
If he's been wrong,
at least he stood for something.
What do you stand for
do you believe in Bertram Cates
I believe in my husband.
What do you believe in
Matt.
I was asleep, but...
What can I do for you, child
I'm not your child any longer,
Mr. Brady--
yours...
or anyone else's.
[Door closing]
What...
What did she want, Sarah
Whe's been hurt, Matt.
You hurt her.
Oh, Matt,
you were always a good man.
that's why I loved you,
even from the very beginning.
people said you made mistakes, wrong decisions.
you could have been president 3 times over,
but I never doubted you, Matt,
because your decisions were honest.
You never sacrificed your principles just to win.
I didn't mean to hurt her.
Sarah...
Sarah, a victory here
would be a monument to God
that would last a 1,000 years!
but Matt,
every man has to build his own monument.
You can't do it for them, Matt.
If you do, it becomes your monument, not theirs,
and they'll topple it the minute they find a flaw in it.
you mean a flaw in me, don't you, Sarah
they turned away from you this afternoon, Matt.
Ah, they didn't understand.
I'll make them understand.
They'll have to understand.
My speech. Where's my speech
Matt...
I'll make them listen.
Matt!
Where's my speech I must have it!
I'll make them understand!
Matt, please don't get excited.
Here--here it is. I have it all down on paper here.
Sarah.
It isn't just this case.
It's god himself that's on trial.
They'll--they'll have to listen to me.
They will listen to me.
They'll listen, dear.
Mother, they laughed at me.
Hush, baby.
I can't stand it when they laugh at me.
It's all right, baby.
It's all right.
They laughed.
Baby...
Ahem.
Testing, testing,
1, 2, 3, 4.
1, 2, 3, 4,
testing.
Testing, 1, 2, 3, 4.
1, 2, 3, 4
[Chattering]
You brought me some more clean shirts
Bert, I left my father.
I messed things up pretty badly
for us, didn't I
It wasn't your fault, Rach.
I know how Brady can twist things--
It wasn't his fault.
I should have done this from the beginning.
I-I want--
Rach...
You don't have to say it.
I'm just glad you're here.
Come on, you sit down.
Well, welcome back to our side, Miss Brown.
What's that
Enunciator
doing a broadcast
got a direct wire to WGN, chicago.
as soon as the jury returns,
we'll broadcast the verdict.
Mmm, radio.
God, that's going to break down a lot of walls.
You're not supposed to say "God" on the radio.
Why the hell not
You're not supposed to say "hell," either
This is going to be a barren source of amusement.
Well, Colonel...
There's a little toy you'll never have any use for,
not with your lungs.
Uh, the radio.
You whisper into it, and it shouts at a million people
through loudspeakers.
What do you think
Can you tell from their faces
Everybody rise.
Hear ye, hear ye. court will reconvene
in the case of the State v. Bertram Cates.
All right. Go ahead
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Harry Esterbrook
speaking to you from the courthouse here in Hillsboro,
where the jury has returned to render its verdict
in the historic Hillsboro monkey trial case.
The judge has taken the bench,
in a few moments, we will know whether Bertram Cates
will be found innocent or guilty.
I wish I could describe the tension,
in this courtroom today,
The verbal and legal elements--
one moment, please.
Please stand by.
I've been on the phone
with the lieutenant governor all morning.
The newspapers haven't been very kind to us.
The boys in the capital seem to think it wouldn't do any harm
if you was to let this whole thing kind of...simmer down.
Well now, wait a minute, Jason, I have an obligation to the law.
Of course you have, Merle,
but...but don't forget, November's not too far off.
[Clears throat]
Gentlemen of the jury, have you reached a verdict
Yes, sir-- er, your honor-- w-we have.
The, uh, verdi ct of the jury is unanimous--
Bertram Cates is found guilty as charged.
And so, ladies and gentleman, you have heard the verdict
as read by presiding Judge Coffey.
Bertram Cates, schoolteacher, keystone, and defendant
in one of the greatest ethical contests known to our country,
Bertram Cates has been found guilty.
The law has been satisfied.
But what profound repercussions
of what has happened in this courtroom will be known only to the future.
Quiet, please.
Order.
Stand by, please.
This court is still in session
You'll remove that now, please.
The prisoner will rise
to hear the sentence of this court.
Bert, do you wish to make any statement
before sentence is passed
Your honor, I'm not a public speaker.
I do not have the eloquence as some of the...
men you've heard in the last few days.
I'm just a schoolteacher.
Not anymore,
You ain't!
[Crowd murmuring agreement]
[Gavel pounding]
I was a schoolteacher.
I feel that...
I've been convicted of violating an unjust law.
I will continue in the future, as I have in the past,
to oppose this law in any way I can.
[Judge] Bertram Cates, this court has found you guilty
of violating public act volume 37,
statute 31428 as charged.
this violation is punishable by fine
and, or imprisonment.
But since there has been no previous violation of this statute,
there's no precedent to guide the bench
passing sentence.
court deems it proper
to sentence Bertram Cates to pay a fine of...
Ahem.
[Excited chattering]
Ah...ah, did ah...
Did your honor say $100
That is correct.
That seems to conclude the business of the trial.
But, your honor, the prosecution takes exception.
Why, the issues are so titanic
the court must mete out more drastic punishment--
I object.
to make an example of this transgressor,
to show the world--
Just a minute,
just a minute.
The amount of the fine is of no concern to me,
because Bertram Cates has no intention of paying
this or any other fine.
If it were one single dollar, he would not pay it.
We are going to appeal this decision to the state supreme court.
Will the court grant us 30 days in which to prepare the appeal
Granted.
Court fixes bond at $200.
I believe that concludes the business of this trial
Therefore, I declare this court adjourned.
Your honor, with the court's permission,
I should like to read into the record
a few short remarks which I have prepared.
I object to that.
Mr. Brady is free to read any remarks,
long, short, or otherwise,
in a Chautauqua tent or a political campaign,
but our business in Hillsboro is completed.
The defense moves that the court be adjourned.
But I-I have a few remarks--
[Judge] and we are all anxious to hear them, sir
But Col.Drummond's point of procedure is well taken.
I'm sure everyone here will wish to remain after the court is adjourned
To hear your address.
I hereby declare this court is adjourned,
Sine die.
[Judge pounding gavel]
[Shouts] My friends, my dear friends
Your attention, please.
[Clamoring]
Fellow citizens and friends of the unseen audience,
from the hallowed hills of sacred sinai
in the days of remote antiquity came the law...
[Clamoring]
[Child bangs gavel]
and here, here in this courtroom...
here in this courtroom...
Oh, no, no.
As they would look to the mountains..
from time remembered,
wherever man's body has known the last of hunger..
[Brady] lost in darkness and despair, and here--
here in this courtroom,
living still, in spite of dunge on, fire and sword
[Man] Eskimo pies, 5 cents.
Eskimo pies!
Eskimo pies, sweet as honey.
Here's where you bring your money.
Eskimo pies.
...is a law.
[Brady continues]
[Brady] from the hallowed hills of sacred sinai
in the days of remote antiquity came the law,
which has been our bulwark and our shield
and here, here in this courtroom,
we have seen vindicated
the faith of our fathers.
living still in spite of dungeon, fire and sword.
Oh, how our hearts be high with joy,
whenever we hear the glorious word
Faith of our fathers, holy faith,
we will be true to thee...
[Loses voice]
till death...
[Breathing heavily]
Matt!
[Mmrs. Brady] Oh, dear god. Matt!
[Man] Get back. Let him have some air.
[Woman] Lord, pass us a miracle
and save our holy prophet!
[Man] Get a doctor.
[Drummond] I cannot imagine the world
without Matthew Harrison Brady.
Ah, get me the Baltimore Herald, please.
What did he die of did they say
He died of a busted belly.
There was much greatness in the man.
can I quote you in the obituary
Write anything you damn--
write anything you please.
How do you write an obituary for a man
who's been dead 30 years
Operator
Say, what did he say to the minister
You know, that fits.
He delivered his own obituary.
Ah, ah, where'd you put that, uh--
Ah, here it is.
His book.
That, ah, was proverbs, wasn't it
"He that troubleth his own house"
shall inherit the wind.
"and the fool shall be servant to the wise in heart."
Well...
Well, Col.Drummond, we're growing an odd crop
of agnostics this year.
[Drops bible]
You know, Hornbeck
I'm getting damned sick of you.
Why
You never pushed a noun against a verb
except to blow up something.
You know, that's a typical lawyer's trick...
accusing the accuser.
Of what am I accused
Contempt of conscience.
sentimentality in the first degree.
Why, because I refuse to erase a man's lifetime
No, because you know what I thought of him,
and I know what you thought,
so let's leave the lamentations to the illiterate.
What is this, be-kind-to-bigots week
Why should we weep for him
Because he's dead.
Oh, no.
Besides, he cried enough for himself
during his lifetime.
The national tearduct
from Weeping Water, Nebraska.
[Laughing] he flooded the nation
like a one-man Mississippi.
You know what he was,
that bible-beating bunco artist.
a giant once lived in that body,
but Matt Brady got lost
because he looked for a god too high up
and too far away.
Wh-why, you hypocrite.
Y-you fraud.
The atheist who believes in God.
Aah, you're just as religious as he was.
Everything is grist for your mill, isn't it
Well, go ahead, grind it up--
Brady's past, Cates' future.
My god, don't you understand
the meaning of what happened here today
What happened here today has no meaning.
You have no meaning.
You're like a ghost pointing an empty sleeve
and smirking at everything
that people feel or want or struggle for.
I pity you.
You pity me
Isn't there anything...
what touches you what warms you
Every man has a dream.
what do you dream about
what--what do you need
you don't need anything, do you
people-- love-- an idea, just to cling to
you poor slob.
you're all alone.
When you go to your grave, there won't be anybody
to pull the grass up over your head,
nobody to mourn you, nobody to give a damn.
You're all alone.
You're wrong, Henry.
You'll be there.
You're the type.
Who else would defend my right to be lonely
[Sighing]
...of the coming of the lord
He is trampling out the vintage
Where the grapes of wrath are stored
He hath loosed the fateful lightning
of his terrible swift sword
His truth is marching on
Glory! Glory!
Hallelujah