TOHO COMPANY PRESENTS
SEVEN SAMURAI
Production
SOJIRO MOTOKI
Screenplay
AKIRA KUROSAWA
SHINOBU HASHIMOTO - HIDEO OGUNI
Photography
ASAICHI NAKAI
Art Direction
SO MATSUYAMA
Lighting
SHIGERU MORI
Recording
FUMIO YANOKUCHI
Music
FUMIO HAYASAKA
Historical Research
K. EAKI (Folklore) Y. SUGINO (Fencing)
IENORI KANEKO - SHIGERU ENDO (Archery)
Assistant Director
HIROMICHI HORIKAWA
Hair & Makeup
JUNJIRO YAMADA
Film Developed by
Toho Developing Co.
Editing Manager
HIROSHI NEU
Cast of Characters
Kikuchiyo
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
Kambei
TAKASHI SHIMURA
Shino
KEIKO TSUSHIMA
Wife
YUKIO SHIMAAKI
Farmer Manzo
KAMATARI FUJIWARA
Schichiroji
DAISUKE KATO
Katsushiro
KO KIMURA
Heihachi
MINORU CHIAKI
Kyuzo
SEIJI MIYAGUCHI
Farmer Mosuke
YOSHIO KOSUGI
Farmer Yohei
BOKUEN HIDARI
Gorobei
YOSHIO INABA
Farmer Rikichi
YOSHIO YSUCHIYA
Grandad
KUNINORI TODO
Thief
EIJIRO TONO
Bandit Scout
KICHIJIRO UEDA
Coolie A
JUN TATARA
Bun-Seller
ATSUSHI WATANABE
Blind Player
SO JIN
Bandit Chieftain
SHIMPEl TAKAGI
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
In the early 16th Century, Japan
was in the throes of civil wars...
and the farmers everywhere
were being crushed...
under the iron heels
of cruel bandits.
Let's take this village too!
Wait!
We looted rice here last fall
I'm afraid they have nothing yet
Let's come back after
the barley has ripened
Is there no god to protect us?
Land-tax!
Forced labor!
War!
Drought!
Then, the bandits!
God must want us farmers to starve!
That's true, better we die
Stop complaining!
That won't help!
Let's go see the Magistrate!
Let's appeal to him!
What's the use?
He'd come only after
the bandits are gone!
Let's give everything to the bandits!
All the food we have!
And then hang ourselves!
That might get some action
out of him!
Let's make bamboo spears
Let's kill the bandits,
kill them all!
They won't come back again,
if we kill them all
I don't like this idea
That's an impossibility!
You kill samurai on the run-
but not bandits!
Stop it!
No time for quarrelling!
We haven't a chance against them!
What would happen if we were
defeated? We'd all be murdered!
They kill even babies in the womb!
Enough!
Better to kill or be killed,
than feel like this
Farmers are born to suffer
That's our lot
Let's greet them meekly
Give up our crops
Just beg them to leave something
so we won't starve
On our knees let's beg them,
so we can live
You think they'll listen?
You've forgotten?
Rice we're eating, how...
Let's go see the Grandad!
And ask his advice!
Negotiate with them. Depend on
who you do your dealing with
They're worse than wolves.
If you give your legs!
Next they ask for your arms!
They know no limit
They'd come again in the fall!
But if we lose... Huh?
So we lose!
Without the crop, we'll die, anyway
We'll fight!
That's too reckless!
We're farmers.
We don't know how to fight
We'll hire samurai!
Hire samurai?
Never heard of such a thing!
I saw it with my own eyes
When your native village was burned
As I was escaping to this village,
I saw...
one village unburned.
It had hired samurai
But Grandad, there are many
different kinds of villages
We're eating gruel.
How do we feed samurai?
We could eat millet!
But will samurai fight for us,
just for food?
They're awfully proud!
Find hungry samurai!
Even bears come out of the forests,
when they're hungry
What insolence!
Poor as I am, I'm no beggar!
Fool!
I warned you
It has ripened
Of course.
Ten days have gone by
What shall we do?
This is an early kind.
Not like ours!
I'm soaked to the bones!
Found any samurai, cheap,
strong and willing?
Some leftovers.
I sell 'em cheap
That's a laugh!
What's so funny?
He's blind!
How about you?
No, thanks
I'd rather eat horse dung
He's broke!
I cleaned him out last night
He drew his sword
so we beat him up
He's dead broke
They only eat millet
Is that true?
Eat right or you'll become
night-blind!
You can have them
for a handful of rice
You and everybody else
What a waste it was!
With that rice we could
have gotten forty of those buns!
Stop it!
Am I not right?
The suckers are mad!
What a waste! What foolishness!
He ate plenty
He drank plenty
Then he beat me up and left
A smart samurai!
How different from the one
who pretends to be sleeping!
Let's get out of here!
Let's go home!
He's crying!
He misses his wife!
I would pay plenty to see them love!
Let's go home! Please!
Go home! How can you hire samurai,
you can't even buy buns
Besides, we don't know anything
at all about samurai
As much as we know about seeds
The strong ones
are beyond our control
Any who seem to be willing
are weaklings!
I was defeated last night
only because I was hungry
Liar!
You had money to gamble away!
Want more trouble?
There's a fight!
This way, this way!
Stop it!
It's depressing!
Play on!
Play loud! We back you!
You want to go home!
And yet...
But I could never
negotiate with them!
What else can we do?
You have to deal with the bandits!
All right!
I see!
But -
What will you offer them this time?
Your daughter?
She's very pretty! It may work!
What's happening?
A thief is in that barn!
He was discovered
and ran in there!
How many thieves?
Just one
One?
What's holding you back?
But we're helpless
He kidnapped a child
Says he'll kill him if we attack!
Listen! Hear that?
Poor kid!
They've been in there since
last night. Poor kid!
His voice has gotten hoarse!
He's seven
His poor parents!
But what's wrong with that samurai?
Shaving his head?
A mystery
He's promised to save the boy.
He asked for two rice-balls
Then he began shaving
and asked for a priest's robe
I don't understand!
This is a priest
I'm a priest!
I'm not after you!
Don't worry
The boy must be starved
Don't come in!
I brought food
For you, too!
Take it!
What's the matter?
Throw it in!
No complaints
about that samurai?
Hurry.
Before he gets to town
What is it?
My name is Katsushiro Okamoto
Make me your disciple!
Disciple?
My name is Kimbei Shimada.
I'm a ronin
And I have no disciples
Rise. We can talk
Please! Take me as your disciple!
Rise! Let's talk as we walk
You embarrass me
You're overestimating me
Listen
I'm not a man
with any special skill
But I've had plenty of experience
in battles,
losing battles, all of them
In short, that's all I am
Drop such an idea
for your own good
No, sir.
My decision has been made!
I'll follow you, sir
I forbid it
I can't afford to take
a kid with me
What do you want?
You are rude!
Mind your own business, kid!
Are you a samurai?
Sure!
I wonder
Who is he?
Pay no attention
Please, sir! I fever to ask!
Why don't you go home?
Haven't you had enough yet?
After he's fed, he'll leave
It's impossible
Sir!
Why not arm them with...?
I thought of that, too
But sir
This would not be a game
A band of forty bandits!
Two or three samurai
could accomplish nothing
Defense is harder than offense
Mountains in back of the village?
Can horses get over them?
Fields in front
The village is wide open
to horsemen...
until the fields are flooded
One guard for each
direction takes four
Two more as a reserve
You'll need at least seven,
including me
We can afford seven, eh?
The Grandad said "four,"
didn't he?
But three more
Wait!
I haven't said "Yes!"
I'm only thinking
In the first place, it's not easy
to find seven reliable samurai
Especially when the total reward
adds up to three meager meals
And the fun of it,
if I may say so
Besides...
I'm tired of fighting
Maybe it's my age
I'm glad I wasn't
born a farmer!
A dog is luckier!
Shit! Take it from me!
Go hang yourselves!
You shut your mouth!
What? I'm just talking straight!
Talking straight?
Don't you have
any pity for them?
Don't make me laugh!
Do you have any pity?
If you do, why don't
you help them?
Want a fight?
Stop it!
Hey! Samurai!
Look at this!
This is for you!
Know what those suckers eat?
Millet!
They're feeding you on rice,
and living on millet
They're giving their best!
I see
Say no more!
I won't waste your food
Look!
Manzo's coming home!
Where are Rikichi and Yohei?
Still looking for samurai!
You really think
samurai would come?
Yes, they're coming. Seven
Yes, seven
Hmm... seven!
You said "four," so I opposed
I thought we'd probably
have to hire ten
But, if I told you that,
you'd bring fifteen
See what I mean?
Grandad! I am worried!
Our girls are crazy
about samurai
The villagers won't like
the samurai to get them
Fool! Have you
forgotten the bandits?
What's the use of worrying
about your beard,
when your head's
about to be taken?
You need my help?
To fight whom?
Katsuishiro!
Hold your weapon tightly
And hit him as he comes
Hit as hard as you can!
Splendid!
Please forgive us
My name is Kambei Shimada
I must find some talented men,
right away
Forgive us
What is this?
Intolerable! Outrageous!
Forgive me. You see,
a war is about to start
with a band of bandits
What Clan?
Our employer,
as a matter of fact
is a village of farmers
A job promising no pay or reward,
except three square meals
while we're on the job
What stupidity!
My ambition is a bit bigger
I'm sorry
Is that final?
Yes!
What a big loss, sir!
So alert a fencer!
What's the matter?
That samurai is all right.
But I'm worried about the other six
Don't be foolish!
See them first.
Then, start worrying!
Try him!
One moment, sir!
Like the last time?
Yes. For your training
Please! No jokes
Forgive me
Interesting
But...
I realize that the farmers
are suffering
I think I understand
why you accepted
But, I'll accept because
your character fascinates me
The deepest friendship often
comes through a chance meeting
Your name?
Gorobei Katayama
Sounds strong, but...
Yohei, what's wrong!
Hurry up!
Come on!
What's wrong, Yohei?
The rice is gone!
You fool!
So I told you so...
I tried my best to watch it!
At night I slept,
holding on to it!
I'll get some from home!
But, what will we do
until you get back?
It's all gone,
except just a handful
Don't be silly!
Here he comes!
This is wonderful!
Thank Heaven!
It's so good
to find you alive!
I'd give you up for lost!
How did you get away?
I laid low in the ditch,
under the water plants
When the castle burned down,
and fell upon me,
I thought that was my end!
Were you terrified?
Not particularly
Are you fed up with fighting?
As a matter of fact,
I'm preparing for a tough war
It will bring us neither money
nor fame. Want to join?
Yes!
Maybe we die this time
I never knew they were so scarce
What are you after, sir?
Samurai
There's one in my yard,
but poor quality
I was astonished
by his gay indifference
He came in saying:
"Feed me. I have no money
but I'll cut your firewood."
I liked his frankness
Haven't you ever seen
firewood cut?
You seem to enjoy it
Oh, that's my nature
You're good
But I'm better
at killing enemies
Killed many?
Well - It's impossible
to kill 'em all
So I usually run away
A splendid principle!
Thank you
Incidentally,
Interested in killing
thirty bandits?
Let's begin
Too bad. A tie
No
I won
You did?
If we had fought seriously,
you'd have been cut and dead
Let's see!
No use
Don't you see?
A real sword will kill you.
It's no use
Wait!
Halt! You can say
whatever you want
What a waste
It's so obvious
Find any?
Missed one
A first-class swordsman
A lost fish looks big
But, I saw his prowess
with my own eyes
He is terrific!
A man interested only
in perfecting his skill
So his answer was "No!"
Too bad!
I told him where
to find me, though
And you?
I caught one
His fencing is... second class
But, quite a character
A cheerful fellow
Good company in adversity
Much obliged
I caught one too,
to tell you the truth
That one dressed like a peddler?
Yes. He was my right
hand man for years
I'll bring clean water
I'm Heinachi Hayashida, a fencer
of the Wood Cut School
Well, three more to find
Three?
Two
Can't take a kid
Sir
I know
I know your line
I was a young man like you, once
"Train yourself
"Distinguish yourself in war
"Because somebody,
maybe a war lord!"
But, time flies
Before your dream materializes
you get gray hair
By that time,
your parents and friends
are dead and gone
Go back home,
leave in the morning
you had enough training
the last few days
Good experience
Please, sir!
Take him, by all means.
Please!
But...
Do! Even though
you call him a kid
Kids are often more
willing than grownups
Provided that we treated him
like a grownup
So, let's treat him like one
Two more
Just one more, I think
Hello!
You've come!
Thank you
- And...?
- We leave tomorrow
Tomorrow?
Let's forget the seventh.
We have no time to lose!
Well
Sir!
- Sir!
- That's all right
- I know. Don't mention it!
Hey! I found a samurai!
A real tough one!
A fee-ro-shus one!
He is like a wild dog
He drank with him later
I asked him. He's coming!
Shall I...?
What are you doing?
Testing
That's not fair!
Just watch
A good samurai will dodge it
But he's drunk
A real samurai would never get
so drunk
Here I am!
See, I told you so!
Who hit me?
Oh! It's you
I remember your head!
I even see it in my dreams!
You had the nerve to ask me
if I was a samurai!
Look! Though clad in rags,
I'm a real samurai!
I've been looking for you
ever since that time!
Wanted to show you this!
Look at this!
You'll know... I belong to
a respectable samurai family
This one is me!
Kikuchiyo? Is that your name?
Yes, sir!
"Born on February 17,
the 2nd year of Tensho"
What's so funny?
You don't look thirteen!
Listen! If you are the Kikuchiyo
mentioned here
you must be thirteen years old
Where did you steal this?
Steal?
To hell with samurai!
Damn!
Steady, Thirteen!
Sir Kikuchiyo!
Courage, Thirteen!
To hell with samurai!
Is he really samurai?
He thinks he is
"Take good care of this!"
Take me with you!
What's the matter, Dad?
Why do you stare at me like that?
Shino! Cut your hair short!
Cut your hair! Dress like a boy!
I don't understand!
Cut, I tell you!
I tell you because I love you!
Samurai are coming! You don't know
what they'll do to you
- Come and cut your hair.
- No, I won't!
But Manzo's seen those samurai!
And he cut her hair!
You're not worried because
yours are boys, but...
- I get it.
- So you keep my daughter.
She'll be safer at your place
Fool!
I'm talking about Manzo!
He says he's worried
about our village
But he's only worried
about his daughter! Damn!
You're a prize fool!
All who have young daughters
are terrified
What are we to do?
The samurai are coming any day now!
Come! Let's go see the Grandad!
Don't stand there! Go!
Get going!
We should do something before
those samurai get here!
Still following us!
I don't see him!
Given up?
Isn't it strange?
Now, I sort of...
miss him!
This way!
Sheeyit!
So that's our castle, eh?
Huh! I'd hate to die
in a dung heap, though
We aren't asking you to
Here we are!
I brought the samurai!
What's wrong?
Here are the samurai!
Huh!
What's wrong?
Well, what kind of hospitality
is this?
What does this mean?
Hey! What's the matter?
Welcome your guests!
Let's go see Grandad
He handles all our affairs
Village patriarch, eh?
He's granting us an audience
What an honor!
Let's go
They're being very foolish indeed
Farmers are always worrying
about one thing or another
Rains, dry weather, winds
In other words, they wake up
worrying and go to bed the same way
Today's no exception
They're just scared,
meaninglessly scared, that's all
But, listen
Why are they afraid of us?
Yet they expect us to do something
for them?
The bandits!
Please! Samurai, please!
Help! Bandits are coming!
Please help!
Keep calm!
Calm down!
Answer me clearly!
From which direction
are they coming?
From mountain!
From front road!
Those who saw bandits,
step forward!
Who saw bandits?
Who beat the alarm?
I did!
Don't be scared!
No bandits are coming!
You suckers!
You welcomed us as you would
a plague!
But when you heard the alarm...
Oh! Samurai!
You turned to worship us
Fools!
Any objection, Grandad?
No
It's all right now
Well, looks like maybe
he's useful after all
So now we're seven, eh?
Sorry this place is so filthy
But, where will you live?
I'll sleep in the stable
With horses?
No! The bandits took them last year
A stable is a nice place
to sleep with one's wife
I have no wife!
Fool!
What's your real name?
I don't remember
Give me a good name
Kikuchiyo!
It becomes you
How would you attack this village?
I'd charge down from the mountain
Down this road?
I'd do the same
WEST
How would you defend?
Shichiroji sure knows his business
Look at those logs
He plans a fence
Your old right hand man, eh?
Remember!
A war is run
We run, both in offense and defense
When you can't run,
it's time to die
SOUTH
After the harvest, we'll flood here
Then this will be well defended
But will we have time to do that?
Spear! Go ahead and spear!
Look! I'm a bandit!
Come on!
Next!
EAST
We'll destroy this bridge
This border will then be safe
What about those houses?
Have to be evacuated
That mill, too?
That old man is stubborn, you know
Remember
You're afraid of the enemies
But, they're afraid of you, too!
You're splendid!
Splendid scarecrows!
But they're men, not sparrows,
not crows!
You, chewing that cud!
Stop it!
You are not a cow!
You on the end! Step forward!
I mean you!
You!
If you want to watch, bring money
What is this?
A spear, sir
Where did you get it?
Grown on a bush?
I know!
Samurai on the run!
If you have one, the others
must have them also
Have you?
Do - you - have - spears?
NORTH
Looks peaceful here.
But a real danger spot
Katsushiro!
We're leaving now!
Yes, Sir! I'm coming!
Still a child
Are you one of the villagers?
A girl?
A boy?
If you are a boy,
why aren't you drilling?
Picking flowers during
such a crisis!
Come!
Good! Good!
Problem is here.
Hey! What are you doing!
A big haul!
What have you got?
Taken from a samurai
on the run
Where did you get those?
In this village?
At Manzo's
Don't like them?
A real fine one!
What's the matter? You wanted
these things, didn't you?
Shame on you!
They stripped those
from samurai they murdered
- I know.
- How dare you...!
One who has never been
hunted would not understand
Go away! It's nothing!
I'd like to kill every
farmer in this village!
A fine idea!
Hey, you!
What do you all think of farmers?
Saints?
Bah!
They're foxy beasts!
They say: "We've no rice, we've
no wheat. We've got nothing!"
But they have!
They have everything!
Dig under the floors!
Or search the barns!
You'll find plenty!
Rice!
Salt! Beans! Sake!
Look into the canyons!
Hidden farms!
They pose as saints
but are full of lies!
If they smell a battle,
they hunt the defeated!
Listen!
Farmers are-
stingy, foxy, blubbering
mean, stupid and, murderous!
God damn!
That's what they are!
But then!
Who made them such beasts?
You did!
You samurai did it!
You burn their villages!
Destroy their farms!
Steal their food!
Force them to labor!
Take their women!
And kill them if they resist!
So what should farmers do?
Damn... Damn...
You are a farmer's son.
Aren't you?
Has... has anything
happened, sir?
Nothing, Grandad
Everything is all right
I sleep here from tonight
I don't like their company
Fool!
Don't make yourself small!
This is your home?
You gave them your house
and you sleep here?
Scared to death!
Go to sleep!
It's like old times
It's so quiet
I can't imagine the mountains
being infested with bandits
Sheeyit!
If I had woman now...
- Where to?
- The mountain?
To practice
No women up there!
Sometimes you sound
pretty sharp
What are you making now?
Our banner
In battle,
we'll need something to wave
What does it mean?
This says "Farm."
Farmers. This village
- These circles?
- Us
Only six, eh?
I'm out?
The triangle represents you,
Sir. Kikuchiyo
It's rice.
- Eat it.
- But...
I tasted millet,
for the first time
It was terrible
Go ahead
Don't be shy.
Want to be alone?
I won't eat it
Why?
I brought it for you
I'd rather give it
to Kyuemon's Granny
Kyuemon's Granny?
I'm not hungry now
I'll eat later
You eat
I'll save mine
What's going on?
Tell me!
This is terrible
No relatives?
No, sir. The bandits...
I wish I could die right away
I want to die soon,
to escape from this misery
But, then
even in the world to come,
there must be great misery,
I'm afraid
There's not!
No war, no bandits,
in the next world
No misery, either
How do you know?
Ever been there?
Why yell so much?
I hate all wretched people!
I feel disgusted with them!
Damn!
I want to do something
Save that feeling
for the bandits
Didn't you...
Did you...
Did you, see me today,
over there, with...
The girl?
Yes
Why didn't you tell...?
You want me to?
Give us some rice!
Give us white rice!
We have no rice!
Don't shout,
you'll get hungry
Give us rice!
The white rice ball!
Listen, you brats!
This is all
we can give you
If we give you more,
we'll be...
See?
Say! Hasn't any one of you
got a pretty sister?
Anyone?
When are you going to harvest?
After ten days
At top speed how long
will it take?
Three days, at least.
I want to flood it, then
We need a moat
at the south border,
so no horsemen can approach
This moat need not be wide
Well, we'll dig a waterway
and flood the farm
The work can be done in one day
Thanks
And there's another thing
Those three houses
and this mill
must be evacuated when
the harvest is completed
What? Me evacuate?
I'm sorry
We can't help it
We can't cover this big an area
Listen!
The crops will soon be harvested
Then, the bandits will come
Let's be ready
From now on
we must be on the alert
We'll harvest in groups,
not individually
From tomorrow,
you'll live in groups
Remember! You move as a group,
not as individuals
Listen, men!
Love your wives plenty tonight
It's stupid!
Come, neighbors!
Throw them away!
Let's not risk ourselves
to protect others!
Come!
Let's protect our own homes!
Stop!
Pick up your spears!
Go back to your line
Where is Yohei?
That blasted fool!
You fool!
The outlying houses are three
The village has twenty
We can't endanger
twenty for three!
No outlying house can be saved
while the village proper
is destroyed!
Remember!
That's war!
You're all in one boat!
He who thinks only about himself
will destroy himself, too!
Such selfishness
will not be tolerated!
INTERMISSION
Sheeyit! Who would
have suspected
So many women lived here!
Where were you hiding these girls?
Give me your sickle!
I'll cut a lot for you
So let's be good friends, eh?
Rikichi!
I see that the married couples
are the most efficient
I'd wish you'd marry soon
Why are you angry?
I only...
Katsushiro, bring him back!
Why did he run away?
Shino, stop dreaming!
What is this?
A bear's lair?
It's been sickled
Rikichi, eh?
I didn't witness it
I was looking for him,
when he came out
His face was strained and sweaty
What did you say to him?
Nothing.
I only suggested that he marry
Something pretty painful
must be eating him
His face tells me that
His lips are tightly set,
like bolted door
Try to open them
Who's there?
It's me!
Is everything all right?
Won't you sit down?
Let's talk
Often, just talking
soothes one's mind
Speaking about a suffering
eases it away
Incidentally, you're
a man of few words
But, if you have something
bottled up inside you,
better let it out
And I believe this is
a good chance to do it
I've nothing bottled up
Let's go out
Don't wake him.
He's a child
He said "Shino."
Shino is...
A woman's name
Certainly doesn't sound
like a child dreaming
Where shall we begin?
First, the weakest
Who's there?
Come out!
Kikuchiyo!
You're lucky!
Had it been the bandits,
your neck...
Yohei!
What is this?
My horse, sir
I thought it was a fat mouse
Sparrow singing, crows crowing
What's the matter?
Aren't the bandits coming?
If they don't come, what a loss!
Hiring those greedy samurai!
- Fool!
- Bandits better not come at all!
What are you going to do
with this old horse?
Stop it! If you cripple it,
Yohei will cry!
What are you talking about?
I'm a good rider!
He's doing all right!
That looks good!
They're merry
The thrashing is finished
and no sign of bandits
They're beginning to think
none are coming
Wishful thinking
Danger strikes when
everything looks so safe
Tell them to take up their posts!
I wish I were a samurai's daughter
A farmer's life is wretched
I'm too fortunate. I'm shamed
Oh, I don't mean that
You're samurai and I'm a peasant
I never...
Oh, I don't mind that!
I'm not worrying about the future!
You chicken!
Aren't you samurai?
Three strangers near
the west road, sir
- No one else knows about this.
- Not yet
Let's keep quiet
I saw three horses on the hill!
The bandits!
I know
- They're here!
- How do you know?
It's evident. This commotion
From which direction?
The hills or the west?
The west
The bandits are coming!
Tell them to stay inside
It's only three bandits
Keep them quiet
They must be scouts
They must not see us
What's up?
The bandits?
They've come?
Quiet!
Where?
That tree...!
Scouts, undoubtedly
They're surprised to see the fence
They don't know about us
I hope you're right
Where is everybody?
What a fool!
Kikuchiyo!
Have they come?
Is that right?
Now they've seen us!
Now that they know,
they mustn't leave
I'll kill them.
They're in my territory
I didn't know...
Go. Catch one of them
to make amends
Take a short cut
Yes, to the horses
Katsushiro!
You just watch! Understand?
Gee! Good horses!
You lie here
- What are you going to do?
- Me?
Katsushiro! It's all over now
Come out
Wait! This is a prisoner of war!
He's begging for mercy!
We mustn't kill him
We don't need your help!
Let her avenge her son's death!
Somebody!
Assist her!
According to that bandit,
their fort must be pretty...
- Flimsy!
- Must be as full of holes
as Yohei's trousers!
If it's that approachable
- Let's attack.
- They are forty
We must decrease them
if we can do it
without losing anybody
We couldn't afford a loss
Any battle is a gamble
Three can kill at least ten
Is that place very far from here?
A day's walk
But we have horses now!
Then half a day
All right!
If we leave now,
we'll get there by dawn
But who?
Not you!
I go! It's decided!
Me too!
I'll be the guide!
- Not enough horses!
- Yes, we have
You ride Yohei's horse.
Nobody else can!
You fool! This way! Damn you!
You call yourself a horse!
For shame!
Hey! Wait!
Please!
I apologize!
Forgive me!
Set fire to all the huts!
And we'll kill them
as they come out!
Looking good, fool! Damn!
Good work!
Rikichi! Look out! Rikichi!
Come back, Rikichi!
Fool! What're you doing?
You fool!
It's your fault!
Who was she?
My wife!
Heihachi!
Hang on!
We were counting on him to cheer us
when the situation became gloomy
And now he's gone!
Don't cry!
Don't cry, fool!
At last they've come!
Don't forget! Three guns!
Twenty to the north,
fifteen to the south!
- Guns?
- All together three!
Go to the south.
Beware of their guns
To the rear! To the rear!
Twelve shifting to the east!
Thirteen!
An arrow got one!
Good old Gorobei!
Now go see if the bridge was cut
- And...
- The guns!
Go to the north
The decisive battle
will be fought there
Why didn't you build
a fence there?
A good fort needs a gap
The enemy must be lured in.
So we can attack them
If only defend, we lose the war
What's wrong with you!
Take these away!
Twelve are coming! Quick!
The bridge!
Are you blind?
That's what we're doing!
And look out for their guns!
I know!
Hey! Stop!
I must find my dad!
He's in there!
He always wanted to die
in the Mill
The stubborn dotard!
Go and get him!
Hey! Get away!
Be quick about it, fools!
On this hill,
twenty of the enemy
Twelve at the east
I don't like it. They're scared
Once again!
That's Shichiroji!
Let us cheer, too!
Come out, all of you!
Now, yell!
I see!
Let's out-yell them!
Yohei! What's wrong with your face!
Once again!
Here they come!
Hey! Get back! Get going!
Damn! Fool! Damn!
Forget those worthless shacks!
Back to your posts! All of you!
Damn! You wolves!
That's Grandad's house!
Where is he?
Where's the young couple?
And the child? God Damn!
What troublesome fools!
Wait! Don't leave your post!
Kikuchiyo! Come back!
Kikuchiyo!
Where are your men?
Speared!
What will power!
Hey! Kikuchiyo! Follow me!
What is it?
The same thing happened to me!
I was just like this baby!
Here I come
What were you staring at?
Everybody all right?
Well done!
Great!
I smell a gun fuse!
Run! Run!
Manzo!
Where are you hit?
Shino!
Bring her!
Don't!
A flea bite is bigger.
What are you screaming about?
It's foolish to reveal
your daughter!
Hey! Halt! That'll do!
Well done!
What's your name?
I'm Rikichi!
They attacked from three directions
and were beaten back
Next it will be here
It may not be tonight
But, they'll come
But it's awfully quiet out there
Right. However,
their main force is there
I'll show you
Good work!
Stick up that scarecrow
Probably in the morning,
they'll launch their attack here
We'll let them get in
Not all of them
Just one
Or two
As soon as they enter,
we shut the rest off
and trap them!
They'll be helpless
We'll decrease them one by one
What about their guns?
We must decrease them, also
I'll get one!
I sure will!
No, you don't!
I'll go
I hear a footstep!
Katsushiro! That's O.K.
Rest a bit
Really I did! Listen!
Hear that?
Rest. I tell you!
You're tired!
Yes. I hear it
Killed two
What's the matter?
What is it? Hurry!
I need sleep
You are...
really great!
I've always wanted
to tell you that!
They coming?
We'll let one in!
Don't forget to close
the line at once!
Oh! They're coming!
Good!
What's wrong? Well done!
Deploy! They're coming!
Fall back! Fall back!
Let's go forward!
We'll let another one in!
Oh! Here they come!
This is fun!
Everyone look
What were you playing, dear?
They're getting wise
- They're mollycoddles!
- They're not so tough!
Four killed just now
Kyuro got two last night
He has real samurai spirit
He's fearless and skillful!
And also gentle!
So modest, even after
capturing that enemy gun!
When he left the hill, he looked
as if he were going to a picnic
You're amusing. Your jabbering
is sure interesting
Yohei!
Keep watch!
Don't make such a wry face
It's quite safe here!
A scarecrow could handle it!
Remember!
Every coward will
end up like that!
Everything all right?
They're plenty tough!
It'll be over soon
The thing is upside down!
We're all burnt out
And hungrier than farmers!
Don't complain!
Your misery will soon be over!
I'm depending on you, Brother!
I'll shoot you
It's me! It's me!
Great work, fools!
You wolves!
You fool!
Why did you leave your post?
Look at this!
I deserve praise!
The post is safe
Going on your own
merits no reward!
In war, it's teamwork that counts!
Gorobei, Kyouzo!
Guard this border! Understand?
Let no one through!
Fall back!
You! Hey! You!
Good God!
Two got through!
God Damn!
God Damn! God Damn!
Yohei! Where's Yohei?
I was watching!
Hang on! Yohei! Damn!
Shichirogi. Take over!
Gorobei!
Thirteen left
But the last seven were costly!
Hey! Are you tired?
You look worn out, old man!
I'll go wash my face
The next clash will be
the showdown
If we must attack, let's do it
before we're too tired
When do you think
the enemy will come?
Well, they are tired too
Some are wounded.
It won't be tonight
But, they're hungry.
And we have reason to believe
there's dissension among them.
They must be desperate
Let's expect them to come in
the morning determined and desperate
Katsushiro!
The chief wants all men
to get some sleep
Two sentries will keep watch
Also, one by one, the men
may visit their families
The decisive battle at last, eh?
Yes. Please spread the word
You heard the order, didn't you?
I'll keep watch
You go to sleep
Now - Manzo!
Run back home
See your daughter
I mean - your son!
I told them
Good. Now rest
Tell me,
what was Kikuchiyo doing?
Still at the graves, sir
We'll die tomorrow!
We may not
But, probably we will die!
Shino!
Where are you, Shino?
Shino?
Sake, eh?
Where did you find this?
I see
It's just as Kikuchiyo said
They have lots of things
I'll take this, then
Shino!
Here's some sake.
Drink and relax
This is not like you
Be bold and fight hard!
Shino!
You no good wench!
Don't be violent!
What do you mean,
falling for a samurai?
Manzo!
Is this your daughter?
Tell me!
You said she fell for a samurai.
What do you mean?
Manzo!
Speak up!
Tell us!
Are you Shino?
Manzo!
Don't be so angry!
When a man sees
Death in his path,
he feels the need
for a woman's arms,
just before a battle
It happens even in a castle!
Have some sympathy for youngsters!
I can't!
My daughter's been seduced!
But they love each other!
And she wasn't given to bandits!
Everybody's too nervous
Relax!
Everybody. At last
the decisive battle!
By the way, Katsushiro!
Fight bravely!
Now you're a full-fledged man!
Hey!
Show some guts!
With those faces you won't win
this battle!
Kikuchiyo, what on earth
are you doing?
I can't kill a lot
with one sword!
Only thirteen left!
Let them all come in!
We'll immediately
close in on them
And trap them at the crossing!
This fight will decide
the outcome!
Here they come!
Shichirogi, Katsushiro West!
Kyouzo, Kikuchiyo East!
Katsushiro! Rikichi!
Katsushiro!
Go to the east!
Quiet!
Or you die!
Good. Well done!
I did it! I did it!
Stand up!
Go to the East!
Katsushiro... Stand up
Be careful
Damn you! Damn!
Kikuchiyo!
The bandits!
All dead!
Again, we've survived
Again we're defeated
The winners are those farmers
Not us
THE END