1930. Prohibition has transformed
Chicago into a City at War.
Rival gangs complete for control
of the city's billion dollar empire
of illegal alcohol, enforcing their will
with the hand grenade and tommy gun.
It is the time of the Ganglords.
It is the time of Al Capone.
An article, which I believe appeared
in a newspaper, asked why,
since it would seem that you are
in effect the Mayor of Chicago,
you're not simply being
appointed to that position.
Well, I tell ya, it's touching.
Like a lot of things in life,
we laugh because it's funny,
and we laugh because it's true.
Some people say,
reformers here say:
"Put that man in jail,
what does he think he is doing?"
What I hope I'm doing, and here's
where your paper's got a point,
is I'm responding to
the will of the people.
People are gonna drink. We all
know that. All I do is act on that.
And all this talk of bootlegging.
What is bootlegging?
On the boat it's bootlegging,
on Lake Shore Drive it's hospitality.
I'm a businessman.
Your reputation is that you control
your business through violence.
That those that don't purchase your
product are dealt with violently.
It's all right.
I grew up in a tough neighbourhood.
We used to say, "You can get further
with a kind word and a gun"
"than you can
with just a kind word."
And in that neighbourhood
it might've been true.
And sometimes
your reputation follows you.
There is violence in Chicago,
but not by me
and not by anybody I employ.
Because it's not good business.
Leave us alone down here,
we've got everything we need.
The green beer you're peddlin'
ain't any good.
It's not supposed to be good.
It's supposed to be bought.
I'm not buyin' any.
Don't worry about it, Pops,
we won't come back.
- How's everyone at your house today?
- They're fine.
- Is your Mama well?
- She has a little cold.
Oh, she does?
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- But she'll be all right.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
That's all right, sweetie.
You be careful crossin' the street.
- Mister!
- You tell your Mama that...
Hey, Mister! Wait!
Mister! Wait!
You forgot your brief...
Yes, I heard it on the radio.
I know.
Now it's time to go to work.
You'll make a good first impression.
I love you, Eliot.
Now, shoo.
Eliot Ness, Special Agent
of the Treasury Department.
- Mr Ness.
- Thank you, Chief.
At the request
of the City of Chicago,
the Department of the Treasury
has inaugurated a programme
to deal with the flow of illegal
liquor and the violence it creates.
Mr Ness!
Of what does this programme consist?
I and other agents of the Treasury
will be working
with the Chicago Police...
Isn't it just another
showpiece programme?
- What do you think of prohibition?
- Do you drink, Mr Ness?
- Come on, answer the questions.
- It's not just a showpiece.
And I'll tell you
how I feel about prohibition.
It is the law of the land.
Do you consider yourself
a crusader, is that it?
What qualifications
do you have for the job?
Do you have any political ambitions?
All right, boys,
I think that's enough.
What are your real plans?
What have you got coming up?
You'll have to read about it
in the paper.
- Let me ride along with you.
- No. Can't help you.
Mr Ness, Lieutenant Alderson,
the Flying Squad.
Are you ready to meet the men?
Yes, I am.
I have one more thing to say.
I know that many of you take a drink.
What you've done before today
is not my concern.
But now we must be pure,
and I want you to stop.
It's not a question of whether it's
'a harmless drink'. It may well be.
But it's against the law.
And as we are going to enforce
the law, we must do first by example.
Are there any questions?
Good. The Department
of the Treasury's had
a man undercover here
for some time now.
We've received word
from this informant
that a large shipment of Canadian
whiskey has arrived in Chicago.
So I hope that you have signed on
for some action.
Remember, the liquor cases
are marked with the red maple leaf.
The Treasury Agent is
in a grey suit with a white scarf.
- He is not to be arrested.
- A grey suit and a white scarf.
- That's it. Are your men ready?
- Yes, sir. They are.
- At ease.
- Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
- How are we doin'?
- Okay.
- Want part of a sandwich?
- No, thank you, sir.
- You nervous?
- No, sir.
- Been with the unit long?
- A short while.
- I suppose we all want to do well.
- Yes, sir.
A message from my wife.
- You married?
- Yes, sir, I am.
Nice to be married, huh?
Just follow me.
- Oh, God...
- Federal officer. Hands in the air.
Get 'em up. Drop it.
Damn it, I can't, it'll break.
Mr Ness. Look, I was just...
Geez, I'm sorry.
Listen, I can do a lot for you,
what you're tryin' to do.
I get the big scoop,
you make a big splash.
Get some support. What do you say?
Let's be real, let me help you.
Okay. Just shut up.
All right now...
Let's do some good!
Hold it right there!
Federal officer. You're under arrest
for violations of the Volstead Act.
Let's cover the doors!
Don't let anybody out!
Preseuski.
- I'm here with permission.
- Who gave you permission?
- Mr Ness!
- Sorry, let him through here.
Let him through here.
You want to take your picture,
take it now.
- You ready?
- Ready.
Liquor, huh?
Get him out of here.
- Tear the place apart!
- I mean now, get him out!
That means you, too.
Christ!
Now, what do you think you're doing?
You want to throw garbage? Throw it
in the goddamn trash basket.
Don't you have
more important things to do?
Yeah.
But I'm not doing them right now.
Do we understand each other?
Okay, pal, why the Mohaska?
- Why are you packin' the gun?
- I'm a Treasury Officer.
All right.
Just remember
what we talked about now.
Hey... Wait a minute!
What the hell kind of police
do you have in this goddamn city?
You just turned your back
on an armed man.
- You're a Treasury officer.
- I just told you I was.
Who would claim to be that,
who was not?
What's your name and unit?
It's right here.
You got a beef?
What is it?
How did you know I had a gun?
What do you want,
a free lesson in police work?
No.
Are you okay, pal?
I had a rough day on the job.
- Are you going home now?
- I was about to.
Well, then, you just fulfilled
the first rule of law enforcement.
Make sure when your shift is over
you go home alive.
Here endeth the lesson.
$100,000 for 40 barrels.
Make sure there are no empties.
I'm gonna give you the ledger,
everything is in the book.
55 gallons to the barrel.
- It's Eddie.
- Come in, Eddie.
So, he gets into the snowplough,
and he says, "Let's do some good".
And then, we bust through...
- Mr Ness?
- Yes?
I came here to thank you.
It was...
...my little girl that got killed
with that bomb.
I'm sorry. Please.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
You see, it's... because I know
that you have children, too.
And that this is real for you,
that these men cause us tragedy.
And I know that you will
put a stop to them.
And you do that, now.
- What do you want?
- I'd like to talk to you.
Come in.
I need a small group of men,
handpicked, starting with you.
Ness! I am just a poor beat cop.
- Now, how can I help you?
- Just work with me.
- But why should I, though?
- Because you're a good cop.
- How do you know that?
- You told me.
If I'm such a good cop...
How come I'm walkin' the beat,
then, at my age?
Do you want to tell me?
Well, maybe I'm that
Whore with a Heart of Gold.
Or The One Good Cop in the Bad Town?
Is that what you want to hear?
I didn't ask you, and I don't care!
You want to stay on the beat?
You do that.
If you'd like to come with me,
I need your help.
I'm askin' you for help.
Well... that's the thing you fear,
isn't it?
Mr Ness, I wish I'd met you
ten years and... twenty pounds ago.
But... I just think it got...
more important to me...
...to stay alive.
And that's why I'm walkin' the beat.
Thank you, no.
That's good, Andy. Let's start up
the thing and take a little ride.
I wanna hear
that Stutz Bearcat engine, boy!
- Yeah, let me open the door here.
- Yeah, go ahead.
Whoopsy daisy,
pick up the door there, Andy.
Throw it in the back seat.
Now, let me get the thing started.
Yeah, start it up, Andy.
Holy mackerel, Andy!
Listen to that Bearcat motor!
Yeah, it sounds like the bear
is chasin' that cat all round it!
Andy! She's boilin' over!
- Mr Ness?
- Yes.
Oscar Wallace.
I've been assigned here
by the Washington Bureau.
- Really?
- Yes.
Well, I'm glad to have you here,
Mr Wallace. Would you excuse me?
We are a little in the dark here,
but any ideas you may have...
Well, actually, yes, sir, I do.
And the one I want to try first...
is this.
He has not filed a return since 1926.
- A return...?
- An income tax return.
- Income tax.
- Yes, sir.
- What do you do at the Bureau?
- Oh, I'm an accountant.
- An accountant?
- Yes, and the Bureau sent me here...
Would you excuse me?
Please.
Okay. Let's go.
- Where are we going?
- These walls have ears.
You said you wanted to know
how to get Capone.
Do you really want to get him?
You see what I'm saying?
- What are you prepared to do?
- Everything within the law.
And then what are you
prepared to do?
If you open the ball
on these people,
you must be prepared
to go all the way.
Because they won't give up the fight
until one of you is dead.
I want to get Capone.
I don't know how.
Here's how you get Capone:
He pulls a knife, you pull a gun.
He sends one of yours to hospital,
you send one of his to the morgue!
That's the Chicago way!
And that's how you get Capone.
Now, do you want to do that?
Are you ready to do that?
I'm making you a deal.
Do you want this deal?
I have sworn to put this man away,
with any and all legal means
at my disposal, and I will do so.
Well, the Lord hates a coward.
Do you know what a blood oath is,
Mr Ness?
- Yes.
- Good. 'Cause you just took one.
How do you think Capone knew
about your raid the other night?
- Somebody on the cops told him.
- Right. Welcome to Chicago.
This town stinks
like a whorehouse at low tide.
First, who can you trust?
Nobody. The cops, nobody.
- 'Cause nobody wants you here.
- Then why are you helping me?
Because I swore to uphold the law.
And if you believe that,
I'll tell you another.
- Now, who can you trust?
- I can trust nobody.
- That's the sorry truth.
- Then, where are we gonna get help?
If you're afraid of getting a rotten
apple, don't go to the barrel.
Get it off the tree.
Get it off the tree...
Finger out of the trigger guard!
Eject those cartridges!
Lay the revolver on the ledge
and stand back!
About face!
Barry! I want you to meet
Mr Eliot Ness.
Treasury Department. How are you?
We need a recruit for extended duty.
He is to be seconded to the Treasury
Department. We have the full...
Barry? Who is consistently
the best shot of this class?
- Williamson and Stone.
- Call them out, one at a time.
- Are either of the men married?
- No.
- Good.
- Williamson!
- You're married.
- I don't want any married men.
All right, stand easy, son.
I want to ask you something.
- Why do you want to join the force?
- To protect and...
To protect and serve...
To protect and...
Please don't search for the yearbook
answer. Just tell me what you think.
- What I think? I...
- You...
...could help... the force.
- You can help...
- With the force.
Thank you.
There goes the next Chief of Police.
At ease!
Stone! Out here.
This kid's a prodigy.
- Why do you want to join the force?
- To protect the property and...
Oh, please, don't waste my time
with that bullshit.
Where are you from, Stone?
- From the Southside.
- Stone?
George Stone, that's your name?
- What's your real name?
- That is my real name.
Nah! What was it
before you changed it?
- Giuseppe Petri.
- Geez, I knew it!
That's all you need,
one thieving wop on the team!
What's that you said?
I said that you're a lyin' member
of a no-good race.
That's much better than you,
you stinkin' Irish pig.
Oh, I like him.
Yeah, I like him, too.
You just joined
the Treasury Department, son.
Yeah, okay.
Eliot Ness.
With reports from stake-outs
on the North and West side, and...
Thank you, Lieutenant. Thank you.
What do you think?
I think there's nothing
like vaudeville.
- That's what I think.
- Now, are you ready to go to work?
- Where are we going?
- On a liquor raid.
We need another man.
Mr Ness? This is very interesting.
I've found a financial disbursement
pattern which shows some irregu...
- You carry a badge?
- Yes.
Carry a gun.
- Jimmy...?
- What?
What the hell are you dressed for?
Hallowe'en?
Shut up. I'm working.
Where? The circus?
- Well, here we are.
- What are we doing here?
Liquor raid.
Here?!
Everybody knows where the booze is.
The problem isn't finding it.
The problem is who wants
to cross Capone. Let's go.
You'd better be damn sure, Malone.
If you walk through this door,
you're walking into a world of trouble.
There's no turning back.
Do you understand?
Yes, I do.
Good. Give me that axe.
- Federal officers!
- Get your hands in the air!
- Nobody moves!
- This is a raid!
- Everybody...
- What are you doin' here?
All this stuff is impounded!
You're all under arrest!
Hey! This isn't right!
Hey! This is no good!
- You got a warrant?
- Sure! Here's my warrant.
How do you think he feels now?
Better... or worse?
- What is that?
- Yes, what is it?
- God, I'm with a heathen.
That is my callbox key.
And that is Saint Jude.
Il Santo Jude.
He's the patron saint of lost causes.
And policemen.
- Patron saint of policemen?
- Everybody needs a friend.
Lost causes, policemen...
- Which do you want to be?
- I want to be a cop.
- You do?
- Yes.
Why?
'To protect the property
and the citizenry... '
Whoa, it's all right.
- What?!
- I got to tell you, congratulations!
It's okay if I get a picture
of you and your men?
Yeah. But not for publication.
Just for us!
Anything you say, Mr Ness.
Closer in... Oh, that's great.
Okay, ready? Hold it.
Life goes on.
A man becomes preeminent,
he's expected to have enthusiasms.
Enthusiasms...
What are mine?
What draws my admiration?
What is that which gives me joy?
- Dames!
- Boozin'!
Baseball!
A man...
A man stands alone at the plate.
This is the time for what?
For individual achievement.
There he stands alone.
But in the field, what?
Part of a team.
Teamwork...
Looks, throws, catches, hustles.
Part of one big team.
Bats himself the live-long day,
Babe Ruth, Ty Cobb, and so on.
If his team don't field... what is he?
You follow me?
No one.
Sunny day, the stands are full
of fans. What does he have to say?
I'm goin' out there for myself.
But... I get nowhere
unless the team wins.
- Team!
- Team.
Jesus Christ!
'Now I lay me down to sleep'
'I pray the Lord my soul to keep'
'If I should die before I wake'
'I pray the Lord my soul to take'
- Amen.
- God bless...
God bless Mommy, God bless Annie,
God bless Daddy. Amen.
Amen.
Good night.
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, little girl.
Want to rub Eskimo?
Butterfly?
- Where are you going?
- What?
Where are you going?
I thought I'd go downstairs,
some work to do for tomorrow.
- You had a full day today, though?
- Yes, I certainly did.
And you've still got
some energy left?
Oh, a lot of work.
Well, why don't you come up
and brush my hair? You 'Detective'.
- How are we doin'?
- Capone's organisation is diverse.
It owns Canadian Holding Company
Associations, which owns in turn
Green Light Laundry, Midwest Cabs,
Jolly Time Playthings...
- Jolly Time Playthings?
- Yes.
Remind me to get a present
for my daughter.
...Bahama Ship-to-Shore,
Miss Lucy Togs... the list is endless!
And all the business is legitimate,
and none is owned by Al Capone.
But we can get him on
income tax evasion if we can show
that any of the 'organisation'
business money is going to him.
- Legally, he receives no income.
- He doesn't receive anything?
- Mr Ness? You have a visitor.
- Mister Ness!
Could we talk for a minute?
I'm John O'Shea, Alderman...
Yes, I know who you are.
Would you excuse us?
We are busy with several large
operations. What can I do for you?
I came up to congratulate you
on a job well done.
Share your good fortune
on such a lovely day.
What's that?
- What is that?
- Mr Ness, you're an educated man.
Let me pay you the compliment
of being blunt.
There is a large and popular business
which you are causing dismay.
Why don't you just cross the street
and let things take their course?
Would you come in here, please?
In Roman times, when a fellow tried
to bribe a public official,
they would cut off his nose,
sew him in a bag
with a wild animal,
and throw that bag in the river.
You tell your master
that we must agree to... disagree!
- You're making a mistake.
- I'm beginning to enjoy my mistakes.
You fellows are 'untouchable',
is that it? No one can get to you?
You tell Capone...
that I'll see him in hell.
Hey! Nice house!
I said, nice house!
Do you live there?
Little girl's havin' a birthday, huh?
Yes.
Nice to have a family.
Yes, it is.
A man should take care,
see that nothin' happens to them.
Catherine?!
Catherine!
- Where's the baby?
- She's upstairs. Eliot!
- What were you doing up?
- I had to finish my ironing.
You did? You're gonna come
with Daddy now, okay?
Eliot? Okay, it's all right!
Okay, let's go.
Stay there!
Keep your eye on the street!
- Where's Malone?
- On the stake-out. He'll be here.
- Who's this guy?
- He's on Malone's list. He's okay.
Drive to the station. She'll let you
know where to go when you get there.
Take off your hat.
Anything happens, shoot first.
You understand me?
Yes, Mr Ness.
Kiss.
- Eskimo and butterfly, Dad.
- Okay.
Now, go!
Malone!
- Are they okay?
- Yeah.
- You sure the cop's okay?
- He'd better be, he's my cousin.
I want to hurt the man, Malone!
You hear me?!
I want to take the battle to him.
I want to hurt Capone.
Well, then, a Merry Christmas,
we've got some great news.
A huge international
shipment's coming.
We've got the time, the place
and the whole shebang.
Well, what are we doin'
standin' here, then?
How do you come by this information?
That's the second rule
of police work:
If you want to keep a secret,
don't tell the boss.
You know he's making
over $3 million a year?
But he's paid no taxes,
nothing's in his name.
If we can establish
any payments to him,
we can prosecute him
for income tax evasion.
What?
I said, we can prosecute him
for income tax evasion!
Try a murderer
for not paying his taxes?!
Well, it's better than nothing.
All right. How do we
link him to the money?
I don't know.
Go to sleep, Oscar.
A convoy of 5-10 trucks
with good Canadian whiskey
will be met by a high-level member
of the Capone organisation.
He will be bringing full payment
for the shipment in cash.
Now, the meet is to take place just
over the border on the American side.
We want to confiscate
the liquor and the cash.
- Captain?
- We will await their signal.
When they're on the road
and have given the signal,
we will engage from
the Canadian side of the bridge.
Thus taking them
by surprise from the rear.
And surprise, as you very well know,
Mr Ness, is half the battle.
Surprise is half the battle.
Many things are half the battle.
Losing is half the battle.
Let's think about what is all the battle.
Let's take the fight
to them, gentlemen!
Thank you, Captain.
All right! Move out!
Take it easy.
Take it easy!
It'll all happen in time.
This is the job.
Don't wait for it to happen,
don't even want it to happen.
Just watch what does happen.
Are you my 'tutor'?
Yes, sir, that I am.
- Did you check it already?
- Yes, I did.
Then leave it alone.
You're a good cop, Giuseppe.
You're doing good.
You're gonna do just fine.
- Wallace, are you cold?
- Yes, I am, a little.
Then stamp your feet.
It'll keep you warm.
You learn something,
20 years walking the beat.
Stitches and standing in the rain...
Listen, Mr Ness...
I had an idea.
You all have your spare shells?
If you have to fire,
hold low and squeeze.
And put your man down.
Because he'll do the same to you.
Shoot to kill.
- Did you hear what I said?
- Yes, I did. Shoot to kill.
Let's go.
Easy...
The Canadians will not show
until I flash the badge.
So we must cover the ground
to the bridge as quickly as possible.
George, the count's right.
I'm concerned about
the size of these barrels!
Malone, you and I will
take the men...
Move it! Move it, Georgie!
Get over here!
Leave the stuff in the cars!
Charge!
What the hell!
You got to die of somethin'.
- Look! Here they come!
- Mounties! Let's get out of here!
Move, move!
Let's go!
I can't believe it!
- Here are the codes.
- Give me that.
Don't let those cars off the bridge!
Stone, take the first car!
Get this shit out of the way!
Tough guy!
Stone!
Go!
I'm okay.
You thugs!
You all right?
Yeah. There he is! Go get him!
All right!
Enough of this running shit!
Well, Georgie-boy!
Well, what have we got here?
Hello.
All right! Drop the gun!
Put your hands in the air,
you're under arrest.
I said, drop it!
Stop!
God, didn't ya hear what I said?!
What are you, deaf?!
What is this, a game?!
Here. Sit down.
Stone's gonna be all right.
I got the fellow with the satchel.
- I had to kill him.
- Oh, yeah.
He's as dead as Julius Caesar.
- Would you rather it was you?
- No, I would not.
Well, then you've done your duty.
Go home and sleep well tonight.
The things you see
when you're out without your gun.
Now you're a long way
from the Southside, George.
I'm talkin' to you. Did you come
here to open a shooting gallery?
I want you to write down the names
of your superiors and contacts.
Why don't you kiss my ass?
- Perhaps you didn't hear me.
- Eliot?
- You've broken the law...
- Eliot!
You can be tough in Leavenworth
for 30 years.
- You're going inside for all day!
- Is that what you want?
- Eliot!
- What?!
Look at this!
- Look at this!
- What is this?
What is this?
You got a lot of money changing
hands in this book.
What is this, 'war'?
And 'police precincts'?
And you got a heading here...
'Circuit Court'.
You got a heading here,
'Circuit Court'. What is this?
Nothin'. There's nothin'
you can make out of it.
If any of these coded entries
indicate payment to Capone,
then we can put Capone away.
- Which entry is Al Capone?
- A. Costa, is that his code name?
You'll do the whole thing
in the joint unless you help us.
Translate this ledger for us!
- In hell.
- In hell?!
You will hang high
unless you cooperate.
This man can finger Al Capone,
put him behind bars.
Why don't you guys just fuck off?!
I'm not fuckin' with you! We'll have
that information one way or another.
- Not that way. Out.
- You're gonna talk!
You're gonna be beggin' to talk!
- You dirty son-of-a-bitch!
- Enough out of you.
Hey, come on, you, on your feet!
I need you to help me
to translate this book!
I'm not gonna ask you a second time.
I'm gonna count to three.
What's the matter? Can't you talk
with a gun in your mouth?
One.
Two!
Three.
I'm gonna talk!
Don't! I'm gonna tell ya whatever
ya want. What do ya want to know?
Now, don't let him clean himself
until after he talks.
Now, ask him what you want to know.
All right... Okay, I want to know
the name of the bookkeeper.
I want a complete translation
of the code. I want a complete...
Mister Ness!
I do not approve of your methods!
Yeah? Well, you're not from Chicago.
- What?
- They got the shipment.
- What?!
- They got the whole shipment.
- I want that son-of-a-bitch dead!
- We're trying to locate...
What am I, alone in this world? Did I
ask you what you're tryin' to do?
I want you to get this fuck where he
breathes! I want Eliot Ness dead!
I want his family dead,
his house burnt to the ground!
I want to piss on his ashes!
Look at this guy, this guy,
he's so serious.
- Well, he's got a lot on his mind.
- He does?
- Yes.
- Like what?
Like what his name is.
John, I thought that was all settled.
I thought we liked John.
I suppose his middle name
will be Law.
No... it'll be Edgar.
- It'll be J. Edgar...
- I don't think so.
God, you're beautiful.
You should have seen us last night.
I know. I should have been here.
I wanted to be here.
I know. I understand, I do.
Just tell me, are you being careful?
- Careful as mice.
- Are you making progress?
- Progress?
- Yes?
Mrs Ness, I think your husband
just became the man who got Al Capone.
Gentlemen! A subpoena was issued
for Alphonse Capone
by my office this morning,
for the crime of evading
and conspiring to evade
Federal Income Tax.
- What's the maximum he could get?
- If convicted on all counts,
Mr Capone could have
up to 28 years.
Excuse me, that's all. Thank you.
The car's in the yard. When ya get
him there, don't answer the phone.
- We'll call, let it ring...
- Twice.
- We'll call...
- From the corner.
- Anybody knocks on the door...
- Come out shooting. I got it.
You enjoy the tactical aspects
of law enforcement, Oscar?
Much more diverting
than accounting.
I'm bein' good to you,
you got to be good to me.
We made a deal,
we're gonna stick to it, okay?
Oh, yes, much more diverting
than accounting.
Okay, we see yous tonight.
All right, all the way down
and no stops.
...he's been saying,
"I will speak up."
For which I must commend
the excellent work
of Eliot Ness
and his squad of Untouchables.
- What was it, a boy or a girl?
- Boy.
- Congratulations! What's his name?
- John.
- John?
- Yeah. John James.
- So she's okay?
- Yeah, she's okay.
In fact, when she gets out,
she wants to repaint the house.
Then she'll find the house too small,
you'll have to move.
- Goodness, it's nice to be married.
- If you can stand the pain.
Mr Burns, where's Mr Wallace?
Didn't you see him? He just went
down in the service elevator.
- You keep an eye out at all times...
- Take it easy, we'll be fine.
They are going to...
- Did he say the service elevator?
- Yes.
- Wallace! Wallace!
- Here, let's take the stairs.
Oh, no.
- No, no!
- Easy... Easy!
Oscar.
Oh, Jesus.
You gonna be all right?
It's always a crime when a young guy
goes down in the line, Jimmy.
I'd hate to see it happen
to someone I know.
Sometimes it's better
not to get involved.
Jimmy!
Take a day off.
Get out of the city for a while.
You know what I mean?
- Al Capone.
- We have no Mr Capone...
- I know, get him.
I said...
- Something you want here?
- My friend was killed today.
- I don't care.
- You don't care.
Now he does.
Come on here, Capone. You want
to fight? You and me, right here?
That's it, come on!
You afraid to come out from behind
your men, to stand up for yourself?
- You want to do the mat now?
- Yeah! Come on, you son-of-a-bitch!
- What?
- Easy.
You talk to me like that in front
of my son? Fuck you and your family!
Easy. It's me. It's me!
Not this way.
You fuck, you got nothin'!
You're nothin' but talk and a badge.
You're here because you got nothin'
in court, no bookkeeper, nothin'!
If you were a man, you would've done
it now! You got nothin', you punk!
Well, no, I understand.
Believe me, I understand.
Well, what's happened?
He says he can't be unprotected.
What is it that the guy says?
He says he won't make
a fool out of himself,
and he won't go into court
without a witness.
So tomorrow morning the D.A. Will
announce that he's dropping the case.
- He's gonna give up.
- He won't do it without a witness.
We have Wallace's files
and the ledgers.
There's a time when I think
you have to cut your losses.
Hello?
Hello.
Yes.
No, he didn't have a family.
How is everything there?
No, you do it however you want.
I promise I will.
You give her my love.
I love you, too.
Mr Ness, we got a ledger here listing
payments to Chicago City officials.
- We got Al Capone, Frank Nitti...
- I think that's enough for today.
- If we don't stay on top...
- That'll do. Thank you.
I'd like to request to stick around.
- We got to bust these guys.
- I know we got to.
Is that it?
- I'm sorry?
- You heard me.
My question is, are we done?
Yes, I think we're done.
So we sat in at a game
that was above our head?
It appears so.
It appears so to Mr Wallace.
He's dead! And the D.A.
Is gonna drop the case!
He will not go into court
without a witness
and without Capone's bookkeeper,
Walter Payne.
- What are you prepared to do now?
- What would you have me do?
I have taken this
as far as it can go.
- What did your wife want?
- She wanted to know if I was...
- My wife?
- Yeah.
She wanted to know
if I was all right.
It's nice being married, eh?
Yes.
She's sitting in some room surrounded
by people she doesn't know,
going over...
kitchen colour charts or something.
Some part of the world still cares
what colour the kitchen is.
Eliot, I want you to do
one more thing for me.
Get back to the D.A. And stall him.
- Wait a minute, stall him with what?
- Just do as I say.
I think I know how to find this guy.
Walter?
Al says we got to get out of town
until he can fix this subpoena thing.
We're leavin' tonight.
Two ball, down.
Mike, you got a minute?
I do now, don't I?
And what are you doin'
in a club for cops, Jimmy?
This is a place for cops.
Can we step outside?
All right, all right,
but I got nothin' to say to ya.
Where the hell are we going, for a
swim? Get out of the rain, you fool.
What? What?!
I just need one more
piece of information.
One more? Jimmy!
- I just risked my life for ya.
- I need to find that bookkeeper.
Are you crazy? You're crazy.
I warned you to get out of town.
- If they knew it was me, I'm dead.
- I need to find that bookkeeper.
You're fuckin' nuts, man!
You're out of your fuckin' mind!
And I tried to save your life.
Get your hands off. You owe me,
Jimmy, I don't owe you nothin'.
- My people are being killed.
- We're your people!
You?! You fuckin' run with the dagos!
They've ruined this town.
For ten years I can't say that I'm
a cop for the shit that's goin' on!
Ah, bullshit! Fuckin' bullshit!
Look at yourself! Look at yourself!
Go on and live the charade, with your
soft clothes and federal stooges.
- What do you think he's gonna do?
- Keep your mouth off that!
I need to know where this guy is,
and I need to know now!
I'm gonna rat you out for all the shit
that I know that you've done!
I'm gonna turn you over!
- This is a dead man talkin' to me.
- Is it?
You're dead.
Who the hell do ya think ya are?
I'll have your ass hangin'
from the flagpole in the mornin'.
Let's cut the woofing, pal.
You tell me,
or you're going to hospital
or the fuckin' morgue!
You're gonna fight it out
and we'll have a case.
Yes? On what basis?
I'm not gonna make a fool...
Don't tell me about
makin' a fool out of yourself.
I have men out there
risking more than that.
We have a lead,
and we are following that lead
at risk to more than our standing.
So don't you dare stop now.
- Yeah, Stone.
- Give me Ness.
He's at the D.A. 's.
Tell him I know where Payne is
and to meet me at my place.
- Al! Al!
- Mr Capone!
- What about that court case?
- I'm gonna tell ya somethin'.
Somebody messes with me,
I'm gonna mess with him.
Somebody steals from me,
I'm gonna say 'you stole',
not talk to him
for spittin' on the sidewalk.
You understand?
Now, I have done nothing
to hurt these people.
But they're angered at me.
So what do they do?
Doctor up some income tax, for which
they got no case, to annoy me.
To speak to me like men? No.
To harass a peaceful man.
I pray to God that
if I ever have a grievance,
I would have
just a little more self respect.
I'll tell you one more thing.
In an all-out prize fight,
when one guy's left standing,
that's how you know who won.
Isn't that just like a wop?
Brings a knife to a gun fight.
Get out of here, ya dago bastard!
Go on, get your ass out of here!
Shots! Shots! I heard shots!
Stay back, everybody stay back,
right now.
Round the back.
Malone!
Malone.
Goddamn! Stone!
Stone!
The phone!
Oh, God. Call an ambulance!
This is Stone, Treasury Department,
1634 Racine, we need an ambulance.
- What?
- 1634 Racine!
This? You want this?
You want this?
What?
- Bookkeeper.
- What?
- Book...
- The bookkeeper?
- Bookkeeper!
- The bookkeeper? What?
- The bookkeeper, he's on this train?
- Yes.
He's on this train.
Now! What are you prepared to do?!
No. Malone. No.
Stay. Stay.
Stay! Malone...
No. No, no!
Not this... Not this man...
Train's leavin' for Miami
12.05, Mr Ness.
We'll be there.
The bookkeeper's no good to us dead.
- Stone?
- Yes, sir.
Cover the south entrance.
We're almost home.
Your attention, please. The Miami
Flier departs at 12.05 from 33.
All aboard.
Stay right there.
Stay right there, honey.
Your attention, please.
The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
now boarding on track 33.
All aboard!
Just here.
I'm just gonna leave this right here.
Your attention, please.
The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
is now boarding on track 33.
All aboard!
One more. Here we go.
Here we go. You ready?
I'm right here, honey. Here we go.
Your attention, please.
May I have your attention, please?
This is the fiinal call
for the Miami Flier,
leaving at 12.05 on track 33.
All aboard!
- Here, let me. Get your bags.
- Oh, thank you so much. Thank you.
Are you all right? Thank you.
You're such a gentleman.
It's so kind of you to help me.
I really wasn't sure
if we'd make it or not.
Is there some problem
I can help you with?
- No.
- I really can't thank you enough.
Isn't this fun? You're being
such a good boy, sweetheart.
Thank you again,
this is so wonderful.
Thank you, sir.
Please, let me take it from here.
You've been such a great help.
Thank you so much.
We're almost there.
I'll take it from here, sir.
Thank you very much for your help.
Don't cry, sweetheart.
We're almost home.
Is something wrong?
Sir?
Come on!
Come on, let's get out of here.
- What are you doin'?
- Shut up!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Hold it!
- Please...
- My baby!
- Stay there. He's all right.
I said hold it!
I'm walkin' out with the bookkeeper.
The bookkeeper and me
are drivin' away.
See? Or else he dies.
He dies, and you ain't got nothin'.
You got five seconds
to make up your mind.
- I'll tell ya what ya want to know!
- Shut up! I'm not kiddin'!
He's crazy! Don't let him do this,
I'll tell you what you want to know!
- You got him?
- Yeah, I got him.
- One!
- Will you stop it!
Take him.
Two.
The two coded entries
in this ledger
represent cash disbursement
to all levels of city officials,
members of the police
and to Alphonse Capone.
- That's correct.
- Excuse me?
I said that is correct.
And you will decipher
these coded entries for us?
I will.
Sorry, Mr Payne, I can't hear you.
I said, I will.
You were in charge
of disbursements for Mr Capone?
Yes, I was.
And you personally
distributed monies...
...vast, undeclared monies...
...to Mr Capone?
Yes, I did.
Would you tell us the amounts?
In a three-year period I personally
disbursed monies to Mr Capone
in excess of one
and a third million dollars.
Would you repeat that amount, please?
- One and a third million dollars.
- Thank you very much.
I don't understand it.
What does Capone have?
We're nailing the lid on his coffin,
and he's smiling.
The son-of-a-bitch
is wearing a gun in court.
Get me the bailiff.
It'll be a fast trial.
The man in the front row wearing
a white suit is carrying a gun.
I don't want this to turn
into something. I'll lead you out.
Could we speak to you
a minute, please?
- Get up against it.
- You heard him. Now, up against it!
- What's this?
- Empty all your pockets, all of it.
- I've got a permit for that.
- Fine, let's see it.
- I'm not the one under indictment.
- Everything on the table.
- Let me see.
- Give him his gun back.
"To Whom It May Concern.
Please extend to the bearer,"
"Mr Frank Nitti, all possible
courtesy and consideration."
"William Thompson,
Mayor of the City of Chicago."
I'm sorry, Mr Ness,
you'll have to give it back.
Fine. But that man does not go
back into that courtroom.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes, sir.
1634 Racine... You know, I used
to have a friend who lived there.
Don't. Let him go.
- No!
- Here, take it.
Here I am, Treasury Man.
Come on! Harass me!
What are you waitin' for?
Don't just stand there!
Harass me!
Don't push me.
- They're gonna burn you, buddy.
- Yeah?
Yeah. I'm gonna come see you burn,
you son-of-a-bitch!
'Cause you killed my friend!
- He died like a pig.
- What did you say?
I said that your friend died
screaming like a stuck Irish pig.
Now you think about that
when I beat the rap.
Did he sound anything like that?
One picture, come on, one picture.
Mr Ness, take a look at this.
Mr Ness?
Mr Ness, are you doin' okay?
I think you'd better see this.
- What is it?
- That's the jury list, Mr Ness.
They've been bribed.
I got it out of Nitti's coat.
Where is Nitti?
He's in the car.
This constitutes no evidence.
I'm not about to allow...
Your Honour, the truth is that Capone
is a killer and he will go free.
There is only one way to deal with
such men, and that is hunt them down.
I have. I have forsworn myself.
I have broken laws I swore to defend.
I am content that I have done right.
That man must be stopped, you must...
I'll be the judge
of what I must do, Mr Ness.
Would you excuse us?
- Bailiff.
- Yes, sir.
I want you to go next door
to Judge Hoffman's Court,
where they've just begun hearing
a divorce action.
I want you to bring that jury in here
and take this jury to his court.
- Are those instructions clear?
- Yes, sir, they're clear.
What's he talking about?
Bailiff, I want you
to switch the juries.
Your Honour, I object!
Overruled.
What did you tell him?
I told him his name was
in the ledger, too.
His name wasn't in the ledger!
Wait a second! Is this the law?
What's goin' on here?
- You're out of order.
- What's goin' on?
- I think...
- Do somethin' here.
What do I look like to you?
Do somethin'!
Order!
Your Honour, we'd like to withdraw
our plea of Not Guilty,
and enter a plea of Guilty.
- Guilty?
- Order in the court!
Order!
Bailiff! Bailiff!
Bailiff, clear the courtroom!
Eliot!
Your Honour!
Is that justice?
Please, why did he switch the jury?
Are you gonna go
after the organisation?
Excuse me.
I'm askin' Your Honour,
is this justice?
Is this justice?
Never stop fighting
till the fight is done.
What did you say?
I said, never stop fighting
till the fight is done.
- What?
- You heard me, Capone. It's over.
You're nothin'
but a lot of talk and a badge.
Here endeth the lesson.
You're nothin'
but a lot of talk and a badge!
So much violence.
Cleaning up a little.
I guess this is goodbye.
Goodbye, George.
I want to... thank you for this.
No. Thank you.
Mr Ness... I think he would have
wanted you to have that.
He'd have wanted a cop to have it.
I'm going home.
Mr Ness!
Any comment for the record?
'The man who put
Al Capone on the spot.'
I just happened to be there
when the wheel went round.
They say they're going
to repeal prohibition.
- What will you do then?
- I think I'll have a drink.