THE PASSION OF JOAN OF ARC
A film by Carl Th. Dreyer
At the Bibliotheque de la
Chambre des Deputes in Paris
resides one of the most
extraordinary documents
in the history of the world:
the record of the trial of
Joan of Arc, the trial
that ended in her death.
The questions of the judges
and Joan's responses
were recorded exactly.
Reading it, we discover
the real Joan...
not in armor,
but simple and human...
a young woman who died
for her country...
and we are witness to an
amazing drama:
a young, pious woman
confronted by a group
of orthodox theologians and
powerful judges.
I swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth...
nothing but the truth...
In France I'm called Joan...
in my village,
I'm called Jeannette.
How old are you?
Nineteen...I think.
Do you know the Lord's Prayer?
Who taught it to you?
My mother.
Will you recite it?
You claim to be sent by God?
To save France...
it's why I was born.
So you think God hates
the English?
I don't know if God loves
or hates the English...
but I do know that the English
will all be chased from France...
except those that die here!
You have said that St. Michael
appeared to you...in what form?
Did he have wings?
Did he wear a crown?
How was he dressed?
How did you know if it was
a man or a woman?
Was he naked?
Do you think God was unable
to clothe him?
Did he have long hair?
Why would he have cut it?
Why do you wear men's clothing?
If we give you women's clothing,
would you wear it?
When the mission that God has
entrusted to me is over...
I will again dress as a woman.
So it is God who orders you
to dress as a man?
And what reward do you
expect from God?
The salvation of my soul.
You blaspheme God.
This is disgraceful.
For me, she is a saint.
Has God made you promises?
That has nothing to do
with this trial.
Shouldn't we let the judges
decide that?
Shall we put this question
to a vote?
So! What has God promised you?
Perhaps that you will be
delivered from prison?
When?
I know neither the day...
nor the hour.
Since she couldn't be made
to confess easily...
we will have to be clever...
Go find a letter bearing the
signature of King Charles.
I will dictate a letter.
I have great sympathy for you!
Do you know the signature
of your King?
I have a letter from him
for you.
I can't read.
To our beloved Joan...
I am preparing to march on Rouen
with a mighty army.
I send you this devoted priest.
Have confidence in him.
Just as Jesus
is the son of God...
you claim to be
the daughter of God?
Will you recite the
Lord's Prayer?
God has told you that you shall
be delivered from prison?
By a great victory!
God has promised you that
you will go to Heaven?
So you are certain of
being saved?
Be careful,
it's a dangerous answer.
Since you are sure of
your salvation...
you have no need of the Church?
Are you in a state of grace?
Respond!
If I am, may God keep me there.
If I am not,
may God grant it to me!
Father...
permit me to attend Mass.
Joan, if we permit you
to attend Mass...
will you stop wearing
men's clothes?
So, you would rather dress
as a man than attend Mass?
These shameless clothes...
abominable to God...
You are no daughter of God...
You are Satan's creature!
Go prepare the torture chamber.
She really looks like
a daughter of God, eh?
The torture chamber.
Regard your judges.
Do you not feel that these
learned doctors
are wiser than you?
But God is even wiser!
Listen, Joan, we know that your
visions do not come from God...
but from the devil.
How do you know a good angel
from an evil angel?
You have knelt before Satan,
not St. Michael!
Don't you see
that it's the Devil
who has turned your head...
who has tricked you...
and betrayed you?
I think she's ready to abjure!
The Church opens its arms
to you...
but if you reject it,
the Church will abandon you...
and you will be alone...
alone!
Yes, alone...
alone, with God!
Even if you part my soul
from my body...
I will confess nothing...
And if I do confess,
later I will say
it was forced from me!
Not for anything in the world
do I want her to die
a natural death.
She is very weak.
She has a fever...
we must bleed her.
Be careful, she could end
her own life...
she's very crafty.
Bring the Sacraments.
Is there something
you wish to tell us?
I fear that I am about to die...
and if I do, I ask you to
bury me in sacred ground.
The Church is merciful...
It always welcomes
the misguided lamb.
Joan, we all want what's
best for you.
Look, I have sent
for the Sacraments.
I am a good Christian.
Do you not know it is the
Body of Christ you refuse?
Do you not see that you
outrage God by your obstinacy?
I love and honor God...
with all my heart.
You claim...that I am...
sent by the devil.
It's not true...
to make me suffer,
the devil has sent you...
and you...
There is nothing left
to be done...
alert the executioner!
Let us try one last time
to save this lost soul...
It is to you, Joan,
that I speak.
It is to you that I say
your King is a heretic!
My King is the most noble
Christian of all.
The arrogance of this woman
is insane.
France has never seen
such a monster...
I have never wronged anyone.
If you do not sign,
you will be burned alive...
The stake awaits you...
You don't have the right to die.
Your King still needs you.
Joan, sign...
and save your life!
Joan, we have great
sympathy for you.
Sign, Joan!
In the name of the Lord. Amen.
Having recognized your errors,
you shall not be excommunicated.
But as you have greatly sinned,
we condemn you...
to perpetual imprisonment,
to eat the bread of sorrow
and drink the water of anguish.
A good day's work:
you have saved
your life and your soul.
She has only made fools of you!
Long live Joan!
Go find the judges!
I take it back, I have lied...
Hurry!
I have committed a great sin...
I have denied God...
to save my life.
But Joan, you have confessed
before everyone
that the devil misled you.
You still believe you were
sent by God?
Her answer will bring her death.
Everything I said was for
fear of the stake.
Have you anything else
to tell us?
We have come to prepare you
for death.
Now...already?
How am I to die?
At the stake.
I'll bring the last Sacrament.
How can you still believe
that you are sent by God?
His ways are not our ways.
Yes, I am His child.
And the great victory?
...my martyrdom!
...and your deliverance?
...death!
Will you take confession?
May the Body of Our Lord
Jesus Christ keep my soul...
unto life everlasting. Amen.
Be courageous, Joan.
Your last hour approaches.
Dear God, I accept
my death gladly...
but do not let me suffer
too long.
Will I be with You tonight
in Paradise?
Jesus!
You have burned a saint!
The flames sheltered
Joan's soul...
as it rose to heaven -
Joan whose heart has become
the heart of France...
Joan, whose memory
will always be cherished...
by the people of France.