Big, round and bright.
They can see us a mile away
on a night like this.
Hey, frog, stop your croaking!
Go on, you runners! You're not
snuggling in a woman's tits tonight.
Carry me, if you're so smart!
Well? Was that your big warehouse
attack?
Oh, my legs!
Why don't you carry my ass?
How could I know they'd be here?
Went for a booty,
came back robbed.
It serves you right, you good-for-
nothings!
Are your mouths watering!
A warehouse!
What the hell did you drag that psycho
along for?
The Germans were right behind us.
They tried to take him away.
If it hadn't been for him,
we wouldn't all be here.
You'd be back in Bobruisk,
in your kerosene shop.
Gleb would be
in his Leningrad swamp.
You know, back home in Slutsk, we had
a guy who made vodka out of soap.
What are you always laughing at?
They asked a guy with a hump:
"How come your back's all round?"
He says: "That's 'cause my chest
caves in!"
- You're a hopeless optimist.
- He should be cured of that.
As for crying, there's already enough
crying in the world.
So she says, "If I'd known all that,
I'd never have given birth to you."
Charge it!
This guy ain't going to holler
no more!
Come on, hurry!
Don't tickle me, or my fart
is going to flatten Europe!
The devil is not so black
as his SS shits.
I'd like to watch that!
Right. Let's go.
If you're so generous,
why don't you drop tobacco off!
"Kill the Bolshevik yids.
Smash a brick in their ugly mugs."
That's all?
Sent planes to deliver just that?
Hey, Jew boys!
Stand up! March on!
Well? Shall we try one more time?
Or like Roubej says, "Stay right on
my heels as trouble won't be far".
Do we go?
Maybe we'll wait till night?
Back there, people are starving,
and we're doing nothing.
Go on! Move! The Germans are
in a hurry! Don't slow'em down!
Damn!
Let's go! Come on!
Where you going?
There you are. We haven't seen
you for a while.
How can we manage without you?
The only reason you fly over us
is to drop your little gifts.
How about a motorbike
and side-car?
Haven't ridden in one
for a long time!
Get down!
They get drunk up there,
and we return the empties!
Hold it, dad.
You'll finish it later.
Who is it?.. Who's there?..
- Quiet! Are you in the police?
- And who are you, guys?
Button up, you'll catch cold.
Is this village Kamenka?
No, no. This is Bagoushovka.
The Germans have been here
two days already.
- Is the cow-shed locked?
- No.
You're going to lead us out, along
with the cow. Got that, dad?
And don't try any tricks.
You'll get us out and run back.
Be quick about it. Just be natural.
Yes, alright. If I have to, I have to.
I like men with common sense.
Fliora, are you awake?
Your doors squeak.
Better grease'em.
How come the Germans didn't kill
the dogs? It's not right.
You're white and your cow, too.
What'll we cover you with?
- I'll get something in the house.
- A rifle, maybe?
That's a trick you can pull on my
neighbor. His name's "Idiot".
There's horse manure.
Roll in it.
What's your rank in the police?
No, I'm not in the police!
It's the defence militia.
Let's go now, and quick! Wouldn't
want your wife start missing you.
Go on!
Don't turn around, or you'll fall.
Crouch down.
Now you go back.
Back home. Got it?
And keep your mouth shut.
You tell nobody.
Get going! Run!
Or your old lady'll bawl you out!
I wonder what our dad's doing now?
He took a little walk
to do his business.
He had a nice pair of boots on.
Box-calf leather.
Maybe he's looking for us,
wants to trade his boots for mine?
Nice cow, good one, stay here.
Hold still!
Hold still, my dear.
Go on, milk her!
We'll get drunk, you and me.
That's the good life!
Uncle Roubej!
Ho, giddy-up! Giddy-up, ho!
Hey, what are you doing?
What are you doing, comrade?
I haven't got time to waste talking
to you!
You got a hatchet? There's meat.
A cow's been killed there!
Hey, wait! It's my horse
you're taking!
There're kids, a lot of people
starving to death!
And us, ain't we people, too?
People are fighting,
and you stay nice and warm inside.
Look what they did!
See what they did?
Easy, boy, take it easy.
You crazy or what?
Put it all in there.
The belt, the jacket...
Hide it in there.
Go on, hurry!
Oh, such a thing!
- What village is that?
- Perekhody.
- We got two families with that name.
- You'll be a Perekhod, too. Got it?
We had one like you who got drowned.
You'll be him.
What was his name?
You got a mother, you got sisters
and brothers.
Olga, Katka, Fedia, and little Sonia.
You remember it all.
Your mother's name is Fiokla Perekhod.
And your name is Zhenka.
You got it?
Let's get out of here.
This morning, I insulted
a German soldier.
And where's my father?
- Say he's gone.
- Gone where?
Where? Hell! What does it matter?
Come with me.
Say you're Mitrophane,
my grandson. You got it?
This is my family.
Aksinya Perekhod, my daughter-in-law...
my sister and her children.
- And who's that?
- My son-in-law. He's an accountant.
Those are my sister's children,
Lima, Raya,
Zoika, Vika, Veronica,
and little Boris.
Get down!
Search the houses!
We came to see you...
These are our neighbors, Maria and
her kids, Lucia, Frosia, Fenya, Ivan.
We know what they want. They'll
take some and deport them to Germany.
Who are they going to take? You?
Come in. Everything's fine.
You go and look on the roof.
Quiet... quiet.
Do you speak German?
Me? Yes. Do you speak it, too?
Do you speak German, too?
Sit down.
Please, eat.
You take all you want, Sir.
What have you got here?
Oh, a partisan!
They put up some resistance not far from
here.
Why are you drinking alone?
Pour some for me, too.
Please, schnapps.
Inhabitants of the village of
Perekhody!
Everybody in the village!
Listen carefully!
You all take your children
and your papers.
Go to the village square.
We look at papers of all families
and lists...
...and how German Army authorities'
orders are being followed.
You must have all documents
proving delivery of
agricultural produce.
No one is to stay in the houses,
or in the barns,
in cellars, on rooves or in attics...
Wait! Where are you running?
They're going to slaughter you!
What are you staring at?
Look down, bastard!
I'm going to kill him!
Take something to eat
for two days.
Bring all children...
...Maintain order and discipline...
Germany is... civilized country.
Everyone who goes to Germany
must have a toothbrush,
toothpaste, shoe-polish, soap,
a towel for every member of a family.
To take fruits and vegetables
is forbidden
in order not to infect Europe.
l, the officer of
sanitary inspection,
ascertain that the cause of death
was seven bullets
that got stuck
in the upper thorax.
Anyone who won't follow
the orders of the German Army
will meet the same
miserable fate.
Herr Major, everything is fine!
Sturmbanfuhrer, everything's ready.
Do we invite them in?
Will there be any signal?
Damn it! Bugger those bastards!
Welcome, my dear friends!
We caught a yid!
This Jew bastard wasn't smart enough
not to get caught!
Dirty Jew!
Grab him!
Let me out! What are you doing,
bastards? I'm one of you!
Quiet!
Now, we're starting our village
meeting.
If anybody has anything to say,
go ahead and sign in!
What are they doing there?
Quiet down!
Get out, but no children.
Right here, out of the window.
Leave the children.
Come on, move it!
Beasts!
Come on, get out.
Have you heard that he's taken up
command of a division?
That's great! Don't you think so?
Let go!
What a picture!
I'll kill you!
To the right.
Look! Empty! Empty!
Ah, shit-ass clerks, that's what
you are! The intelligentsia!
More gasoline.
Let it soak through.
Get up! Lead the cows!
You! March!
Go! Faster!
Faster, you bastard!
Petro, want some honey?
We'll leave you here, grandma...
to reproduce!
You make all of us some children.
To love... to have children...
Out of the way!
Move! Out of the way!
Wait!
Are you all crazy?!
You want to just kill them?..
Just like that?
They're all SS! Punitive detachment!
They lit the fire. We're not Germans!
Sit down!
They made us do everything.
Bastards! I lost my children
in that burning hell!
Rank and unit?
Walter Stein, SD Major.
15th Einsatzkommando.
That's the leader.
He gave all the orders.
He's an old, sick man.
He never did any harm to anyone.
He is,
like his father was,
a man of principle.
He... he never harboured
any hatred of your people.
He's never killed anyone,
he wouldn't kill a fly.
Everyone here can confirm that,
and he hopes they will.
He's just a tired, old man.
"I want to quit."
That's what he's saying.
He wants to take care of his grand-
children. He's got grandkids just like you.
But this is war time, and it's
nobody's fault, this German says.
Swine! Dog!
A typical German!
Bastard! Shit!
He's the one...
He's the one who said: "Leave
the children.
You can come out,
but not the children".
He's a fascist! Executioner!
Yes, I said that: "Come out
and leave the children".
Translate it.
I said that because with the children
it starts all over again.
You've no right to exist.
Not every race
has a right to exist.
Listen!
Everyone, listen!
Inferior races
spread the contagion of communism.
You have no right to be.
And our mission will be accomplished.
If not today, tomorrow.
It isn't me. He's the one who said it!
We're not Germans!
We won't do it again!
Forgive us!
We're not Germans!
Not Germans! You've forgotten
what these dogs did?!
They're degenerates! They should be
killed! But we're not Germans...
Then who are you, you filthy slime?
They made us do it!
We're not Germans!
Death to the fascist bastards!
Make them pay! Kill them!
You'll do that yourself.
And you'll pay like the Germans.
Give it to me! Give it!
I'm one of you!
Brothers, I'm one of you!
Comrade, let's light it!
Comrade, let me have a torch!
Out of the way!
The new one!
Come on, we're going!
626 VILLAGES IN BYELORUSSIA
WERE BURNT TO THE GROUND
WITH ALL THEIR INHABITANTS
Move it! Let's go!
The End