Yes, sir.
I got grease
in this lining.
It'll take about
30 minutes to check it.
Check the oil, too.
Boys just
passing through?
Yep.
Pittsburgh?
Uh-huh.
We got
a sales convention.
What do
you guys sell?
Druggist supplies.
Buster's going
to get an award.
He sold 17,000 bucks
worth of stuff last month.
Fastest
and the best.
Hey, give us
another round, will you?
It's a hot day
for driving.
Late afternoon
is better.
You guys have
plenty of time.
Make Pittsburgh in two,
maybe three hours.
Hey, he's right.
What do you say?
Play a little pool?
Wait out the heat?
It's going to
cost you money.
Grab yourself a cue.
Good thing
he can afford it.
Keep them coming,
will you, friend?
J.T.S. Brown.
Hmm?
Ah.
You miss again,
you lose again.
What's the kid
in hock for?
About 60, 70 bucks.
Next game, 10 bucks.
Nice-looking boy.
It's too bad he can't
hold his liquor.
I made it, boy!
Pay up, sucker!
Talk about luck.
What do you mean?
You couldn't make
that shot again
in a million years.
I couldn't, huh?
Go ahead,
set them up
the way they were before.
Why?
Go ahead.
Bet you 20 bucks
I'll make this shot.
Nobody can
make that shot,
not even
a lucky lush.
How's that?
That the way
they were before?
Yeah.
That's it.
Come on.
Put it up.
Ha ha ha!
Set them up again.
Come on.
Set them up again!
You're drunk, boy.
No more bets.
We got to be
at that convention
in the morning.
Up the flagpole
with the convention!
I got my money
on the table.
I don't want it.
I'll try you.
Well.
Don't be a chump.
Don't bet
any more money.
Well, well, well!
You figure
I'm a little drunk,
and you just want in
real friendly
while the money's
still floating, huh?
Okay.
Go ahead.
Set them up.
You want some
easy money, huh?
Here's $105.
That's one week's
commissions.
You want to take
the whole thing?
I'll take a piece.
No. I want him.
Okay.
I'll meet you
in the car, chump.
Morning, Henry.
Quiet.
Yeah.
Like a church.
Church of the good hustler.
Looks more like a morgue.
Those tables are the slabs
they lay the stiffs on.
I'll be alive
when I get out, Charlie.
Any table?
Any table.
No bar?
No bar.
No pinball machines.
No bowling alleys.
Just pool.
Nothing else.
This is Ames, mister.
Nice clean pocket drop.
How much am I going to win
tonight?
10 grand.
I'm going to win
10 grand in one night.
Who's going to beat me?
Come on, Charlie.
Who's going to
beat me?
Okay, okay.
Nobody can beat you.
10 grand.
Is there
any other pool room
where a guy can leave
with 10 grand in one night?
I can remember
hustling an old man
for a dime a game.
You looking
for action?
Maybe.
You Eddie Felson?
Who's he?
What's
your game?
You name it,
we shoot it.
Look, friend.
I'm not trying
to hustle.
Don't try to
hustle me.
Okay. I'm Eddie Felson.
Got any straight pool
shooters here?
What kind of
straight pool game?
The expensive kind.
Come here to play
with Minnesota Fats?
Yeah, that's right.
Want some free advice?
How much
will it cost?
Who are you,
his manager?
His friend?
His stooge?
He's my partner.
You well-heeled,
partner?
We got enough.
Go home.
Fats don't need
your money.
Nobody's beat him
in 15 years.
He's the best.
You got that
wrong, mister.
I am.
You just go ahead
and play him, friend.
Where can I find him?
Comes right in this poolroom
every night,
8:00 on the nose.
You shoot
a good stick.
Thanks.
Gee, you shoot
straight pool, mister?
Now and then.
You know how it is.
You're Minnesota Fats,
aren't you?
They say Minnesota Fats
is the best
where I come from.
Is that a fact?
They say old Fats
just shoots the eyes
right off them balls.
Where do you
come from?
California. Oakland.
California?
Is your name Felson?
That's right.
I hear you've been
looking for me.
Yeah. That's right, too.
Big John?
You think this boy
is a hustler?
You like to gamble?
Gamble money
on pool games?
Let's shoot
a game of straight pool.
$100?
You shoot
big-time pool, Fats.
That's what
everybody says.
Let's make it
$200 a game.
Now I know why
they call you Fast Eddie.
Eddie, you talk
my kind of talk.
Sausage,
rack 'em up!
How do you feel?
Fast and loose, man.
In the gut, I mean.
Tight, but good.
Willie, hang on
to that.
You break.
I didn't
leave you much.
You left enough.
6 in the corner.
15 in the corner.
Ace in the side.
8.
10.
11.
Boy, he is great!
Geez, that
old fat man!
He moves
like a dancer.
12.
Cross side.
And those fingers.
Them chubby fingers!
That stroke.
It's like
he's playing the violin.
3 ball.
4 ball.
Cross corner.
[Taps Cue]
Nice shot.
Safe.
7 ball in the corner.
6 in the corner.
125. Game.
13.
5.
10.
Game!
2 in the corner.
13.
125. Game.
Ace in the corner.
Quit.
He's too good.
Charlie,
I'm going to take him.
Your shot.
You miss?
You don't leave much,
do you, fat man?
That's what
the game's all about.
Uh-huh.
2 ball, side pocket.
[Taps Cue]
Very good shot.
I got a hunch,
fat man.
It's me from here on in.
1 ball, corner pocket.
Did that ever
happen to you?
All of a sudden
you feel like
you can't miss?
I dreamed about
this game, fat man,
every night on the road.
5 ball.
This is my table, man.
13 ball.
7 ball.
4 ball.
Game!
8 ball.
11 ball.
Rack 'em!
10 ball in the corner.
1 ball in
the corner pocket.
Game!
Pay the man again, Fats.
How much we ahead?
Approximately
1,000 bucks.
Fats, let's shoot
for $1,000 a game.
Preach.
Get me some whiskey
and some ice.
Get me some bourbon.
J.T.S. Brown.
No ice.
Preach.
Get it atJohnny's.
You got a bet.
[Whispering]
Cash me in.
2 in the corner.
7.
Ace in the corner.
2 ball, side pocket.
5 ball.
9 ball.
125. Game.
10 ball.
Will you cut
that sunshine out?
Hey, mister!
Name's Gordon,
Bert Gordon.
Mister.
Would you mind moving?
You bother me.
5 ball.
That's game.
How much we got?
11,400, cash,
here and in my pocket.
Preacher, get me
some breakfast.
Egg sandwich and coffee.
You want
something, Charlie?
You're coming
with me.
The pool game
is over.
No, it isn't,
Charlie.
The pool game
is over
when Fats
says it's over.
You wanted 10,000,
you got 10,000.
Get with it, Charlie!
You can't see it.
I came after him,
and I'm
going to get him.
I'm going with him
all the way.
The pool game
is not over
until Minnesota Fats
says it's over.
I beat him all night,
and I'm going to
beat him all day.
I'm the best
you ever seen, Fats.
I'm the best there is.
Stay with this kid.
He's a loser.
What did he say?
25 hours, Eddie.
25 hours you've been
playing straight.
Get me a drink.
You don't
need a drink.
Shut up!
Just get me a drink.
18,000, Eddie.
We're ahead
18,000!
Minnesota Fats decides
when this game's over.
It's over now.
Fast Eddie,
let's play
some pool.
Let's go, Eddie.
You look beautiful, Fats.
Just like a baby.
All pink and powdered up.
What are you
doing, Eddie?
You beat him bad.
Want to kill yourself?
Are you chicken,
Charlie?
Yeah, I'm chicken.
Leave me the money.
Go to hell.
Charlie, you better
give me that money.
Give it to me.
It's mine.
Okay.
Here. Be a damned fool!
Oh, yeah.
You really look beautiful, Fats.
Ha ha ha!
I'll break.
9 ball.
15.
125.
Eddie?
Wake up, Eddie.
We lose again.
[Bottle Falls]
This is all
we got left?
That's all you got.
That's all we got left.
Willie,
give me
the stake money.
Fats, I got
about $200 here.
Game's over, Eddie.
I got
about $200 here.
You can't run out on me.
You watch me.
Fats, come on.
Come on.
Hey, Fats?
Eddie.
I'm sorry, Charlie.
Give me a towel,
will you?
May I have
your attention, please?
Ha ha ha!
Are you sure?
Can I get you
something?
Later.
Long wait for a bus?
Yes.
How long
you been waiting?
What?
How long have you
been waiting?
Since 4:00.
Just a cup
of black coffee, please.
And ma'am,
wait a minute!
Would you like
another cup?
Fine. Thanks.
What time's
the bus leave?
What bus?
Yours.
8:00.
That wouldn't give us
much time, would it?
You're right.
I guess it wouldn't.
Hello and good-bye.
Have a nice trip.
Thanks.
I will.
Give it to me.
6:00 bus toJersey City,
Alexandria,
Triangle,
and Williamsburg, Virginia,
loading on platform
number three.
How much
do I owe you?
It was paid for
by the lady.
Give me some bourbon.
J.T.S. Brown.
Check.
Want a chaser?
No.
Have a nice trip?
Fair.
Can I sit down?
Why not?
We already know
each other's secrets.
Thanks for the...
for the breakfast.
Two ships passing
in the night
should always buy
each other breakfast.
Can I buy you
another drink?
Another one for me
and the lady.
Check.
You look different.
More relaxed.
The lights.
And the scotch.
You missed your bus.
I wasn't
waiting for one.
Why go
to the bus station?
The same reason
you went.
That hour
of the morning,
you haven't
got much choice.
I only live
three blocks from there.
Where do you live?
Around.
I know where you live.
In a locker
in the bus station.
What's it like
living in a locker?
Cramped.
You always
drink like this
so early in the morning?
You always ask
so many questions?
No, not always.
Sometimes I wake up,
and I can't sleep,
not without a drink.
The bars don't open
until 8:00.
Mac over there
has faith in me.
When I'm broke,
he trusts me.
Don't you
trust me, Mac?
Check.
When I'm not broke,
I usually have
a bottle in my room.
Then I sleep
very well.
You talk funny,
but I like it.
I used to be
an actress.
What do you do now?
I'm a college girl.
Tuesdays and Thursdays
I go to college.
You don't look like
a college girl.
I'm the emancipated
type.
Real emancipated.
I didn't mean that.
You just don't
look young enough.
I'm not.
Why go to college?
Got nothing to do
on those days.
What do you do
on other days?
I drink.
Hey!
No. No more.
I'm getting sleepy.
Thank you very much,
mister.
Eddie. The name's Eddie.
The name
should be Eddie.
What should
my name be?
Whatever you
like it to be.
I like it to be
what it is... Sarah.
That's a biblical name.
You want to know
its meaning?
I could always
get us a bottle.
No.
Afifth of scotch?
Do you want me to
step out in the alley?
No.
I'll take you home.
All right.
It's all right.
I'm not drunk.
I'm lame.
Why me?
Please.
Please!
You're too hungry.
Take it. It's yours.
You can have this room
for $1.50 a night
or $7.00 by the week.
For the night.
In advance.
Clara Macy.
Bottle of beer.
Hey, mister.
Can I grab a cue?
You're Eddie Felson,
aren't you?
Who?
I saw you play
at Ames the other night.
I tell you what.
I'll keep one hand
in my pocket.
You're out
of our league.
What are you stuck for?
Three. That's
enough for me.
Thank you.
Can I buy
you fellows a drink?
Okay.
Say, you know,
you shoot good,
but you also
shoot lucky.
Yeah, I shoot lucky.
Why did you do that?
I wanted to see what kind
of a day it is.
Like any other.
People come, people go.
Give me a drag.
What time is it?
11:00.
I'll be back later.
Why?
Come here.
Whoa! You need
to shave.
There's a razor
and shaving cream
in the bathroom.
Compliments
of the house.
Why did you
say that, Sarah?
How did you know
my name was Sarah?
You told me.
I lie.
When I'm drunk,
Okay. So what's your name today?
Sarah.
Eddie.
Look,
I've got troubles,
and I think
you've got troubles.
Maybe it would
be better
if we leave
each other alone.
I got my things
over at the hotel.
I'll bring them
over later.
I'm not sure.
I don't know.
What do you
want to know?
And why?
Hey!
Ooh!
Thank you.
[Knock On Door]
Where you been
all day?
At school.
It's Thursday.
Oh, I forgot.
You were asleep
when I left.
I didn't want to
wake you.
Did you go out?
Yeah. For a couple
of hours.
A present.
I've been living here
for almost three years.
Now, in three days,
it seems as if
I know everybody.
When I pass people
on the street,
I want to say,
"I got a fella."
Thanks.
Where do you go
when you go out?
Museums,
art galleries, concerts.
I believe you
when you say
you go to school.
You want to go
with me?
Are you kidding?
See that book?
I've tried to
get through it
ever since I got here.
You read all them books?
Uh-huh.
You got it
all in your head?
They get mixed up
when I'm drunk.
Usually
they're mixed up.
Stop talking about yourself
like you're a lush.
You ought to
get some treatments.
I'm getting
treatments right here.
I'm hungry.
Take your choice.
We won't have to leave
the house
until Tuesday.
What did this
cost you?
Pay when you've
got the money.
I want to know.
The bills
are right here.
What do you want?
Don't you ever
cook anything?
Eggs. How do you
like them?
Raw.
Oh.
I cut my finger.
I got something
in my bag.
Oh, it's not bad.
Eddie, what's
in that case?
Haven't you opened it?
No. Why should I?
It's yours.
It's a machine gun.
Someone told me
when I came to the city,
I'd need a machine gun.
Where do you get the money
to pay for all this?
I mean, the liquor
and the groceries
and the rent?
From the rich
old man
who used to be
my lover.
[Knock On Door]
[Knock Knock Knock]
Hello, Eddie.
Hello, Charlie.
Come on in.
That's my girl.
Hello, Eddie's girl.
I looked all over
for you.
How'd you find me?
I asked around.
Do you
want me to go?
No.
Stick around.
Can we get you
a drink?
I don't want to be
no bother.
Don't play it small,
Charlie.
How should I play it?
I'm broke.
So am I.
Sit down.
Would you get us
some drinks?
You walk out on me...
No good-bye,
like a thief in the dark.
We were partners.
We were
more than partners.
He was like a...
A son.
Yeah.
I've known him
since he was 16.
The first time
I saw him,
I said, " this is
a talented boy.
This is a smart boy."
Talk to me,
Charlie.
Come back on the road.
Nah. I've had
that kind of life.
What kind of life
have you got
scuffling around
the small rooms?
I'll connect.
You'll get your money back.
You want to play
Minnesota Fats again?
Is that
what's on your mind?
Never been out of it.
I want to beat
that fat man
with that curly hair
and those diamond rings.
They wiped the floor
with him,
and he wants to
go back.
What for?
I said you'd get
your money!
He thinks I care
about the money.
I care about you.
Do you care about me?
We're together
a long time,
so how do you
say good-bye?
You give me the car
and 100 bucks.
Do you think I care
about the dough
or the car?
I care about you.
This boy is
the greatest pool hustler,
a high-class con man.
He can charm anybody
into anything.
Did he ever tell you
how well we were doing?
We had everything!
We had money to burn,
whiskey, dames...
Excuse me.
Take her along.
If you don't want to start
right away,
we won't.
We'll drive to Miami,
have some laughs,
lie in the sun.
With what?
Don't worry about it.
I'll raise the money.
Oh, yeah?
Where?
What's the difference?
I'll raise it.
Can I have
another drink?
Did you hold out
on me, Charlie?
How much?
My 25%.
Approximately
1,500 bucks.
Oh, you crumb!
With that 1,500,
I could've beat him.
That's all I needed,
Charlie.
Give me the money.
To play Fats?
To play Fats!
If you're coming back
on the road, okay.
If you're giving it
to Minnesota Fats,
nothing doing.
You still don't see,
do you?
You are nothing
but a small-time Charlie.
You'd love to
keep me hustling.
A couple more years
with me,
you might make enough
to get a poolroom
with a handbook
on the side.
Is that when you
say good-bye to me?
That's what
you think?
Yeah!
All right.
That's what I want.
A poolroom with
a little handbook
on the side.
I'm getting old.
Lay down and die
by yourself.
Don't take me with you.
Just like that?
Yeah,
just like that!
Thanks for the drink,
Eddie's girl.
Here.
Everybody,
everybody wants
a piece of me!
Aren't you going to
have one?
What did he have to
come back here for?
Come here.
Come here!
Going out?
Yeah, for a little while.
Ohh.
Hey.
You okay?
What are you writing?
Oh, it's a story,
a story
I'm making up.
Give it to me.
What's this
supposed to mean?
Give it back to me.
What's this
supposed to mean?
"We have a contract
of depravity.
All we have to do
is pull a blind down."
Write yourself
another story.
Well, what else
have we got?
We never talk
about anything.
We stay
in this room,
and we drink,
and we make love.
We're strangers.
What happens
when the liquor
and the money run out,
Eddie?
You told Charlie
to lay down and die.
Will you say that
to me, too?
What happens, Eddie?
Just find yourself
another rich old lover.
And I'm sure
you'll help me.
Are you waiting
for me to cry?
You bum.
You poolroom bum!
Give me three cards.
Give me
a bottle of beer.
How'd you make out?
I made
a couple of bucks.
Poker game?
Yeah.
Is it open?
Huh?
It's open.
What will you have?
Give me a beer.
Okay?
Sit down.
What's the limit?
Half on a dollar.
Give me 10 bucks worth.
$10.
Make it 20.
$20.
Cut.
Deal.
Bourbon,J.T.S. Brown.
Two.
I'm buying.
I thought
you only drank milk.
Only when I work.
Yeah? Why?
I like it.
It's good for you.
Besides, you start
drinking whiskey gambling,
it gives you an excuse
for losing.
How'd you do
in the game?
I lost 20 bucks.
Poker's not
your game.
What is?
Pool.
Are you being cute?
I don't think anyone
shoots better pool
than I saw you shoot
at Ames.
You got talent.
So what beat me?
Character.
Yeah, sure, sure.
You're damn right
I'm sure.
Everybody's got talent.
I got talent.
You can't play poker
for 40 hours on talent.
Minnesota Fats
isn't the best
just because
he's got talent.
Minnesota Fats has
more character than you.
I got drunk.
He drank as much
as you did.
Maybe he knows
how to drink.
You think that's a talent,
too?
What do I do now?
Lie down and bow?
What do I do?
Go home?
That's your problem.
So I stay
until I hustle up enough
to play Fats again.
Maybe by that time,
I'll develop myself
some character.
Maybe by that time,
you'll die
of old age.
How much do you
think you'll need?
1,000.
No. 3,000 at least.
He'll start
at 500 a game.
He'll beat the pants
off you.
That's the way he plays
against a man
who knows the game.
He might be
scared of you.
That could
change things,
but I wouldn't
count on it.
How do you know?
Nobody knows that much.
See that big car
outside?
I get a new one
every year
because I make it my business
to know
what guys will do.
I made enough off you
to pay for it twice.
In that case,
you owe me
another drink.
Go ahead.
Eddie? Is it okay
if I get personal?
What have you been
so far?
Eddie,
you're a born loser.
What's that
supposed to mean?
First time
in 10 years
I ever saw Minnesota Fats
hooked,
but you
let him off.
I got drunk.
Sure you got drunk.
You had the best
excuse for losing.
Winning can be heavy, too.
Drop that load,
too,
when you got
an excuse.
Feeling sorry
for yourself
is a great
indoor sport
enjoyed by all,
especially
the born loser.
Thanks for the drink.
Wait. Maybe I can help you.
To do what?
Get the 3,000.
Play Minnesota Fats.
Why?
10 reasons,
maybe 15.
There's something
in it for me.
How much?
75%.
For who?
For me.
Who do you
think you are?
General Motors?
How much do you
think you're worth?
I'm putting up
the money.
I get 75%
if you win.
You think
I can lose?
I never
saw you win.
You saw me beat
Minnesota Fats for $18,000.
When you hustle,
at the end
of the game,
you count
your money.
That's how you
find out who's best.
Why back me, then?
Find yourself
a big poker game.
I like action.
One thing I think
you're good for
is action.
Besides,
you got talent.
Yeah, you already
told me that.
Cut that slice down
to bite size,
maybe we can talk.
No. I don't make
bad bets.
75/25.
That's it.
Kiss off.
Hey, wait.
What will you do
about the money?
There are places.
I'll scuffle around.
The word's out on you.
You walk in
the wrong place,
they'll eat you alive.
When did you
adopt me?
I don't know when it was.
Hi.
You lucky punk.
I quit you.
You want in,
friend?
How much
you playing for?
$1.00 on the 5,
2 on the 9.
I'll play you
a couple.
Whew!
That's it for me.
You quitting, too?
You're
a good player.
How much
are you ahead?
A couple bucks.
I guess it's just
you and me.
I guess it is, boy.
Let's raise
the bet.
2 on the 5,
5 on the 9.
You know what, kid?
I think
you're a hustler.
Try me.
Shoot.
Okay.
You sure you don't
want to quit?
Let's cut
the small stuff.
$100 freeze out.
10 games.
10 bucks a game.
Winner take all.
Then we'll see
who quits.
Okay, friend.
You're on.
Call it.
Heads.
You win.
You better not miss,
friend.
I don't rattle, kid.
But just for that,
I'm going to
beat you flat.
That's one.
That's five.
That's six.
That's 10.
You two-bit punk.
Pay up.
100 bucks.
You quitting, friend?
Yeah,
I'm quitting.
Why, you're a pool shark,
boy.
A real pool shark.
So's he.
But you're better
than he was...
much better.
There's your money, boy.
All right.
Pool shark!
Wait a minute.
Let's give this boy
his money.
We always pay
what we lose, boy.
Ooh!
Aah!
[Pounding On Door]
Who is it?
It's me.
It's Eddie.
What happened?
I got beat up.
They...
they broke my thumbs.
Oh, my God!
They...
they broke my thumbs.
They broke my...
It's all right.
I'm here.
[Typewriter]
You can read it
if you want to.
You want to go out?
To a movie?
No.
You want a drink?
No. Do you?
What is it so hot in here for?
Please!
Sarah, you think
I'm a loser?
A loser?
Yeah.
I met this guy,
Bert Gordon.
He said
I'm a born loser.
Would he know?
He knows a lot.
Why did he tell you?
I'm not sure.
He said some people
look for an excuse to lose.
What does he do,
this Bert Gordon?
He's a gambler.
Is he a winner?
Well,
he owns things.
Is that
what makes a winner?
What else does?
Does it bother you,
what he said?
Yeah.
Yeah,
it bothers me a lot,
'cause twice, Sarah,
once at Ames
with Minnesota Fats
and then at Arthur's...
in that cheap,
crummy poolroom.
Now,
why did I do it?
I could've
beat that guy cold.
He never
would have known.
I just had to
show those punks
what the game is like
when it's great.
You know,
like anything can be great.
Anything can be great.
Bricklaying can be great
if a guy knows
what he's doing and why
and can make it
come off.
When I'm
really going,
I feel like
a jockey must feel
with all that speed
and power
underneath him.
He's coming
into the stretch,
the pressure's
on him,
and he just feels
when to let it go
and how much,
'cause he's got
everything working...
timing, touch.
It's a real
great feeling
when you're right
and you know
you're right.
It's like I got oil
in my arm.
The pool cue's
part of me.
It's got nerves
in it.
You feel the roll
of those balls.
You don't
have to look.
You just know.
You make shots that
nobody's ever made,
and you play that game
the way nobody's
ever played.
You're not a loser, Eddie.
You're a winner.
about anything.
I love you, Eddie.
You know,
someday, Sarah,
you're going to settle down,
and you're going to marry
a college professor.
You're going
to write a great book...
Maybe about me, huh?
Fast Eddie Felson,
hustler.
I love you.
You need the words?
I need them very much.
If you ever say them,
I'll never let you
take them back.
Are you glad?
Yes, I'm glad.
Hello, Eddie.
Hi.
How's business?
Slow.
Why the openhand bridge?
Something wrong
with your hand?
I had a little accident.
You seem to do okay
that way.
My game's 20% off,
maybe more.
Somebody step
on your hand?
A big creep
broke my thumbs.
A man named
Turk Baker?
You know everybody,
don't you?
Everybody who can hurt me.
Everybody who can help me,
I pay.
Where do I sign up?
First match
is Louisville, Kentucky.
I'll be there.
What happened to you?
My thumbs.
I don't mean
your thumbs.
Maybe I'm not
such a high-class piece
of property right now.
A 25% slice
of something big
is better than a 100%
slice of nothing.
Hey, give us
a couple of drinks,
will you?
J.T.S. Brown.
Good evening, sir.
Give us a nice
quiet table.
Yes, sir.
Right this way.
Would you like a drink
before dinner, sir?
Okay?
Sherry.
Very old.
Very dry.
Two.
Sherry?
It's a nice joint.
You look very pretty.
I feel pretty.
What's so funny?
Your tie.
I've never seen you
wear one.
Afirst time
for everything.
Oh, yeah.
That's great.
Excuse me, sir.
To you, Eddie.
Thank you, sir.
What is it, Eddie?
Want another drink?
What do you
want to tell me?
I'll be leaving town
for a little while.
For how long?
Oh, I don't know.
A week? Ayear?
More like a week.
I'll be back.
Sure.
Let's go.
Taxi.
No, I want to walk.
Come here.
Come on.
You better get
some dry things on.
Don't you want to know
where I'm going?
No.
Yes. I want to know what for,
but I don't want to ask.
I'm going to Louisville
with a friend
to make some money.
I need it, the money.
I'll be leaving early
in the morning.
Leave now.
Oh, grow up.
Why should I?
I'm going to Kentucky
to play pool.
I need the money.
I said I'd be back.
If you were coming back,
you wouldn't have
taken me out tonight
or bought this dress.
You're hustling me, Eddie.
I never hustled you,
even when I thought I was.
What do I do?
Sit here and wait?
You'll come back
and you'll love me,
and then you'll
go away again.
Is that your
idea of love?
I got no idea of love.
Neither one of us
would know what it was
if we saw it
coming down the street.
I'd know it.
What are you trying
to do to me?
I love you.
Well, what's your idea of love?
Chains?
No.
I made you up,
didn't I?
You weren't real.
I made you up like
everything else.
There was no
car crash, Eddie.
When I was 5,
I had polio.
The rich old man
is my father.
He walked out on us
when I was 7.
He sends me a check
every month.
That's how he buys his way
out of my life.
The men I've known...
after they left,
I'd say they
weren't real.
I made them up.
I wanted you
to be real.
I'm so scared, Eddie.
I'm scared.
Sarah Packard,
Bert Gordon.
Miss Packard,
how do you do?
That brown one
is mine.
It goes in there.
I got it,
I got it.
You sure you're
comfortable, Miss...
Packard.
Sarah Packard.
I have trouble
remembering names.
You want anything?
No, I'm fine.
You ever been
to Louisville
during derby week?
I've never been
to Louisville.
Lots of class.
See some of
the best-dressed,
most beautiful women
in the world.
James Findley's
very rich.
Grandfather left him 20%
of the tobacco company.
And he hustles pool?
He's a gentleman
gambler,
gets his kicks
playing with hustlers.
He's got an old
southern mansion.
Drinks 8-year-old
bourbon.
How good is he?
They say he's
one of the best.
You must have
confidence in me.
I have confidence
in Findley.
What's that mean?
I'm confident
he's a loser.
You're only
half a loser.
The other half,
a winner.
Here, I got it.
No, I pick up
all the tabs.
Fats knew the game
was in the clutch.
He played it smart.
In my head,
I played that game
1,000 times.
Play it again.
Learn something.
Fats went
in theJohn.
Washed his face.
Combed his hair.
Came back
all ready to go.
You were through.
You saw
how he looked.
All set to start
all over again.
You know what
you were doing?
You were waiting
to get beat.
Flattened out
on your butt.
Swimming around
in glory and whiskey.
Probably deciding
how you could lose.
How do you know
what Eddie was thinking?
I know.
I've been there
myself.
We've all
been there,
haven't we,
Miss Packard?
Got a match, Eddie?
Doesn't your lighter
work, Mr. Gordon?
I forgot
all about it.
How's your hand?
Fine.
Good. I don't like
backing cripples.
Why did you
say that?
Mr. Gordon
meant no offense.
It was a figure
of speech.
That's right,
Miss Packard.
A fact is a fact.
Smart girl,
Eddie.
Right this way,
Mr. Gordon.
Suite 56.
I wired ahead
for two suites
adjoining.
I want two suites.
We're filled up.
You must have
gotten my wire.
Look through
your reservations.
You were right,
Mr. Gordon.
I mislaid
your wire.
Two adjoining
suites.
[Billiard Balls Clicking]
That's sweet music
in there.
You can almost smell
the action and money!
I can feel it
in my shoes.
Eddie?
Hey, Billy,
how are you?
Fast Eddie!
Everybody's here.
It's like
a hustlers convention.
The guys will be
glad to see you.
What room
are we in?
57.
I'll be up later.
Thank you, sir.
Wait a minute,
Miss Packard.
We're
neighbors now.
You can
call me Sarah.
I want to talk.
Do we need words?
We could try
to cut each other up.
It would be bad
for Eddie.
You know what's good for him?
To win.
For whom
and for what?
What makes
the world go round?
For money
and for glory.
For whom?
Today for me.
Tomorrow for himself.
You own all the tomorrows
because you buy them today,
and you buy cheap.
Nobody has to sell.
You bastard!
Look, you're here
on a rain check.
You're hanging on
by your nails.
If Eddie hears
that glory whistle,
you finish last.
So don't make trouble.
Live and let live...
while you can.
I'll make it up to you.
How?
You tell me.
[Starting Bell]
Thanks.
There are three late scratches
from the following race...
Rosemary, Stroke of Luck,
and Ellen Parr.
Where's Bert?
He went off someplace.
With the 200 bucks
I won last night
and today
at the track,
I got $540.
Here, you hold it.
Just for luck.
Findley's here.
Where?
Over there
by the bar.
Aren't you going
over to him?
He'll be over here.
You ready
for another?
Thank you.
I haven't seen you
in a long time.
I haven't been here
for a long time.
Miss Packard.
Eddie Felson.
James... uh...
Findley.
Hello.
I've heard about you.
You play
pocket billiards.
Now and then.
Why? Do you?
A little.
I generally lose.
So does Eddie.
Well, I win sometimes.
I'll bet you do,
Mr. Felson.
How much?
Bert?
Mr. Felson's
making a proposition.
Could be.
Maybe you'd like
to come out
to my place
some evening.
We could play
a few games of billiards.
When?
Come out tonight.
What time?
I'm having
some people over
right after the races.
Why don't you
all come over?
We'll be there.
Good, good.
I'll stay at the hotel.
I'm a little tired.
There'll be
a lot of laughs.
Findley's parties
are famous.
He invites everybody
from top to bottom.
It excites him
to be around
what he calls
the criminal type.
Some men
are like that.
Some women, too.
[Dixieland Jazz]
~~
[Whispers]
[Band Stops Playing]
What happened?
She's had a little
too much to drink.
Go upstairs and sleep it off.
Come on.
Go upstairs.
[Band Plays Again]
Would you like
a drink?
No, none for me.
Come on,
let's play.
Thought we came
to play pool.
I don't play pool.
I play billiards.
My house, my game.
You don't
have to play
if you don't want to.
Well, we won't.
Let me play.
How much?
We'll start small.
$100 a game?
You ever play
billiards before?
Sure.
You hustling me?
Come now.
You can afford $100
to find out.
Deal the cards.
Beautiful shot, Felson.
You've played
billiards before.
You gentlemen sure
you don't care
for a drink?
Nothing for me.
How do we stand?
About even.
If that's
his best game,
I can beat him.
You ever played
billiards before?
What's the difference?
You got a pool cue,
balls on the table.
Let's raise the stakes
to 500.
You really think
you can beat him?
He thinks he can.
I know he can.
I asked him will he.
With Eddie,
that's two different things.
I can beat him.
All right. 500.
Have you noticed, Bert?
This fella here bears
a striking resemblance to you.
It seems as though
you might have modeled
for the artist.
Possible.
Mark that one up,
too, Bert.
I'll beat him
the next game.
How are the hands?
They're fine.
Rack up your cue.
We're leaving.
The night is young.
The night is $2,000 old.
Bert, wait a minute.
I said we're leaving.
I didn't think he knew
how to hustle.
I can beat him.
I don't believe you.
I think you're still a loser.
All right, then.
I'll play him
on my own money.
I'll be right back.
Okay, come on.
Let's play.
Here it is.
I'm broke.
That's unfortunate,
Mr. Felson.
For whom,
Mr. Findley?
Bert, you can't
get off me now.
The bank is closed.
I know when to quit.
You don't.
What do you
want me to do?
Don't beg him, Eddie.
Go back to the hotel.
Please, Eddie.
Don't beg.
Go on back
to the hotel.
Doesn't any of this
mean anything to you?
This place, the people.
They wear masks, Eddie.
And underneath the masks,
they're perverted,
twisted, crippled.
Shut up!
Don't wear a mask, Eddie.
That's Turk, Eddie.
He's not going to break
your thumbs.
He'll break your heart.
He hates you
because of what you are.
Would you get off my back,
Sarah?
Get off my back!
Go ahead and play him,
Eddie.
Play him for $1,000 a game.
Would you take a check, Bert?
Cash.
How much do I owe you?
12,000.
Here.
It's been an interesting evening.
Yeah. Sure has.
Charles.
Call a cab
for these gentlemen, please.
I'd show you
to the door, but...
Yeah, you're tired.
And beat.
Yeah.
You must come again.
Yeah, sure.
There's your share.
3,000.
Your cab's waiting.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Thanks.
Come on, Eddie.
Let's go.
I want to walk.
It's a long walk.
I got time, Bert.
You want me
to tell her for you?
Tell her what?
You got to be hard,
Eddie.
[Knocks]
When are you leaving?
In a little while.
It's what you want,
isn't it?
It's what Eddie wants.
He, uh, told me
to give you some money.
Put it on the bed.
Isn't that
the way it's done?
That's the way
it's done.
That way you are
looking at me.
Is that the way
you look at a man
you've just beaten?
As if you'd
taken his money
and now you want his pride?
All I want's
the money.
Sure.
Just the money.
And the aristocratic
pleasure
of seeing him fall apart.
You're Roman, Bert.
You have to win them all.
You got a drink?
Give me my key,
please.
Room 57.
Well, come on,
give me my key.
How did she
get in the room?
She closed the door
and went in there
maybe 10 minutes.
Hey, let him come in.
Eddie, uh...
Eddie?
She come in here, Eddie.
She...
asked me for a drink.
I give her one, and...
we had a few more.
Eddie, she came in here.
Aah!
Eddie, stop!
Uhh!
Stop it!
[Bert Screaming]
Came to play pool, Fats.
That's good, Eddie.
For how much?
You name it.
$1,000 a game.
Let's make it
$3,000 a game, Fats.
Come on, $3,000.
That's my bankroll,
my life savings.
What's the matter, Fats?
If you beat me
the first game,
I'm on my way back
to Oakland.
Let's go.
Get on me, Bert.
I can't lose.
Willie.
Call it.
Heads.
How should I play that one,
Bert?
Play it safe?
You always told me
to play the percentage.
Well, here we go,
fast and loose.
1 ball, corner pocket.
Percentage players die broke,
too, don't they, Bert?
How can I lose?
12 ball.
I mean, how can I lose?
'Cause you were right, Bert.
It's not enough
to have talent.
You got to have character,
too.
4 ball.
Yeah, I sure got
character now.
I got it in a hotel room
in Louisville.
Shoot pool, Fast Eddie.
I'm shooting pool, Fats.
When I miss,
you can shoot.
5 ball.
14 ball.
4 ball.
That's the game.
Game.
8 ball.
13 ball.
I quit, Eddie.
I can't beat you.
Willie, give him the stake.
You got yourself
a pool player.
Preacher, give me my coat,
will you?
Where do you think
you're going?
Eddie?
You owe me money!
Just how do you figure that,
Bert?
What do you figure
I owe you?
Half.
In Louisville,
it was 75%.
Well, here it's half.
What if I don't pay you,
Bert?
You don't pay me?
You're going to get
your thumbs broken again.
And your fingers.
If I want them to,
they'll break your right arm.
Better pay him, Eddie.
So you figure
you're still my manager?
I'm a businessman, kid.
You got many games
lined up?
We'll make
a lot of money.
50%?
It don't have to be 50.
It'd be 30, 25.
We really stuck
the knife in her.
Aaah.
We really
gave it to her good.
And if it didn't
happen in Louisville,
it'd happen
someplace else.
If it didn't happen now,
it'd happen in six months.
That's the kind of dame
she was!
But we twisted it,
didn't we, Bert?
Maybe that doesn't
stick in your throat
'cause you spit it out
just like everything else!
But it sticks in mine.
I loved her, Bert.
I traded her in
on a pool game.
That wouldn't mean
anything to you,
because who did you
ever care about?
"Win", you said.
You don't know
what winning is.
You're a loser.
'Cause you're
dead inside.
You can't live
unless you make
everything else
dead around you!
Too high, Bert.
The price is too high.
If I take it,
she never lived.
She never died.
We both know
that's not true.
She lived.
She died.
Well, we'd better...
Tell your boys
they better kill me,
because if they
just bust me up,
put all those pieces
back together,
and then,
so help me God, Bert,
I'll come back here
and I'll kill you.
No.
All right.
Only, uh...
don't ever walk into
a big-time pool hall again.
Fat man.
You shoot a great
game of pool.
So do you, Fast Eddie.