You can go out without
asking anyone.
You can even play piano
if you want to.
Oh... Oh, but, Franz, you must
try to sleep now.
O God...
this is Franz Kemmerick...
only 19 years old.
He doesn't want to die.
Please don't let him die.
Paul.
- Paul.
- Franz.
Take my boots home
for Mueller.
Oh, no, Franz, no.
And if... Paul...
you find my watch,
send it home.
Franz!
Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor!
Doctor! Where's the doctor?
Why isn't there a doctor here?
Doctor, come quick!
- Franz Kemmerick is dying!
- Which one is that?
- Amputated leg.
- I've amputated a dozen legs today.
- Bed 26, sir.
- You see to it.
I'm due in the operating room.
One operating after another since
5:00 this morning.
Sixteen dead today, and
yours is the 17th.
There'll probably be 20
by the morning.
You're looking good.
Very good today.
What's your hurry? Hey! I'll bet
he stole those boots!
I got it, Kat.
Listen: "The sum of an
arithmetic series...
is S = A + L x N over 2."
Interesting, isn't it?
What do you wanna learn
that stuff for?
One day you'll stop a bullet
and it'll all be worthless.
I get a lot of fun out of it.
My boots!
Mueller.
I saw him die.
I didn't know what it was like
to die before.
And then... then I
came outside...
and it felt...
it felt so good to be alive that
I started in to walk fast.
I began to think of the
strangest things...
like being out in the fields.
Things like that.
You know... girls.
And it felt as if
there were...
something electric running from
the ground up through me.
And I started. I began
to run hard.
I passed soldiers and I heard
voices calling to me.
I ran and I ran.
I felt as if I couldn't breathe
enough air into me.
And... And now I'm hungry.
I don't mind the war now.
Be a pleasure to go to the front
in boots like these.
It's a good invention
just the same.
If you crack each separate louse, think
of all the energy you use up. Watch.
Burned to death.
How was patrol? Bad?
Must've been terrible if they had
time to gather the harvest.
We passed a cherry tree and when
he saw it, he went crazy.
I could hardly drag him away.
It was... beautiful.
I have a big orchard with cherry
trees at home.
When they're in full blossom...
from the hayloft it looks
like one single sheet.
So white.
- Perhaps you can get leave soon.
- You may even be sent...
back as a farmer.
A woman can't run a farm alone.
That's no good, you know?
No matter how hard
she works.
Harvest coming on again.
What's the matter
with him?
Got a letter yesterday from his wife.
He wants to get back to his farm.
We'd all like to get
back home.
I wonder what we'd do if it were
suddenly peacetime again?
Get drunk and look
for women!
I'd go looking for
a Cinderella...
that could wear this
for a garter.
And when I'd found her, nobody'd
see me for two weeks.
I'll go back to the
peat fields...
and those pleasant hours
in the beer gardens.
And there's worse things
than cobbling too.
Look. My family.
I oughta give you a kick in the
backside for starting all this.
It's all right for all you to talk.
You've got something to go back to.
Wives, children, jobs.
But what about us? What have
we got to go back to?
- School?
- Why not?
You know everything already.
A man can't take all that rubbish
they teach you seriously...
after three years of
shells and bombs.
You can't peel that
off easily.
They never taught us anything
really useful...
like how to light a cigarette in the
wind or make a fire out of wet wood...
or bayonet a man in the belly instead
of the ribs where it gets jammed.
What can happen to us
afterwards?
I'll tell you. Take our class.
Out of 20, three are officers...
nine dead...
Mueller and three others
wounded...
and one in the madhouse.
We'll all be dead someday,
so let's forget it.
Hurry up! Get in there!
Hurry up!
Himmelstoss!
What's up?
- What are you, crazy?
- It's Himmelstoss!
Himmelstoss? There is justice
in the army!
Well, well. So, we are
all here, huh?
A bit longer than you,
Himmie.
Since when have we become
so familiar?
Stand up and click your heels
together! All of you!
- Take a running jump at yourself!
- Who's your friend?
Would somebody get General
Ludendorff a nice, comfortable chair?
I command you as your
superior officer!
- Do you want to be court-martialed?
- I do!
There's going to be a big
attack tonight...
and I'd just love to
get out of it.
Kiss my butt!
It isn't customary to ask for
salutes here.
But I'll tell you what we'll do.
We're going to attack a town that
we tried to take once before.
Many killed and many wounded.
It was great fun.
This time you're
going with us.
If any of us stops a bullet,
before we die...
we're going to come to you, click
our heels together and ask stiffly...
"Please, Sergeant Himmelstoss,
may we go?"
You'll...
You'll pay for this,
you...
There it is.
Right on time. Better
get ready, boys.
I'm wounded!
It's just a scratch, you yellow rat!
Up! Get out with the others!
- Up!
- No! No! No!
You yellow rat!
Stinking yellow rat! Let the
others do it, eh?
Get up!
Get up! Forward!
- Get out here.
- Command... was forward.
Command was forward!
Forward!
Forward! Forward!
Counterattack.
I want to help you.
Stop that! Stop it, stop it.
I can bear the rest of it.
I can't listen to that!
Why do you take so long dying?
You're going to die anyway!
Oh, no.
Oh, no. You won't die.
Oh, no. You won't die. They're
only little wounds.
You'll get home. You'll be
all right.
You'll get home long
before I will.
You know I can't run away. That's
why you accuse me.
I tell you, I didn't want to kill you.
I tried to keep you alive.
If you jumped in here again,
I wouldn't do it.
When you jumped in here you were my
enemy, and I was afraid of you.
But you're just a man like me,
and I killed you.
Forgive me, comrade.
Say that for me. Say you
forgive me.
Oh, no. You're dead.
You're better off than I am.
You're through.
They can't do any more
to you now.
Oh, God, why did they
do this to us?
We only wanted to live,
you and I.
Why should they send us out
to fight each other?
If we threw away these rifles
and these uniforms...
you could be my brother just
like Kat and Albert.
You'll have to forgive me, comrade.
I'll do all I can.
I'll write to your parents.
I'll write to...
I'll write to your wife.
I'll write to her.
I promise she'll not want
for anything.
I'll help her and your
parents too.
Only forgive me.
Forgive me!
Forgive me. Forgive me.
Forgive me.
Terrible thing happened
yesterday.
I stabbed a man. With my own
hands, stabbed him.
I know how it is.
Your first time.
Never mind. The stretcher-bearers
will find him.
- He's dead. I watched him die.
- You couldn't do anything about it.
We have to kill. We
can't help it.
That's what we are here for.
Look there, for instance.
That got him. You should've seen how
he leaped in the air.
That fellow had to shoot with us
for today with three hits.
If he keeps it up, he'll have a
decoration for his...
buttonhole this evening.
Don't you lose any more sleep
over this business.
Maybe it was because I was out
there with him so long, huh?
Sure, that's it.
After all, war is war.
March! Forward!
Forward, march!
Quick there! Forward!
Company... halt!
Dismissed!
Uncommissioned officers,
enlisted men...
dismiss!
Come on! Let's get outta here!
- Give me your best sausage.
- Two.
Give me a beer.
One, two, three!
Hey, come on. A beer.
Hey, get out of here!
Come on. Give me a beer.
A beer. One b...
here's hoping we get falling-down
drunk tonight.
Here's how it started.
I'd forgotten there were
girls like that.
There aren't.
Just look at those thin,
little shoes.
She couldn't march many
miles in those.
Paul! Don't speak about marching.
You're boring the young lady.
A thousand pardons.
- How old you think she is?
- Oh, about 22.
No, that'd make her
older than us.
She's... 17.
A girl like that.
That'd be good,
Albert?
We wouldn't have much of a
chance with him around.
We could take a bath wash
our clothes...
All right.
And I might even go so far
as to get deloused.
Wait a minute! She's a long way
from here now.
Look at the date.
May, 1917.
- Four months ago.
- That's true.
Well, here's to her anyway.
Here's to them all,
everywhere.
Albert...
- We might as well wash up anyway.
- All right.
Personally, I like them
bigger around.
This conversation was on a high
moral plane up to now.
Now we do need a bath.
- A bath?
- For what?
You wouldn't understand.
This water is freezing. This romantic
business has gone too far.
Ahh, but think of her
beautiful eyes!
Oh, and her hair.
- Here we are!
- We're not gonna miss a thing!
Go away!
- What are you doing here?
- Bathing!
They tell me there's some people in
this world takes a bath every week!
Women!
Mademoiselle, you want to swim?
Mademoiselle!
Aw, baby!
Aw, no, girls! Don't go away!
Aw, mama!
- Please don't go!
- Don't go away!
Food! Food!
Halt! You know you're forbidden
to cross.
You fellows stay on this side
or you'll get...
yourselves in a lot of trouble.
What are they jabbering
about?
They want us to swing over tonight.
They're expecting us.
- That's fine!
- We'll do it!
That blonde's crazy about me.
But there's four of us and
only three of them.
I was the one that
stopped them!
That blonde piece of work is mine.
You three fight for what's left.
Fight's the word. All's fair
in love and war.
What do you mean? What're
you gonna do?
You'll find out.
Au revoir!
- C'est moi, blondie!
- Bon ami! Bon ami!
Vos camarades!
She means the door.
Not only modest, but dashing!
A perfect fit.
It might've been made for me.
An officer's coat.
We're calling distinguished
company.
Merci.
Have another little drink,
comrade.
Is this your birthday
or mine?
Why?
You've been buying me drink
after drink for two hours.
What I'm trying to figure
out is why.
Why?
Oh. I it's just that the boys...
told me to amuse you
for a little while.
Oh, nice boys.
They... They said you'd
understand.
I've been betrayed!
Yeah, you certainly have.
Take that for a minute!
I'll give you more!
It's too loud.
Suzanne. And I wouldn't even
know you if I did.
And yet, I'll remember
you always.
Toujours.
Oh, if you could only know how
different this is...
from the women we
soldiers meet.
You. That's what I'm
talking about. Vous.
It seems as though all war and
terror and grossness...
had fallen away from me...
like a miracle.
Like something I never believed.
Pauvre garon.
Frau Paul.
We're going, Paul.
Have a look. Nice, new coffins.
Huh! For us.
I must say, that's a very cheerful
preparation for this offensive.
That's very considerate of them.
But I don't see any long...
enough for our comrade Tjaden.
Mind you, I'm not speaking
to you, you traitors.
- But no coffin's gonna get me.
- I should say not, heartbreaker.
You'll be thankful if they slip
a waterproof sheet...
around that Aunt Sally of a
carcass of yours.
Oh... Oh, my side!
My side.
Catholic hospital,
Albert.
They say you always get good
food and good treatment.
- We're lucky.
- After that rainy dressing station...
and 24 hours on the train, we
deserve to have some luck.
I'm Hamacher.
Yeah, that's my name.
I got a crack in the head and they
gave me a certificate stating...
"Josef Hamacher is
periodically...
not responsible for
his actions."
And ever since then, Hamacher has
been having a grand time.
I hope you boys are not too
badly wounded.
The others die off so quickly we
don't have time to get acquainted.
You'll get to know us...
very well.
Thank you.
You too.
I'm sorry, my dear. It's
time to go now.
Yes, sister.
Watch.
If they take his clothes away,
you've seen the last of him.
See? They're taking him to
the dying room.
Dying room?
When you're ready to kick the
bucket, they get you out...
of the way so they can
use the bed.
In the corner of the building
there's a little room...
right next to the morgue!
It's so convenient. It saves
a lot of trouble.
But suppose he gets well?
I've seen a lot of them go
in that dying room...
but nobody ever
comes back.
Sister.
Sister. Sister.
- Is that you ringing, Paul?
- Yes.
- Is something going on?
- I think I have a haemorrhage.
The bandage is all wet. I've been
ringing forever and nobody comes.
I think I'm bleeding.
Sister, get me a sterile dressing
and an ice pack.
- Why didn't someone call me?
- He's been ringing.
Nobody can walk, Sister.
- Sister, is it bad?
- No. No, we'll be all right.
We've got it in time.
What's the matter? What
are you doing?
We must rearrange
your bandages.
Where are you
taking me?
To the bandaging ward.
No, no! I'm not going!
I'm staying here!
Paul! Paul!
- Now, now!
- I'm not going to the dying room!
- We're going to the bandaging ward.
- Why are you taking my clothes?
You're lying to me! But I'll come
back. I won't die!
I'll come back!
I won't die!
I'm not going to die!
I'll come back!
Sister Libertine, how is he?
Poor boy. They had to
amputate his leg.
Paul. Paul.
Paul.
Oh, he is...
gone.
Gone.
Hello. Welcome home,
Albert!
- How do you fell, kid?
- All right.
But I've got such
an awful pain.
My foot hur...
Hamacher. Did they cut
my leg off?
Of course not! How many did
you have? Two?
You still got them!
One, two!
Don't play the fool, Hamacher.
Tell me truthfully.
Of course not. And
you look fine.
Look. See?
- I won't be a cripple.
- Now, now.
- I won't live like that!
- Be calm.
I'll kill myself the first
chance I get!
Albert!
- I won't live! I won't live!
- Yes, you will.
Albert! Albert!
Albert, I've come back!
I told you I'd come back. Look,
everybody! I've come back!
Paul. Paul.
That's not where I'm going.
I live over there.
Paul, I'm so happy.
Hamacher, I've come back
from the dead!
It's most irregular. Never
happened before.
Albert, get well quickly...
so we can go home soon.
- Everything will be all right now.
- Yes, Paul.
Everything will be all right...
now.
Oh! Paul! Paul!
Paul.
- What's the matter, Paul?
- Nothing.
Nothing.
Paul.
Give me your hanky chief.
- Mother?
- Here I am, Paul. Here I am.
Mother's ill.
- Are you wounded?
- No, Mother. I got leave.
Here I am crying instead
of being glad.
Anna, get down the jar
of blackberries.
You still like them,
don't you?
Yes, Mother. I haven't had
any for a long time.
We might almost have known
you were coming.
- I'm making potato cakes.
- Don't let them burn.
Paul... sit down...
beside me.
My Paul.
My baby.
I almost forgot, Mother. I've got
some little presents for you.
Look, Mother. Bread,
sausage and rice.
Paul, you've been starving
yourself.
Hadn't I better go and tell
father Paul's home?
Paul could watch the things
on the stove.
No, I'm getting up.
Oh, Paul, you're a soldier now,
aren't you?
But somehow, I don't seem
to know you.
I'll take these off,
mother.
I'll get your suit. It's in the
wardrobe, just where you left it.
Are you really here,
Paul?
You won't...
You won't disappear,
will you?
No. I'm here.
Your things are ready
for you, Paul.
I remember when you
caught that one.
Yes. And you took it away from
me, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
We're behind the lines, but we know
how to honour the soldier...
who goes on in spite of
blood and death.
Gentlemen, my son.
- Prosit.
Cheers.
I'm glad to know you, young man,
I am glad to know you.
How are things out there?
Terrible, eh? Terrible.
But we must carry on.
After all, you do at least get
decent food out there.
Naturally, it's worse here.
Naturally.
But the best for our soldiers all
the time. That's our motto.
The best for our soldiers.
But...
you must give the Frenchies
a good licking!
And, if you boys want to
come home...
let me show you what you must
do before you can come home.
Give us a hand there,
men.
Now, then, there's the line.
Runs so,
in a "V".
Here is St. Quentin. You can
see for yourself.
You're almost through now.
All right?
Shove ahead out there and
don't stick to that...
everlasting French warfare!
Smash through the johnnies! And
then you will have peace.
When you get in it... the war isn't
the way it looks back here.
Oh! You don't know
anything about it.
Of course, you know about
the details...
but this relates
to the whole!
You can't judge that.
Of course, you do your duty
and you risk your life.
But for that, you receive
the highest honour.
I said that every man in the war
ought to have the Iron cross.
First, the enemy lines must be
broken through in Flanders.
- On to Paris! Push on to Paris!
- Right.
No, not in Flanders. I'll tell you
just where the...
break should come.
Here.
The enemy has too many
reserves there.
- I insist upon Flanders!
- Why should they do that...
when they're halfway through
St. Quentin already?
Because Flanders is
a flat country!
- No mountains, no obstructions!
- There's too many rivers there!
From the farms they
have gone;...
from the schools, from
the factories.
They have gone bravely,
nobly, ever forward...
realizing there is no other duty
now but to save the fatherland.
Paul! How are you,
Paul?
Glad to see you,
Professor.
You've come at the right moment,
Baumer! Just at the right moment.
And as if to prove all have said,
here is one of the first to go.
A lad who sat before me on
these very benches...
who gave up all to serve in the
first year of the war...
one of the iron youth who have made
Germany invincible in the field.
Look at him... sturdy and bronze
and clear-eyed.
The kind of soldier every one
of you should envy.
Oh, lad, you must
speak to them.
You must tell them what it means
to serve your fatherland.
- No, I can't tell them anything.
- You must, Paul.
Just a word... Just tell them how
much they're needed out there.
Tell them why you went and
what it meant to you.
I can't say anything.
You can remember some deed of
heroism, some touch of nobility.
Tell about it.
I can't tell you anything
you don't know.
We live in the trenches
out there. We fight.
We try not to be killed,
sometimes we are.
That's all.
No. No, Paul.
I've been there! I know
what it's like.
That's not what one
dwells on, Paul.
I heard you in here reciting
that same old stuff...
making more iron men,
more young heroes.
You still think it's beautiful
and sweet to die...
for your country, don't you?
We used to think
you knew.
The first bombardment
taught us better.
It's dirty and painful to die
for your country.
When it comes to dying for
your country...
it's better not to die at all!
There are millions out there dying
for their countries...
and what good is it?
Paul!
You asked me to tell them how
much they're needed out there.
He tells you,
"Go out and die."
Oh, but if you'll pardon me, it's
easier to say "Go out and die"
than it is to do it.
Coward!
And it's easier to say it than
to watch it happen.
No! No! Boys, boys!
- I'm sorry, Baumer, but I must say...
- It's no use talking like this.
You won't know
what I mean.
Only, it's been a long while since we
enlisted out of this classroom.
So long I thought maybe the whole
world had learned by this time.
Only now they're sending babies,
and they won't last a week!
I shouldn't have come
on leave.
Up at the front you're alive or
you're dead, and that's all!
You can't fool anybody
about that very long.
Up there we know we're lost and done
for whether we're dead or alive.
Three years we've had
of it... four years.
Every day a year and every
night a century.
Our bodies are earth and our
thoughts are clay...
and we sleep and
eat with death.
We're done for because you
can't live that way...
and keep anything
inside you!
I shouldn't have come on leave.
I'll go back tomorrow.
I've got four days more, but
I can't stand it here!
I'll go back tomorrow!
Sorry.
Mother, you'll catch clod here.
You must go to sleep.
There'll be plenty of time
to sleep...
when you're gone.
Must you go tomorrow, Paul?
Must you?
Yes, Mother. Orders were
changed.
Are you very much afraid,
Paul?
No, Mother.
There's something I want to
say to you, Paul.
It's...
Just be on your guard against
the women out there.
They're no good.
Where we are, there aren't
any women, Mother.
Be very careful at the
front, Paul.
Yes, Mother,
I will.
I'll pray for you
every day.
And if you could, get a job that's
not quite so dangerous.
Yes, Mother. I'll try and get
in the cookhouse.
- That can easily be done.
- You do it then, and if...
- The others say anything...
- That won't worry me, Mother.
Now, you must go to bed and
you must get well...
quickly before I come back.
I put two sets of underwear...
new ones... in your pack.
They'll keep you nice
and warm.
They're all wool.
That's sweet of you.
Good night...
my son.
Good night,
Mother.
Oh, Mother, Mother.
You still think
I'm a child.
Why can't I put my head
in your lap and cry?
- Is this the 2nd Company?
- Yes, sir.
- Is this all of it?
We had 150 men, but this is all
that came back yesterday.
But now they're going to give us
enough to make 150 again.
How old are you?
Sixteen.
No use. I couldn't
find anything.
We'll have to eat the
sawdust.
Not me! I'll go hungry first.
It makes me sick.
Now it's gonna be a
real war again.
Paul! How's old Paul?
Here I am.
You know, the 2nd Company's
getting hard to find.
Nobody seemed to know
where you were.
I'm glad you found it.
I guess I don't get
much of this.
There used to be some food in the
sawdust. Now it's all sawdust.
No joke, either. Eats ya
up inside.
This doesn't look much like
the old 2nd Company.
The replacements are
all like that.
Not even old enough to
carry a pack.
All they know how
to do is die.
I guess... some of the old-timers
are here yet.
Paul, they're trying to invent
something to kill me right now.
Where's Westhus?
Messenger dog was wounded.
He went out to get it.
- Is it true about the armistice?
- Doesn't look that way back there.
You mean they want us to
go on fighting?
That's what they say.
They're crazy!
Germany'll be empty
pretty soon.
Where is... Where is Detering?
He got homesick. You remember
about the cherry blossoms?
I guess he never got
over that.
He started out one night to go home
and help his wife with the farm.
They got him behind the lines, and
we never heard of him since.
He was just homesick, but probably
they couldn't see it that way.
Where's Kat? Is he...
Not Kat! If he were out, the
war would be over.
You remember what he always says:
They're saving him for the last.
- Where is he?
- He's out looking for food...
something to make
soup with.
- Which way?
- Down the road about...
two miles that way.
I'll see you later.
Kat!
Paul!
Hello, Paul.
- How's the side?
- Oh, it's all right now. It's fine.
- Have any luck?
- No, the general's staff's been...
over this country
with a rake.
Let's sit down there.
Tell me, Paul... how was
it at home?
Have a good leave?
- In spots.
- What's the matter?
I'm no good for back
there anymore, Kat.
None of us are. We've been
in this too long.
The young men thought I was a
coward because I told them that...
we learn that death is stronger
than duty to one's country.
The old men said
"Go on. Push on to Paris."
My father even wanted me to
wear my uniform around him.
It's not home back
there anymore.
All I could think of was, "I'd like
to get back and see Kat again."
You're all I've got left,
Kat.
I'm not much to have left.
I missed you, Paul.
At least we know what it's all about
out here. There're no lies here.
Push on to Paris?
You ought to see what they've
got on the other side.
They eat white bread
over there.
They've got dozens of
airplanes to our one...
and tanks that'll go
over anything.
What've we got left?
Guns so worn they drop shells
on our own men.
No food, no ammunition,
no officers.
Push on to Paris!
So that's the way they talk
back there.
I guess we'd better
be going.
How I lied to my
poor mother.
I told her it wasn't so bad
out here because there was...
always a lot of us together.
Now that I'm with you, I'm beginning
to believe that I told her the truth.
Down!
That's another one that missed us.
Come on. Let's go.
Wait a minute. Looks like the old
bread wagon's broke down.
I guess I don't walk the
rest of the way.
Did that get ya, Kat?
Aah, I think it broke my shin.
That's not so bad.
Hold it together.
- Just my luck?
- Good luck.
That means the war is over.
Oh, no, sir!
This war don't end till
they really get me.
Now this one...
Easy, now.
- Hey!
- Easy!
Easy!
Come on. I'll take you in.
Give me your hand.
Easy.
All right.
Well, kid... now we're gonna
be separated.
Maybe we can do something together
later on when the war is over.
Yes, kid.
You give me your address,
I'll give you mine.
You can't get both of us
in one day.
Ah, we'll surely see each
other again, Kat.
Remember that day when you brought
the whole pig into the factory?
And that day in the woods when you
taught us how to dodge shells?
And my first bombardment.
How I cried.
I was a young recruit then.
Here we are.
All right now, Kat.
You could've spared yourself
the trouble. He's dead.
Oh, no. He's just fainted.
He was hit in the shin.
He's dead.
Would you like to take
his pay book?
- You're not related, are you?
- No, we're not related.
Your deal. Get his name
and number?
Yeah, Corporal Stanislaus
Katczinsky, 306.
THE END