Counselor! I've got him!
Down! You come down!
Down for good!
Forgive this early intrusion.
How are you?
I am a great admirer of yours.
Honored to meet you.
May I?
Can I use your typewriter, sir?
Your arm, please. Relax it.
- Your age?
- 43.
So, what are you cooking up?
Another film without hope?
- First time taking the cure?
- Yes.
Take a deep breath.
Come in.
- I'm sorry. I'll come back later.
- No, do come in.
Breathe in.
Deeper.
Good morning... May I smoke?
Cough.
Breathe in.
- You've already read it?
- Yes.
Breathe.
And... what do you think?
Well, I made some notes,
but we'll talk later.
Your system is a bit worn out.
You may get dressed now.
Nice looking girl. American, right?
You've got some fine merchandise there.
This treatment will do you good,
you'll see.
Nurse. 300 ml of holy water,
3 doses to be taken at 15 minute intervals,
on an empty stomach.
- Mud bath every other day...
- What time is it?
After the mud bath, ten minutes in the
mineral water as prescribed...
- I'll wait for you at the spring.
- Yes, thank you.
Sir!
Sir, your glass.
0ver here.
You want to talk about the film?
- Yes, of course.
Fine. Just tell me if you'd like
the producer to see my report.
Frankly, I wouldn't want to be
the one to cause you any trouble.
No, don't worry.
I'm the one who called you in.
0n first reading it's evident
that the film lacks a problematic,
or a philosophical premise...
Would you like to sit down?
...making the film
a series of gratuitous episodes,
perhaps amusing
for their ambiguous realism.
0ne wonders what the authors
are trying to say...
Are they trying to make us think?
To scare us?
From the start, the action reveals
a poverty of poetic inspiration.
Forgive me, but this might be
the definitive proof
that cinema is 50 years
behind all other arts.
The subject doesn't even have the merits
of an 'avant garde' film,
but it has all the shortcomings.
Here, my notes.
I doubt they will be helpful.
It's still a mystery that you'd think of me
for a collaboration that, frankly,
I don't think can work.
No, no. 0n the contrary.
You'll be most helpful.
You see, the film...
I really want to make this film.
I postponed the shoot
for two weeks because...
Mezzabotta! Pardon me.
Mezzabotta! Mario!
You're here too?
Guido!
What happened to you!
Hey, big Guido, how are you?
You've sprouted quite a few
white hairs, old Snaporaz!
Are you drinking that stuff?
It's bad for you.
They said my liver is, well...
And you, what's your treatment?
Just a second... Gloria!
- Your daughter. She's all grown up.
- No, she's not my daughter.
Cruel bees, sucking all the life
from these poor flowers.
- Darling, this is my friend...
- I'm sorry. My shoes...
Gloria. Gloria Morin.
- Nice to meet you.
Fine, thank you.
I know all about you.
Pupi always, always tells me.
We even had a big fight
when I was very critical of your last film.
That's not true. You liked it a lot.
Let's go for a drink. Let's go.
And you, are you here alone?
And your wife?
- Yes, I'm alone.
- Better that way...
Well, I mean, better in general...
You heard about Tina and me?
- Tina?
We're waiting for an annulment.
That's why we're here together.
We're engaged.
Congratulations.
Well, big Guido. What are you
working on? Something good?
Sure is the ideal place to do some thinking.
Daumier, the author, Miss...
Pardon me, what is your name?
- Gloria.
- Gloria Morin.
Nice to meet you.
I am a big admirer of yours.
I'm flattered.
Are you an actress?
Did I see your photo somewhere?
An actress. Yes, well...
I have ambitions in that area.
Actually enormous ambitions,
but that's all, for the moment.
She's got a degree in philosophy.
Allow me. Mario Mezzabotta.
- Nice to meet you.
I don't have a degree.
I'm doing my thesis. It's a bit different.
- And the subject?
- A difficult one.
The loneliness of modern man
in contemporary theater.
Interesting subject. Right, Professor?
And what is the meaning
of the capricious apparitions
of the girl of the spring?
An offer of purity?
Of warmth to the protagonist?
Of all your story's overabundant
symbols, this is the worst...
She didn't make it. Better that way.
- Yack! How are you?
- Not too bad.
- Did anybody recognize you?
- I don't think so.
You brought all that luggage?
It's just five suitcases.
Gowns occupy so much space.
I brought one... you'll see.
Did you get it all?
Carla, it's quiet here at night.
There's nothing going on.
But it's a fashionable spa.
There must be some fashion shows,
some trendy clubs,
even at our hotel.
Have you been behaving?
- Yes, yes.
Actually... I couldn't get you a room
in my hotel,
and besides it's full of people who know me.
So, I found someplace else.
A perfect hotel...
Very pretty, you know...
- But why?
- And how's this guy?
- Sgulp? Great.
You look a little pale. How come?
See, the hotel is right here.
Signora, guests!
See. Like I told you. It's not...
but it's very quiet. If you're hungry,
I'll get them to bring a couple
of sandwiches.
It feels a little sad here.
- No, it's typical!
Besides I'm hungry.
You had lunch, but I didn't.
Hello, Sir.
How's the solitaire coming along?
Everything's ready,
the room, the bathroom.
Rest assured.
Signora will feel at home.
Yes, thank you. You wouldn't
have anything ready for lunch?
- The restroom, please?
- It's over there.
I'll see to it personally.
Trains, such horrible things.
They leave your hands so black.
Are you happy I'm here?
- Yes.
- Really happy or a little happy?
- Very happy.
Hmm. Smack!
Mm, what a nice smell!
Guido, I thought this black velvet
was going to wrinkle.
- Really? Good, good.
- But no. Not a wrinkle.
Even after a three-hour trip.
You didn't even tell me you like it.
Do you like it?
Such a beautiful lady!
So refined.
That thing she has on her head...
What is it? Ploosh?
- Plush, plush.
- Ah, ploosh.
I looked around for it like crazy.
I was quite desperate.
But you know me.
When Carla makes up her mind...
- Snarp!
- Sgulp!
I read a good Donald Duck last week...
There was a dinosaur...
- Here she is, my sweet-buns.
- Be good, a dinosaur...
Guido be good.
What do you want to do now?
Are you sure you've been behaving?
- Sure, why?
Anyway, now sweet-buns is hungry.
0h, my wedding ring.
Listen, Guido.
That little thing you promised me...
What little thing?
Now I bet she brings up
her husband again.
You don't think so?
You'll see, old Snaporaz.
My poor Luigi doesn't seem
happy at all.
You see, my husband is not
the confident type.
He gets depressed.
He's not stupid, you know.
He's actually very clever...
It's so hot here!
He knows all of Roman history by heart.
He just needs a push.
He's still working at the
fuel company, same salary.
Really?
Be good and put down my purse.
You'll break it.
I love that little purse.
He gave it to me.
Why don't you find him a job?
You know so many people.
You've promised it so many times.
I even had a dream about it.
I dreamed that
you did find him a job,
but he'd lost his mind
and killed us both.
- Who?
- You and me!
Know where we were?
In that little street, Via della Croce,
where I bought you
the same tie your wife did.
Do you remember?
And I never knew
if you were wearing hers or mine.
We were there on a cot,
in each other's arms, naked.
And he came in and he killed us
both with a broom!
- Draw the blinds more.
- Yes.
That's it. Now go into
the corridor for a minute,
then pretend you've come
to the wrong room
and found a stranger.
0h, that's good.
We've never done this one.
Hold it there.
Let me look at you.
No. No. Your make-up
needs to be more, more...
- More what?
- More like a slut!
Give me your eyeliner.
- Nice lampshade.
- Yes, yes.
- I'd like one for my place.
- Don't move.
What is this hotel called?
The Railway Hotel.
I want to write to my
husband so he'll send me
an express letter right away.
He writes such nice letters.
I'll let you read them.
- Fine, but keep still...
Make a slutty face.
Go out in the corridor.
- So, it's a part I have to play.
- Yes.
Who do you think I am?
0ne of your actresses?
You don't think
I could be one of them?
Not me. I wouldn't want
to lead that life.
I like staying home.
Go on, get out. I'm sleeping now.
Tell me. If I were really
to do something like this,
would you be jealous?
Why? Would you really?
Who knows?
- May I get you something?
- No, I just came out on a whim.
- Would you like me to run you a bath?
- No, I was just...
- A glass of water, perhaps?
- No, thank you.
What did she want?
What did she say?
The owner, she wanted
to give me a glass of water.
Come here. Come.
0pen up the sheet.
- Guido, do you love me a little?
- Yes, yes.
Is that you, Mama?
So many tears, my son,
so many tears.
Papa, wait! Don't go.
We talked so little.
Listen Papa,
I have so many questions.
I cannot answer them yet.
See the ceiling here? It's so low.
I would have liked it higher.
It's ugly, my son, ugly.
I would have liked it different.
Couldn't you take care of it?
You used to draw so well. I'd like...
0h, the Commendatore,
he shouldn't have bothered.
- Hello.
- Respects. He's got very little time.
Hi.
How is he doing, this son of mine?
Careful. Don't let him move you.
He isn't doing well? How come?
It is so hard, realizing that
one has made such huge mistakes.
But I...
Mother prepared you
a little something.
A little cheese and two peaches.
Don't worry about me.
Sure, this place gets a little lonely,
but your mother comes every day.
She keeps me company, you know.
And keeps everything in order.
A little decorum is always necessary.
That's how we were brought up.
And with your wife, Luisa... all fine?
Yes. Luisa...
You two together have been
my joy. Goodbye, son...
What is this place?
Do you like it here?
I haven't figured it out yet.
But it's going much better.
At first, you see, at first...
Guido! I do my best.
What more can I do?
Poor Guido, you must be tired.
Shall we go home?
I'm Luisa, your wife.
Don't you recognize me?
What are you thinking about?
- Hello.
Good afternoon.
Guido! In a few days,
I'll get you an introduction
so you can get
all the advice you need.
Nice mystical figure. Right?
I brought you the three old men.
0ne is a Russian,
another is a retired general...
What old men?
The ones for the role of the Father.
Cover me, Cesarino...
Come here, buffoon.
How are you?
So nice to see you, Super Tarzan!
- I called you six times.
- Yes, yes I know.
- It's about Claudia's script.
- So?
I thought about mailing it to you.
In fact, I've already mailed it.
- Really?
You've still got your looks.
Why don't you go back to acting?
I was up all night with
an idea for the spaceship.
Why don't we make the upper story...
Conocchia, don't take my arm!
I hate it! And wear a jacket!
Now I need to wear a jacket
to talk to you...
How are you? How was your trip?
Good. It's been an hour...
What a blinding vision! Beautiful!
- Really?
- Yes.
You're always telling me
I'm 'bellissima'
but you never tell me about my part.
How was my screen test?
- Great, or you wouldn't be here.
They told me I have to look
motherly and eat a lot of pasta.
I should gain six pounds. Is this all?
See? You already know
more than I do.
You are the author.
You should be telling me something.
- What should this lady do?
- What?
Agostini!
I don't want to bother you.
The hotel is grand,
the whisky, excellent.
But I have three questions.
Yes, yes, later. What is it?
Ah, yes, yes. Pardon me.
Agostini, we should...
I just didn't feel like talking to that guy.
Claudia is getting offers
from all over the world.
I can't keep her waiting.
Give her something.
Do you have a script,
a few pages, an idea?
Does Claudia realize that this
might be a great part?
Perhaps the best she's ever
played? I'll explain...
I'm telling you as a friend,
you're gonna lose her.
- You want to see the old men or not?
- Are you crazy? We're ready...
What?
- The old men.
- Where are they?
- Here.
Signora Carla called. She doesn't
want to stay in that hotel.
It's ugly. She's right.
- What can I do? Bring her here?
I'll call the old men.
Sorry, I wanted to introduce you
to my little wife.
Thrilled.
She writes too. She's a columnist
for some ladies' magazines.
She's got a few questions for you.
My readers go crazy for romance.
Could you tell me something
about your love life?
Here they are.
Say hello to the Dottore.
Step down. You too, General.
- How old are you?
- 70.
- And you?
- 64.
- 68.
They aren't old enough.
What? This one
has one foot in the grave.
Next time I'll get three corpses.
You asked for a pathetic type...
This one makes you wanna cry
the minute you see him.
Hello, Commendatore.
If you kneel, what do I do?
Get up or you'll hurt yourself.
How are you, little Guido?
Hello, Commendatore.
We took a helicopter.
This one screamed the whole way.
Where's the swimming pool?
We haven't even checked in. Shut up!
Has the treatment helped?
- Yes.
- Feeling better? Here.
- What is it?
Just a token.
- You're always giving me presents.
- It's just like mine.
It doesn't need winding.
A watch! A little watch, everyone!
- So, are your ideas any clearer now?
- Yes, I really think so.
We've got the Americans...
I've seen her passport.
She's 52 years old?
Ah, she's a little girl.
Good evening, signora.
And who are you, darling?
Mr. Director, another little question...
He wants to know the relationship
between Catholicism and Marxism.
Thank you, I got it.
You want to know about
my political affiliation.
As an honest man,
and all of you Italians are,
you should be able to answer me.
Is Italy an essentially Catholic country?
Yes, it is!
You shut up and eat your ice-cream.
It's the estimate for the spaceship.
I need to talk to you later,
face to face,
I'm at the end of my rope.
This is a madhouse!
Fine, we'll discuss it later.
What was that about your cholesterol?
...only one great writer.
The early Fitzgerald.
Then his writing became an orgy
of pragmatism or brutal realism.
What does Left or Right mean?
You're such an optimist
to believe that in a world
this confused and chaotic
there are people so lucid
as to belong exclusively
to the Left or the Right.
The Americans have this new
theory about cholesterol...
- Is your ice-cream good?
- Very good.
Could you say approximately
how many scenes she'll be in?
What?
- How many scenes?
- Five.
0nly five.
Maybe six, or even seven.
Good evening.
Hi, Guido.
The Ambassador's got his eye on signora.
So?
- I thought you'd want to know.
- Good, now I know.
- Do you want me to ask her to dance?
- Yes, ask her.
Dear friends there's only one truth...
But I am so anxious to know,
to understand my character.
I need to coexist with my character
for a while before shooting...
The lady says she needs
to know her character.
I need to get inside her skin,
her ideas, or I'll fail.
Hasn't the Maestro explained
the part yet?
- No.
- I am sorry, dear lady.
I don't have such information.
I'm only the producer.
Guido, isn't it true that I know nothing?
- Right. Not a thing.
And now three days of rest.
They look like glass.
The first cherries of spring.
Thanks. And for Guido?
Mario Mezzabotta,
all 200 pounds of him.
Shall we take a little walk?
I know... Naturally,
you think I've lost it.
Yes.
- I'm 30 years her senior. So what?
- It's all right.
I may be the fool, the old imbecile,
the one who foots the bill. So what?
Could you create something important,
beautiful and real on a commission?
For instance, if the Pope asked you?
Yes, yes. I'll think about it.
Excuse me.
Listen, I'm not deluding myself.
Maybe she's only with me
for the money.
Actually, that's certainly it.
But I've never felt closer
to anybody in my life.
Just look at her.
She's pretty, charming, intelligent.
She has it all. 0nly for the money?
But there are so many rich young men
around these days, loads of them.
It's clear. She cares for you.
Right. And she hasn't tried
to pressure me.
I made up my mind rationally.
The poor thing has never
even mentioned my wife,
my family, never a reproach.
How did you meet her?
In London. She was in school
with my daughter.
How many years have you
been married?
Many. 31.
And your wife...
My wife took it really badly.
She hates her.
While Gloria, poor thing,
is fond of her.
So spell it out. I am a fool!
There must be a shooting schedule.
Dates.
0therwise we're off to Germany.
We have other offers.
Will you be leaving me
in the dark 'til the end?
You look like a little snail.
- What is a little snail?
- Une petite escargot.
Can you hear the voice
of the springs?
The Romans used to call it
'Happy Waters. '
Maya, let's entertain these bores.
May I?
Are you ready, Maya?
What am I holding?
A velvet purse.
- And inside?
- A white handkerchief.
A red one.
- No drugs, I hope.
- No, it's aspirin.
- A purse.
- Is there any money in it?
2,725 lire.
And this lady here.
What is she thinking?
No dirty thoughts, I hope.
Just think about something.
About what?
Whatever you like.
Are you thinking?
Yes.
I'd like to live another 100 years.
Best of luck!
And what is in this pretty
lady's head?
Let me be.
May I think about someone?
Yes. Go ahead, Lady!
Forget about it. I'm ashamed.
What about?
Can I really think of a person?
I'd be afraid to have my thoughts read.
Don't you worry darling,
no risk there.
Would you like to leave? It's cold.
A little kiss and a big slap.
Is that right?
Ladies and gentlemen,
you're thinking, 'What a trickster. '
Well, sorry to disappoint you,
but there's no trick.
And it isn't just a coincidence.
It's an exceptional example
of magnetic fields and telepathy.
I transmit your thoughts to Mlle. Maya.
You! Do you believe
you can hide your thoughts?
Please, leave her alone.
Don't insist.
Thoughts are sacred.
See, it's all a game.
Maya, are you ready?
Just a moment, could we know
what you gentlemen are thinking?
You for instance.
What are you thinking?
What else? My director.
My cross and my delight.
- How are you?
- Fine. And you?
It has been quite a while... years!
Unfortunately yes, my dear.
Just a moment. You're famous now.
Cut it out.
Just tell me what's your trick?
Well, it's partly a trick,
but part of it is real.
I don't know how, but it happens.
- Can you transmit anything?
Anything. Except for her to get lost.
- Do you want to try?
- Yes. Wait.
I bet now, with you, it won't work.
I don't understand. I can't repeat...
Asa... nisi... masa?
Is this right?
- Right?
- Yes.
But what does it mean?
Guido, come here!
Where are you?
Don't be spoiled! What a wonder!
I don't want to take a bath,
I don't want to...
Come here... let me catch you?
I know what that rascal wants.
He wants to be carried
by his sweetheart,
doesn't he, the strapping lad.
Come here. Come here.
He never wants to take
the wine bath, the naughty boy.
Don't you know that if you do
you'll grow into a strong man?
Guido is scared! Guido is scared!
The Devil and damnation!
Granny, granny!
The wood is all wet this year.
This prowling cat is just
like your grandfather.
Always on the prowl
and only comes in for food.
Shame on you! Go to bed.
Last time I slammed the door
in his face
and left him outside for two days.
I could have married again
and found a handsome man,
rest assured, better
than your grandfather.
What an idiot I am!
I thought that if I took another
husband, my first husband,
whether in heaven or hell,
wouldn't have waited.
Be quiet! Go to bed, children!
Nanny, Claudio wet himself!
What are you doing?
Go to sleep. You too, sleep.
Little Guido, get under the covers.
It's cold. Be still.
Did you say your prayers?
Aren't you a beautiful sticky bun?
The most beautiful!
Give me a kiss, too.
Who do you love best? Me?
Is that right?
You can't fool me.
I'm going to give you a spanking.
I can tell when you're pretending.
Sleep tight, little creatures.
Close your eyes.
Guido, don't close your
eyes tonight!
It's the night the portrait's eyes move.
You're not scared, are you?
You must be quiet!
Uncle Agostino will look into
the corner and find the treasure!
Don't be afraid, Guido!
We'll be rich!
Do you remember the spell?
Asa Nisi Masa... Asa Nisi Masa... sh!
Sir, you got two or three calls from Rome.
Your wife, I think.
Fine. Get me the line.
- Gino, get the gentleman the line.
- All right.
- This is for you. Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Marcella, that call from Rome, quickly.
No, I'm not offended.
There's only one thing
that offends me.
You know me. No.
I forgive him everything.
Let's have a little chat.
Sit beside me for a moment.
No, I'm going to bed.
I'm very tired and waiting for a call.
Would you like some?
No, thank you.
I have such a headache.
Give me your hands.
No, sit down.
I have a healing fluid
in my left hand.
I put it on my belly when it aches.
Take off your hat.
Is it any better?
Yes, maybe.
Why do you look at me that way?
0h, don't say I'm beautiful.
You make it sound insulting.
What's with you?
I don't know.
I feel I made all the wrong
decisions in my life and in my work.
Tell me, why do you enjoy
torturing me?
Torturing you?
Talk to me as you would
to an old friend.
I need to feel close to my director.
Did you see my last movie,
the one shot in Belgrade?
My character was a woman
marked by the injuries of time,
yet still desirable...
- Play "Mystification".
- I don't know it.
But yes...
What a character... this woman...
But...
In whom people find protection
and love.
I am this character.
I am like her in life and love.
That's why I'm so lonely.
And I have always forgiven
everything in the man...
the men, I love.
- Sir, Rome on the line.
- Thank you.
I am very sensual. Wicked, too!
Yes, yes, you're very close.
I'll be right back.
Rome on the line. You may speak.
Hello, yes!
- Do you want Luisa?
- Yes.
Feeling guilty, you beast?
This is Rossella.
Hi, Rossella. How are you?
Luisa was looking for me.
Where were you this time?
Your rest cure? What an excuse...
Here comes Luisa.
Guido, I called you twice.
Where were you?
I know. I'm sorry.
I was up in the production office.
We're working.
How are you?
Not bad... And the treatment?
Is it helping?
Perhaps. But, you know,
I can't really rest.
And you? What are you doing?
Having fun?
The usual. I'm with Rossella, Tilde, Enrico.
They were about to leave.
But are you having a good time?
Did you meet anybody?
Hardly. It's a terrible bore.
But for my work, it's better this way.
- Good night, Guido.
- 'Night.
You've met no one you know?
Are you always alone?
0f course.
Really?
Luisa, why don't you come visit?
Just a short stay.
It's easy to get here.
When are you going
to start shooting, you bore?
I don't know.
Let me talk to Luisa, please.
So, should I come?
Do you want me to?
If you'd like to.
You could even bring a friend.
But would it make you happy?
0f course, or I wouldn't ask you.
- Sir, are you staying on?
- No.
When should I come?
Whenever it's good for you.
Careful, I'll come.
Darling, I wouldn't have asked.
I'd love it...
So long, and good night.
Bye, Mr. Alienated. Good night.
Night, Guido.
Monsieur Guido, my agent thought...
Just a second, madam. I am going
to step into the office so...
- Shit!
- It's in my best interest.
Tomorrow morning
we'll discuss everything. All right?
Beams for the central structure:
10,000.
Planks for steps: 260.
'Evening.
Do you need something?
No, thanks.
Go on with your work.
What a well-behaved
production team.
Hi.
0h, hi Eleonora.
2,350. Corrugated iron.
Listen, Dottore, since you're here.
I called the pensione about
the German, but she's gone.
- You must find her.
- She's in Paris with a circus.
Really?
What should I do?
What an honor, Dottore.
You've caught me
with my pants down!
Listen Guido.
About the farm... there's that...
Ah, here. Where's this place?
It doesn't even have a note
about the address, nothing!
It's in the Prince's estate.
- Who's in here?
- My little nieces.
Eva and Dina.
'Evening.
C'mon. Let him take a look at you.
Perhaps he'll give you
a little part.
- Nice to meet you.
- My pleasure.
Where are you from?
- Trieste.
- Hurray for Italy!
You've got a nice set up here,
don't you?
Tell him about my cousin.
Guido. This one's cousin
is six feet tall.
You should see her.
She might be good for the movie.
This one... you she-devil...
It's true. She's tall like me
standing on the bed.
See?
She's twice been voted
Miss Nylon Stockings.
Is Guido in there? I'm coming in.
Sleep, Conocchia, sleep.
I'll see you tomorrow.
May I ask you a question?
Go ahead.
My friend here says...
you can't make a love story.
- Shut up!
- She's right.
Should I wake you up
in the morning, Guido?
No, thanks.
0ur commander will never
catch us unprepared.
This production crew never sleeps!
Such a splitting headache.
What did I eat?
They're always horsing around,
but they're good guys.
Do you need anything, Guido?
Is it a new idea?
Do you have something to tell me?
No, thank you, no.
Go back to bed.
I don't need anything.
- Anything at all.
- No, thank you. Good night.
Good night my ass!
Who can sleep here?
How can I get any sleep?
Conocchia, calm down.
Allow me. I have been in this
business for 30 years,
I've worked on movies
you couldn't begin to imagine
and I have never been afraid
of anything!
What are you shouting for,
you crazy old man!
There, you've said it now. 0ld.
Finally you've spat it out.
Conocchia is old.
What do you want?
Get back inside.
You always keep me in the dark.
I never know what to do.
When to talk or when to shut up.
I don't want to bother you.
I don't want to know
what this movie is about.
- You want to keep it a secret? Go ahead.
- Please, go back to bed.
But if I'm to help you out,
as I've always done,
and you were so happy then,
you must tell me something!
Tell me: get rid
of the French woman...
this is how I want the spaceship...
tell me: go hang yourself,
but do tell me something.
You've changed so much,
Guido my friend.
What are you doing now?
Crying? Aren't you ashamed?
I'll be leaving tomorrow.
I'm quitting.
I don't want to be in your way.
You need some young blood.
Just be careful. You're not
the man you used to be, either.
A crisis of inspiration?
And what if it weren't a
passing one, my dear?
What if it's the final collapse
of a filthy liar
with no flair or talent? Sgulp!
Let's say you are purity itself.
But what the hell does it mean
to be really honest?
Didn't you hear
what the Falcaccio said?
"It's time to set all the symbols aside,
the echoing of purity, innocence, escape."
What is it you want then?
Yes, this could be it.
There's a museum in the town,
and you, the guard's daughter,
grew up surrounded by images
of ancient beauty...
You're right.
I've come to stay forever.
I want to create order,
I want to cleanse...
Hello?
They're asking for you
from the Railway Hotel.
Fine. I'll take it.
Hello? Who's that? Hello?
Guido, I feel dreadful.
The mineral water made me sick.
I have a temperature. Come.
Come here, immediately.
At this time of night?
I can't. I'll come tomorrow.
Come.
The poor thing, if you only knew
how she was asking for you.
Here's the ice.
- She's melting. She's got at least 104.
- Yes, fine. Just go now.
- Should I bring the peas?
- What peas?
When she was delirious
she asked for peas. It's a good sign.
No, just forget about it.
- If you need anything, let us know.
- Yes, thanks.
Carla, is this the first time you've run
such a high fever so suddenly?
No. It shoots up over nothing.
Then it goes away.
My husband is used to it.
It doesn't scare him
No, don't get up.
Stay under the covers.
- I'm so hot. I'm thirsty.
- Wait, I'll give it to you. Here.
Drink slowly or you'll get
all bloated!
- Is it day or night?
- What are you talking about?
It's four o'clock in the afternoon.
Listen, now we'll wait for the
doctor and see what he has to say.
It wouldn't be a bad idea to send
your husband a telegram.
We can't take full responsibility for this.
Yes, he ought to know.
No, I don't want it to be over.
If he comes, he'll take me away.
And I have bought
so many nice little dresses.
Why did you gorge on
all that water?
That's for sick people.
Are you sick?
You're always ready when
there's something to gorge on.
What else should I do?
You're always leaving me here alone.
I drafted my will two years ago.
Anyway, it's not like you die sooner
just because you make a will.
You see, I have a brother
and a sister too,
but I'd like the apartment
to go to my husband.
It's mine, but how would
the poor thing manage with out it...
even if he does get remarried?
Ah, these sheets!
Listen, tell me the truth,
the truth, you hear?
Why do you stay with me?
What can I tell the Cardinal tomorrow?
Yes, I did read the little synopsis
your producer sent us.
It's very interesting.
From a factual point of view though,
the meeting between
the protagonist
and a prince of the church could
not happen during a mud treatment
as you describe it.
I'm sorry but it's absolutely not feasible.
A high prelate has his
own private room.
True, but I was looking for
an unconventional setting.
What do you mean?
The protagonist received
a Catholic upbringing and...
- Good morning.
- Monsignor, this is Guido Anselmi.
Nice to meet you.
You must be the director.
Yes.
Is the subject of this film
a religious one?
Well, yes, in a manner of speaking.
As I was saying, the protagonist
had a Catholic upbringing,
like all of us, for that matter.
So, he has certain complexes,
certain needs he can no
longer repress.
And a prince of the church appears to him
like the depositary of a truth
that he can no longer accept
although it still fascinates him.
So, he seeks contact, some help,
perhaps a flash of understanding.
Saul in Damascus, right?
Don't we all harbor such hopes?
I do realize the idea might sound a
bit superficial, gothic if you want...
No, no, that's not it.
I don't believe cinema
lends itself well to certain topics.
You mix sacred
and profane love too casually.
Isn't that so?
- Maybe.
Yours is a great responsibility.
You can either corrupt
or educate thousands of souls.
His Eminence
will listen to you all the same.
You can ask him some questions.
Allow me to introduce you
to the director.
Please, do sit down.
Please pardon the intrusion,
Your Eminence. I wouldn't presume,
But my producer is restless,
perhaps he's right,
and he insisted that I...
- Are you married?
- Yes.
- Any children?
- Yes. I mean, no.
- How old are you?
- 43.
- Do you hear this singing bird?
- Pardon?
- Do you know what it's called?
- No.
It's called Diomedeo.
The legend has it that
when Diomedes died,
all these little birds gathered
and accompanied him to his grave
singing a funeral lamentation.
Hear? It sounds like wailing.
Guido, Guido let's go see
the Saraghina.
Coming.
Saraghina, dance the Rumba.
Here.
Shame on you, shame on you...
It's a mortal sin, it's a mortal sin...
I don't believe it, it can't be true...
Look at your mother, look at her!
- Mother.
- Stop there.
0h God, I'm so ashamed,
so ashamed and hurt!
But above all, during his whole life
and in any place where he lived,
the pious Luigi most abhorred
any talk or dealing with women,
whose presence he avoided
in such a way that whoever
saw him thought he had a natural
dislike of them...
Get down!
Don't you know that Saraghina
is the devil?
No, I didn't. I really did not.
So, what does it mean?
It's a character inspired by
your childhood memories.
No connection with a real
critical conscience.
No, if you really want to make
a polemical piece
about the Italian Catholic
consciousness, you would need
a much higher degree of culture
as well as inexorable logic and clarity.
Forgive me, but...
your naivet is a serious failing.
Your little memories,
bathed in nostalgia,
your inoffensive and fundamentally
sentimental evocations
are all the expressions
of an accomplice...
"How?" said the parish priest,
"With a communist?"
See? He didn't say: 'a man'.
Catholic conscience?
Just think what Suetonious was
at the time of the Caesars!
No, your intention was to denounce,
but you end up
supporting it like an accomplice.
See? What confusion...
what ambiguity!
Dear Doctor, I'm very angry with you!
But you don't need me anymore.
That isn't true, absolutely not true.
127: showers and mud treatments.
129: massages.
131: inhalations.
Hello, Commendatore.
You know, I've figured out
what you're trying to talk about...
Man's inner confusion.
But you've got to be clearer.
You have to make yourself understood.
0therwise what's the use of it?