The Assistant Warden wants
this one out of the block early.
Wants to get it over with fast.
Okay, let's do it.
Psst! Hey.
Come on, wake up,
it's time.
Wake up.
Let's go, it's time.
Well, this is it.
7474505B.
What wing?
- Maximum wing, Block 9.
Standard release?
Parole, three out of five.
Good behavior.
Give me a minute.
One Timex digital watch, broken.
One unused prophylactic.
One soiled.
Boots, black.
Belt, black.
One black suit jacket.
One pair black suit pants.
One hat. Black.
One pair of sunglasses.
$23.07.
Sign here.
What's this?
What?
This car.
This stupid car.
Where's the Cadillac?
The Caddy. Where's the Caddy?
The what?
The Cadillac we used to have.
The Bluesmobile.
I traded it.
You traded the Bluesmobile for this?
No, for a microphone.
A microphone?
Okay, I can see that.
What the hell is this?
This was a bargain.
I picked it up at the Mount Prospect
City Police Auction last spring.
It's an old Mount Prospect police car.
They were practically giving them away.
Well, thank you, pal.
The day I get out of prison,
my own brother picks me up in a police car.
You don't like it?
No, I don't like it.
Car's got a lot of pickup.
It's got a cop motor,
a 440 cubic-inch plant.
It's got cop tires,
cop suspension, cop shocks.
It was a model made before catalytic converters
so it'll run good on regular gas.
What do you say?
Is it the new Bluesmobile,
or what?
Fix the cigarette lighter.
What are we doing here?
You promised you'd visit the
Penguin the day you got out.
Yeah. So, I lied to her.
You can't lie to a nun.
We gotta go in and visit the Penguin.
No fucking way.
Who is it?
Jake and Elwood.
Come in.
Hello, boys.
Nice to see you.
Please, have a seat.
No, boys.
Come over here in front of me.
I want to see your faces.
The county took a tax assessment
of this property last month.
They want $5,000.
Doesn't the Church have to pay that?
They would, if they were
interested in keeping the place.
But they aren't.
The Archbishop wants to
sell this building outright
to the Board of Education.
What's gonna happen to you?
I'll be sent to the missions: Africa,
Latin America,
Korea...
- Forget it.
$5,000? No problem.
We'll have it for you in the morning.
Let's go.
No. I will not take your filthy, stolen money!
Well, then.
I guess you're really up shit creek.
I beg your pardon.
What did you say?
I offered to help you.
You refused to take our money.
Then I said, "I guess you're
really up shit creek. "
Ow! Christ, Jake,
take it easy, man.
Elwood!
Jesus Christ!
Shit! Goddamn it!
Son of a bitch!
Jesus Christ.
You son of a bitch!
You fat penguin!
Fuck this noise, man!
You are such a disappointing pair.
I prayed so hard for you.
It saddens and hurts me
that the two young men whom I raised
to believe in the Ten Commandments,
have returned to me as two thieves
with filthy mouths and bad attitudes.
Get out!
And don't come back
until you've redeemed yourselves.
Boys, you gotta learn
not to talk to nuns that way.
Jake, Elwood.
Curtis!
- Hey, man!
You look fine, man!
Good to see you, man!
Hey, buy you boys a drink?
Boys, things are bad.
They gonna sell this place
to the Board of Education
and I'll be out on the street.
That money's got to be in the Cook
County Assessor's Office within 11 days.
They wouldn't turn you out, would they?
Shit. What's one more old nigger
to the Board of Education?
Curtis, you and the Penguin
are the only family we got.
You're the only one
that was ever good to us
singing Elmore James tunes and
blowing the harp for us down here.
Well, the sister was right.
You boys could use a little churching up.
Slide on down to the Triple Rock
and catch Rev. Cleophus.
You boys listen to what he's got to say.
Curtis,
I don't want to listen
to no jive-ass preacher
talking to me about heaven and hell.
Jake, you get wise.
You get to church.
All I'm saying is we got to figure out
some way to get that money honestly.
That could be a problem.
It's like the Penguin says.
We've got to make that
move towards redemption.
We got to go to church.
We've got to make that move towards redemption.
Bullshit.
Come on.
And now,
this week's sermon
is from our beloved,
the Rev. Cleophus James!
James.
Come on, Reverend!
- Come on, preacher.
And now, people.
Take your time!
When I woke up this morning
I heard a disturbing sound.
Yeah.
I said, when I woke up this morning
I heard a disturbing sound!
What I heard was the jingle-jangle
of a thousand lost souls!
I'm talking about the souls
of mortal men and women
departed from this life!
Wait a minute!
Those lost, anguished souls
roaming unseen over the earth,
seeking the divine light
they'll not find,
because it's too late!
Too late! Yeah!
Too late for them to ever see again
the light they once chose
not to follow. All right!
Don't be lost when your time comes!
"For the day of the Lord cometh
"as a thief in the night. "
Amen.
Say Amen!
Can I get Amen?
Let Us an All go back
To the old Old landmark
Let us an all go back
Let us all all go back
To the old Old landmark
As we stay in the service of the Lord
Let us kneel
Kneel in prayer
Gonna hold
Hold my breath
Let us kneel
Kneel in prayer
Gonna hold
Hold my breath
Let us feel
Feel that prayer
Kneel in prayer
Let us preach
Preach the word
Got to preach Preach the word all the way
Do it, know it, feel it
Let us preach
Preach the word
Got to preach
all the way
Let's go
All the way
Yea, Lord
Gonna preach
Yeah, Lord
Yeah
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Let's go
All the way
To the old
Old landmark
Yeah
I know
Jake, are you all right?
Oh, Child
Say it loud
Hallelujah
The band.
Do you see the light?
The band!
What light?
Have you seen the light?
Yes! Jesus H.
Tap-Dancing Christ!
I have seen the light!
The band, Elwood,
the band!
The band?
The band.
Band.
The band!
Praise God!
And God bless the United States of America.
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Let us all
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Let us all
All go back
To the old
Old landmark
Do it, know ft, feel it
Gonna go back
All go back
Stay in the service
of the Lord
Yea, Lord
We'll put the band back together,
do a few gigs.
We get some bread.
Bang. $5,000.
Yeah, getting the band back together
might not be that easy, Jake.
What are you talking about?
They split.
They all took straight jobs.
Yeah? So you know where they are.
You said you were keeping
in touch with them.
I got a couple of leads,
a few phone numbers.
But I mean, how many of them
visited or even wrote you, huh?
They're not the kind of
guys who write letters.
You were outside.
I was inside.
You were supposed to keep
in touch with the band.
I kept asking you if we
were gonna play again.
What was I gonna do,
take away your only hope?
Take away the very thing
that kept you going in there?
I took the liberty of bullshitting you.
Okay?
You lied to me.
It wasn't lies.
It was just bullshit.
What?
Rollers.
No.
Yeah.
What? What did I do?
You failed to stop at a red signal.
The light was yellow, sir.
May I see your license, please?
God damn it!
Man, I haven't been pulled
over in six months.
I bet those cops have got SCMODS.
SCMODS?
State County Municipal Offender Data System.
Elwood, we show your license
currently under suspension.
Step out of the car, please.
First you trade the Cadillac for a microphone.
Then you lie to me about the band.
Now you're gonna put me
right back in the joint.
They're not gonna catch us.
We're on a mission from God.
Elwood.
We are in high-speed pursuit
northbound on Courtland Avenue.
Black-and-white 1974 Dodge
sedan with Illinois plates.
Request assistance.
We'll be all right if we can
just get back on the expressway.
This don't look like no expressway to me!
Don't yell at me.
What do you want me to do, motorhead?
Try not to be so negative all the time.
Why don't you offer some constructive criticism?
You got us into this parking lot, pal.
Now you get us out!
You want out of this parking lot? Okay.
Will there be anything else?
Yes. Do you have a Miss Piggy?
There's Hanson Burgers.
Yeah, lots of space in this mall.
Disco pants and haircuts.
Yeah.
Baby clothes.
This place has got everything.
New Oldsmobiles are in early this year.
Pier 1 imports.
They broke my watch!
I'm gonna catch that sucker
if it's the last thing I ever do.
Nice place, huh?
Hey, Sam.
Hey, Lloyd.
Anybody call for me on the phone?
No. No calls.
Some guy left this card.
Cop. Said he'd be back.
This here's my brother, Jake.
He just got out of the joint.
He's gonna be staying
with me for a few weeks.
Yeah. Okay.
Did you get me my Cheez Whiz, boy?
Well, it ain't much,
but it's home.
How often does the train go by?
- So often you won't even notice it.
What are you doing?
- Making dinner. Want some?
No.
Tomorrow we got to get
the band back together.
I'm gonna quit work in the
morning, first thing.
And how are you going to get to work,
Mr. Lead Foot,
Mr. Hot Redder,
Mr. Motor Head?
Those cops took your license away.
They got your name,
your address.
No, they don't got my address.
I falsified my renewal.
I put down 1060 West Addison.
1060 West Addison?
That's Wrigley Field.
I gotta hit the sack.
Hey, you sleaze! My bed!
This, gentlemen, is the elegant
abode of one Elwood Blues.
Thanks for your help,
Mr. Mercer.
I kind of like the Wrigley Field bit.
Yeah, real cute.
All right, Sam?
Hi, has my friend arrived yet?
Failed to report in yesterday.
I don't want no trouble.
You just tell us where they are
and there'll be no trouble.
Stand back.
It's almost 9:00.
We've gotta go to work.
Well, Elwood,
sit down.
What's on your mind?
I got to quit.
Why is that, Elwood?
I'm going to become a priest.
Well, okay.
Listen, I'll call payroll and have
them get your severance pay ready.
Good luck.
God bless you, sir.
- Well, thank you.
What's this?
This is the last known address
of "Bones" Malone and "Blue Lou" Marini.
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
Yeah.
Mrs. Toronto?
Tarantino.
Ma'am, do you have a Thomas Malone
or Louis Marini living here?
Not anymore.
They moved out a long time ago.
I don't take in boarders,
not for a long time.
May we come in, ma'am?
- Please.
Did they leave a forwarding address?
A phone number?
No.
Did they live quietly?
What were their personal habits?
They were good boys
but they made a lot of racket at night.
Are you the police?
No, ma'am.
We're musicians.
Mr. Man!
Yes, ma'am?
They left this card.
Maybe it'll help you?
Thanks.
Thank you.
You're marvelous.
I'm Murph, and these
are the Magic Tones.
Steve "The Colonel" Cropper,
Donald "Duck" Dunn,
Willie "Too Big" Hall
and Tom "Bones" Malone.
We'll be back for the Armada Room's two-hour
disco swing party after this short break.
Till then,
don't you go changing.
So, Jake, you're out. You're free.
You're rehabilitated.
What's next? What's happening?
What you gonna do?
You got the money you owe us, motherfucker?
Look, let's just get something straight here...
The reason he got locked in
the slam in the first place
was for sticking up a gas
station to cover you guys.
You're kidding.
He pulled that job to pay for
the band's room-service tab
from that Kiwanis gig in Coal City.
You did?
That's right.
So I don't want to hear anymore
of this small-change shit.
We're putting the band back together.
Now, who here at this table
can honestly say
that they played any finer
or felt any better than they did than
when they were with the Blues Brothers?
You were the backbone.
The nerve center of a great
rhythm-and-blues band.
You can make that live,
breathe and jump again.
"Murph and the Magic Tones?"
Look at you in those
candy-ass monkey suits.
And I thought I had it bad in Joliet.
At least we got a change
in clothes, sucker.
You're wearing the same shit
you had on three years ago.
Jake ain't lying.
We had a band powerful enough to
turn goat piss into gasoline.
We'll never get that fat sound again.
- Not without some more horns.
We'll never get Mr. Fabulous.
Where is he?
Forget it.
Mr. Fabulous is the top
maitre d' at the Chez Paul.
He's pulling down six bills a week.
Matt Murphy got married.
Where is Matt "Guitar" Murphy?
He opened a soul food restaurant
with his old lady on Maxwell Street.
And he took Blue Lou with him.
You'll never get Matt and Mr. Fabulous
out of them high-paying gigs.
Oh, yeah?
Well, me and the Lord,
we got an understanding.
We're on a mission from God.
Mainly French cuisine.
No, sir. Mayor Daley no longer dines here.
He's dead, sir.
Private dining rooms are available.
Oh, no. I thought it was
supposed to be 5 years.
Didn't you get 5 years?
Uh, no, sir, not you.
And your name, sir?
Rizzolo, for 8 at 11:30.
Thank you.
Mr. Fabulous, how marvelous
it is to see you.
You're looking younger than ever.
Wait.
You guys can't come in here.
Oh, nonsense, my dear fellow.
My brother and I have come to dine
to celebrate my early release
from the service of the state.
Wait. Let's talk outside.
Let's have a cup of coffee outside.
Why, heavens, no.
We seek a full meal and all
the compliments of the house.
Come, Elwood.
Let us adjourn ourselves to the nearest table
and overlook this establishment's board of fare.
Good evening.
Chez Paul. Wait! Hey!
Uh, sir, do you mind calling back
in about five minutes, please?
I'm sure, we'll have a table
for you in just a few moments.
Excuse me, won't you?
Give us a bottle of your finest champagne,
five shrimp cocktails
and some bread for my brother.
We have a Dom Perignon, '71, at $120.
That'll be fine, pal.
Come on. Seriously, you guys, the
food here is really expensive.
The soup is fucking $10.
Come on. Let's go outside.
I'll buy you a cup of coffee.
We're putting the band back together.
Forget it. No way.
We're on a mission from God.
Hold it, hold it.
What's this?
Waiter? Sir?
Please, waiter?
Yes, sir?
How are your salads?
The salads are fine.
It's just that we'd like
to move to another table,
away from those two gentlemen.
Why? Have they been disturbing you?
- No.
It's just that, well, frankly,
they're offensive... smelling.
I mean, they smell bad.
Excuse me, sir. I'll see if I can
locate another table for you.
Thank you.
Wrong glass, sir.
How much for the little girl?
The women?
How much for the women?
What?
Your women,
I want to buy your women.
The little girl.
Your daughters.
Sell them to me.
Sell me your children.
Maitre d'! Maitre d'!
Hey, cut it out,
cut it out.
The owners are gonna ask me
to call the cops.
You wouldn't do that to me,
would you, man?
He just got out of Joliet.
He's on parole.
You can't call the cops on him, man.
We're putting the band back together.
I said no.
Absolutely not!
You! How much for your wife?
We're putting the band back together.
We need you, man.
We need your horn.
I can't. I really can't.
We got everybody except Matt "Guitar" Murphy
and Blue Lou and we're getting them next.
No way.
If you say no, Elwood and I
will come here for breakfast,
lunch and dinner every day of the week.
Okay, okay. I'll play.
You got me.
White men!
White women!
The swastika is calling you!
The sacred and ancient symbol of your race
since the beginning of time.
The Jew is using the black
as muscle against you.
And you are left there,
helpless.
Fuck you! Why don't you
go back where you belong?
What are you gonna do about it, Whitey?
Just sit there?
Go back where you came from!
Of course not!
Son of a bitch!
You are going to join with us,
the members of the American Socialist
White People's Party. '
an organization of decent,
law-abiding white folk
just like you.
Blow it out your ass,
you bastards!
Go to hell!
I pledge allegiance to Adolf Hitler.
The immortal leader of our race.
To the order for which he stands.
And to the order for which he stands.
One great cause.
Sacred and invincible.
Hey, what's going on?
Those bums won their court case,
so they're marching today.
What bums?
The fucking Nazi Party.
Illinois Nazis.
I hate Illinois Nazis.
Heil Hitler!
- Heil Hitler!
Ten hut!
Gruppenfhrer!
Yes, sir!
Gruppenfhrer, get that
car's license plate number.
We're gonna kill that son of a bitch.
Boom, boom, DOOITI, DOOITI
Come on home, babe
Oh, come on home
Oh, come on home,
come on home to me, babe
I love you
Come on
come on, come on
Oh, come on home
Come on, I love ya
Hold me
I know
I love you
Look out
When she walk that walk
And talk that talk
And whisper in my ear
Tell me that she love me
I love that talk
That baby talk
When she talk like that
I can't take it like that
Haw, haw, haw, haw
Hey, hey, yeah
Come on home,
pretty babe
Walk your walk
Talk your talk
Talk your talk, baby
Talk
Yeah.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
That was Boom Boom, the song
that I wrote, back in the '50s
No, you didn't.
...was such a big hit.
No, you didn't!
I wrote Boom Boom.
Can I help you, boys?
You got any white bread?
Yes.
I'll have some toasted
white bread, please.
You want butter or jam
on that toast, honey?
No, ma'am. Dry.
Got any fried chicken?
Best damn chicken in the state.
- Bring me four fried chickens and a Coke.
You want chicken wings or chicken legs?
- Four fried chickens and a Coke.
And some dry white toast, please.
You all want anything to drink with that?
- No, ma'am. - A Coke.
Be up in a minute.
We got two honkies out there
dressed like Hasidic diamond merchants.
Say what?
They look like they're from
the CIA or something.
What they wanna eat?
The tall one wants white bread. Toast.
Dry. With nothing on it.
Elwood!
And the other one wants four
whole fried chickens and a Coke.
And Jake! Shit!
The Blues Brothers!
Hi, Jake.
Matt! How you doing?
How you doing?
How was Joliet?
Oh, it's bad.
On Thursday night they serve
a wicked pepper steak.
Can't be as bad as the cabbage rolls
at the Terre Haute Federal Pen.
Or that oatmeal at the Cook County Slammer.
They're all pretty bad.
Matt! Me and Elwood,
we're putting the band back together.
We need you and Blue Lou.
Oh, man. Don't talk that way around here.
My old lady,
she'll kill me.
Ma'am, you gotta understand.
This is a lot bigger
than any domestic problems
you might be experiencing.
Matt, what the hell is he talking about?
- Don't get riled, sugar.
Don't you,
"don't get riled, sugar" me!
Now, you not going back on the road no more.
And you ain't playing any more
two-bit, sleazy dives.
You're living with me now.
And you're not gonna go sliding around
with your old white hoodlum friends.
But, babes!
This is Jake and Elwood!
The Blues Brothers!
They still owe you money, fool!
Ma'am, would it make you feel
any better if you knew that
what we're asking Matt
here to do is a holy thing?
You see,
we're on a mission from God.
Don't you blaspheme in here!
Now, this is my man,
this is my restaurant,
and you two are gonna just
walk right out that door,
without your dry, white toast,
without your four fried chickens
and without Matt "Guitar" Murphy!
Now, you listen to me!
I love you.
But I'm the man and you're the woman.
And I'll make the decisions
concerning my life!
You better think about what you saying.
You better think about the
consequences of your actions.
Oh, shut up, woman!
You better think
- Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Yeah, think
Think, think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
Let's go back
Let's go way on back when
I didn't even know you
You couldn't have been too much more than 10
Just a child
I ain't no psychiatrist
I ain't no doctor with degrees
It don't take too much high IQ
to see what you're doing to me
You better think
Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Think, think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
Oh, freedom
Freedom
Yeah, freedom
Right now, freedom
Freedom
Oh, freedom right now
Hey, think about it
You, think about it
There ain't nothing you could ask
I could answer you, but I won't
But I was gonna change that, I'm not
if you keep doing things I don't
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Damn it
Think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
People walking around every day
playing games and taking scores
Tryin' to make other people lose their mind
Be careful you don't lose yours
Hey, think
Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Think, think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
You need me
Need me
And I need you
Don't you know
Without each other there
ain't nothing either can do
Yeah, think about it, babe
What you trying to do to me
To the bone, man
Think about it right now
Oh, freedom
Freedom
Yeah, freedom
Right now
You, think about it
There ain't nothing you could ask
I can answer you, but I won't
But I was gonna change my mind
if you keep doing things I don't
Yeah, think
Think
Think about what you're trying to do to me
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
You need me
Need me
And I need you
Don't you know
Without each other there
ain't nothing either can do
Yeah, yeah
Think about it, baby
What you're trying
to do to me
To the bone, man
Think about it, baby
Yeah, right on
To the bone
For deepness
To the bone, for deepness
Yeah
To the bone
For deepness, think about it
To the bone, for deepness
Right now
Think about it,
yeah, yeah, yeah
To the bone, for deepness
Think about it
For deepness
Don't give me the blues,
brother, hey
You had better
Stop and think about it
Think
Let's boogie.
Well, go ahead, damn it!
Pardon me, but we do have a strict policy
concerning the handling of the instruments.
An employee of Ray's Music
Exchange must be present.
Now, may I help you?
Ray, it's me. Joliet Jake.
I once rented some column
speakers from you for my band,
The Blues Brothers.
Hey, Ray. it's me, Murph, of
Murph and the Magic Tones.
Remember me?
I bought three Fender amps.
Oh, we sell a lot of amplifiers.
Not like these.
They were beautiful.
Upholstered with thick,
red shag.
Oh, right, right!
I remember now.
As a matter of fact, I'll buy
them all back for $350 a piece.
$350?
I paid $800 each,
not 6 months ago.
Well, you know depreciation, man.
Ray, we're here to buy stuff.
We need pianos,
amps, mikes, the works.
Now, go on! Get!
Breaks my heart,
a boy that young going bad.
Tell me a little about this
electric piano, Ray.
Oh, you have a good eye, my man.
That's the best in the city of Chicago.
How much?
$2,000 and it's yours.
You can take it home with you.
Matter of fact, I'll throw
in the black keys for free.
$2,000 for this chunk of shit?
Come on, Ray!
I mean, really, Ray.
It's used.
There's no action left in this keyboard.
Excuse me.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the action on this piano.
Well, singing about the
fella you've been dancing with
All over the neighborhood
So, why didn't you ask me, baby
Or didn't you think I could?
Well, I know that the
boogaloo is out of sight
But the shingaling's the thing tonight
But if that was you and me out there, baby
I would have shown you how to do it right
Do it right
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Here we go loop de loop
Shake it out, baby
Here we go loop de la
Bend over
Let me see you shake your tailfeather
Come on
Come on Let me see you
shake your tailfeather
Come on
Come on, baby
Yeah, come on, baby
All right
Do the twist
Do the fly
Do the swim
And do the bird
Do the duck
Do the monkey
Watusi
And what about the frug
Do the mashed potato
What about the boogaloo
The Bony Maronie
Come on, let's do the twist
Ah, twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Twisting
Okay, man.
We'll take
these axes.
Naturally. And as usual,
I gotta take an IOU.
You guys go inside,
get yourselves a bite.
I've got to
make a phone call.
Now, Jake, does this phone
call concern our first gig?
Have I ever lied to you?
What are we gonna do, man?
We don't got no gig.
How much money you got?
I got a quarter.
That's enough for a phone call. Come on.
What are you doing, Elwood?
You said we were gonna make a call.
I said I was gonna make a call.
Who are you gonna call, Jake?
Do you remember Maury Sline?
Sline? Booking agent?
What about him?
He got us some good showcases in the old days.
He got us the Morgan Park,
he got us the Tick Took.
I got him laid.
He owes me.
Give it a shot.
Hey, Jake.
There's got to be at least
$7 worth of change here.
Yeah?
Sir.
What did you find out?
Okay.
I called a friend at
the Motor Vehicle Department.
That license plate is like a
rash all over the computer.
The car belongs to a known traffic menace.
What's his name?
His name is Elwood Blues.
He's got a record a mile long.
And he's a Catholic.
Did you get his address?
- Of course.
1060 West Addison.
Let's go.
Anybody with that kind of record
is gonna make a mistake.
I want all party members in the tri-state
district to monitor the city, county,
and state police on their C.B's.
Mr. Blues is gonna fuck up.
And when he does,
he better pray the police
get to him before we do.
All right, man.
We've been in this car
for three hours now.
Where the hell is this place?
I told you it'd take
a little while to get there.
What's the name of the place?
Uh, the name of the place is, uh,
Bob's Country Bunker.
Here we are.
Bob's Country Bunker?
Jake,
the sign says,
"Tonight only, the Good Ole Boys. "
Blues Brothers!
It should read,
"Tonight only,
"the Blues Brothers' triumphant return. "
Must be some kind of mistake.
You guys unload the stuff.
Elwood, come with me.
What can I get you boys?
You thirsty, you hungry
or just driving through?
Maybe you'd like a beer,
or something a little harder?
We happen to make the
state's best pepper steak.
No, thank you, ma'am!
We may be sucking back a few
beers a little later on.
We'll be here all night.
You see, we're the band.
You are?
Oh, gee, that's nice!
Hey, Bob,
this is the band!
All right!
What kind of music
do you usually have here?
We got both kinds.
We got country and western.
Jake, are you sure
this is the place?
Yeah! Sure!
This is the place.
Hi! You the Good Ole Boys?
That's us!
The rest of the band's
out in the parking lot
getting our stuff together.
Well, I'm sure glad
to have you boys here.
I'm Bob and this here is my place.
It's a beautiful place, Bob!
I guess you wanna get your
steel guitars and everything
set up on stage,
don't you?
Claire, go and turn those stage lights on
and get these boys going up there.
Chicken wire?
What do you say we set up for sound check?
Excuse me, sonny,
I guess I'll give this to you.
You're the tallest one.
Okay, what is it?
Well, that there is a list of the songs
you boys will be playing tonight.
Man, I don't think we know any
of the songs on this list.
This list doesn't mean anything.
They're just requests.
Do our regular set.
First tune!
Give Me Some Loving.
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
What are those damn freak
pecker heads playing?
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
We're glad to be here
in Kokomo tonight.
We're the Good Old Blues
Brothers Boys Band from Chicago.
We sure hope you'll like our show.
I'm Elwood.
This is my brother Jake.
Well, my temperature's rising
and my feet on the floor
Crazy people knockin'
'Cause they wanted some more
Let me in, baby
I don't know what you got
You better take it easy
'Cause this place is hot
And I'm so glad you made it
That ain't no Hank Williams song!
Give me some loving
Get off the stage!
Every day
Why'd they turn off the lights?
Maybe they blew a fuse.
I don't think so, man.
Those lights are off on purpose.
We gotta figure out something
these people like, and fast!
I got it.
Remember the theme from Rawhide?
The old favorite.
Rowdy Yates.
What key?
A.
Good country key.
Rawhide in A.
Rollin ', rollin ', rollin'
Though the streams are swollen
Keep them dogies rollin'
Rawhide
The rain and wind and weather
Hellbent for leather
Wishin' my gal was by my side
All the things I'm missin'
Good vittles,
love and kissin'
Are waiting at the end of my ride
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, Rawhide
Move 'em on
Head 'em up
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in,
Rawhide
Yah!
Theme from the TV show Rawhide.
Thank you.
We'd like to do a favorite
of the horn section.
We hope it's one of yours.
Sometimes it's hard to be a woman
Giving all your love
To just one man
And if you love him
Oh, be proud of him
'Cause after all
He's just a man
Stand by your man
Give him two arms to cling to
And something warm to come to
When nights are cold and lonely
Stand by your man
And tell the world you love him
Keep giving all the love you can
Stand by your man
And show the world you love him
Keep giving all the love you can
Baby
Stand by your man
Well, folks, it's time to call it a night.
But do what you feel, and
keep both feet on the wheel.
You don't have to go home
but you can't stay here.
So, till next time:
Move 'em on Head 'em up
Head 'em up
Move 'em on
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, Rawhide
Rawhide
Let's get the hell
out of here.
Shit, I wanna tell you boys that's some
of the best goddamn music we've had
at the Country Bunker in a longtime.
Sorry we couldn't remember
The Wreck of the Old 97.
Why, hell!
You guys can learn it next
time when you come back.
Bob, about our money for tonight.
That's right.
$200
and you boys drank $300 worth of beer.
When we first came in the bar lady
never charged us for the first round
so, like, we figured beer was
complimentary for the band.
Beer was, like, complimentary
for the band, you know.
No.
Well, I'll just go out and take up
a collection from the boys.
Well, I'll tell you,
I sure would appreciate it.
I say this trip is nowhere, man.
I say we gotta quit.
What? Quit?
Well, I wish you guys
would make up your mind.
Otherwise, I've gotta call Mr. Ronzini
at the Holiday Inn and
get our old gig back.
Back at the Armada Room?
Listen, they want us to pay
for the beer we drank.
So you guys better split.
The next gig is
gonna be dynamite!
Huge! You'll see.
I say we give The Blues Brothers
just one more chance.
Why not?
If the shit fits, wear it!
Scoot over, goddamn it!
Boys look a little upset.
Hey, man. Don't worry.
We got a couple of days.
We'll get the Penguin's tax money.
I mean, look.
We got an appointment
to see Mr. Sline tomorrow.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Let's skate.
Goddamn it.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Are you The Good Ole Boys?
Yeah, that's right.
I'm Tucker McElroy,
lead singer,
driver of the Winnebago.
I'd like to talk to you,
but we're running very late.
My name is Jacob Stein,
American Federation
of Musicians Union,
Local 200.
I've been sent here to see if you
gentlemen are carrying your permits.
Our what?
Your union cards.
May I see your cards, please?
Suppose we ain't got no union cards
and we go in and start playing anyway.
What you gonna do about that?
You gonna stop us? Stein?
You gonna look pretty funny trying to eat
corn on the cob with no fucking teeth!
Listen,
let me talk to Bob,
the owner.
See if we can put your band
on contract waivers for tonight.
I don't want you to move from this spot.
- Just let me handle this.
We'll, uh...
We'll talk to Bob.
Get in the car and start her up.
You know you boys owe me a lot of money
for that beer you drank tonight!
Goddamn it!
Bob, we loved playing here tonight.
My brother's writing out
an American Express traveler's cheque
to cover the extensive bar tab.
Well, I sure would appreciate it.
I'd better check up,
see how he's doing.
See, I have to sign it, too.
I usually sit in the car and write it out
on the, uh, glove compartment lid.
Okay?
I need a pencil.
Were them guys from the union?
Union?
What the hell union?
Those boys skipped out of here
owing me a lot of money for beer.
What the hell are you guys
all dressed up for?
We're The Good Ole Boys!
You're The Good Ole Boys?
A.F.M. Shit!
Our Lady of Blessed Acceleration,
don't fail me now!
I don't believe it!
It's that shitbox Dodge again.
The bastards are ours now!
Holy shit!
Boys, you're in big trouble.
Maury, you owe me.
We'll play anywhere,
anytime, for anybody.
Put us in, uh,
the Double Up Lounge,
or the Morgan Park Theater,
or the Crystal.
We always knocked them
dead in those joints.
Discos.
They're all discos.
Singles.
Mixed singles, gay singles.
Those people like to tumble and carry on.
They like to dance with each other.
We are a dance band.
I don't know, boys.
I just don't know.
Times have changed,
you know what I mean?
What are you guys gonna do?
The same act?
You wear the same farchadat suits.
You'll scare people away.
Don't you ever wear blue jeans or jumpsuits
like Wayne Cochran and the C.C. Riders?
You gotta come through for us.
We need $5,000, fast.
$5,000?
Who do you think you are?
The Beatles?
You know the size hall you gotta
work to take in that kind of money?
We'll fill any hall in the country.
You guys familiar with
the Palace Hotel ballroom?
Never heard of it.
Nice place up north.
Built in the '40s on Lake Wazapamani.
That seats 5,000.
You guys fill that place,
you can make $5,000, easy.
Book us for tomorrow night.
Hold it!
Tomorrow night?
A gig like that, you gotta
prepare the proper exploitation.
I know about that stuff.
I been exploited all my life.
Forget it. There's no way with you guys.
Forget about it.
Say, how's Mrs. Sline?
I might have some information
she'd like to know.
You blackmailing me?
If you wanna put it that way.
Maury, we need this gig!
We're on a mission from God.
You get us the hall, and I guarantee
we'll pack them in from miles around.
What do you say?
Okay. I'll get you the Palace Hotel.
I'll print up showbills.
I'll make
the place look real pretty, okay?
I don't think you guys
are gonna gross dollar one.
But if you do, I want a
taste of the gate, okay?
Thanks, Maury.
Let's go, boys!
Listen,
you boys heard me talk about Jake and Elwood.
Well, they used to live here,
just like you.
And I used to sing to them,
just like with you.
Tonight,
Jake and Elwood are
going out to sing and play
to raise money to help you children.
Your lazy butts are in this, too!
So get up on that wagon.
We're going up north
to put the word in the streets.
Tonight only,
the fabulous Blues Brothers,
Rhythm and Blues Revue
at the Palace Hotel ballroom,
Route 16,
Lake Wazapamani.
The fabulous Blues Brothers,
Show Band and Revue.
There you go, boy.
All right, man!
Check it out!
Tonight only!
From Chicago!
The Blues Brothers.
Rhythm and Blues Revue.
One night only!
The fabulous...
Blues Brothers Show Band and Revue.
You!
On the motorcycle!
You two girls!
Tell your friends!
Free parking.
$2 cover charge only, folks!
That's a lot of entertainment.
For $2.
Will you please put this
in the window, lady,
because it's real important.
Tonight only, from Chicago,
the fabulous Blues Brothers,
Rhythm and Blues Revue,
for your dancing pleasure.
And it's ladies' night tonight
at the Palace Hotel ballroom.
"Tonight only, the Blues Brothers,
"genuine Rhythm and Blues Show and Revue.
"Palace Hotel ballroom.
Tonight only. "
How we doing?
So far we covered Lake, McHenry
and part of DuPage County.
Good.
Let's get to the gig.
What is it?
We're out of gas.
Oh, shit.
Wow, a classic.
What a room!
This place is gonna swing tonight.
It's a fucking barn.
We'll never fill it.
We've gotta fill this hall tonight.
A lot of young children are depending on it.
Young children?
Why, what do you mean?
Jake and Elwood are donating the
band's share of the door money
to pay the taxes on the Saint
Helen's Orphanage in Calumet City.
What?
We're out of gas.
Yep.
Mind if we fill her up?
Nope.
I said we're out of gas.
Tanker truck's late.
Should have been here two hours ago.
Uh, it's always late on Thursdays.
I guess we'll have to wait.
Yeah.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, you. Could you fill it up with premium,
please, and check under the hood?
Sure.
You, uh, want I should, uh,
wash the dead bugs off the windshield?
Oh, no. Don't worry.
I'm in kind of a hurry.
Where in the hell are they?
So, uh, maybe you'd like to come by
and see the show.
Oh, um, I'm awfully sorry,
but I do have a prior dinner engagement.
Thanks, Marvin.
Debbie, get me Troopers Daniel and Mount.
I don't see those Blues Brothers.
We'll wait.
Okay, you're all set.
That'll be, uh, $94.
Here's $95.
Thank you, Elwood.
Okay.
And that's $1 change.
Oh, keep the change.
Oh, thanks.
Uh, so, look.
Uh, if your date
don't work out tonight for any reason,
there's a motel up on the interstate.
Uh, maybe we could,
say, uh, meet
around, uh, midnight?
I'll think about it,
Elwood, okay?
Bye.
Son of a bitch!
Come on!
We're really late.
You better step on it, man.
Yeah.
I always like to perform for angry mobs.
You can't quit now.
What can they be doing?
My head hurts.
That Night Train's a mean wine.
You'd better get bright!
We got a show to do.
Then we gotta figure out some
way to collect that gate money,
get it to the Cook County
Assessor's office
as soon as they open in the morning.
We want the show!
Gentlemen,
I'm leaving.
Man, we were so close.
Hey, you guys know Minnie The Moocher?
I knew a hooker once named Minnie Mazola.
No! The song Minnie the Moocher.
Yeah. So what?
Hit it!
Hey folks here's a story 'bout
Minnie the Moocher
She was a low-down hoochie coocher
She was the roughest toughest frail
But Minnie had a heart
As big as a whale
She messed around with a bloke named Smokey
She loved him though he was cokey
He took her down to Chinatown
And he showed her how
to kick the gong around
She had a dream about the King of Sweden
He gave her things that she was needin'
He gave her a home built of gold and steel
A diamond car with the platinum wheels
This is glue.
Strong stuff.
What the hell
are you doing?
This can is from a surplus disposal run.
Fifteen overcharged ounces
of pure uncompounded isoproponyl
butane monosulphide.
When combined with oxygen
and a little heat
it will cause a rapid expansion.
Poor Min, poor Min
Poor Min
Okay, let's take them!
Wait a minute.
I've never even heard these
boys sing, all right?
All right.
They're not going no place.
All right, cover all exits!
Let's go! Come on! Hurry up!
Move it!
Who wants an Orange Whip?
Orange Whip?
Three Orange Whips.
Excuse us.
Good evening, ladies.
One, two. One, two, three, four.
Now, ladies and gentlemen
it is the distinct pleasure of
the management to present to you
the evening's star attraction.
Here they are, back after their
exclusive three-year tour
of Europe, Scandinavia and the Subcontinent.
Won't you welcome, from
Calumet City, Illinois,
the show band of Joliet
Jake and Elwood Blues.
The Blues Brothers!
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
We're so glad to see so many of
you lovely people here tonight.
We'd especially like to welcome
all the representatives
of Illinois' law enforcement community,
who have chosen to join us here
in the Palace Hotel ballroom at this time.
We certainly hope you all enjoy the show.
And remember that no matter who you are
and what you do to live,
thrive and survive
there're still some things
that make us all the same.
You. Me. Them.
Everybody.
Everybody
Needs somebody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugar to kiss
I need you
I need you, you, you
In the morning
You
When my soul's on fire
Sometimes I feel
I feel a little sad inside
When my baby mistreats me
I never; never find a
place to hide I need you
Sometimes I feel
I feel a little sad inside
When my baby mistreats me
I never never find a
place to hide I need you
People, when you do find
that special somebody,
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman,
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
Signify your feelings
with every gentle caress
because it's so important
to have that special somebody
to hold, to kiss,
to miss,
to squeeze and please!
Everybody needs somebody
Everybody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugar to kiss
I need you
In the morning
When my soul's on fire
When there ain't no
one around I need you
I need you, you, you
I need you
Thank you.
That was for Wilson Pickett.
This is dedicated to the
late, great Magic Sam.
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
Come on baby don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
Six and three is nine
Nine and nine is 18
Look there brother baby
and you'll see what I seen
Baby, don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
Come on
Baby, don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
The Mafia's after us now.
You guys were hot!
You were great! Insane.
I've got to record you.
Bullshit.
Bullshit?
I don't bullshit.
I'm president of Clarion Records
the largest recording company
on the Eastern seaboard.
So what?
Here's $10,000.
An advance on your first recording session.
Is it a deal?
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal.
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal!
Listen, all these cops out here,
they're sort of waiting for us.
We gotta get out with nobody seeing us.
You know a back door out?
Sure. I used to be head bouncer
here back in the '70s.
There's an electrical service duct
right behind your drummer's riser.
Do us a favor.
Take $1,400
and give it to Ray's Music
Exchange in Calumet City
and give the rest to the band.
You got it.
Thanks.
Me and Elwood are gonna make a break for it.
You and the band keep playing.
Something's wrong.
Where's Jake?
Where'd those Blues Brothers go?
I sure hope this thing leads someplace.
Elwood,
we're gone, man.
Who is that girl?
Well, Jake.
You look just fine down there
slithering in the mud like vermin.
No problem.
You're not gonna get away from me this time.
Check that out!
Let's go!
It's good to see you,
sweetheart!
You contemptable pig.
I remained celibate for you.
I stood at the back of a cathedral
waiting,
in celibacy, for you
with 300 friends and relatives in attendance.
My uncle hired the best
Romanian caterers in the state.
To obtain the seven limousines
for the wedding party
my father used up his last favors
with Mad Pete Trullo.
So for me, for my mother,
my grandmother,
my father, my uncle,
and for the common good
I must now kill you and your brother.
Oh, please don't kill us!
Please, please, don't kill us.
You know I love you, baby!
I wouldn't leave you!
It wasn't my fault!
You miserable slug!
You think you can talk
your way out of this?
You betrayed me!
No, I didn't. Honest!
I ran out of gas!
I had a flat tire!
I didn't have enough money for cab fare!
My tux didn't come
back from the cleaners.
And old friend came in from out of town!
Someone stole my car!
There was an earthquake!
A terrible flood!
Locusts! It wasn't my fault,
I swear to God!
Oh, Jake...
Jake, honey.
Let's go.
Take it easy.
You're going to totally
demolish the cars.
You want to maybe consider going
after the Blues Brothers?
It's 106 miles to Chicago.
We got a full tank of gas,
half a pack of cigarettes,
it's dark, and we're wearing sunglasses.
Hit it.
Shit, man. Can't this damn
thing go any faster than this?
Bob, I think I've got a little problem.
Goddamn, boy.
Don't you say a fucking word.
All units,
we have a signal 10-79.
Officers are in pursuit:
a black-and-white 1974 Dodge sedan
southbound on 47.
Respond to signal 10-79.
Occupants of vehicle:
one Joliet Jake Blues,
one Elwood Blues.
Considered extremely dangerous.
Gruppenfhrer!
Hey, Jake,
I gotta pull over.
Southbound on State Highway 47.
Hi! Wanna hand me the mike?
Thanks a lot.
This is car...
What number are we?
55.
Car 55.
We're in a truck.
Signal 10-79 still engaged.
Vehicle traveling southbound
approaching Chicago city limits.
Commander advises will contact Chicago
precincts for a local intercept.
Maintain pursuit.
Use of unnecessary violence in the apprehension
of the Blues Brothers has been approved.
Well, this is definitely Lower Wacker Drive.
If my estimations are correct
we should be very close to
the Honorable Richard J. Daley Plaza.
That's where they got that Picasso.
Yep.
Son of a bitch!
There they are.
Oh, no!
What the fuck was that?
The motor.
it's thrown a rod.
Is that serious?
Yep.
Faster.
Holy shit!
I've always loved you.
There it is!
Come on!
Sir, where's the office of
the Assessor of Cook County?
Down the hall,
turn right.
Take the elevator to 1102.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse me.
Did you see two guys come in here
with black suits and hats,
one carrying a briefcase?
Yeah, I just sent them down there.
Thank you.
Hold the door.
Let's go.
Can I help you?
This is where they pay the taxes, right?
Right.
This money is for the year's assessment on
the Saint Helen of the Blessed Shroud Orphanage
in Calumet City, Illinois.
$5,000.
It's all there, pal.
Stand back!
Fire!
And here is your receipt.
Warden threw a party in the county jail
Prison band was there and they began to wail
The band was jumping and the joint began to swing
You should have heard those
knocked-out jailbirds sing
Let's rock
Everybody let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Spider Murphy played the tenor saxophone
Little Joe was blowing on the slide trombone
The drummer boy from Illinois
went crash, boom, bang
The whole rhythm section was the Purple Gang
Let's rock Everybody let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
They were dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
They were dancing,
dancing, dancing, dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They were dancing to the jailhouse rock
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They were dancing to the jailhouse rock
Sad Sack was sitting on a block of stone
Way over in the corner weeping all alone
The warden said buddy
don't you be no square
if you can't get a partner
use a wooden chair
Let's rock
Everybody let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock yeah
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
They was dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
They were dancing,
dancing, dancing, dancing
Dancing to the jailhouse rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
People, when you do
find that special somebody,
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman,
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
Signify your feelings
with every gentle caress,
because it's so important
to have that special somebody
to hold, to kiss,
to miss,
to squeeze and please!
Edit: r3p0