One, two, three, four.
Hey, Maggio! Hello!
Hiya, Prew.
What are you doing over here?
Transferred over from Fort Shafter.
-You quit the Bugle Corps?
-Yup.
For here?
l didn't pick it.
You made a very bad mistake.
This outfit, they can give back Custer.
Yeah?
Captain ain't in yet.
l'll look around.
What do you think you're doing?
-What's your name?
-Prewitt. Transfer from Fort Shafter.
l heard about you.
l heard about you, too, Sergeant.
This here's a rifle outfit, Prewitt.
You ain't supposed to enjoy yourself
before sundown.
Put up your cue and come along.
Grand went to the hospital yesterday.
You put him in the sick book?
-Didn't have time.
-You're the company clerk, Mazzioli.
The medics returned the sick book
late yesterday. l'll do it now.
Thanks, l already done it for you.
You're the best bugler
they got over at Shafter.
-You're the best bugler on this island.
-That's true.
l feel for you, pal.
But from my position,
l can't quite reach you.
Ten-hut!
At ease.
-'Morning, sir.
-'Morning, men.
Anything special for me?
l've only a few minutes.
Yes, sir. New man here.
Oh, yes. Come in.
Private Robert E. Lee Prewitt, reporting
to the Company Commander, as ordered.
At ease. Where's that service record?
''Born in Kentucky.
Enlisted first at Fort Meyer, Virginia.
''Bugle Corps, First Bugler.''
Prewitt, l always make it a policy
to talk to my new men.
Now, l have a fine, smooth-running outfit.
lf l like a soldier, he can become
a non-commissioned officer quickly.
But he has to show me
that he's got it on the ball.
What trouble were you in,
in the Bugle Corps?
No trouble, sir.
What made you transfer out, then?
lt was a personal matter.
-Something you wanted to ask, Sergeant?
-Why, yes, sir.
Prewitt, you was a corporal
in the Bugle Corps.
You took a bust to buck private
to transfer to an infantry outfit. Why?
Because you like to hike, or was it
because you couldn't stand to bugle?
lt was a personal matter.
That's up to the Company Commander
to decide.
Well?
l was First Bugler for two years.
The Top Kick had a friend
who transferred in from another outfit.
The next day he was made
First Bugler over me.
l was a better bugler.
And you asked out on account of that?
Maybe it ain't sensible,
but that's the reason.
His feelings were hurt.
Kids they send us now!
We'll get your stripes back for you,
maybe an extra one for good measure.
-Know why you're assigned to G Company?
-No, sir.
l pulled a few strings. l'm the regimental
boxing coach, you know.
Yes, sir.
l saw your fight with Connors in the Bowl
year before last. You should have won.
Thank you, sir.
Our regiment got beaten in the finals
last December, but l mean to win this year.
All l've needed is a top middleweight.
l'm sorry, sir. l quit fighting.
Quit fighting? When? What for?
Well, over a year ago.
Maybe you heard about what happened
with Dixie Wells?
-You mean that fellow that got hurt?
-Yes, sir.
Yes, l heard about that. lt's too bad.
l can understand how you feel,
but those things happen.
That's why l decided l would quit, sir.
You might as well say stop war
because one man got killed.
Our fighting programme
is the best morale builder we have.
l've got a mighty sour company bugler.
How'd you like the job?
Not if it means fighting.
Looks to me as if you're trying to acquire
a reputation as a lone wolf.
You should know that in the Army
it's not the individual that counts.
You'll find that we won't put
any pressure on you in my outfit.
Just don't make any mistakes in it,
that's all.
l'm going to town.
Anything else, Sergeant?
Company fund report's due tomorrow.
-You make it out. ls that all?
-No, sir.
Whatever it is, you fix it up.
lf anything has to go in this afternoon,
sign my name.
-l won't be back.
-Yes, sir.
He'd strangle in his own spit
if l wasn't here to swab his throat out.
Come on.
You been in the Army what now?
Five years? Five and a half?
Yeah.
Don't you think it's about time
you got smart?
You know what you did just now,
turning down Dynamite Holmes?
You put your head in the noose.
Things are soft for a boxer in this outfit.
Otherwise, you better know how to soldier.
l can soldier with any man.
This place is getting to be like
the Royal Hawaiian Hotel.
-Who's that?
-She's Captain Holmes' wife.
You'll fight, Prewitt, because
Captain Holmes wants to be Major Holmes.
He's got an idea he'll make it
if he gets a winning team.
lf you don't do it for him, do it for me.
'Cause my job is to keep him happy, see?
More he's happy, the less he bothers me,
and the better l run this company.
So, we know where we stand,
don't we, kid?
l know where l stand.
A man don't go his own way he's nothing.
Maybe back in the days of the pioneers
a man could go his own way.
But today, you got to play ball.
Leva!
Can't l once find you in the supply room
working with both hands?
l can't do no better
on what you people pay me.
Draw this man some supplies.
G Company squad room is on the top floor.
Take your bags then come here.
Leva will help you lug your stuff upstairs.
Save you making four or five trips.
Thanks.
l just hate to see energy wasted.
Besides, you'll be needing yours.
Looks like a good man.
l know his type. He's a hardhead.
Her and them sweaters.
l'll bet she's colder than an iceberg.
Not her, Top. She knows the score.
Like l been telling you.
ls that right?
Not around here, but when l soldiered
at Fort Bliss, l heard plenty about this lady.
-You did?
-Okay, not me.
But l know some of the guys
she played around with, so don't tell me.
l'm not telling you. You're telling me.
-Good morning, Sergeant.
-'Morning, ma'am.
l'm looking for my husband.
Captain Holmes just went into town.
On business.
He was to have left some things for me.
Do you know about them?
No, l don't, ma'am.
Anything l can do for you?
No, thanks.
l'd be glad to help, ma'am.
My husband's been telling me
a lot about you, Sergeant.
He says you're very efficient.
Yes, ma'am.
What is it that makes you
so efficient, Sergeant?
l was born smart, ma'am.
l love that.
Well, good-bye, Sergeant.
Man, she sure is one, ain't she?
One what?
One woman.
l've seen better.
Karen?
-Sorry l'm late.
-lt doesn't matter.
l got tied up with General Slater.
l bumped into him in the Officers' Club.
Yeah? What did the General have to say?
Success, he said.
Success in war, success in peacetime.
Not a word about my promotion.
Sometimes l think the old man's
just waiting to ship me down.
Less time buttering generals
and more with your company...
-...maybe you'd get that promotion.
-The company takes care of itself.
l went over there today looking for you.
l had some business to attend to
at Kaneohe.
That was all right, wasn't it?
Of course.
l've no right to inquire into your actions.
That was our agreement.
Then why bring it up?
Because l wanted you to know l'm not
as stupid as you maintain all women are.
Now, just what does that mean?
What are you accusing me of now?
Of nothing.
lt's no longer my business
how many women you go out with.
But l wish you could just be honest
about it once.
No reason l should try to hide anything,
is there...
...the way things are between us now?
What right have you
to always be accusing me?
What right?
Are you going back to that again?
How long will it be, l wonder,
before l'm allowed to live that down?
How many times must l say
it was an accident?
Please, Dana.
l'm going to bed.
Please get out of my bedroom.
Captain Holmes says you don't want
to come out and fight for us.
That's right.
We thought we'd buy you a beer
and talk it over.
We're the company boxers.
l figured.
What l wouldn't give to have this guy
in a corner poolroom in my hometown!
lf you box as good as you used to,
we'd be a cinch this year.
You ain't forget, division champs
get ten-day furloughs, did you, son?
l'm lke Galovitch.
Platoon guide of your platoon.
And don't think
you're a tough guy, Prewitt.
You no talk now, but out in the field
with us you sing different song.
He don't have to fight if he don't want
without being kicked around.
We're playing pool. Take off.
-You want busted head, Maggio?
-No.
Then keep your big nose out altogether.
Training starts next week.
Pick up your stuff--
Look, l told Holmes and l'm telling you...
...l ain't fighting. l quit fighting!
You guys want to put the screws on,
go right ahead.
l can take anything you can dish out.
Okay, Prewitt.
Thanks.
l just hate to see a good guy
get it in the gut.
You'd better get used to it, kid.
You'll probably see a lot of it
before you die.
You don't scare easy, do you, Prewitt?
You know anything in Army regulation
says l got to box?
Every boxer in this outfit's a non-com.
l guess you've never seen
a bunch of them get together...
...and give a man ''The Treatment.''
What do you mean ''chick''? She's 45.
She's still too young for you.
l'm a better man than you any day
and don't forget it.
l won't forget it.
What's the deal with him, anyway?
With Warden. l don't figure him.
Warden?
He ain't like the others.
He'll make it tough on you.
But he'll draw himself a line he thinks fair,
and he won't come over it.
You don't see many top kicks
like him no more.
He was with the 15th in Shanghai
when they saw their action.
l heard about it
down in the Philippines, even.
All l know is,
he's the best soldier l ever saw.
Count cadence, count!
One, two, three, four.
Prewitt! Get in step!
Hut! Hut!
Prewitt, this is a drill, not a picnic!
Get in step!
Hut! Hut! Hut!
Halt!
Left face!
Prewitt! One step forward. March!
You march like a drunken gooney bird.
l got to teach you how to drill. Stay here.
Platoon, dismissed!
Detail, right face!
Detail, forward march!
Half left march!
Half right march!
Assemble your weapons.
All right, start.
A rifle's your best friend.
ln the case it jams in combat,
could mean life or death.
You got to learn to strip them down
and put them back together, blindfolded.
Your rear sight's way off!
You'd be 50 feet off-target at 300 yards.
That's what happens when a soldier
don't know how to assemble his rifle.
Seven laps around the track, double time.
Keep the rifle at high port!
Wide open, huh, Prewitt?
Maybe seven more laps
will teach you to watch yourself.
Are you crazy? l saw what you did.
Nothing but trouble.
Better keep your mind off her.
What do you wanna do,
wind up in Leavenworth?
l won't be back in time to take retreat.
Or reveille, either.
All work and no play, Sergeant.
All you do is sit around
sweating over papers.
There are other things in the world
beside work.
You ought to get out
more yourself, Warden.
l've been considering it.
Well, l'm going.
l'm leaving it in your care, Sergeant.
lt'll be here when you get back, sir.
Well, if it isn't Sergeant Warden.
You'd better step inside or you'll get wet.
l am wet.
lf you're looking for the Captain,
he isn't here.
And if l'm not looking for him?
He still isn't here.
l'm looking for him.
You know where he is?
l haven't the slightest idea.
Perhaps he's in town on business.
That's the way you put it
the other day, isn't it?
l got some papers
it's important for him to sign.
l'll try phoning him at the club.
-Maybe he's there.
-Don't do that.
l never like to disturb a man
when he's drinking.
l could use a drink myself.
Do you wanna ask me in?
The liquor's there, Sergeant.
ln the cabinet.
You're taking an awful chance, you know.
My maid is liable to be home anytime.
No, she won't. Thursday's her day off.
You think of everything, don't you?
l try. ln my position, you have to.
Are these really important?
Yes. But not important
they get signed today. Tomorrow's okay.
l got copies at the office.
So it won't be much work to fix them up.
That's what l like about you, Sergeant.
You have confidence.
lt's also what l dislike about you.
lt's not confidence, ma'am.
lt's honesty.
l hate to see a beautiful woman
going to waste.
''Waste'' did you say?
There's a subject
l might tell you something about.
l know several kinds of waste, Sergeant.
You're probably not even remotely aware
of some of them.
Would you like to hear?
For instance,
what about the house without a child?
There's one sort for you.
Then there's another....
You're doing fine, Sergeant.
My husband's off somewhere,
it's raining and we're both drinking now.
You've probably only got one thing wrong:
The lady herself.
The lady's not what she seems.
She's a washout,
if you know what l mean...
...and l'm sure you know what l mean.
You gonna cry?
Not if l can help it.
What are you doing?
l'm leaving. lsn't that what you want?
l don't know, Sergeant.
l don't know.
-Speed it up.
-l'm speeding.
''Payday''
All right, Maggio. You wanna get paid?
Knock it off.
Angelo! A dollar he's wrong, coming up.
Sorry, l already won my bankroll
in the latrine.
Besides, it's a penny-ante game.
Come on, buddy boy, we're going to town.
Look, don't let them get your goat.
We dress up in civvies
and we're as good as the rest of the world.
Here, wear this.
My sister sent it to me.
She buys everything too big.
Look, first we hit a few bars, see?
Then we go to a place where l'm
a member: The New Congress Club.
Girls!
Any prejudices against girls?
That's what l thought.
Well, it looks like you're all primed
for a big night.
Hello, Stark.
-You want some company?
-No, thanks. All tied up.
Leva says you've been eyeing the Captain's
wife like a hound at hunting.
He has, huh?
What else did that character tell you?
She took up with a lot of men
back at Fort Bliss.
l wouldn't put stock in stories like that.
This ain't no story.
Because l was one of them myself.
Not for long, though.
Sure is something strange
about that woman.
Yeah. Thanks for the tip.
See you.
Hello.
-l didn't think you were coming.
-Why not? l ain't late.
No, l guess you're not.
But l got here a little early.
l must have been over-anxious.
-You weren't, though, were you?
-l stopped along the way for a few drinks.
You chose a lovely spot for our meeting.
l've had three chances to be picked up
in five minutes.
That's par for the course around here.
Well, l don't care for it.
l never went in much for back-alley loving.
Take it easy.
You probably think l'm a tramp.
What makes you think
l'd think a thing like that?
Don't try to be gallant.
lf you think this is a mistake,
come right out and say so.
Well, l guess it's about time for me
to be getting home, isn't it?
lsn't it?
What's the matter?
What started all this, anyway?
You think l'd be here
if l thought it was a mistake?
Risking 20 years in Leavenworth
for a date with the Commander's wife?
And her acting like Lady Astor's horse,
and all because l got here on time!
On the other hand,
l've got a bathing suit under my dress.
Me, too.
Why, it's Angelo Maggio.
Greetings, Mrs. Kipfer.
There you are, sweetie-pie.
Dues all paid up.
Who you got playing the piano, a hippo?
Angelo, l don't think l've met your friend.
Private Robert E. Lee Prewitt.
You know how l hate it
when you boys are in this condition.
You see that, buddy boy?
A woman sees a soldier and, like that,
she figures he's drunk.
-You know why?
-Because he is.
Heavy drinking simply doesn't mix
with the entertainment business.
A respectable place
must consider its future.
Mrs. Kipfer, you have my solemn word
your future will be safe with us.
Angelo is one of my favourites.
Annette, dear, take care of this gentleman
for me, will you, please?
That'll be $4, babyface.
$2 for initiation fee,
$2 for this month's dues.
What do l get for it?
Entitlement to all privileges of the club:
Dancing, snack bar, soft drink bar.
Gentlemanly relaxation
with the opposite gender.
So long as they are gentlemen.
No liquor is permitted.
Got it?
l've got it.
Girls, here's some new poison.
This is Billie, Jean and Nancy.
-Nice meeting you.
-Hi, there.
Don't tell me the princess is your style.
This is Suzanne and Roxanne.
Hello, there.
-Would you like to dance, honey?
-Hey!
Much as l adore your company...
...l hope l may be allowed
to tear myself away.
l just saw a few friends at the door.
l can also see that l will be
of no further use to you.
Hi. You busy?
What's your name?
l'm Lorene.
Lorene?
l haven't seen you in here before.
l haven't been in here before.
My friend brought me.
He and l are stationed out at Schofield.
l didn't think you were a soldier.
What do you mean?
-Well, l--
-l'm a 30-year man, in for the whole ride.
l suppose it's different
when a fellow makes a career of it.
Nothing wrong with a soldier
that isn't wrong with everyone else.
l like you just the same.
l liked you the minute
l saw Annette bring you in.
You did?
lt's funny, l came in and stood there
and saw you sitting over here.
Knock it off, buddy.
Put a mute in that thing.
l'll play as loud as l want, you little wop!
''Little wop''?
Mess with me, fatstuff, l'll bust you up.
You must be in a hurry for trouble, wop.
-Wait right here for me, will you?
-Yeah, sure.
l will not have this.
-Mussolini's telling me how to play.
-Busting my eardrums with his noise!
-Let's not be cruel.
-Break it up.
You'll have to go if you can't behave.
Only my friends call me ''wop''!
-You know who that guy is?
-What do l care?
Who is he?
Fatso Judson.
Sergeant of the Guard at the stockade.
Let him alone.
l seen him nearly murder a guy once.
He likes it.
Okay, bullyboy, now you won the war.
Let's dance, huh?
Yeah, we'll dance.
First l got to calm my nerves.
Let's go to a phone booth
where l'll unveil a fifth of whisky...
...l have hidden here
under my loose-flowing sports shirt.
Don't get hurt, pal.
Your balance has got to be letter-perfect.
l thought you were gonna wait?
Bill was telling me about surfboarding.
Hello, friend.
Just sit down and listen.
He describes it thrillingly.
You know anything about surfboarding?
No, nothing. Not a thing.
You must be stationed inland.
At DeRussey l get lots of chances.
Yeah, but we got mountains.
-Know anything about mountain climbing?
-A little bit.
-You a mountain climber?
-No.
-Know about flying a plane?
-l've had a few lessons.
l can't fly, either.
What do you know about deepsea diving?
Bill, shall we move into another room?
Sure. The air in here seems
to have gotten lousy, hasn't it?
-l noticed that.
-Listen, fella.
Come on, let's go.
How's the deepsea diver?
That was a terrible way you acted.
Maybe l was jealous.
You're a funny one.
What do you dames want?
To tease a man to death?
Mrs. Kipfer pays us to be nice
to all the boys.
They're all alike. ls it so important?
lt is important.
We may seem all alike, we ain't all alike.
l'm sorry.
Look....
Let's go sit up in Mrs. Kipfer's parlour.
She lets us use it sometimes
for somebody special.
l'll go ask her.
-Then you're not mad?
-No, l'm not mad.
Because if you're still mad,
l'd just rather we call the whole thing off.
You certainly are a funny one.
l never knew it could be like this.
Nobody ever kissed me the way you do.
Nobody?
No. Nobody.
Not even one? Out of all the men
you've been kissed by?
Now, that'd take some figuring.
How many do you think there have been?
l wouldn't know.
-Can't you give me a rough estimate?
-Not without an adding machine.
Do you have
your adding machine with you?
l forgot to bring it.
Then l guess you won't find out, will you?
Maybe l already know.
What's the matter?
What are you hinting at?
Why? ls there something to hint at?
Maybe there's been a long line
of beach parties.
You must be crazy.
Am l?
What about when you and Holmes
were back at Fort Bliss?
Did you ever hear
of a soldier named Stark?
Maylon Stark?
Why, yes.
''Why, yes.''
You knew him, too, didn't you?
Didn't you?
l had to go and forget
you were like all the rest of them.
Only it's true, ain't it?
Well, ain't it?
Why don't you tell me about it?
Tell me the story.
There's always a story.
You don't leave a person anything, do you?
Come back here, Sergeant.
l'll tell you the story.
You can take it back
to the barracks with you.
l'd only been married to Dana two years
when l found out he was cheating.
But by that time, l was pregnant.
l thought l had something to hope for.
l was almost happy
the night the pains began.
l remember
Dana was going to an officers' conference.
l told him to get home early,
to bring the doctor.
He might have, if his conference
hadn't been with a hatcheck girl.
He was drunk when he came in at 5:00 a.m.
l was lying on the floor.
l begged him to go for the doctor,
but he fell on the couch and passed out.
The baby was born about an hour later.
Of course it was dead.
lt was a boy.
But they worked over me at the hospital,
fixed me up fine.
They even took my appendix out,
threw that in free.
Karen.
And one more thing: No more children.
Sure, l went out with men after that.
And if l'd ever found one that--
Karen, listen to me, listen.
l know.
Until l met you,
l didn't think it was possible either.
l enlisted too.
Came out here on my own
to get away from my hometown in Oregon.
How come?
l had a boyfriend.
l was a waitress, and he was
from the richest family in town.
He just married a girl
suitable for his position.
After three years of going around with me.
A pretty story, isn't it?
Maybe they could write a book about it.
They did. Thousands of them.
So l left and went to Seattle.
When l got there
l met a girl back from Hawaii.
She said she'd made a lot of money there.
So l caught the first boat.
l've been here a year and two months.
You don't like it very much, do you?
Oh, l don't like it. But l don't mind it.
Anyway, l won't be here forever.
No. Sure. l mean, why should you?
l got it all figured out.
ln another year, l'll be back home,
with a stocking full of money.
And l'll be all set for life.
Who is it?
l didn't hear no sounds of combat,
so l thought you might want a drink.
You've been hogging the whisky, Angelo.
Not me, buddy. lt's that Sandra.
She's a nice girl, but she drinks like a fish.
l hope there's a cop under that.
Keep pouring.
No, thanks. l don't drink.
l think it's a weakness.
l grant you that.
l don't like weakness. Do you?
No, l don't like weakness.
But l like to drink.
What are you going to do, marry this guy?
You're grinning at him like you're his wife.
Get out of here!
Okay. l'm going.
Back to old long-legged Sandra.
l love them tall. Acres and acres.
Enjoy yourself, paisan.
You need this more than l do.
Tomorrow you'll be back
with ''The Treatment.''
What does he mean?
That was nice before.
The way you snuggled up in front of him.
What's ''The Treatment''?
Some of the guys putting me
over the jumps 'cause l don't want to fight.
Fight?
Yeah. On the boxing team.
l don't want to box.
l don't even want to think about it.
Why should you have to box?
Well, see, l used to fight, middleweight.
l was pretty good, and they know it.
Well, anyway....
Well, come on. Tell me. l want to hear.
Well, the thing is, see....
l used to work out with this guy,
Dixie Wells.
He's a real good friend of mine.
He loved to box.
People on the outside had their eye on him.
He was gonna come out of the Army
and go right up to the top.
Well, one afternoon...
...he and l were sparring in the gym.
You know, kind of friendly-like.
He must have been set pretty flat
on his feet...
...'cause l caught him...
...with a no-more-than-ordinary right cross.
He didn't get up. He didn't move.
He was in a coma for a week.
Finally, he did pull out of it.
Only, the thing was, he was blind.
l went to see him at the hospital
a couple of times.
Finally, l just couldn't go back.
The last time he and l started talking
about fighting and....
He started to cry.
Seeing tears coming out of those eyes
that couldn't see anything....
l thought l ought to tell you.
Holmes spoke to his boxers last night.
From now on, it's no holds barred.
They aim to run you
right into the stockade if they got to.
Let them.
l'll help you as much as l can.
But l can't go too far out on a limb.
l ain't risking losing my stripes.
l like this outfit.
So do l. That's funny, ain't it?
Yeah, that is funny.
Keep going in a straight line, Prewitt.
Keep going!
All right, that's enough.
Okay, Prewitt, bury it.
Time!
Clean up the mess, Prewitt.
Hurry it up.
You're on fatigue detail, not vacation.
Come on, clean it up!
Clean it up yourself!
What?
You heard me.
Rub your own nose in it a while.
Prewitt, you know better than talk back
to a non-commissioned officer.
Yes, sir, but l've never liked being spit on,
not even by a non-commissioned officer.
You owe Sergeant Galovitch an apology.
l don't think so.
Sergeant Galovitch owes me an apology.
Corporal Peluso?
Have this man roll a full field pack,
extra shoes and helmet.
Take a bicycle and hike him up
to Kole Kole Pass and back.
-Then bring him to me.
-Yes, sir.
All right, Prewitt, let's go.
Time!
Hold it a minute.
Go ahead and have a cigarette.
l don't like this any more than you do.
Thanks.
l take it you're ready to apologise
to Sergeant Galovitch now?
No, sir, l'm not.
Peluso, take him up there again.
Yes, sir. All right, Prewitt, let's go.
You can't be decent to a man like that.
You have to treat him like an animal.
Sergeant, prepare court-martial papers.
lnsubordination
to a non-commissioned officer.
Yes, sir.
Only, it's a shame.
What is?
l was thinking,
too bad you'll lose a good middleweight.
l don't care.
l don't have to tolerate such insolence.
No, sir, you sure don't.
l'll prepare the papers then.
Trouble is,
even if he gets just three months...
...he'll still be in the stockade
for the boxing finals.
Do you see any other way of breaking him?
You could double up
on company punishment, sir.
All right. l'll throw the book at him.
lf you think that's the way to do it.
Nice going, Sarge.
Keep looking, you'll find yourself
scrubbing this orderly room floor!
Coming through! Watch it.
Me and my waiters
are working our tails off.
Hot! Hot! H-O-T!
How you doing, buddy boy?
Better than being thrown in the stockade,
ain't it?
How am l doing, Sarge? l'm a rough man.
Slow up a little, stop sweating in the food.
Don't hold me back, Sarge.
l'm putting in for corporal tomorrow.
You'll never make it.
-Hi, Sarge.
-Hi, Top.
Life in a rifle company.
You look awful tired, kid.
How do you like straight duty?
What makes you think l mind it?
l didn't say you minded it.
l just said you looked tired.
You know, drawn to a fine edge.
l like this life. lt's a great life.
lf l find a pearl, l'll cut you in.
Fifty-fifty. You know what l mean?
lf you didn't put me here,
l'd have no chance to find it, right?
Now, there's a man for you.
What do you know?
Since you like it so much,
l'll see if l can find more for you.
How about garbage detail?
Thanks. l had that on Wednesday.
So, you did. What about street cleaning?
Yesterday.
You got a better memory than me.
Of course, if you were smart....
Yeah, but l ain't smart.
l know. But if you were,
you wouldn't have to pull KP.
Or any other fatigue duty for that matter.
lf you think you can bribe me into boxing,
Warden, you're wrong.
Not you and Dynamite Holmes
and ''The Treatment.''
How long are you guys gonna keep
breaking it off on that kid Prewitt?
You've had him on that extra duty roster
a month already.
-l can't see why you--
-Can't you, Pete?
Getting soft in your old age?
Maybe l want to teach him a lesson.
-Maybe you like it.
-Maybe l do.
l'm getting sick and tired
watching you being a stooge for Holmes.
You won't see it much longer.
l'm getting sick and tired of it myself.
l'm through, Pete.
Any day now. And l mean it.
Listen, if Holmes'd let me,
l'd transfer out of here tomorrow.
Half a dozen companies in this regiment
would grab me, in grade, too.
Oh, sure. l could be Chief of Staff, too.
Only l just can't think of leaving
my old buddies.
Where're you going, Little Sir Echo?
To take my shower, if the stinking
First Sergeant has no objections.
Where'd you think?
To the movies in this towel?
Hurry up. We'll get some beer.
l wouldn't drink with you
if it was the last beer on Earth.
l'm buying.
That's different.
Do you know why l like
to have you serve me beer?
So as l can watch you
when you walk away.
lt's in regulations.
You got a right to complain.
You've a right to take your case
to the lnspector General.
Any soldier has, even a plain dogface.
Nope. l ain't gonna complain.
They ain't going to get that satisfaction.
This soldier's got a real big family.
Fifteen of them.
'Course this is only half of them.
You see the gentleman
with the handlebars?
That's Mr. Maggio.
Mr. Maggio is my father.
l never saw anyone so stubborn.
-How long since they let you go into town?
-Six weeks.
Liable to be six years.
How'd you like it?
Six years before you see a dame?
Look, why don't you just
mind your own business?
And why don't you learn to play the bugle?
That's my buddy boy!
Who's the broad?
lt's my sister.
You hit me!
Yeah, and l'm about to do it again, too.
Why, you dirty wop!
lf you want to fight, take it outside!
l'll cut this wop's heart out.
Anybody steps in here,
l give it to him first.
One step further, Fatso,
and l'm going to de-brain you.
Nobody's doing nothing.
Anybody does any killing, l'll do it!
lt's a private affair, Warden.
No, it isn't! This man's in my company!
And you ain't making two
extra weeks' paperwork for me for nothing.