You wanna talk about
the vanishing wilderness?
Why are you so anxious about this?
Because they're building a dam
across the Cahulawasse River.
They're gonna flood a whole valley, Bobby.
They're drowning the river, man.
- We're talkin' to you.
- All right.
Just about the last wild, untamed,
unpolluted, unfucked-up river in the South.
- Don't you understand?
- We understand.
There ain't gonna be no more river.
Just gonna be a big, dead lake.
It's a very clean way
to make electric power.
Those lakes provide many people
with recreation.
My father-in-law has a houseboat
on Lake Bowie.
You push a little more power into Atlanta...
... a little more air conditioners
for your smug little suburb...
... and you know what's gonna happen?
They're gonna rape this whole landscape.
They're gonna rape it.
- That's an extreme point of view, Lewis.
- It is.
Extremist.
We're gonna leave Friday from Atlanta.
I'm gonna have you back
in your little suburban house...
... in time to see the football game
on Sunday afternoon.
I know you'll be back in time to see
the pompom girls at halftime.
I know that's all you care about.
Lewis, I wanna thank you.
Is there any hillbillies up here?
Yeah, there's some people up there
that ain't never seen a town before.
No bigger than Aintry, anyway.
Them, those woods, are real deep.
The river's inaccessible,
except at a couple of points.
How we gonna get there, Lewis?
I'm gonna take you there.
What the hell do you know about canoein'?
I know enough about canoein'
to handle the both of you.
I don't know what that means,
but I'll go along with you.
This is the last chance we got
to see this river.
Just wait until you feel
that white water under you.
- Ain't that right?
- I don't know if I'm ready.
If we are lost, I don't wanna hear about it.
I've never been lost in my life.
I'll have you in the water in another hour.
Christ, Drew!
Drew, look at the junk.
Look here.
I think this is where everything finishes up.
We just may be at the end of the line.
Hey, not so loud, Bobby.
Let's not upset these people.
People?
What people?
This area may be evacuated already.
That's my '51 Dodge.
No, that's my car. That's my car.
All my youth and passion...
...spent in that back seat.
It's all gone you see.
All gone. Rust and dust.
Lewis...
...we got a live one here.
- Howdy.
Let me ask you something.
Are you from the power company?
Power company?
What power company?
About the dam.
No, no, no.
Look, come here a minute.
See that car there?
We want somebody to drive 'em
down to Aintry for us.
Hell, you're crazy.
No shit.
Fill that one up with gas, okay?
Say, mister...
I love the way you wear that hat.
You don't know nothin'.
Lewis, just ask him about his hat.
I don't think you understood me.
I wanna get some drivers...
...to drive this car...
...and that car down to Aintry.
You understand?
You might get the Griner brothers.
- Who?
- The Griner brothers.
Where do they live?
They live back over that way.
$4.99.
Right.
Talk about genetic deficiencies.
Isn't that pitiful?
Who's pickin' the banjo here?
Come on, I'm with you.
I'm lost.
I could play all day with that guy.
I believe you could, too.
I believe you could.
- That's good.
- That's very good, sir.
Goddamn, you play a mean banjo.
Hey, you wanna play another one?
Give him a couple of bucks.
Can that Chubby boy handle himself?
Who? Bobby?
He's rather well thought of
in his field, Lewis.
Insurance?
I've never been insured in my life.
I don't believe in insurance.
There's no risk.
I have some.
Over here.
Shit!
God almighty!
Anything we can do for you?
No. It ain't as bad as I thought.
Your name Griner?
What do you wanna know for?
Can you and your brother drive two cars
down to Aintry for us?
Drive 'em down there for what?
Me and my buddy, we're gonna take
a canoe trip down the Cahulawasse.
We'd like to have them cars in Aintry
when we get there.
Be there by Sunday noon.
Canoe trip?
That's right, a canoe trip.
What the hell you wanna go fuck around
in that river for?
Because it's there.
It's there all right.
You get in there and can't get out,
you gonna wish it wasn't.
Listen, Lewis, let's go back to town and...
...play golf.
I'll give you $30 to take those cars
down to Aintry.
I'd take $50.
$50, my ass.
Lewis, don't play games with these people.
What'd you say?
I said, "$50, my ass."
Lewis!
I'll do it for $40.
You good for $10?
Sure.
You got it.
Brando!
- Lewis, you guys all right?
- All set.
Brando, come on out!
- We heard all this...
- I said it's all set, Drew.
This river cruise gonna happen or not?
Just get in your car, huh?
Lewis, for God's sake!
You think we should let 'em
show us to the river?
If I thought that,
I would have let them go first, Ed.
We know about where it is.
Here we go.
Well, we fucked up.
You better let them show us.
You're missin' the whole point, Ed.
Where are you goin', city boy?
We'll find it.
It's only the biggest fuckin' river
in the state.
We'll find it.
Lewis, you son of a bitch,
why do we have to go so damn fast?
You're gonna like it.
When you see the river,
you're gonna like it.
Jesus Christ!
- Lewis.
- Are you all right?
Lewis, you are gonna kill us both,
you son of a bitch...
...before we ever see any water.
Slow it down, Lewis, come on.
Come on, don't fool around.
Listen, Ed.
Listen.
Hear it?
Sometimes you have to lose yourself
before you can find anything.
Any snakes around here?
This is the one.
There she is.
Looks good.
A couple of more months
and she'll all be gone.
Even up as far as here?
From Aintry on up.
One big, dead lake.
Over here!
Couldn't we have found a harder place
to get in?
- This is steep here, now.
- All right.
- Watch yourself.
- I'm watchin'.
You're losin' glass on your bow.
It's freezin'!
Hell, it'll hold.
What the hell are we gonna do...
...if we come off this river
and our cars aren't there?
They'll be there.
They're rough-lookin' boys, them hillbillies.
You judge people by the way they look.
You can trust 'em.
I'm goin' with you, Ed,
and not with Mr. Lewis Medlock.
I saw how he drives these country roads...
...he don't know nothin' about.
I guess you're gonna be with me, Chubby.
Get them supplies up there.
It's cold!
Put this on.
Looks like my mama's corset or something.
Here you go.
Thank you.
- Okay, let's go.
- I'm comin'.
Can't go in the water
without your paddle, boy.
I coulda went up the river without my oar.
Shit!
If we hit any strong water...
...instead of bare-assin' through it...
- I'm ready.
- Come on.
- I'm comin' on.
I got myself a plump partner here.
We can save ourselves
considerable hardship...
...if we just back water,
talk it out before we make our move.
You got that, boy?
All right, put on your life jacket.
Which way are we goin'?
I think downstream would be a good idea,
don't you?
All right.
You and Bobby see some rocks,
you yell out now, right?
Lewis, is this the way
you get your rocks off?
- Let's go.
- Keep your eyes open, Drew.
- I'll race you.
Keep your eyes open, Robert.
That a boy, that a boy.
Every move you make, call it out.
I'm behind you.
Right. Here we go.
See how fast we can shoot this bush.
What is this?
Is this some fast water we're comin' up to?
All right, Drew,
just get in behind Lewis there.
Look at this!
- Let's pick up some speed.
- All right. Let's go.
Just a little, there you have it.
To the left.
Hey, now, that didn't hurt too bad, did it?
I'm with you, Ed.
Now you got it, boy. Very good.
Look, Ed.
Well, for the Lord's sake,
will you look at that?
What do we do now?
This is gonna be fun!
Just follow us!
Hey, what happens
if we flip this thing over?
Now that you brought that up,
hang on to your paddle.
And if you hit any rocks,
don't hit 'em with your head.
Watch Lewis.
Maybe we can learn something.
Back water now.
Oh, yeah.
Go right.
Go right, go right.
- Look up ahead where you're goin'!
- All right, I'm lookin'.
Don't quit, don't quit.
Come on, paddle, paddle.
Okay!
We did it!
Are you gonna call them out now?
- Right, go right.
- Go right.
All right, now left.
Left, to your left.
All right.
- Keep it straight.
- Watch that tree.
- Left.
- Watch your head.
We ain't gonna make it!
Turn it!
Hey, this doesn't seem right.
Just a little unorthodox.
Go left, Chubby. Come on.
Straighten it out.
All right, I got it straight.
Oh, my God!
- Yes, thank you, Lord.
- Turn it around.
Hold it up there. Slow it down.
All right, go.
Go!
Good, push straight ahead.
Hell, here's a big one!
We're gonna make it. Keep it straight.
I'm with you, Ed!
All right. You're doin' all right, now.
Keep her headed right.
Go, go, go...
There's a rock!
On the right, watch it now.
- Okay, now.
- I got it.
All right now, Chubby, don't fall apart.
What the hell I tell you?
He's something else, ain't he?
- Hold on.
- I'll tell you, Lewis...
...that's the best,
the second best sensation I ever felt.
You did good, Chubby, you did good.
Damn, I thought we'd bought
the farm there for a while.
You know that one place there...
You know what I was just thinking?
The first explorers saw this country...
...saw it just like us.
In a canoe.
I can imagine how they felt.
Yeah, we beat it, didn't we?
Didn't we beat that?
You don't beat it.
You don't beat this river.
Machines are gonna fail.
And the system's gonna fail.
Then...
And then what?
Then survival.
Who has the ability to survive.
That's the game: Survive.
And you can't wait for it to happen,
can you?
You can't wait for it.
Well, the system's done all right by me.
Oh, yeah.
You got a nice job.
Got a nice house...
...nice wife...
...nice kid.
You make that sound...
...rather shitty, Lewis.
Why do you go on these trips with me, Ed?
I like my life, Lewis.
Yeah, but why do you go
on these trips with me?
You know, sometimes I wonder about that.
Here's to you, Lewis.
Hot damn, he got one!
Terrific, Lewis.
I hate him.
I'm glad we came here.
Lewis?
Lewis does not drink.
It's true, Lewis, what you said.
There's somethin' in the woods
and the water that we have lost in the city.
We didn't lose it, just sold it.
Well, I'll say one thing for the system.
System did produce the air mattress.
Or, as it's better known among
we camping types, the instant broad.
And if you fellas will excuse me,
I'm gonna go be mean to my air mattress.
I do baptize thee now,
in the name of modern technology.
How sweet, yeah.
Lewis?
Does he think he is Tarzan, or what?
He knows the woods, though.
He really does.
Not really.
He learned 'em, he doesn't feel 'em.
That's his problem.
He wants to be one with nature
and he can't hack it.
This is a hell of a time to be tellin' us that.
Jesus!
Lewis, you scared the shit out of me!
Oh, who was it, Lewis?
I don't know. I thought I heard something.
Something or someone?
I don't know.
Good night, Lewis.
Good night, Drew.
I'm goin' to sleep.
Night has fallen.
And there's nothin' we can do about it.
I had my first wet dream in a sleepin' bag.
How was it?
Great.
There's no repeatin' it.
Never mind.
No matter what disaster may occur
in other parts of the world...
...or what petty little problems...
...arise in Atlanta...
...no one can find us up here.
Good night, Lewis.
Goddamn it!
Hey, Bobby,
look what came out of the forest.
Get a shot, Ed?
Hell, sometimes a man can...
...hunt for three years...
...never get a shot. Isn't that right, Lewis?
- Right.
I don't understand
how anyone could shoot an animal.
Some people never can, Drew.
I've known tournament archers,
damn good shots.
Never out of the five ring.
Draw down on a live animal
and they get buck fever.
What the hell's that?
Loss of control, psychological.
Who gives a shit?
You take that Chubby boy
with you today, okay?
Hope we can get off this river today.
Don't get too far ahead, now.
No, we'll be takin' it slow.
Easy, easy, my man.
I got eaten alive last night.
My bites have got bites.
I'm a salesman, Ed.
Good morning.
I'm not mad at you, Ed.
Just do me a favor, don't holler at me.
I'm not used to bein' hollered at.
Damn friend of yours screamed at me
all day long yesterday.
Paddle, you son of a bitch.
Look!
What in the hell are Lewis and Drew
doin' up there anyway?
Probably they're doin'
the same thing we are.
Bobby?
How goes it?
What the hell you think you're doing?
Headin' downriver.
Little canoe trip. Headin' for Aintry.
Aintry?
Sure, this river only runs one way, Captain.
Haven't you heard?
You ain't never gonna get down to Aintry.
Why not?
'Cause.
This river don't go to Aintry.
You done taken the wrong turn.
See, this here river don't go nowhere
near Aintry.
Where does it go then?
Boy, you are lost.
Well, hell, I guess this river
comes out somewhere, don't it?
That's where we're going, somewhere.
Look, we don't want any trouble here.
If you gentlemen have a still near here,
that's fine with us.
Why sure. We'd never tell anybody
where it is.
You know something?
You're right, we're lost.
- We don't know where in the hell we are.
- A still?
Right, yeah, you're makin' whiskey up here.
We'll buy some. We could use it.
Do you know what you're talkin' about?
We don't know what you're talking about.
You said something about makin' whiskey.
Ain't that what you said?
We don't know what you're doing,
and we don't care.
That's none of our business.
That's right,
none of your goddamn business.
We've got quite a long journey
ahead of us, gentlemen...
Hold it.
You ain't going no damn where!
This is ridiculous. Excuse me.
Hold it, or I'll blow your guts out
all over these woods.
Wait, we can talk this thing over.
What is it you require of us?
Well, we require that you get
your goddamn ass up in them woods.
- All right, now, look.
- Right now! You get up there now.
Okay, all right.
- Get up there.
- All right.
Faster, boy.
- Move your ass.
- Easy with the weapon!
You shut up.
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Back here.
- What's the trouble?
- You're in trouble.
- Just don't argue with 'em, Ed.
- See that saplin' over yonder?
- You heard him.
Back up against this.
Is this a matter of money?
If we want money, we'll take it.
- Back up against the tree.
- I'm pretty far back against it now.
Now, stay just there. Now, be real still.
If he tries that again, shoot that one there.
I'll blow his damned balls off.
You ain't a big boy.
Be still now.
Now let's you just drop them pants.
Drop?
Just take 'em right off!
I mean, what's this all about?
Don't say anything, just do it.
Just drop 'em, boy!
You ever had your balls cut off,
you fuckin' ape?
Lord.
Look there, that's sharp.
I bet it'd shave a hair.
Why don't you try it and see?
Lord. Deliver us from all...
Pull off that little bitty shirt there, too.
Is he bleeding?
He bled.
Them panties, take 'em off.
Get up, boy!
Come on, get on up there.
No, no, no.
Oh, no. Don't.
- Don't.
- Hey, boy.
- You look just like a hog.
- No, don't.
Just like a hog.
Come here, piggy, piggy, piggy.
Come on, piggy. Come on, piggy.
Come on, piggy, give me a ride.
- Get up and give me a ride.
- All right.
- Get up! Get up there!
Oh, no, no.
Looks like we got us a sow here
instead of a boar.
Don't!
What's the matter, boy?
I bet you squeal.
I bet you can squeal like a pig.
Let's squeal. Squeal now.
Squeal.
Squeal louder. Louder.
Louder.
Louder!
Louder! Get down now, boy!
There, get them britches down.
That's that.
You can do better than that, boy.
Come on, squeal. Squeal!
What's you wanna do with him?
He got a real pretty mouth, ain't he?
That's the truth.
You're gonna do some prayin' for me, boy.
And you better pray good.
Here, hold that on him.
You better run, you son of a bitch!
Can't we do anything for him?
No.
It's a center shot.
I thought they'd surely kill us.
They would have.
They would have for sure.
What we gonna do with him?
There's not but one thing to do:
Take the body down to Aintry.
Turn it over to the highway patrol.
Tell 'em what happened.
Tell 'em what, exactly?
Just what happened.
This is justifiable homicide if anything is.
They were sexually assaulting
two members of our party at gunpoint.
Like you said, there was nothin' else
we could do.
Is he alive?
Not now.
Well, let's get our heads together.
Come on, let's not do anything foolish.
Anybody know anything about the law?
I was on jury duty once.
It wasn't a murder trial.
Murder trial?
I don't know the technical word for it,
Drew, but I know this:
You take this man and turn him over
to the sheriff, there'll be a trial all right.
Trial by jury.
So what?
We killed a man, Drew.
Shot him in the back.
A mountain man.
Cracker.
Gives us somethin' to consider.
All right, consider it. We're listening.
Shit, all these people are related.
I'll be damned if I'll come back
and stand trial...
...with this man's aunt and uncle...
...maybe his mama and his daddy
sittin' in the jury box.
What do you think, Bobby?
How about you, Ed?
I don't know. I really don't know.
Now you listen, Lewis.
I don't know what you got in mind...
...but if you conceal this body,
you'll be charged with murder.
That much law I do know.
This ain't one of your fuckin' games!
You killed somebody!
There he is!
I see him, Drew.
That's right, I killed somebody.
But you're wrong if you don't see this
as a game.
Now you listen, Ed!
Damn it, we can get out of this thing!
Without any questions asked!
We get connected up with that body
and the law...
...this thing's gonna be hangin' over us
the rest of our lives.
We gotta get rid of that guy.
Just how are you gonna do that, Lewis?
Where?
Anywhere.
Everywhere.
Nowhere.
How do you know that other guy
hasn't already gone for the police?
What in the hell is
he gonna tell 'em, Drew?
What he did to Bobby?
Why couldn't he go get
some other mountain men?
Now why isn't he gonna do that?
You look around you, Lewis!
He could be out there anywhere,
watchin' us right now.
We ain't gonna be so goddamned
hard to follow, draggin' a corpse.
You let me worry about that, Drew.
You let me take care of that.
You know what's gonna be here?
Right here. A lake.
As far as you can see.
Hundreds of feet deep.
Did you ever look over a lake...
...and think about somethin' buried
underneath it?
Buried underneath it!
Man, that's about as buried as you can get!
Well, I am telling you, Lewis,
I don't want any part of it.
Well, you are part of it!
It is a matter of the law!
The law?
What law?
Where's the law, Drew?
You believe in democracy, don't you?
Yes, I do.
Well, then, we'll take a vote.
I'll stand by it.
So will you.
What do you say, Bobby?
Let's bury him.
I don't want this gettin' around.
Okay?
It's up to you, Ed.
It's all up to you, Ed.
Now just think what you're doin', Ed.
For God's sake.
You got a wife.
You got a child.
You're not involved in this.
Think about your family, Ed.
This may be the most important decision
of your whole life, Ed.
Yes!
There's no way we can change this.
There's no way we can change
what happened to Bobby.
We gotta do the right thing.
We must live with it for the rest
of our lives.
Right!
I'm with Lewis.
All right, let's get on with it, then.
Lewis. Let's go.
What's the plan, Lewis?
Plan?
We just paddle on down to Aintry,
get the cars and go home.
Put your jacket on, Drew.
Drew!
Put your life jacket on!
Drew, paddle! Drew!
Drew?
Drew, what's the matter?
Lewis, somethin's wrong. To the side.
Something's wrong!
No! Go on!
What is it?
Don't stop, Ed!
- I'm gonna pull in.
- Go! Go!
What happened?
Look out!
Where's Drew?
My leg's broke.
I'm takin' roll call!
Drew was shot!
Somethin' happened to him.
What?
Drew was shot.
Shot?
Here, here.
Hold him here.
- I got him.
- Hold on!
Drew was shot!
Bobby, Drew was shot!
He was shot, Bobby!
Drew was shot!
Here's his jacket!
He wasn't wearin' it!
Maybe Lewis is right!
Of course, he's right. Of course!
You mean that other guy shot him?
Did he?
Did you see him?
Drew was shot.
Lewis says that other guy...
...that toothless bastard, shot him!
He's right up there!
He's gonna try and kill us, too!
If he killed Drew...
...he's gonna have to kill us!
Lewis, I'll tell you what.
We'll wait until dark, and we'll put you
in the bottom of the canoe...
...and we'll sneak out of here.
- Okay, Ed?
- Bobby, look at those rapids down there!
- Look at those rapids!
- Christ!
We can't move out of here in the dark.
We're not gonna move you, Lewis.
Lewis, we're trapped in this gorge.
What're we gonna do, Lewis?
You're the guy with the answers.
What the hell do we do now?
Now you get to play the game.
You're ruined! Lewis, you're ruined!
Listen.
He's hurt bad, isn't he?
What're we gonna do?
The guy must know exactly where we are.
Well, if he knows where we are...
...then we sure as hell know
where he's gonna be.
Right up there.
Christ!
What a view!
Goddamn it!
You'll never get out of this gorge alive!
Pull yourself together.
Release.
I don't believe it!
You did it, Ed.
You killed him!
Good.
Lewis had a bad night.
More than once I thought he'd die.
You did it, Ed. Good.
You sure it's him?
That's the guy with the gun, huh?
I think so.
He wasn't just some guy...
...up there huntin' or something?
- You tell me!
Was he shot?
What about here? What about right there?
Could have been a rock.
What are you gonna do with Drew?
If a bullet made this,
there are people who can tell.
Oh, God!
There's no end to it.
I didn't really know him.
Drew was...
...a good husband...
...to his wife Linda.
You're a wonderful father
to your boys, Drew...
...Jimmy and Billy Ray.
And if...
...we come through this, I promise...
...to do all I can for 'em.
He was the best of us.
Amen.
Christ! Look at that! God help us.
We made it. We made it, Ed.
We made it.
- We're back, Ed!
- Yeah.
- We gotta get Lewis to a doctor.
- Right, Ed.
Gotta get Lewis to a doctor.
We're back! We made it!
Everything happened...
Listen, everything happened right here.
Everything happened right here.
Lewis broke his leg in those rapids there.
- And Drew drowned here. In this place.
- No, no, Ed.
- No, nothin' happened here.
- Bobby, listen to me!
We got to stop them from lookin' upriver.
It's important that we get together
on this thing.
You understand?
I understand, Eddie, I understand.
That's right, Lewis. That's our story.
Lewis, we're back.
- It's all right.
- Get Lewis to a doctor.
All right, Ed.
All right.
We'll find a place to put it.
We're not out of this yet!
They brought the cars.
You come for the cars, sir?
Yes.
Do you have a phone?
Phone?
Telephone?
Yes, sir.
You're gonna be all right.
What in the world happened to you guys?
Drew Ballinger.
Did you look for him?
A long time.
Could you show us where it happened?
How'd you manage to shoot yourself
with your own arrow?
Didn't think it could be done.
This is nice.
What's that?
Chromium, paper tissues...
...hot water... That's nice.
You fallin' asleep?
Don't forget to phone your wife.
Let her know how you are.
Yes, I will, thank you.
Hello. Come on in.
We saved you a seat.
Do you feel like eating something?
Please.
Some corn?
Would you like some peas?
This corn is special, isn't it?
I love good corn.
We need that cucumber
I got out of the garden last night.
You know how long it was?
- Tell me.
- Twelve-and-a-half inches long.
Then I measured it around,
and it's ten-and-a-half around.
That's the darndest lookin' cucumber
you'll ever see.
I tell you, I'll send it over
and let you see it, if you doubt it.
I think you're crazy sometimes.
We can show you the place.
Now I know where you told me it was.
We just wanna cooperate.
You recognize that piece of canoe?
Now, we lost one. That could be it.
But you ain't sure?
Yeah, I think so, but it's kind of confusing.
I'd think you'd recognize your own canoe.
I'd appreciate it if you'd show me
that spot.
Ed, we're in trouble. They don't believe us!
What did you tell him, Bobby?
What we agreed on.
I heard you. I was in that room, Bobby.
What did you tell him?
They found part of the green canoe, right?
Upstream, and you got scared.
Didn't you, Bobby? I know you.
You told him the truth, didn't you, Bobby?
- You told him the truth!
- I didn't do that!
I told 'em...
...like we said.
But I don't think they believed me.
Ed, I think they found that other canoe...
...upstream, above where we told him.
I never said that.
Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
- I know damn well you did.
I know what I said.
Yeah, well, that's a goddamn lie.
Sheriff, that ain't what he said
this morning.
You tell me how a canoe can drift upriver.
Now what about this?
Look, Sheriff...
...we been through quite a lot.
I don't know what's wrong
with your man there.
Mr. Queen's got a brother-in-law...
...back up in there somewhere.
He took off huntin' three days ago and...
...nobody's heard from him since.
Mr. Queen thought maybe you all...
...might've happened up on him
somewhere.
Well, we didn't.
Don't let 'em go. These boys is lying.
We got nothin' to hold 'em for.
We don't have a thing.
Let's just wait and see
what comes out of the river.
That there's the town hall.
Right over there's the old fire station.
Played a lot of checkers over there.
All this land's gonna be covered
with water.
Best thing that ever happened
to this town.
We may have to stop just a minute
for the church to get out of the way.
Christ.
Doctor, how's our boy?
We're doin' everything we can for him.
But there's a chance he might lose the leg,
so take it easy on him, okay?
I'll talk with you later.
Officer?
Has he been awake yet?
No, we're still waitin' for him
to come around.
Lewis, listen, we had to change our story.
How you feeling?
Never better.
Did you hear me?
What happened on that last set of rapids?
I don't remember nothing.
Nothing.
- Want me to drive Drew's car back?
- No.
Talk to his wife?
I'll do it, Bobby, thank you.
You all about ready to leave?
Yeah.
The Griner boys brought these cars
down to you from Orie, is that right?
Right.
You happen to see another man
with 'em up there?
There was someone, wasn't there?
I think so, yes.
Before you go, buddy,
let me ask you something.
How come you all ended up
with four life jackets?
Didn't we have an extra one?
No.
Drew wasn't wearin' his.
Well, how come he wasn't wearin' it?
I don't know.
Don't ever do nothin' like this again.
Don't come back up here.
You don't have to worry
about that, Sheriff.
I'd kinda like to see this town die peaceful.
I hope Deputy Queen
finds his brother-in-law.
He'll come in drunk probably.
Good-bye, Ed.
'Bye, Bobby.
I don't think I'll see you for a while.
Hey, Charlie.
What you got there, guy?
What's the matter?
It's all right.
Go to sleep.
English subtitles conformed by
SOFTITLER