Teacher...
I see your talents have gone
beyond the mere physical level.
Your skills are now at the point
of spiritual insight.
I have several questions:
What is the highest technique
you hope to achieve?
- To have no technique.
- Very good.
What are your thoughts
when facing an opponent?
There is no opponent.
And why is that?
Because the word "l" does not exist.
So, continue.
A good fight should be...
...like a small play, but played seriously.
A good martial artist does not
become tense, but ready.
Not thinking, yet not dreaming.
Ready for whatever may come.
When the opponent expands, I contract.
When he contracts, I expand.
When there is an opportunity...
...I do not hit.
It hits all by itself.
Now, you must remember...
...the enemy has only images
and illusions...
...behind which he hides his true motives.
Destroy the image,
and you will break the enemy.
The hit that you refer to...
...is a powerful weapon...
...easily misused by the martial artist
who deserts his vows.
For centuries now...
...the code of the Shaolin Temple
has been preserved.
Remember...
...the honor of our brotherhood
has been held true.
Tell me now the Shaolin Commandment
Number 13.
"A martial artist has
to take responsibility for himself...
"...and to accept the consequences
of his own doing."
I'm ashamed to tell you now.
Among all the Shaolin men I have taught...
...there is one who has turned
the ways of knowledge and strength...
...to his own base ends.
He has perverted all we held sacred.
His name is Han.
In defiance of all our beliefs...
...he has brought disgrace
to the Shaolin Temple.
So, it is now for you to reclaim
our lost honor.
Yes, I understand.
There is a man here. You will go to him.
Hello, Mr. Lee. My name is Braithwaite.
Hello, Mr. Braithwaite.
I've come to speak to you
about a matter of great importance.
- Have some tea?
- Yes, indeed.
This is very pleasant.
I've come to speak to you
about a tournament of martial arts.
A tournament to which
you've already received an invitation.
Specifically, a tournament organized
by Mr. Han.
Han's tournament.
I know, I know...
...but we'd like you to attend
that particular tournament, Mr. Lee.
"We," Mr. Braithwaite?
It's Lahn's time.
Yes, of course.
Kick me.
What was that?
An exhibition?
We need emotional content.
Try again.
I said, "emotional content"...
...not anger!
Now try again with meaning!
That's it!
How did it feel to you?
Let me think.
Don't think! Feel!
It is like a finger pointing a way
to the moon.
Don't concentrate on the finger
or you will miss...
...all that heavenly glory.
Do you understand?
Never take your eyes off your opponent.
Even when you bow.
That's it.
There!
That's Han. That's the only film
we have on him.
We know that he was a member
of your temple. A Shaolin monk...
...now a renegade.
That's Oharra behind him.
Personal bodyguard.
Tough, ruthless, as you might expect,
being Han's bodyguard.
We got our hands on a demonstration film
of Oharra.
All real bricks and boards.
Nothing phony about any of it.
This was before he picked up
a facial scar somewhere.
This is where you'll be going.
An island fortress, really.
After the war...
...the nationality of the island
was uncertain.
And sometime after that, Han bought it.
What do you know about Han?
He lives like a king on that island,
totally self-sufficient.
All of his efforts, seemingly...
...are directed towards supporting
what he calls his school of martial arts.
Han's only contact with the outside world
is this tournament...
...which he holds every three years.
This was a stewardess, Mary King,
found floating in the harbor.
Nothing unusual
about a body in the harbor.
But this girl was last seen at a party
aboard Han's private junk.
They had reported her lost at sea
before the body was found.
We believe he selects attractive girls...
...methodically builds
their dependence on drugs...
...then sells them to an elite clientele
around the world.
What did the autopsy reveal
as the cause of death?
She did not drown.
She OD'd?
Yes.
Cause of death was a heroin overdose.
I gather you still don't have enough
to bust up his operation.
We know everything.
We can prove nothing.
We want you to go in there as our agent.
Get us our evidence.
And come out in one piece
to give it to you.
We'll give you anything you need.
Electronic equipment, weapons, anything.
Drink?
No, thanks.
Guns!
Now, why doesn't somebody pull a.45,
and bang, settle it?
No. No guns.
Look at this map here.
As you know, the possession of a weapon
is a serious offense here.
Han's island rests partly
within our territorial waters.
If we were given any reason to believe
that he has any kind of arsenal...
...we'd move in on him.
Besides, Han would never allow guns
on the island, anyway.
He had a bad experience with them once
and he's fearful of assassination.
Can't really blame him.
Any bloody fool can pull a trigger.
I guess I won't need anything.
There's a radio on the island.
We'll be monitoring it on the chance
that you can get to it.
And then you'll come?
Someone will.
We aren't an agency of enforcement.
We function as gatherers of information.
Evidence upon which
interested governments can act.
I see.
If there's any trouble,
you make a phone call.
Oh, by the way...
...two months ago, we managed to place
a female operative on the island.
Since then, we've lost her.
If she's still there,
she might have something.
Her name is Mei Ling.
Are you sure you won't have one?
No, thanks.
Now the time has come
to tell you something very difficult.
I am happy you have decided
to go to Han's tournament.
Yeah.
The last of the tournaments was held
three years ago.
I was in the city with your sister...
...at that time.
I didn't know that.
Many of Han's men had come in
from the island.
They were everywhere,
bullying and arrogant.
We were on our way into town.
Stay back!
Run!
Now you know the truth.
When you get to the city...
...pay your respects to your sister
and your mother.
I will, old man.
You will not agree
with what I am going to do.
It is contrary to all
that you have taught me.
And all that Su Ling believed.
I must leave.
Please try to find a way to forgive me.
Double or nothing?
That's about $1,000 a foot, Roper!
Why not?
I'm sorry, Mr. Roper isn't in right now.
May I take a message?
That's a tough shot, Mr. Roper.
Excuse me, fellows.
I say you can't make it.
What will you bet?
You've got to love him.
Come on, Roper, it's 175 big ones
by Monday, the 15th.
Only 150.
You forget the interest.
Well, maybe I ought to talk to Freddie.
You take advantage, Roper.
Come on, fellows.
It's the dough, Roper,
or we gotta break something.
You got it?
Freddie says this is for your own good.
Better confirm that flight
to Hong Kong for me.
How much do I have left in the bank?
$63.43.
It's all yours.
Thanks!
Only, I think you'll need it.
You want to bet?
Going on a trip, are you?
This jig's got a passport!
Where are you going, jig?
Where's the plane ticket for?
Hong Kong, via Hawaii.
He's not going to Hawaii.
Well, look what we've got here!
Assaulting a police officer.
Hey, soldier, shape it up!
Roper! Hey, how are you, man?
How am I? I'm glad to see you,
that's how I am.
How long has it been? Five?
Six years, man. Not as long as it seems.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
What have you been doing since 'Nam?
Hanging in a little bit.
- All these yours, man?
- Always first class.
Same old Roper.
Come here.
Parsons.
Yeah, from New Zealand. This man's
putting quite a collection together.
Know him?
No, never saw him before.
What do you know about this Han cat?
Just rumors. I hear he likes to live big.
They don't live so big over there.
Ghettos are the same all over the world.
They stink.
Same old Williams.
What have we got here? A little action.
Insects. I'll lay you $50 on the big one.
$50 on the big one. All right?
I'll give you five to one.
Would you bet $100?
You're on.
Come on, let's end this thing quickly.
Hey, that's it, come on,
just get him on his back!
For crying out loud,
would you believe that?
Oh, shit!
Do I bother you?
Don't waste yourself.
What's your style?
My style?
You can call it the art of fighting
without fighting.
The art of fighting without fighting?
Show me some of it.
Later.
All right.
Don't you think we need more room?
Where else?
That island, on a beach.
We can take this boat.
Okay.
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Pull me in. Pull me in!
Don't try to pull yourself up...
...or I'll let go of the line.
Would you look at that?
A woman like that could teach you
a lot about yourself.
Welcome.
This way.
I'll show you to your rooms.
The banquet begins promptly at 8:00.
I think you'll find our little island
quite charming.
I hope you haven't spent all that money
you won from me yesterday.
I plan to win it back.
How?
You'll find out after you've lost it.
You seem to be very much at home here,
Mr. Roper.
This guy, Han,
has a great sense of hospitality.
And a fantastic sense of style.
Yeah, it's great.
Then why are you so apprehensive?
Apprehensive?
No, I was just wondering
whether it was okay to drink the water.
Mr. Roper, don't con me.
Want to bet?
No, I really don't think so. Thanks.
What's the matter? Are you on a diet?
I'd like to eat if I could find something
I could keep down.
I can't wait to meet our host.
I hear this is only one of his "B" parties.
Have you ever been
to a martial arts tournament like this?
Never.
I have a funny feeling
we're being fattened up for the kill.
Better keep an eye out for the referee.
Know what I mean?
Yeah.
Gentlemen, welcome!
You honor our island.
I look forward to a tournament...
...of truly epic proportions.
We are unique, gentlemen...
...in that we create ourselves.
Through long years of rigorous training,
sacrifice...
...denial, pain...
...we forge our bodies in the fire of our will.
But tonight, let us celebrate.
Gentlemen...
...you have our gratitude.
Mr. Williams!
For me?
You shouldn't have.
But...
...l'll take you, darling.
And you.
Please understand, if I missed anyone...
...it's been a big day. I'm a little tired.
Of course, Mr. Williams.
You must conserve your strength.
Come in.
A gift, Mr. Lee.
If you don't see anything you like...
There was a girl at the feast tonight.
Which girl, sir?
The owner of this dart.
Yes, I know the one.
I'll send her to you.
Another fine mess you got me into.
Come in.
Well, well, one more lovely than the next.
What did you have in mind?
Pick one.
I already have.
A wise decision.
I want to talk to you...
...Mei Ling.
Where do you come from?
Braithwaite.
Let's be quiet.
Have you seen anything?
Nothing much. I'm kept in the palace...
...watched always.
I know nothing of Han's activities
away from the palace.
But I can tell you this:
- People disappear.
- Who?
The girls. Every one of them.
They're summoned to Han's at night,
and the next day they're gone.
I know I don't have much time.
You must attend the morning ritual
in uniform.
Outside.
Why are you not in uniform?
Gentlemen, let the tournament begin!
Bolo!
Good work, you made me some bread!
- Mr. Roper?
- I'm ready.
Okay.
I've got myself a real pigeon here.
Keep the action going for me, will you?
What do you think, Roper?
No sweat. Give my friend
eight to three all the way.
I'm finding out about myself.
This is the real me, definitely.
Do you like it here?
Yes. But a little lower.
I know. I mean here, on the island.
Yes, I like it here.
A little lower.
A man like you belongs here.
To you I'm just another pretty face.
Where are you going?
Out in the moonlight, baby.
It is not allowed. You must stay.
Good-bye.
A human fly!
It seems that one of you...
...was not content last night...
...with the hospitality...
...of the palace...
...and sought diversion...
...elsewhere on the island.
Who it was...
...is not important at this time.
What is important is that...
...my guards performed
their duties incompetently.
And now they must prove...
...themselves worthy to remain among us.
Are you shocked, Mr. Williams?
Only at how sloppily your man works.
Mr. Lee?
Are you ready?
Boards don't hit back.
Go!
Oharra!
Oharra's treachery has disgraced us.
If you want to talk about this,
I'll be in my room.
I got you.
Williams, come here! I want you to go
to Han's study as soon as possible.
Hey, Roper, I'll see you in half an hour.
- Mr. Han?
- You fought well yesterday.
Your style is unorthodox.
But effective.
It is not the art but the combat you enjoy.
The winning.
We are all ready to win.
Just as we are born knowing only life.
It is defeat that you must learn
to prepare for.
I don't waste my time with it.
When it comes, I won't even notice.
How so?
I'll be too busy looking good.
What were you looking for
when you attacked my guards?
It wasn't me.
You were the only man outside the palace.
I was outside, but I wasn't the only one.
You will tell me who else.
Mr. Han, suddenly I'd like
to leave your island.
It is not possible.
Bullshit, Mr. Han!
You come right out of a comic book!
Been practicing?
My friend, Williams,
is expecting me in my room.
I wanted to talk to you.
We will meet your friend, Williams, later.
Okay.
This is my museum.
It is difficult to associate these horrors...
...with the proud civilizations
that created them.
Sparta, Rome, the Knights of Europe,
the Samurai.
They worshipped strength...
...because it is strength
that makes all other values possible.
Nothing survives without it.
Who knows what delicate wonders
have died out of the world...
...for want of the strength to survive?
What's this?
A souvenir.
Up here.
A guillotine. No thanks.
This is the only angle I care to see it from.
If you please, Mr. Roper.
You mean you want me
to put my head on that thing?
An act of faith.
I'm a man of little faith, Mr. Han.
Very few people can be totally ruthless.
It isn't easy.
It takes more strength
than you might believe.
Now you've got eight more.
Then there is a point
you will not go beyond.
Faked out again.
This way.
Our power plant.
Oh, yes.
A lifetime of women.
A man's strength can be measured
by his appetites.
Indeed, a man's strength flows
from his appetites.
No, they are my daughters.
Your daughters?
I'm sorry. I thought...
I misunderstood. Miss Han...
Also, they are my most personal guard.
I admire your judgment.
Nobody is as loyal as Daddy's little girl.
Mr. Roper?
No, thanks, I'll get up myself.
Nice meeting you.
Opium!
We are investing in corruption, Mr. Roper.
The business of corruption
is like any other.
Provide your customers
with products they need, and...
...encourage that need a little bit
to stimulate your market and...
...soon your customers will depend on you.
I mean really need you.
It's the law of economics.
Right.
Here we are stimulating
quite another need.
You wonder why I am exposing
so much of myself?
I forget what I see very easily.
But then, why are you?
I'm hoping you'll join us,
represent us in the United States.
I'm beginning to understand
this tournament thing, the whole set-up.
It's a great way to recruit new talent.
And who are they?
Refuse found in waterfront bars.
Shanghaied?
Just lost, drunken men
who no longer care...
...where they find themselves
each morning.
You left some rather sizeable debts
in America.
Diner's Club hasn't called in my card yet.
There were some questions
which I was forced to ask.
I got no answers.
And you want me to join this?
There are certain realities.
I want us to have a clear understanding.
No.
There's no misunderstanding between us.
Help me!
I'm only 17!
Help me! Please, help me!
Come back, please!
You have to come back, please!
Quiet!
The battle with the guards
was magnificent.
Your skill is extraordinary.
And I was going to ask you to join us.
My God, this came in half an hour ago!
Why didn't I...
Put your colonel on.
Well, wake him up.
I don't care if he's not alone!
Damn it all, I don't care who he's with!
You bloody well put him on the line!
Good morning, Mr. Roper.
We have been waiting for you.
What's going on?
Would you be good enough to participate
in this morning's edification?
Edification?
What are you going to do to him?
Not me, Mr. Roper. You.
Like you said...
...there's a point I won't go beyond.
I was right about you.
We shall strive to be worthy
of your sense of grandeur.
I will find someone
with whom you can fight.
Quick, go destroy them! Kill!
Kill them!
Kill!
You have offended my family...
...and you have offended
the Shaolin Temple.
Remember...
...the enemy has
only images and illusions...
...behind which he hides his true motives.
Destroy the image,
and you will break the enemy.