Captain's Log. Stardate 8130.3.
Starship Enterprise on
training mission to Gamma Hydra.
Section 14, coordinates: 22/87/4.
Approaching Neutral Zone,
all systems normal and functioning.
Leaving Section 14 for Section 15.
Stand by. Project parabolic course
to avoid entering Neutral Zone.
Course change projected.
Captain! I'm getting something
on the distress channel.
Imperative! This is the Kobayashi
Maru, 19 periods out of Altair Six.
We have struck a gravitic mine
and have lost all power...
This is the Starship Enterprise.
Can you give us your coordinates?
Enterprise, our position is
Gamma Hydra, Section 10.
In the Neutral Zone.
Hull penetrated, life support
systems failing. Can you assist us?
Data on Kobayashi Maru.
Third class neutronic fuel carrier,
crew of 81. 300 passengers.
Damn!
Mr Sulu? Plot an intercept course.
May I remind the Captain
that if a Starship enters the Zone...
I'm aware of
my responsibilities, Mister.
Estimating two minutes to intercept.
- Now entering the Neutral Zone.
- Warning. Neutral Zone entered.
We are now in violation of Treaty.
Stand by, Transporter Room,
ready to beam survivors aboard.
Captain! I've lost their signal.
Sensors indicate three Klingon
cruisers, bearing 316 mark 4.
- Closing fast.
- Visual.
Battle stations! Activate shields!
- Shields activated!
- Say we are on a rescue mission.
- They're jamming all frequencies.
- Klingons on attack course...
We're in over our heads.
Mr Sulu! Get us out of here!
Alert! Klingon torpedoes activated.
Evasive action!
- Engineering! Damage report!
- Main energiser hit!
Engage auxiliary power!
Prepare to return fire!
Shields collapsing, Captain!
- Fire all phasers!
- No power to the weapons, Captain.
Captain, it's no use!
We're dead in space!
Activate escape pods! Send out
the Log Buoy. All hands abandon ship.
All right. Open her up.
- Any suggestions, Admiral?
- Prayer, Mr Saavik.
The Klingons don't take prisoners.
Lights!
Motors on!
Captain?
Trainees... to the briefing room.
Maintenance Crew,
report to Bridge Simulator.
- Physician, heal thyself.
- Is that all you've got to say?
- What about my performance?
- I'm not a drama critic.
Are you gonna stay
with the sinking ship?
- Permission to speak candidly, sir?
- Granted.
I don't believe this was
a fair test of my command abilities.
There was no way to win.
Every commander may face
a no-win situation.
- Has that never occurred to you?
- No, sir. It has not.
How we deal with death is at least
as important as how we deal with life.
As I indicated, that thought
had not occurred to me.
Well, now you have
something new to think about.
Admiral? Wouldn't it be easier to put
an experienced crew back on the ship?
Galloping around the cosmos
is a game for the young, Doctor.
What is that supposed to mean?
Aren't you dead?
You want to learn what efficiency
rating I'll give your cadets?
I am understandably curious.
They destroyed
the Simulator Room and you with it.
The Kobayashi Maru scenario
frequently wreaks havoc
with students and equipment.
You took the test three times yourself.
Your final solution was,
shall we say... unique.
It had the virtue
of never having been tried.
Oh, by the way... thank you for this.
I know of your fondness for antiques.
"It was the best of times,
it was the worst of times..."
- Message, Spock?
- None that I'm conscious of.
Except, of course, happy birthday.
Surely, the best of times.
Captain Spock, Captain Spock,
space shuttle leaving in 15 minutes.
- Where are you off to?
- The Enterprise.
I must check in
before your inspection. And you?
Home.
Doctor! What beams you
into this neck of the woods?
"Beware of Romulans bearing gifts."
- Happy birthday, Jim!
- Thanks.
Romulan ale!
Bones, you know this is illegal.
I only use it for medicinal purposes.
I got aboard a ship
that brings in a case now and then
across the Neutral Zone.
- Now, don't be a prig.
- 2283.
Yeah, well, it takes this stuff
a while to ferment.
Here, give me that.
Now, you open this one.
I'm almost afraid to.
What is it? Klingon aphrodisiacs?
No.
Oh, Bones... this is... charming.
For most patients your age,
I recommend Retinax Five.
- I'm allergic to Retinax.
- Exactly. Cheers!
Cheers.
Happy birthday.
- I don't know what to say.
- You could say thank you.
Thank you.
Damn it, Jim!
What's the matter with you?
Why are we treating
your birthday like a funeral?
- Bones, I don't want to be lectured.
- What the hell do you want?
This is not about age.
And you know it.
It's about you flying a computer
when you want to be hopping galaxies!
Spare me your notions of poetry.
We all have our duties.
Bull! You're hiding,
hiding behind rules and regulations.
- Who am I hiding from?
- From yourself, Admiral!
Don't mince words, Bones.
What do you really think?
Jim...
I'm your doctor and I'm your friend.
Get back your command.
Get it back before you turn
into part of this collection.
Before you really do grow old.
Starship Log. Stardate 8130.4.
Log Entry by
First Officer Pavel Chekov.
Starship Reliant on orbital
approach to Ceti Alpha Six,
in connection with Project Genesis.
We keep searching for a lifeless
planet, to satisfy the requirements
of a test site for the Genesis
Experiment. So far, no success.
Standard orbit, please. Mr Beach,
any change in the surface scan?
Negative. Limited atmosphere
dominated by craylon gas, sand,
high velocity winds.
Incapable of supporting lifeforms.
Does it have to be
completely lifeless?
You've found something?
We've picked up a minor energy flux
reading on one dyno scanner.
Damn. Are you sure? Maybe
the scanner's out of adjustment.
I suppose it could be a particle
of pre-animate matter,
caught in the matrix.
All right.
Get on the Comm-pic to Dr Marcus.
Maybe it's something we can transplant?
You know what she'll say.
Now, let me get this straight.
Something you can transplant?
I don't know.
It may only be a particle
of pre-animate matter.
Then again, it may not.
You boys have to be clear on this.
There can't be so much as a microbe,
or the show's off!
Have a look. But if it is
something that can be moved...
You bet, Doctor. We're on our way.
Don't have kittens,
Genesis is going to work.
They'll remember you in one breath
with Newton, Einstein, Surak!
Thanks a lot.
No respect from my offspring.
Par for the course. Are you teaming
up with me for bridge after dinner?
Maybe.
What is it?
Every time we have dealings
with Starfleet, I get nervous.
We are dealing with something that...
...could be perverted
into a dreadful weapon.
That overgrown Boy Scout you used
to know is exactly the kind of man...
Jim Kirk was many things,
but he was never a Boy Scout!
Captain Terrell,
stand by to beam down.
Chekov, are you sure
these are the correct coordinates?
Captain, this is the garden spot
of Ceti Alpha Six.
I can barely see it.
There's nothing here!
The Tricorder must be broken.
Chekov! Over here!
Those look like cargo carriers.
Hey, give me a hand.
What the hell happened?
If they crashed,
where's the rest of the ship?
What the hell is that?
Botany Bay...
Botany Bay?!
Oh, no!
We've got to get
out of here now! Damn!
- What about the...
- Never mind that! Hurry!
Chekov, what's the matter with you?
Chekov!
Come on! Hurry!
Starship Reliant to Captain Terrell.
This is Commander Kyle.
Will you please respond, Captain?
Captain Terrell! Respond, please!
Let's give them a little more time.
Khan!
I don't know you.
But you...
I never forget a face.
Mister...
...Chekov!
Isn't it?
I'd never thought
to see your face again.
- Chekov, who is this man?
- A criminal, Captain.
A product of late 20th century
genetic engineering.
- What do you want? Sir, I demand...
- You are in a position
to demand nothing, sir.
I, on the other hand,
am in a position to grant... nothing.
What you see is all that remains
of the ship's company and crew
of the Botany Bay...
...marooned here 15 years ago
by Captain James T. Kirk.
- Listen! You men and women...
- Captain! Captain...
Save your strength.
These people have sworn
to live and die at my command
200 years before you were born.
Do you mean...
he never told you the tale?
To amuse your captain? No?
Never told how the Enterprise picked
up the Botany Bay, lost in space,
in the year 1996, myself and the
ship's company in cryogenic freeze?
- I've never even met Admiral Kirk.
- Admiral?
Admiral?!
Admiral...
Never told you how... Admiral Kirk
sent 70 of us into exile
on this barren sand heap,
with only the contents
of these cargo bays to sustain us?
You lie! On Ceti Alpha Five
there was life!
- A fair chance!
- This is Ceta Alpha Five!
Ceti Alpha Six exploded
six months after we were left here.
The shock shifted the orbit of this
planet and everything was laid waste!
Admiral Kirk... never bothered
to check on our progress.
It was only the fact of
my genetically engineered intellect
that allowed us to survive.
On Earth...
...200 years ago...
...I was a prince...
...with power over millions!
Captain Kirk was your host!
You repaid his hospitality
by trying to steal his ship
and murder him!
You didn't expect to find me.
You thought this was...
Ceti Alpha Six!
Why are you here?
Why?!
Allow me to introduce you
to Ceti Alpha Five's only remaining
indigenous lifeform.
What do you think?
They've killed 20 of my people.
Including my beloved wife.
Oh, not all at once.
And not... instantly, to be sure.
You see, their young
enter through the ears...
...and wrap themselves
around the cerebral cortex.
This has the effect of rendering
the victim extremely susceptible
to suggestion.
Later, as they... grow...
...follows madness.
And death.
Khan! Listen to me!
These are pets, of course.
Not quite domesticated.
Khan... Captain Kirk
was only doing his duty.
No!
That's better.
Now, tell me... Why are you here?
And tell me where I may find...
...James Kirk.
Enterprise to
Admiral Kirk's shuttle.
You're cleared for docking.
Approach portside torpedo bay.
Enterprise, this is Admiral Kirk's
party on final approach.
Enterprise welcomes you.
Prepare for docking.
I hate inspections.
I'm delighted. Any chance
to go aboard the Enterprise.
I am glad to have you
at the helm for three weeks.
I don't think these kids can steer.
Open the airlock.
- Permission to come aboard, Captain.
- Welcome. You know my training crew.
They certainly know you.
Yes. We've been through
death and life together.
Mr Scott, you old space dog!
You're well?
I had a wee bout, sir,
but Dr McCoy pulled me through.
- A wee bout of what?
- Shore leave, Admiral.
- And who is this?
- Midshipman First Class.
- Peter Preston, engineer's mate!
- First training voyage?
- Yes, sir!
- I see.
Well... shall we start
with the Engine Room?
We'll see you there.
Everything is in order.
That'll be a pleasant surprise,
Mr Scott.
I'll see you on the bridge, Admiral.
Company dismissed!
Mr Scott, are your cadets capable
of handling a minor training cruise?
- Give the word, Admiral!
- Mr Scott, the word is given.
Admiral, what about
the rest of the inspection?
Later.
This is Starfleet Operations.
Enterprise is cleared for departure.
Admiral on the bridge.
Very well, Mr Saavik.
You may clear all moorings.
- All moorings are clear, Captain.
- Thank you.
Lieutenant? Have you ever piloted
a Starship out of spacedock?
Never, sir.
Take her out, Mr Saavik.
Aye, sir.
For everything there is a first time,
Lieutenant. Don't you agree, Admiral?
- Aft thrusters, Mr Sulu.
- Aft thrusters.
- Would you like a tranquilliser?
- Ahead one quarter impulse power.
- We are free and clear to navigate.
- Course heading, Captain?
Captain's discretion.
Mr Sulu? You may... indulge yourself.
Aye, sir.
That about do it?
There can't be more information we
could squeeze into the memory banks.
- Next time we'll design a bigger one.
- Who'd build it?
Dr Marcus? Comm-Pic
coming in on hyperchannel.
- It's the Starship Reliant.
- On the screen, please, Jedda.
Come in, please. This is
the Reliant calling Regula One.
Repeat, this is USS Reliant.
Commander, we are receiving.
This is Regula One. Go ahead.
Dr Marcus. We're en route to you
and should be there in three days.
En route? Why? We weren't expecting
you for another three months.
- Has something happened?
- Ceti Alpha Six has checked out.
- Then I don't understand why you...
- We have received new orders.
Upon our arrival at Regula One,
all materials of Project Genesis
will be transferred to this ship
for testing on Ceti Alpha Six.
Who the hell do they think they are?
Commander Chekov,
this is completely irregular.
- I have my orders.
- Pin him down, Mother!
Who gave the order?
The order comes from...
Admiral James T. Kirk.
I knew it! All along
the military's wanted to get...
This is completely improper,
Commander Chekov!
I do not intend to allow Reliant
or any other unauthorised personnel
access to our work or materials.
I'm sorry that you feel that way.
The Admiral's orders are confirmed.
Please prepare to deliver Genesis
to us upon our arrival. Reliant out.
Well done, Commander.
You realise, sir, they will attempt
to contact Admiral Kirk
and confirm the order.
Hold, please.
Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant, are you wearing
your hair differently?
It's still regulation, Admiral.
May I speak, sir?
Self-expression doesn't seem
to be one of your problems.
You're bothered by your performance
on the Kobayashi Maru.
- I failed to resolve the situation.
- It's a test of character.
May I ask
how you dealt with the test?
You may ask.
That's a little joke.
Humour. It is a difficult concept.
- It is not logical.
- We learn by doing.
Who's been holding up
the damn elevator?
- Did she change her hairstyle?
- I hadn't noticed.
Wonderful stuff, that Romulan ale.
- Admiral Kirk?
- Kirk here.
An urgent Comm-Pic from Space Lab
Regula One for you. Dr Carol Marcus.
- I'll take it in my quarters, Uhura.
- It never rains but it pours.
As a physician, you should appreciate
the dangers of re-opening old wounds.
- Sorry.
- Jim, can you read me?
I can hear you, Carol.
What's the matter?
Why are you taking
Genesis away from us?
Taking Genesis?
Who is taking Genesis?
- I can see you, but I can't hear.
- Carol...
- Jim, did you give the order?
- What order? Who is taking Genesis?
Please help us! I won't let them
have Genesis without authorisation!
On whose authority
can they do this?
- No one's authority!
- Please do something.
- Uhura, what's happening?
- Transmission jammed at source.
Alert Starfleet Headquarters.
I want to talk to Starfleet Command.
We must have order in here.
This has to be some sort of mistake.
Mistake?! We're all alone here.
They waited until everyone
was on leave to do this.
Reliant is supposed
to be at our disposal.
- Starfleet clearly never intended...
- I know that, but...
I tried to tell you! Scientists have
always been pawns of the military.
Starfleet has kept the peace
for 100 years.
I cannot subscribe
to your interpretation of this event!
You may be right, Doctor. But what
about Reliant? She's on her way.
Something may be wrong in Regula One.
We've been ordered to investigate.
If memory serves, Regula One is
a scientific research laboratory.
I told Starfleet Command all we had
was a boatload of children.
But... we're the only ship
in the quadrant.
These cadets of yours, how will they
respond under real pressure?
As with all living things,
each according to his gifts.
Of course, this ship is yours.
No, that won't be necessary.
Just get me to Regula One.
As a teacher on a training mission,
I'm happy to command the Enterprise.
If we are to go on actual duty,
the senior officer must assume command.
It may be nothing.
Garbled communications.
You take the ship.
You proceed from a false assumption.
I'm a Vulcan.
I have no ego to bruise.
You remind me that logic
dictates your actions?
I would not remind you
of that which you know so well.
If I may be so bold, it was a mistake
for you to accept promotion.
Commanding a Starship
is your first, best destiny.
Anything else is a waste of material.
I would not presume to debate you.
That is wise.
In any case... were I to invoke logic,
logic clearly dictates
that the needs of the many
outweigh the needs of the few.
Or the one.
You're my superior officer.
You are also my friend.
I have been
and always shall be yours.
Stop energisers. Prepare speakers.
An emergency situation has arisen.
By order of Starfleet Command,
as of now, 1800 hours,
I'm assuming command of this vessel.
Duty officer, so note in the log.
Plot a new course
for Space Laboratory Regula One.
Engine Room.
Mr Scott!
We'll be going to Warp Speed.
- Course plotted for Regula One.
- Engage Warp engines.
- Prepare for Warp Speed.
- Ready, sir.
I know that none of you were
expecting this. I'm sorry.
I'm going to have to ask you to grow
up a little sooner than you expected.
Warp Five, Sulu.
So much for
the little training cruise.
Course to intercept Enterprise
ready, sir.
- Helmsman?
- Sir. May I speak?
We're all with you, sir.
But consider this.
We are free. We have a ship
and the means to go where we will.
We have escaped
permanent exile on Ceti Alpha Five.
You have proved
your superior intellect...
...and defeated
the plans of Admiral Kirk.
You do not need to defeat him again.
He tasks me.
He tasks me, and I shall have him.
I'll chase him round
the moons of Nibia
and round the Antares maelstrom
and round perdition's flames
before I give him up!
Prepare to alter course.
Space Station Regula One,
please come in.
Dr Marcus, please respond.
This is Enterprise call...
There's no response
from Regula One.
- But no longer jammed?
- No, sir. No nothing!
There are two possibilities.
They're unable or unwilling to respond.
- How far?
- 12 hours 43 minutes, present speed.
Give up Genesis, she said. What does
that mean? Give it up to whom?
It might help if I knew what Genesis
was, beyond the biblical reference.
Uhura, have Dr McCoy
join us in my quarters.
Mr Saavik? You have the con.
I've got Sick Bay ready. Will someone
please tell me what's going on?
Computer. Request security procedure
and access to
Project Genesis summary.
Identify for retina scan.
Kirk... Admiral James T.
Security Scan approved.
Summary, please?
Project Genesis.
A proposal to the Federation.
- Carol Marcus.
- Yes.
What exactly is Genesis?
Well, put simply,
Genesis is life from lifelessness.
It is a process whereby
molecular structure is reorganised
at the sub-atomic level into life-
generating matter of equal mass.
Stage One of our experiments
was conducted in the laboratory.
Stage Two will be attempted
in a lifeless underground.
Stage Three will involve
the process on a planetary scale.
It is our intention to introduce
the Genesis device
into a pre-selected area of a lifeless
space body, such as a moon.
The device is delivered,
instantaneously causing
what we call the Genesis Effect.
Matter is reorganised
with life-generating results.
Instead of a dead moon,
a living, breathing planet
capable of sustaining whatever
lifeforms we deposit on it.
Fascinating.
The moon simulated here represents
a fraction of Genesis' potential,
should the Federation wish to fund
the experiment to its conclusion.
When we consider the cosmic problems
of population and food supply,
the usefulness of this process
becomes clear.
This concludes our proposal.
Thank you for your attention.
It literally is Genesis.
The power of creation.
- Have they proceeded?
- The tape was made a year ago.
I can only assume
they've reached Stage Two by now.
But, dear Lord, do you think
we're intelligent enough to...
Suppose... What if this thing
were used where life already exists?
It would destroy such life...
in favour of its new matrix.
Its new matrix? Do you have any idea
what you're saying?
I was not attempting
to evaluate its moral implications.
In cosmic history it has always been
easier to destroy than to create.
Not any more! Now we can do
both at the same time.
According to myth,
Earth was created in six days.
Now watch out! Here comes Genesis!
We'll do it for you in six minutes!
Really, Dr McCoy, you must learn
to govern your passions.
They will be your undoing.
Logic suggests...
Logic?! My God,
the man's talking about logic!
We're talking about
universal Armageddon!
- You green-blooded, inhuman...
- Bridge to Admiral Kirk.
Sensors indicate a vessel
in our area, closing fast.
- What do you make of her?
- It's one of ours. It's Reliant.
Try the emergency channels.
Picture, Mr Saavik.
Slow to one-half impulse power.
- Let's be friends.
- Slowing to one-half impulse power.
Reliant in our section.
This quadrant, sir. And slowing.
Sir? May I quote General Order 12?
"On the approach of any vessel,
"when communications
have not been established..."
The Admiral is well aware
of the regulations.
Aye, sir.
Is it possible
their Comm system has failed?
It would explain many things.
They're requesting
communications, sir.
Let them eat static!
They're still running
with shields down.
Of course!
We are one big happy fleet!
Ah, Kirk, my old friend! Do you know
the Klingon proverb that tells us,
"Revenge is a dish
that is best served cold?"
It is very cold... in space.
This is damned peculiar.
- Yellow Alert!
- Energise defence fields!
A voice. They say their Chambers coil
is overloading their Comm system.
Scanning.
Their coil emissions are normal!
- Their shields are still down.
- Raise ours.
- Their shields are going up!
- Lock phasers on target.
Locking phasers on target.
- They're locking phasers.
- Raise shields.
Fire!
- Sulu, get those shields up!
- Trying, sir.
I can't get power, sir!
Scotty?
- Uhura, turn off those channels!
- Mr Scott on the screen.
We're just hanging on, sir!
The main energiser's out!
- Try auxiliary power!
- Aye, sir.
Damage report.
- They knew exactly where to hit us.
- Who knew where to hit us? And why?
One thing is certain.
We cannot escape on auxiliary power.
Visual!
- Sulu, divert all power to phasers.
- Too late.
Hang on!
Scotty! What's left?
Just the batteries! I can have
auxiliary power in a few minutes!
We don't have a few minutes!
- Can you give me phaser power?
- A few shots!
- Not enough against their shields.
- Who are they?
Admiral! The commander
of the Reliant is signalling!
He wishes to discuss
terms of our surrender.
Visual on screen.
Do it! While we still have time.
On screen, sir.
- Khan!
- You still remember, Admiral.
I cannot help but be touched.
I, of course, remember you!
What is the meaning of this attack?!
Where is the crew of the Reliant?
Surely I have made
my meaning plain.
I mean to avenge myself
upon you, Admiral.
I've deprived your ship of power
and will deprive you of your life!
But I wanted you to know first
who it was who had beaten you.
Khan...
If it's me you want...
...l'll have myself beamed aboard.
Spare my crew!
I make you a counter-proposal.
I'll agree to your terms if...
...if... in addition to yourself,
you hand over to me
all data and material regarding
the project called... Genesis.
- Genesis? What's that?
- Don't insult my intelligence.
Give me some time to recall
the data on our computers.
I give you 60 seconds, Admiral.
Clear the bridge.
At least we know
he doesn't have Genesis.
Keep nodding as though
I'm still giving orders.
Mr Saavik, punch up the data charts
of Reliant's command console.
- Hurry!
- 45 seconds.
The prefix code?
- The chart's up, sir.
- Admiral!
We're finding it.
- Please.
Please, give us time. The bridge is
smashed, the computers inoperative.
Time is a luxury
you don't have, Admiral.
Damn!
- Admiral?
- It's coming through now, Khan.
Reliant's prefix number is 16309.
I don't understand.
You have to learn
why things work on a Starship.
Each ship has its own
combination code.
To prevent an enemy from doing
what we're attempting.
Using our console to order Reliant
to lower her shields.
Assuming he hasn't
changed the combination.
Fifteen seconds.
Khan, how do we know
you'll keep your word?
I've given you no word
to keep, Admiral.
In my judgment,
you simply have no alternative.
I see your point.
Stand by to receive our transmission.
Mr Sulu, lock phasers on target
and await my command.
Time's up... Admiral.
Here it comes.
Now, Mr Spock.
Sir! Our shields are dropping!
Raise them!
I can't!
Where's the override?!
Fire!
Fire! Fire!
- We can't fire!
- Why can't you?
They've damaged the photon control
and the Warp Drive. We must withdraw.
- No! No!
- Sir, we must!
The Enterprise can wait!
She's not going anywhere!
- Sir, you did it!
- I did nothing!
Except get caught with my breeches
down. I must be getting senile.
Mr Saavik? You go right on
quoting regulations!
In the meantime, let's find out
how badly we've been hurt.
- Is the word given, Admiral?
- The word is given.
Warp Speed.
Aye.
He stayed at his post...
when the trainees ran!
- Admiral? This is Spock.
- Yes, Spock?
Engine Room reports
auxiliary power restored.
We can proceed at impulse power.
Best speed to Regula One. Kirk out.
I'm sorry, Scotty.
Approaching Regula
and Space Lab Regula One.
Space Station Regula One, this is
the Starship Enterprise. Come in.
Space Station Regula One,
do you read?
Space Station Regula One, this is
Enterprise. Please acknowledge.
This is Enterprise.
Do you read me?
Space Station Regula One,
do you read? Please come in.
There's no response, sir.
Sensors, Captain?
Still inoperative. There's no way
to ascertain what's inside the station.
No way of telling
if Reliant is still in the area.
What do you make
of that planetoid beyond?
Regula is class 'D'. It consists
of various unremarkable ores.
Essentially a great rock in space.
- Reliant could be behind the rock.
- A distinct possibility.
- Engineering?
- Aye, sir.
Mr Scott? Do you have
enough power for transporters?
Barely, sir.
- I'm going down there.
- Khan could be there!
He's been there, hasn't found
what he wants. Who can you spare?
I can spare me.
Begging your pardon. General Order
15: "No flag officer shall beam
"into a hazardous area
without armed escort."
There's no such regulation!
All right, join the party.
Mr Spock, the ship is yours.
Jim, be careful.
We will!
Indeterminate life signs.
Phasers on stun.
Move out.
Jim!
Rigor hasn't set in. This couldn't
have happened too long ago.
Carol...!
Enterprise calling Space Lab
Regula One. Respond, please.
Admiral! Over here.
Dr Marcus, come in, please!
Oh, my God!
Please acknowledge signal! Please...
This is Lieutenant Saavik.
We're all right. Please stand by.
Oh, sir! It was Khan!
- We found him on Ceti Alpha Five.
- Easy...
He... put... creatures in our bodies!
To control our minds!
It's all right. You're safe now.
Made us say lies... do things.
But we beat him. He thought
he controlled us, but he did not!
- The Captain was strong.
- Captain...
Where's Dr Marcus?
Where are the Genesis materials?
He couldn't find them.
Even the data banks were empty.
- Erased?
- He tortured those people.
But none of them would
tell him anything. He went wild.
He slit their throats.
He wanted to tear the place apart.
But he was late. He had to get back
to Reliant to blow you to bits!
Where's Reliant's crew? Dead?
Marooned on Ceti Alpha Five.
He's mad. He blames you
for the death of his wife.
I know what he blames me for.
The escape pods are all in place.
Where's the Transporter Room?
- Did he make it down here?
- It was not my impression.
He spent most of the time trying to
wring information out of the people.
The unit's been left on. This means
nobody remained to turn it off.
Those people bought escape time
for Genesis with their lives.
This is not logical. These
coordinates are deep inside Regula.
A planetoid we know to be lifeless.
If Stage Two was completed,
it was going to be underground.
- Underground, she said!
- Stage Two of what?
- Kirk to Enterprise.
- Spock here.
Captain Spock, damage report.
If we go by the book, like Saavik,
hours could seem like days.
- Let's have it, Captain.
- The situation is grave.
We won't have main power
for six days.
Auxiliary power
has temporarily failed.
Restoration may be possible
in two days... by the book, Admiral.
You can't even beam us back?
Not at present.
Captain Spock. If you don't hear
from us within one hour,
your orders are to restore
what power you can,
take the Enterprise
to the nearest Starbase
and alert Starfleet Command
when out of jamming range.
Sir, we won't leave you behind!
Uhura, if you don't hear from us,
there won't be anybody behind.
Gentlemen, you can stay here, or...
If it's all the same, Admiral,
we'd like to share the risk.
Right. Let's go. Saavik.
- Go? Where are we going?
- Where they went.
Suppose they went nowhere?
Then this will be your big chance
to get away from it all.
Admiral...
Genesis, I presume.
Phasers down!
You!
- Where's Dr Marcus?
- I'm Dr Marcus!
Jim!
Is that David?
Mother! He killed everybody
we left behind.
Of course he didn't. David,
you're just making this harder.
I'm afraid it's even harder
than you think, Doctor.
Please don't move.
Chekov!
I'm... sorry, Admiral.
Your Excellency,
have you been listening?
I have indeed, Captain.
You have done well.
I knew it! You son-of-a bitch!
- Don't move! Anybody!
- Captain? We are waiting.
- What's the delay?
- All is well, sir.
You have the coordinates
to beam up Genesis.
First things first, Captain.
Kill Admiral Kirk.
Sir, that is difficult. I...
- I try to obey, but...
- Kill him!
I...
Kill him, Terrell, now!
God's sakes!
What is it?
Khan, you bloodsucker!
You're gonna have to do your own
dirty work now! Do you hear me?
Kirk!
Kirk, you're still alive,
my old friend.
Still, "old friend"! You've managed
to kill just about everyone else,
but like a poor marksman,
you keep missing the target.
Perhaps I no longer need
to try, Admiral.
He can't take it!
Khan!
You've got Genesis,
but you don't have me!
You were going to kill me, Khan!
You're going to have to come here!
I've done far worse than kill you.
I've hurt you.
And I wish to go on... hurting you.
I shall leave you as you left me.
As you left her.
Marooned for all eternity,
in the centre of a dead planet.
Buried alive!
Khan!
This is Lieutenant Saavik calling
Enterprise. Can you read us?
- He's coming around.
- Pavel?
It's no use, Admiral.
They're still jamming all channels.
If Enterprise followed orders,
she's gone.
If she couldn't obey, she's finished.
So are we, it looks like.
I don't understand!
Who's responsible for all this?
Who is Khan?
- It's a long story.
- We appear to have plenty of time.
Is there anything to eat? I don't
know about you, but I'm starved.
How can you think of food now?
First order of business. Survival.
There is food in the Genesis cave.
Enough to last a lifetime...
if necessary.
We thought this was Genesis.
It took the Starfleet
Corps of Engineers
ten months in spacesuits
to tunnel out all this.
What we did in there,
we did in a day.
David, why don't you show Dr McCoy
and the Lieutenant our idea of food?
- We can't just sit here!
- Oh, yes, we can.
This is just to give us
something to do, isn't it?
Come on.
- Admiral?
- As your teacher, Mr Spock, says,
"I like to think that there
always are... possibilities."
I did what you wanted.
I stayed away.
Why didn't you tell me?
How can you ask me that?
Were we together?
Were we going to be?
You had your world
and I had mine.
And I wanted him in mine.
Not chasing through the universe
with his father!
Actually... he's a lot like you.
In many ways.
Please tell me what you're feeling.
There's a man out there
I haven't seen in 15 years,
who's trying to kill me.
You show me a son
that'd be happy to help him.
My son...
My life that could have been...
...and wasn't.
And what am I feeling?
Old.
Worn out.
Let me show you something...
...that'll make you feel young,
as when the world was new.
Impulse power restored.
Excellent. More than a match
for poor Enterprise.
You did all this in a day?
The matrix formed in a day.
The lifeforms grew later,
at a substantially accelerated rate.
Jim! This is fantastic!
Have you ever seen the like?
Can I cook or can't I?
Where is she?
Sir? May I ask you a question?
- What's on your mind, Lieutenant?
- The Kobayashi Maru.
Are you asking
if this is that scenario?
On the test, will you tell me what
you did? I would really like to know.
Lieutenant, you are looking
at the only Starfleet cadet
who ever beat the no-win scenario.
How?
I reprogrammed the simulation
so it was possible to rescue the ship.
- What?
- He cheated!
I changed the conditions of the test.
I got a commendation for original
thinking. I don't like to lose.
Then you never faced
that situation... faced death?
I don't believe in a no-win scenario.
- Spock. It's two hours. Ready?
- Right on schedule.
Just give us your coordinates
and we'll beam you aboard.
I don't like to lose.
But we were immobilised.
Captain Spock said it'd be two days.
Lieutenant, you of all people
go by the book. Spock!
- You know Dr Marcus.
- Of course.
- I'm taking this bunch to Sick Bay.
- By the book?
Regulation 46A. "If transmissions
are monitored during battle...
"...no uncoded messages
on an open channel."
- You lied.
- I exaggerated.
Hours instead of days.
Now we have minutes instead of hours.
- Inoperative below C-Deck.
- What is working?
We have partial main power.
Best we could do in two hours.
- Admiral on the bridge.
- Battle stations!
Tactical!
She can still outrun us...
and outgun us.
- But there is the Mutara Nebula.
- Scotty, can we make it inside?
The energiser's bypassed,
so don't give me too many bumps.
- No promises. On your way.
- Trouble with the nebula
is all that static discharge and gas
clouds our tactical display.
Visual won't function
and shields will be useless.
Sauce for the goose, Mr Saavik.
The odds will be even.
There she is!
Not so wounded
as we were led to believe.
So much the better.
Estimating nebula penetration
in 2.2 minutes.
Reliant is closing.
If they go in there, we'll lose them.
Explain it to them.
- That was close.
- They don't want us going in there.
One minute to nebula perimeter.
Why are we slowing?
We daren't follow them into the
nebula. Our shields would be useless.
- They are reducing speed.
- Uhura, patch me in.
You're on, Admiral.
Admiral Kirk here. We tried it
your way, Khan. Game for a rematch?
Khan! I'm laughing
at the "superior intellect".
- Full impulse power.
- No, sir!
You have Genesis.
You can have whatever...
Full power! Damn you!
I'll say this for him,
he's consistent.
We are now entering
the Mutara Nebula.
Emergency lights.
Tactical.
Inoperative.
Raise the shields.
As I feared, sir, not functional.
I'm reducing speed.
Target, sir.
- Phaser lock inoperative.
- Best guess, Sulu. Fire when ready.
Aft torpedoes! Fire!
Hold your course.
Evasive starboard!
Fire!
Damage, Mr Scott?
Admiral, I've got to take
the mains off the line.
- The radiation...
- Scotty?!
Joachim!
Yours... is the... superior...
I shall avenge you!
Could you use another hand, Admiral?
Man the weapons console,
Mr Chekov.
- Spock.
- Sporadic energy readings.
Port side, aft.
Could be an impulse turn.
He won't break off now.
He followed me this far,
he'll be back.
But from where?
He's intelligent,
but not experienced.
His pattern indicates
two-dimensional thinking.
- Full stop.
- Full stop, sir.
Z-minus 10,000 metres.
Stand by photon torpedoes.
Torpedoes ready, sir.
Look sharp.
Fire!
Uhura, send to Commander, Reliant:
"Prepare to be boarded."
Aye, sir.
Commander, Reliant,
this is Enterprise.
Surrender and prepare
to be boarded.
Enterprise to Reliant. You are
ordered to surrender your vessel.
Reliant! Come in, Reliant. You are
Enterprise to Reliant. You're ordered
to surrender your vessel. Respond.
No, Kirk.
The game's not over.
To the last...
I will grapple with thee!
Admiral? Scanning
an energy source on Reliant.
A pattern I've never seen before.
- It's the Genesis Wave!
- What?
They're on a build-up to detonation!
- How soon?
- We encoded four minutes.
- We'll beam aboard and stop it.
- You can't.
Scotty! I need Warp Speed
in three minutes, or we're all dead.
- No response, Admiral.
- Scotty!
Mr Sulu, get us out of here.
Best possible speed.
Are you out of your Vulcan mind?!
No human can tolerate that radiation!
As you are so fond of observing,
Doctor, I am not human.
- You're not going in there!
- Perhaps you're right.
- What is Mr Scott's condition?
- Well, I don't think that he...
I'm sorry, Doctor, I have
no time to discuss this logically.
Remember.
Spock! Get out of there! Spock!
Spock! Get out of there!
- Time from my mark?
- Two minutes ten seconds.
Engine Room! What's happening?
- Spock!
- You dumb ninny! Get out of there!
No! God, don't!
Time?
Three minutes, 30 seconds.
- Distance from Reliant?
- 4,000 kilometres.
We're not going to make it, are we?
No!
No! You can't get away!
From hell's heart, I stab at thee!
For hate's sake,
I spit my last breath... at thee!
- Sir! The mains are back on line!
- Bless you, Scotty. Go, Sulu!
My God, Carol. Look at it.
Engine Room? Well done, Scotty.
Jim! I think you'd better
get down here.
- Bones?
- Better hurry.
Saavik, take the con.
No! You'll flood
the whole compartment!
- He'll die!
- Sir! He's dead already.
It's too late, Jim.
Spock!
Ship... out of danger?
Yes.
Don't grieve, Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs of the many... outweigh...
...the needs of the few.
Or the one.
I never took...
the Kobayashi Maru test.
Until now.
What do you think of my solution?
Spock...!
I have been...
...and always shall be...
...your friend.
Live long... and prosper!
No!
We are assembled here today to pay
final respects to our honoured dead.
And yet it should be noted that,
in the midst of our sorrow,
this death takes place
in the shadow of new life.
The sunrise of a new world.
A world that our beloved comrade
gave his life to protect and nourish.
He did not feel his sacrifice
a vain or empty one.
And we will not debate his profound
wisdom at these proceedings.
Of my friend, I can only say this...
Of all the souls I have
encountered in my travels...
...his was the most...
...human.
Honours... hup!
Come.
I don't mean to intrude.
No, not at all.
I should be on the bridge.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Would you like a drink?
Lieutenant Saavik was right.
You never have faced a death.
No, not like this.
I haven't faced death.
I've cheated death.
I've tricked my way out of death...
...and patted myself on the back
for my ingenuity.
- I know nothing.
- You knew enough to tell Saavik
that how we face death is at least
as important as how we face life.
- Just words.
- But good words.
That's where ideas begin.
Maybe you should listen to them.
I was wrong about you. And I'm sorry.
Is that what you came here to say?
Mainly.
And also that I'm... proud...
...very proud... to be your son.
Captain's Log, Stardate 8141.6.
Starship Enterprise departing
for Ceti Alpha Five to pick up
the crew of USS Reliant.
All is well.
And yet, I can't help wondering
about the friend I leave behind.
"There are always possibilities,"
Spock said.
And if Genesis is indeed
"life from death",
I must return to this place again.
He's really not dead.
As long as we remember him.
"It's a far, far better thing I do
than I have ever done before.
"A far better resting place
"that I go to than I've ever known."
Is that a poem?
Something Spock was trying
to tell me. On my birthday.
You okay, Jim? How do you feel?
Young.
I feel young.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the continuing voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission...
to explore strange new worlds.
To seek out new lifeforms
and new civilisations.
To boldly go...
where no man has gone before.
Subtitles: SDI Media