How are you?
- And how are you?
I'm fine, I go to school.
Guess where we're taKing you today?
To eat "passatelli" at the farm.
What do you thinK of that?
LooK, Dad's here too.
He's a lovely lad!
Give Dad a Kiss.
How's he?
- He's normal.
He's grown, hasn't he?
He's in the fifth grade.
And he got dead drunK
the other night.
How are you Keeping?
- I'm much better.
Mamma, the pastries!
Uncle, Mamma brought you pastries.
We'll be bacK before evening.
Have a smoKe on me.
Is Father Pazzaglia still alive?
He's been dead ten years now.
He's been gone quite a time!
He was alive last year.
- That was Father Amadeo.
Is he dead as well?
- No, he's alive.
Exactly, that's what I was saying.
I saw him last year, walKing
along with a bunch of flowers.
I wonder where he was going?
Teo was a bright lad
when he was eight.
I don't want
to offend you, Aurelio,
but Teo was smarter than you
at school.
I grant you that.
That's quite true.
He still is, even now.
Do you liKe being with us, Teo?
Uncle, the sea's over there.
It's liKe a blue streaK.
Dad, can I drive the horse?
- No!
What can I do just sitting here,
then? Let me drive it!
That'll be the first time a horse
was driven by a mule!
That's a shorter road.
An awful road, full of potholes,
enough to taKe this carriage.
Is something wrong?
Why do you carry those
in your pocKet?
These stones!
Aren't they heavy?
- They're beautiful, stones are.
Stop the carriage!
Teo needs to taKe a leaK!
If he has to...
Watch how you get down.
You too?
Don't be long, Grandpa,
I'm hungry.
My father's father used to say:
To be fit as a fiddle,
you have to piddle!
To be fit as a frog,
pee often liKe a dog.
How green!
How beautiful, Teo...
How old's the mare?
- Three years and two months.
She's only got one vice,
she can't stand train whistles.
When I'm at the station stand,
it's really a job to hold her!
What'll you give her to eat today?
- Cappelletti (pasta).
You forgot to unbutton your fly!
Uncle pissed in his pants!
They said he was normal!
You didn't undo your fly!
He forgot.
It's really true.
The sea looKs liKe a blue streaK.
You pissed in your pants!
- Shut up!
He didn't open the shop!
It doesn't matter,
you can change at the farm.
Come here, or I'll throw myself
under the wheels!
Sit down, you criminal!
Shall we move on?
Ah, that was a fine meal!
You all go and see the spring.
My son Teo and I will stay here
and have another glass of wine.
Fine, but just one and no more.
Know what I'll do?
I'll have a nap.
Good. It won't do you any harm
here in the shade.
The eggs's lovely, isn't it, Teo?
Me too. When I see an egg,
I could looK at it for hours.
I asK myself how Nature manages
to maKe things so perfect.
God made Nature,
not an ignorant lout liKe you!
Oh, don't bust my chops!
See you later here.
I'm relying on you, Dad. Menghino,
how far away is this spring?
Uncle, looK, I'm hypnotizing it.
Oliva, there's a toad!
It looKs liKe Father Balosa!
What's it liKe?
- Fantastic!
It won't give you a hangover.
We'll put it here.
Throw that stone away!
You naughty little boy!
I Know what your name is,
you delinquent!
Dad, Uncle Teo's up a tree!
What's that? What's he shouting?
- I can't understand.
Uncle Teo's up a tree!
I want a woman!
But where am I going
to get you a woman, my boy?
Uncle's up there.
I want a woman!
There he is, up there!
Come down, Teo,
you'll hurt yourself.
QuicKly, get a ladder!
Is this how you Keep an eye on him?
How did he get up there?
I'll go up.
- I'll hammer you into the ground.
How did he get up there?
If he falls he'll breaK every bone.
You go indoors and stop
playing the actress.
How did he do it?
We were having a drinK,
and liKe a shot...
He was away and up there
liKe a cat.
What're you doing?
Throwing stones at your old dad!
That's enough, now!
Now, now! Don't you do the same!
Come down, Teo,
your brother's angry.
Come down, now!
I WANT A WOMAN!!!
It's quite a normal urge. He's 42!
- Yes, but he'll fall down.
When I was 42... I'll tell you!
Now, that's enough, Teo!
Climb down, Teo!
Good shot, Uncle,
right on his head!
Right on the target.
Now, I'll come up,
but don't throw anything at me!
We'll taKe some birds home.
Do you want to Kill us all?
- Now, I'm coming up.
Yes sirree! If you throw
one at me, you'll hear about it!
What a shot! Murderer! I hope
somebody KicKs you in the nuts!
Christ, what'll I do now?
JerK off?
I'm an asshole, a stupid asshole.
Well, let's all go home!
Driver, hitch up the horse,
we're going home!
Are you going to leave him up there?
- Yes! Hitch up the horse. Let's go!
As you wish.
- Dad! Titta!
Call your mother!
Where's your mother?
Leaving him there?
- He's all right up there.
Let's go! I want to go home.
But he's my son!
Aurelio, listen to me.
I want a woman!
- Miranda!
Teo, we're going. Come down!
We're just pretending.
Listen, Aurelio...
Send me up there. He'll come down.
Everyone in the carriage!
We're leaving right away. Get in.
Teo, what're you doing? Staying
there? We're going now. It's late.
It's getting darK.
Who'll taKe you bacK?
You going to stay up there?
All right, then, ciao!
Come down!
Teo, Holy Mother of God!
Are you going to come down?
We're leaving!
Good-bye, Uncle!
He'll Kill the lot of us, today.
Come on, let's have you all out!
Get out, now! No questions!
What're you crying about?
Now, you drive to the hospital
and call the attendants.
And come bacK right away,
or I'll throw myself down the well!
What're you crying about?
It's a big laugh, it's just comic!
Listen to him, Miranda.
Poor lad.
Do you feel better?
I want a woman!
I can't stand any more!
MaKe him shut up!
I've had enough!
Dad... Dad...
- What do you want?
Shall I go and call Volpina?
LooK, Dad.
Mamma, they've arrived.
Good evening, Doctor.
- What's happened?
He's up the tree.
- Nice place. Fresh air. All yours?
It's only an old farm.
He's been up there for five hours.
You can't see him now,
because of the foliage.
What have you done to him?
- Nothing.
He's been shouting
and throwing stones.
I hope he won't always be liKe
this... his whole life, Doctor.
A dwarf nun!
Lt'll be bad for him
and worse for us.
Keep cool, she'll attend to things.
Were you getting a bit of air?
Is she going up?
Come down! I'm not going
to play these damn silly games!
Jesus, just looK at that!
She's got him to come down!
She's got him down
and he's quite happy.
Teo, Teo...
Here he is.
So, have you been up
to your tricKs again, have you?
What were you doing up there?
Counting how many stones
fig trees grow in this season.
TaKe him home.
Some days he's normal, some days
he isn't... just liKe all of us.
Ciao, Uncle!
- Titta, taKe care.
You can see Gigino's place
from up there.
It's a long time since
I saw him.
Between 11 o'clocK and midnight,
in Caghetta's boat.
It's thirty stories high
and has sixteen smoKestacKs.
ThinK what a pirate could do
with a ship liKe that!
Where's "Ronald Coleman"?
I don't see him.
Gradisca! Hurray for Gradisca!
Hello, sister.
- Your steamboat. Climb aboard!
Where're all these people going?
Where're they going with hearts
all pounding? Where're they going?
Today is a very important day for
our country, for our fatherland...
Come on, we're off!
If you drop me,
you'll have to pay for it all.
I'd liKe to tell you, but I can't
because it's all still in the air.
Where're these people going?
How far out will it be?
- Eight Kilometers.
But thanKs to Galileo, it will
seem liKe 400 meters to us.
Marvelous! Lt'll seem liKe
it's coming straight at us.
Mr. Lawyer, how much will it weigh?
About two and a half times
the weight of the Grand Hotel.
Plus the Arch of Augustus!
"Go thou, Queen of the Sea
"Thou passeth and thy destiny
"I shall follow in the waves
"Watching the glistening waKe..."
Get closer to your mother,
and you move nearer to your son.
SucK me off! The water's
really freezing!
My nuts has shriveled to the size
of two dried beans.
You swam out?
- Sure!
I did the Australian crawl.
"I want to dance with you
"All night liKe this..."
The third day I went there
with my boat, whistled as usual
and out came the dolphin.
It looKed at me
and said "mamma"!
What a load of bull!
Dolphins are intelligent,
my dentist told me so.
LooK how many there are.
Millions and millions
and millions of stars.
Jesus Christ, you guys!
I wonder
how the whole lot
stays up there in place?
It's pretty simple for us.
If we have to build a house,
so many bricKs, so much lime...
But up there, Sweet Jesus!
Where do you put the foundations?
They aren't just confetti,
you Know!
Are you asleep? Answer me!
Are you cold? Want my jacKet?
Come on, taKe my jacKet.
Put it round your shoulders or
you'll get a chill and complain.
We've still a long time to wait,
haven't we? It's one o'clocK.
How would I Know? They said
it'd be around midnight.
Even if it's late, it's coming
from America, you Know.
Go fucK yourselves, all of you!
He's a friend...
He sent you best wishes.
Every time I was full of hope,
but it never came to anything.
And now...
Know how old I am?
- Fifty-two?
I'm not ashamed to tell the truth.
In fact, I always add
a few years on. I'm thirty.
That's surprising, my darling.
- I haven't given up hope.
I thought you were seventeen age.
I want one of those long encounters
that last a lifetime.
I want a family, children,
a husband
to chat with in the evening
at supper, maybe,
and to maKe love with now and then,
because that's important too.
But affection is perhaps
even more necessary than love.
I'm so full of affection.
But who can I lavish it on,
who wants it?
Why are you crying? LooK at
the silly girl, she's crying!
The girl is delicate
and sensitive, oh yes!
She's right! Men are all the same!
- Don't cry, my darling!
Here it is!
- Dad, Dad!
The Rex! The Rex!
Hurray for the Rex! The greatest
thing the regime has built!
As the representative of the Podesta,
I wish you a safe journey!
Long live Italy!
What's it liKe?
Just looK at this!
Can't see a darned thing!
I'll Keep to the wall.
The last fog liKe this was in '22.
Careful now, stop.
There's a man here!
Well, damn it all.
Gina! Gina!
Where am I?
I don't seem to be anywhere.
If death is liKe this,
I don't thinK much of it.
Everything's gone.
People, trees, birds, wine...
Up yours!
Dino, I can't even find
my house. Where am I?
You are in front of your house.
It's there...
Where're you going in all this fog?
- To school. Ciao, Grandpa.
Just thinK of that.
I was in Norway. Two women...
beautiful, huge, Norwegians!
Beans, olives,
toasted melon seeds...
It's open, you can get in.
Last one in's a queer!
Naso, get an eyeful of this.
It's gorgeous!
Where are you, my love?
It was number 18.
18... Campari.
Aldina, do you want to Know
who it was?
We Know, it was Campari.
I Knew him in the race at Monza.
Aldina!
Be careful, Lallo!
What is it?
- An ear.
LooK, an ear!
Can I come in?
- I'm closed.
Can I come in, miss?
What do you want?
- A cigarette.
Can I help you?
- You couldn't manage.
What do you mean? I can lift 80
Kilos. I can even lift my father.
What do you weigh?
- I don't Know.
I could lift you, too.
Let's see you.
I really can.
- Let's see.
You silly boy,
put me down, let me go!
You're strong!
- I'll lift you again.
Now that's enough.
What're you doing?
You'll let me fall! You mad thing!
Put me down, that's enough!
You'll let me drop, you crazy boy!
You really are mad...
What's happened to me? My head...
See how many times I did it?
Yes, my little darling...
Come here... you really are nice.
Drive me crazy, just a little.
What should I do?
- SucK!
Come on...
You can have this one, too...
Don't blow! SucK!
Is this right?
- Yes, darling, yes!
You have to sucK, you idiot!
I can't breathe!
Let me alone. Get out, now,
I've got to close up.
What was it you wanted?
A cigarette?
I'll give you one.
Now, beat it!
I can't manage it.
Come on, get out!
- Good night!
DrinK it. It'll do you good.
It's hot!
- It has to be hot.
There's a fly.
Where is it?
- It was there.
The only house with flies
in winter...
How did it happen with you and Dad?
What? - How'd you meet,
fall in love, get married?
What's all this about?
Anyway, who remembers!
Your dad's not a great one
for compliments.
He was a laborer at Saludecio,
my folKs had a bit of money and
they didn't thinK much of him...
Well, we eloped
without saying a word to anyone.
When did he give you
your first Kiss?
What Kind of a question is that?
I don't even Know whether
there was one.
The first time, he raised his hat,
and that's all.
It was the most one could do
in those days.
It's not liKe now,
when all Kinds of things go on.
But I never manage anything.
- Stay covered, you're all sweaty.
What do you mean "manage,"
and you still in short pants?
Well, get me some long ones then,
liKe the other Kids!
What others? Gina!
She told me I wasn't to send
any more love letters.
Go and asK the doctor
to come as soon as he can.
Get him to examine you
at the same time.
Run along...
But I'll send letters
just when I liKe.
In Africa! I'll become
a doctor and go to Africa!
That'll teach her!
It's snowing outside!
It's true, it's snowing!
Professor Fighetta, up yours!
If it goes on liKe this, there'll
be no school for a few days.
The mountains are all white.
Let's go and see the snow
on the sea.
It's wet, it won't sticK.
Go away!
Get the hell out of the way!
Stop there! The sparrows!
Wait, I'll come with you.
Titta! LooK how it's coming down!
Let's open the window.
Lovely!
Me too!
It's still snowing! Four days
this goddamn stuff's been around!
This will go down as
the Year of the Big Snow.
Since the last Ice Age,
it never snowed so heavily
in our town.
That must've been a boy,
not the other person.
As I was saying...
the exceptional years were
1541... 1694...
1728... 1888...
when oddly enough,
it snowed on July 13th.
Where's she?
How's your mother?
- Better now.
She's still in hospital,
but she's off the critical list.
That's good, poor woman.
Give her my regards.
Your mother's a Kind lady.
She always gave me soup
and wine. She's good...
How are you feeling?
I've brought you some flowers.
- ThanK you. How are you?
Hello, Aurelio. They're lovely!
I was just looKing out,
now I'll go bacK to bed.
But I'm feeling better today.
What lovely colors!
Are you hot, with this?
Have you eaten?
- Yes.
Are you still annoying your father?
- He whips so hard!
I'll finish up, stupid!
There's a nice garden here,
I didn't Know.
It looKs as though it's in bloom,
with the snow.
It's still snowing.
In one way you're lucKy to be here
warm in bed, with this weather.
He's tired, poor man,
when he gets home.
You shouldn't answer bacK,
you're a grown up now.
Don't throw ice! It hurts!
Wind and rain, go home again.
I don't want to feel the pain.
Idiot! No!
A quite difficult shot, Excellency!
No! Not at Gradisca! No!
Enough! I give up!
If you breaK my windows,
I'll breaK your sKull!
Who is it?
What is it?
LooK, it's the Count peacocK!
There it is!
It's coming down!
Shall we catch it, boys?
I don't understand.
What's happened?
I'll tell you in the car, Uncle.
Why in the car?
Where're we going?
Quite near. To Aunt Zaira's farm.
A relative's come from America
and wants to say hello to you.
Well, why doesn't he
come here, then?
Who is this relative?
My aunt is dead.
Bear up.
No, don't do that...
Open up!
No, I won't!
Lallo! He's fainted.
Dad, Uncle's feeling poorly.
TaKe him to the whorehouse, then!
MaKe the sign of the cross.
How do you feel now?
- Better!
Don't taKe it so hard...
be strong!
Now everybody in line.
Where're the orphans?
Stop that!
Give me your arm, Naso.
MaKe way, maKe way,
my breasts are full of milK!
I raise my glass
to the newly weds and say...
May bride and groom find
marriage glowing in Battipaglia.
When you're drunK,
you can even rhyme!
Gradisca's getting married
and going away!
We're sorry if we made you angry,
and we hate to see you go!
You'll miss us badly!
Silence is golden,
but words are silver.
May this married couple live
happily ever after!
Where's the bride?
Our Gradisca is going away because
she's found her Gary Cooper.
It's true that Gary's cowboy,
while Matteo is a carabiniere
but love's always love.
Good lucK, Gradisca!
Long live the bride and groom!
You have crowned
your dream of love.
Now it's your duty
to have many children.
For your family, for the church
and for your country!
Now we're all together...
one more toast before we leave.
Photograph! Photograph!
Now we'll taKe the photograph.
A mirror!
Everybody get behind the bride!
She's lovely, our Ninola!
- Why're you crying?
I'm not, now.
- Get closer together.
The carabiniere
must move bacK a little.
Stand in the light.
Hold it!
It's raining.
Smile.
- O.K., O.K. Another one.
Don't fall all over us,
you drunKen lout! - Gangway!
Let's move into the sun, the bride
in the center. Ready for a photo?
I've made up another rhyme
that goes liKe this.
Though the world may be full
of beautiful things
Full of towns that are attractive,
even more than here,
A drop of water'll be good
for you... you'll get a bath.
Get up!
It's stopped raining, sit down.
Play!
A wet bride is a lucKy bride!
Viva I'ltalia!
How will you live,
so far away from here?
Good-bye to you all!
Go home!
Biscein bids you good-bye!
Naso, I'm going home!
Wait for me, I'll come with you!
My bouquet! Wait!
Good-bye! I love you all!
Gradisca's going!
- She's leaving!
Good-bye, Gradisca!
The puffballs!
Where's Titta?
Shall we go fishing in the harbor?
Titta's went away some time ago.