[Birds Squawking]
[Squawking, Cawing]
[Wings Flapping]
[Chirping, Twittering]
[Squawking Intensifies]
[Cable Car Bell Dinging]
[Squawking Continues]
[Car Horn Honking]
[Boy Wolf Whistles]
[Squawking, Chirping]
[Birds Chirping]
Hello, Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Miss Daniels.
Have you ever
seen so many gulls?
What do you suppose it is?
There must be a storm at sea.
That can drive them inland,
you know.
I was hoping you'd be
a little late.
He hasn't arrived yet.
But you said 3:00.
I know.
I've been calling
all morning.
Oh, Miss Daniels,
you have no idea.
They are
so difficult to get.
Really, they are.
We have to get them
from India when they're
baby chicks, and then...
This one won't be a chick,
will he?
Oh, no, certainly not.
This will be a full-grown
mynah bird.
- And he'll talk?
- Well, yes, of course he'll...
Well, no, you'll have
to teach him to talk.
I guess maybe I'd better phone.
They said 3:00.
Maybe it's the traffic.
I'll call.
Would you mind waiting?
Well, maybe you'd better
deliver him.
Let me give you
my address.
Oh, well, all right,
but I'm sure they're
on the way.
Would you mind
if I called?
No. All right.
I wonder if you
could help me.
What?
I said, I wonder
if you could help me.
- Yes. What is it
you're looking for, sir?
- Lovebirds.
Lovebirds, sir?
Yes. I understand there
are different varieties.
Is that true?
Well, yes,
there are.
Well, these are for
my sister for her birthday,
and as she's only gonna be 11,
I wouldn't want
a pair of birds...
that were...
too demonstrative.
I understand completely.
At the same time, I wouldn't
want them to be too aloof.
No, of course not.
Do you happen to have
a pair of birds that are...
just friendly?
Oh, I think so.
Now, then, let me see.
[Chirping Continues]
Aren't those lovebirds?
No. Those are, uh...
red birds.
I thought they were
strawberry finches.
Yes. We call
them that too.
Here we are.
Lovebirds.
Those are canaries.
Doesn't this
make you feel awful?
Doesn't what make me feel...
Having all these poor, innocent
creatures caged up like this?
Well, we can't just let them
fly around the shop.
I suppose not.
L- Is there an ornithological
reason for keeping them
in separate cages?
Certainly.
It's to protect the species.
Yes, that's important,
especially during
the molting season.
That's a particularly
dangerous time.
Are they molting now?
Oh, some of them are.
How can you tell?
Well, they... get a sort
of hangdog expression.
Yes, I see.
Well, what about
the lovebirds?
Are you sure
you wouldn't like to see
a canary instead?
We have some very nice
canaries this week.
All right.
May I see it, please?
Oh! Oh!
[Mrs. MacGruder]
What is it?
Oh! Oh!
[Mrs. MacGruder]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
There we are.
Oh, there.
Wonderful.
Back in your gilded cage,
Melanie Daniels.
What did you say?
I was merely drawing
a parallel, Miss Daniels.
How did you know my name?
A little birdie
told me.
Good day, Miss Daniels.
Madam.
Hey, wait a minute.
I don't know you.
Ah, but I know you.
How?
- We met in court.
- We never met in court
or anyplace else.
- That's true. I'll rephrase it.
I saw you in court.
- When?
Don't you remember one of your
practical jokes that resulted
in the smashing of a window?
- I didn't break that window.
- Yes, but your little prank did.
- The judge should've
put you behind bars.
- What are you, a policeman?
I merely believe in the law.
And I'm not too keen
on practical jokers.
- What do you call
your lovebird story...
- I really wanted the lovebirds.
You knew I didn't work here.
You deliberately...
I recognized you when I came in.
I thought you might like
to know what it's like to be
on the other end of a gag.
What do you think
of that?
I think you're a louse.
I am. Good day,
Miss Daniels. Madam.
And I'm glad you didn't get
your lovebirds.
I'll find something else.
See you in court.
Who was that man?
I have no idea.
[Cable Car Bell Dinging]
They said the mynah bird would
be here later this afternoon,
if you care to come back.
No, you'd better send him.
May I use this phone?
Why, certainly.
Daily News?
It's Melanie Daniels.
Could you get me the City Desk?
Just a minute,
Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Charlie.
Melanie.
I want you to do
a favor for me.
No, this is a small one.
Pressure you?
Why, Charlie, darling,
would I try to pressure you?
Would you call the Department
of Motor Vehicles for me?
Find out who owns
this license plate:
W- J-H-0-0-3.
Yes, a California plate.
No. I'll stop off
in a little while.
Is Daddy in his office?
No, I don't want
to break in on a meeting.
Tell him I'll see him later.
Thank you, Charlie.
Do you have any lovebirds?
Well, no, not in the shop,
but I can order them for you.
How soon?
Well... Well, when
would you want them?
Immediately.
Well, I could probably have them
here by tomorrow morning.
Would that be
all right?
That would be just fine.
[Chirping]
[Door Slides Closed,
Elevator Hums]
[Door Slides Closed]
Miss, is that
for Mitch Brenner?
Yes.
He's not home.
That's all right.
He won't be back
until Monday... I mean,
if those birds are for him.
Monday?
Yes.
I don't think you should leave
them in the hall, do you?
Well... Where did he go?
Bodega Bay.
He goes there every weekend.
Where's that?
Up the coast,
about 60 miles north of here.
Sixty mi... Oh!
It's an hour and a half
by freeway, or two hours
if you take the Coast Highway.
I'd look after them myself,
but I'm going away too.
I'm awfully sorry.
[Engine Revving]
[Tires Screeching]
[Bell Dings]
Good morning.
I wonder if you
could help me.
I'll try my best.
I'm looking for a man
named Mitchell Brenner.
Yeah.
Do you know him?
Where does he live?
Right here, Bodega Bay.
- Yes, I know, but where?
- Right across the bay there.
Where?
Now, see where
I'm pointing?
Yes.
[Shopkeeper]
See them two big trees
across there?
On the other side
of the bay? Yes.
And the white house?
Yes.
That's where
the Brenners live.
The Brenners?
Mr. And Mrs. Brenner?
No. Just Lydia
and the two kids.
The two kids?
Yeah, Mitch
and the little girl.
Oh, I see.
How do I get down there?
You follow the road
around the bay, and that'll
take you to their front door.
The front door. Is there
a back road I can take?
No. That's the only road.
You see, I want
to surprise them.
Oh.
I don't want them
to see me arrive.
Oh.
It's a surprise, you see.
Well, you could get yourself
a boat and cut right across
the bay to their dock.
Where would I get a boat?
Down by
the Tides Restaurant.
- Did you ever handle
an outboard boat?
- Of course.
- Want me to order one for you?
- Well, thank you.
What name?
Daniels.
Okay.
[Shop Bell Dings]
[Rotary Phone Dialing]
I wonder if you
could tell me...
Yeah.
Hold it a minute, please.
- The little girl's name?
- The little Brenner girl?
Yes.
Uh, Alice, I think.
[Shuffling Sound]
Harry, what's
the Brenner girl's name?
- [Harry] Lois.
- [Shopkeeper]
Alice, isn't it?
- [Harry]
No, it's Lois.
- It's Alice.
- Are you sure?
- Well, I'm not positive,
if that's what you mean.
I need her exact name.
Oh, uh... Just hold on
one more minute, please.
In that case,
I'll tell you what you do.
Go straight through town
till you see a little hotel
on your left.
Then you turn right there.
Now, you got that?
Yes.
Near the top of the hill,
you'll see the school,
and just beyond,
a little house
with a red mailbox.
That's where Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher, lives.
You ask her about
the little Brenner girl.
Well, thank you.
Save yourself a lot of trouble.
Name's Alice for sure.
Can I have the boat
in about 20 minutes?
How much for
the phone calls?
Oh, it's nothing.
Thank you.
[Children Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
[Engine Stops]
[Doorbell Rings]
[Woman]
Who is it?
Me.
Who's "me"?
Miss Hayworth?
Yes.
I'm Melanie Daniels.
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
Yes?
The man at the post
office sent me.
He said you could
tell me the name
of the Brenner girl.
Cathy?
The one who lives in the
white house across the bay?
That's the one. Cathy Brenner.
He seemed sure it was
either Alice or Lois.
Which is why the mail
never gets delivered to
the right place in this town.
I'm sorry.
Smoke?
Thank you.
Did, uh... you want to see
Cathy about something?
Well, not exactly.
Oh.
Are you a friend
of Mitch's?
No, not really.
I've been wanting a cigarette
for the last 20 minutes.
I just couldn't convince
myself to stop.
This tilling of the soil
can become compulsive, you know.
It's a very pretty garden.
Oh, thank you.
Well, it's something to do
in your spare time.
There's a lot of spare time
in Bodega Bay.
Are, uh, you planning
on staying long?
No, just a few hours.
Then you're leaving
after you see Cathy.
Well, something
like that.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to sound
so mysterious.
Actually, it's
none of my business.
Well, I better be
on my way.
Thank you
very much.
Not at all.
Did you drive up from San
Francisco by the coast road?
Yes.
Nice drive.
It's very beautiful.
Is that where
you met Mitch?
Yes.
I guess that's where
everyone meets Mitch.
Now you sound a bit mysterious,
Miss Hayworth.
[Chuckles]
Do I?
I don't mean to.
Actually, I'm an open book,
I'm afraid.
[Chirping]
Or, rather, a closed one.
- Oh, pretty. What are they?
- Lovebirds.
I see.
Good luck, Miss Daniels.
Thank you.
Can I get out this way?
[Engine Starts]
Go right around.
It'll take you back
to the main road.
Thank you.
[Engine Revs]
[Engine Starts]
[Seagulls Cawing]
Do you have a boat
for Miss Daniels?
Yes, ma'am.
It's the one
right below.
[Chirping]
[Motor Starts]
[Motor Stops]
[Motor Cranking]
[Motor Starts]
Are you all right?
Yes, I think so.
What made it do that?
That's the damnedest thing
I ever saw.
It seemed to swoop down
at you deliberately.
Oh, you're bleeding too.
Let's take care of that.
Okay?
That's a girl.
Come on.
What happened, Mitch?
Gull hit her.
A gull?
Oh. Let's try
up at the restaurant,
all right?
Might need a tetanus shot.
I had a booster
before I went abroad last May.
[People Chattering]
What happened?
Hello, Deke.
Young lady cut herself.
Shall I call a doctor?
I don't think it's
that serious. Let's see.
Helen, get some cotton
and antiseptic.
Um, you cut yourself
outside, miss?
Don't worry, Deke.
She did it in a boat.
I had a man trip and fall in
the parking lot once. Sued me
before I could bat an eyelash.
I don't think Miss Daniels
is gonna sue anybody.
Here.
Well, you're the lawyer.
Thank you.
What's that?
Just some peroxide.
I'll clean out the cut.
So you're a lawyer.
That's right. Of course,
I usually defend people,
but if I were prosecuting...
Do you practice here?
Uh-uh, San Francisco.
What are you doing up here?
What kind of law?
Criminal.
Is that why you want to see
everyone behind bars?
Oh, not everyone.
Only violators
and practical jokers.
That's right.
Ow!
Oh, sorry.
What are you doing up here?
Didn't you see
the lovebirds?
You mean, you came all this way
to bring me those birds?
To bring
your sister those birds.
You said it was her birthday.
Besides, I was
coming up anyway.
What for?
To see a friend of mine.
Careful.
Oh, sorry.
Uh... who's your friend?
Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher.
Annie Hayworth.
Well, small world.
Yes.
How do you know Annie?
We went to school
together... college.
Did you? Imagine that.
How long are you staying
up here?
The weekend.
Well, I think
the bleeding's almost stopped.
Why don't you hold that on...
So you came up
to see Annie, huh?
Yes.
- I think you came up to see me.
- Now, why would I want
to see you of all people?
I don't know, but you must've
gone to a lot of trouble...
to find out who I was
and where I lived.
It was no trouble at all.
I simply called
my father's newspaper.
Besides, I was
coming up anyway.
I've already told you that.
You really like me, huh?
I loathe you.
You have no manners.
You're arrogant and conceited.
I wrote you a letter
about it, in fact,
but I tore it up.
- What did it say?
- None of your business.
I can't say I like your
seagulls much, either.
I come all the way up here to...
You were coming up
anyway, remember?
[Door Opens]
Mitch?
I thought I saw your car.
What are you doing in town?
I had to acknowledge
a delivery.
A what?
Mother, I'd like you
to meet Melanie Daniels.
Miss Daniels, my mother.
How do you do?
How do you do, Miss Daniels?
Acknowledge a what?
A delivery.
Miss Daniels brought us
some birds from San Francisco.
Oh.
For Cathy for her birthday.
Where is she?
Across at Brinkmeyer's.
Miss Daniels is staying
up here for the weekend.
So I've already invited her
for dinner tonight.
- Well, you did go to the trouble
of bringing those birds.
- Oh, I couldn't possibly.
You did say birds?
Yes, lovebirds.
Oh, I see.
So we couldn't let you
get away without thanking you
in some small way.
And you haven't met Cathy,
and you are staying
the weekend.
Well, yes, but...
You are, aren't you?
Certainly, but...
Then it's all settled.
What time is dinner,
Mother?
7:00, the same as usual.
- I'll pick you up.
Where are you staying?
- With Annie, of course.
Oh, of course.
How stupid of me.
A quarter of 7:00?
Annie may have
made other plans.
I'll have to see.
Besides, I can find
my own way.
You're sure now?
You won't hire a boat
or anything?
I'm sure.
7:00, then.
Maybe.
We'll be waiting for you.
How's your head?
Much better, thank you.
A gull hit me,
Mrs. Brenner, that's all.
[Rings]
Oh, hi.
Did you find her all right?
Yes, I did.
I was wondering...
Uh, that sign there.
Do you suppose
I could have the room
for just a single night?
I was planning on renting it
for a longer time...
I would appreciate it.
I've tried
everywhere in town.
They're all full.
Well, all right.
Got your bags in the car?
[Chuckles]
Well, it's utilitarian,
I'll say that.
I just picked up
some things for the night
at the general store.
I hadn't planned
on staying very long.
Yes, I know.
Did something
unexpected come up?
Yes. May I use your phone?
I'd like to call home.
I just put some coffee
on the stove.
[Seagulls Cawing]
Don't they ever
stop migrating?
[Seagulls Cawing]
[Rings]
Hi!
Miss Daniels?
Yes.
Oh, they're beautiful!
They're just what I wanted.
Is there a man and a woman?
[Cathy]
I can't tell which is which.
Well, I suppose so.
Hello there.
Annie had no plans, huh?
No.
We're very glad
you could come.
Are you hungry?
Reasonably.
Dinner's just
about ready.
We've been looking
at the chickens. Something
seems to be wrong with them.
There's nothing wrong
with those chickens.
I'm going to call
Fred Brinkmeyer right now.
What good's that gonna do?
The chickens won't eat.
He sold the feed to me,
didn't he?
Caveat emptor, Mother.
Let the buyer beware.
Whose side are you on?
Merely quoting
the law, dear.
Never mind the law.
This won't take long,
Miss Dan... Hello, Fred?
Lydia Brenner.
I didn't interrupt
your dinner, did I?
How about a drink?
I'd love one.
That feed you
sold me is no good.
The chicken feed.
Well, it's just no good.
The chickens won't eat it.
They're always hungry.
I opened a sack for them
when I got home, and they
just wouldn't touch it.
You know chickens
as well as I do,
and when they won't eat,
there's something wrong
with what they're being fed.
No, they're not
fussy chickens.
Who? What's he
got to do with it?
Is that your father?
Mm-hmm.
Please sit down.
I don't care how many sacks
of feed you sold him.
My chicken...
Oh, I see.
Dan Fawcett.
This afternoon?
That proves what I'm saying.
The feed you sold us...
Oh.
Well, maybe I better
go over and see him.
You don't think
there's something
going around, do you?
No, never!
No, they don't
seem sick at all.
They just won't eat.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'll try
to go over and see him.
Maybe he...
Uh-huh.
All right.
Thanks.
He had a call from
Dan Fawcett a while ago.
His chickens
won't eat either.
It's what you said, Mom.
Mr. Brinkmeyer's feed
is no good.
No, Cathy.
He sold Mr. Fawcett
a different brand.
You don't think
they're getting sick,
do you, Mitch?
I still don't understand
how you knew I wanted lovebirds.
Your brother told me.
Then you knew Mitch
in San Francisco?
Is that right?
No, not exactly.
Mitch knows a lot
of people in San Francisco.
Of course, they're mostly hoods.
- Cathy!
- Well, Mom, he's
the first to admit it.
He's spends half his day
in the detention cells
at the Hall of Justice.
In a democracy, Cathy,
everyone is entitled
to a fair trial.
Your brother's
practice...
Aw, Mom, please!
I know all
that democracy jazz.
They're still hoods.
He has a client now
who shot his wife
in the head six times.
Six times!
Can you imagine it?
I mean, even twice
would be overdoing it,
don't you think?
- Why did he shoot her?
- He was watching
a ball game on television.
- What?
- His wife changed the channel.
Are you coming
to my party tomorrow?
I don't think so.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
Don't you like us?
Oh, darling,
of course I do.
Don't you like
Bodega Bay?
I don't know yet.
Mitch likes it very much.
He comes up every weekend,
you know,
even though he has
his own apartment
in the city.
He says San Francisco's
like an anthill
at the foot of a bridge.
I suppose it does get
hectic at times.
Well, if you do decide to come,
don't say I told you about it.
It's supposed to be
a surprise party.
They've got
this whole complicated
thing figured out...
where I'm going to Michele's
for the afternoon,
and Michele's mother will say
that she has a headache, would
I mind if she took me home.
Then when I get home here,
all the kids'll jump out!
Oh, won't you come?
Won't you please come?
I don't think so.
She's a charming girl,
isn't she, Mitch?
Hmm? Yes.
Certainly pretty.
Mm-hmm.
- How long have you known her?
- Now, I told you, dear,
we met yesterday.
In a bird shop.
She was selling birds?
No, no. I just led her
into believing that I believed
she was, and then...
It's all very complicated.
But she did buy the lovebirds
and then drove all the way here.
Mother.
Yes?
Where did you
go to law school?
Forgive me.
I suppose I'm
just naturally curious
about a girl like that.
She's very rich,
isn't she?
Yeah, I suppose so.
Her father's part owner of
one of the big newspapers.
You'd think he could manage
to keep her name out of print.
She's always mentioned
in the columns, Mitch.
Yes, I know.
She is the one who jumped
into a fountain in Rome
last summer, isn't she?
Yes.
I supposed I'm old-fashioned.
I know it was supposed to be
very warm there, but...
Well, actually the newspapers
said she was naked.
Yes, I know, dear.
It's none of my business,
but when you bring
a girl like that...
Darling?
Yes?
I think I can handle
Melanie Daniels by myself.
Well... as long as you know
what you want, Mitch.
I know exactly
what I want.
Be able to find
your way back all right?
Oh, yes.
Will I be seeing you again?
San Francisco's
a long way from here.
I'm in San Francisco
five days a week with a lot
of time on my hands.
I'd like to see you.
Maybe we could go swimming
or something.
Mother tells me
you like to swim.
How does Mother know
what I like to do?
We read the same gossip column.
Oh, that... Rome.
I really like to swim.
We might get along very well.
In case you're interested,
I was pushed into that fountain.
Without any clothes on?
With all my clothes on.
The newspaper that ran
that story...
happens to be a rival
of my father's paper.
You were just a poor, innocent
victim of circumstances?
I'm neither poor nor innocent.
The truth of that particular...
The truth is, you're running
around with a pretty wild crowd.
Yes, that's the truth, but I
was pushed into that fountain,
and that's the truth too.
Uh-huh. Do you really
know Annie Hayworth?
No. At least I didn't
until I came up here.
So you didn't go
to school together?
No.
And you didn't come here
to see her?
No!
You were lying!
Yes, I was lying.
What about the letter
you wrote me? Is that a lie?
No, I wrote the letter.
- Well, what did it say?
- It said, "Dear Mr. Brenner.
I think you need
these lovebirds after all.
They may help your personality."
That's what it said.
But you tore it up?
Yes.
Why?
Because it seemed
stupid and foolish.
- Like jumping into
a fountain in Rome.
- I told you what happened!
You don't expect me
to believe that, do you?
I don't give a damn
what you believe!
- I'd still like to see you.
- Why?
I think it might be fun.
That might've been
good enough in Rome,
but it's not good enough now.
It is for me.
Well, not for me.
- What do you want?
- I thought you knew.
I want to go through life...
jumping into fountains naked.
Good night.
[Birds Chirping,
Squawking]
Miss Daniels,
is that you?
Yes.
Hi.
Is something wrong?
Is that cut beginning
to bother you?
No, it's not the cut
that's bothering me.
- Would you like some brandy?
- If you have some, I'd love it.
I'll get it.
Why don't you sit down.
Oh, would you like a sweater
or something, a quilt?
No. No, thank you.
Won't you call me Melanie?
All right.
Thank you.
Gets a bit chilly here
at night sometimes,
especially if you're
over near the bay.
Well, how did
your evening go?
Did you meet Lydia?
Or would you rather
I changed the subject?
I think so.
- Well, how do you like
our little hamlet?
- I despise it.
I suppose it doesn't offer much
to the casual visitor,
unless you're thrilled
by a collection of shacks
on a hillside.
It takes a bit
of getting used to.
Where are you from
originally?
San Francisco.
How did you happen
to come up here?
A friend invited me
up for a weekend
a long time ago.
Look, I see no reason
for being coy about this.
It was Mitch Brenner.
I guess you knew that anyway.
I suspected as much.
Well, you needn't worry.
It's been over and done with
a long time ago.
Annie, there's nothing
between Mr. Brenner and me.
Isn't there?
Well, maybe there isn't.
Maybe there's
never been anything
between Mitch and any girl.
What do you mean?
I think I'll have
some of that.
I was seeing a lot of him
in San Francisco.
One weekend, he invited me
up to meet Lydia.
- When was this?
- Oh, four years ago,
shortly after his father died.
Of course, things
may be different now.
Different?
With Lydia.
Did she seem
a trifle distant?
Mm, a trifle.
Well, then perhaps things
aren't quite so different.
You know, her attitude
nearly drove me crazy.
When I got back to
San Francisco, I spent days
trying to figure out...
what I'd done
to displease her.
- Well, what had you done?
- Nothing.
I simply existed.
So what's the answer?
Ajealous woman, right?
A clinging,
possessive mother?
Wrong. With all due respect
to Oedipus, I don't think
that was the case.
Then what was it?
Lydia liked me.
That's the strange part.
Now that I'm no longer a threat,
we're very good friends.
- Then why did she
object to you?
- Because she was afraid.
- Afraid you'd take Mitch?
- Afraid I'd give Mitch.
I don't understand.
Afraid of any woman who
would give Mitch the one thing
Lydia can give him: Love.
That adds up to
a jealous, possessive woman.
No, I don't think so.
You see, she's not afraid
of losing Mitch.
She's only afraid
of being abandoned.
- Someone ought to tell her
she'd be gaining a daughter.
- [Chuckles]
No. She already
has a daughter.
Well, what about Mitch?
Didn't he have anything
to say about this?
Well, I can understand
his position.
He'd just been through
a lot with Lydia
after his father died.
- He didn't want to risk
going through it all again.
- Oh, I see.
So it ended.
Not right then, of course.
We went back to San Francisco,
saw each other now and then,
but we both knew it was over.
- Then what are you doing
here in Bodega Bay?
- I wanted to be near Mitch.
Oh, it was over and done with,
and I knew it, but...
I still wanted
to be near him.
I still like him
a hell of a lot,
and I don't want to lose
that friendship... ever.
[Phone Ringing]
Hello.
No, no, no,
I wasn't asleep.
Yes, just
a little while ago.
Sure. Hold on.
It's Mitch.
For you.
Hello? Oh, yes,
this is Melanie.
Fine, thank you.
No, no trouble at all.
I simply followed the road.
Well... There's
no need to apologize.
I can understand...
That's very kind of you.
No, I'm not angry.
Well, I couldn't.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
No, I wouldn't want
to disappoint Cathy, but...
I see.
All right.
Yes, I'll be there.
Good night, Mitch.
[Hangs Up Phone]
He wants me to go to Cathy's
party tomorrow afternoon.
I said I would.
It should be fun.
I'll be there, too,
to help.
Oh, it seems so pointless.
Well, I think
I'll go to sleep.
It's been a busy day.
My luggage.
That's pretty.
Where'd you get that?
Brinkmeyer's?
Mm-hmm. Do you think
I should go?
Well, that's up to you.
No, it's really
up to Lydia, isn't it?
- Never mind Lydia.
Do you want to go?
- Yes.
- Then go.
- Thank you, Annie.
[Clattering Sound]
Oh. Wonder
who that can be.
Is someone there?
Who is it?
Look.
Poor thing.
Probably lost his way
in the dark.
But it isn't dark,
Annie.
There's a full moon.
[Children Chattering,
Laughing]
[Annie]
Cathy, that's very good.
Very good.
Okay. Here we go.
[Annie]
Attagirl. Come on.
Don't let him get you.
No, I really shouldn't
have any more.
I'm driving.
Well, actually, I'm trying
to get you to stay for dinner.
A lot of roast beef left over.
No, I couldn't possibly.
I... have to get back.
All right.
Cheers.
Why do you have to rush off?
What's so important
in San Francisco?
Well, I have to get to work
tomorrow, for one thing.
You have a job?
I have several jobs.
What do you do?
I do different things
on different days.
Like what?
Well, on Mondays and Wednesdays,
I work for the Travelers' Aid
at the airport.
Helping travelers?
No, misdirecting them.
I thought you could read
my character.
On Tuesdays, I take a course
in General Semantics
at Berkeley...
finding new
four-letter words.
- That's not a job, of course...
- You mean, you don't have to...
- And on Thursdays,
I have my meeting and lunch.
- In the underworld, I suppose.
I shall disappoint you.
We're sending
a little Korean boy
through school.
We actually raise money
for it.
You see, Rome...
That entire summer,
I did nothing but...
Well, it was very easy
to get lost there.
So when I came back,
I thought it was time
I began...
I don't know...
finding something again.
So, on Mondays and Thursdays,
I keep myself busy.
- What about Fridays?
- Fridays? They're free.
I sometimes go
to bird shops on Fridays.
I'm very glad you do.
A nice, innocent,
little day.
Oh, yes.
- I have an Aunt Tessa.
Have you got an Aunt Tessa?
- Mm-mm.
Mine is very prim
and straight-laced.
I'm giving her a mynah bird
when she comes back from Europe.
Mynah birds talk, you know.
Can you see
my Aunt Tessa's face...
when this one tells us
one or two of the words
I've picked up at Berkeley?
You need a mother's care,
my child.
- Not my mother's.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
What have you got
to be sorry about?
My mother?
Don't waste your time.
She ditched us when I was 11
and ran off with some hotel man
in the East.
You know what
a mother's love is?
- Yes, I do.
- You mean it's better
to be ditched?
No. I think
it's better to be loved.
Don't you ever see her?
I don't know
where she is.
Well, maybe I ought to go
join the other children.
[Children Chattering]
[Annie]
All right. Here we go.
One...
two...
three.
There you go.
[Children Laughing]
[Child]
Look! Look!
Hey!
No touching allowed!
[Squawking]
- Oh!
- [Birds Squawking]
[Children Screaming]
[Loud Pop]
[Squawking, Screaming
Continue]
Help me get the children
into the house.
There you go.
[Sobbing]
[Children Sobbing]
Have they gone,
Mitch?
I think so.
[Lydia]
Is anyone hurt?
[Woman]
Jenny got a scratch down
her cheek, but it's nothing.
That makes three times.
Mitch, this
isn't usual, is it?
The gull when I was
in the boat yesterday,
the one at Annie's last night...
Last night?
What do you mean?
A gull smashed
into Annie's front door.
Mitch, what's happening?
L... I don't know.
Do you have to go back
to Annie's?
No. I have my things
in the car.
Stay and have something to
eat before you start back.
I'd feel a lot better.
Would you like
some mustard with that?
[Melanie] No, thank you.
Why didn't Annie stay?
Said something about going home
to take a call from her sister.
[Chirping]
What's the matter
with them?
with all the birds?
Where did you want this coffee?
Here on the table,
honey.
Hurry up with yours, Mitch.
I'm sure Miss Daniels
wants to be on her way.
I think you ought to stay
the night, Melanie.
We have an extra room
upstairs and everything.
That road can be
a pretty bad one at night.
If I go across to Santa Rosa,
I'll come out on the freeway
much earlier, won't I?
Yes, and the freeway
is much quicker.
But she'll be hitting
all the heavy traffic
going back to San Francisco.
[Chirping Grows Louder]
[Cathy]
Just listen to those lovebirds.
[Chirping Stops]
[Twittering]
Mitch.
[Birds Screeching]
Cover your faces!
Cover your eyes!
That's a sparrow,
all right.
We know what it is, Al.
Did you have a light
burnin' or somethin'?
Yes, but there wouldn't
have been that much light
going up the chimney.
[Al] Sometimes birds
are attracted by light.
Sure is a peculiar thing.
All right, but we've
got to do something
about it!
I don't think I get you,
Mitch. Do about what?
[Mitch Sighs]
Well, the birds
invaded the house.
What's more likely...
they got in the room
and just panicked.
I'll admit a bird will
panic in an enclosed room,
but they didn't just
get in:: They came in,
right down the chimney.
[Al] My wife found a bird in
the back seat of her car once.
Tell him about the party.
We had a party here
this afternoon for Cathy,
for her birthday.
How old is she?
Eleven! In the middle
of the party,
some seagulls came down
at the children!
Miss Daniels was attacked
by a gull yesterday.
Yeah. Were the kids
bothering the birds
or something?
If you make any kind
of a disturbance near them,
they'll come after you.
Al, the children
were playing a game.
Those gulls attacked.
[Al] Now, Lydia, "attack"
is a pretty strong word,
don't you think?
I mean, birds just don't
go around attacking people
without no reason.
The kids probably scared 'em,
that's all.
These birds attacked.
You got quite a mess here,
I'll admit that.
Maybe you ought
to put some screen
on top of your chimney.
You want help
cleaning up?
No. I can handle it.
[Lydia Gasps]
[Mitch] It shouldn't be
too much of a job.
I'll take Cathy
up to bed.
I think I should stay,
don't you?
It would be nice
if you could.
My things are in the car.
Do you want to go with me?
All right.
[Al] Well, anything
else I can do, Mitch?
No thanks, Al.
We'll be all right.
Good night, Lydia.
Sure is peculiar.
[Door Closes]
[Shovel Grating]
[Lydia]
Mitch. Mitch. Mitch!
Yes, Mother?
I'm going to drop
Cathy off now.
I'll probably drive over
to the Fawcett farm.
Okay.
[Truck Starting]
[Truck Driving Away]
Mornin'.
Good morning, George.
Is Mr. Fawcett around?
I think so, ma'am.
Ain't seen him this morning,
but he ought to be in there.
Thanks.
Dan, are you home?
[Screen Door Slams]
Uh...
[Gasping For Air]
[Choking]
[Motor Starting]
[Motor Racing]
[Sobbing]
Mother!
What is it, dear?
What's the matter?
[Sobbing]
Oh!
Al Malone, the deputy,
just called. He wants me
over at the Fawcett place.
Some detectives
from Santa Rosa
will be there.
Will it be all right?
Yes. I was just taking
your mother in some tea.
Oh, be careful,
please.
And you be careful?
[Footsteps Departing,
Door Opening, Closing]
[Knocking]
[Lydia]
Mitch?
No, it's me,
Mrs. Brenner.
I thought you might
like some tea.
Oh. Thank you.
Where's Mitch?
Al Malone wanted him
out at the Fawcett farm.
Why?
Didn't Al believe
my story?
He was calling
from the farm.
Then he saw.
Oh, he must have.
They sent for
the Santa Rosa police.
What good will they do?
[Gasping]
Do you think
Cathy's all right
at the school?
Yes, I'm sure
she's fine.
Do I sound very
foolish to you?
Oh, no.
I keep seeing
Dan's face.
And they have
such big windows
at the school.
All the windows are
broken in Dan's bedroom.
All the windows!
Try not to think
about that.
I wish I were
a stronger person.
I lost my husband
four years ago,
you know.
It's terrible how you...
you depend on someone else
for strength, and then...
suddenly all the strength
is gone, and you're alone.
I'd love to be able
to relax sometime.
I'd love to be
able to sleep.
- Do you think
Cathy's all right?
- Annie's there.
She'll be all right.
I'm not
like this, you know?
N- Not usually.
I don't fuss and fret
about my children.
When Frank died...
You see, he understood
the children. He really
understood them.
He had the knack of
entering into their world,
of becoming part of them.
That's a
very rare talent.
Yes.
[Sighs]
Oh, I wish, I wish...
I wish I could be like that.
I miss him.
Sometimes, even now,
I wake up in the morning
and I think,
"I must get
Frank's breakfast."
And I get up, and there's
a very good reason
for getting out of bed,
until of course...
I remember.
I miss talking to him.
Cathy's a child,
of course, and Mitch...
Well, Mitch has
his own life.
[Teacup Rattling]
I'm glad
he stayed here today.
L- I feel safer
with him here.
Would you like
to rest now?
No.
No, don't go.
I feel as if
I don't understand you
at all, and l...
I want so much
to understand.
Why, Mrs. Brenner?
Because my son seems
to be very fond of you.
And I don't quite know
how I feel about it.
I don't even know
if I like you or not.
Is that so important,
your liking me?
Well, yes.
I think so.
Mitch is important to me.
I want to like
whatever girl he chooses.
And perhaps
if you don't?
Well, then I don't think
it'll matter much
to anyone but me.
Oh, I think it would
also matter to Mitch.
Mitch has
always done exactly
what he wanted to do.
[Crying]
But, you see, l-I don't
want to be left alone.
I don't think I could
bear to be left alone!
[Sobbing]
Oh, forgive me.
This business
with the birds
has upset me, l...
I don't know what I'd do
if Mitch weren't here.
Why don't you try
to sleep now, Mrs. Brenner?
I wish I was stronger.
[Sighing]
Do you think
she's all right?
she's all right
at the school?
- Would you like me
to go for her?
- Oh, l-I couldn't ask it.
- Oh, I don't mind, really.
- Would you?
- I'd feel so much better.
- I'll go right now.
[Sighs]
Melanie?
Thanks for the tea.
[Shuts Off Motor]
[Children]
# I married my wife
in the month ofJune #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# I brought her home
By the light of the moon #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She combs her hair
But once a year #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
- # With every stroke
She shed a tear #
- [No Audible Dialogue]
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Rustical quality
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# He brought her home
By the light of the moon #
[Fainter]
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She combed her hair
But once a year #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# With every stroke
She shed a tear #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She swept up her floor
But once a year #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# She said that brooms
Were much too dear #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She churns her butter
In her dad's old boot #
# Ristle-tee, Rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# And for a dash
She'd use her foot #
# Ristle-tee, Rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# The butter it came out
All grizzle-y gray #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# The cheese it took legs
and ran away #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She let the critter
get away #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# I asked my wife
to wash the floor #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# She gave me my hat
And she showed me the door #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Now, now, now #
# I married my wife
in the month ofJune #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now #
# I brought her home
by the light of the moon #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# She combed her hair
But once a year #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee #
# Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality #
# Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now #
# Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now ##
[Annie]
All right, children. Now,
please put your song books away,
then stand up
alongside your desks.
We'll go out for recess
as soon as everybody gets ready.
[Annie]
We are not going
into the playground...
until everybody
has quieted down.
[Children Chattering]
Close that door.
Quickly. Please.
What?
[Door Closing]
What is it?
Look.
We've got
to get the children
out of here.
[Chattering Continues]
Shh, shh, shh!
All right, children.
Now, quiet.
Quiet. Miss Daniels
would like to see...
how we conduct ourselves
during a fire drill.
[Children Protesting]
I would like you
to show her how quiet
and obedient you can be.
- Oh, uh, we're going
out of school now.
- [Children] Leave school?
We want those of you
who live nearby
to go directly home.
[Children]
Home?
I want the rest of you to go
down the hill all the way
to the hotel. Is that clear?
[Together]
Yes, Miss Hayworth.
Melanie?
I want you to go
as quietly as possible.
Do not make a sound
until I tell you to run.
Then run as quickly
as you can. Now, does
everybody understand?
[Together]
Yes, Miss Hayworth.
All right, John,
you lead the way.
[Loud Fluttering]
[Birds Shrieking]
[Children Screaming]
[Cawing]
[Screaming]
[Squawking]
Cathy! Cathy!
[Crying]
[Birds Squawking]
[Honking Horn]
[Clattering,
Squawking]
[Squawks Fading]
Well, Daddy, there
were hundreds of them.
No, I'm not hysterical.
I'm trying to tell you this
as calmly as I know how.
All right, Daddy.
Yes, Daddy.
Well, just now.
Not 15 minutes ago.
At the school.
No, I don't. Just a minute.
What's the name of the school?
- Just the Bodega Bay School.
- The Bodega Bay School.
Well, I don't know
how many children...
30 or 40.
No, the birds didn't attack
until the children
were outside the school.
Help you, Mrs. Bundy?
I need some change,
Mr. Carter.
Crows, I think.
Well, I don't know, Daddy.
Is there a difference
between crows and blackbirds?
There is very definitely
a difference, Miss.
Thank you.
They're different,
Daddy.
Well, I think
these were crows.
Well, yes.
Hundreds of them.
Yes, they attacked
the children.
Attacked them!
[Machine Dispensing]
Well, I don't
know when,
but I simply can't
leave now, Daddy.
All right. Yes.
Good-bye.
They're both
perching birds, of course.
But quite different species.
The crow is
Corvus brachyrhynchos,
and the blackbird
is Euphagus cyanocephalos.
Thank you.
You have the number
at the Fawcett farm?
Right here in this book, miss.
I can't see that
it makes any difference,
Mrs. Bundy.
Crows or blackbirds,
if the school was attacked,
that's pretty serious.
[Scoffs]
I hardly think
that either species...
would have sufficient
intelligence to launch
a massed attack.
[Chuckles]
Their brainpans are
not big enough to...
I just came from the school,
madam. I don't know anything
about their brainpans, but...
Well, I do.
I do know.
Ornithology happens
to be my avocation.
Birds are not
aggressive creatures, miss.
They bring beauty
into the world.
It is mankind, rather, who...
[Helen]
Sam! Three
southern fried chicken.
Baked potato
on all of them.
Yes, may I speak to
Mitch Brenner, please?
Yes, I'll wait.
It is mankind, rather,
who insists upon...
making it difficult
for life to exist
upon this planet.
Now, if it were not for birds...
Mrs. Bundy, you don't
seem to understand.
This young lady said there
was an attack on the school.
Impossible!
Oh, Mitch?
Oh, I'm glad I caught you.
Something terrible has ha...
It's the end of the world!
Two Bloody Marys,
Deke.
What actually happened
at the school?
Bunch of crows...
attacked
the school kids.
It's the end of the world.
"Thus saith the Lord God...
"unto the mountains and
the hills, and the rivers
and the valleys.
"Behold I, even I...
"shall bring a sword
upon you.
And I will devastate
your high places."
Ezekiel, chapter six.
"Woe unto them that rise up
early in the morning, that
they may follow strong drink. "
Isaiah, chapter five.
It's the end of the world.
I hardly think a few birds
are going to bring about
the end of the world.
These weren't a few birds.
I didn't know
there were many crows...
in Bodega Bay
this time of year.
The crow is
a permanent resident
throughout its range.
In fact, during
our Christmas count,
we recorded...
How many gulls did
you count, Mrs. Bundy?
Which gulls, Mr. Sholes?
There are several varieties.
The ones who've
been playing devil
with my fishing boats.
- Have you had
trouble with gulls?
- One of my boats did, last week.
This young lady was hit
by a gull only Saturday.
Deke, I'm still waiting
for those Bloody Marys.
Comin'right up.
Could you ask them to lower
their voices, please? They're
frightening the children.
A whole flock of gulls
nearly capsized
one of my boats.
Practically tore
the skipper's arm off.
You're scaring the kids.
Keep it low.
All right.
Yeah, but he's
scarin' me, too.
Are you tryin' to
say that all these...
Nah, that sounds
impossible, Sebastian.
Deke, look, I'm just
tellin' you what happened
to one of my boats.
The gulls were after
your fish, Mr. Sholes.
Really, let's be
logical about this.
What were the crows
after at the school?
What do you think
they were after?
Miss, uh...
Daniels.
I think they were
after the children.
- For what purpose?
- To kill them.
- Why?
- I don't know why.
I thought not.
Birds have been on
this planet, Miss Daniels,
[Door Closes]
Since archeopteryx,
140 million years ago.
[Footsteps Approaching]
Doesn't it seem odd that
they'd wait all that time...
to start a... a war
against humanity?
No one called
it a war.
Scotch,
light on the water.
You and Mr. Sholes seem
to be implying as much.
Who said
anything about a war?
All I said, some gulls...
[Helen]
Want some more coffee?
No.
...came down on
one of my boats.
They could have been
after the fish,
just like you said.
- The Captain should
have shot at them.
- Huh?
Gulls are scavengers,
anyway. Most birds are.
Get yourselves guns
and wipe them off
the face of the Earth!
- [Chuckles]
That would hardly be possible.
- Why not, Mrs. Bundy?
Because there are
8,650 species...
of birds in the world
today, Mr. Carter.
It is estimated
that 5,750,000,000 birds...
live in the
United States alone.
The five continents
of the world...
Kill 'em all. Get rid
of the messy animals.
...probably contain
more than 100 billion birds.
- It's the end of the world.
- Those gulls must have been
after the fish.
[Mrs. Bundy] Of course!
Hurry up, children.
Finish your lunch.
Are the birds gonna
eat us, Mommy?
Hell, maybe we're
all getting a little
carried away by this.
Admittedly, a few birds
did act strange, but that's
no reason to believe that...
I keep telling you,
this isn't a few birds.
These are gulls, crows, swifts...
I have never known birds
of different species
to flock together.
The very concept
is unimaginable.
Why, if that happened,
we wouldn't have a chance!
How could we possibly
hope to fight them?
We couldn't, you're
right. You're right,
Mrs. Bundy.
- What's the matter?
Somethin' wrong out here?
- We're fighting a war, Sam.
A war?
Against who?
- Against birds!
- I'm glad you all think
this is so amusing.
You've frightened the children
half out of their wits.
If the young lady said...
she saw the attack
at a school, why
don't you believe her?
What attack?
Who attacked the school?
Birds did. Crows.
You're all sitting
around here debating!
What do you want
them to do next?
Crash through that window?
Mommy!
Ssh.
Put on your coat.
Why don't you all go home,
lock your doors and windows?
- What's the fastest way
to San Francisco?
- The freeway, ma'am.
- How do I find it?
- I'm goin'out that way, lady.
You can follow me.
- Well then, let's leave now.
- Haven't finished my drink yet.
[Panting]
I got here as fast
as I could. Where's Cathy?
She's with Annie.
She's all right.
Al, why
aren't you over at the school,
- where the attack was?
- 'Cause I just got back
from Dan Fawcett's place.
- He was killed
last night by birds.
- What?
Hold it, you don't
know that for a fact.
- What are the facts?
- The Santa Rosa Police
think it's a felony murder.
They think a burglar
broke in and killed him.
How do they explain
the dead birds all over
the floor?
Santa Rosa Police
figure they got in after
the old man was killed.
Were the Santa Rosa Police
at your school today?
- Are you coming?
- Now take it easy, lady.
There isn't a bird
anywhere in sight!
"Look at the birds of the air.
They do not sow or reap.
Yet your Heavenly Father
feeds them."
Something like this happened
in Santa Cruz last year.
The town was just
covered with seagulls.
- Please finish your drink.
- That's right, sir.
I recall it.
A large flock of seagulls
got lost in a fog,
and headed into the town
where all the lights were.
They made some mess, too,
smashing into buildings
and everything.
They always make a mess.
The point is that no one
seemed to be upset about it.
They were all gone
next morning, just as though
nothing at all had happened.
- Poor things.
- I'm leaving!
Are you coming?
All right,
all right!
Well, hope you folks
figure this thing out!
It's the end
of the world!
I better get back
to the cannery. What
do I owe you, Deke?
S- Sebastian,
hold it a minute.
Huh?
L- I don't want to be
an alarmist, but...
No one ever said you were.
I think we're in real trouble.
I don't know how
this started, or why,
but I know it's here
and we'd be crazy
to ignore it.
To ignore what?
The "bird war"?
Yes, the "bird war."
The bird attack, plague...
Call it what you like,
they're massing
out there someplace,
and they'll be back.
Ridiculous.
C- Come here.
Unless we do something
right now, unless we get
Bodega Bay on the move, they...
Look, Mitch.
Even if... Even if
this is true, even
if all the birds...
Don't you
believe it's true?
No, Mitch, frankly I don't.
There's no reason l...
Well, it's happening.
Isn't that a reason?
I like Bodega Bay as
well as the next man...
Fine, then help me.
You're an important man.
If you help, they all will.
Help how?
What do you want to do?
[Seagull Crying]
Mrs. Bundy said
something about Santa Cruz.
[Crying Continues]
About seagulls getting lost
in a fog and flying in
towards the lights.
[Sebastian] We don't
have fog this time of year!
[Mitch] Make our own fog!
How do you figure to do that?
We can use smoke pots,
the way the Army uses them.
- Look!
- [Seagull Crying]
They're attacking again.
Melanie, you stay in here.
Come on, Al!
[Seagulls Crying]
Look out!
[Gull Crying]
[Muffled]
Look at the gas.
That man's lighting a cigar!
[All Shouting]
Hey, you! Watch out!
Don't drop that match!
- Get out of there!
- Mister, run!
[Screaming,
Warnings Continue]
[Shouting, Indistinct]
[Calling]
[Screeching]
[Screaming]
[Man]
Hey!
[Gulls' Screaming
Increases]
[Wings Flapping]
[Siren Wailing]
[Screaming, Flapping
Become Thunderous]
[Gulls Pounding
On Glass]
[Shrieking]
[Gulls Crying,
Fainter]
Why are they doing this?
They said when you got here,
the whole thing started!
[Crying]
Who are you?
What are you?
Where did
you come from?
I think you're
the cause of all this.
I think you're evil!
Evil!
[Gasps]
Oh, God!
[Woman Sobbing]
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Running Footsteps
Approaching]
I think they're going!
[Panting]
We can get Cathy
at Annie's now.
[Seagulls Calling,
Faintly]
[Crow Cawing]
The crows again.
Shh!
[Single Crow
Cawing]
[Softly]
Come on.
[One Crow Caws]
[Wings Flapping]
[Flapping, Cawing
Continue]
Oh, no.
Stay here.
S- Stay here.
[Screams,
Sobs]
Cathy!
Where's Cathy?
[Cawing]
[Cathy Sobbing]
[Loud Cawing]
[Sobbing Continues]
Mitch, don't!
Oh, don't leave
her there, Mitch.
[Sobbing]
[Body Being Dragged]
[Gasping]
Oh!
[Footsteps
Mounting Stairs]
[Cawing]
[Door Opening,
Closing]
[Sighing]
[Wings Fluttering]
[Strange,
Loud Chattering]
[Crying]
[Feathers Rustling]
[Whispering]
Come on.
[Sobs]
Shh.
[Loud Cawing]
[Louder Cawing,
Nearby]
[Starting Motor]
[Sobbing]
Wh-When we got back from
taking Michele home...
we-we heard the explosion
and we went...
we went outside
to see what it was.
All-All at once the...
the birds were everywhere!
[Sobbing]
All at once she
pushed me inside...
and they covered her!
Annie...
She pushed me inside!
[Hammering]
Give me another one,
darling.
How long have they
been gathering there?
Oh, about 15 minutes.
Seems like a pattern,
doesn't it?
They strike,
then disappear, and
then start massing again.
[Hammering]
Doesn't look so very
different, does it?
A little smoke hanging
over the town, otherwise...
[Scoffs]
You want to try
your father again?
No, I tried
a little while ago.
The phone's dead.
Still got power,
haven't we?
Yes.
[Lydia]
Mitch, I'm getting
something on the radio.
Come on.
[Man On Radio, Indistinct]
I can't get any
of the local stations.
I think this
is San Francisco.
"...and the work of
a team of professionals. "
End quote.
In Bodega Bay
early this morning,
a large flock of crows...
attacked a group of children
who were leaving the school
during a fire drill.
One little girl was
seriously injured and taken
to the hospital in Santa Rosa,
but the majority
of children reached safety.
We understand there was
another attack on the town,
but this information
is rather sketchy.
So far, no word
has come through...
to show if there
have been further attacks.
On the national scene today,
in Washington...
Well, is that all?
[Radio Continues,
Indistinct]
I'll have to get some
more water. Mustn't let
this fire go out.
Did you get the windows
in the attic, Mitch?
Yes, I got 'em all, dear.
When do you think
they'll come?
I don't know.
If there are
bigger birds, Mitch,
they'll get into the house.
Well, it's just a chance
we'll have to take.
Maybe we ought to leave.
No, not now!
Not when they're massing
out there.
When?
W- We'll just
see what happens.
Where will we go?
L- I don't know. I think we're
safe here for the time being.
Let's get the wood in now.
What happens when
you run out of wood?
I don't know!
We'll break up the furniture.
You don't know!
When will you know?
When we're all dead!
If only your father
were here...
[Radio Continues]
[Sobbing]
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mitch.
Make yourself
some coffee, won't you?
[Man On Radio]
"In assuming the tasks
of the presidency,
I said that few generations..."
Where are they heading?
Somewhere inland.
Santa Rosa?
Maybe.
Come on.
Let's get the wood.
[Banging]
- Mitch? Can I bring
the lovebirds in here?
- No!
But, Mom,
they're in a cage.
They're birds, aren't they?
Let's leave them
in the kitchen, huh, honey?
[Scratching]
Mitch, why are
they doing this,
the birds?
We don't know, honey.
Why are they trying
to kill people?
I wish I could say.
[Gasping]
[Swallowing, Gasping]
L- I'm sick, Melanie.
I want to...
[Gagging]
I'll go with you.
[Door Slams]
[Cathy Coughing]
[Coughing Continues]
[Door Opens]
[Birds Singing,
Wings Fluttering]
[Crows Cawing]
[Many Species Calling,
Wings Flapping]
[Flapping Grows Louder]
[High-Pitched Chirping]
[Staccato Drumming
On Roof]
[Log Landing
In Fireplace]
[Birdcalls, Drumming
Rising In Intensity]
[Roar, Rising In Pitch
And Intensity]
[Loud Crashing]
[Loud Screeching
Continues]
[Screeching,
Fluttering]
[Fluttering,
Rumbling]
[Rumbling Continues]
[Pecking]
[Birds Shrieking]
[One Bird Screeches]
[Sounds Diminish]
They're going.
[Screeches Fading]
[Wings Fluttering]
Mitch?
[Fluttering Continues]
[Fluttering]
[Wings Flapping]
[Gasps]
[Screeching]
[Whimpering]
[Moaning]
[Softly]
Oh, Mitch!
[Lydia, Indistinct]
[Mitch]
Melanie! Melanie!
[Birds Shrieking]
Oh, poor thing!
Poor thing!
Listen, get some water,
bandages and antiseptic.
Quickly!
Bandages.
[Gasps]
It's terrible.
Cathy, get some brandy.
No, no, no!
No, no, it's all right.
No, it's all right,
it's all right,
it's all right.
It's all right.
No.
[Gasping]
Shh! Shh!
Cathy, get the lamp.
[Sighs]
We've got to get her
to a hospital.
We can't, Mitch.
There's no place we can go.
There's San Francisco.
We'd never make it.
We have to try.
We'll go by way of Bay Hill
Road. Then we don't have
to go through town.
We can't stay here.
She needs help!
I'm frightened.
Terribly frightened.
I don't know
what's outside there.
We better get started
before another attack comes.
We'll take Melanie's car.
That'll be faster
than the truck.
Can you finish
the bandaging?
I'll try.
All right.
[Lydia]
Mitch? See if you can get
anything on the car radio.
[Soft Cooing,
Beating Of Wings]
[Fluttering]
[Cawing]
[Rustling]
## [Switching Stations]
[Announcer]
The bird attacks have
subsided for the time being.
Bodega Bay seems
to be the center, though
there are reports...
of minor attacks
on Sebastopol and
a few on Santa Rosa.
Bodega Bay
has been cordoned off
by roadblocks.
Most of the townspeople
have managed to get out,
but there are still some
isolated pockets of people.
No decision has been
arrived at yet as to what
the next step will be,
but there's been some
discussion as to whether
the military should go in.
It appears that the bird
attacks come in waves, with
long intervals between.
The reason for this
does not seem clear as yet.
[Clicks Off Radio]
[Starts Motor]
[Motor Turning Over
Slowly]
[Shuts Off Motor,
Sets Parking Brake]
Did you hear anything
on the radio?
It's-It's all right.
Come on.
[Turning Doorknob]
[Gull Crying]
No. No!
Shh. Shh.
- Mitch?
- Shh!
Stay there.
Can I bring
the lovebirds, Mitch?
They haven't harmed anyone.
A- All right.
Bring them.
[Shutting Door]
[Starts Motor]
[Car Driving Away,
Bird Squawking Intensifies]