(clap of thunder)
(man shouts at horses)
(stage coach driver) 'Andale caballo'
'Andale caballo'
(shouts in Spanish)
'Seor '
- Tighten up that girth.
- Seor I must go to San Felipe.
My mother is dead!
Straight down the road about 50 miles.
Yeah get outta here.
Hey. Hey amigo
Come here.
Perfect.
You're perfect!
I swear to God boys he's just right.
I'm gonna put you on that stage and
watch those faces when they see you come in!
(both laugh)
v ovo
- By God I...
- Never mind dear.
(tuts)
Over there.
Not that door the other one there.
Pull. Pull.
There you are. Now just sit down
and be quiet like a good little boy.
You see? He does understand.
Who knows perhaps he can even talk.
Now now even the peasants...
A bit of mustard?
Thank you.
Even the peasants are entitled to their rights.
After all they have won a revolution.
Or at least almost.
Animals that's what they are. Animals.
(burps)
Even animals can be tame and harmless.
Personally I consider them unfortunate brutes.
Yes brutes. Quite right.
Precisely my dear lady precisely.
I hate saying it
but you should hear them in the confessional.
- You would never imagine. Did you know...?
- I can imagine Father.
I can imagine.
Living in such promiscuity
all of them in one room
male and female together
lying in a heap like rats in a sewer.
At night when the lights are out
all their inibitions disappear.
You never know who is next:
mother sister daughter... goat.
Every country has its own plague.
- Just like them niggers we got back home.
- Just like animals. That's what they are.
Exactly. Which is why they're half-wits.
Hey you. Do you know who your father was?
Do you know how old you are?
He doesn 't know.
Do you know how many kids you have? Huh?
Do you know how many kids your mother had?
He doesn 't know anything.
It was to benefit scum like this
that the Agrarian Reform was imposed.
And that ass Madero wanted to give
the government and our land to idiots like this.
We are all pawns in the hands of Almighty God.
Fortunately Divine Providence
has disposed of that rash individual Madero.
My dear Monsignor let us be realistic.
What you call Providence I call General Huerta.
He put the peasants in their place.
Which is the best place for animals
because that's what they are.
Animals.
(voices echo) I can imagine.
- I can imagine living in such promiscuity...
...wanted to give the government and our land
to idiots like this!
- Goats.
- Animals.
- Rats!
- Just like them niggers we got back home.
- Half-wits!
- Animals!
Divine Providence has disposed...
Just like them niggers.
Animals. Because that's what they are. Animals.
...like them niggers.
- Brutes!
That's what they are animals.
- Like them niggers.
- Brutes!
Animals!
- I consider them unfortunate brutes.
- I can imagine...
Niggers.
- Brutes!
- Niggers!
...like them niggers.
- Idiots!
- Niggers!
...like them niggers.
- Idiots! Half-wits!
(driver) 'Anda caballo anda'
(driver) 'Anda caballo'
Hey you give us a hand and push.
Think they'd get off their asses to help us
the bastards? Hell no!
'Anda' 'Caballo huyo'
(driver shouts horses neigh)
Haaaahh!
(gasps)
(cockerel crows)
Take him away before he dirties everything.
Now ladies and gentlemen you will give
everything to my nios without any trouble.
- We kill them all OK Pap?
- (gunshot)
I've told you Chulo
no shooting unless Pap pulls the trigger.
Come.
Come come come come!
(boys chatter in Spanish in background)
You wanted to know my family? That's my sons.
Each one of them from a different mother.
And now you kneel.
Kneel!
'Pap'
This is my father. I think.
- Pleased to meet...
- Go inside before Chulo kills everyone.
My mother had the blood of the Aztecs
which was before your people.
And now I ask you a question.
Can you make a baby?
That's sad. But we will fix that.
'Seora'
(Adelita) Let me go! Let go.
Go on.
Go.
(cow moos)
(whistles)
- Go... go... go... go... go!
- (Adelita screams)
(gasps)
(cockerel crows)
Pretty good huh?
Oh Jesus help me I'm going to faint.
No no no no no.
You faint now and you miss the best part.
(chatter and laughter)
Juanito you get everything?
You'll pay for this you bastard!
- I'm a citizen of the United States of America!
- You're an American son of a bitch.
Understand Yankee?
(chuckles)
Thank you.
Thank you. For everything.
(all gasp)
(laughter)
(horses whinny)
(all laugh)
Have you a light?
There is a hole in the roof.
Hey!
(gun barrels click)
- I wouldn 't do that if I were you.
- Why?
You pull that trigger and shoot me I fall.
And if I fall they'll have to alter all the maps.
You see when I go
half this bloody country goes with me.
Including yourself.
(laughs)
- You understand now?
- Ah s s s s s s I understand.
'S
It's like a miracle of God.
You you are a great magician.
I stop your motorcycle
you do the magic with my coach. We are even.
- Even?
- S
To fix my motorcycle would be even.
I'll be inside.
Oh! We kill him now Pap?
No. First we fix the motorcycle. Shh!
- It's whisky.
- Thank God for that huh?
Where are you going in this contraption?
Well... Where are you going?
- Shaver Mines.
- Oh-ho.
Lucanina huh? I know that place.
I know the man who owns it
that fat German son of a bitch!
That crazy tub of lard Mr Aschenbach
who wrings our people dry like slaves
even his personal servants.
One girl had an ass:
her cheek s were hard like drums.
I got her pregnant and he...
Oh Jesus Christ!
Will you shut up and go and fix my motorcycle?
OK.
Anything you say Firecracker.
(all shout at once)
(Juan) Take your hands off that. Now!
(laughs)
Well good for you Firecracker.
I don 't know why I named you Napoleon
when you have no imagination. This is a bank!
- Mesa Verde
- S Pap Mesa Verde. Mesa Verde.
If we can get this Firecracker to come with us
we will be rich.
Where does he come in?
The dynamite's right here.
No no. You need an expert for that.
You only need matches and balls.
And I got those.
-  S?
- 'S
See that tree over there?
(explosion)
Short fuse.
Now you understand
why we need the firecracker?
Huh?
- Where the hell are we?
- What kind of work you do for the German?
Listen I asked you a question.
What do you do for the German?
- I've been looking for silver for him.
- Silver?
You know something? I don 't understand you.
Why do you waste your time and your holy water
looking for silver? To me that's a sin.
- Have you any better ideas?
- S Gold is better than silver.
There isn 't any gold in these hills.
(laughs) Yes there is.
In Mesa Verde.
Of course.
Whoever heard of having a bank in the country!
Uh-huh. A bank?
Not a bank. The bank.
The most beautiful wonderful fantastic
gorgeous magnificent bank in the world.
When you stand before the bank
and you see it has the gates of gold
like it was the gates of heaven.
And when you go inside
everything everything is gold.
Gold spittoons gold handles. And money.
I know 'cause I saw when I was
eight years old. I went there with my father.
He tried to rob the bank. They caught him
but they won 't catch me.  Eh Pap?
Right.
Listen Firecracker you listen to me.
Listen why don 't you come with me
and we will work together?
And we will become rich.
(laughs)
What the hell is your name?
John.
What?
- What is your name?
- John.
(Juan laughs) That's fantastic. That is incredible.
My name is Juan and yours is John.
Juan and John.
So what?
Can 't you understand that is that is the...
Oh...
Destiny.
No. And I mean it.
Why?
You want more money? I'll give you more
than half. I don 't care about the money.
As long as we can work together.
Listen what I'm telling you.
We are like two brothers.
You make the holes with the holy water
and then I walk in and do the dirty work.
Listen it takes one bandito to know another.
(laughs)
- So you can read?
- You don 't have to read.
I see a man 's picture I see a price
I know that man is in trouble.
Hey what kind of trouble are you in?
- Oh we fought a revolution in Ireland.
- A revolution?
Seems revolutions are all over the world
like the crops.
We had a revolution.
The brave people went in.
What it did to them was terrible. Pancho Villa
the world's best bandit chief two balls like a bull
he went in the revolution as a great bandit
came out as what? Nothing.
A general. That to me is the bullshit.
(begins to kick-start motorcycle)
Wait a minute.
You come here to join the revolution?
No no.
One was enough for me.
(motorcycle revs up)
Stop! You dirty...
...son of a bitch!
Gringo... bastard!
(gunshot)
(hissing)
(squeaking)
Hey!
Duck, yo u sucko"
- Say which way is it to Lucanina?
- Fuck you! Go find it yourself!
Mexico is big
but for you it is going to be very big!
(Juan 's voice echoes)
(distant laughter)
(clatter of hooves horse whinnies)
(Juan) John where are you? It's us!
Come on come on you.
Come on in there.
Just a little further inside.
That's right heathen bastards.
What's this?
You crazy? You talk to yourself now?
Oh my friend didn 't I tell you Mexico was big?
Oh shit.
Who are those people inside?
You mean who were those people inside?
(explosion resounds)
Who were they? Who were those people inside?
(Juan) Chulo!
Who were those people for Christ's sake?
Well one of them was Aschenbach
then there was three soldiers and one captain.
Everybody dead in there.
Will you keep quiet
and go get our friend's equipment together?
Anyway when I went to Aschenbach
and I told him
I said you wanted to see him
he wouldn 't believe that.
I said "That's too bad
because he's discovered silver."
Then he was ready to come running.
The other one the captain... I think the captain
and Aschenbach were working together.
The captain says "I want to see the man."
I said "How can you see him? He's blown off
his hand with dynamite he is bleeding to death."
When they heard that
they broke their asses to get here.
Anyway it's no problem because
there are diamonds here no questions.
Also you have no contract so... you are free.
(Juan laughs)
There will be one little problem with the army.
They will have a hot ass
when it comes to the death of a captain.
But don 't worry.
I am your friend Juan and I will help.
I will do anything say anything...
No no no. I don 't need any help from you
to know I've been screwed.
You fuckin ' chicken thief.
What do you want with me?
Nothing.
I just thought that maybe...
...we could go to Mesa Verde.
(chuckles)
The bank. Isn 't there anything else
you remember about Mesa Verde?
Yes there's a place
where you can sit down and eat.
- When you look in front you...
- See the bank.
That's right. How do you know?
Listen Mesa Verde that's only the beginning.
Let me tell you it will be Juan and John
the two especialistas in bank s eh?
We'll call it Johnny and Johnny.
That's more American.
Amigo we go to America
there are bank s all over the place.
In California Colorado
Kansas City Texas and Austin.
You have to think of the big future
that we have ahead of us.
I'm thinking of the big train behind us.
Hey! Out of the way!
(horn blasts)
(train wheels screech)
(train chuffs)
Hey you.
I know that face.
Where have I seen you before?
(conductor) Stop right where you are!
Drop that knife you bastard.
(knife drops)
I have family.
(laughs)
I have a family too.
(conductor screams)
(train wheels screech)
(train horn blasts)
(hubbub of conversation)
Beautiful eh?
'Uno dos uno dos uno dos'
'Pelotn izquierda'
(officer shouts in Spanish)
Tienen algo qu pedir?
Y tu?
(shouts orders in Spanish)
Listos
(orders continue)
'Armas'
'Preparen '
(gun barrels click)
Apunten
- 'Fuego'
- (gunshots)
(gunshot)
Hey God you're sure this is Mesa Verde?
Do you have your beans with chilli?
I don 't want nothing from you.
- Aw come on have some beans.
- Listen you son of a bitch!
You pull that trick on me again
I break your goddamn head!
Well for Christ's sake.
A train comes along and I take it.
- Been waiting in your Mesa Verde ever since.
- It's not my Mesa Verde.
- This place is covered with soldiers like flies.
- Just the way we like it.
Just the way we like it?
If it's a revolution... it's confusion.
(mouths silently)
What are you talking about?
Revolution confusion?
Where there's confusion
a man who knows what he wants...
...stands a good chance of getting it.
- I don 't understand you.
This him?
That's him.
Him who?
- Do you trust me?
- No.
- You want to get inside there?
- S
Well I'm going to see to it
you have that chance. Come on.
(man groans)
(man shrieks)
(doctor) Don 't move goddamn it!
Hold him still.
(man shrieks)
(man gasps and groans)
(man screams)
That does it. Relax now. Relax.
It's all over.
If you'd let this infection go any longer
your widow would be paying my bill.
(old man coughs)
Mallory!
You've hardly joined us here in Mesa Verde.
Already you're front-page news.
"Irish dynamiter wanted for murder."
You have a real talent for making friends.
(chuckles) You've stirred up a hornet's nest.
I'll grant you the captain but...
...till now nobody dared
take a crack at foreign capitalists.
Not even Pancho Villa.
It seems even His Majesty's Secret Service
would like to get their hands on you.
And yet you are an asset to us.
Even if sometimes you do drink a bit too much.
Who says I drink too much?
Your liver does.
What about that one him?
He's all right.
Except that when operating
he cuts deeper than I do.
What the doctor means is
one time we did a little work together.
And now to our work friends.
I have good news.
In two days Villa and Zapata
will attack simultaneously from north and south.
(man coughs)
We here like those in other cities
must begin parallel actions of harassment.
Pereto's downfall is just a question of week s.
Whereas Miguel's is only a question of hours
if he doesn 't stop smoking.
Easy to say.
We'll attack in four places at the same time.
Antonio you hit the city hall and old prisons.
You will need to divide into two groups
one of them under the command of Jos.
Jess the railway station
and the marshalling yards as planned right?
Get in position in good time in small groups
so you won 't attract attention.
And act like ordinary travellers
or railroad employees.
You Manolo together with Juanito will attack
the army barrack s with our main forces agreed?
This is their point of maximum concentration
and is the key to the success of our plan.
You must create
the impression of a massive attack.
And if necessary
be prepared to make the final sacrifice.
The fourth and last target
Ortega the post office.
When the enemy is busy on four fronts
we'll move against our real objective.
Do we still agree?
- You'll need men.
- I only need one man.
One?
S
Him?
Him? Him?
What is with this "him"? Him who? Who him?
To do what? That's what I want to know!
To attack the bank.
The bank?
We will take care of the bank.
That's why we're here
so don 't worry about that.
Well then what can I say?
Except... I hope you make it.
Me too. And him.
Well we'll meet again tonight to discuss details.
I have to go now.
I left a woman in labour
and she can 't wait till the revolution is over.
(all laugh)
- Tierra y libertad
- (all) 'Tierra y libertad'
Leave one at a time and keep out of sight.
Speaking of sight how's your cataract?
At least I have a good eye. With the other...
Shh! You don 't have to say anything.
I understand everything.
'Tierra y libertad'
Y libertad
(rapid gunfire)
(shouting)
'Capitn ' 'Aviselas Capitn '
'Pronto' 'Hola munvase'
(gunfire continues)
Go.
Psst psst! 'Oye'
(gunfire and explosions)
Bravo Chulo.
Take it take it.
(gunfire explosions shouting in Spanish)
There must be a lot of money in the bank
look at all those soldiers.
- You know how this work s?
- S It's a...
...short fuse.
- No.
- No?
Normal rate.
30 seconds.
S 30 seconds.
(man shrieks)
- What did you find?
- Nothing but scrap paper.
Wait a minute. Hey it's pointing down there.
(gunshot)
Psst!
(gunshot resounds)
(gunshot)
There is the safe!
Duck, yo u sucko 's
- Where are you going for Christ's sake?
- I don 't know but something's wrong.
I went into the bank.
There's no money there nothing.
The bank and the money were transferred
to Mexico City a month ago.
They've been using this place
for a political prison ever since.
(laughs)
- What? A political prison?
- I never said a thing about money.
All I asked was if you wanted to get inside.
But this bank is my life this is my dream.
The reality is you've just liberated 150 patriots
through sheer courage in the face of danger.
(laughs)
(crowds shout in distance)
Ah yes...
...you're a grand hero of the revolution now.
-  Vivela Juan!
- I don 't want to be a hero. I want the money!
The money!
- You taught me one thing.
- What?
How to get fucked!
(man sings softly)
- What's that?
- It's a map.
It's your country you're lying all over.
Not my country.
My country is me and my family.
Well your country's also Huerta...
...and the Governor and landlords.
And Gunther Ruiz and his locusts.
- This little revolution we're having here.
- Revolution?
Please don 't try to tell me about revolution!
I know how revolutions start.
People that read book s
go to people that don 't read book s and say
- "The time has come for change."
- Shh!
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh! Shit shush!
I know what I'm talking about
when I'm talking about revolutions!
The people who read book s go to the people
who can 't read and say "We need change"
so the poor people make the change.
The people who read the book s sit around
big polished tables and talk and talk and eat.
But what has happened to the poor people?
They are dead!
That's your revolution.
Shh.
So please don 't tell me about revolutions.
Then what happens?
The same fucking thing starts all over again!
'Capitn '
'Vamos'
(sighs)
I don 't like it either.
Only Gunther Ruiz is less than 20 miles
from here on the road that leads to that bridge.
They will comb the area bush by bush.
So the order is to pull back
hide in the San Ysidro caves.
Oh that's a brilliant order.
Here we are facing it.
You and the rest of you dreamers
want to piss it up against the wall!
Not everybody can fight.
There are those who must organise
co-ordinate.
Yes yes of course.
Yeah well...
...don 't pay any attention to me.
It's personal.
Sorry about those orders. I'm staying.
I don 't give a fuck about your revolutions.
I'm tired of running up and down these
mountains and getting nowhere so I've stopped.
Right here at the bridge of San Jorge.
Maybe it's out of spite for you
and your slow dream or maybe...
Ah maybe my feet are sore.
'Hombres' Me and irlands are gonna catch
ourselves a couple of fucking locusts.
(commotion)
'Atente' You go back and hide in the grotto.
If things go bad here every man for himself.
You move your asses!  Comprenden?
(men shout)
If something happens
and your father doesn 't come back
then I pray that the great God in heaven
takes care of you.
Well... Good luck.
Thank you.
(men shout)
Listen when they are out of sight
we will make a run for it.  S?
No? You can 't mean to stay here? All those
explosions must have gone to your head!
Remember John and Juan?
America.
The millions.
No.
I don 't understand!
Wasn 't that was a trick for us to get out?
- What can we do against those locusts?
- You'd be doing me a favour if you'd leave.
If I had a choice between a chicken thief
and ridding the world of a few uniforms
I'd not choose the chicken thief.
OK.
No!
(laughs)
Oh no no. You will like that huh?
Well you listen to me you Irish piece of shit!
You think you're the only man
with the balls to stay? You are wrong!
I have the balls and I stay.
He says there's no danger
just watch the bridge from a long way.
No matter how I look with them
I'm still too close to the bridge.
Why am I mixed up in this revolution anyway?
God why didn 't you strike me down
instead of letting me say "I stay too"?
Oh look at him! All because of him.
He acts like a tourist only he's staying.
(laughs) Look at him.
What the hell does he care?
He is having fun.
I'm glad he's having fun God
because I am not having fun.
Oh-ho no.
Hey...
What's this?
Now he goes to sleep huh?
Go ahead you sleep sleep.
I tell you something when he's asleep I'll go.
Shh!
(laughs)
Stop over there Sergeant.
Hey!
God only an idiot could sleep at a time like this!
(clatter of hooves)
(clicks)
(gun rattles)
Abandon the truck s!
Break rank s and take cover under the bridge!
Artillery fire. The bridge!
(gunfire continues)
(gunfire persists)
(gunfire ceases)
All of them.
Six.
I've never counted them before.
No Juan no.
No for Christ's sake.
They're waiting for you out there.
(rapid gunfire)
(gunfire continues)
(lull in gunfire)
(gunfire recommences)
(gunfire continues)
(gunfire ceases)
(soldier) 'No se mueven '
'Capitn '
(shouting in Spanish)
(man) Hold it!
Move that bastard out of the truck.
(man) See that he gets to the camp alive!
(truck moves away)
(clap of thunder)
(official shouts in Spanish)
'Uno dos uno'
'Uno dos uno dos'
'Uno dos uno dos uno dos'
'Pelotn alto'
'lzquierda'
'Posicin de tiro'
Tienen algo qu pedir?
Pelotn
'Preparen '
- 'Armas'
- (gun barrels click)
'Apunten '
(gunshots)
(gunshots continue)
(man shouts in Spanish)
Tienes algo qu pedir?
(officer shouts orders in Spanish)
'Posicin de tiro'
'Preparen armas'
(gun barrels click)
'Apunten '
(John) Duck you suckers!
(rapid gunfire)
(gunfire and shouting)
(speaks Spanish)
(continues in Spanish)
'Preparen ' 'Armas'
(gun barrels click)
'Apunten '
'Fuego'
(continues to shouts orders)
(gunshots)
But for the rich you sing.
Oh Jesus Juan.
(John laughs)
Anyway if they ever get this thing under way
you might be able to...
...might be make the border by what
some time tonight don 't you think?
America. It's America Juan!
Oh Jesus if it's as great as they say it is
filled bags stuffed full of dreams...
Juan?
Oh Jesus.
Jesus Juan.
What is it Juan and... John?
Johnny and Johnny?
I make the holes and you get in. 50-50 right?
(clattering)
(clanging)
(agitated chatter)
(siren blasts)
What's happening?
Oh they're just moving the train around.
Seems we'll be leaving shortly.
The uniforms have loaded the last of their shit.
(whistle blows)
(train whistle blows)
(squawks)
(squawking persists)
(chicken clucks softly)
(squawking recommences)
(intense squawk)
(silence)
(train whistle blows)
(crashing)
(rapid gunfire)
Get out of the way.
What do you want from me you scum?
Let me by.
(gunfire continues outside)
(noise of gunfire intensifies)
It's yours.
There's a fortune inside.
...pearls.
(man shouts) 'Jvenes a Mxico'
Well this will not be going to America.
(Juan) Maybe the train won 't but we will.
Hey...
Which way is America?
Well it's sure as hell not that way.
That's the way.
Well then...
...let's go.
(both laugh)
(cheering)
Even Pancho Villa's heard much about you.
He's always saying
"I want to meet this Miranda."
Me?
That's right.
The military junta commander
told us everything that you've done.
Whatever you heard I assure you
they were only words.
Words cannot describe
what Juan has done and suffered for the cause.
(Juan laughs)
Hey doctor.
How you been eh?
This is a man who should talk to Villa.
Hey.
John.
We thought we'd lost you doctor.
(wheels screech)
(crashing)
Have you got a light?
Listen Gunther Ruiz is after us
and Villa wants to talk to me.
We should get outta here.
Jesus Juan you can 't leave now.
You're a glorious hero of the revolution.
Can I tell you something?
Fuck you!
That's all.
A military train carrying over 1000 soldiers and
heavy weapons is heading straight towards us.
What about Villa's troops?
He met resistance in the Sierra
and ask s us to hold out for 24 hours.
- Where the hell are we?
- Approximately here.
Ah it's a beautiful desert there.
Not a stream or a canyon in 100 miles.
- How long you think it'll take them to get here?
- Three hours more or less.
Three hours.
Well it look s as though
we'll have to stop 'em right here doesn 't it?
All that takes
is unbolting a couple of yards of track.
But then what? They'd still slaughter us.
Wait.
There's more than one way to stop a train.
- How much dynamite have we?
- Maybe 200 Ibs.
Is that enough for you?
Oh yes. It'll have to do all right.
- But I also need a locomotive and a man.
- S s s OK.
OK.
- Someone who's brave and loyal to the cause.
- Never mind that. What do I have to do?
Someone like Dr Villega.
Well...
- I... I'm honoured.
- (John) I don 't doubt it doctor.
Also because an old friend of ours
is in command of that train.
A Colonel Gunther Ruiz.
(train whistle blows)
(John) Let's get shovelling man.
We'll never get up enough pressure that way.
Come on put your back in it Villega.
Let's stop pretending right away.
You know everything don 't you?
- You sensed it or guessed it.
- Simpler than that Villega.
I saw you that night in the rain.
I see.
You've already judged and condemned me.
That's why you brought me with you. To kill me.
It's easy to judge. Have you ever been tortured?
Are you sure you wouldn 't talk?
I was sure. And yet I talked.
Some men died because of me.
What should I do? Kill myself? Why?
The dead remain dead but I have not changed.
I still believe in the same things.
I can still serve the cause.
Shut up Villega! Shut up for Christ's sake.
When I started using dynamite
I believed in many things. All of it!
Finally I believe only in dynamite.
I don 't judge you Villega.
I did that only once in my life.
Get shovelling!
(John) The end of the line Villega.
And I can 't help you now.
Just close your eyes and jump.
'Dios mo frena'
(screechging)
(whistle blows)
(gunfire and explosions)
(explosion)
(gunfire continues)
(piercing gunshot)
(second gunshot)
Oh shit...
God...
(groans)
Hey.
Man remember huh?
You remember what you told me huh?
You told me about America.
And the bank s and the gold.
Like you told me on the train remember?
Hey hey.
Hey.
(Juan laughs)
No you son of a bitch. Come on
you son of a bitch. You know you told me that.
You leave me now
what the fuck is gonna happen to me?
- You'll make it General.
- Oh shit I don 't want to be a general.
Come on talk to me.
Keep talking.
Talk. Tell me about Villega Villega.
Remember Villega?
- Villega?
- S
He died.
He died a great...
...grand glorious hero of the revolution.
(John laughs)
OK.
Easy easy. I'll go I'll get help huh?
General?
- Have you a light?
- S
Oh my friend...
...I'd hate to give you a royal screwing.
I go get help.
(gunfire continues)
Johnny!
(thinks) What about me?