THREE COLORS
BLUE
Hurry, Anna.
Get back in.
Are you able to talk?
During the...
were you conscious?
I'm sorry to have to inform you...
Do you know?
Your husband...
died in the accident.
You must have been unconscious.
Anna?
Yes, your daughter too.
Is someone there?
Who did that?
Mr. Leroy,
call the head of the ward.
Someone broke a window
in the corridor on the first floor.
Come right away.
I'll look in the garden.
I can't... I'm unable to...
I broke the window.
Don't worry.
I'm sorry.
We'll replace it.
Don't worry.
Is it today?
This afternoon. At five o'clock.
Can I do anything for you?
We are gathered here
to pay our last respects
to a man,
a composer that the entire world
considered one of the greatest.
No one
can accept that he is gone.
We also mourn
his five year-old daughter
who died by his side.
Patrice,
millions of men
and women
awaited the music you composed
for the Unification of Europe,
which we all hope to celebrate soon.
Hello.
I know you don't want to see me.
You're right.
- Can I come in?
- No.
Julie...
it's not for an interview.
What then?
I'm writing an article
about your husband.
- I need to know something.
- About what?
The concert
for the Unification of Europe.
It doesn't exist.
You've changed.
You weren't so rude before.
Haven't you heard?
I had an accident.
I lost my daughter and my husband.
Is it true you wrote
your husband's music?
Hello!
Bernard?
Hello, ma'am.
Did you do what I asked?
- You cleared out the blue room?
- Everything.
Madam, we' re all deeply sorry.
Marie.
Why are you crying?
Because you're not.
I keep thinking of them.
I remember everything.
How can I forget?
Would you like something to drink?
No thank you.
Let's sit down.
This could take a while.
I'll be right back.
No one must know.
Even
You'll pay for my mother's
rest home for the rest of her life.
You'll take care of Marie...
and the gardener.
You'll sell all our possessions.
The money will go
to the same account.
The 270641196?
Yes.
May I ask you why?
No.
Would you excuse me?
But what will you have left?
My own account.
I haven't started yet.
I put it aside...
The day I left?
Yes.
Here it is.
I was waiting to hear from you.
You were right.
Lots of corrections.
No more than usual.
It's beautiful.
I love this chorus.
Yes.
Hello?
It's Julie.
Do you love me?
Yes.
Since when?
Since I started working
with Patrice.
Do you think of me?
Do you miss me?
Yes.
Come, if you want to.
Now?
Yes, now. Right away.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Olivier?
I fell.
Take it off.
The rest too.
They took everything.
Only the mattress is left.
I appreciate what you did for me.
But you see,
I'm like any other woman.
I sweat. I cough.
I have cavities.
You won't miss me.
You understand that now.
Shut the door when you leave.
Julie!
I don't want any children
in the building.
Let me ask you something.
It may help.
What do you do?
Nothing.
I mean, for a living?
Nothing at all?
Nothing at all.
I have what you're looking for.
You'll like it,
but it's being redone.
It may take a while.
But I can live there now?
Sure. It needs a quick paint job,
the carpets changed...
I'd like to see it now.
May I?
Of course. What's your name?
Julie de Courcy, with a|
Sorry, Julie Vignon.
I'm going back
to my maiden name.
Coffee and ice cream?
As usual.
Is anyone there?
I'm sorry for the noise.
I've almost finished.
I haven't heard anything.
May I?
I heard you got locked out
last week.
Your husband lent me a blanket.
I spent the night in the stairwell.
I wanted you to sign this.
What is it?
Everyone has signed already.
We don't want loose women
in our building.
The young woman downstairs...
I don't want to get involved.
She's a whore!
That's not my problem.
You're in perfect health.
Everything is fine.
You're in good spirits.
Hello, it's Antoine.
It's for you.
Hello. My name is Antoine.
You don't know me.
No, I don't. Excuse me...
Who is this?
He's been looking for you.
I said he could call.
That's okay.
I'd like to meet you.
It's important.
Nothing's important.
It's about an object.
What object?
A necklace...
with a cross.
I'd forgotten about it.
I found it near the car.
But...
I couldn't keep it.
That's stealing.
If you want to ask me something,
I got there just after...
No.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to return the necklace,
but I wanted
to ask you something, too.
Yes?
When I opened the door,
your husband was still alive.
He said...
...I don't understand...
he said...
"Now try coughing."
My husband was telling us a joke.
It's about a woman who...
who can't stop coughing.
She sees a doctor.
He examines her and gives her
a pill. She swallows it.
She asks what it is.
The doctor says: "It's the most
powerful laxative there is."
"A laxative for a cough?"
"Yes," says the doctor.
"Now try coughing!"
It made us laugh.
Then the car crashed.
My husband always liked
to repeat the punch line.
You returned it.
It's yours.
Are you sick?
Are you okay?
You always gotta hold
onto something.
What did you say?
Thanks.
For what?
I'm staying.
They needed everyone's signature
to kick me out. So I'm staying.
Your place is cool.
When I was a kid,
I had a lamp just like this.
I'd stand under it
and stretch out my hand.
I dreamt of jumping up
and touching it.
I forgot all about it.
Where did you find it?
I found it.
Is it a souvenir?
You live alone?
Yes.
I could never spend
a night alone.
Something must have happened.
You're not the type
somebody dumps.
Sorry. I talk too much.
Poor guy.
Who?
He was asleep there last night.
He's gone now,
but he left his flute.
A coffee.
I searched everywhere.
And?
I found you.
No one knows where I live.
No one.
It took a few months.
Then I got lucky.
My cleaning lady's daughter
saw you in the area.
I've come here ever since.
You're spying on me?
No.
I miss you.
You ran away?
From me?
Do you hear what he's playing?
It sounds like...
Yes.
I've seen you.
Maybe that will do for now.
I'll try.
How do you know this music?
I invent lots of things.
I like to play.
Just a second.
A problem with your place?
No, I'd like another one
just like it.
I can manage that.
But it'll take some time.
How long?
Two or three months.
You cut yourself shaving.
My cat scratched me.
Mom?
Marie-France.
It's me.
Julie.
Come closer.
They told me you were dead.
You seem fine.
Young. So young.
You were always younger,
but now you look 30.
- When we were kids...
- I'm not your sister.
I'm your daughter.
I'm 33.
I know, I know.
I'm joking.
I'm fine.
I have everything here.
The TV...
I can see the whole world.
Do you watch too?
No.
You want to tell me
about your husband and your home?
Or about your children?
Or about yourself?
Mom...
my husband and daughter
are dead.
I have no home any more.
They told me.
Before, I was happy.
I loved them.
They loved me too.
Mom, are you listening?
Yes, Marie-France.
Now I have only
one thing left to do:
Nothing.
I don't want any belongings,
any memories.
No friends, no love.
Those are all traps.
Do you have any money, my child?
To get by?
I have enough.
That's important.
You can't give up everything.
Mom.
Yes?
Was I scared of mice
as a kid?
You weren't scared.
It was Julie who was scared.
Now I'm scared.
I'm glad to see you.
Come in.
I have a favor to ask.
My wife isn't here.
Come on in.
Can you lend me your cat?
Excuse me?
Your cat.
I need it for a couple of days.
He's not neutered.
He can get violent.
I'm not sure he likes you.
Why are you here?
I saw you from the bus.
You were running like crazy.
Are you crying?
It's the water.
- You don't wear underwear?
- Never.
I borrowed the neighbor's cat
to kill the mouse.
It had babies.
It's only normal, Julie.
You're afraid to go back?
I'll go clean up.
I'll see you at my place.
It's Lucille.
I need a favor.
Take a taxi here.
I'll pay you back.
Now?
It's late.
It's 11:30. You have 25 minutes.
It's important.
I can't.
Please. I've never asked you
anything. I have to now. Come.
Where?
3 Cite du Midi. It's near Pigalle.
First door on the left.
There's a buzzer
Say it's for me. You'll come?
Yes?
I'm here to see Lucille.
I'm coming.
You came.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Are you angry?
No.
Lucille, we're on in 5 minutes.
Get me ready.
After I changed,
I came here for a drink.
I looked around the audience,
for no reason.
In the middle,
in the first row, I saw my father.
He seemed tired.
He was nodding off...
but kept staring
at the girl's ass.
The shithead who let you in
wouldn't make him leave.
If you pay, you can peep.
Get it?
I didn't know who I could count on.
I was desperate.
I didn't know who to talk to.
- So I called you.
- And your father?
Ten minutes ago,
he looked at his watch and left.
I realized the last train
to Montpellier is at 11:45.
Lucille, why do you do this?
Because I like to.
I think everyone likes to.
Julie, you saved my life.
I didn't do a thing.
I asked you to come and you came.
Same thing.
No.
Isn't that you?
Lucille, we're on.
It's me.
...the European Council asked you
to finish the score
begun by Patrice de Courcy.
I agreed to.
I'm working on it now...
trying to understand
what he was aiming for.
It's not easy... I don 't know.
Can you tell us something
about this score, shown here
for the very first time?
It's the first part
of a major concerto
Patrice composed,
commissioned
by the European Council.
The concerto was
to be played just once
by twelve symphonic orchestras
in the twelve united
European cities.
Patrice was someone who...
was secretive.
The only one person
who understood him...
was Julie, his wife.
I tried asking her to participate
in this program,
but unfortunately,
she refused.
I assume that these documents
are from the archives.
No, they're not archives.
Who can predict...?
They're photos and documents
I found in Patrice's desk
at the Conservatory.
His wife didn't want them.
I'm not sure
I should show them.
He was a great man.
One of the most important
composers of our time.
I'll be five minutes.
Where did I put it?
A green calling card.
Did you watch TV today?
Not at all.
Here it is.
Her number at home and at work.
Why do you want it?
Today, on TV,
she showed the scores
I took from you.
Yes...
After the accident, when
nothing was sure, I made a copy.
When you picked it up,
I knew you'd destroy it.
I kept the copy.
I sent it to Strasbourg.
Why did you do that?
This music is so beautiful.
You can't destroy things like that.
Olivier!
I'm sorry.
It's nothing.
I heard you're finishing
Patrice's concerto.
I thought I could try...
You can't.
You have no right.
It'll never be the same.
Understand?
I said I'd try.
I don't know if I'll finish.
I'll tell you why. It was a way...
that's what I thought...
to make you cry, make you run.
The only way of making you say,
"I want" or "I don't want".
It's not fair.
You didn't leave me any choice.
You don't have the right to.
You want to see what I've done?
I'm not sure I understood.
If I could play for you...
Do you know what the chorus sings?
I thought Patrice had told you.
No.
In Greek, the rhythm is different.
Who was that girl?
What girl?
In the photos on the program.
She was with Patrice.
Didn't you know?
Just tell me.
Were they together?
Yes.
Since when?
Several years.
Where does she live?
Near Montparnasse.
They often met at the courts.
She's a lawyer.
Or she works for one.
What do you want to do?
Meet her.
Excuse me.
...what about equality?
Is it because I don't speak French
that the court won't hear my case?
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Yes?
You were
my husband's mistress?
Yes.
I didn't know. I just found out.
It's a shame.
Now you'll hate him.
You'll hate me too.
I don't know...
Of course you will.
Is that his baby?
Yes.
But he didn't know.
I found out...
I found out after the accident.
I didn't want a child, but
it happened. Now I want to keep it.
Do you have a cigarette?
You shouldn't.
You want to know
when and where?
How many times a month?
No.
You want to know if he loved me?
Yes, that was my question.
But why ask?
I know he loved you.
Yes.
He loved me.
Julie...
Will you hate me now?
Come in.
Did something happen?
You met her?
Once you asked me
to take Patrice's papers.
- You didn't want to.
- No, but if I had...
The photos were among them?
Yes.
If I had taken them,
I'd have known.
If I'd burned them,
I'd never have known.
That's right.
Maybe it's better this way.
Can you show me
what you've composed?
These are the violins?
The altos.
And now...
Wait a second. Lighter,
without the percussions.
Let's remove the trumpets.
Piano, piano, sul, sul taste.
Instead of a piano...
A flute?
A flute. Start back here.
That's as far as I got.
And the finale?
I don't know.
There was a paper.
The counterpoint
was supposed to come back.
He told me: "It's a memento."
Try weaving it back in.
Van den Budenmayer?
He wanted to allude to him at the
end. You know how much he loved him.
Are you still in touch
with our lawyer?
Sometimes.
Did he sell the house yet?
I don't know.
I doubt it. He'd have called.
Tell him not to.
Okay.
If you can handle all this,
will you show me?
I'll show you.
There was a mattress inside.
Mr. Olivier bought it.
I didn't think you'd need it.
That's fine.
Have you been here before?
No, never.
Upstairs are the bedrooms and the
office. I'll show you them later.
This is the kitchen.
It's always been like this.
Is it a boy
or a girl?
A boy.
Have you chosen a name?
Yes.
I thought...
he should have his name
and his house.
Here.
Do you still need me?
No, you can go home.
Thank you.
I knew it.
What?
Patrice told me a lot about you.
Really?
Like what?
That you are good.
That you are good and generous.
That's what you want to be.
People can always count on you.
Even me.
I'm sorry.
It's me. I've finished.
Come pick it up tomorrow.
Or now, if you're not too tired.
I'm not tired. But I won't come
pick up the score.
What?
I won't pick it up.
I've been thinking about it all
week long. This music can be mine.
A little heavy and awkward,
but mine. Or yours,
but everyone would have to know.
Are you there?
I'm here.
You're right.
It's me again.
I wanted to ask you.
You really sleep
on the mattress...?
Yes.
You never told me.
No, I didn't.
Do you still love me?
I love you.
Are you alone?
Of course I'm alone.
I'm coming.
Though I speak
with the tongue of angels,
If I have not love,
I am become as hollow brass.
Though I have the gift of prophecy,
And understand all mysteries
And all knowledge...
And though l have enough faith
To move the mightiest mountains,
If I have not love,
I am nothing.
Love is patient.
Love is kind.
It bears all things.
It hopes all things.
Love never fails.
For prophecies shall fail,
Tongues shall cease,
Knowledge shall wither away.
For prophecies shall fail,
Tongues shall cease,
Knowledge shall wither away.
And now shall abide...
Faith, hope, and love.
But the greatest of these three
Is love.
Subtitled by Andrew Litvak
Subtitling: C.M.C. - Paris