Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
NEON GENESIS
Sections 1 and 2 of the east complex will be closed at 18:00 today.
Please finish the
replacement by 16:30.
Both Misato and
Ayanami scare me.
Help me...
Help me, Asuka.
Hey, wake up.
Hey.
Open your eyes.
Hey, hey...
Asuka...
...Asuka...
Asuka!
Help me.
Why don't you make fun
of me like you used to?
Hey!
I'm so disgusting.
Episode 25'
All doorways to our main
facilities are closed?
And we're in the
`ffirst alert" mode?
Why?
He was the last
Angel, wasn't he?
Yes, all the Angels
were supposedly destroyed.
Aren't we finally at peace?
So what's going to happen
to this place and the Evas?
And Ritsuko
isn't around.
I think Nerv
will be disbanded.
I have no idea what
lies ahead for us.
We have to put up with it until the Instrumentality Project begins.
Humans are incomplete...
...and they must become independent life forms by means of the Instrumentality Project...
Sounds like
an ideal world.
The Committee will use the Eva instead of Adam and Nerv to realize it.
Just as
Kaji expected.
The promised
time has come.
We've lost the
Longinus Lance...
...so we can't use Lillith
to proceed with the project.
We expect you to carry out the project using a duplicate of Lillith, Eva Unit 01.
That's different
from Seele's scenario.
Humans exist to
create Eva.
Humans should evolve
into a new form.
That's what the
Eva series is for.
We don't have to give up being human
to cling to an ark called Eva.
This is only a rite of passage for humanity at an impasse to rebirth.
A fated destruction will lead to the pleasure of resurrection.
In order for God, humanity and all life forms to unite as one someday...
Death won't
create anything.
You all
deserve death.
The meaning of humanity
is their wish to survive.
That's the hope of the woman who willingly stayed inside the Eva.
I see. That's the true objective of the Second Impact.
Was I noticed?!
No, that's not it.
It's the beginning.
The sixth network
is down!
Switch the left to an
emergency blue connection!
You can open
the satellite.
Yes. ~~What about
the right one?
All outside network links have been disconnected from the other side.
Is their
target Magi...?
Data is coming in from
all external terminals.
They're attempting
to hack into Magi.
As I thought.
Is Magi-2 in Matsushiro
the only invader?
No!~~At least five of the
Magi types are invading!
I can confirm the invasion from Germany, China and America!
Seele is using
its full potential.
The power balance
is 5 to 1.
We are at
a disadvantage.
The fourth defensive
shield has fallen.
I'm closing the
main database.
It didn't work!
I can't stop their advance!
It has entered the outer shell.
The backup system is inoperative.
This is bad. The seizure of Magi means the occupation of headquarters.
I know.
The independent defense
of Magi, right?
Yes, Lt Ibuki will explain at the second command center.
He's such an egoist, trying to use a woman he deserted.
Status?
Good morning.
A-801 was issued from
Tokyo-2 a while ago.
801?
Repeal of the privileged protection of Special Taskforce Nerv...
...and the transfer of command
to the Japanese government.
It's their
last notice.
Yes, that's right. ~~They're currently trying to hack into Magi.
We're at
a disadvantage.
This is Ibuki.
Dr. Akagi has started working
on protective measures.
Ritsuko has...?
Am I doing
something silly?
Logic has no meaning in the relationship between a man and a woman.
Don't you think so...
...Mom?
Recovery of ground communication in Goura has been increased by 0.2 percent.
How much longer?
She seems to be finishing up.
It's just like Dr. Akagi.
Only an invasion
of Magi?
I don't think we'll
get off that easy.
The seizure of Magi
is just a prologue.
Their object is to seize headquarters and the remaining Eva units.
Yes, and we have both
Lillith and Adam, as well.
No wonder those
old men are so hasty.
The hacking of
Magi has stopped.
B-Danang type-M defense system is employed.
Invasion will be impossible for the next 60 days.
See you later, Mother.
Ikari used the 666 protection.
It's so hard to break through.
We'll have to give up
on the seizure of Magi.
We wanted this to be peacefully, but we'll have to occupy the headquarters directly.
Let's carry out the
mission as planned.
Radar sites No. 8 through 17
have been disabled!
A special taskforce battalion is advancing from the Goura defensive line.
Two battalions are approaching from Gotenba, as well.
Three aircraft squadrons
are approaching from Mishima.
Our last enemies
are humans, after all.
All personnel,
to first class battle stations.
Battle stations...?
Even though they
aren't Angels...
...but humans?
The other side doesn't
think that way.
What happened?!
Hey?!
What is it?
The south
hub station...
The 7th tunnel
was destroyed.
A fire has broken out
in west cargo bay 5.
The invaders have reached
the first level.
The units in the
west are decoys!
If their target is the Evas,
they'll try to kill the pilots first!
Put Shinji on standby
in Unit 01 immediately!
Okay.
Where's Asuka?
She's in hospital
room 303.
Very well.
Move her to Unit 02.
But she hasn't regained her
synchro rate with Unit 02 yet!
She will definitely be
killed if she stays there.
So hiding her in the Eva is the most certain way to protect her.
Roger.
Stop the treatment
of the pilot...
...and prepare for launch!
As soon as she gets onboard, hide Unit 02 at the bottom of the lake.
She'll be found soon, but it's a little better than the cage.
Where's Rei?
Unknown.
I can't find her.
She'll be killed.
Find her quickly.
Unit 02 has
been launched!
After going through route 8,
it will be positioned at 70 deep.
Launch Unit 01, and position
it inside the Geo Front...
We can't,
the pilot hasn't...
Oh, my god...
All gates of Central Dogma up to level 2 will be closed.
All noncombatants,
stand by at route 87.
The 3rd underground wall was destroyed.
They've advanced to the second level.
They've mobilized
a division.
The occupation of headquarters
is only a matter of time.
Professor Fuyutsuki,
please take care of the rest.
I know.
Say hello
to Yui.
The second group
isn't responding!
Communications with the 77th
computer room has been cut off.
The 52nd linear rail
was destroyed.
They're so annoying.
I would've preferred Angels.
It can't be helped.
We're not used to killing humans.
Cut the red
cables first.
Invaders on level 3,
block-M.
We can't stop them!
From block-F, also. The main bypass was broken through by force.
Abandon everything down to level 3!
All combatants, withdraw!
Inject Bakelite into all routes
and pipes up to section 803!
Okay.
30 seconds to complete the injection
of Bakelite into section 703.
20 seconds to complete the injection
of Bakelite into section 737.
We should be able to
hold out a little longer.
Major Katsuragi, route 47 was destroyed,
and group 3 has been pinned down!
At this rate, Shinji...
Prevent the noncombatants from
engaging in hand to hand combat.
These guys
are pros.
If the group can't return to Dogma,
it would be better to surrender.
Sorry, I have to leave
the rest to you.
Okay.
Forget about Mt. Futago.
Hurry to block off the Nagao Pass.
It's taking longer
than expected.
We don't have
an easy job.
It's not fair.
We aren't equipped with effective anti-personnel weapons.
We're only equipped to
handle terrorists at most.
If the tactical defense force is fully mobilized, this place won't even last for a second.
Come to think of it...
...foreseeing this, the budget cut on dealing with invaders might have been decided.
Now that you
mention it...
Release the safety.
I... I can't shoot guns.
You've done it in
training many times!
But those
weren't humans!
You fool!
If you don't shoot,
you'll die!
Rei...
You're here,
after all.
The promised time has come.
Let's go.
The second level is
completely secured, over.
The original Magi at the second command center hasn't been seized yet.
Fighting at the left
wing on the lower level...
Carry out the heat dissolution
procedure immediately.
As soon as you find
the Eva pilots, kill them.
You're also allowed
to shoot noncombatants.
Yanagihara and Shinjo units,
enter the lower level, quickly.
I found the `TThird. "
Proceeding with termination.
Don't blame me, kid.
Don't blame me.
Let's go...
...to Unit 01.
The purple one
has been secured.
There was no problem
injecting the Bakelite.
The red one seems to have been taken out, and we're currently searching...
This isn't good.
They're attempting to physically
separate you from Unit 01.
There's no time
to lose.
Let's go, Shinji.
Choose whether you escape
here or get in Unit 01.
At this rate, you'll
die meaninglessly!
Help me, Asuka...
...help me.
You beg a girl for help at a time like this, and try to look away!
It's terrible to
be so indecisive!
Now, stand up!
Stand up!
No, I want
to die.
I don't want
to do anything.
Don't act like a child!
You're still alive, aren't you?
Then why don't you try
harder before you die?!
It's alright. Not this place, but separate Terminal Dogma first.
They've blown up so many places, but, as expected, they aren't doing that in here!
They probably want to finish it in one blow, but the original Magi is underneath us.
They want to try and
seize it intact, I guess.
But we're poorly equipped against biochemical weapons.
If they use them,
we're doomed.
And the N2 weapon, as well.
Speak of the devil...!
They aren't holding
back at all!
They're overdoing it.
Why do they want
the Eva so desperately?!
They're going to cause
the Third Impact...
...by using the Eva series
instead of an Angel.
The Second Impact, that occurred 15 years ago, was deliberately set by humans.
It was to reduce Adam to an egg to prevent the other Angels from causing a greater tragedy.
Shinji...
...just like Adam, a lifeform called Lillith created us, the 18th Angels.
The remaining Angels
were other possibilities...
...that look different
from humans.
We were destined to hate each other even though we both are `hhuman. "
Listen, Shinji, destroy
all of the Eva series.
That will be the only
way for us to survive.
The phone doesn't
work anymore.
Nagano Prefecture New Tokyo-2
Prime Minister's Residence 3rd Office
No. We've confirmed explosions from ballistic missiles three minutes ago.
The Human Instrumentality Project that Nerv was secretly advancing...
...turned out to involve the Third Impact leading to the extinction of all human life.
I guess humans are the only
lifeforms that hate each other.
Now all that's left is to take care of the ruins of Nerv Headquarters.
Are you going to ask Germany or
China to help in reconstruction?
They'll knock
down the price.
So it will be closed for the next 20 years just like old Tokyo.
The heat on the surface has dropped. High pressure steam is no longer a problem.
All units are at
their initial positions.
Currently, up through level 3 of Dogma and the purple one are under our control.
What about
the red one?
It was found at the bottom of the underground lake, at 70.2 deep.
The condition of
the pilot is unknown.
I'm alive...
I don't want to die...
~~~~~I don't want to die...
I DON'T WANT TO DIE!
Stay alive.
You shouldn't die.
I won't let you die.
Please, die with me.
You shouldn't die.
Stay alive.
Please, die with me!
Don't kill her!
Stay alive.
Mama, you're here!
Mama!
What the...?
Did we get it?
Mama...
Mama,
I understand...
...what the AT field is!
You're protecting me!
You're watching me!
You've been together with me from the beginning, Mama!
Eva Unit 02 activated!
Asuka's alright!
She's alive!
She is...?!
The cable!
Just concentrate on
its power cable!
Even if I don't have
the umbilical cable...
I've got 12,000 special
armor plates and...
...the AT field!
I won't lose...
...to you guys!
Eva, which should have been disabled,
is interfering with us again.
It takes poison to
quell poison, after all...
Eva series...?
Is it complete...?
They mobilized all nine of the units equipped with the S2 Organ...
It's too showy.
Are they going to
make it happen here?
Listen, Asuka...
...make sure to destroy all of the Eva series, alright?
I'll send Shinji out soon,
so hang in there.
So, emergency route 20 is open to get to Unit 01, right?
Yes, three power
lines are secured.
If you get there in 3 minutes,
you can head directly to cage 7.
Make sure to destroy
all of them...?
How could she be so harsh to someone who just got well?
Nine units in
3 and half minutes...
I only have
20 seconds for each.
That's one.
This is it.
I missed.
We failed to kill the target.
Request further instructions.
No need to pursue.
That place will be blown up.
Return immediately.
Roger.
I bought us
some time.
Don't worry.
It's not too serious.
The power is on.
You can go.
Listen, Shinji, you'll be
alone from this point on...
...so you'll have to decide
everything on your own.
I can't...
I can't.
I can't pilot the Eva if I have
to hurt or kill people.
I don't have the
right to do so.
I thought I had no choice
but to pilot the Eva...
...but it was
only an excuse.
I don't see anything so
I don't deserve the Eva, either.
There's nothing
I can do for anyone!
I did something
terrible to Asuka...
...and I killed
Kaworu, too.
I have no compassion,
I'm just sly and cowardly.
All I can do
is hurt people!
If so, I'd rather
do nothing!
I won't sympathize
with you.
If `yyou" don't want to get hurt,
die without trying anything.
Nothing will happen,
even if you cry!
You hate yourself.
Therefore, you're still
hurting others anyway.
You hurt yourself because you know it's more painful to hurt others.
But no matter how you feel, the result comes from your own judgement.
It's meaningful, Shinji.
It's about
you yourself.
Don't look away, but think about what you can do to atone for your sin.
But you're not me, and you
don't understand anything!
What's the matter with that?!
Are you going to quit now?!
If you don't
do anything...
...I won't
forgive you.
I'll never forgive you!
I'm not perfect
myself right now.
I realize what I've done wrong,
and regretted it later again and again.
That's how
I have been.
It's been a continuous cycle of premature delight and self-disgust...
...but each time,
I felt like I stepped forward.
Listen, Shinji...
...pilot the Eva one more time,
and break your cycle as an Eva pilot.
Find your own answers as to why you came here and why you're still here.
And when you settle the matter,
make sure you come back.
Promise?
Take care.
That's an adult kiss.
Let's do the rest
when you come back.
I should have changed the carpet like Asuka suggested...
...right, Pen-Pen?
Kaji, I did the
right thing, didn't I?
You're so
damn persistent...
...and I can't rely
on that stupid Shinji!
I've been waiting.
Sorry, but I changed Magi's
program before you did.
It's the last request
from your daughter.
Mom, please
die with me.
It didn't work...?
Why not?
Denied
Casper betrayed me!
You chose your man
instead of your daughter.
Akagi Ritsuko...
I truly...
You liar.
How is she
doing out there?
There's less than
1 minute until the limit.
At this rate,
Asuka will...
I can't lose...
...because Mama's
watching me!
Mama...
Mother?
This is the
last one!
The Longinus Lance...?!
The internal power
has run out.
Eva Unit 02 has reached
its activation limit.
What's happening...?
The defeated
Eva series are...
The Eva series
have reactivated.
Are they going
to finish it off?
What's happening?!
I can't keep watching!
I don't want to watch!
Is that Unit 02?!
I'll kill you.
Out of control?!
Stop, Asuka.
Don't!
I'll kill you.
Shinji!
Unit 02...
Asuka is...!
But I can't get
onboard the Eva.
There's nothing
I can do.
Mother...
Unit 01 has
activated.
Evangelion Unit 01...?!
It truly
is a demon!
Asuka...
To be continued
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing Todd Perkins Hiroaki
Fukuda Dave Brain Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
Shinji: Misato: Ritsuko: Rei: Asuka:
Gendou: Fuyutsuki:
Makoto: Maya: Shigeru:
Committee:
Ogata Megumi Mitsuishi Kotono Yamaguchi
Yuriko Hayashibara Megumi Miyamura Yuko
Tachiki Fumihiko Kiyokawa Genmu Yuuki
Hiro Nagasawa Miki Koyasu Takehito
Nagasumi Takashi Suzuki
Katsumi Koyasu Takehito