RABBI: Savree maranun
verabonun verobotay
Baruch atah Adonai eloheynu
melech ha-olam
Boray p'ree ha-gafen
Baruch atah Adonai eloheynu
melech ha-olam
A-sher kid'shanu b'mitzvo-tav
V'ratza va-nu
v'shabbat kaddsho
B'ahavah oov-ratzone
hin-cheelanu
Zee-karon Pma-ah-say
Way-sheet kee hoo yom
T'cheelah Fmikraay kodesh
Zaycher leetzeeat mitzrayim
Kee vanu vachatah v'ohtahnu
keydashta mekol ha-ahmim
V'shabbat kadd-shcha
b'ahavah oov-ratzone
Hin-chal-ta-nu
Baruch atah, Adonai
m'kaddaysh ha-Shabbat
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Name?
Horowitz, Salomon.
(MANY PEOPLE
TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Schneider, Sarah.
MAN 1: Birnbaum, Olga.
(CHILDREN CRYING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Over there. Over there!
Kommen Sie doch.
Isak Hudes.
Zucker, Helena.
MAN 2: Zucker, Helena.
Hirsch, Salomon?
Hirsch, Salomon.
Hauptman, Chaim!
Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
Feber, Ludwig!
MAN 3: Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
Josef Klein.
MAN 4: Klein.
Davidowich, lgnacy.
Paula Biffer.
Nadel, Rachela.
Steiner, Gertruda.
Steiner, Hilda.
(GLOOMY SUNDAY PLAYING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(GUESTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISPERING)
MAITRE'D: Jerzy, you know who that man is?
I don't know.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
Let's get together, please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir.
Bring them over
a round of drinks.
Very good, sir. And who
shall I say they are from?
You can say they are from me.
From the gentleman.
Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir.
Agnieszka, I would give anything
to hear you sing tonight.
(SIGHS) But I know you won't.
(LAUGHS)
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman alone at the
table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're
the picture of loneliness.
Oh.
Mmm, what a lovely fragrance.
You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please.
Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady?
Pernod.
Im Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion
(MEN WHISTLING AND LAUGHING)
lst Holzauktion
lm Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion
MAN: Come to the table,
girls! Drink with us!
Ist Holzauktion
Links um die Ecke 'rum,
rechts um die Ecke 'rum
Überall ist heute Holzauktion
Come to us! Marry us!
(WHISPERING)
Der ganze Klafter
Süßsholz kostet 'nen Taler
'nen Taler, 'nen Taler
Der ganze Klafter Süßholz
kostet 'nen Taler
'nen Taler. ..
Thank you.
I'll tell you what
I mean by cooperative.
Two days after
the law is passed
that all Jews have
to wear the star,
the Jewish tailors are
turning them out by the gross
in a variety of
fabrics at three zloty each.
Tell me about
your cellar wines.
I have an excellent German Riesling.
1937. Mmm, French.
A Bordeaux. Château Latour, '28, '29?
No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea
what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem
of a riding club.
A Margaux, '29?
No, no, we don't have that.
Burgundy then? A
Romanée-Conti, '37? Yes.
It's human nature.
"We'll do this to avoid that."
That's what they have done
since thousands of years.
It's what they do.
They weather the storm.
But this storm is different. This is not the Romans.
This storm is the SS.
Wem Gott will
rechte Gunst erweisen
Den schickt er
in die weite Welt
Wem Gott will rechte
Gunst erweisen
Den schickt er
in die weite Welt
Faleri, Falera
Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha
Faleri, Falera
Den schickt er
in die weite Welt
Martin.
Yes, sir.
Who is that man?
That's Oskar Schindler!
Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha
Den schickt er
in die weite Welt
Faleri, Falera
Den schickt er
in die weite Welt
(ALL CHEERING)
(SINGING SONG IN GERMAN)
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
An alle Juden!
Ab sofort ist es alien
Juden untersagt...
Fleisch auf koschere Art
zuzubereiten.
Meldung an alle Juden.
Ab sofort...
Rabbi...
Private property
cannot be confiscated.
How long are the schools
going to be closed?
I do not know.
"Article 47, pillage
is formally prohibited."
You don't know anything!
I am familiar with the Hague Convention.
Religious...
They come into our house and tell
us we don't live there anymore.
It now belongs to
a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know
what they tell me.
And what they tell me
changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed
to be able to help?
I mean, what if I
just took this thing off?
What are they
going to do about it?
They will shoot you.
Why don't you stop this silly talk?
Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
I am.
Where can we talk?
There's a company you did the
books for on Lipowa Street.
Made what?
Pots and pans?
By law, I have to
tell you, sir, I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German.
So there we are.
A good company, you think?
Modestly successful.
I know nothing about
enamelware. Do you?
I was just the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around,
whatever you do...
You could make other things,
couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits.
Army contracts.
Once the war ends, forget
it, but for now it's great.
You can make a fortune,
don't you think?
I think most people right now
have other priorities.
Like what?
(SIGHS)
I'm sure you'll do just fine
once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get,
the better you'll do.
Well, I can get the signatures I need.
That's the easy part.
Finding the money to buy
the company, that's hard.
You don't have any money?
Not that kind of money.
You know anybody?
Jews, yeah. Investors.
You must have contacts in
the Jewish business community,
working here.
What community? Jews can
no longer own businesses.
That's why this
one's in receivership.
But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it. I'd pay them back
in product, pots and pans.
Pots and pans.
Something they can use.
Something they can
feel in their hands.
They can trade it
on the black market,
do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy.
If you want, you could
run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up
all the money,
I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind
my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known
the company's in business.
I'd see that it had
a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at, not the work.
Not the work.
The presentation.
I'm sure I don't know anybody
who'll be interested in this.
(EXHALES) Well,
they should be, Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Achtung! Achtung!
An alle Juden.
Ab sofort ist es verboten...
PRIEST RECITING: Vere dignum
et justum est, aurum et salutary,
no’s tibia semper et
unique gratis agree:
Domino sancta, Pater
omnipotent, sauterne Deus...
I've got a client who'll sell
marks for zloty at 2.45-to-1.
Wool, mink collar.
It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it
for ration coupons.
Wicks, for lamps.
You have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do
with a truckload of wicks?
Nine by 12, nine by 14.
I don't know.
Big, beautiful, Persian.
Past.
What?
You don't recognize this?
It's shoe polish.
In metal containers?
You asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers. This is glass.
In metal containers.
It's not what I asked for.
What's the difference?
OTHERS: Shah!
My client sold
it to his client,
who sold it to the German army.
Only by the time it
got there, because
of the freezing cold,
it broke. All 10,000 units.
Mmm, ooh, ooh, ooh.
This is not my problem.
This is not his problem.
This is not your problem?
This is not my problem.
All right.
The German army wants to
find out where it came from.
I am going to make
sure they find out.
Now it's your problem.
You, be quiet!
(CHUCKLES)
Metal containers.
Hello.
Pardon me for interfering,
but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know where I can find
a nice shirt like that?
PRIEST: ...laudare,
benedicere et predicare.
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell
anything on the street.
We don't do that.
We're here to pray.
PRIEST: Jesum Christum
Dominum Nostrum...
Do you have any idea how much
a shirt like this costs?
Nice things cost money.
PRIEST: ...adorant Dominationes,
tremunt Potestates.
Coeli coelorumque
virtutes ac Beata Seraphim
socia exultatione
concelebrant...
How many?
I'm going to need some other
things, too, as things come up.
This won't be a problem.
From time to time.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Achtung! Achtung!
(CHILDREN CRYING)
OFFICER 1: Name? Adresse?
OFFICER 2: Formular ausfüllen!
OFFICER 1: Weiter, weiter!
OFFICER 2: Nicht drängeln!
Kommen Sie hierher!
SteHen Sie sich doch an!
(SILVERWARE CLATTERING)
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Achtung, Achtung!
Alle Juden sind verpflichtet...
im abgesonderten
jüdischen Bezirk zu wohnen.
Nichteinhaltung der Meldepflicht
bei der Einwohnerbehörde...
verstößt gegen das Edikt 44/91
und führt zur Anzeige...
beim Militärgericht.
This is obviously the right place.
How are you doing?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Goodbye, Jews!
GIRL: Goodbye, Jews!
This iz the vechteka, Moyshe.
Ojciec.
Nyne, this kan neash zyane.
(SIGHS)
(BABY CRYING)
(WOMAN SINGING LULLABY IN POLISH)
Oh, my God.
Oy, God. Oh, my God.
It could not be better.
It could be worse.
How? Tell me.
(SHOUTING) How on Earth
could it possibly be worse?
(SLAMS DOWN SUITCASE)
MAN: Dzien dobry.
Dzien dobry.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Hey, Goldberg.
Poldek.
What's this?
The Judenrat has
its own police now.
You don't say.
Ordnungsdienst.
I'm a policeman now, could you believe it?
It's hard to believe.
No, it's not hard to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek.
The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could put in a good
word for you with my superiors.
Your superiors?
Come on, they are not as bad
as everyone says.
Well, they're worse
than everyone says,
but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Give me my housing assignment.
Come on.
You look funny in
that hat, Goldberg.
(LAUGHS)
You look like a clown,
you know.
STERN: He's a very important man. Just
give him two minutes of your time.
Since when did time cost money?
Just sit down and listen.
Please. Sir?
For each 1,000 you invest,
I will repay you with...
Two hundred.
Two hundred kilos of
enamelware a month,
to begin in July and to
continue for one year.
After which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough.
It's not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look where
you've been put. "Not good enough."
A couple of months ago you'd be right.
Not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods,
that's the only currency
that'll be worth
anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed, my friend.
Did I call this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern
you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here.
I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be
a percentage in the company.
(LAUGHING) Forget the whole thing.
Get out.
How do we know
that you will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract?
To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do.
That's our contract.
(CONVERSING IN POLISH)
...mielismy racje.
Piec, szesc, siedem,
osiem, dziewiec.
(MACHINERY BUZZES)
(SCHINDLER CLAPPING)
The standard SS rate for Jewish skilled
laborers is seven marks a day,
five for unskilled and women.
This is what you pay
the Reich Economic Office.
The Jews themselves
receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages. Generally,
they get a little more.
Are you listening?
What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
The Jewish worker's salary.
You pay it
directly to the SS,
not to the worker.
He gets nothing.
But it's less.
It's less than what
I would pay a Pole.
It's less.
That's the point I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
(SNIFFS)
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory
over at Lipowa Street.
It's owned by a German.
But it's outside the ghetto, so
you can barter for extra goods,
for eggs,
I don't know what you need,
with the Polish workers.
You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for
10 healthy women for the...
I am healthy.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Bring your sister, okay?
(SHOUTING ORDERS
IN GERMAN AND POLISH)
Chodz.
You need to convince
them you have a trade,
something valuable
to the war effort.
Like what?
What if you don't?
I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list.
And they put you on trucks...
No, no, that's not true.
You're a musician?
Yeah.
I'd find a good
hiding place if I were you.
I'm not going to
hide like some animal.
There are places to hide.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Der Nächste!
I'm a graduate of
the University of Lviv.
I used to work at the
hydroelectric station in Roznów.
MAN: Blauschein.
I'm gonna get
the necessary papers
because this carol
is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line all day,
you'll still get one of these.
They are no good. You'll
have to leave the line now,
then you'll get
a blue card, a Blauschein,
to say that you are
an essential worker.
I'll get these papers
for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist. Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
GOLDBERG: Poldek!
Enjoying the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines?
Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container maybe?
(GOLDBERG LAUGHS)
Not essential? I think you
misunderstand the meaning of the word.
No Blauschein, sir. Stand over there.
Move. Next!
What do you mean,
"Not essential"?
I teach history and literature.
Since when it's not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right?
It's very good.
He's 53 years old.
It's too new.
Mmm. Thank you.
You're crazy.
You left it in your drawer.
How many times have I told you?
Your work certificate you keep
in your pocket at all times.
And you leave yours in your drawer.
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
Take the round sheet of tin,
dip it in soap emulsion,
then place it
centrally in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
The soup pot.
Soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz,
stay together.
Sir,
I have 10 work permits here
for the Deutsche
Emailwarenfabrik
cosigned by Mr. Bankier
and myself.
FOREMAN: if it's carbonized,
clean it with a file.
But don't touch both the
electrodes at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted.
Here, have a try.
Roll the metal under the press,
but be very careful
unless you want your fingers
to become part of the teapot.
Occupation?
I'm a writer.
I play the flute.
But Moses is
a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots.
He can make tanks.
He can make whatever
Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled. Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
FOREMAN: Now, dip the basin with the
tongs into the enamel solution.
And after swiveling it around,
carefully place it aside to drip dry.
And whatever he
asks you, allow me
just to represent
you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
SCHINDLER: Filing, billing, keeping
track of my appointments, shorthand.
Typing, obviously.
How is your typing?
Uh, all right.
Please.
(TYPING SLOWLY)
(BELL RINGS)
(TYPING EXTREMELY SLOW)
(TYPING SLOWLY)
(TYPING NORMALLY)
(BARELY TYPING)
(TYPING QUICKLY)
You need a secretary.
Pick one.
I don't know how.
They're all so qualified.
You have to choose.
(SIGHS)
PHOTOGRAPHER: Prosze sie ladnie usmiechac.
Big smile. Big smile.
Uwaga.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(PLAYING STATELY MUSIC
ON PIANO)
if you would,
look after my guest.
SCHINDLER: Boxed teas are good.
Coffee, pâté,
kielbasa sausage,
cheeses, Beluga caviar.
Yes.
And, of course,
who could live
without German cigarettes?
Get me as many as you can find.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities,
oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes
of Cuban cigars. The best.
Yes. And dark,
unsweetened chocolate.
Not in the shape of ladyfingers,
the chunk chocolate.
Big as my hand,
you sample at wine tastings.
Yes.
We're going to need lots of cognac.
The best, Hennessy.
Dom Pérignon champagne.
Get L'Espadon sardines,
and, oh, try to find
nylon stockings.
SCHINDLER: It is my distinct
pleasure to announce
the fully operational status
of Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik.
FOREMAN: Patrz jakies szmaty!
Manufacturers of superior
enamelware crockery,
expressly designed
and crafted for military use.
Utilizing only
the most modern equipment,
D.E.F.'s staff of
highly skilled and
experienced
artisans and journeymen
deliver a product of
unparalleled quality,
enabling me to proffer, with
absolute confidence and pride,
a full line of
field and kitchenware
unsurpassable in all respects
by my competitors.
See attached list
and available colors.
Anticipating the enclosed bids
will meet with your approval
and looking forward to a long and
mutually prosperous association,
I extend to you in advance
my sincerest gratitude
and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross
from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred,
no, make it 10 for Wednesday.
All this stuff here
goes to Madritsch's
factory on
Tuesday of next week.
(HORN HONKING)
SCHINDLER: My father was fond of saying,
"You need three things in life,
a good doctor, a forgiving
priest, and a clever accountant."
The first two,
I've never had much use for.
But the third...
Just pretend,
for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying
I couldn't have
done this without you.
The usual thing would be
to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way,
be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
(SIGHS)
Get out of here.
(DOOR BUZZES)
SCHINDLER:
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed.
Look at her.
You know something?
You would like her.
Oskar, please.
What?
I don't have to like her just because you do.
You would, though.
It doesn't work that way.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
Be careful of the step, miss.
Mrs. Schindler, Marek.
(GLOOMY SUNDAY PLAYING)
It's not a charade, all this?
How could it be a charade?
The clothes,
the car, the apartment.
Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many
people are on my payroll.
Oskar.
My father, at the height of his
success, had 50. I've got 350.
Three hundred and fifty workers
on the factory floor,
with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money. For me.
(SIGHS)
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home? Everybody.
All the time.
Hmm.
They won't soon forget the name
Schindler here, I can tell you that.
"Oskar Schindler," they'll say.
"Everybody remembers him."
"He did something
extraordinary."
no one else did."
"He came here with nothing,
a suitcase,
and built a bankrupt company
into a major manufactory."
"And left with
a steamer trunk."
"Two steamer
trunks full of money."
"All the riches
of the world."
Hmm.
It's comforting to see
that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's no way I could
have known this before,
but there was
always something missing.
In every business I tried, I can
see now, it wasn't me that failed.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was, there's
nothing I could have done about it,
because you can't
create this thing.
And it makes all the difference in the
world between success and failure.
Luck?
War.
(BALLROOM DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar, no doorman
or maitre d' will ever presume
I'm anyone other than
Mrs. Schindler, and I'll stay.
Goodbye, darling.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
I could try to read this, or I could
eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
Yes.
Better this month than last?
Any reason to think
next month will be worse?
The war could end.
What?
There is a machinist outside
who'd like to thank you
personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes. He's very grateful.
It'll just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir, for
giving me the opportunity to work.
You're welcome. I'm sure
you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up.
They would have killed me,
but I am essential to the
war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
I'm sure you do.
I'll continue to
work hard for you.
That's great. Thanks.
God bless you, sir.
All right.
You are a good man.
He saved my life.
Yes, he did.
God bless him.
Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
STERN: I'm sorry, Herr Direktor,
but you're running very late.
This is for
the Obersturmbannführer, sir.
And this is for his niece, Greta.
It's her birthday.
Greta as in Garbo.
By the way, don't
ever do that to me again.
Go, go, drive!
Don't bow.
Did you happen to notice that
that man had one arm?
Did he?
What's his use?
Very useful.
How?
Very useful! Success!
Achrar kach loe nedah...
OFFICER: Besen und Schaufeln
werden ausgeladen
jeder nimmt sich eine und dann
wird die Straße gereinigt.
We'll be late for work.
(HORN HONKING)
CZURDA: You shouldn't
think of them as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that
some of the officers here
don't give a damn
about production.
To them, it's
a matter of national priority
that Jews be
made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shoveling snow, it's
got a ritual significance.
Come with me.
I am an essential worker.
Essential worker?
(LAUGHS)
Yes.
(OFFICER LAUGHING)
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Essential worker
for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed Jew?
Twice as useless!
Yes, yes.
I lost a day
of production, Rolf.
LOWENSTEIN:
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow. Look at the snow.
Look at the snow!
(GUNSHOT)
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with the Economic Office.
It's your right.
Would it do any good?
Of course not.
(CHUCKLES)
A big shot from the SS Budget and
Construction Office came to lunch,
and he told us that to believe the
Jewish skilled worker had a place
in Reich economics
was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
(MOANING)
(PANTING AND MOANING)
Herr Direktor?
Shit. I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
SOLDIER ON PA: Leave your
luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it. Given name
first, then your surname.
Do not bring your
baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER: Lassen
Sie Ihr Gepäck am Bahnsteig.
Stern?
He's on the list.
He is?
Well, let's find him.
I'm sorry.
You can't have him.
He's on the list. If he were an essential
worker he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk.
What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct.
I didn't ask you
about the list.
I asked you your name.
Klaus Tauber.
Tauber.
Hauptscharführer, this gentleman
thinks a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is
somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it,
it'll disrupt production
and the Armaments Board
will want to know why.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER: Achtung,
dieser Zug fährt jetzt ab.
Is he on the list?
Yes, sir. Itzhak Stern.
Well, the list is correct, sir.
There is nothing I can do.
What is your name?
SOLDIER ON PA:
Close and secure all doors.
My name? My name is Kunder.
This train is now leaving.
Kunder.
Hauptscharführer Kunder.
K-U-N-D-E-R.
And what's yours?
Schindler.
S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be
in Southern Russia before the
end of the month. Good day.
CONDUCTOR: Zamykac dokladnie drzwi.
Dokladnie zamykac drzwi.
Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Stern! Itzhak Stern!
KUNDER: Stern! Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern!
Sir?
Herr Direktor.
(COUGHING)
My apologies.
Stop the train!
He's here!
I apologize.
Stop the train!
Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here.
Initial there.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Makes no difference to us, you understand.
This one, that one.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING) It's
the inconvenience to the list.
It's the paperwork.
I somehow left my
work card at home.
I tried to explain them
it was a mistake, but...
I'm sorry, it was stupid!
What if I got here
five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
Sacrean, sacrean end tzukeer.
Tzukeer end sacrean.
I woke up from
a dream this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room
with 12 people I didn't know,
only to discover I
was broke and sharing
a room with 12
people I didn't know.
(CHUCKLING) You laugh about it?
I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with. It's the
restrictions to my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out.
That's all I care about.
I like it here. There's
a kind of, I don't know,
ancestral squalor to it all.
You are a slave to these people.
No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart.
Oh, yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius.
You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found
time to organize a thought.
I can't remember
the last time I did that.
When's the last
time we did this?
When's the last time
we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me
onto a truck today.
No one took my
business away from me.
You don't really
have a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it.
This is the bottom.
The ghetto is liberty.
This street divides the ghetto
just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A, civil employees,
industrial workers, and so on.
Left side,
Ghetto B, surplus labor,
the elderly and infirm, mostly.
Which is where you
will want to start.
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down?
I'm fucking freezing.
KUNDE: We expect a labor
force of 25,000 to 30,000.
Segregated, of course. The men
in the barracks near the quarry.
The women on
the other side of the wire.
GOETH: My place is where?
There, sir.
There?
Yes, the villa.
You call that a villa?
Their synagogue,
can you see it?
That's not a villa.
We're planning to turn it
into the camp stables.
It's a house.
GOETH: What's that over there?
KUNDE: Kindergarten.
Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist,
shoemaker, practical physicians.
There they are, sir.
(SNIFFS) Hmm.
One of you is
a very lucky girl.
There is an opening
for a job away from all
this backbreaking
work at my new villa.
(SNIFFS)
Uh...
Which of you has
domestic experience?
Ja, on second thought, I don't
really want someone else's maid.
All those annoying
habits I have to undo.
(CHUCKLES) I don't want
to give you my cold.
What's your name?
Helen Hirsch.
What?
(COUGHING)
What? I can't hear.
Helen Hirsch.
Ja.
WOMAN: Take it all down!
(OFFICER BLOWS WHISTLE)
OFFICER: To work!
WOMAN: Take it down!
It is not safe!
She says the foundation was poured wrong.
She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks,
not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer.
You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant.
The entire foundation
has to be torn
down and re-poured.
If not, there will be
at least a subsidence
at the southern
end of the barracks.
Subsidence, and then collapse.
And you are an engineer?
Yes.
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate of civil engineering
from the University of Milan.
An educated Jew,
like Karl Marx himself.
Unterscharführer!
Jawohl?
Shoot her.
What?
(GASPS)
Herr Kommandant,
I'm only trying to do my job.
Ja, I'm doing mine.
But, sir, she's
foreman of construction.
We are not going to have
arguments with these people.
Okay.
No. Shoot her here,
on my authority.
It will take more than that.
GOETH: I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, re-pour it, rebuild it.
Like she said.
We have more to see, but we have
only one more hour of light.
(HUMMING)
GOETH: Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now, the young will
ask with wonder about this day.
Today is history,
and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago,
(SINGING MORNING PRAYER) when
elsewhere they were footing the blame
for the Black Death,
Kazimierz the Great...
Ke laolam chasedo
...so-called, told the Jews
they could come to Krakow.
They came.
Not that fat. No, less.
They trundled their
belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less.
They settled.
They took hold.
They prospered in business,
science, education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
(PRAYING CONTINUES)
Nothing.
And they flourished.
For six centuries there
has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening,
those six
centuries are a rumor.
They never happened.
Today is history.
Absitzen und in
Zweierreihen antreten!
Kameraden! Schneller!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
I think we will
start with Ghetto B.
SOLDIERS: Hopp, hopp,
hopp, hopp!
(DOGS BARKING)
All right?
Start from both sides?
No, no, I would like you to start there.
The right side?
The right side, yeah.
And then move around.
All right.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER: Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepäck stehen.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
SOLDIER: Aufmachen!
Lakoom.
Loe ani loe yodahat olay kaday lehachnese
at hayladeem mitachat la shoolchan.
Mitacht la meeta.
Bohow.
SOLDIERS: Hopp, hopp,
hopp, hopp!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING
IN GERMAN)
SOLDERS: Runterkommen!
(SOLDIERS BANGING ON DOORS)
SOLDIER: Rauskommen, Juden!
SOLDER: Na platz!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Gold, Chaim!
Platz Chodi.
Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him.
(SPEAKING POLISH)
Nie zabijaj! Nie zabijaj!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
SOLDIER: Ziehen Sie warme Kleidung
an und begeben Sie sich zum Platz...
Keine Koffer! Keine Koffer!
Gehen Sie durch!
Hey, little boy.
Wie alt bist du, he?
Na, wie heißt du?
Wie heißt du, eh?
Keine Koffer, hab ich gesagt!
(SCREAMING)
Packt keine Koffer!
Keine Koffer!
Rüber zum Platz Chodi!
Koffer hier lassen!
Blauschein.
Platz Chodi!
Was soll der Koffer hier?
Alles rüber zum Platz Chodi!
(SOLDIERS CONTINUE SHOUTING)
(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS
APPROACHING)
We're getting out
through the sewers.
I have to check
if they're clear.
Mila, pack some things.
Nothing bigger than this.
I can't go in the sewers. I told
you I won't go in the sewers.
You can go. Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
SOLDIER: Move! Over there!
Over there! Move!
Your card, Jew!
Define Papiere, Jude!
That line.
Deine Karte!
Ich geh nicht rauf
wegen Deiner verdammten Karte!
Deine Scheißkarte!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(WOMAN WAILING IN GERMAN)
Was soll denn die Scheiße?
Bist du denn verrückt geworden?
Mit diesem Scheißgewehr hättest
du mich erschießen können!
Du hast so nah an mir
vorbeigeschossen!
Was heißt hier Entschuldigung. Du bist woh!
Verrückt ge Worden!
SOLDER: Zurückbleiben!
Zurückbleiben!
Nicht sprechen, nicht sprechen!
Einfach zu den Lastwagen gehen!
Weiterlaufen! Weiterlaufen!
Nicht sprechen!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Komm her, du Judensau!
Bleib stehen, hab ich gesagt.
Bleib stehen!
(WOMAN WHISPERING IN POLISH)
(WOMAN SPEAKING POLISH)
Chodzcie tu szybko!
(DOOR BURSTS OPEN)
She's good as dead.
Leave her.
Give me a moment.
Just let me bring her inside.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MAN ANNOUNCING
IN GERMAN ON PA)
You can join her
or join the line.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Women to the left!
Wilhelm!
Rose!
Men to right. Women to the left.
(WOMAN PROTESTING)
Women to the left.
Let me go!
I won't leave my husband!
Women to the left,
and men to the right.
Promise me, be safe.
Your government is
in the wrong country!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(WAILING)
Mama! Mama!
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(MACHINE GUN FIRE)
Mila!
(BELL CHIMING)
(SCREAMS)
You have a Blauschein.
Blauschein
doesn't matter anymore,
they are
cleaning out the ghetto.
There is not
enough room for you.
What are you talking about?
We tried it
before. There's
more than enough room.
I changed my mind!
Mama!
Oh, look at the space in there.
Now look at me.
You are just scared.
I can fit the girl,
but not you.
Mama, I'm coming out!
Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here
than who knows where.
Mama!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(DOGS BARKING)
Herr Kommandant!
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report
I've been given orders
to clear the bundles
from the road,
so there will be no obstructions
to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the lines,
little Polish clicking soldier.
(CHUCKLES)
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes.
Oh, you are a friend
of my son's.
Don't worry, I'll go quietly.
I'll be no trouble.
No, get under the stairs.
They'll be done
searching soon.
You'll be safe there.
Please hide. Please.
...warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs.
BOY: I've searched the building.
There's no one here.
Also, gehen wir
zum nächsten Block.
Einverstanden.
Danka!
Mama!
(PANTING)
Hello, Adam.
Hello, Danka.
Come with me. I will
put you in the good line.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING
IN DISTANCE)
Do you know the saying, "An
hour of life is still life"?
You are not a boy anymore.
I'm saying a blessing for you.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(CHILDREN'S CHOIR SINGING
OYF 'N PRIPETSHOK)
Oyfn pripetshok brent a fayerl
Un in shtub iz heys
Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech
Dem alefbeys
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech
Dem alefbeys
(GUNS SHOOTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Zetzhe kinderlech
gedenktzhe tayere
Vos ir lerent do
Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol
Komets alefo
(OFFICERS SHOUTING)
Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol
Komets alefo
Ofyn pripetshok brent a fayerl
Un in shtub iz heys
Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech
Dem alefbeys
(DOG BARKING)
Oh, please, let's go.
Let's go, please.
Come on.
Zetzhe kinderlech
gedenktzhe tayere
Vos ir lerent do
Zogtzhe noch amo!
Un take noch amol
Komets alefo
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol
Komets alefo
(WHIMPERING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Markieren.
(SPEAKING POLISH)
Nie! Prosze pana, niech pan...
(HITS PIANO KEYS)
GIRL: ...nie znajdziemy!
(MACHINE GUN FIRE)
(RAPID PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(MACHINE GUN FIRE CONTINUES)
Was ist das? Ist das Bach?
Nein, nein. Mozart.
Mozart?
Ja.
Das wollen wir
heute noch schaffen?
Nee, schaffen wir nie.
I wish this
fucking night were over.
(PIANO PLAYING CONTINUES)
(PIANO PLAYING STOPS)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
OFFICER: Appell! Fünferreihen!
Antreten!
Halt, alle anstellen!
Los, los, Fünferreihen!
Mützen ab!
Namen verlesen!
Wer aufgerufen wird, hebt seine
Hand und ein deutliches Jawohl!
(OFFICER CALLS OUT NAMES)
MAN: Jawohl.
Keller, Fanni!
Jawohl.
Adalbert, Hermann!
Faber, Dorothea!
Jawohl.
Goldstein, Pola!
Warmberger, Markus!
Jawohl.
Edelstein, Max!
(SOLDIERS CONTINUE
SHOUTING NAMES)
Appell abtreten!
Do pracy!
The worst is over.
We are workers now.
(MAN SPEAKING GERMAN ON PA)
OFFICER:
Keine Müdigkeit vorschützen!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Oh, God, Amon.
(OFFICER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY)
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER: Sofort
in der Baracke zurückmelden!
(GUNSHOT)
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(RELOADING RIFLE)
(WOMAN SHRIEKING)
(OFFICER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(BONES CRACK)
OFFICER: Komm du mal
schön her! Komm du schön!
Na komm! Na komm!
Amon, you're such
a damned fucking child!
Wakey, wakey.
(SIGHS)
WOMAN: Make coffee.
Make it yourself.
MAN: The SS will manage
certain industries itself
inside Plaszow.
A metalworks, brush factory,
another for reprocessing
Jewish clothing
from the ghettos for use by
bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry like
yours that stands to benefit most
by moving inside the wire of
Commandant Amon Goeth's camp...
No, no, no. Sit,
sit. Julian, how are you?
Good to see you, my friend.
Oskar Schindler.
Leo John.
(WHISPERS)
(CHUCKLES)
Franz, good to see you.
Hello, Oskar.
Glad you could join us.
My pleasure. Julius.
How are you?
You lost weight.
Only in the shoulders.
Please, everybody, sit down.
How are you doing?
Oskar Schindler.
We started without you.
Fine. I miss anything good?
I was explaining to Herr Bosch
and Herr Madritsch
some of the benefits of moving
their factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
(CHUCKLES)
Since your labor
is housed on-site,
it's available to
you at all times.
You can work them
all night if you want.
Your factory policies,
whatever they've
been in the past,
they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know,
where do you get a suit
like that?
What is that? Is that silk?
Of course.
Ja.
It has a nice sheen about it.
Thank you.
Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one, but the
man who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
SCHINDLER:
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this. I have to find out.
I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No. (SIGHS)
No.
They're not gone.
They're here.
They're mine! Every day that
goes by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is
shot costs me money.
I have to find somebody else.
I have to train them.
We are going to be
making so much money
that none of this
is going to matter.
It's bad business.
(SNIFFS)
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena, thank you.
Scherner told me
something else about you.
Yeah? What's that?
That you know the meaning
of the word "gratitude."
That it's not some
vague thing with you
like it is with others.
You want to stay where you are.
You've got things
going on the side.
Things are good.
You don't want anybody
telling you what to do.
I can understand all that, you know.
I know you.
What you want is
your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved?
The paperwork alone,
and then you've got to
build the fucking thing.
Getting the fucking permits is
enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up,
they stand around, they argue
about drainage, foundations,
codes, exact specifications,
parallel fences
four kilometers long,
1,200 kilograms of
barbed wire, (CHUCKLING)
6,000 kilograms of electrified
fences, ceramic insulators,
three cubic meters of
air space per prisoner.
I'm telling you, you want to shoot somebody.
I've been through it,
you know? I know.
Well, you know. You've
been through it. (SPITS)
You could make
things easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
SOLDER: Aus dem Weg da!
(DOGS BARKING)
SOLDIER: Weitergehen!
Weitergehen!
(SOLDIER SPEAKING IN POLISH)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz,
make sure I see my cut
from the factory
owners in this camp.
Leaving you to take
care of my main account,
the Schindler account.
He wants his independence.
I gave it to him.
But independence costs money.
This, you understand?
Look at me.
Don't forget who you
are working for now.
(WOMAN SHRIEKING)
(ACCORDION MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: Jawohl!
SCHINDLER: Make sure he stays.
He's a slippery bastard!
We need more wine.
More wine!
Stand on my friend.
Don't let him leave.
(GUESTS CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING)
(GUESTS SINGING IN GERMAN)
(TOASTING IN GERMAN)
Was passiert
denn in einem Leben
Prost! Prost!
Thank you, Herr Direktor.
Prost, Herr Direktor!
What are you doing?
What? Scratching my head.
Makes them think we have lice. Helps
make them keep their distance.
Do you have lice?
Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my
desk has the birthdays
of our SS friends'
wives and children.
Don't forget to send something.
Record payoffs to
the Main Administration
and Economics Office,
the Arm...
Slowly, Stern, slowly.
The Armaments Board, Governor
General's Division of the Interior
and Chief of Police as "fees."
And make them on
the first of each month,
as opposed to individual
payoffs to our SS contacts.
The list is in the lower drawer
of my desk, which you...
"First of month..."
SS contacts list, lower drawer
of my desk, which you handle
as cash contributions
to legitimate charities
sent, of course,
to each official's office.
Dealings with our
black market contacts
listed as suppliers in
the legitimate ledger
are more complicated.
Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it?
You can't forget it.
It gives me a headache.
It gives me a headache!
(DOGS BARKING)
(SIGHS)
I couldn't get you out of here.
I'll be all right.
Anyway, I'm here almost every week.
Wednesdays, usually.
I'll look in on you,
see how you're doing.
Here, put these in your pocket.
Come on.
Herr Direktor,
don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for... Good luck.
Achtung, Mützen ab!
Work!
An die Arbeit!
What are you making?
Hinges, sir.
I've got some
workers coming in tomorrow.
Where the hell they from again?
Yugoslavia, Herr Kommandant.
I've got to make room.
Make me a hinge.
Yes, sir.
(GUARDS MUTTERING)
Keep going, you're doing well.
Oh, that's very good.
But I'm a bit confused,
and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand
is that you've been working
since I think, what,
about 6:00 this morning?
Yet, such a small pile
of hinges.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(GUN CLICKS)
(GUN CLICKS) Oh, Christ.
May I try that, sir?
Check the angle lever.
Maybe it's bent.
No, no. You wouldn't hear a click
if it was the angle lever.
Maybe it's the pin.
Maybe the pin shaft is greasy.
Ja, come on.
What did I just say? Here.
(GUN CLICKS)
Herr Kommandant.
I beg to report that my heap of
hinges was so unsatisfactory
because the machines were being
recalibrated this morning.
(GUN CLICKS)
I was put on to shoveling coal.
(GUN CLICKING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(SOBBING)
Strange, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you, Muek.
Ah, Lisiek. Don't touch the
leather, it's just been oiled.
Rottenführer.
Oh, for me?
Oh, thank you very much,
Herr Direktor.
STERN: Herr Direktor!
Herr Direktor!
Herr Direktor.
He was making hinges slowly.
So the man can
turn out a hinge in
less than a minute.
Why the long story?
Hmm?
(MACHINES WHIRRING)
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Nobody knows who
stole the chicken, hmm?
Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around with a chicken
and nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him about the chicken.
Still nobody knows.
(SOBBING)
It was you.
You committed this crime.
No, sir.
But you know who, though.
Yes.
Who?
Him!
He's very gifted.
Yeah, sure.
Bring him over.
Sir. Thank you.
Thank you again, Herr Direktor.
You're welcome again.
It's an honor to work
for such a great company.
It's great to have you.
I promise to learn everything there is
to know about enamelware production.
That's great.
Hello? Miss Elsa Krause is here.
I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak
to the Herr Direktor.
Yes.
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
Pernod? Cognac?
No. No, thank you.
So, what can I do for you?
They say that no one dies here.
They say your
factory is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina Perlman,
not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow on false
papers since the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are
Chana and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people. They are
killing older people now in Plaszow.
They bury them up
in the forest. Look,
I don't have any money.
I borrowed these clothes.
I'm begging you. Please.
Please bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled.
I ask one thing.
Whether or not the worker
has certain skills.
That's what I ask
and that's what I care about.
My father is an importer,
not a metalworker.
Such activities are illegal. You will
not entrap me! (CONTINUES ARGUING)
Cry, and I will have you arrested.
I swear to God!
(SOBBING)
People die.
It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody?
Great!
What am I
supposed to do about it?
Bring everybody over?
Is that what you think?
Send them over to Schindler.
Send them all!
His place is a haven, didn't you know?
It's not a factory.
It's not an enterprise
of any kind.
It's a haven for
rabbis and orphans
and people with no
skills whatsoever!
(SIGHS)
You think I don't
know what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time.
I know, I know!
Are you losing money?
That's not the point!
So the point is?
It's dangerous!
It's dangerous to me!
You have to understand. Goeth
is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of
it in his situation.
He's got this
whole place to run.
He's responsible for everything
here, all these people.
He's got a lot of
things to worry about.
And he's got the war which
brings out the worst in people.
Never the good, always the bad.
Always the bad.
But in normal circumstances he wouldn't
be like this. He'd be all right.
There'd just be the good
aspects of him, which...
(CHUCKLES)
He's a wonderful crook.
A man who loves good food, good
wine, the ladies, making money...
Killing.
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski told me the other day,
somebody escaped
from a work detail
outside the wire.
Goeth lined up everybody from
the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of
Bejski, the man to the right of him.
He walked down the line shooting
every other man with a pistol.
Twenty-five.
What do you want
me to do about it?
Nothing, nothing.
We're just talking.
"Perlman."
Perlman!
Husband and wife.
Jakob and Chana Perlman!
Have Goldberg bring them over.
SOLDIER: Mützen ab!
Appell abtreten!
(GUESTS SINGING DRUNKENLY
IN GERMAN)
I'm sure this will be better
than those rags, Lisiek.
Herr Direktor, I was just helping
Lisiek to find something
to clean the stains from the
Herr Kommandant's bathtub.
Go clean it.
Pardon me, Herr Direktor.
(SCHINDLER CHUCKLES)
You don't have to
report to me, Helen.
You know who I am? Hmm?
(WHISPERING) I'm Schindler.
Of course.
I have heard, and
you have been here before.
Here, why don't you
keep this someplace?
Go on, take it.
I get extra food here.
Well, if you don't want to eat it, trade it.
Or give it to Lisiek.
Why not build yourself up?
My first day here, he beat me
because I threw out
the bones from dinner.
He came down to the basement
at midnight, and he...
He asked me where they were.
For his dogs, you understand.
I said to him,
I don't know how I say this.
I never could say it now,
I said to him,
"Why are you beating me?"
He said, "The reason
I beat you now
is because you
ask why I beat you."
I know your sufferings, Helen.
It doesn't matter.
I have accepted them.
Accepted them?
One day he will shoot me.
No, no, no, he won't shoot you.
I know. I see things.
We were on the roof on Monday,
young Lisiek and I,
and we saw the Herr Kommandant
come out of the from door
and down the steps by the
patio, right there below us,
and there on the steps
he drew his gun and he
shot a woman who
was passing by.
A woman carrying a bundle.
Through the throat.
Just a woman on her way
somewhere, you know?
She was no fatter or thinner
or slower or faster
than anyone else,
and I couldn't
guess what had she done.
The more you see of
the Herr Kommandant,
the more you see there is no set
rules that you can live by.
You can't say to yourself, "If I
follow these rules, I will be safe."
He won't shoot you because
he enjoys you too much.
He enjoys you so much he won't
even let you wear the star.
He doesn't want
anyone else to know
it's a Jew he's enjoying.
He shot the woman
from the steps
because she meant
nothing to him.
She was one of a series,
neither offending
or pleasing him.
But you, Helen.
It's all right. It's not
that kind of a kiss.
(SOBBING)
Thank you.
Shh.
Here.
Right. The wine.
Wonderful party, Amon.
Thank you.
(GROANS)
Why do you drink
that motor oil?
Hmm? I send you good
stuff all the time.
Your liver's going to explode
like a hand grenade.
You know, I look at you.
(SNIFFS)
I watch you.
(SIGHS)
You're never drunk.
(SNIFFS) Oh, that's...
That's real control.
Control is power.
That's power.
SCHINDLER:
Is that why they fear us?
We have the fucking power to
kill, that's why they fear us.
They fear us because we have
the power to kill arbitrarily.
A man commits a crime,
he should know better.
We have him killed, and we
feel pretty good about it.
Or we kill him ourselves
and we feel even better.
That's not power, though.
That's justice.
It's different than power.
Power is when we have
everyjustification to kill,
and we don't.
You think that's power?
That's what the emperors had.
A man stole something,
he's brought in
before the emperor,
he throws himself down on the
ground, he begs for mercy.
He knows he's going to die.
And the emperor pardons him.
This worthless man.
He lets him go.
I think you are drunk.
That's power, Amon.
That is power.
Amon the Good.
I pardon you. (LAUGHS)
GOETH: What do they want?
STERN: I don't know, but they're in
my office now reviewing our books.
As my accountant, tell me, should
I be alarmed that the auditors
are reviewing my books?
Well...
Or have you done
your job properly?
You needn't be alarmed.
I needn't be alarmed.
(SHOUTS ANGRILY)
(GASPS) I'm sorry, sir.
Do you know how much
this saddle is worth?
Do you know how much it costs?
All right.
(PANTING)
Stern, what the hell are you
doing following me around?
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Baracken eins, elf
fünfzehn und zwounddreißig
am Appellplatz melden.
(WHISTLING)
(BOTH WHISTLING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(WHIMPERING)
She was smoking on the job.
Tell her not to do it again.
(SHOUTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
I have to report, sir.
I've been unable to remove
the stains from your bathtub.
What are you using, Lisiek?
Soap, Commandant.
Soap? Not lye?
Go ahead, go on, leave.
Leave, I pardon you.
I pardon you.
(GUNSHOT)
(SIGHS)
WOMAN: Although I am not a
rabbi, in these circumstances
I pray to the Almighty
that he will forgive me
if I intone the blessings.
Baruch atah hashem
ehloheinu melech haolam
Asher tzivanu al haraayot
V'asar aleinu et haarusot
V'hitir lanu et han'suot
Al y'dei chupah v'kidushin
WOMAN SINGER IN CLUB:
Milosc tak pieknie tlumaczy
Zdrade i klamstwo i grzech
Choc bys ja przeklal w rozpaczy
Ze jest okrutna i zla
Milosc ci wszystko wybaczy
Bo milosc moj mily to ja
So...
This is where you
come to hide from me.
I came to tell you
that you really
are a wonderful cook
and a well-trained servant.
I mean it, if you need
a reference after the war,
I'd be happy to give you one.
It must get lonely down here
when you're listening to everyone
upstairs having such a good time.
Does it?
You can answer.
But what's the right answer?
That's what you're thinking.
What does he want to hear?
The truth, Helen,
is always the right answer.
Yes, you're right.
Sometimes we're both lonely.
Yes. I...
(SIGHS)
I mean,
I would like so much to
reach out and touch
you in your loneliness.
What would that be like,
I wonder? I mean...
What would be wrong with that?
I realize that
you're not a person in
the strictest sense
of the word, but...
(SIGHS)
No, maybe you're right
about that too, you know,
maybe what's wrong isn't...
It's not us.
It's... No, it's this.
I mean,
when they compare you to
vermin, and to rodents,
and to lice...
I just...
No, you make a good point.
You make a very good point.
Is this the face of a rat?
Are these the eyes of a rat?
Hath not a Jew eyes?
Ci wszystko wybaczy
Bo milosc moj mily
I feel for you, Helen.
To ja
(PANTING)
No, I don't think so.
You're a Jewish bitch.
You nearly talked me
into it, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Bravo.
(GRUNTS)
(MURMURING HAPPILY)
(YELLS)
(VIOLIN MUSIC PLAYING)
GUESTS: Hoch!
Hoch! Hoch!
Bravo!
MAN: Bravo!
GUESTS: Hoch!
Hoch! Hoch!
(LAUGHING)
(MUSIC AND TALKING STOPS)
On behalf of the workers, sir,
I wish for you
a happy birthday.
Happy birthday
Well, the staff, please.
Thank you very much for the lovely cake.
(OFFICER CLEARS THROAT)
Thank you very much.
Tell them thank you from me.
To ostatnia niedziela
Dzisiaj sie rozstaniemy
The trains arrived and the people
were driven out with clubs.
They were lined up in front
of two big warehouses.
One was marked "Cloak Room,"
and the other "Valuables."
And there they
were made to undress.
A Jewish boy handed them pieces of
string to tie their shoes together.
They shaved their hair.
They told them it was needed to
make something
special for U-boat crews.
And then they were herded
down a big corridor
to bunkers with Stars
of David on the doors
and signs that said
"Bath and Inhalation Room."
SS gave them soap.
They told them to
breathe all the time
because it's good
for disinfecting.
And then they gassed them.
Mila, why soaps?
So that they would
agree to go in, I think.
Come on, Mila, stop it. Your bedtime
stories are scaring everyone.
Yeah. You know
it's ridiculous.
I cannot believe it.
I didn't say I believed it.
I said I heard it.
From who?
From somebody who heard it
from someone who was there.
You know, if they were there,
they would have been gassed.
Yes.
It doesn't make any sense.
We're their workforce.
What sense does it make
to kill your own workforce?
To go to all this trouble of
assembling a workforce only to...
No, it can't be true.
We are very,
very important for them.
WOMAN 1: Yeah, we do now.
Good night.
WOMAN 2: Good night.
WOMAN 3: Good night.
Sweet dreams.
MAN ON PA:
Attention, attention.
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
Attention, attention.
We have to go to
the Appellplatz.
Everyone who is alive...
MRS. DRESNER:
The list makers are here.
...is to come to
the Appellplatz.
There is going
to be a selection.
Attention, attention.
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(WHISTLE CONTINUES)
Meine Herren.
Raz!
Dra!
...die Hunderttausend
Ungarn kommen...
(SPEAKING GERMAN
INDISTINCTLY)
OFFICER: Alle in einer
Einzelreihe aufstel/en!
You could afford to
lose some weight, Amon.
And you've got to
cut down on the cognac.
Morning.
What's going on?
It's another
semi-annual physical.
There.
Oh, I've got another
shipment coming in of...
What are they this time?
Hungarians.
Ja, Hungarians.
We've got to separate the sick
from the healthy to make room.
SOLDEIR: Teraz! Teraz!
(GUTE NACHT MUTTER PLAYING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Gute Nacht Mutter
Gute Nacht
Das darf nicht
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
bis zum Abend dauern!
(SOLDIER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SONG CONTINUING)
WOMAN: Let me help you.
SOLDER: Zack, zack, zack!
WOMAN 1:
We've got to go out there.
WOMAN 2: Don't go.
Look alive, Rebeka.
Gute Nacht Mutter
SOLDER: Naokolo!
Predzej! Predzej!
SOLDER: Naokolo! Naokolo!
Gute Nacht...
That's my mechanic.
Whose bright idea was
it to get rid of him?
Ruszaj sie! Naokolo!
Szybciej! Szybciej!
Trzymaj ubrania!
Gute Nacht
Otworz usta.
Zajrzymy do gardla.
Wez gleboki oddech.
Jeszcze. Jeszcze.
Unies ramiona.
Obroc sie. Przykucnij.
(SOLDIER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY)
SOLDIER: Formowac kolmune!
Du hast verziehen mir
Du hast gewacht
No, no, no.
Wait, go away. She can work.
Come here. Look, separate
the sick from the healthy.
Those who can work and those who can't.
She can work.
You can work, you can come.
SOLDIER: Ruszac sie! Szybciej!
(MAMATSCHI PLAYING)
Es war einmal
ein kleines Bübchen
(CHILDREN SINGING ALONG)
Das bettelte so wundersüß
Mamatschi schenke mir
ein Pferdchen
Ein Pferdchen
wäre mein Paradies
Daraufbekam der kleine Mann
Ein Schimmeipaar aus Marzipan
SOLDIERS: Stehen bleiben!
Stehen bleiben!
Die sieht er an er
weint und spricht
Solche Pferde wollte ich nicht
(CHILDREN CONTINUE SINGING)
Mamatschi schenke mir
ein Pferdchen
Ein Pferdchen wäre
mein Paradies
Mamatschi solche Pferde
wollte ich nicht
Es war einmal
ein kleines Bübchen
Das bettelte so wundersüß
Da kam das Christkind
reingeflogen
Und schenkte ihm
was er begehrte
Those not selected for transport,
put your clothes back on.
HUJAR: Go back
to the barracks.
Return to the barracks.
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
MAN: Go back to the barracks.
(TRUCK ENGINE REVVING)
Oh, my God!
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
Ein Pferdchen wäre
mein Paradies
Mamatschi solche Pferde
wollte ich nicht
(WOMEN SHRIEKING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Olek? Olek?
MRS. DRESNER: Danka?
Olek! Olek!
(SCREAMING)
Olek?
Danka?
OFFICER: Ab in die Baracke!
In die Baracke mit euch!
I didn't see him!
They're hiding. I'm telling
you, they're hiding.
I know Danka. She knows a good place.
She took all of them together.
(WHISPERING) SOLDIER:
Zurück in die Baracken!
...mein Paradies
Mamatschi solche
Pferde wollte ich nicht
Find your own hiding place. There's
no room for you here. Go away, quick!
Get out.
This is our place. Get out!
(MEN SHOUTING)
Oskar!
Amon. Gentlemen.
Why didn't you call me?
I tried to call you.
Here, Hujar, move.
Quite a picnic, huh?
Madritsch. Oskar.
They're running
a little late, you know?
It's taking
longer than I thought.
A drink?
Something cold. Bowle.
The Bowle.
Oh, another beautiful day.
(WOMAN SHOUTING IN POLISH)
Cisza! Spokoj!
(PEOPLE MOANING)
Die Beladung der
Transportwagen ist beendet.
Wir sind abfahrbereit.
Wody! Wody!
Wasser... Wasser.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Wohlsein.
Oh, thank you.
What do you say we
get your fire hoses out
here and hose down the cars?
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES) Indulge me.
GOETH: Hujar.
Yes, sir.
Go bring the fire hoses.
Where's the fire?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
SCHINDLER: In the windows.
That's it, that's it.
On the roof. That's it, good, good.
In the window, in the window.
Come on. Come on.
That's it, more, more.
That's it, that's it.
More, more.
This is really cruel, Oskar.
You are giving them hope.
You shouldn't do that.
That's cruel!
Come on, try and reach
the far end. Look out.
MAN: (WAILING)
Water! More water!
I've got some 200-meter hoses
back in Emalia.
I have 20 meters at
home in my garden.
We can reach the cars at the end.
(OFFICERS LAUGHING)
What? What?
Hujar.
Yeah, sure.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(LAUGHING)
Don't forget the roof.
On the roof on the other side.
Scharführer,
every time the train stops
you open the doors, you give
them water, yeah? Jawohl.
This car! This car!
(WOMAN SHRIEKING)
SCHINDLER: I'm not saying you'll
regret it, but you might.
You should be aware of that.
We will have to risk regret.
All right, sure. It's a nice day.
I'll go for a drive with you.
What about you?
I violated the Race
and Resettlement Act.
Though I doubt anyone can point
out the actual provision to me.
I kissed a Jewish girl.
(CHUCKLING)
Did your prick fall off?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
GOETH: He likes women.
He likes good-looking women.
He sees a beautiful woman,
he doesn't think.
(CHUCKLES)
I mean...
He has so many women.
And they love him.
Ja, they love him. I mean, he
is married, Ja, but he's...
All right, no. She was Jewish.
He shouldn't have done it.
But you didn't see this girl.
I saw this girl.
This girl was, woof...
She was very good-looking.
They cast a spell on you,
you know, the Jews.
When you work closely with
them, like I do, you see this.
They have this power.
It's like a virus.
Some of my men are
infected with this virus.
They should be pitied, not punished.
They should receive treatment.
This is as real as typhus.
I see this all the time.
It's a matter of money? Hmm?
You're offering me a bribe?
A bribe? No.
No, please. It's a gratuity.
Heil Hitler!
Hello, Amon.
Sit down.
We give you Jewish girls
at five marks a day, Oskar.
You should kiss us, not them.
God forbid you ever get
a real taste for Jewish skirt.
There's no future in it.
They don't have a future.
That's not just good,
old-fashioned, Jew-hating talk.
It's policy now.
MAN: Ja, schön gefangen! Gut!
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Nochmal, ja! Schön!
SOLDER: Also los! Bewegung!
Schneller hier!
Zack, zack, zack!
Beweg deinen Arsch!
Das geht auch schneHer!
Bewegt euch!
Schlaft nicht ein!
(CHOIR SINGING REQUIEM)
Nur die ganzen Fetzen,
nicht das Gemüse!
Komm, das kannst du mit den
Händen machen, fass da vorn an!
Die Kleinteile lass liegen!
(SCREAMING INSANELY)
(LAUGHING)
(CONVERSING IN GERMAN)
So ist es! Walhalla!
Walhalla läuft hier!
(REQUIEM CONTINUES)
GOETH: Can you believe this?
As if I don't have enough to
do, they come up with this?
I have to find every rag
buried up here and burn it.
The party's over, Oskar.
They're closing
us down, sending
everybody to Auschwitz.
When?
I don't know. As soon as
I can arrange the shipments.
Maybe 30, 40 days.
That ought to be fun.
SCHINDLER:
I've been talking to Goeth.
I know the destination.
These are
the evacuation orders.
I'm to help organize the shipments,
put myself on the last train.
That's not what I
was going to say.
I made Goeth promise me he'll
put in a good word for you.
Nothing bad is going
to happen to you there.
You'll receive
special treatment.
The directives
coming in from Berlin
mention "special treatment"
more and more often.
I'd like to think
that's not what you mean.
Preferential treatment,
all right?
Do we have to invent
a whole new language?
I think so.
You're staying, I take it.
In Krakow? What on Earth for?
What for? You have
a business to run.
Of course, you'll have to hire new workers.
Poles, I guess.
They cost a little more, but...
What are you going to do?
You ran my business.
No, I'm going home.
I've done what I came here for.
I've got more money than any
man can spend in a lifetime.
Some day, this is all
going to end, you know.
I was going to say
we'll have a drink then.
I think I better have it now.
(GOD BLESS THE CHILD PLAYING)
Bible says And it still is news
Mama may have Papa may have
But God bless the child
That's got his own
Yes, the strong gets more
While the weak ones fade
Empty pockets don't
ever make the grade
Mama may have Papa may have
But God bless the child
That's got his own
Money,
you've got lots of friends
They're pounding on your...
GOETH: I don't understand.
You want these people?
"These people"?
My people, I want my people.
Who are you, Moses?
Come on, what is this?
Where's the money in this?
Where's the scam?
It's good business.
It's good business
in your opinion.
Look, you've got to move
them, the equipment,
everything to Czechoslovakia.
Pay for all that and build another camp.
Doesn't make any sense.
Look, Amon...
It's good for me.
You're not
telling me something.
I know them. I'm familiar with them.
I don't have to train them.
You're not
telling me something.
It's good for you.
I'll compensate you.
That's right.
It's good for the army.
Yeah, of course.
You know what I'm going to make?
What?
Artillery shells. Everyone's
making artillery shells.
Tank shells, they need that.
Tanks shells, ja.
Everybody's happy.
Everyone's happy, except me.
You're probably
scamming me somehow.
If I'm making 100,
you've got to be making 300.
And if you admit to 300, then
it's 400, actually. But how?
I just told you.
You did, but you didn't.
Ja, all right, don't tell me.
I'll go along with it. It's just
irritating I can't work it out.
Look, all you have to do is
tell me what it's worth to you.
What's a person worth to you?
No, no, no, no.
What's one worth to you?
Poldek Pfefferberg.
Mila Pfefferberg.
And...
Uh... Stagel, Stagel...
Paul.
Paul Stagel.
STERN: Doctor.
The investors. I want all of them.
Yes, sir.
Fischer. Ismail Fischer.
Fischer, Ismail.
Josef Scharf.
One moment, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Come on, Stern.
Scharf, Scharf.
The children.
All the children.
STERN: Herbert Stier.
SCHINDLER: Thank you.
How many?
Four hundred, 450.
More, more.
Feigenbaum, Jakob.
Wolf. Wolf Wein.
Feigenbaum, Lutek, Jakob...
Nacha. Yes? Nacha.
Nacha, that's right.
SCHINDLER: And Wolf.
How many?
600.
More.
SCHINDLER: You can do
the same thing I'm doing.
You might even
make money at it.
MADRITSCH: I don't know.
Come on, Julius, I know about the
extra food and clothes you give them.
Paid for out of
your own pocket.
If we make a combined
approach, we could
get more than 4,000 out,
mine and yours.
Oskar...
We could relocate them in something
like safety, in Moravia.
I don't know.
How many cigarettes
have you smoked tonight?
Too many.
For every one... (COUGHS)
you smoke, I smoke half.
I've done all I can.
I will not accept that.
No, Oskar, I can't do any more.
No.
How many? How many?
850, give or take.
Give or take what, Stern?
Count them. How many?
That's it.
You can finish that page.
What did Goeth say about this?
You just told him how many
people you needed and...
You're not buying them.
You're buying them? You're paying
him for each of these names?
If you were
still working for me,
I'd expect you to
talk me out of it.
It's costing me a fortune.
Finish the page and leave
one space at the bottom.
You...
The list is an absolute good.
The list is life.
All around its
margins lies the gulf.
Oskar,
there's a clerical error here
at the bottom of the last page.
No, there's one more name
I want to put there.
I'll never find a maid as well
trained as her at Brinnlitz.
They are all country girls.
No.
One hand of 21.
If you win, I pay you
7,400 reichsmarks. No.
Hit a natural, I make it 14,800.
No.
If I win,
the girl goes on my list.
I can't wager Helen
in a carol game.
Why not?
Wouldn't be right.
She's just going to Auschwitz
Number Two, anyway.
What difference does it make?
She's not going to Auschwitz.
I'd never do that to her.
No, I want her
to come back to Vienna with me.
I want her to come
to work for me there.
I want to grow old with her.
Are you mad?
Amon, you can't take
her to Vienna with you.
No, of course I can't.
That's what I'd like to do.
What I can do,
if I'm any sort of a man,
is the next most
merciful thing.
I shall take her
into the woods and
shoot her painlessly
in the back of the head.
What was it you
said for a natural 21?
Was it 14,800?
Schindlerjuden to these tables!
Say your names clearly.
We are the family Dresner.
Juda, Jonas, Donata, and Chaja.
We are Rosners.
Henry, Manci...
And Leo.
And our son.
I am Olek.
Maria Mischel.
Chaim Nowak.
Wulkan, Markus.
Michael Lemper.
Itzhak Stern.
Rebeka and Joseph Bau.
Rosalia Nussbaum.
Wilhelm Nussbaum.
Jakob Levartov.
Farber, Rosa.
Farber, Andrzej.
Sara.
Friehof, Fischel.
Mietek Pemper.
Poldek and Mila Pfefferberg.
Horowitz, Dolek.
Adam Levy.
Marcel Goldberg.
Klipstein, Isak David.
Altmann, Eduard.
Grunberg, Miriam.
Luftig, Eliasz.
Hilmann, Eduard.
Erna Rothberg.
Zuckermann, Jetti.
Helen Hirsch.
(PENCIL SCRAPING PAPER)
The worst is over.
Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
Be careful. Men to this transport
Watch your step. Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(PEOPLE COUGHING)
Wonderful, Olek, wonderful.
You know how we
make ice into water?
(BLOWING)
Olek, get another one!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(PEOPLE COUGHING)
MAN: Alle in einer
Einzelreihe aufstellen!
You'll be
pleased with the level
of efficiency I get
from these workers.
Budzyn, under my command,
was the envy of every other
commandant in the labor camp system.
The prisoners, however...
Excuse me.
They would have rather
been somewhere else.
SCHINDLER: The train with the
women has already left Plaszow
and will be
arriving here very shortly.
I know you've
had a long journey.
But it's only a short walk
further to the factory,
where hot soup and
bread is waiting for you.
Welcome to Brinnlitz!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
MRS. DRESNER:
Beans in cholent?
MILA: Beans are the best part.
DANKA: I don't like beans.
Beans and meat and
potatoes and bread.
That's not the way
you make cholent.
Eggs in cholent?
Yes!
DANKA:
I don't like cholent.
MRS. DRESNER:
No, you don't.
What do you like?
I like caviar.
REBEKA: One day on the fire...
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(DOGS BARKING AND SNARLING)
Alle vorm Wagen
in Position bleiben.
Alle in der Gruppe
zusammenbleiben.
Wegbleiben vom Wagen!
Wegbleiben vom Wagen,
hab ich gesagt!
Schneller!
Dalli, dalli, dalli!
Was ist da hinten los!
(DOG BARKING)
SOLDIER: Schnell!
SOLDER: Los, raus mit euch.
Zack, zack, zack! Raus!
Dreißig, fünfunddreißig,
vierzig, fünfundvierzig.
SOLDER: Aussteigen!
Where are the list makers?
Where are the tables?
Raus mit euch!
Hopp, hopp!
...bagaze w wagonach!
Dalli! Rausgehen!
Schneller!
Zostawcie bagaze w wagonach!
Los, ein bisschen schneller!
Mama, where are we?
They're in Auschwitz.
The train was never routed here.
A paperwork mistake.
POLISH WOMAN:
Szybciej! Szybko!
GERMAN WOMAN:
Die Schuhe werfen!
Schneller! Schneller!
Ubrania skladac!
Pod prysznic!
Zieht euch aus! Bewegung!
Bewegt euch! Stellt euch
auf und zieht euch aus!
Rozbierac sie tam szybciej!
Schneller!
WOMAN:
Szybko sie rozbierac.
Dostaniecie mydlo i recznik i
pojdziecie pod prysznic do dezynfeckji!
Szybko sie rozbierac!
Schneller!
Zabierajcie to mydlo i szybko!
Zieht euch schneller aus!
Bewegung!
Szybko! Szybko!
Sofort hinein! Schneller!
Pojdziecie pod prysznic!
Szybko!
Schneller!
Hinein zum Bad!
Schneller! Schneller!
Szybko! Szybko!
Tu wchodzic!
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
(WOMEN WAILING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
(LAUGHING)
Blick hinunter!
Die Hand auf die Schulter!
MAN: How old are you, mother?
WOMAN: Sixty-eight.
Cough for me, mother.
They say to fall against
the fence is a kindness.
Don't kill yourself
against the fence, Clara.
If you do, you'll never know
what happened to you.
How old are you, mother?
Sixty-six, sir.
Sir?
Good morning.
A mistake has been made. We
are not supposed to be here.
We work for Oskar Schindler.
We are Schindler Jews.
Who is Oskar Schindler?
He had a factory in Krakow.
Enamelware.
A pot maker.
How old are you, mother?
You are not the only
industrialist who needs labor,
Herr Schindler.
I remember earlier this year,
IG Farben ordered
a trainload of Hungarians
for its chemical factory.
The train came in
through the archway
and the officer in charge of the
selection went immediately to work
and sent 2,000 of them
straight away to
Special Treatment.
It is not my task
to interfere with
the processes that
take place down here.
Why do you think I can help you
if I can't help IG Farben?
Allow me to express the reason.
I'm not making any
judgment about you.
It's just that I know
that in the coming months,
we're all going to
need portable wealth.
I could have you arrested.
I'm protected by powerful friends.
You should know that.
I do not say I
am accepting them.
All I say is, I'm not comfortable
with them on the table.
I have a shipment
coming in tomorrow.
I'll cut you 300 units from it.
New ones.
These are fresh.
The train comes,
we turn it around.
Mmm, yes, yes.
It's yours.
I understand.
I want these.
You shouldn't
get stuck on names.
That's right. It creates
a lot of paperwork.
Zoldinger, Ernestina!
Waldergrun, Hilda!
Waldergrun, Leonora!
Laast, Anna!
Pfefferberg, Mila!
Dresner, Chaja!
Dresner, Dan ka!
Nussbaum, Sidonia!
Rosner, Manci!
Hirsch, Helen! Grosz, Chaja Sara!
Seelenfreund, Estella!
(DOGS BARKING)
(WOMEN SHOUTING)
WOMAN SOLDIER: Schneller laufen!
Schneller laufen! Schneller!
Schneller! Schneller!
Mach schon! Voran!
Los, los, los! Schneller!
SOLDIERS: Schneller!
Bewegt euch!
Bojcie sie! Bojcie sie!
(SCREAMING)
No! No! No!
WOMAN SOLDIER: Mädchen, los jetzt aber!
Jetzt aber Tempo!
(SCREAMING)
(SHRIEKING)
Danka! Danka! Danka!
No! No! No!
(SCREAMING)
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
These are mine! These are my workers!
They should be on my train!
They're skilled munitions workers!
They're essential!
Essential girls!
(SHRIEKS)
Their fingers polish the insides
of shell metal casings.
How else am I to
polish the inside
of a 45 millimeter
shell casing?
You tell me.
You tell me!
Back on the train!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Under Department "W" provisions
it is unlawful to kill a
worker without just cause.
Under the Businesses
Compensation Fund
lam entitled to file
damage claims for such deaths.
If you shoot without thinking,
you go to prison, I get paid.
That's how it works.
So, there will be
no summary executions here.
There will be no interference
of any kind with production.
In hopes of ensuring
that, guards will
no longer be allowed
on the factory floor
without my authorization.
For your cooperation,
you have my gratitude.
Come on, come.
SOLDIER: Mensch, seit Jahren hab
ich so etwas nicht mehr gesehen.
SCHINDLER: Come on, boys, come.
Guck dir mal die Buddeln an!
PRIEST: Et dimitte
nobis debita nostra...
sicut et nos dimittimus...
CONGREGATION: ...quotidianum
da nobis hodie.
Et dimitte nobis
debita nostra...
sicut et nos dimittimus...
debitoribus nostris...
No doorman or maître d'will
ever mistake you again.
I promise.
...sed libera nos a malo
Itzhak.
This is Itzhak Stern,
my accountant. Itzhak...
You must be
Mrs. Schindler.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Emilie has volunteered
to work in the clinic.
Very generous of you.
I know.
We need to talk
when you have a moment.
This is my wife, Stern. I don't
keep any secrets from my spouse.
Oskar, please, attend to business.
It's much more attractive.
Madam.
Hello.
What is it? We've received
an angry complaint
from the Armaments Board.
The artillery shells,
tank shells, rocket casings,
apparently all of them have
failed quality control tests.
That's to be expected.
Start-up problems.
This isn't pots and pans.
This is a precise business.
I'll write them a letter.
They're withholding payment.
Sure, so would I, so would you.
I wouldn't worry about it. We'll
get it right one of these days.
There's a rumor you've been going
around miscalibrating the machines.
They could shut us down,
send us back to Auschwitz.
I'll call around, find out
where we can buy shells.
Pass them off as ours.
I don't see the difference.
Whether they're made here
or somewhere else...
You don't see a difference?
I see a difference.
You'll lose a lot of money.
Fewer shells will be made.
Stern, if this factory
ever produces
a shell that can
actually be fired,
I'll be very unhappy-
WOMAN: Hello, madam.
How do you do?
(MACHINE GRINDING)
How are you doing, Rabbi?
Rabbi!
Good, Herr Direktor.
Sun's going down.
Yes, it is.
What day is this? Friday?
It is Friday, isn't it?
Is it?
What's the matter with you? You
should be preparing for the Sabbath.
Shouldn't you?
I've got some wine.
In my office. Come.
RABBI LETARTOV: Savree
maranun verabonun verobotay
Baruch atah, Adoshem
eloheynu, melech ha-olam
Boray p'ree ha-gafen
WORKERS: Amen.
Baruch atah, Adoshem
eloheynu, melech ha-olam
A-sher kid'shanu
b'mitzvo-tav v'ratza va-nu
V'shabbat kaddsho b'ahavah
oov-ratzone hin-cheelanu
Zeekaron Pma-ahsay
v'raysheet
Kee hoo yom t'cheelah Pmikraay
kodesh zaycher leetzeeat mitzrayim
Kee vanu vachatah v'ohtahnu
keydashta mekol ha-ahmim
V'shabbat kadd-shcha b'ahavah
oov-ratzone hin-chal-ta-nu
Baruch atah, Adoshem,
m'kaddaysh ha-Shabbat
Gut Shabbos.
(WORKERS RESPOND) Gut Shabbos.
SCHINDLER: What?
Do you have any money
hidden away someplace
that I don't know about?
No.
Why? Am I broke?
Uh...
Well...
WINSTON CHURCHILL ON RADIO:
Yesterday morning, at 2:41 a.m.,
at General Eisenhower's
headquarters,
General Jodl signed the Act
of Unconditional Surrender
of all German land,
sea and air forces in Europe
to the Allied
Expeditionary Force
and simultaneously
to the Soviet High Command.
The German war is,
therefore, at an end.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR) But let us
not forget for a moment...
I think it's time the guards
came into the factory.
Japan,
with all her treachery...
The unconditional surrender of
Germany has just been announced.
At midnight tonight,
the war is over.
Tomorrow you'll
begin the process
of looking for survivors
of your families.
In most cases,
you won't find them.
After six long years of murder,
victims are being mourned
throughout the world.
We've survived.
Many of you have come up to me
and thanked me.
Thank yourselves.
Thank your fearless Stern
and others among you
who worried about you
and faced death
at every moment.
I'm a member of the Nazi Party.
I'm a munitions manufacturer.
I'm a profiteer of slave labor.
I am a criminal.
At midnight you'll be free,
and I'll be hunted.
I shall remain with you until
five minutes after midnight,
after which time,
and I hope you'll forgive me,
I have to flee.
I know you have received
orders from our commandant,
which he has received
from his superiors,
to dispose of the population
of this camp.
Now would be the time to do it.
Here they are, they're all here.
This is your opportunity.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Or you could leave
and return to
your families as men
instead of murderers.
In memory of the countless
victims among your people,
I ask us to observe
three minutes of silence.
RABBI LEVARTOV: Yitgadal
veyitkadash shemey raba
Be'olma di'vera chir'utey
veyamlich malchutey
Ve'yatzmach purkaney
vi'ykarev meshichey
Bechayeychon u'veyomeychon
u'vechayey di chol beyt yisrael
Ba'agala u'vizman
kariv ve'imru amen
WORKERS: Amen.
Yehey sh'mey raba mevorach
le'olam u'le'olmey olmaya
Yitbarach ve'yishtabach ve'yitpa'ar
ve'yitromam ve'yitnasey
Ve'yithadar ve'yit'aleh
ve'yiythalal
She'mey dikudsha b'rich hu
Yehey sh'lama raba min shemaya
ve'chayim tovim
Aleynu ve'al kol yisrael
ve'imru amen
WORKERS: Amen.
Thank you, Mr. Jereth.
STERN: Open wide.
As soon as peace occurs,
I want...
I want that cloth
distributed to the workers.
Two and a half meters each.
Also, each person is to
get a bottle of vodka.
They won't drink it.
They know its value.
Likewise those Egipshi
cigarettes we organized.
It'll be done.
Everything you ask.
We've written a letter,
trying to explain things
in case you are captured.
Every worker has signed it.
Thank you.
It is Hebrew, from the Talmud.
It says, "Whoever saves one
life, saves the world entire."
(RING CLATTERING)
I could have got more out.
I could have got more.
I don't know.
If I just...
I could have got more.
Oskar, there are 1,100 people who are
alive because of you. Look at them.
If I'd made more money.
(LAUGHS)
I threw away so much money.
(SOBBING) You have no idea.
If I had just...
There will be generations
because of what you did.
I didn't do enough.
You did so much.
This car.
Goeth would've bought this car.
Why did I keep the car?
Ten people right there.
Ten people.
Ten more people.
This pin...
Two people.
This is gold.
Two more people.
He would have given me
two for it, at least one.
He would have
given me one, one more.
One more person.
A person, Stern.
For this.
(SOBBING) I could have gotten
one more person, and I didn't.
And I didn't!
(LOUD SOBBING)
You have been liberated
by the Soviet Army!
Have you been in Poland?
I just came from Poland.
Are there any Jews left?
Where should we go?
RUSSIAN OFFICER: Don't go
east, that's for sure.
They hate you there.
I wouldn't go west either,
if I were you.
We could use some food.
Isn't there a town over there?
CHORUS: Avir harim tzalul
kayayin Ve-reiach oranim
Nisa be-ru'ach ha'arbaim
Im kol pa'amonim
U-v-tardemat ilan va-even
Shvuya ba-haloma
Ha-ir asher badad yoshevet
U-ve-liba homa
Yerushalaim shel zahav
Ve-shel nehoshet ve-shel or
Ha-lo le-khol shirayich
Ani kinor
Yerushalaim shel zahav
Ve-shel nehoshet ve-shel or
Ha-lo le-khol shirayich
Ani kinor
Heil Hitler.
Eicha yavshu borot ha-mayim
Kikar ha-shuk reka
Ve-ein poked et Har ha-Bait
Ba-ir ha-atika
U-va-me'arot asher ba-sela
Meyalelot ruchot
Ve-ein yored el Yam
ha-Melach
Be-derech Yericho
Yerushalaim shel zahav
Ve-shel nehoshet ve-shel or
Ha-lo le-khol shirayich
Ani kinor
Yerushalaim shel zahav
Ve-shel nehoshet ve-shel or
Ha-lo le-khol shirayich
Ani kinor