-Here's some for 37 cents.
- Here's some for 32.
31.
- That's it. Don't they have any generics?
- I think this is the generic.
I never heard of that brand.
Maybe we should get this.
You're paying for advertising.
- Tuna. We should get tuna.
- Please, no more tuna.
- It's got protein. We need protein.
- Beans are protein.
- Beans make you fart.
- We got a convertible.
I'm gettin' it for myself.
One burrito and one large Slush.
- 21 dollars and 67 cents.
- Can you fill this up?
21.67
Jesus. Look, I forgot to pay for this.
You could have gotten caught.
What if somebody saw?
You know what the minimum age
for execution is in Alabama?
- About sixteen?
- Ten.
- There's a cop behind us.
- A cop?
- There's nothing to worry about, all right?
- There might be.
Just relax. Please.
- Is he still there?
- Yeah.
- Goddamn it.
- Calm down, all right?
There's a cop behind us, that's all.
There's no problem.
- What?
- His light's on.
Fuck. Fuck. Goddamn it.
- What are we gonna do?
- It's probably nothing. It might be a taillight.
- We don't have any money for bail.
- Bail? Nothing's happened.
- Nothing? You stole something, didn't you?
- Shut up. All right?
All right. Here he comes.
- Show me your hands.
- Jesus.
Show me your hands. Get 'em up.
Get 'em up. Up.
Now put your hands on top of your head
and get outta the car.
- Outta the car.
- Go.
Yeah, I'm sure of it. It's number three and five.
Ridiculous. All this over a can of tuna.
Keep quiet.
Yeah. You sure about that?
Yeah. He's standing right here.
All right. Bye.
I think we may get a confession.
- I just heard someone shot Jimmy Willis.
- He's dead.
Oh, my God. Who would do such a thing?
- Hello, Bill. I'm Sheriff Farley.
- Hi.
- Do you know why you're here?
- Yeah, I do. I'm sorry.
It was a stupid thing to do.
- Have you been made aware of your rights?
- Yes.
- You're willing to waive that right?
- I'll cooperate fully.
I'll sign a statement, or whatever
makes this whole thing easier.
Good. Good. That's good.
But I want you to know,
Stan, he had nothing to do with it.
Did he help you plan it?
No. I mean... I mean, it wasn't planned out.
You know, it just happened.
Did Stan try to stop you at any time?
No. I mean, he was...
- Is that a big deal?
- Aidin' and abettin'.
- Aiding and abetting? Is that a major thing?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
An accessory?
Are you guys kiddin'? An accessory?
I didn't help. I didn't plan it.
You didn't try to stop it.
I didn't know it was happening.
I found out later in the car.
Why didn't you get out,
call the police then?
He's my friend.
Well.
Your friend has put you in a lot of trouble.
What's gonna happen to Bill?
Nothing. Unless he's convicted.
If he is, we're gonna run enough electricity
through him to light up Birmingham.
We were friends at NYU, and we both
applied and we got scholarships to UCLA.
So we figured the scenery would be
nicer going through the South.
- What about the tuna fish?
- I forgot about the tuna fish.
And then we left.
Did he catch you with the tuna fish?
Is that how it started?
- No, he didn't say anything.
- But he knew about it.
I don't know.
Let's talk about that for a moment.
You paid for the groceries.
- And then what?
- We went out to the car, and that's it.
When'd you shoot him?
- What?
- At what point did you shoot the clerk?
- I shot the clerk?
- Yes. When did you shoot him?
- We need ya out here.
I'm in the middle of a damn confession here.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
- What's the matter?
- Do you know what this is all about?
- Yeah, they're fucking with us.
- You don't believe them?
- They don't execute for shoplifting.
- You think we're booked for shoplifting?
No. You're being booked for shoplifting.
I'm booked for accessory to shoplifting.
No, Stan. I'm being booked for murder and
you're being booked for accessory to murder.
It's time to make your phone calls.
- Goddamn it.
- Could you contact your parents?
How? Call the Chilean consulate?
What can they do?
Send a guide into the mountains
looking for them?
We need to call an attorney. A great attorney.
Do you know any great attorneys?
No. I'm calling my mother.
Hello, Ma. We're in Wazoo.
It's in Beechum County, Alabama, Ma.
Not too good, Ma. We... we've been arrested.
Ma. Ma, please. Ma, please.
First of all, we didn't do it, all right?
Murder.
Ma. Ma, ple... Ma, it's a mistake.
We must look like the guys who did it.
- Tell her what we think is happening...
- Shut up.
We think they're trying to set us up as
patsies. You know how corrupt it is here.
The Klan's here, they're inbred,
they sleep with their sisters.
- Some of them do.
- All right, Ma, listen.
We gotta get an attorney,
and it's gonna cost a lot of money.
- How much would an attorney cost?
- A decent one? $50,000. $100,000.
50,000. 100,000... I know, Ma. I know.
- Can we use any attorney?
- I think so.
He says he thinks so.
He is?
Well, that's a great idea.
You think he'll do it?
- We got an attorney in the family.
- Who?
My cousin Vinny.
What is that?
Where's he from?
- What?
- You stick out like a sore thumb around here.
- Me? What about you?
- I fit in better than you.
- At least I'm wearin' cowboy boots.
- Oh, yeah. You blend.
I bet the Chinese food here is terrible.
- I don't see anything.
- The wheels went out of balance
- right after we hit that mud.
- No, that's not it.
I think you should put it
on a rack and take a look.
What's wrong?
- What?
- What's the problem?
The car was shimmying on the highway.
- You got mud in your tyres.
- I got mud in my tyres?
Let me ask you, how do you
get mud into the tyres?
That's a figure of speech.
The mud gets around the inside of the wheel.
- Throws the balance off.
- Did you ever hear that? Mud in the tyres?
No.
She never heard it.
She knows everything about cars.
See, down here, everybody gets stuck
in the mud every now and then.
- Yeah. We're famous for our mud.
- Famous for your mud?
How's your Chinese food?
You keep on askin' about that. Can't you
tell they don't have Chinese restaurants?
Gotta let everybody know
you're a tourist. Come on.
And you're a fuckin' world traveller?
Our jail was condemned this morning.
That's why we bringin' you all
out to the state corrections facility.
Unlock the gate.
Go on through.
- Do you know what happens in these places?
- Yeah, I know what happens.
There's often a big guy named
Bubba no one will tangle with.
He'll protect you - if you become
his sex slave and do whatever he wants.
There's only the two of us here.
What about those cots?
What if they put somebody else in here?
Stan.
- Shut up.
- OK.
I can't believe my luck.
Here.
We got somebody for you.
You must be Stan. How you doin'?
Why'd they bring you in here?
I just got in. I asked for the new guys
and they brought me here.
He's sleepin', huh? Cute little guy.
You know, maybe I'll just start with you.
Let him sleep a little bit.
- Look, I don't wanna do this.
- I don't blame you.
If I was in your situation,
I'd wanna get through this whole thing
as quickly and with as little pain as possible.
So let's try our best to make it
a simple in-and-out procedure.
What's the matter?
Relax, relax. Relax.
Maybe we should spend
a couple of minutes together.
You know, to get acquainted before we,
you know, before we get to it.
- What's wrong with you?
- I don't wanna do this.
I understand, but what are your alternatives?
My alternatives? To what? To you?
I dunno. Suicide. Death.
Look, it's either me or them.
You're gettin' fucked, one way or the other.
Lighten up, OK?
Don't worry, I'm gonna help you.
Gee, thanks.
Excuse me, but I think a modicum of
gratitude would not be outta line here.
- You think I should be grateful?
- Yeah. I mean it's your ass, not mine.
I think you should be grateful. I think
you should be down on your fuckin' knees.
I didn't know your visit was such an honour.
I'm doin' a favour.
You're gettin' me for nothin', you little fuck.
Boy, that's one hell of an ego you've got.
What the fuck is your problem?
- I did not come here just to get jerked off.
- No. No, no.
I'm not jerking you off.
I'm not doing anything.
You're on your own. I'm just
takin' care of Sleeping Beauty.
- Billy.
- Back off.
- Vinny. Hey, Vinny.
- Vinny?
- Vinny Bag o' Donuts. How are you?
- This is Vinny?
I don't know where to start.
Have you had any murder cases before?
- None. This'll be my first.
- Your first?
Yeah.
What kind of cases have you had?
Assault and battery? Armed robbery?
No.
Well, I expect he's done burglary,
grand theft auto, drugs.
No. Nothin' like that either.
What kind... what kind of law
do you practise?
Well, up till now, personal injury.
Well, you're a trial attorney, right?
I mean, personal injury trials.
Well, actually, this'll be my first
foray into the trial process.
I haven't had to go to court yet.
Knock on wood.
You haven't had to go to court yet.
- How long you been practising?
- Almost six weeks.
But...
You graduated six years ago.
What have you been doin'?
Studyin', for the bar.
Six years?
- That's a lot of studying.
- Well, to be honest with you,
l... I didn't pass my first time out.
- That's OK. You passed the second time?
- I'm afraid not.
- Three times a charm?
- Not for me it isn't.
No. For me, six times was a charm.
Six times.
- A little informal, aren't we?
- I was resting...
- Not wearing a coat or tie.
- Sorry.
Well, approving an attorney from
out of state is a pretty informal matter.
- I just have a few questions.
- OK. Fire away, Judge.
- Where'd you go to law school?
- Brooklyn Academy of Law.
Is that an accredited law school?
Yes.
- How long you been practising?
- About six...
Almost sixteen years.
- Any murder cases?
- Quite a few. Yes.
- What was the outcome?
- You know. Win some, lose some.
This is not the forum to be cavalier.
Of course. Now, let me see.
Most recently, I had a axe murder,
which I won, on the grounds
of temporary insanity.
- Wanna hear the facts of the case?
- No.
- What else?
- Let me see. What else?
You ever heard of the Son of Sam?
The fella who received
orders to kill from a dog?
- That one.
- You defended him?
Well, no, not exactly.
I defended the first guy they arrested.
And he was found innocent and set free
and they caught the real guy.
Well.
We don't have any serial killers
in Beechum County.
What we do have is as sophisticated a justice
system as they do in the rest of the country.
- I'm sure.
- You being from New York an' all
might have the impression that law is
practised with a degree of informality here.
- It isn't.
- Right.
I tell you this because I want you
to know that when it comes to procedure,
I'm not a patient man.
Sir, when you come into my courtroom,
you ought to know the letter of the law.
- I'll react harshly when you don't.
- You should.
Being from New York
won't get you special treatment.
It shouldn't.
You won't. You'll be given
no leeway whatsoever.
I expect you to know this information
when you come into my courtroom.
Right.
- You willing to accept those terms?
- Right. No problem.
Just this?
This is gonna be great. Vinny's first case.
So? What can I do to help?
- Nothin'?
- No.
What the fuck is that?
Wanna sit at the counter?
Hey. How ya doin'?
Listen, what's the story with this
incredibly, remarkably loud whistle
at 5.30 in the morning?
It's the steam whistle.
Over at the sawmill.
Tell folks it's time to get up.
You can hear it for miles.
- Y'all want somethin'?
- Yeah.
- Breakfast?
- You think?
Good choice. Two.
Excuse me.
You guys down here hear about the ongoing
cholesterol problem in the country?
- What's this over here?
- You never heard of grits?
Sure. Sure, I heard of grits.
I just actually never seen a grit before.
- Honey, you gonna try it?
- You first.
- What is a grit, anyways?
- It's made out of corn.
- Them hominy grits.
- Hominy.
- How d'you cook it?
- Simmer it in water for 15 or 20 minutes,
put it on the plate and add butter.
So? You gonna eat it or not?
Here?
- Is your attorney here?
- I am the attorney.
Jim Trotter the Third.
District attorney of Beechum County.
Vincent La Guardia Gambini. First. Brooklyn.
Nice to see you.
Yeah.
- Vinny.
- Hey.
All rise for His Honour
Judge Chamberlain Haller.
The court of Beechum County
is now in session.
Be seated.
First case. The people of the State
of Alabama versus William Robert Gambini
and Stanley Marcus Rothenstein,
- "Steen." She called me "Stine".
- Just...
Counsellor, your clients are charged with
first-degree murder. How do they plead?
- Your Honour, my clients...
- Don't talk to me sitting in that chair.
- But he told me to sit here.
- When you address this court, you will rise
and speak to me in a clear, intelligible voice.
- Sorry. My clients...
- What are you wearin'?
Huh?
- I'm wearin' clothes.
I don't get the question.
When you come into my court
looking like you do,
you not only insult me,
but you insult the integrity of this court.
I apologise, sir, but this is how I dress.
Next time you come into my courtroom,
you will look lawyer-ly.
I mean, you comb your hair
and wear a suit and tie.
And that suit better be made
outta some kind of cloth.
- You understand me?
- Yes. Fine, Judge. Fine.
Good. You may continue.
How do your clients plead?
My clients are caught completely by surprise.
They thought they were getting
arrested for shoplifting a can of tuna.
What are you telling me?
That they plead not guilty?
- No. I'm just trying to explain.
- I don't wanna hear explanations.
The State of Alabama has its procedure.
And that procedure, at this point in time, is
to have an arraignment. Are we clear on this?
Yes. But there seems to be
a great deal of confusion here.
- Mr Gambini.
- You see, my clients...
All the way?
All I ask from you is a very simple
answer to a very simple question.
There are only two ways to answer.
"guilty" or "not guilty".
But my clients didn't do anything.
Once again, the communication
process has broken down.
It appears to me that you want
to skip the arraignment process,
go directly to trial, skip that,
and get a dismissal.
Well, I'm not about to revamp
the entire judicial process
just because you find yourself
in the unique position
of defending clients
who say they didn't do it.
Now, the next words out of your mouth
are either gonna be "guilty" or "not guilty".
I don't wanna hear commentary,
argument or opinion.
If I hear anything other than
"guilty" or "not guilty",
you'll be in contempt.
I don't even wanna hear you clear your throat.
I hope I've been clear.
Now, how do your clients plead?
I think I get the point.
No. I don't think you do.
You're now in contempt of court.
- Will you go for two counts of contempt?
- Not guilty.
Thank you.
Bail will be set at $200,000.
Preliminary hearing will be set
for 9.30am tomorrow morning.
Bailiff, please take Mr Gambini into custody.
His bail will be set at $200.
Come with me, please.
All rise as the judge leaves.
You have to bail me out.
You know that, right?
Let's go.
They're gonna nuke
this guy Norton this weekend.
Looks like it.
You got one huge responsibility,
taking on this murder case.
You screw up and those boys get fried.
I know.
- So you think you know what you're doin'?
- Yeah, I think I know what I'm doin'.
You didn't look like you knew what you were
doin' today in that courtroom. Why is that?
Well, it's a lot of procedure,
that's all. I'll learn it as I go.
- Learn as you go?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Didn't they teach that in law school?
- No, they didn't.
They teach you contracts,
precedence, interpretations.
Then the firm that hires you,
they teach you procedures.
- Or you can go to court and watch.
- So why don't you go to court and watch?
Because, between your father's garage and
working nights, when was I supposed to go?
I thought this summer I would
take off a couple of months.
But it ain't no big deal.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
How can you be so sure when you don't
know what it is you're supposed to know?
It's a procedure. Like rebuilding
a carburettor has a procedure.
You know how the first thing you do is
you take the carburettor off the manifold?
Suppose you skip the first step, and as you're
replacing one of the jets, you drop the jet.
It goes down, rolls along the manifold
and into the head. You're fucked.
You've learned the hard way that
you gotta remove the carburettor first.
That's what happened to me today.
I learned the hard way.
Actually, it was a good
learning experience for me.
All right. Well, is there any way I could
help out in this procedure situation?
Yeah. Keep bailing me out.
We can't afford to keep bailing you out.
I've cashed in half the traveller's cheques.
I didn't wanna cash 'em in,
but I didn't wanna bounce a cheque.
I tried hustling the money,
but I got stiffed, so I cashed...
Whoa, whoa. What do you mean, you got
stiffed? Did you say you got stiffed?
Hey. Vincent La Guardia Gambini.
- His name's JT.
- JT.
I believe you and Lisa played
a game of pool for $200, which she won.
I'm here to collect.
- How about if I just kick your ass?
- A counteroffer?
That's what we lawyers - I'm a lawyer -
we lawyers call that a "counteroffer".
Let me see. This is a tough decision.
Get my ass kicked or collect $200?
What do you think?
I could use a good ass kicking,
I'll be very honest with you.
Nah, I think I'll just go with the 200.
Over my dead body.
You like to renegotiate as you go along, huh?
OK, then. Here's my counteroffer.
Do I have to kill you? What if I was just
to kick the everlovin' shit outta you?
- In your dreams.
- No, no, no. In reality.
If I was to kick the shit outta you,
do I get the money?
- If you kicked the shit outta me?
- Yeah.
Yeah, then you get the money.
- What happened? Rear-ended?
- No, I fell.
OK. Let's see if we agree on the terms.
The choice now is I get my ass kicked
or, option B, I kick your ass
and collect the 200.
I'm going with option B.
Kicking your ass and collecting $200.
- Are we gonna fight now?
- Yeah. First, let me see the money.
- I have the money.
- All right. Let me see it. Show it to me.
- I can get it.
- You can get it?
All right. Get it.
And then we'll fight.
You fell in your place or somebody else's?
- My place.
- Shit.
He blew the arraignment.
It's a simple procedure.
You heard the judge. All he had
to do was say "guilty" or "not guilty".
So? What are you saying?
What am I saying? You saw what happened
in there. You wanna stay with him after that?
Shit, Stan. I don't wanna fire him.
He's family. And my mother,
the way her health is right now...
I appreciate that. But should you die for that?
Wouldn't your mother
be more upset if you die?
The thing is, given the chance,
I think he could do a good job.
- No, you're wrong.
- Come on, fellas, knock it off. Let's go.
Stan, listen.
You have to see the Gambinis in action.
These people, they love to argue.
I mean, they live to argue.
My parents argue, too -
that doesn't make them lawyers.
Stan, I've seen your parents argue.
Trust me, they're amateurs.
Is that a drip I hear?
Yeah.
Weren't you the last one
to use the bathroom?
So?
- Did you use the faucet?
- Yeah.
- Then why didn't you turn it off?
- I did turn it off.
Well, if you turned it off,
why am I listening to it?
Did it occur to you it could be
turned off and drip at the same time?
No. If you turned it off, it wouldn't drip.
- Maybe it's broken.
- Is that what you're saying? It's broken?
Yeah, that's it. It's broken.
- You sure?
- I'm positive.
- Maybe you didn't twist it hard enough?
- I twisted it just right.
How could you be so sure?
If you will look in the manual, you will
see that this particular model faucet
requires a range of 10 to 16
foot-pounds of torque.
I routinely twist to
maximum-allowable torquage.
How could you be sure
you used 16 foot-pounds of torque?
Because I used a Craftsman model 1019
laboratory edition
Signature Series torque wrench.
The kind used by Caltech
high-energy physicists
and NASA engineers.
Well, in that case, how could
you be sure that's accurate?
Because a split second before the torque
wrench was applied to the faucet handle,
it had been calibrated by top members
of the state and federal
department of weights and measures
to be dead-on balls accurate.
Here's a certificate of validation.
Dead-on balls accurate?
It's an industry term.
I guess the fucking thing is broken.
We gotta move.
Then I heard two loud bangs,
like firecrackers.
I looked up and saw two young men
run out from the Sac-o-Suds
and jump into a green car
with a white convertible top,
and drive off like the dickens.
Miss Riley, are those two young men
present in the courtroom?
- Yes, sir. They are.
- Could you point 'em out for me, please?
They sittin' right there.
Now, Mrs Riley, is this the car?
- Yes, sir. It is.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Let the records show Mrs Constance Riley
identified the defendants' car.
I was makin' my breakfast.
I saw them two boys go into the store.
Then later I heard a gunshot.
Looked out the window.
They were running out.
Got into the car and drove off.
Is this the car?
Yes. It is.
Thank you, sir.
Then you saw those two boys run out o' the
Sac-o-Suds, jump in this car and take off?
Yeah. They peeled away.
Car was all over the road.
Thank you, sir.
I asked him if he did it,
and he said "l shot the clerk."
I asked him again, and again
he said "l shot the clerk."
Your Honour, no further questions.
- Mr Gambini.
- Yes.
- Do you have anything to add?
- Thing? What thing?
Not for me to say.
No, sir.
You can stand down.
- Do you have any other witnesses?
- No, Your Honour.
The court finds sufficient evidence
exists for this matter to go to trial.
I'm setting this matter for trial
this Monday, February 2, 10am.
Mr Gambini.
Stand up.
Now, didn't I tell you next time you appear in
my courtroom that you dress appropriately?
You were serious about that?
- Why didn't you ask them any questions?
- Questions? Ask who questions?
You knew you could ask questions.
Didn't you, Vin?
If you'd put up a fight, you could have
gotten the case thrown out.
Hey, Stan. You're in Ala-fuckin'-bama.
You come from New York.
You killed a good old boy.
There is no way this is not going to trial.
What the fuck is goin' on here, Vinny?
You fuckin' up this case or what?
I told you. It's just procedure.
I'm bound to fuck up a little.
A little? You got thrown in jail. Twice.
I know I was in jail. I don't need you
to point it out to me, OK?
You're my fiancee.
You're supposed to stand by your man.
You know, encourage me a little bit.
A little encouragement.
Is that what you want? I'm sorry.
You were wonderful in there.
The way you handled that judge...
You're a smooth talker. You are.
All right, knock it off. Knock it off.
Do you think I like fuckin' up? Is that it?
You raggin' on me is not gonna give me
any great spontaneous knowledge.
- Yeah?
- So shut it.
- You done readin'?
- Yeah.
Do you wanna go to bed?
I don't know. I don't feel good.
You shouldn't feel good.
You haven't slept much in three days.
That's part of it. You know what it is?
I'm... I'm really scared.
You should be.
How the fuck did I get into this shit?
"Sure. No problem. I could win the case."
I already got myself sent to jail twice.
I could win this thing, though.
I know I could.
If I could keep my ass awake and outta jail
long enough, betcha I could, huh?
You know what I think? Honestly?
I think that once you're out there
and you're doin' your thing,
I think you're gonna be really great.
Really great.
If you don't fuck up.
If this was a conspiracy,
they'd have to get all those people to lie.
Do you think that's what's happening?
Look, I think we should meet with
the public defender. See what he's like.
If he's honest, then we should go with him.
All right.
- That's death row in there.
- It is?
The chair ain't working like it used to.
The guy we fried last week - took us
three attempts and his head caught fire.
See, there's no money in the budget
to get it looked at.
I say it'd be cheaper to get it fixed than
keeping running up them extra electric bills.
Hi, Stanley.
My name is John Gibbons
and I'm an attorney
in the public defender's office.
- Hi, John.
- Hey.
Now, the evidence against you
is pretty strong, so
why don't you just tell me
your side of the story?
- Hey, Vin.
- Hey, Billy.
How are ya?
- How do you feel? OK?
- All right.
- Where's Stan?
- Stan, he's not comin'.
He's...
Well, he wants to go with the public defender.
Listen, Vin...
I'm going with the public defender, too.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I just didn't know
what little experience you have with this.
- What, are you scared?
- Yeah, I'm scared.
Maybe I could have handled
the preliminary a little better.
But what's most important
is winning the case.
I could do it. I really could.
Let me tell you how, OK?
The DA's gotta build a case.
Building a case is like building a house.
Each piece of evidence is a building block.
He wants to make
a brick bunker of a building.
He wants to use serious,
solid-looking bricks, like these, right?
- Right.
- Let me show you something.
He's gonna show you the bricks.
He'll show you they got straight sides.
He'll show you how they got the right shape.
He'll show them to you
in a very special way
so that they appear to have
everything a brick should have.
But there's one thing
he's not gonna show you.
When you look at the bricks at the right
angle, they're as thin as this playing card.
His whole case is an illusion, a magic trick.
It has to be an illusion, cos you're innocent.
Nobody, I mean nobody, pulls the wool over
the eyes of a Gambini. Especially this one.
Give me the chance. One chance.
Let me question the first witness.
lf, after that point, you don't think that I'm the
best man for the job, fire me then and there.
I'll leave quietly. No grudges.
All I ask is for that one chance.
I think you should give it to me.
You should give it to him? What was he
before he was a lawyer? A fuckin' comedian?
If he doesn't ask the right questions,
your lawyer will.
No, he can still fuck things up.
Cross-examination is about knowing
what to say and what not to say.
Let's say he asks all the possible questions,
and the witness has all the answers.
He ends up proving the prosecution's case.
How did he ever talk you into it?
At my cousin Ruthie's wedding,
the groom's brother was that guy Ali Kazam.
- You know who I'm talkin' about?
- The magician with the ponytail?
Right. He did his act, and every time he made
something disappear, Vinny jumped on him.
He nailed him. It was like
"It's in his pocket" or "He's palming it."
Or "There's a mirror under the table."
He was like "Wait. It's joined in the middle
and there's a spring around it."
"lt pops it open when it's inside the tube."
It was like Ali Kazam's worst nightmare.
But he was just being Vinny.
He was just being
the quintessential Gambini.
There goes the quintessential Norton.
Lookee here, JT.
Hey, hey, little Yankee boy.
Look here what I got.
- What is it?
- $200.
Bring it here. Let me see it.
How do I know that's not a bunch
of ones with a 20 wrapped around it?
- It's 200 bucks.
- Fan it out. Show it to me.
Yeah, right.
Does that freight train come through
at 5am every morning?
No, sir. It's very unusual.
OK.
I was making a lot of money,
winning most of my cases.
Thank you, Shirley.
But my clients were guilty as hell.
Finally, after getting this fella off some
serious charges for the fourth time,
I tell you the truth, my conscience got to me.
I'd be serving justice more
by putting the guilty in jail.
That's what I've been doing and
I'm a happier man for it.
- How about you?
- Well, I got a bullshit traffic ticket.
In court, I got the cop on the stand
and argued with him until
he admitted he was wrong.
And the judge, this Judge Malloy,
all the while, he's laughing and smiling,
and then, afterwards,
he asked me to go to lunch with him.
Then he says to me "You know what?
You'd be a good litigator."
I don't know what the hell he was talking
about. I don't know what a litigator is.
I never thought of becoming a lawyer.
But Judge Malloy was from Brooklyn, too.
I mean, he did it.
So all of a sudden it seemed possible.
So I went to law school.
Then from time to time, he would come by,
see how I was doin', if I needed anything.
He was a nice man.
I mean, to go out of his way
like that for me, you know?
He wanted his son to follow in his footsteps,
but he became a musician or something.
I remember when I graduated,
he was so proud of me.
That's quite a story.
Yeah.
- We got some case ahead of us here, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
- How do you feel about it?
- Well, l...
I'd like to have a murder weapon.
But, other than that, I feel pretty good.
- You do?
- Oh, yeah.
What you doin' this afternoon?
- You're goin' hunting?
- That's right.
Why are you goin' hunting?
Shouldn't you be preparing for court?
I was thinkin' last night "lf only
I knew what he knows." You know?
If he'd let me look at his files. Oh, boy.
I don't get it. What does getting to
Trotter's files have to do with hunting?
Well, you know. Two guys
out in the woods, guns, on the hunt.
It's a bonding thing, you know.
Show him I'm one of the boys.
He won't let me see his files, but maybe
he'll relax enough to drop his guard
so that I can finesse
a little information out of him.
- What am I gonna wear?
- What are you gonna hunt?
I don't know. He's got a lot
of stuffed heads in his office.
Heads? What kind of heads?
I don't know. He's got a boar,
a bear, a couple of deer.
Whoa. You're gonna shoot a deer?
I don't know. I suppose. I mean, I'm
a man's man. I could go deer hunting.
A sweet, innocent, harmless,
leaf-eating, doe-eyed little deer.
Hey, Lisa. I'm not gonna go out
there just to wimp out, you know?
I mean, the guy'll lose respect for me.
Would you rather have that?
What about these pants I got on?
You think they're OK?
lmagine you're a deer.
You're prancing along. You get thirsty.
You spot a little brook.
You put your little deer lips
down to the cool, clear water.
Bam. A fuckin' bullet rips off
part of your head.
Your brains are layin'
on the ground in little bloody pieces.
Would you give a fuck what kind of pants
the son of a bitch
who shot you was wearing?
I'd sure like to get a look at your files.
- You would?
- Sure.
You got a Xerox machine over there?
No.
That's OK. I'll have my secretary do it.
Shirley, can you Xerox all the files on the
Gambini/Rothenstein case for Mr Gambini?
Yeah. Thanks, sweetheart.
- What's all that?
- Trotter's files. All of 'em.
- You stole his files?
- I didn't steal his files.
Listen to this. I'm just ready to finesse him.
I'm starting to finesse him. I got him goin'.
He offers to have his secretary
copy everything for me.
- That's very impressive finessing.
- That's not all.
He's letting us use his hunting cabin
when he gets back.
It's in the woods. It's quiet.
He sleeps like a baby when he's there.
Terrific. You're a helluva bonder.
What's this? Are you reading this book?
- Yeah.
- Do me a favour, OK? Don't read this book.
OK? Thank you very much.
All right.
Don't you wanna know
why Trotter gave you his files?
I told you why already.
He has to by law. You're entitled.
It's called disclosure, you dickhead.
He has to show you everything,
otherwise it could be a mistrial.
He has to give you a list of all his witnesses.
You can talk to all his witnesses.
He's not allowed any surprises.
They didn't teach you that
in law school either?
Now let me ask you this.
How many levels of thickness
have you gone through?
- What'd you have for breakfast?
- Well...
What's that brown stuff?
Yesterday you told me that freight train
hardly ever comes through here at 5am.
I know. She's supposed
to come through at ten after four.
Can you participate in this - in which the
final decision may be death by electrocution?
Ma'am?
I think it should be left up to the victims'
families, rather than the courts.
The defendants in this case are charged
with robbing a convenience store.
And then, in a most cowardly fashion,
shooting the clerk in the back.
Now, if sufficient evidence is offered
to prove these facts, you think you could...
Fry 'em.
She'll do.
Mr Gambini. Come in. Come in.
I just got a fax from the New York
State Office of Judicial Records.
They have no records
of any Vincent Gambini ever trying
any case in the entire state of New York.
You're not gonna find any records of Vincent
La Guardia Gambini practising in any courts.
- I just told you that.
- You don't understand.
See, 20 years ago, I became a actor.
There was this prominent stage actor
in New York. His name was Vincent Gambini.
- Maybe you heard of him.
- No.
Never heard of him? Doesn't matter. Anyway,
I had to change my name, which I did legally.
So now I practise law under
my legally changed stage name.
- What name is that?
- Jerry Ga...
Jerry Gallo.
You can still call me Gambini.
Sorry.
- What name did you tell him?
- Jerry Gallo.
- Jerry Gallo? The big attorney?
- Yeah.
- Think that was a smart move?
- Yeah. He's a seriously accomplished lawyer.
His name'll show up all over the place.
- His name was in the papers all last week.
- I saw that.
- You didn't actually read the articles?
- No.
- That's too bad.
- Why is that?
Cos he's dead.
What's the matter with you?
I dunno.
- You're acting like you're nervous.
- Well, yeah. I am.
Why? I'm the one that's under the gun.
The trial starts tomorrow.
You wanna know what
I'm nervous about? I'll tell you.
I am in the dark here with this legal crap.
I have no idea what's goin' on.
All's I know is you're screwin' up
and I can't help.
- You lent me your little camera, didn't ya?
- Oh, Vinny.
I'm watchin' you go down in flames, bringin'
me with you, and I can't do anything about it.
And?
I hate to bring it up - I know
you got enough pressure on you -
but we agreed to get married
when you won your first case.
Meanwhile, ten years later, my niece, the
daughter of my sister, is gettin' married.
My biological clock is tickin' like this,
and the way this case is goin',
I ain't never gettin' married.
Lisa, I don't need this. I swear to God,
I do not need this right now, OK?
I got a judge that's just aching
to throw me in jail.
An idiot who wants to fight me for $200.
Slaughtered pigs. Giant loud whistles.
I ain't slept in five days.
I got no money. A dress-code problem.
And a little murder case which, in the
balance, holds the lives of two innocent kids.
Not to mention your
biological clock, my career,
your life, our marriage,
and let me see, what else can we pile on?
Is there any more shit we can pile on
to the top of the outcome of this case?
Is it possible?
Maybe it was a bad time to bring it up.
What the fuck is that?
This is very romantic.
Out here in this field,
under the stars, quiet.
No one around for miles.
It's very romantic.
I don't see no stars.
Honey, move. My back.
I have to get up.
Wait. Let me...
This fuckin' jacket.
Fuck.
- You OK?
- What was in that plastic thing in the trunk?
It's your suit.
- What is my suit doing in the trunk?
- I had it cleaned.
I thought it'd be a nice surprise -
go in there with a clean suit.
I have 30 fuckin' minutes to take a shower,
get a new suit and get to the courthouse.
- You fuckin' shower, I'll get your fuckin' suit.
- Little Yankee wuss.
Look here. Got your $200.
You gonna kick the shit out of me now?
Mr Gambini,
are you mockin' me with that outfit?
Mockin' you? I'm not mockin' you, Judge.
Then explain that outfit.
I bought a suit. You seen it.
Now it's covered in mud.
This town doesn't have a one-hour cleaners,
so I had to buy a new suit.
Except that the only store you could
buy a new suit in has got the flu.
You get that? The whole store got the flu.
So I had to get this in a second-hand store.
So, it's either wear the leather jacket -
which I know you hate - or this.
So I wore this ridiculous thing for you.
Are you on drugs?
Drugs? No. I don't take drugs.
- I don't like your attitude.
- What else is new?
- I'm holding you in contempt of court.
- There's a fuckin' surprise.
- What'd you say?
- What?
What'd you just say?
What'd I say? What?
Your Honour, counsel, members of the jury.
The evidence in this case is gonna show
that at 9.30 in the morning of January 4th,
both defendants, Stanley Rothenstein
and William Gambini,
were seen gettin' out of their
metallic green 1964 Buick Skylark
convertible with a white top.
It's gonna show they were seen entering the
Sac-o-Suds convenience store in Wazoo City.
The evidence is gonna show that,
minutes after they entered the Sac-o-Suds,
a gunshot was heard by three eyewitnesses.
You will then hear the testimony
of the three eyewitnesses
who saw the defendants runnin' out of the
Sac-o-Suds just after the shots were heard,
gettin' into their faded metallic green 1964
Buick Skylark and drivin' off in great haste.
Finally, the state is gonna prove that
the defendants, Gambini and Rothenstein,
admitted then recanted their testimony
to the sheriff of Beechum County.
Now let's get down to it.
Your verdict is gonna depend on
what you think of the sworn testimony.
Not what I think. What I think don't count.
You're the jury. It's your job
to decide who's tellin' the truth.
Truth. That's what "verdict" means.
It's a word that comes down from ol'
England, and all our little ol' ancestors.
Now, we're gonna be asking
you to return a verdict
of murder in the first degree
for William Gambini
and a verdict of accessory to murder in the
first degree for Stanley Rothenstein,
for helping Gambini
commit this heinous crime.
Counsellor, you wish to make
an opening statement?
Counsellor?
- Vinny.
- What?
Come on, it's time to make
your opening statement.
Come on, Vin.
Everything that guy said is bullshit.
Thank you.
Objection, Your Honour. Counsel's
entire opening statement is argument.
Objection sustained.
The entire opening statement,
with the exception of "thank you",
will be stricken from the record.
The jury will please disregard
counsel's entire opening statement.
And you, Mr Gambini, will not use that kinda
language in my court. Understand?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Putz.
Counsellor. Your statement, sir.
Well, now.
Ladies and gentlemen of the j-j-j...
of-of the j-j-j...
jury.
On-on...
On January ffffffff....
fourth of this year, my client did indeed
visit the Sac-o-Suds c... co...
convenience store.
But-but
he didn't
kill anyone. He...
We intend to prove that the ppppp...
prosecution's case
is circumstantial and-and-and
coincidental. Thank you.
That's it? What about
everything we talked about?
- I get a little nervous...
- A little?
I'm gettin' better.
I heard a gunshot, so I looked out the window
and I seen them two boys
run out, get into their car,
and drive off like maniacs, their tyres
screechin', smokin', goin' up on the kerb.
Is this the car?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
No further questions, Your Honour.
Your witness.
All right. Mr T-T-T...
Tipton.
Now, when you viewed my clients,
- how-how far away were you?
- About 50 feet.
Now, do you think that that's close enough
to make an accurate i-i-i-identification?
Yes.
- Mr Tipton, I see you wear eyeglasses.
- Sometimes.
Would you care to show those eyeglasses
to the jury, please? Thank you.
Thank you. Mr Tipton,
were you wearing them that day?
- No.
- You see.
You were 50 feet away, you made
a positive eyewitness identification,
and-and-and yet
you were not wearing your
necessary prescription eyeglasses.
They're reading glasses.
Well, Mr...
Could you tell the court
what colour eyes the defendants have?
Brown. Hazel green.
No more questions.
Mr Gambini. Your witness.
- He's a tough one.
- Yes.
Mr Tipton.
When you viewed the defendants
walkin' from their car into the Sac-o-Suds,
what angle was your point of view?
They was kind of walking toward me
when they entered the store.
And when they left,
what angle was your point of view?
They was kind of walkin' away from me.
So would you say you got a better shot of
them goin' in, and not so much comin' out?
- You could say that.
- I did say that. Would you say that?
Yeah.
Is it possible the two youths...
Two what?
What was that word?
- What word?
- Two what?
- What?
- Did you say "yoots"?
- Yeah. "Two youths."
- What is a yoot?
Excuse me, Your Honour. Two youths.
Is it possible the two defendants
entered the store, picked 22
specific items off of the shelves,
had the clerk take money,
make change, then leave.
Then, two different men
drive up in a similar...
Don't shake your head. Wait till you hear
the whole thing so you can understand.
Two different men drive up
in a similar-looking car,
go in, shoot the clerk,
rob him and then leave?
No. They didn't have enough time.
- How much time was they in the store?
- Five minutes.
- Five minutes? Did you look at your watch?
- No.
Oh, I'm sorry. You testified earlier
that the boys went into the store
and you had just begun to make breakfast.
You were just ready to eat
and you heard a gunshot.
So obviously it takes you five minutes
to make breakfast, so you knew that.
- Do you remember what you had?
- Eggs and grits.
Eggs and grits. I like grits, too.
How do you cook your grits?
You like 'em regular, creamy or al dente?
- Just regular, I guess.
- Regular. lnstant grits?
No self-respectin' Southerner uses
instant grits. I take pride in my grits.
So, Mr Tipton.
How could it take you
five minutes to cook your grits
when it takes the entire
grit-eating world 20 minutes?
I dunno. I'm a fast cook, I guess.
I'm sorry, I was over here. I couldn't hear.
Did you say you're a fast cook? That's it?
Are we to believe that boiling water
soaks into a grit faster in your kitchen
than on any place on the face of the earth?
I don't know.
Perhaps the laws of physics
cease to exist on your stove.
Were these magic grits?
Did you buy them from the same guy
who sold Jack his beanstalk beans?
- Objection, Your Honour.
- Sustained.
- Are you sure about that five minutes?
- I don't know.
- I think you made your point.
- Are you sure about that five minutes?
I may have been mistaken.
I got no more use for this guy.
You're fired.
I want him.
Come on, now. Move it.
- Don't worry. I'll bail you out.
- Don't. I'm gonna stay in prison tonight.
Maybe I can finally get some sleep.
I'm doin' good, huh?
Hey, how ya doin'?
Hey, Mr Crane. What are these pictures of?
- My house and stuff.
- House and stuff.
And what is this brown stuff
on the windows?
- Dirt.
What is this rusty, dusty,
dirty-lookin' thing over your window?
- It's a screen.
- A screen.
It's a screen.
What are these really big things
right in the middle of your view
from the window of your kitchen
to the Sac-o-Suds?
What do we call these big things?
- Trees?
- Trees, that's right.
Don't be afraid.
Just shout 'em out when you know.
Now, what are these thousands
of little things that are on trees?
- Leaves.
And these bushy things between the trees?
- Bushes.
So, Mr Crane.
You could positively identify the defendants
for a moment of two seconds
looking through this dirty window,
this crud-covered screen,
these trees with all these leaves on them,
and I don't know how many bushes.
- Looks like five.
- Don't forget this one and this one.
- Seven bushes.
- Seven bushes. So, what do you think?
Is it possible you just saw
two guys in a green convertible,
and not necessarily
these two particular guys?
- I suppose.
- I'm finished with this guy.
Mrs Riley, when you saw the defendants,
were you wearing your glasses?
Yes, I was.
Over here, dear.
Would you mind puttin'
your glasses on for us, please?
- Whoa. How long you been wearin' glasses?
- Since I was six.
- Have they always been that thick?
- Oh, no. They got thicker over the years.
So as your eyes have gotten more and more
outta whack as you've gotten older,
how many different levels
of thickness have you gone through?
I don't know.
Over sixty years, maybe ten times.
- Maybe you're ready for a thicker set.
- Oh, no. No, I think they OK.
Maybe we should make sure.
Let's check it out.
Now, how far were the defendants from you
when you saw them entering the Sac-o-Suds?
- About 100 feet.
- 100 feet.
Would you hold this, please? Thank you.
Sorry. Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry.
OK. This is 50 feet. That's half the distance.
How many fingers am I holding up?
Let the records show that
counsel is holding up two fingers.
Your Honour, please, huh?
Sorry.
Now, Mrs Riley, and only Mrs Riley,
how many fingers am I holding up now?
Four.
What do you think now, dear?
I'm thinkin' of gettin' thicker glasses.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- You did good out there today, Yankee.
I like the competition. You like competition,
too? Makes things kinda fun, doesn't it?
- I'm enjoying myself so far.
- I got a little surprise for you tomorrow.
What's that? You know you have
to disclose all your evidence to me.
I just got it myself. I'll disclose it first thing
in the morning. Judge gonna have to admit it.
- Should I be worried?
- I sure would be if I were you.
Honey, where did you read
about all that disclosure shit?
Let me show you. Why?
I'm a special automotive instructor
of forensic studies for the FBl.
- How long you been in that position?
- 18 years.
Your Honour.
May we approach the bench, please?
If you wish.
I object to this witness
being called at this time.
We've been given no prior notice he'd testify,
no discovery of any tests he's conducted,
and the defence is entitled to advance
notice of any witness who will testify,
particularly those giving scientific evidence,
so we can prepare for cross-examination,
and to give the defence an opportunity to
have reports reviewed by a defence expert
who might then be in a position to
contradict the veracity of his conclusions.
- Mr Gambini.
- Yes, sir.
That is a lucid, intelligent,
well thought-out objection.
- Thank you, Your Honour.
- Overruled.
Now, Mr Wilbur.
These are photos of tyres
belonging to the defendants' car.
And these are photos of the tyre marks left
by the assailants' car as it fled the store.
- Now, are you familiar with these?
- Yes, I am.
Could you elaborate, please, sir?
We compared the tyre marks
outside the convenience store
with the rear tyres of the defendants' car.
They're the same model and size tyre.
Michelin model XGV,
size 75R, 14-inch wheel.
They're the same size and model tyre.
- Anything else, sir?
- Yes, indeed.
The car, leaving the convenience store,
spun its rear tyres dramatically
and left a residue of rubber on the asphalt.
Now, I took a sample of that rubber
and analysed it.
I also took a sample of the rubber
from the rear tyres of the defendants'
Buick and analysed that, too.
What kind of equipment
did you use to find this out?
I used a Hewlett-Packard 57-10A
dual-column gas chromatograph
with flame analysation detectors.
Is that thing turbocharged?
Only on the floor models.
Now, Mr Wilbur.
What was the result of your analysis?
The chemical composition between
the two samples was found to be identical.
ldentical.
No further questions, Your Honour.
- Your Honour.
- Thank you, Mr Wilbur.
Court'll take a 60-minute recess for lunch.
Your Honour, I respectfully request a full
day's continuance to go over this sh... stuff.
- Request denied.
- Thanks a lot.
- And, Mr Gambini.
- Yes, sir?
I'd like to speak to you in my chambers.
- You're a dead man.
- I'm a dead man?
I faxed the clerk of New York and asked
him what he knew about Jerry Gallo.
You wanna know what he replied?
- Did you say "Jerry Gallo"?
- Yes, I did.
- Gallo with a G?
- That's right.
Jerry Gallo's dead.
- I'm aware of that.
- Well, I'm not Jerry Gallo.
I'm Jerry Callo. C-A-L-L-O.
All right.
Let's get this cleared up right now.
Hello. This is Judge Chamberlain Haller.
Can I speak to the clerk?
OK. I'll be here.
He's gonna call back after three.
That gives you a stay of execution.
Unless by some miracle you happen
to win this case in the next 90 minutes.
Why don't you go to lunch?
Thanks.
- I got my pictures back.
- Good.
What'd the judge say?
He said he found out that Gallo is dead.
He found out. What'd he say?
Lisa, I'm tryin' to think about
the case now, OK? I'm sorry.
- Can I help?
- "Can I help?"
No, you can't help.
I wish you could, but you can't.
OK, you're lookin' at me.
What is that look supposed to mean?
I'm a piece of shit cos I can't
figure out a way for you to help?
OK, you're helpin'. I'll use your pictures.
These are gonna...
I'm sorry. These are gonna be a help.
I should have looked
at these pictures before.
I like this. This is our first hotel room, right?
That'll intimidate Trotter.
Here's one of me from behind.
I didn't think I could feel worse
than I did a second ago. Thank you.
Here's a good one of the tyre marks.
Could we get any farther away?
Where'd you shoot this from? Up in a tree?
What's this over here?
It's dog shit. Dog shit. That's great.
Dog shit. What a clue.
Why didn't I think of that?
Here's one of me reading. I should've asked
you a long time ago for these pictures.
Holy shit. You got it, honey.
You did it. The case cracker.
Me in the shower.
I love this. That's it.
That is it. I'm outta here.
Lisa.
I'm sorry.
Fuck.
I know I'm missin' somethin'.
Did you find anything?
Very, very little.
- Something?
- Nothin'.
Is it possible that two separate cars could
be driving on Michelin model XGV 75R-14s?
- Of course.
- Let me ask you this.
What's the best-selling single model tyre
being sold in the United States today?
The Michelin XGV.
- And what's the most popular size?
- 75R-14.
The same size as on the defendants' car.
But two faded green
1964 Buick Skylark convertibles?
Excuse me. What I'm askin' you
is if the most popular size of the most
popular tyre is on the defendants' car?
Well, yeah.
Yes.
Thank you.
No further questions.
The witness can stand down.
Counsel.
Yeah. Prosecution rests.
Mr Gambini. Your first witness.
I will ask you one more time,
and one more time only.
- If I ask you again...
- Your Honour...
Please, can I have a five-minute recess?
- My next witness is not in the courtroom.
- Three minutes. No more.
Sheriff, do me a favour. Please trace this.
- It's not my job. Do your own investigating.
- Please. I only have three minutes.
Lisa. Lisa, please. I'm sorry. I'm sorry, OK?
I need you in the courtroom,
and I need the phone.
Honey, come on. Stop it. I need the phone.
We have to make up. Let's make up.
We gotta go back inside.
Everybody's waitin' for us.
- We don't have a lot of time.
- Shut up.
- Gimme this.
- Fuck you.
What is it with you with that mouth?
Mr Gambini. Tell me why.
- Lisa, I need your help.
- I don't give a shit. Leave me alone.
Come on, I found it.
Your Honour, the defence calls as
its first witness Miss Mona Lisa Vito.
I object, Your Honour.
This person is not on the witness list.
This witness is a automobile expert
and is being called to rebut
the testimony of George Wilbur.
Your Honour, would you instruct the bailiff
to escort Miss Vito to the witness stand?
Hold up your right hand.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
- the whole truth, and nothing but the truth?
- Yeah.
Miss Vito. You're supposed to be some kinda
expert in automobiles. Is that correct?
Is that correct?
- Will you please answer the counsel?
- No. I hate him.
Your Honour, may I treat Miss Vito
as a hostile witness?
You think I'm hostile now,
wait till you see me tonight.
- Do you two know each other?
- Yeah, she's my fiancee.
Well, that would certainly
explain the hostility.
I object to this witness. lmproper foundation.
I'm not aware of this person's qualifications.
I'd like to voir dire this witness
as to the extent of her expertise.
Granted.
Mr Trotter, you may proceed.
Miss Vito, what's your current profession?
- I'm an out-of-work hairdresser.
- Out-of-work hairdresser.
Now, in what way does that qualify
you as an expert in automobiles?
- It doesn't.
- Well, in what way are you qualified?
Well, my father was a mechanic.
His father was a mechanic.
My mother's father was a mechanic.
My three brothers are mechanics.
Four uncles on my father's side...
Miss Vito, your family's obviously qualified.
But, have you
ever worked as a mechanic?
- Yeah. In my father's garage, yeah.
- As a mechanic?
What'd you do in your father's garage?
Tune-ups, oil changes, brake relining,
engine rebuilds, rebuilds on trannies...
OK. OK. But does being an ex-mechanic
qualify you as being expert on tyre marks?
No. Thank you. Goodbye.
Sit down and stay there
until you're told to leave.
Your Honour. Miss Vito's expertise
is in general automotive knowledge.
It is in this area
that her testimony will be applicable.
Now, if Mr Trotter wishes
to voir dire the witness
as to the extent of her expertise in this area,
I'm sure he's gonna be more than satisfied.
OK.
All right. All right.
Now, Miss Vito.
Being an expert on
general automotive knowledge,
can you tell me
what would the correct ignition
timing be on a 1955 Bel Air Chevrolet,
with a 327 cubic-inch engine,
and a four-barrel carburettor?
- That's a bullshit question.
- Does that mean that you can't answer it?
It's impossible to answer.
- Because you don't know the answer.
- Nobody could answer that question.
Your Honour, I move to disqualify
Miss Vito as a expert witness.
- Can you answer the question?
- No. It is a trick question.
Why is it a trick question?
- Watch this.
- Cos Chevy didn't make a 327 in '55.
The 327 didn't come out till '62.
And it wasn't offered in the Bel Air
with a four-barrel carb till '64.
However, in 1964 the correct ignition timing
would be four degrees
before top, dead centre.
Well...
She's acceptable, Your Honour.
Your Honour, this is a picture taken
by my fiancee outside the Sac-o-Suds.
Can we agree on this?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
I'd like to submit this picture
of the tyre tracks as evidence.
Mr Trotter.
No objection, Your Honour.
- Miss Vito. Did you take this picture?
- You know I did.
- And what is this picture of?
- You know what it's of.
Miss Vito, it has been
argued by me, the defence,
that two sets of guys met up
at the Sac-o-Suds, at the same time,
driving identical metallic mint-green
1964 Buick Skylark convertibles.
Now, can you tell us,
by what you see in this picture,
if the defence's case holds water?
Miss Vito. Please answer the question.
Does the defence's case hold water?
No.
The defence is wrong.
- Are you sure?
- I'm positive.
How could you be so sure?
Because there is no way that these
tyre marks were made by a '64 Buick Skylark.
These marks were made
by a 1963 Pontiac Tempest.
Objection. Can we clarify whether
the witness is stating opinion or fact?
- This is your opinion?
- It's a fact.
I find it hard to believe
that this kind of information
could be ascertained
simply by looking at a picture.
Would you like me to explain?
- I would love to hear this.
- So would l.
The car that made these two equal-length
tyre marks had positraction.
Can't make those marks without positraction,
which was not available on the '64 Skylark.
- And why not? What is positraction?
- It's a limited slip differential
which distributes power equally
to both the right and left tyres.
The '64 Skylark had a regular differential
which, anyone who's been
stuck in the mud knows,
you step on the gas, one tyre spins,
the other does nothin'.
That's right.
- Is that it?
- No. There's more.
When the left tyre mark goes up on the kerb
and the right tyre stays flat and even...
Well, the '64 Skylark had a solid rear axle,
so, when the left tyre goes up on the kerb,
the right tyre tilts and rides along its edge.
But that didn't happen here.
The tyre mark stayed flat and even.
This car had an independent rear suspension.
Now, in the '60s there were only two other
cars made in America that had positraction
and independent rear suspension,
and enough power to make these marks.
One was the Corvette, which could never
be confused with the Buick Skylark.
The other had the same body length,
height, width, weight,
wheel base and wheel track
as the '64 Skylark,
and that was the 1963 Pontiac Tempest.
And because both cars were made by GM,
were both cars available
in metallic mint-green paint?
- They were.
- Thank you, Miss Vito.
No more questions.
Thank you very, very much.
You've been a lovely, lovely witness.
Mr Trotter, would you like
to question Miss Vito?
Mr Trotter.
No. No, Your Honour. No further questions.
In that case, Your Honour,
I'd like to recall George Wilbur.
Miss Vito, you can stand down.
You realise you're still under oath.
Yes, Your Honour.
Mr Wilbur, how'd you like
Miss Vito's testimony?
Very impressive.
She's cute too, huh?
Yes, very.
- Mr Gambini.
- Sorry, Your Honour.
Mr Wilbur, in your expert opinion,
would you say that everything Miss Vito
said on the stand was 100% accurate?
- I'd have to say that.
- And is there any way in the world
the Buick that the defendants
were driving made those tyre tracks?
Come on. You can say. It's OK, they know.
Actually,
- no.
- No.
Thank you. No more questions.
Your Honour, I call Sheriff Farley.
You may stand down now, Mr Wilbur.
- Sheriff, you realise you're still under oath?
- Yes, sir.
Sheriff Farley.
- What'd you find out?
- On a hunch,
I took it upon myself to check if there was
any information on a '63 Pontiac Tempest
stolen or abandoned recently.
This computer read-out
confirms that two boys,
who fit the defendants' description,
were arrested two days ago
by Sheriff Tilman in Jasper County, Georgia,
for driving a stolen metallic
mint-green 1963 Pontiac Tempest
with a white convertible top,
Michelin model XGV tyres, size 75R-14.
- Is that it?
- No.
A.357 Magnum revolver
was found in their possession.
Sheriff Farley, just to refresh
the court's memory,
what calibre bullet
was used to murder Jimmy Willis?
- A.357 Magnum.
- The defence rests.
Mr Trotter.
Your Honour, in light of Miss Vito's
and Mr Wilbur's testimony,
the State'd like to dismiss all charges.
Order in the court.
Order here.
I have to get out of here by three.
Make sure all the bags are in the car.
Vinny, I'm sorry to have ever doubted you
at any time, and for this I apologise.
Under the circumstances... You were
great. I just want to say thank you.
You're welcome. I hope we can do it again.
- Fine job, Mr Gambini.
- Thanks.
- Y'all come back and see us any time now.
- I'll see.
- Vin.
- Bill.
- You're welcome.
- Vin, l....
Listen. Take your time, pick the right words,
get back to New York, gimme a call.
- Vinny, you did a terrific job.
- Thanks.
You got an open invitation
any time you come here.
- We can get us a deer next time.
- OK. Thanks a lot.
I feel like if I don't get outta here
now, I might never be able to leave.
Mr Gambini.
I have a fax here from the clerk of New York.
I owe you an apology, sir.
I'm honoured to shake your hand.
"Win some, lose some."
Your courtroom manner may be rather
unconventional, but I gotta tell you,
you're one helluva trial lawyer.
Thank you. And you're one helluva judge.
Sorry.
Bye, now.
What the hell was that all about back there?
I had a friend send a fax to the judge,
confirming the very impressive
legal stature of Jerry Callo.
What friends you got in the clerk's office?
- Your friend.
- My friend?
Judge Malloy.
So what's your problem?
My problem is I wanted to win my first case
without any help from anybody.
Well, I guess that plan's moot.
Yeah.
This could be a sign of things to come.
You win all your cases,
but with somebody else's help, right?
You win case after case,
and then afterwards,
you have to go up to somebody
and you have to say "Thank you."
Oh, my God. What a fuckin' nightmare.
I won my first case.
You know what this means.
- Yeah. You think I'm gonna marry you.
- You're not gonna marry me now?
No way. You can't win a case by
yourself. You're fuckin' useless.
I thought we'd get married this weekend.
You don't get it, do you? That is not
romantic. I want a wedding in church
with bridesmaids and flowers.
How many times did you
say that spontaneous is romantic?
Hey, a burp is spontaneous.
A burp is not romantic.