[Man] ''Once upon a time
there wasa lovelyprincess.
''Butshe hadan enchantment
upon herofa fearfulsort...
''which couldonlybe broken
by love's first kiss.
''She waslockedaway
in a castle...
'guardedbya terrible
fire-breathing dragon.
''Manybrave knightshadattempted
to free herfrom this dreadfulprison,
''but noneprevailed.
''She waitedin
the dragon'skeep...
''in the highest room
ofthe tallest tower...
forhertrue love
andtrue love's first kiss. '''
[ Laughing ]
Like that's ever gonna happen.
- [PaperRustling, Toilet Flushes]
- What a loadof--
Somebodyonce toldme
the worldisgonna rollme
lain 't thesharpest tool
in theshed
She waslookin'kindofdumb
with herfingerandherthumb
ln theshape ofan ''L '''
on herforehead
Theyearsstart comin '
andthey don'tstop comin'
Fedto the rules
andlhit thegroundrunnin'
Didn 't makesense
not to live forfun
Yourbraingets smart
butyourheadgets dumb
So much to do
So much to see
So what's wrong with
takin'the backstreets
You'llneverknow
ifyou don'tgo
You'llnevershine
ifyou don't glow
Hey, now
You're an all-star
Getyourgame on, goplay
Hey, now, you're a rockstar
Get theshowon, getpaid
Andallthat
glitters isgold
Onlyshootin'stars
break the mould
lt'sa coolplace
andtheysay itgets colder
You're bundledup now
but wait tillyouget older
But the meteormen
beg to differ
Judging bythe hole
in thesatellitepicture
The ice we skate
isgettin'prettythin
The water'sgetting warm
soyou might as wellswim
My world's on fire
How 'boutyours
That's the wayllike it
andl'llneverget bored
- Hey, now, you're an all-star
- [ Shouting ]
Getyourgame on, goplay
Hey, now, you're a rockstar
Get theshowon, getpaid
Andallthat
glitters isgold
Onlyshootin'stars
break the mould
[ Belches ]
- Go!
- [RecordScratching]
- Go. Go. Go.
Hey, now
You're an all-star
Getyourgame on, goplay
Hey, now, you're a rockstar
Get theshowon, getpaid
Andallthat
glitters isgold
Onlyshootin'stars
break the mould
- Think it's in there?
- All right. Let's get it!
Whoa. Hold on. Do you know
what that thing can do to you?
Yeah, it'll grind
your bones for its bread.
[Laughs] Yes, well, actually,
that wouldbe agiant.
Now, ogres--
They're much worse.
They'll make a suit
from your freshly peeled skin.
- No!
- They'll shave your liver.
Squeeze thejelly
from your eyes!
- Actually, it's quite good on toast.
- Back! Back, beast!
Back! I warn ya!
- [ Gasping ]
- Right.
[ Roaring ]
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Roaring ]
[ Roaring Continues ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Whispers ] This is the part
where you run away.
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Laughs ]
[Laughing]
And stay out!
''Wanted. Fairy tale creatures.''
[ Sighs ]
[Man's Voice]
Allright. This one's full.
- Take it away!
- [ Gasps ]
- Move it along. Come on! Get up!
- Next!
Give me that!
Your flying days are over.
That's 20 pieces ofsilver
for the witch. Next!
- Get up! Come on!
- Twenty pieces.
- [Thudding]
- Sit down there!
- Keep quiet!
- [Crying]
This cage is too small.
Please don't turn me in.
I'll never be stubborn again.
I can change.
Please! Give me another chance!
- Oh, shut up.
- Oh!
- Next!
- What have you got?
- This little wooden puppet.
I'm not a puppet.
I'm a real boy.
Five shillings
for the possessed toy.
- Take it away.
- Father, please!
Don't let them do this!
- Help me!
- Next. What have you got?
- Well, I've got a talking donkey.
- [ Grunts ]
Right. Well, that's good for
ten shillings, ifyou can prove it.
Oh, go ahead, little fella.
Well?
Oh, oh, he'sjust--
He'sjust a little nervous.
He's really quite a chatterbox.
Talk, you boneheaded dolt--
-That's it. I've heard enough. Guards!
- No, no, he talks!
He does. I can talk.
I love to talk.
I'm the talkingest
damn thing you ever saw.
- Get her out of my sight.
- No, no!
I swear! Oh!
He can talk!
[ Gasps ]
Hey! I can fly!
- He can fly!
- He can talk!
- Ha, ha! That's right, fool!
Now I'm a flying,
talking donkey.
You might have seen a house fly,
maybe even a super fly,
but I bet you ain't
never seen a donkey fly.
Ha, ha!
Uh-oh.
[ Grunts ]
Seize him!
After him!
He's getting away!
[ Grunts, Gasps ]
[Man]
Get him! This way! Turn!
You there. Ogre!
Aye?
By the order of Lord Farquaad,
I am authorized to place
you both under arrest...
and transport you to
a designated... resettlement facility.
Oh, really?
You and what army?
[ Gasps, Whimpering ]
[ Chuckles ]
Can I say something to you?
Listen, you was really, really somethin'
back there. Incredible!
Are you talkin' to--
me? Whoa!
Yes, I was talkin' to you. Can I
tell you that you was great back there?
Those guards!
They thought they was all ofthat.
Then you showed up, and bam!
They was trippin' over themselves
like babes in the woods.
That really made me
feel good to see that.
- Oh, that's great. Really.
- Man, it's good to be free.
Now, why don't you go celebrate your
freedom with your own friends? Hmm?
But, uh, I don't
have any friends.
And I'm not goin'
out there by myself.
Hey, wait a minute! I got
a great idea! I'll stick with you.
You're a mean,
green, fiightin' machine.
Together we'll scare
the spit out ofanybody that crosses us.
[ Roaring ]
Oh, wow!
That was really scary.
lfyou don't mindmesayin ',
ifthat don't work, yourbreath
certainly willget thejob done,
'cause you defiinitely
need some Tic Tacs or something,
'cause your breath stinks!
You almost burnedthe hair
outta mynose,
just like the time--
[ Mumbling ]
Then I ate some rotten berries.
I had strong gases eking out
of my butt that day.
Why are you following me?
I'll tell you why.
'Cause I'm all alone
There's no one here
beside me
Myproblems
have allgone
There's no one
to deride me
But you gotta have friends--
Stop singing!
It's no wonder
you don't have any friends.
Wow. Only a true friend
would be that truly honest.
Listen, little donkey.
Take a look at me. What am I?
Uh--
- Really tall?
- No! I'm an ogre.
You know.
''Grab your torch and pitchforks.''
Doesn't that botheryou?
Nope.
- Really?
- Really, really.
- Oh.
- Man, I like you. What's your name?
Uh, Shrek.
Shrek? Well, you know
what I like about you, Shrek?
You got that kind of
I-don't-care-what-nobody-
thinks-of-me thing.
I like that.
I respect that, Shrek. You all right.
Whoo! Look at that. Who'd want
to live in a place like that?
That would be my home.
Oh! And it is lovely!
Just beautiful.
You are quite a decorator.
It's amazing what you've done
with such a modest budget.
I like that boulder.
That is a nice boulder.
I guess you don't
entertain much, do you?
I like my privacy.
You know, I do too.
That's another thing we have in common.
Like, I hate it when
you got somebody in your face.
You're trying to give them
a hint, and they won't leave.
There's that awkward silence.
- Can I stay with you?
- Uh, what?
Can I stay with you, please?
- Ofcourse!
- Really?
- No.
- Please! I don't wanna go back there!
You don't know what it's like to be
considered a freak. Well, maybe you do.
But that's why we gotta stick together.
You gotta let me stay!
- Please! Please!
- Okay! Okay!
- But one night only.
- Ah! Thankyou!
- What are you-- No! No!
- This is gonna be fun!
We can stay up late,
swappin' manly stories,
and in the mornin'
I'm makin' waffles.
- Oh!
- Where do, uh, I sleep?
Outside!
Oh, well,
I guess that's cool.
I mean, I don't know you,
and you don't know me,
so I guess outside
is best, you know.
[ Sniffles ]
Here I go.
Good night.
[ Sighs ]
lmean, ldo like the outdoors.
l'm a donkey. l wasborn outside.
l'lljust besitting by myself
outside, lguess, you know.
By myself, outside.
l'm allalone
There'sno one here beside me
[ Bubbling ]
[ Sighs ]
[Creaking]
I thought I told you to stay outside.
- I am outside.
- [Clattering]
[Clattering]
Well, gents, it'sa farcryfrom
the farm, but what choice do we have?
It's not home,
but it'll dojust fiine.
What a lovely bed.
- Got ya.
- [ Sniffs ] I found some cheese.
- Ow! [ Grunts ]
- Blah! Awful stuff.
- Is that you, Gorder?
- How did you know?
Enough!
What are you doing in my house?
[ Grunts ]
Hey!
- [ Snickers ]
- Oh, no, no, no.
- Dead broad offthe table.
- Where are we supposed to
put her? The bed's taken.
Huh?
[ Gasps ]
[ Male Voice ]
What?
I live in a swamp. I put up signs.
I'm a terrifying ogre!
What do I have to do
to get a little privacy?
- Aah!
- Oh, no.
Oh, no.
- No! No!
- [ Cackling ]
- [ Cackling Continues ]
- What?
- Quit it.
- Don't push.
- [ Squeaking ]
- [ Lows ]
What are you doing
in my swamp?
[Echoing]
Swamp! Swamp! Swamp!
- [ Gasping ]
- Oh, dear!
Whoa!
All right, get out of here.
All ofyou, move it!
Come on! Let's go!
Hapaya! Hapaya! Hey!
- Quickly. Come on!
- No, no!
No, no.
Not there. Not there.
- Oh!
- [ Sighs ]
Hey, don't look at me.
I didn't invite them.
Oh, gosh, no one invited us.
- What?
- We were forced to come here.
- By who?
- LordFarquaad.
He huffed und he puffed und he...
signed an eviction notice.
[ Sighs ]
All right.
Who knows where
this Farquaad guy is?
- [ Murmuring ]
- Oh, I do. I know where he is.
Does anyone else
know where to fiind him?
- Anyone at all?
- Me! Me!
- Anyone?
- Oh! Oh, pick me!
Oh, I know!
I know! Me, me!
[ Sighs ]
Okay, fiine.
Attention,
all fairy tale things.
Do not get comfortable.
Your welcome is offiicially worn out.
In fact, I'm gonna see
this guy Farquaad right now...
and get you all off my land
and back where you came from!
[ Cheering ]
- [ Twittering ]
- [ Cheering Continues ]
Oh! You!
You're comin' with me.
All right, that's
what I like to hear, man.
Shrek and Donkey, two stalwart friends,
offon a whirlwind big-city adventure.
I love it!
-  On the road again
Sing it with me, Shrek.
- Hey. Oh, oh!
I can't wait to get
on the road again
What did I say
about singing?
- Can I whistle?
- No.
- Can I hum it?
- All right, hum it.
[ Humming ]
[ Grunts ]
[Whimpering]
That's enough.
He's ready to talk.
[Coughing]
[ Laughing ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Run, run, run,
as fast as you can.
You can't catch me.
I'm the gingerbread man!
- You're a monster.
- I'm not the monster here. You are.
You and the rest ofthat fairy tale
trash, poisoning my perfect world.
Now, tell me!
Where are the others?
- Eat me!
- [ Grunts ]
I've tried to be fair
to you creatures.
Now my patience has reached its end!
Tell me or I'll--
No, no, not the buttons.
Not my gumdrop buttons.
All right then.
Who's hiding them?
Okay, I'll tell you.
Do you know the muffiin man?
- The muffiin man?
- The muffiin man.
Yes, I know the muffiin man,
who lives on Drury Lane?
Well, she's married
to the muffiin man.
- The muffiin man?
- The muffiin man!
- She's married to the muffiin man.
- [DoorOpens]
My lord! We found it.
Then what are you waiting for?
Bring it in.
[Man Grunting]
- [ Gasping ]
- Oh!
- Magic mirror--
- Don't tell him anything!
No!
- [GingerbreadMan Whimpers]
- Evening.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Is this not the most
perfect kingdom ofthem all?
Well, technically
you're not a king.
Uh, Thelonius.
- You were saying?
- What I mean is, you're not a king yet.
But you can become one. All
you have to do is marry a princess.
- Go on.
- [ Chuckles ]
So, just sit back
and relax, my lord,
because it's time foryou to
meet today's eligible bachelorettes.
And here they are!
Bachelorette numberone
isa mentallyabusedshut-in
from a kingdom far, faraway.
She likessushi
andhot tubbinganytime.
Herhobbies include cooking
andcleaning forhertwo evilsisters.
Please welcome Cinderella.
Bachelorette numbertwo
isa cape-wearinggirl
from the landoffancy.
Although she lives with
seven othermen, she'snot easy.
Just kissherdead, frozen lips
andfindout what a live wire she is.
Come on.
Give it up forSnow White!
Andlast,
but certainlynot least,
bachelorette numberthree
isa fieryredhead...
from a dragon-guardedcastle
surroundedbyhot boiling lava!
But don't let that coolyou off.
She'sa loadedpistol
who likespina coladas
andgetting caught in the rain.
Yours forthe rescuing,
Princess Fiona!
So willit be
bachelorette numberone,
bachelorette numbertwo
orbachelorette numberthree?
- Two! Two!
- Three! Three!
- Three!
Three? One?
[ Shudders ] Three?
Three!
Pick number three, my lord!
Okay, okay, uh, number three!
Lord Farquaad,
you've chosen Princess Fiona.
lfyou lovepina coladas
- Andgetting caught in the rain
- Princess Fiona.
- lfyou're not intoyoga
- She's perfect.
All I have to do is
just fiind someone who can go--
But I probably should mention
the little thing that happens at night.
- I'll do it.
- Yes, but after sunset--
Silence! I will make
this Princess Fiona my queen,
andDuLoc willfinally
have theperfect king!
Captain, assemble
your fiinest men.
We're going to have
a tournament.
But that's it. That's it
right there. That's DuLoc.
I told ya I'd fiind it.
So, that must be
Lord Farquaad's castle.
[Donkey]
Uh-huh. That's theplace.
Do you think maybe
he's compensating for something?
[ Laughs ]
[ Groans ]
Hey, wait.
Wait up, Shrek.
Hurry, darling.
We're late. Hurry.
- Hey, you!
- [ Screams ]
Wait a second.
Look, l'm notgonna eatya.
- I just-- I just--
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Whimpering, Groans ]
[Turnstile Clatters]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Instrumental Muzak ]
It's quiet.
Too quiet.
[ Creaking ]
- Where is everybody?
- Hey, look at this!
[Clattering, Whirring,
Clicking]
[Clicking]
[Clicking Quickens]
Welcome to DuLoc
such a perfect town
Here we have some rules
Let us lay them down
Don't make waves, stay in line
and we'llget along fine
DuLoc is a perfect place
Please keep offofthe grass
Shine your shoes, wipe your... face
DuLoc is, DuLoc is
DuLoc is a perfect
-  Place
- [Camera ShutterClicks]
[ Whirring ]
Wow! Let's do that again!
No. No.
No, no, no! No.
[Trumpet Fanfare]
- [Crowd Cheering]
- [Farquaad] Brave knights.
- You are the best andbrightest
in allthe land.
- [DonkeyHumming]
Todayone ofyou
shallprove himself--
All right. You're going the right way
for a smacked bottom.
- Sorry about that.
- [Cheering]
That champion shall have the honour--
no, no-- the privilege...
to go forth and rescue
the lovely Princess Fiona...
from the fiiery keep
ofthe dragon.
lfforany reason
the winneris unsuccessful,
the fiirst runner-up
will take his place...
and so on and so forth.
Some ofyou may die, but it's
a sacrifiice I am willing to make.
[Cheering]
Let the tournament begin!
- [ Gasps ]
- Oh!
- What is that?
- [ Gasping ]
- It's hideous!
- Ah, that's not very nice.
- It'sjust a donkey.
- Huh?
Indeed. Knights, new plan!
The one who kills the ogre willbe
namedchampion! Have at him!
- Get him!
- Oh, hey! Now come on! Hang on now.
[ Woman ]
Go ahead! Get him!
Can't wejust settle this
over a pint?
[Man]
Killthe beast!
No? All right then.
Come on!
ldon't give a damn
about my reputation
- You're living in thepast
lt'sa newgeneration
- Damn!
- [ Whinnying ]
- A girlcan do
whatshe wants to do
Andthat's what
l'mgonna do
Andldon't give a damn
about mybadreputation
Oh, no, no, no, no, no
Not me
-Me, me, me
- Hey, Shrek, tag me! Tag me!
Andldon't give a damn
about my reputation
Neversaidl wanted
to improve mystation
Ah!
[ Laughs ]
- Andl'm always feelin'good
when l'm having fun
- Yeah!
Andldon't have
toplease no one
The chair!
Give him the chair!
Andldon't give a damn
about mybadreputation
Oh, no, no, no, no, no
Not me
Me, me, me
Oh, no, no, no, no
Not me, not me
- Not me
- [BellDings]
- [ Cheering ]
- [ Laughs ]
Oh, yeah! Ah! Ah!
Thankyou!
Thankyou verymuch!
I'm here till Thursday.
Try the veal! Ha, ha!
- [ShrekLaughs]
- [CrowdGasping, Murmuring]
Shall I give
the order, sir?
No, I have a better idea.
People of DuLoc,
I give you our champion!
- What?
- Congratulations, ogre.
You've won the honour of
embarking on a great and noble quest.
Quest? I'm already on a quest,
a quest to get my swamp back.
- Your swamp?
- Yeah, my swamp!
Where you dumped
those fairy tale creatures!
- [CrowdMurmuring]
- Indeed.
All right, ogre,
I'll make you a deal.
Go on this quest for me, and
I'll give you your swamp back.
Exactly the way it was?
Down to the last
slime-covered toadstool.
- And the squatters?
- As good as gone.
What kind ofquest?
[ Donkey ] Let me get this straight.
You're gonna go fiight a dragon...
and rescue a princessjust so Farquaad
will give you back a swamp...
which you only don't have
because he fiilled it full of
freaks in the fiirst place.
- Is that about right?
- Maybe there's a good reason
donkeys shouldn't talk.
I don't get it. Why don't you just
pull some ofthat ogre stuffon him?
Throttle him,
lay siege to his fortress,
grind his bones to make your bread,
the whole ogre trip.
Oh, I know what.
Maybe I could have
decapitated an entire village...
and put their heads
on a pike,
gotten a knife, cut open their
spleen and drink their fluids.
Does that sound
good to you?
Uh, no, not really, no.
Foryour information, there's a lot
more to ogres than people think.
- Example?
- Okay, um, ogres are like onions.
- [ Sniffs ] They stink?
- Yes-- No!
- They make you cry?
- No!
You leave them out in the sun,
they get all brown, start
sproutin' little white hairs.
No! Layers!
Onions have layers.
Ogres have layers!
You get it? We both have layers.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, you both
have layers. Oh.
[ Sniffs ]
You know, not everybody likes onions.
Cake! Everybody loves cakes!
Cakes have layers.
I don't care...
what everyone likes.
Ogres are not like cakes.
You know what else
everybody likes? Parfaits.
Have you ever met a person, you
say, ''Let's get some parfait,''
they say, ''No,
I don't like no parfait''?
- Parfaits are delicious.
- No!
You dense, irritating,
miniature beast ofburden!
Ogres are like onions!
End ofstory.
Bye-bye. See ya later.
Parfaits may be the most delicious thing
on the whole damn planet.
You know, I think
I preferred your humming.
Doyou have a tissue orsomething?
l'm makinga mess.
Just the wordparfait
make mestartslobbering.
l'm on my way from misery
to happiness today
Uh-huh, uh-huh
l'm on my way from misery
to happiness today
Uh-huh, uh-huh
Andeverything
thatyou receive upyonder
ls whatyougive to me
the dayl wander
l'm on my way
Ooh! Shrek!
Did you do that?
You gotta warn somebody before you
just crack one off. My mouth was open.
Believe me, Donkey, if
it was me, you'd be dead.
[ Sniffs ]
It's brimstone.
- We must be getting close.
- Yeah, right, brimstone.
Don't be talking about it's
the brimstone. I know what I
smell. It wasn't no brimstone.
It didn't come off
no stone neither.
[Rumbling]
Sure, it's big enough,
but look at the location.
[ Laughing ]
Uh, Shrek? Uh, remember when
you said ogres have layers?
Oh, aye.
Well, I have a bit
ofa confession to make.
Donkeys don't have layers. We wear
our fear right out there on our sleeves.
- Wait a second.
Donkeys don't have sleeves.
- You know what I mean.
You can't tell me
you're afraid of heights.
I'm just a little uncomfortable
about being on a rickety bridge
over a boiling lake of lava!
Come on, Donkey.
l'm right here besideya, okay?
For emotional support,
we'll just tackle this thing
together one little baby step at a time.
- Really?
- Really, really.
- Okay, that makes me
feel so much better.
-Just keep moving.
- And don't look down.
- Okay, don't look down.
Don't look down.
Keep on moving. Don't look down.
[ Gasps ]
Shrek! I'm lookin' down!
Oh, God, I can't do this!
Just let me off, please!
- But you're already halfway.
- But I know that half is safe!
Okay, fiine. I don't
have time for this. You go back.
- Shrek, no! Wait!
-Just, Donkey--
- Let's have a dance then, shall we?
- Don't do that!
Oh, I'm sorry. Do what?
- Oh, this?
- Yes, that!
Yes? Yes, do it. Okay.
[ Screams ]
No, Shrek!
- No! Stop it!
- You said do it! I'm doin' it.
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die.
Shrek, I'm gonna die.
Oh!
That'll do, Donkey.
That'll do.
Cool.
[ Donkey ] So where is this
fiire-breathing pain-in-the-neck anyway?
Inside, waiting for us
to rescue her.
[ Chuckles ]
I was talkin' about the dragon, Shrek.
[WaterDripping]
[WindHowling]
[ Donkey Whispering ]
You afraid?
No, but-- Shh.
Oh, good. Me neither.
[ Gasps ]
'Cause there's nothin'
wrong with bein' afraid.
Fear's a sensible response
to an unfamiliar situation.
Unfamiliar dangerous
situation, I might add.
With a dragon that breathes fiire
and eats knights and breathes fiire,
it sure doesn't mean you're a coward
ifyou're a little scared.
I sure as heck ain't no coward.
I know that. [ Gasps ]
Donkey, two things, okay?
Shut... up.
Now go over there and see
ifyou can fiind any stairs.
Stairs? I thought
we was lookin' for the princess.
The princess will be up the stairs in
the highest room in the tallest tower.
- What makes you think she'll be there?
- I read it in a book once.
Cool. You handle the dragon.
I'll handle the stairs.
I'll fiind those stairs.
I'll whip their butt too.
Those stairs won't know
which way they're goin'.
[ Creaking ]
I'm gonna take drastic steps.
Kick it to the kerb. Don't mess
with me. I'm the stair master.
I've mastered the stairs.
I wish I had a step right here.
I'd step all over it.
Well, at least we know
where the princess is, but where's the--
Dragon!
[ Screams ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Roars ]
Donkey, look out!
[ Screams ]
[ Whimpering ]
- Got ya!
- [ Roars ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Shouts ]
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh! Aah! Aah!
[ Gasping ]
[ Growls ]
No. Oh, no. No!
[ Screams ]
- Oh, what large teeth you have.
- [ Growls ]
I mean, white, sparkling teeth.
I know you probably hear this
all the time from your food,
but you must bleach, 'cause that
is one dazzling smile you got there.
Do I detect a hint
of minty freshness?
And you know what else?
You're-- You're a girl dragon!
Oh, sure! I mean,
ofcourse you're a girl dragon.
You'rejust reeking
offeminine beauty.
What's the matter with you?
You got something in your eye?
Ooh. Oh. Oh.
Man, I'd really love to stay,
but, you know, I'm, uh-- [ Coughs ]
I'm an asthmatic, and
I don't know if it'd work out if
you're gonna blow smoke rings.
Shrek!
[ Gasps ]
[ Whimpering ]
No! Shrek! Shrek!
Shrek!
[ Groans, Sighs ]
[Chorus Vocalizing]
[ Vocalizing Continues]
Oh! Oh!
- Wake up!
- What?
Are you Princess Fiona?
I am, awaiting a knight
so bold as to rescue me.
Oh, that's nice.
Now let's go!
But wait, Sir Knight.
This be-ith our fiirst meeting.
Should it not be
a wonderful, romantic moment?
- Yeah, sorry, lady. There's no time.
- Hey, wait. What areyou doing?
You should sweep me
off my feet...
out yonder window and down a rope
onto your valiant steed.
You've had a lot oftime
to plan this, haven't you?
Mm-hmm.
[ Screams, Grunts ]
But we have to
savour this moment!
You could recite
an epic poem for me.
A ballad? A sonnet!
- A limerick? Or something!
- I don't think so.
Can I at least know
the name of my champion?
Um, Shrek.
Sir Shrek.
[ Clears Throat ]
I pray that you take this favour
as a token of my gratitude.
Thanks!
[Roaring]
You didn't slay the dragon?
- It's on my to-do list. Now come on!
- [ Screams ]
But this isn't right!
You were meant to charge in,
sword drawn, banner flying.
That's what all
the other knights did.
Yeah, right before
theyburst into flame.
That's not the point. Oh!
Wait. Where are you going?
The exit's over there.
Well, I have to save my ass.
What kind of knight are you?
One ofa kind.
[Donkey]
Slowdown. Slowdown, baby, please.
lbelieve it'shealthytoget to
knowsomeone overa longperiodoftime.
Just callme old-fashioned.
[Laughs]
I don't want to rush into
a physical relationship.
I'm not emotionally ready
for a commitment of, uh, this--
Magnitude really is
the word I'm looking for.
Magnitude-- Hey, that is
unwanted physical contact.
Hey, what are you doing?
Okay, okay. Let'sjust back up a little
andtake this onestep at a time.
We reallyshouldget to knoweach other
first asfriends orpenpals.
l'm on the roada lot,
but ljust love receiving cards--
I'd really love
to stay, but--
Don't do that! That's my tail!
That's my personal tail.
You're gonna tear it off.
I don't give permission-- What
are you gonna do with that?
Hey, now. No way.
No! No!
No, no! No.
No, no, no! No! Oh!
[ Growls ]
[ Roars ]
- [Roaring]
- [ Gasps ]
- Hi, Princess!
- It talks!
Yeah, it's getting him
to shut up that's the trick.
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
Oh!
- [Thuds]
- [ Groans ]
[ Shrek Groans ]
[ Roars ]
[ Roaring ]
Okay, you two,
head for the exit!
I'll take care ofthe dragon.
[ Echoing ]
Run!
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Roaring ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Roars ]
[ Panting, Sighs ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Roars ]
[ Roars, Whimpers ]
- [Dragon Growling ln The Distance]
- You did it!
You rescued me!
You're amazing. You're--
You're wonderful. You're...
a little unorthodox I'll admit.
But thy deed is great,
and thine heart is pure.
- I am eternally in your debt.
- [ Clears Throat ]
And where would a brave knight be
without his noble steed?
I hope you heard that. She called me
a noble steed. She think I'm a steed.
[Fiona Laughs]
The battle is won.
You may remove your helmet,
good Sir Knight.
- Uh, no.
- Why not?
I have helmet hair.
Please. I would'st look
upon the face of my rescuer.
No, no, you wouldn't-- 'st.
But how will you kiss me?
What? That wasn't
in thejob description.
Maybe it's a perk.
No, it's destiny.
Oh, you must know how it goes.
A princess locked in a tower
and beset by a dragon...
is rescued by a brave knight,
and then they share
true love's fiirst kiss.
Hmm? With Shrek?
You think-- Wait.
Wait. You think that
Shrek is your true love?
Well, yes.
- [ Laughing ]
You think Shrek
is your true love!
What is so funny?
Let'sjust say I'm
not your type, okay?
Ofcourse, you are.
You're my rescuer.
Now-- Now remove your helmet.
Look. I really don't think
this is a good idea.
-Just take offthe helmet.
- I'm not going to.
- Take it off.
- No!
- Now!
- Okay!
Easy. As you command,
Your Highness.
You-- You're a-- an ogre.
Oh, you were expecting
Prince Charming.
Well, yes, actually.
Oh, no. This is all wrong.
You're not supposed
to be an ogre.
[ Sighs ] Princess, I was sent
to rescue you by Lord Farquaad, okay?
He's the one
who wants to marry you.
Then why didn't
he come rescue me?
Good question. You should
ask him that when we get there.
But I have to be rescued
by my true love,
not by some ogre
and his-- his pet.
So much for noble steed.
You're not making
myjob any easier.
I'm sorry, but yourjob
is not my problem.
You can tell Lord Farquaad
that if he wants to rescue me properly,
I'll be waiting for him
right here.
Hey! I'm no one's messenger boy,
all right? I'm a delivery boy.
You wouldn't dare.
- Put me down!
- Ya comin', Donkey?
I'm right behind ya.
Put me down, oryou will
suffer the consequences!
This is not dignifiied!
Put me down! [ Screams ]
Okay, so here's
anotherquestion.
Say there's a woman
that digs you, right, but you
don't really like her that way.
How do you let her down real easy
so her feelings aren't hurt,
but you don't get burned
to a crisp and eaten?
You just tell her
she's not your true love.
Everyone knowest what happens
when you fiind your--
Hey!
[ Sighs ]
The sooner we get
to DuLoc the better.
You're gonna love it there,
Princess. It's beautiful!
And what of my groom-to-be?
Lord Farquaad? What's he like?
Let me put it this way,
Princess.
Men of Farquaad's stature
are in short supply.
[ Laughs ]
I don't know. There are those who
think little of him.
[ Both Laughing ]
Stop it. Stop it,
both ofyou.
You'rejustjealous you can
never measure up to a great
ruler like Lord Farquaad.
Yeah, well, maybe
you're right, Princess.
But I'll let you do the ''measuring''
when you see him tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
It'll take that long?
- Shouldn't we stop to make camp?
- No, that'll take longer.
- We can keep going.
- But there's robbers in the woods.
Whoa! Time out, Shrek!
Camping's starting to sound good.
Hey, come on.
I'm scarier than anything we're
going to see in this forest.
I need to fiind
somewhere to camp now!
[Bird Wings Fluttering]
[ Grunting ]
- Hey! Over here.
- Shrek, we can do better than that.
I don't think
this is fiit for a princess.
No, no, it's perfect.
Itjust needs a few homey touches.
- Homey touches? Like what?
- [Crashing]
A door? Well, gentlemen,
I bid thee good night.
You want me to read you
a bedtime story? I will.
lsaidgoodnight!
Shrek, what are you doing?
[ Laughs ]
I just-- You know-- Oh, come on.
I wasjust kidding.
[Fire Crackling]
And, uh, that one,
that's Throwback,
the only ogre to everspit
overthree wheat fields.
Right. Yeah.
Hey, can you tell my future
from these stars?
The stars don't tell the future, Donkey.
They tell stories.
Look, there's Bloodnut,
the Flatulent.
- You can guess what he's famous for.
- I know you're making this up.
No, look.
There he is,
and there's the group of hunters
running away from his stench.
That ain't nothin' but
a bunch of little dots.
Sometimes things are
more than they appear.
Hmm?
Forget it.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Shrek, what we gonna do
when we get our swamp anyway?
Our swamp?
You know, when we're through
rescuing the princess.
We? Donkey, there's no ''we.''
There's no ''our.''
There'sjust me and my swamp.
The fiirst thing I'm gonna do is build
a ten-foot wall around my land.
You cut me deep, Shrek.
You cut me real deep just now.
You know what I think?
I think this whole wall thing
isjust a way to keep somebody out.
- No, do ya think?
- Are you hidin' something?
Never mind, Donkey.
Oh, this is another one of
those onion things, isn't it?
No, this is one ofthose drop-it
and leave-it-alone things.
- Why don't you want to talk about it?
- Why do you want to?
- Why are you blocking?
- I'm not blocking.
- Oh, yes, you are.
- Donkey, I'm warning you.
- Who you trying to keep out?
- Everyone! Okay?
Oh, now we're gettin' somewhere.
Oh! For the love of Pete!
What's your problem?
What you got against the whole world?
I'm not the one
with the problem, okay?
It's the world that seems
to have a problem with me.
People take one look at me
and go, ''Aah! Help! Run!
A big, stupid, ugly ogre!''
[ Sighs ] Theyjudge me before
they even know me.
That's why
I'm better offalone.
You know what?
When we met, I didn't thinkyou was
just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
Yeah, I know.
So, uh, are there
any donkeys up there?
Well, there's, um, Gabby,
the Small and Annoying.
Okay, I see it now. The big shiny
one, right there. That one there?
- That's the moon.
- Oh, okay.
[Orchestra]
[Dulcimer]
[Farquaad]
Again. Showme again.
[Music Stops, Rewinds]
Mirror, mirror, show her to me.
Show me the princess.
- Hmph.
-  [ Rewinds, Resumes ]
Ah. Perfect.
[ Inhales ]
[Snoring]
[ Vocalizing ]
[ Vocalizing Continues]
[ Whistling ]
[Whistling Continues]
-  [ Vocalizes ]
-  [ Whistles ]
-  [ Vocalizing ]
-  [ Whistling ]
-  [ Vocalizing, High-pitched ]
-  [ Whistling, High-pitched ]
[Continues]
[ Sizzling ]
[ Sniffs, Yawns ]
Mmm, yeah, you know
llike it like that.
- Come on, baby. I said I like it.
- Donkey, wake up.
- Huh? What?
- Wake up.
- What?
- Goodmorning.
How do you like your eggs?
- Good morning, Princess!
- What's all this about?
We kind of got off
to a bad start yesterday.
I wanted to make it up to you.
After all, you did rescue me.
- Uh, thanks.
- [ Sniffs ]
Well, eat up.
We'vegot a big dayaheadofus.
- [ Belches ]
- Shrek!
What? It's a compliment.
Better out than in,
I always say. [ Laughs ]
- Well, it's no way to behave
in front ofa princess.
- [ Belches ]
- Thanks.
- She's as nasty as you are.
[ Laughs ] You know,
you're not exactly what I expected.
Maybe you shouldn'tjudge people
before you get to know them.
[ Vocalizing]
[Man]
La liberte! Hey!
Princess!
- [ Laughs ]
- What are you doing?
Be still, mon cherie,
for I am your saviour!
And I am rescuing you from this green--
[ Kissing Sounds ]
- beast.
- Hey!
That's my princess!
Go fiind your own!
Please, monster!
Can't you see I'm a little busy here?
Look, pal, I don't know
who you thinkyou are!
Oh! Ofcourse!
Oh, how rude.
Please let me
introduce myself.
Oh, Merry Men!
[ Laughs ]
[Accordion]
Ta, dah, dah, dah, whoo
I steal from the rich
and give to the needy
-  He takes a wee percentage
-  But I'm not greedy
I rescue pretty damsels
Man, I'm good
-  What a guy, Monsieur Hood
- Break it down.
I like an honest fiight
and a saucy little maid
-  What he's basically saying
is he likes to get--
-  Paid
-  So
-  When an ogre in the bush
grabs a lady by the tush
-  That's bad
When a beauty's with a beast
it makesme awfullymad
He's mad
He's really, really mad
I'll take my blade and
ram it through your heart
Keep your eyes on me, boys
'cause I'm about to start
[ Grunts, Groans ]
- [ Karate Yell ]
- [ Merry Men Gasping ]
[Panting]
Man, that wasannoying!
Oh, you little--
[ Karate Yell ]
[ Accordion ]
[ Shouting, Groaning ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Chuckles ]
Um, shall we?
- Hold the phone.
- [ Grunts ]
Oh! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on now.
- Where did that come from?
- What?
That! Back there.
That was amazing!
Where didyou learn that?
Well-- [ Chuckles ]
When one lives alone,
uh, one has to learn these things
in case there's a--
- There's an arrow in your butt!
- What?
- Oh, would you look at that?
- Oh, no. This is all my fault.
- I'm so sorry.
- Why? What's wrong?
- Shrek's hurt.
- Shrek's hurt. Shrek's hurt?
Oh, no, Shrek's gonna die.
- Donkey, I'm okay.
- You can't do this to me.
I'm too young foryou to die.
Keep your legs elevated.
Turn your head and cough.
- Does anyone know the Heimlich?
- Donkey! Calm down.
Ifyou want to help Shrek,
run into the woods and fiind me
a blue flower with red thorns.
Blue flower, red thorns. Okay,
I'm on it. Blue flower, red thorns.
Don't die, Shrek. Ifyou see
a long tunnel, stay away from the light!
- [ Both ] Donkey!
- Oh, yeah. Right.
Blue flower, red thorns.
- Blue flower, redthorns.
- What are the flowers for?
- For getting rid of Donkey.
- Ah.
Now you hold still,
and I'll yank this thing out.
Ow! Hey!
Easy with the yankin'.
- I'm sorry, but it has to come out.
- No, it's tender.
Now, hold on.
- What you're doing
is the opposite of help.
- Don't move.
- Look, time out.
- Would you--
[ Grunts ]
Okay. What do you propose we do?
Blue flower, red thorns.
This would be so much easier
if I wasn't colour-blind!
- Blue flower, red thorns.
- [Shrek] Ow!
Hold on, Shrek!
I'm comin'!
Ow! Not good.
-Okay. Okay, I can nearly see the head.
-[ Grunts ]
- It'sjust about--
- Ow! Ohh!
Ahem.
Nothing happened.
We werejust, uh--
Look, ifyou wanted to be alone,
all you had to do was ask.
Oh, come on!
That's the last thing on my mind.
The princess here
wasjust-- Ugh!
- Ow!
- Hey, what's that?
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
That's-- Is that blood?
[ Sighs ]
[Bird Chirping]
[ Grunts ]
Mybelovedmonsterandme
Wego everywhere together
Wearin'a raincoat
that hasfoursleeves
-  Gets us through allkinds
ofweather
- Aah!
She willalwaysbe
the onlything
That comesbetween me
andthe awfulsting
That comes from living in a world
that'sso damn mean
[ Croaks ]
Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Hey!
- La-la, la-la, la-la-la-la
- [ Both Laughing ]
La-la, la-la, la-la
There it is, Princess.
Your future awaits you.
- That's DuLoc?
- Yeah, I know.
You know, Shrek thinks Lord Farquaad's
compensating for something,
which I think means
he has a really-- Ow!
Um, I, uh--
- I guess we better move on.
- Sure.
But, Shrek?
- I'm-- I'm worried about Donkey.
- [ Blubbering ]
- What?
- I mean, look at him.
- He doesn't look so good.
- What are you talking about? I'm fiine.
That's what they always say,
and then next thing you know,
you're on your back.
- Dead.
- You know, she's right.
You look awful.
Do you want to sit down?
- I'll make you some tea.
- I didn't want to say nothin',
but I got this twinge in my neck,
and when I turn my head like this, look.
- [ Bones Crunch ]
- Ow! See?
-Who's hungry? I'll fiind us some dinner.
-I'll get the fiirewood.
Hey, where you goin'?
Oh, man, I can't feel my toes!
I don't have any toes!
I think I need a hug.
Mmm.
Mmm. This is good.
This is really good.
- What is this?
- Uh, weedrat.
Rotisserie style.
No kidding.
Well, this is delicious.
Well, they're also great
in stews.
Now, I don't mean to brag,
but I make a mean weedrat stew.
[ Chuckling ]
[Sighs] lguessl'llbe dining
a little differentlytomorrownight.
[ Gulps ] Maybe you can
come visit me in the swamp sometime.
I'll cook all kinds
ofstuff foryou.
Swamp toad soup, fiish eye tartare--
you name it.
[ Chuckles ]
I'd like that.
[ Slurps, Laughs ]
See thepyramids
along the Nile
Um, Princess?
-  Watch thesunrise
from a tropic isle
- Yes, Shrek?
- I, um, I was wondering.
- Just remember, darling
allthe while
Are you--
You belong to me
[ Sighs ]
Are you gonna eat that?
[ Chuckles ]
- Man, isn't this romantic?
Just look at that sunset.
- Sunset?
Oh, no!
I mean, it's late.
- I-It's very late.
- What?
Wait a minute.
I see what's goin' on here.
- You're afraid ofthe dark, aren't you?
- Yes!
Yes, that's it. I'm terrifiied.
You know, I'd better go inside.
Don't feel bad, Princess. I used to
be afraid ofthe dark, too, until--
Hey, no, wait.
I'm still afraid ofthe dark.
- [ShrekSighs]
- Good night.
Good night.
- [ Door Creaks ]
- [Donkey] Ohh!
Now I really see
what's goin' on here.
Oh, what are you
talkin' about?
I don't even wanna hear it. Look,
I'm an animal, and I got instincts.
I know you two were diggin'
on each other. I could feel it.
You're crazy.
I'm just bringing her back to Farquaad.
Oh, come on, Shrek.
Wake up and smell the pheromones.
-Just go on in
and tell her how you feel.
- I--
There's nothing to tell.
Besides, even if I did tell her that,
well, you know--
and I'm not sayin' I do
'cause I don't--
she's a princess,
and I'm--
An ogre?
Yeah. An ogre.
- Hey, where you goin'?
- To get... more fiirewood.
[ Sighs ]
Princess?
Princess Fiona?
Princess, where are you?
[Wings Fluttering]
Princess?
- [Creaking]
- [ Gasps ]
It's very spooky in here.
I ain't playing no games.
[ Screams ]
- Aah!
- Oh, no!
- No, help!
- Shh!
- Shrek! Shrek! Shrek!
- No, it's okay. It's okay.
- What did you do with the princess?
- Donkey, I'm the princess.
- Aah!
- It's me, in this body.
Oh, my God!
You ate the princess!
- Can you hear me?
- Donkey!
- Listen, keep breathing!
I'll get you out ofthere!
- No!
- Shrek! Shrek! Shrek!
- Shh.
- Shrek!
- This is me.
[ Muffled Mumbling ]
Princess?
What happened to you?
You're, uh, uh,
uh, different.
- I'm ugly, okay?
- Well, yeah!
Was it something you ate? 'Cause
I told Shrek those rats was a bad idea.
- You are what you eat, I said. Now--
- No.
I-- I've been this way
as long as I can remember.
What do you mean? Look,
I ain't never seen you like this before.
It only happens
when the sun goes down.
''By night one way,
by day another.
''This shall be the norm...
''until you fiind
true love's fiirst kiss...
and then
take love's true form.''
Ah, that's beautiful.
I didn't know you wrote poetry.
It's a spell.
[ Sighs ]
When I was a little girl,
a witch cast a spell
on me.
Every night I become this.
This horrible, ugly beast!
I was placed in a tower to await the day
my true love would rescue me.
That's why I have to marry
Lord Farquaad tomorrow...
before the sun sets
and he sees me...
like this.
[ Sobs ]
All right, all right. Calm down.
Look, it's not that bad.
You're not that ugly.
Well, I ain't gonna lie. You are ugly.
But you only look like this at night.
Shrek's ugly 24-7.
But, Donkey,
I'm a princess,
and this is not how a princess
is meant to look.
Princess, how 'bout ifyou
don't marry Farquaad?
I have to.
Only my true love's kiss
can break the spell.
But, you know, um,
you're kind ofan ogre,
and Shrek-- well,
you got a lot in common.
Shrek?
Princess, I--
Uh, how's it going, fiirst ofall?
Good?
Um, good for me too.
I'm okay.
I saw this flower and thought ofyou
because it's pretty and--
well, I don't really like it,
but I thought you might like it
'cause you're pretty.
But I like you anyway.
I'd-- uh, uh--
[ Sighs ]
I'm in trouble.
Okay, here we go.
[Fiona]
lcan'tjust marry whoeverl want.
Take agoodlook
at me, Donkey.
lmean, really,
who couldeverlove a beast
so hideousandugly?
''Princess'''and ''ugly'''
don'tgo together.
- That's whylcan't
stayhere with Shrek.
- [ Gasps ]
Myonlychance to live happily
everafteris to marry mytrue love.
- [ Deep Sigh ]
- Don'tyousee, Donkey?
That'sjust how
it has to be.
lt's the only way
to break thespell.
- You at least gotta
tell Shrek the truth.
- No!
You can't breathe a word.
No one must ever know.
What's the point of being able to talk
ifyou gotta keep secrets?
Promise you won't tell.
Promise!
All right, all right.
I won't tell him. But you should.
I just know before this is over,
I'm gonna need a whole lot
ofserious therapy.
- Look at my eye twitchin'.
- [DoorOpens]
[ Snoring ]
[Fiona]
ltellhim, ltellhim not.
I tell him,
I tell him not.
I tell him.
Shrek!
Shrek, there's something
I want--
[ Snoring ]
Shrek.
- Are you all right?
- Perfect!
Never been better.
I-- I don't--
There's something I have to tell you.
You don't have to tell me
anything, Princess.
- I heard enough last night.
- You heard what I said?
Every word.
I thought you'd understand.
Oh, I understand.
Like you said, ''Who could
love a hideous, ugly beast?''
But I thought that
wouldn't matter to you.
Yeah? Well, it does.
[ Gasps, Sighs ]
- Ah, right on time.
- [Horse Whinnies]
Princess, I've brought you
a little something.
[Fanfare]
[ Yawns ]
What'd I miss? What'd I miss?
[ Muffled ] Who said that?
Couldn't have been a donkey.
Princess Fiona.
As promised.
Now hand it over.
Very well, ogre. The deed
toyourswamp, clearedout, asagreed.
Take it and go
before I change my mind.
Forgive me, Princess,
forstartlingyou,
but you startled me,
for I have never seen
such a radiant beauty before.
I am Lord Farquaad.
Lord Farquaad?
Oh, no, no.
- [ Snaps Fingers ]
- Forgive me, my lord,
for I wasjust saying...
a short... farewell.
That is so sweet. You don't have
to waste good manners on the ogre.
It's not like
it has feelings.
No, you're right.
It doesn't.
Princess Fiona, beautiful, fair,
flawless Fiona.
- I askyour hand in marriage.
- [ Gasps ]
Will you be the perfect bride
for the perfect groom?
Lord Farquaad, I accept.
Nothing would make--
Excellent! I'll start the plans,
for tomorrow we wed!
No! I mean, uh,
why wait?
Let's get married today
before the sun sets.
Oh, anxious, are we?
You're right.
The sooner, the better.
There's so much to do!
There's the caterer,
the cake, the band, the guest list.
Captain, round up
some guests!
[ Fiona ]
Fare-thee-well, ogre.
Shrek, what are you doing?
You're letting her get away.
- Yeah? So what?
- Shrek, there's something
about heryou don't know.
Look, I talked to her
last night. She's--
I know you talked to her last night.
You're great pals, aren't ya?
Now, ifyou two are such good friends,
why don't you follow her home?
Shrek, I--
I wanna go with you.
I told you, didn't I?
You're not coming home with me.
I live alone!
My swamp! Me! Nobody else!
Understand? Nobody!
Especially useless, pathetic,
annoying, talking donkeys!
- But I thought--
- Yeah. You know what?
You thought wrong!
Shrek.
lheardthere was
a secret chord
That Davidplayed
anditpleasedthe Lord
Butyou don't really
care formusic, doya
ltgoes like this
the fourth, the fifth
The minorfall
the majorlift
The baffledking
composinghallelujah
Hallelujah
Baby, l've been here before
lknowthis room
l've walkedthis floor
lusedto live alone
before lknewyou
l'veseenyourflag
on the marble arch
But love isnot
a victorymarch
lt'sa cold
andit'sa broken hallelujah
Hallelujah
Andalllever
learnedfrom love
lshowto shoot atsomeone
-  Who outdrewyou
- [Moaning]
Andit'snot a cry
you can hearat night
lt'snotsomebody
who'sseen the light
- lt'sa cold
andit'sa broken hallelujah
- [ Moaning ]
Hallelujah
[Thumping Sound]
Donkey?
- [ Grunts ]
- What are you doing?
I would think, ofall people, you would
recognize a wall when you see one.
Well, yeah.
But the wall's supposed
to go around my swamp, not through it.
It is around your half. See,
that's your half, and this is my half.
Oh! Your half. Hmm.
Yes, my half.
I helped rescue the princess.
I did halfthe work,
I get halfthe booty.
Now hand me that big old rock,
the one that looks like your head.
- Back off!
- No, you back off.
- This is my swamp!
- Our swamp.
- Let go, Donkey!
- You let go.
- Stubborn jackass!
- Smelly ogre.
Fine!
- Hey, come back here.
I'm not through with you yet.
- Well, I'm through with you.
Uh-uh. You know,
with you it's always, ''Me, me, me!''
Well, guess what!
Now it's my turn!
So you just shut up
and pay attention!
You are mean to me.
You insult me and you don't
appreciate anything that I do!
You're always pushing me around
or pushing me away.
Oh, yeah? Well, if I treated you
so bad, how come you came back?
Because that's what friends do!
They forgive each other!
Oh, yeah.
You're right, Donkey.
I forgive you...
for stabbin' me in the back!
Ohh! You're so wrapped up
in layers, onion boy, you're
afraid ofyour own feelings.
- Go away!
- There you are, doing it again
just like you did to Fiona.
All she ever do was like you,
maybe even love you.
Love me? Shesaidl was ugly,
a hideous creature.
lheardthe two ofyou
talking.
She wasn't talkin' about you.
She was talkin' about, uh,
somebody else.
She wasn't talking
about me?
Well, then who was
she talking about?
Uh-uh, no way. I ain't saying anything.
You don't wanna listen to me.
- Right? Right?
- Donkey!
- No!
- Okay, look.
I'm sorry, all right?
Hmph.
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry.
I guess I am just a big,
stupid, ugly ogre.
Can you forgive me?
Hey, that's what friends
are for, right?
Right. Friends?
Friends.
So, um,
what did Fiona
say about me?
What are you asking me for?
Why don't you just go ask her?
The wedding!
We'll never make it in time.
Ha-ha-ha! Never fear, for where
there's a will, there's a way,
and I have a way.
[ Whistles ]
- Donkey?
- [ Donkey Laughing ]
lguess it'sjust
myanimalmagnetism.
[ Laughing ]
Aw, come here, you.
All right, all right. Don't get
all slobbery. No one likes a kiss ass.
All right, hop on
and hold on tight.
I haven't had a chance to
install the seat belts yet.
[ Donkey Laughing ]
Whoo!
[Bells Tolling]
[ All Gasping ]
People of DuLoc,
we gather here today...
to bear witness...
- to the union...
- Um--
- ofour new king--
- Excuse me.
- Could wejust skip ahead
to the ''I do's''?
- [ Chuckling ]
Go on.
Go ahead, have some fun. Ifwe
need you, I'll whistle. How about that?
Shrek, wait, wait!
Wait a minute!
- You wanna do this right, don't you?
- What are you talking about?
There's a line you
gotta wait for.
The preacher's gonna say, ''Speak now
or forever hold your peace.''
- That's when you say, ''I object!''
- I don't have time for this!
Wait. What are you doing?
Listen to me!
- Look, you love this woman, don't you?
- Yes.
- You wanna hold her?
- Please her?
- Yes!
Then you got to, got to
try a little tenderness
- The chicks love that romantic crap!
- All right! Cut it out.
- When does this guy say the line?
- We gotta check it out.
- [ Donkey Grunting ]
- And so, by the power vested in me,
- [Shrek] What doyousee?
- The whole town's in there.
- lnowpronounceyou husbandand wife,
- They're at the altar.
- kingandqueen.
- Mother Fletcher! He already said it.
- Oh, for the love of Pete!
- [ Grunts ]
I object!
- Shrek?
- [ Gasps ]
Oh, now what
does he want?
[ Crowd Clamouring ]
Hi, everyone.
Havin' a good time, are ya?
I love DuLoc,
fiirst ofall.
- Very clean.
- What are you doing here?
Really, it's rude enough
being alive when no one wants you,
-but showing up uninvited to a wedding--
-Fiona!
- I need to talk to you.
- Oh, now you wanna talk?
It's a little late for that,
so ifyou'll excuse me--
- But you can't marry him.
- And why not?
Because-- Because he'sjust
marrying you so he can be king.
Outrageous!
Fiona, don't listen to him.
- He's not your true love.
- And what do you know about true love?
Well, I-- Uh--
- lmean--
- Oh, this isprecious.
[ Chuckling ] The ogre
has fallen in love with the princess!
- Oh, goodLord.
- [CrowdLaughing]
An ogre andaprincess!
[Laughing Continues]
Shrek,
is this true?
Who cares?
lt'spreposterous!
Fiona, my love, we're but a kiss away
from our ''happily ever after.''
Now kiss me!
Mmmm!
''Bynight one way,
by dayanother. '''
I wanted to show you before.
- [ Whimpers ]
- [CrowdGasping]
Well, uh,
that explains a lot.
[Farquaad]
Ugh! lt's disgusting!
Guards! Guards!
lorderyou toget that
out ofmysight now! Get them!
- Get them both!
- No, no!
Thishocus-pocusaltersnothing.
Thismarriage isbinding,
andthat makesme king!
- See? See?
- No, let go of me! Shrek!
- No!
- [Farquaad] Don'tjust
standthere, you morons.
Get out of my way!
Fiona!
Arrgh!
l'llmakeyou regret the day we met.
l'llseeyou drawn andquartered!
- You'll beg for death to save you!
- No! Shrek!
- And as foryou, my wife,
- Fiona!
I'll have you locked back in that tower
for the rest ofyour days!
- lam king!
- [ Whistles ]
I will have order!
I will have perfection! I will have--
Aaah!
- Aah!
- All right. Nobody move.
I got a dragon here,
and I'm not afraid to use it.
- [Dragon Roars]
- I'm a donkey on the edge!
- [ Belches ]
- [DonkeyLaughs]
Celebrity marriages.
They never last, do they?
[ Cheering ]
Go ahead, Shrek.
Uh, Fiona?
Yes, Shrek?
I-- I love you.
Really?
Really, really.
I love you too.
[ All ]
Aawww!
[Fiona's Voice] ''Untilyou
findtrue love's first kiss...
[Echoing]
andthen take love's true form. '''
[Echoing Continues] ''Take love's
true form. Take love's true form. '''
Fiona?
Fiona.
Are you all right?
Well, yes.
But I don't understand.
I'm supposed to be beautiful.
But you are beautiful.
[ Chuckles ]
I was hoping this would be
a happy ending.
lthought love was onlytrue
in fairytales
[ All ]
Oy!
Meant forsomeone else
but not forme
Love was out toget me
That's the way itseemed
Disappointment
hauntedallmy dreams
Andthen lsawherface
Nowl'm a believer
Andnot a trace
Ofdoubt in mymind
- l'm in love
-  Ooh-ahh
l'm a believer
lcouldn 't leave her
lfltried
God bless us, every one.
Come on,y'all!
Then lsawherface Ha-ha!
Now I'm a believer
Listen!
Not a trace
Ofdoubt in mymind
I'm in love
Ooh-ahh
I'm a believer
I couldn't leave her if I tried
- Ooh!
- Uh!
Then I saw her face
Now I'm a believer
Hey!
Not a trace
Uhh! Yeah.
Ofdoubt in mymind
One more time!
I'm in love
I'm a believer
Come on!
I believe, I believe
I believe, I believe, I believe, hey
Y'allsing it with me!
l
Believe
I believe
People in the back!
-  I believe
- l'm a believer
lbelieve
[ Hysterical Laughing ]
Oh, that's funny.
Oh. Oh.
lcan't breathe.
lbelieve in self-assertion
Destinyor
a slight diversion
Nowitseems
l'vegot myheadon straight
l'm a freak
an apparition
Seemsl've made
the right decision
To tryto turn backnow
it might be too late
- l want to stayhome today
- Don't wannago out
- lfanyone comes toplay
-  Gonnaget thrown out
- l wanna stayhome today
- Don't want no company
No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
l wanna be a millionaire
someday
But know what it feels like
togive it away
Watch me march
to the beat ofmyown drum
Andit's offto the moon
andthen backagain
Same oldday
Samesituation
Myhappiness rearsback
asifto say
- l wanna stayhome today
- Don't wannago out
- lfanyone comes my way
-  Gonnaget thrown out
- l wanna stayhome today
- Don't want no company
No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
l wanna stayhome
stayhome, stayhome
- l wanna stayhome today
- Don't wannago out
- lfanyone comes toplay
-  Gonnaget thrown out
l wanna stayhome today
Don't want no company
No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
lgetsuch a thrill
whenyou lookin my eyes
Myheartskipsa beat
Girl, lfeelso alive
Please tellme, baby
ifallthis is true
'Cause deep down inside
alll wanted wasyou
Oh-oh-oh
Makesme wanna dance
lt'sa newromance
Oh-oh-oh
llookintoyoureyes
The bestyears ofourlives
When we first met
lcouldhardlybelieve
The things that wouldhappen
and we couldachieve
So let'sbe together
forallofourtime
Oh, girl, l'm so thankful
thatyou arestillmine
You always considerme
like an ugly duckling
Andtreat me like a Nostradamus
was whylhadtoget myshine on
lbreaka littlesomething
to keep mymindon
'Causeyou hadmymindgone
Eh-eh, eh-eh, eh-eh
Turn the lights on, Come on, baby
Let'sjust rewindthesong
'Cause alll want to do is
make the restyears the bestyears
Allnight long
-  Oh-oh-oh, makesme wanna dance
- Makesme wanna dance
-  Oh-oh-oh, it'sa newromance
- lt'sa newromance
-  Oh-oh-oh, llookintoyoureyes
-  Oh, yeah, yeah
- Lookintoyoureyes
-  Oh-oh-oh
-  The bestyears ofourlives
-  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
-  Oh-oh-oh, makesme wanna dance
-  Whoa-oh-oh, dance, yeah
Oh-oh-oh
lt'sa newromance
-  Oh-oh-oh, llookintoyoureyes
- Lookintoyoureyes, yeah
Oh-oh-oh
The bestyears ofourlives
Everything looksbright
Standing inyourlight
Everything feels right
What's left is out ofsight
What'sagirlto do
l'm tellingyou
You're on mymind
l wanna be withyou
'Cause whenyou're
standin'next to me
lt's like wow
Andallyourkisses
seem to set me free
lt's like wow
And when we touch
it'ssuch a rush
lcan'tget enough
lt's like-- lt's like
Ooh-ooh
Hey, what
lt's like wow
Ooh-ooh, hey
Hey, yeah
lt's like wow
Everything is looking
right now, right now
- lt's like wow
- Andlgot this feeling
This feeling
it'sjust like wow
lt'sjust like wow
- You are alll'm thinking of.
- Like wow
Everything feels right
- Everything looksbright
Allmysensesare right.
- Like wow
- Everything feels right
Baby, baby, baby
the wayl'm feelingyou
ls like wow
[lnstrumental]
There issomething
that lsee
ln the way
you lookat me
There'sa smile
There'sa truth
lnyoureyes
What an unexpected way
On this unexpectedday
Couldit be
This is where lbelong
lt isyou lhave loved
Allalong
There'sno more mystery
lt is finallyclearto me
You're the home
myheart'ssearchedfor
So long
lt isyou lhave loved
Allalong
Whoa, overandover
l'm filled with emotion
Asllook
lntoyourperfect face