Thirty-five years ago,
a gang of bandits...
were caught by the gendarme
on Cudi mountain.
In the course of
these thirty-five years,
illness and prison violence
wiped off all the bandits.
All but one...
Mother Ceran. Is that you?
Yeah. Who are you?
It's Baran.
Baran. The Bandit, you are back?
I'm back Mother Ceran. What
happened to the village?
The water came. Covered everything.
They said ''Go away from here.''
Everyone has deserted the village.
I, alone, stayed here.
I told them not to go.
They wouldn't listen.
Things turned bad after you went
to jail. Evil won the day.
The weak were trampled on.
Where is Mustafa, Ceran?
Left for the city, long time ago...
This place is finished.
Everything's sunk.
Our graves will be next.
Come with me. You'll be
food for the beasts here.
The beasts are of us. Evil is
elsewhere.
I am the madwoman of
this place. I cannot go anywhere.
You're heading for trouble.
I said the same to your father.
I told him ''They'll trap you.''
He wouldn't listen. He went and
didn't come back.
Now if I say ''Don't go!'' You'll go.
I know you will.
Take this, Bandit. It will
protect you from bullets.
Are you going to kill me, Bandit?
Aye Mustafa. I will.
Do you have a gun?
I do.
Give it to me.
Why did you inform on me,
brother Mustafa?
Stupidity, poverty, call it what
you like. This has been killing me.
I can't sleep.
You visit me every night.
I hear your footsteps behind
me. I'm tired of watching my back.
People call me informer. I've lost
face. Even my children shun me.
Why did you do it?
I caved in for a few gold pieces.
Shame on those who forced me.
Who forced you?
I was sworn not to tell, but it
doesn't matter anymore.
Berfo made me do it.
Berfo?
Berfo! He is the one who asked
me to inform on you.
Woe, brother Berfo...
Why did he do it?
To steal Keje from you.
Did Keje go with him?
Yeah. she went with him.
After you went to jail...
Berfo took your gold, then
he went to Keje's father.
I begged him not to. I said ''Keje
is Bandit's girl. Spare her at least.''
He said, ''Fool! I did it all for Keje.''
He took the gold and Keje,
and he disappeared.
Then we heard
he went to Istanbul.
So, this is the thirty year story.
So Keje went with him.
Her father made her go.
She became Berfo's.
We put you in jail. I made a
mistake. I was starved.
Still I'm starved brother.
Bad luck, that gold was.
All went to women and gambling,
All of it.
Our village was covered with dam
water. Everyone was scattered around.
No-one knows who is where.
I'm groveling here as you see.
Anyway, thank god it will all end
now. Come on, finish it off.
Bandit... Bandit.
I can't wait any
longer. Kill me...
Bandit! ....
Greetings.
Hello.
Here. You smoke?
Have one of these, uncle.
No... Please.
please take one of these.
Where are you heading, uncle?
Istanbul, God willing.
Yeah, you're the only one missing
anyway.
Oh my God! Shit! The police.
What shall I do now?..
Bring this bag to
Kismet Garage in Tarlabas i.
Bring this to Kismet Garage
Car mechanic's.
For God's sake!
Please... It's life or death
uncle. I'm begging you please.
I'll pay you a lot.
Please do it man!
-Stop! Police.
-What is this, man?..
Shut up! Cut it out! Go on!
Just a moment. There's a mistake.
What's the charge?
Come on brother.
Where are you taking me man?
I'm off the train, nicely going
home.
Excuse me, can I ask something?
What have I done now?
Clean?
Clean.
He's clean, inspector.
Come on, talk man!
Talk what brother?
You! Did you sell us out, you?
No! I swear. There's no such
thing brother Demircan.
How can you give the stuff costing
billions to just anyone in the street?
The police surrounded me.
Honestly, I swear...
I wasn't afraid of getting caught.
It was for the stuff.
Or? Are you a police mole?
What are you saying brother? That's
the guy's suitcase over there.
What did we do? Didn't we send out
two couriers and tipped...
the cops on
on the wrong one?
How come the cops didn't go after
the decoy then? And got you?
This was only your first job. Talk!
Are you an informer? Say it!
Bring him in.
Forgive me brother.
I had trouble finding the place.
That's him! That's the guy!
It is my first time in Istanbul.
Okay. The stuff is here.
Wow! That was a close one.
What's happened to this thing?
It had an accident. I'm sorry.
Here. It was a promise. Buy
yourself new suitcase.
No. I don't want it.
Take it. You have no idea what you
saved me from. Thanks.
Wasn't trouble at all.
Almost had it man. Yours truly
almost would've had it.
Huh?
Nevermind. Okay. Thanks
I'll be off now uncle if it's okay
with you.
What are you doing?
Just looking.
What at?
Where am I now?
Tarlabas i.
Well... Okay.
Where will you go now?
I don't know really. I'm looking
for a place to stay.
A hotel?
Right, friend. Some place
cheap you know.
Ah! Okay. Come with me.
God bless you, brother.
I felt a little strange you know.
Come with me, uncle. Don't worry.
I did it four times.
Big deal.
Cut the crap you two.
You should never trust a woman.
They always cocktease.
-How did it go?
-It was taken care of.
-Is the job done?
-What job?
Are you still there?
Just a minute uncle, wait for me.
How you doing?
Welcome back. Did you take care
of your business?
Yeah. Why the long face?
I got news from my brother.
He's really in a squeeze.
Well. Prison is a tough place.
Emel! Who are you talking to?
Just friends, come on mom.
Okay, see you then.
Get in! What friends at this
hour? Come help me.
You are a slut.
There is whore in you.
The place is coming down again.
The witch's lost it.
This guy is waiting for you.
-Who's this?
-Just a poor old soul.
Where are you taking him?
To my hotel. He has nowhere to stay.
Wait for me.
-Who did he say he was?
-His grandpa.
-No? He's still alive?
-Lay off Avarel, you're a moron.
Cheapest hotel in Tarlabas i.
Girl Naci will do us a favour.
Naci, you got a room?
What do you want it for?
I'm going to stick it up
you know where.
I'll headbutt your face in,
then you'll see.
-Say it girl, got a room?
-Yes Master Cumali, at your service.
Give a room for uncle here.
Who's this guy anyway?
How do I know he'll pay?
Actor Kemal still owes me
a month's rent.
You're having your period or
something?
Give him the room,
don't drive me crazy.
-ID?
-What?
Hakan... What's up kid?
Come here, I'll kill you. I told
him I'm not buying the mintendo thing.
Bastard spat at me.
Comehere!
Come on uncle Kemal have some water
or something.
I'll be alright now.
Alright? You're getting worse every
day.
You've got to see a doctor.
You haven't been around lately.
I took care of some business.
That's my boy.
It is worst when it starts
during shooting.
The other day-what am I saying-six
months ago, I was playing a small part.
I began coughing, it wouldn't
go away.
Finally, they kicked me out.
Didn't pay me, either.
I hate the communists but in those
days these things were better in Russia.
If you fell ill, they
took you straight to hospital.
This would never have happened.
Especially to an artist like you.
Still, those reds. They ruined
my country.
Don't start again Andrei Mishkin.
All that's over now.
You know, you got me out of a
difficult situation there.
Not at all.
Your binoculars puzzled the cops.
I said I was peeping around.
Why do you
carry them around anyway?
Well. It is a keepsake.
You live in this hotel?
Yeah.
Why? Don't you have a family?
A home?
No. It's better this way.
Why are you in Istanbul uncle?
I am looking for somebody.
Where is that somebody?
I don't know...
What do you mean
''I don't know''?
I don't know where he is.
How are you going to find him
in this huge city?
I will.
Uncle, ten million people
live in this city.
I will look at all ten million
faces if I have to.
When did you last see
this somebody?
Thirty, thirty five years ago.
And you're going to look for
someone you haven't seen for...
...thirty five years
in a city like Istanbul?
You're out of your mind!
Is she looking?
She is. You got her Cimbom.
What is this? You get mushy the
moment you see the girls.
Are we going out tonight?
We got to do some work first.
We're all broke.
Look at the legs on that Fatma.
I'm not going to spend the rest of
my life stealing car stereos.
Wish we could break into Demircan's
lot. He is close to Mafia.
I risked my life for Demircan's job
while you were sitting...
...on your
backs, you faggots.
Cumali, watch your language man.
Fuck off smart ass! So what?
I'm crazy for this Fatma.
What are you staring at you bums?
She's taking you for a ride, idiot.
What? Stupid!
Isn't this him?
What's up?
Well. You know... Nothing.
You're going to look for
your man?
For God's sake, you'll get lost
uncle!
Really? We'll see.
In Istanbul? I don't believe it.
Idiot! Go get lost.
I'll come along with you today. Just
in case. This city could swallow a man.
God bless you. So many people,
so crowded.
Just like the ward
I was in.
Now. Who are we looking for?
Keje.
And where are we headed if we
don't know where she is?
I don't know.
So, Why do we go this way
and not that way?
I don't know. Don't keep asking
questions. I'm only trying to hear...
...the sound of this place.
Don't distract me. Just walk.
We're crazy to be walking
like this. Someone called Keje.
Address: Istanbul.
My feet hurt. This can't go on.
You go back if you want.
What if you get lost?
Displaying your wares again, eh?
You go to the hotel.
I'll be along.
Who's that?
He's the guy who helped me.
Got me walking all day.
Come inside. I'll ask you something.
-What happened to the thing?
-What thing baby?
You were going to take me to see
my brother in prison.
-Anything for you.
-Tomorrow's the open visit.
-Okay, we'll go.
-Mom will kill me if she finds out.
Don't let mom find out about the
prison. She hates my brother.
Come on. Give us a hug.
My dear Kemal Bey.
It's been three months.
I can only bow in humiliation
Naci Bey brother.
I can't wait till you get a part.
This is your last week.
Besides, this coughing of yours.
It's just too much.
I know. Even the syrups don't
soothe it anymore.
All the guests are complaining.
The whole building is shaking.
Any messages for me?
Sure, the mayor called.
He is upset you haven't called.
Fuck off! I'm going out.
The police!
If they ask I'm not here.
If the police find this on me,
I'm fucked. They're already after me.
Why are you armed?
Do you have enemies?
In Istanbul, everyone is your
enemy.
You never know what will
happen next.
See how it shines. Fourteen bullets
at a time. We stole it.
Common property of the gang.
What is this place?
Istanbul.
Istanbul!
Where else?
Istanbul! It looks like where I
live. There are plains...
mountains and towns.
As if I'm on top of Cudi.
How are you?
Fine. I miss you badly though.
Me too, sweetheart.
How's Mom?
God damn her.
Shut up! Cut it out!
Is this him?
Cumali. My brother.
Hello Cumali brother.
Hello brother Sedat. May God
spare you. How are you?
Not too well.
Something wrong?
Yes. Got mixed up in something
here. The top guys passed my...
sentence. They'll stab me.
Sedat!
Shut up! I've got to escape chief.
If I make it to the medical centre,
then I'll escape from the hospital.
But you need to bribe people to get
to the medical centre.
How much?
Two hundred million.
Wow!
Anyway, forget it now.
You're okay?
I'm not.
You take care of this girl chief.
She is your responsibility.
If anything happens to her I will
get out of my grave, and find you.
They will kill him.
How can he get this kind of money?
The money will be found.
Who will find it?
Two hundred million isn't nothing.
I will find it.
No. How can you shoulder such a
burden?
Your brother is
my brother.
Cumali! My hero.
What are you doing here?
Looking around.
What is that in your hand?
Binoculars.
You've no shame? Peeping on
people's wives and daughters.
No, I wouldn't...
I am looking for someone.
With binoculars?
Aye, How else could I see him?
Go away, man.
I have to find two hundred million.
You're kidding?
-Where the hell is he?
-This is for you, from Sekine.
-Where is mine, baby?
-Idiot!
Go inside.
And you go home too.
He must have lost his way.
Who?
That guy, the one in the hotel.
Why do you hang around
with that peasant?
Watch your language! He is
old enough to be your father.
This is how I talk to my father.
Hey! Hakan. Where's your mom?
She's out working.
So she went out early today. Naci, girl,
are you sure you didn't see uncle?
I told you I didn't.
You sure get obsessed about things.
The guy's got lost.
I shouldn't have let him go alone.
Where have you been, uncle?
We were all worried about you.
-We thought you were lost.
-I was lost, brother.
Great! So how did you
find your way back?..
The old way. I trailed my way back.
This city is a prison Cumali.
I can't breathe in this city.
It stinks like rotten carcass.
The wards used to smell like this.
Here, I brought you candies.
What's that?
Binoculars.
-Can I have a look?
-Sure.
Who uses this?
The gendarme, army officers,
and once... The bandits.
What is a bandit?
A brigand, a robber.
Living on mountains.
Just a human being like you
and me.
You know any bandits?
I know one. He was called Baran.
The clan chief sent Baran's father...
...to the mined border and had
him killed.
And Baran rebelled and took to the
mountains.
Baran is very young then. He is in
love with a girl. And a terrific shot.
It was a mighty mountain like
that one.
He fought the clan chief's
bandits at that time.
He picked them out with these binoculars
and gave them the bullet.
Are you that Baran?
Yes. I am.
Hakan. To your room, quick!
It is bed time.
Come on, Cumali.
Shut up. Give me the binoculars
Off you go.
Are you a bandit?
It was thirty five years ago.
Wow! Our uncle, a bandit!
So, what have you done
all these thirty five years?
I was in jail.
What? For thirty five years?
Thirty five years.
That's enough to kill a man.
It did kill all my friends.
Look, here.
How come you weren't pardoned?
I killed three more in prison.
What?
They sent hired men on me.
I finished them off.
You were talking about a
sweetheart. Is that Keje?
Aye.
You're looking for her?
Keje and the man who abducted Keje.
The first film about the Southeastern
problem will soon be released.
The film is expected to boldly take up
the greatest problem of this country.
In other news. The attempt on
business tycoon Mahmut Saho%lu's
life is under investigation.
The police have not yet made a
public statement. In the meantime,
Saho%lu remains silent.
The elusive Saho%lu is the owner of
an empire that has extraordinarily
grown to the size of thirty
companies in the last twenty years
and has reached everywhere like the
tentacles of an octopus.
He recently gave his only TV
interview to date to Mithat Bereket.
Mahmut Bey, you have become the
centre of attention with your
outbursts against the Industrialists'
Association and the government.
Yes!
In fact, there are various
unpleasant allegations about your
own wealth. You accuse the
Association of illegal practices,
but you cannot explain how you grew
so powerful in a matter of twenty years?
You are also accused of loansharking
and of seizing businesses with
Mafia assistance.Your textile factory
is shown as an example.
There are also allegations
that granting of your bankers'
licence is somewhat questionable.
-Who sent you here?
Excuse me?
You! Who pays you? How dare you
present rumours as the truth?
Please watch your tone. You can't
talk to me like that.
Go send me your boss...
You won't pull me down, ever!
-I am a journalist.
-You are a hired pen!
No, I am an independent journalist.
I employ a hundred people like
you. Go tell those who mess with me
they can't tear me down. They
don't have what it takes.
Get out of my house! Get out!
Turn the damn thing off. Cut!
I found you.
What does it say?
Come on, tell us.
I'm not saying!
Say it and I'll treat you to a
whore.
Fuck off then, don't!
-You're going to talk, or not?
-Cumali, don't!
-It could go off, man.
-Speak up, what did she write?
Brother Cumali, come help me.
What is it? What happened?
Come to the hotel. I'll show you
someone. I saw him. On TV.
I'll be right back. You guys stay
put. We'll be on a job tonight.
Yeah, you put the kid to bed.
Make sure he drinks his milk.
Did you wet yourself?
He was here?
Who?
Berfo! In a wheelchair.
Tubes up his nose.
Where is he? Where has he gone?
Who are you talking about, man?..
He means Mahmut Saho%lu.
Mahmut Saho%lu? You know him?
Take me to him.
Why did you bring this geezer?
Hush! He'll hear.
He is an old bandit.
-What?
-A bandit!
Meaning what?
You know, a bandit. On the
mountains. A highwayman.
You sure he didn't make it up?
I saw the photo. He snuffed three
people in prison.
Imagine what he
must have done in the mountains.
Run for it!
Hey, Bandit, come on!
Will you find him for me?
Take me to him
Give me a break, for God's sake.
God damn it.
We're just drifting bums.
Every job should have some
respectability. Look at us.
As they say: Live fast, die young
and you'll leave a handsome corpse.
Let me tell you something. Only way
to play this game is to play it big
When my father migrated to
Istanbul, he got a job as a waiter.
That's where he lost the game
I've been a mechanic, a bouncer
at clubs, parked cars.
Still I am a nobody.
I went to jail for nothing.
We're all the same.
The other day, I quarreled with my
dad, He wants me to go back to my...
job at the factory. I said no.
You're a worker and look where it
got us. He went mad.
We should all move out like Cumali.
I will go to brother Demircan. I'll
say: Rescue us from this life.
Get us on your team.
We'd be like royalty round here.
We'll get respect, man.
Everyone will look up to us,
shop owners etc. The girls.
Maybe I shouldn't come.
Sure! Left to yourself, you'd
get lost again. Stick to me
Just a minute, uncle.
Beg your pardon?
The week is over. You owe me.
Put him on my bill.
-But, Cumali...
-Shut up or I'll clobber you.
I have friends, I have partners I am
responsible to. I have to be careful.
Now, you almost sank us on that job
the other day. Still, you didn't
talk to the police, you're okay. I
know that.
Our business is no kids' play,
amateurs fail.
So last time, you begged and prayed
and I let you have your chance.
What will you say for yourself
this time Cumali?
This time we are here to put
ourselves entirely at your command.
I and my friends are solid, brother
Demircan.
Order us to die and we will.
And we know our way around.
You can't find better men to deal
the stuff.
There isn't a club we don't know.
Give us just one chance,
then decide.
Okay, we'll give it a try. Not a
word to anyone about this though.
And stay out of the
police's way.
If you get caught
I don't know you.
And this uncle over there, is he
part of your gang?
No. He's a bandit.
A real bandit. A mountain man.
That's of course, back when.
No bandits left on the mountains,
uncle.
Now, all the bandits are
down in the city.
I have important news for you.
Come inside, mom's out.
Sekine, when will you put out?
Cimbom's all horny.
God damn you, asshole!
Didn't I tell you not to wear
mini-skirts?
Mom first, now you start.
You jealous pig!
What is it?
We have a deal with brother
Demircan.
We'll push some of
the stuff for him.
So, it means we're finding money.
Don't look at my face like an idiot.
I'll be able to save your
brother.
Thank god!
My hero!
Don't. Mom will be
back any minute now.
Come on girl, give it to me.
We'll be married anyway.
Not before the wedding,
Shit! It's mom.
What shall we do? Let's pretend we
are just talking.
No! To the window...
Keje...
We almost got nailed there.
This is not the right way to go.
What's wrong with way?
Drugs are bad news. Don't do it.
You are poisoning people.
I've known many dealers in prison.
They all ended up badly.
''Don't do it'', eh? What should I do
then? Is theft better?
Or conning people?
Which one is better?
None. None of that is fitting for
human beings.
All of that is fitting for human
beings.
Or they wouldn't be around.
Why did you do it then?
You know why my dad named me Cumali?
My father adored Yilmaz Gney.
He named me after one of Gney's
screen characters.
He saw ''Ince Cumali''
fifteen times.
In everyday life my father imitated
Yilmaz Gney.
Walked and talked like him.
Looked a bit like him too.
My stepmother betrayed
him. Can you imagine?
A betrayed hero!
He shot them both. My stepmother
was crippled and the guy died.
So that's what my father got for
being a good guy.
I mean, anything can happen in
life.
Besides, I don't like doing this. But
Emel needs the money for her brother.
Back in jail, we knew two Kemals,
Mustafa Kemal and Dodo Kemal.
Dodo Kemal was a very young
convict. A murderer.
Every morning, he used to get the
papers first. He used to go through...
the pages like crazy, looking for
news of an amnesty.
After years of this, he did receive
his pardon and was freed.
A week later, he had murdered
someone and was back in jail.
You remind me of him. If I had
a son, he would be your age.
And if my father were alive, he
would be your age, Bandit.
Will you take me to him, brother.
Who?
The man on the TV.
Take me to him.
That's all I ask of you.
This is my request.
Is this the place?
Yes. This is it.
Are you sure?
Don't drive me nuts Bandit.
You said ''take me'', and I did.
This guy is one of the richest guys
in Turkey.
What is your business
with him uncle?
Look, I'm leaving. Can you find
your way back to the hotel?
You saw what you wanted to see.
The car's gone too. Let's go now.
Who are you looking for, man. Why
should I care anyway?
I don't own you.
I'm leaving.
Hey! What's going on? Just a
minute. Where are you taking us?
Didn't I tell you ''Let's go''
It is my fault. I should have left.
Get lost if you want. Am I your mom
or your dad? You're a grown man.
Get me out of here!
Get me out!
I'll break down the door.
Get me out of here!
Stop it Bandit! Are you out of your
mind? Don't!
What were you doing there?..
Were you there to kill Mahmut Bey?
No. I don't have a gun.
Why were you watching the place?
You're an ex-convict.
Are you a hitman?
No such thing.
Sir, there's a call for you sir.
Sir, please let me explain, you see,
this poor old guy is penniless.
We were looking for a job for
him when we saw that mansion.
We thought they might be hiring
a gardener or something.
We are not terrorists or anything.
We are your decent, honest...
one hundred percent Turkish,
sort of people.
Cut it out! Get out of here,
both of you.
See, my spiel worked. The guys
thought we were terrorists.
You're not going to
that house again, understand?
Hello.
Hello brother.
You are coming with us.
Where are you going?
Who are you?
You are not coming. Just him.
Come Baran.
Come closer.
I'll tear off these tubes!
This emphysema is a motherfucker.
I've never been so helpless.
Oxygen is like poison.
After a while, it starts eating up your
brain. It makes you speak nonsense.
You have changed
your name, Berfo.
Aye. I changed my name.
Is Keje alive?
Yes.
Is she with you?
Why did you betray me Berfo?
Betray? So you call this betrayal,
do you? I give up.
Now if I say to you: I did all of
that because I was in love.
I was dying from love.
Who could possibly say anything
to me?
What the hell is ''betrayal''?
I did it for love, damn it.
Yes I did it. I am a man who has
informed on his closest friend.
Could you have done that?
Betray your most beloved friend?
Could you steal his gold and use it
to buy the woman your friend loved?
Could you have sent your friend to
certain death.
I did do it. For love.
Now tell me.
Which one of us loved Keje
more? You, or I?
Which one of us
dared to sin like that?
I am ready to burn in hell
for this love. Are you?
Keje didn't want me though. Granted
when I paid her father...
Keje curiously gave in. She followed
me But never spoke a word since.
Not to me, not to anyone else.
For thirty five years now, she has
kept silent, Baran.
I begged her to speak, I beat her,
threw her out in the street.
I wept at her feet, but she
didn't speak.
She didn't speak and she didn't
give me children.
Still, I wouldn't give Keje up.
I didn't re-marry and
I didn't ask for children.
If I had wanted it,
you couldn't see me.
I could have sent you back to
that prison.
Do you know why you are here?
You will go to Keje and talk to
her.
If she doesn't speak to you either,
then I'll know she has given up on
the world, I'll know she doesn't
want anybody.
That she has buried herself alive.
And if she speaks?
Keje. Keje.
I was shot in jail, Keje.
I didn't die.
I fell ill, I left one lung there,
still I lived on.
They beat me up relentlessly.
But I didn't die. I
lived on to see you once again.
Now I am told that no-one hears your
voice, that you have stopped speaking.
Aren't you going to talk to me
either, Keje?
Am I not going to hear your voice?
Do bandits...
...still...
...turn into...
...stars when they die?
On the mountains, you hear the
sounds of wilderness.
I used to lie on a rock and watch
the sky, the stars.
I would think
of you.
And a star would shoot across the
sky and I would say...
''There, another
bandit has died.''
I would remember, when we were kids
how I told you of ancient brigands...
and how you looked at the
stars.
I also...
...have been...
...watching the stars
at night.
But..
...I have not seen you.
That's how I knew...
...you were alive.
And I waited for the day you would
come back.
My voice sounds...
...strange to me now.
As if someone else is speaking.
and I am listening.
I lived my whole life for this
moment alone.
Whatever happens now, let it.
I will come back for you.
Wait for me, Keje.
Well done boys. Here you are.
I hope we've done a good job,
brother Demircan.
Do you still want to join the
team?
You mean we're in the Mafia now?
Let's get laid tonight.
Let's splash out.
How much did you take?
More than you did.
Why is that?
I'm the boss. I arranged the job.
Don't steal from me again.
Don't steal my money!
I swear to buggery, I haven't
Cemal.
They don't call me Razor Cemal
for nothing, I swear I'll cut you up.
I swear I'm only putting aside a
few pennies for the nitedo.
What the hell is that?
A toy for the kid.
Don't make me shit on your toy.
I'll kill you.
Don't, brother. She is
our sister.
Cemal, don't!
Stay out of this, old fart.
You might catch your death.
Why didn't you kill that man?
She beats up mom all the time.
Weren't you a bad-knit?
That was way back when.
I am not a bandit any more.
Who did this? You went to
that guy again, didn't you?
It wasn't them. Just a little
accident downstairs.
Weren't you done with that?
This is the last time.
No-one knows about it.
You don't either, okay?
I cut on what Demircan gave
us. If he finds out, he'll skin me.
You said you wouldn't.
I swear this is the last time.
I'm doing this for Emel's brother.
Don't tell anyone.
Not even the gang.
I'm sorry. See what happened to
you because of me.
Don't mention it. It's alright.
That pimp wasn't worth it dear.
No harm done..
My son says you used to be
a bandit. That you will save us all.
Kids are strange.
He is making it up.
He's always been a dreamer anyway.
Do I have any messages, my dear
Naci Bey?
I am not your personal secretary.
No, it's just that, it was about
this film.
A glass of wine?
No, Andrei Mishkin.
It's bad for my cough.
My father used to be
a connoisseur of wine.
As you know, ambassadors value
expertise in wine,
more than anything else.
He would feel its bouquet, its
aroma and establish its vintage.
He used drink white wine
in a tulip glass...
and the red in short stemmed Roman.
He opened an exquisite bottle the day
I graduated from Law School.
I, timidly, told him I wouldn't practise
law and I wanted to be an actor,
he threw me out of the
house.
You made a mistake by choosing
acting.
No. See, I am penniless, I can't pay
the rent, I can't even buy medicine.
But I wouldn't give up acting for
anything. I don't mind the illness
but being a burden on other people
saddens me.
Cumali has raised the money.
What?
The two hundred million is ready,
brother Sedat.
You're kidding!
Please brother. Please.
It's nothing.
You are quite a guy, you know that?
I entrust Emel to you.
God knows when I'll appear again.
Slip the money to the guard,
he'll give it to me.
Brother Cumali, I have
decided to return home.
And Keje?
I will take her with me as well.
That would mean war.
No. It wouldn't. I have to
make some money though.
You mean I'm supposed to
find you a job.
Aye. That's it.
You go to the hotel and stay put.
I'll take care of it.
I bet he is not getting any action
either.
-How do you mean?
The poor soul has gone thirty
five years without a woman.
That's right.
I wonder if he ever did it.
Cumali.
An amulet? How cute.
It's for bullets.
Bullets?
It is said that no bullets will
touch a man wearing this.
Come on, don't look so naive.
Don't worry about the fee,
it's on Cumali.
What?
What is it? Trouble?
No. Mom's at my aunt's tonight.
So I thought I'd drop by.
Wow! I've hit the jackpot, girl.
Come here you.
Slow down! I shouldn't have come.
You're behaving like an animal.
I've had enough of your
teasing. Come here.
Let go of my arm...
I swear you're hurting me.
Let go I said, or I'll get
mad.
God bless you, but I am tied to
someone else.
You're offering me a treasure but,
I can't. Go to your child.
Can't I stay a little longer then?
I promise I won't bother you.
We belong to each other now. If
necessary, I'll marry you under...
both religious and civil law.
I gave my word to your brother.
What a nasty world this is!
Thanks for all
you've done for my brother.
I love you so bad, man.
I'm going to die of this love, man.
You too must return home,
Androshka Mishkin.
To die in your own country
Even if the communists are back.
What kind of country is this?
An ambassador's son hangs himself...
because he couldn't get medicine.
He couldn't see a doctor.
That's what this country is like.
That's why we have to have money.
You are powerful if you have money.
She's gone... the slut!
The whore! She ran away!
She left me alone like this.
No... I swear I didn't do a thing.
I wasn't the one.
Idiot! I'm not talking about you,
I mean her lover. He was in jail.
Now he escaped.
And they ran off together.
Her father had also run away like
this. God damn them all.
Wasn't that her brother in jail?
What brother? It was her lover!
She fooled you, the slut.
He was a sworn hooligan. Here, the
letter. I couldn't separate them.
The bastard went to jail, but
she still stuck with him.
God! The whore really took good
advantage of you, man.
Milked you like a cow.
Shut up you, shut up!
I'm going nuts.
Brother Demircan wants you.
Later...
Now.
Get me those buggers! Find them.
Wherever they crawled in. Find them!
Nice place, isn't it?
Very nice, brother. It's paradise.
I'm closing the deal on it.
I'll divide it into plots and I'll
sell it to the developers.
Cumali, some of the stuff we gave
you is missing.
We brought you all the money we got
right and honest, brother.
Please brother. You know
we aren't that sort.
You were seen dealing the other
night. You sold our stuff...
and got your money.
So I wondered whose stuff it was
that you were dealing.
No brother, definitely.
We're your men.
There must be a mistake here
somewhere.
Still, keep your eyes open. We've
got two packs missing.
If you hear anything.
Sure brother, your wish is my
command.
Hey lad, it seems something else
is on your mind.
Somebody played a trick on me,
I'm pissed. But I'll get even.
That's my boy. Never forgive
things done to you. I never did.
What's this?
The stereo wouldn't come off,
so I swiped the whole car.
Come on. Get off the car.
I'm sorry. I lost control.
Here. Shoot me.
Don't be stupid. Put it back.
Any news on Emel?
No.
They are at this hotel.
Go bring my daughter.
The bastard bedded me first, spent
my money. Then he seduced Emel.
Go bring my daughter. I'll give you
whatever you want. Anything.
Bandit! Come here.
Where to?
-The call?
-It didn't come.
What if it came while we were out?
We never went out. We made love
non-stop. You are an animal.
My bones are aching.
We have to get the passports
today.
We catch the loving brother and
sister in bed.
Do brothers do this to their sisters?
Don't you know incest
results in disaster?
God forbid, you could have
handicapped kids or something.
Now look here, whore.
I'm going to pull the trigger,
and blow the bastard's head off.
Bloody pieces of his brains
will splatter all over your face.
Don't do it. Don'! Don't!
I will, I will, I will.
Brother, I did wrong, okay,
she's all yours. Let me go.
Let's forget the whole thing.
I'll never cross your path again. Ever.
I'll stand guard at the door.
See who you left me for! The guy
for whom you broke my heart.
And I stole from the worst man
in the country for you.
I put my life in the line.
If he hears it, he'll wipe me off.
I do that for you, and you do this
to me.
And all for this bugger.
How could you?
Don't!
This is not worth going to
jail for. Spare them.
We're going.
I always imagined it would be hard
to kill a man.
But it was so easy, Bandit.
You go back home. Now murder
has come into this.
Police is in this thing.
We'll go elsewhere.
I've ruined my life.
We must get out of town.
Go to the mountains.
Where?
We will go up the mountain.
They can't find us there.
We will take her, and go...
Keje?
Keje.
Let's go to the hotel tonight, and
get our things.
My money's at the hotel, too.
Come out!
Come here. I'm talking to you.
Stop, or I'll shoot!
What place is this?
I don't know.
I was hit.
Let me see.
Shall I die?
Everybody dies.
Will this wound kill me?
No. It's just the skin.
Don't worry.
I've never been wounded before.
We couldn't get the money either.
We'll make it, won't we? We'll
get out of this whore of a city?
Get out of here.
The police are looking for you.
You'll get us in trouble, too.
We'll just lie low for a day or
two, and then we'll leave.
Definitely not. Go away from here.
Auntie, dear... Okay. Lend me some
money then.
Go away! Not a penny for you.
You were trouble even as a child.
When I was a child? Very well,
Let me tell you about my childhood.
There's nothing to tell.
You know what I went through in
this house after my father...
-went to jail, don't you?
-Shut up!
Every time your child-bugging
husband came after me...
you would
hide in the kitchen.
That bugger almost raped me before
I stabbed him.
Every time he made a pass, you looked
away 'cos he might leave you.
Talk about decency, you slut!
You screwed every guy in the
neighbourhood.
Go away. Get out of my house.
Police! Help!
We've got to find some money.
Can you ask Keje?
No. I can't.
Suppose we robbed someplace?
I took an oath not to do such
things.
You say no to everything.
You get us money then.
Hey, Deli. Listen, we're fine.
Get us some money.
We've got money. Brother Demircan
gave us work. Come over.
Are you crazy? The police are
everywhere.
No they are gone. They think you
left for good.
We'll be over. Okay.
I'm going back to the neighbourhood
You go. I have to take care of some
business. I will see you there.
Don't get lost, okay?
We have to leave the city. There's
this lad who helped me a lot.
He is in trouble. I must
help him.
Will you come with me?
I will.
I will come back for you.
Have you seen Cumali, my friend?
I can't find him, or his friends.
Demircan's men took him away.
It seems it's not only the police
he's in trouble with.
Where is my stuff?
You talked before you killed
the girl. You said you stole.
Your closest friend told me.
Are they in this too?
No. They know nothing.
I did it alone.
You will either return the stuff,
or the money.
I gave the money to the woman.
Give me back my money!
Cut the crap!
I killed two people.
They betrayed me.
And you betrayed me.
She conned me.
What is it to me?
I want my money.
What is it?
-You have the boy.
-Yes, I have him.
Let him go.
Not before he pays me back.
It's not the money.
We spend it in one night sometimes.
Our reputation is at stake here.
You know these things. If you let
someone cheat you...
it is bad for
your reputation.
If he is an upstart bastard like
this, it's worse.
I can't let the
word get around.
The police are after him. And he
was conned out of his money.
Let me put it this way to you. If
he doesn't pay up, it won't
be the police who pulls his rope.
How much does he owe?
Two hundred million.
I'll pay you.
Where will you find that kind of
money?
The debt is my responsibility.
Leave the kid alone.
This is between you and me.
From now on, if something goes
wrong, you and I will talk.
Okay, bring the money and take
the kid.
What is this? I want money.
It is a cheque. It stands for
money. Just give it to them.
You owed me a life.
You've settled your debt now.
Keje?
She stays.
So it's Keje in return for a
kid's life. Keje for a life.
Baran.
I don't know how long I'll live
but I shall not give you up until...
my last breath. I may yet...
come back
to you, Keje.
I'll keep silent Baran.
Until you return.
Where did you get this cheque?
It's as good as gold.
Return the boy.
Go cash this at the bank.
You go, I'll have a word with Cumali.
Don't you ever cross my path again.
Now, it's the police's
turn.
Don't hide behind a poor old man.
One more mistake and I'll kill you!
I won't even bother asking this
time. Now fuck off!
Boy, we sure got fucked back there.
The police, let's disperse. We'll
meet back at the neighbourhood.
I am lost.
Master Demircan has news for you.
The cheque bounced.
Wha? What're you saying, brother?
Bandit! Run!
The police will be
here any minute. Cumali was shot.
-Who shot him?
-Demircan's men.
Why?
Your cheque bounced. The guy
you got it from cheated you.
We're all in trouble.
-Where is Cumali?
-Must have run to the hotel.
There is this warmth crawling up my
legs. What is it?
You were shot often enough, Bandit.
You ought to know. Am I going to die?
I remember my stepmother.
How she jumped off the roof in her...
white dress. I thought she'd fly
away like a bird.
But she hit the
ground like a rock.
Then, I thought of Emel. She never
believed I could shoot her.
Neither did I.
It all happened so fast.
I will go to hell, won't I?
Who knows where anyone goes?
We were going to go where you
lived, to the mountains.
I'm so scared. Don't leave me,
I'm scared.
Don't be scared. You are only
going into earth.
Then you will
be earth.
Then you will flow with the waters
and become the sap of a flower.
A bee will come to the sap.
And, perhaps, I will be that bee.
The boy died. That thing you gave
me was a fake. Why?
Remember we used to play stones as
boys?
I used to beat you all the
time.
You never asked why I always
won. I always cheated.
You knew the boy would die.
Why did you do it?
Why is the boy's death so
important?
You sacrificed Keje to save the
life of a nobody.
That woman has spent her whole life
waiting for you.
What does life matter in the face
of love?
True. What does life matter in the
face of love?
I told you I would
answer for the boy.
''You should talk to me if
anything goes wrong,'' I said.
You didn't keep your promise.
You killed him. That won't do.
You broke the agreement.
Watch it, you bastard!
Fuck...
The motive behind one of the
bloodiest massacres in recent years
is still unknown.
Is there a connection between
the murder of Mahmut S,aholu
and the slaughter of the drug
dealers?
S,aholu's widow remains silent.
We know where you are. Give
yourself up! You won't be harmed.
Surrender! Hands on your head!
Or we shall open fire.
I won't go back to jail.
I can't stand being locked
up anymore.
Surrender! Or we'll open fire!
Once, I came face to face with a
wolf. I pointed my gun at her...
and the wolf was growling.
I thought, one of us will be dead
in a moment. A matter of strength.
Go, you are too young.
It'd be a pity...
We don't want to harm you. This
is the last warning. Surrender.
I am coming, bandits!
I am coming.
Keje! Keje!
Goodbye, Bandit.
Ah! Bandit, ah!