He was just
all alone.
He couldn't enjoy a game with anyone else.
Like living inside a dream...
That's the kind of man he was.
Wake up.
Wake up!
Alright?
The world is like a steaming pot of stew.
lnside the mixed-up stew.
no ingredient is any more
important than another.
ln the end, all you see is the combined product,
but there is one thing that you can't forget.
Do you know what that one thing is?
Meat?
Everyone thinks that,
but if there's no stew base, it's not a stew.
With the same ingredients,
it could become a curry,
The stew base is on that counter over there...
l'm not talking about that!
Damn that robber bitches a lot.
Spike, let's go.
l'm going in from the back
Alright.
lf you're waitin for the police,
it's useless,
We know all the security around here.
Why do you think we do this?
Engine, hurry, up and do it!
This is the mark of a security firm.
l was an employee there.
l see.
l was laid off and became a robber.
lsn't that funny?
l see...
Laugh.
Is it funny?
lt is funny huh?
l didn't tell you to laugh!
Hey! This place is closed.
Go somewhere else.
lf you understand, then hurry up
and put the money in this money card.
Who the fuck are you?
Hey! Can't you hear me?
Shit...
Hey! Take those off and listen to me!
l'll take this.
You bitch!
Spike!
Yeah?
Can you put the tab for the donut on them?
Don't move!
Jet...
Yeah?
You said three people.
Drop your weapons!
To deceive an enemy,
you start with your ally.
How does deceiving me help?
Are you listening?
Most of all, you took too long taking a shit!
Shut up! Don't you care if she dies?
Are you listening?
You're ignoring me?
Can't you see her?
l'm sorry, Grandma.
We're not police or security guards
We don't think about saving civilian lives.
What?
Seems it's not your day.
Damn it, he's a cowboy.
Hey! Hey! What are you saying?
You low life!
You're a cowboy?
Who...
Who are you?
Just your average bounty hunter.
Hurry up and go, Jet.
Don't rush me.
Huh?
Why don't you think before you go?
Hurry up...
ln the game of Shougi,
you think ahead and predict
the opponent's moves.
Moves!
When the timing is right,
be where your opponent wants to be.
Being one step ahead is true purpose.
lt doesn't mean that you can just move
wherever you want.
l want to move here.
With just rules, you can't win at Shougi,
You don't get it, do you?
Alright, Spike, ln Shougi,
your personality shows in the game.
lf you just play around when you feel like it and...
Hurry up...
Spike, if the hostage had been shot,
what were you going to do?
lt happens...
As usual, for a 125,000 wulong criminal,
there's too much risk involved
Bounty hunting is harder than just that.
Before l teamed up with you,
l lived a normal life.
Yes! Yes! That's the move l was going to make!
How about that, Spike?
Found him! Found him! Found him!
Knock knock, chick!
Ship number 12 took route 8 going into the city.
Okay.
Send me the car and the criminal's information.
Yes, yes.
Underaged, huh?
l hate taking care of kids.
lt's not him?
lt's time for CBC News.
Starting with today's top news...
At 10:00 am, on Albea City Number7 Highway
in the Red Hills Residential Area
an exploding gas tanker killed 72 people
and injured 15 more.
The impact was devastating.
Now to Ms, Lai Lee ,who is live at the scene.
l'm on site here, where
rescuers are searching for victims,
and experts are analyzing the disaster area.
After the original accident,
another incident occurred.
People up to three kilometers from the scene
started to lose consciousness and collapse.
For a short period, there was extreme panic,
Now, three hours later ,
things have started to calm down.
There must have been some sort of chemical
inside the tanker.
Yes, The police have told us that
the chemicals ignited and caused the explosion.
There is chance that this was a biological attack,
so because of that, no one can enter
the area of the accident,
Has the reason for the explosion been confirmed yet?
At the moment, we don't know any of the details,
However, the gas tanker was reported stolen.
The police think that there is a possibility
of biological terrorism.
That's all for now. This was live from
the scene of the accident.
Every station is talking about this.
Again...
Huh?
lt seems like last night was also Cup Ramen.
Don't be an idiot,
Yesterday, and the day before,
all 3 meals were Cup Ramen.
Did you forget?
l see...
l thought it was a dream.
lf you prefer something else, l have others.
Cup Udon... Cup Soba...
lf you pull the string it's really hot.
We also have Cup Sushi, but that expired a year ago.
lf that's okay...
Thank you for the food!
Humans can't always eat dried food.
We also need protein.
What are you talking about?
l'm saying meat tastes good.
Next time, you should catch a bigger one
instead of a smaller one.
Hey, Faye! How was it?
How was it? Listen to what l have to say.
So he's a simple-minded hacker?
l'll get him after l go to the derby.
There was a weird explosion,
Well l'm taking one...
Yeah, this.
You were there?
So there's a big fuss about this, huh?
Huh? Virus? Weapon? Oh, l see...
Huh?
Hey, what's this?
Hey you guys! Even Ein?
You're dirty! Bacteria! Bacteria!
What was that?
Ah! Please, no! Stop!
Stop it! Stop it already!
Government officials have decided to put
a 300,000,000 wulong bounty
on the head of the perpetrator of this crime.
300,000,000?
Huh?
What's the meaning of this?
Even there?
Yeah.
How was it?
lt's strange,
l've never seen anything like this.
On most of the patients,
l can see brain activity.
There's absolutely no clue as to what did it though.
We have no idea whatsoever.
l don't know any more than you do.
ln every patient, there was normal bodily activity,
but now they're all like new born babies.
lt just gets worse.
Worse than natural causes, or the Ebola virus?
lf anything, it's more like AlDS.
We can't tell what it is though.
What's that supposed to mean?
There's no evidence of anything ever being there.
lt's annoying that there aren't any clues.
The only thing that we can think of is
a new type of virus, or a biological weapon,
lt is ...
tremendously powerful.
Huh?
l'm sorry, it's my allergies.
l thought they were gone.
Maybe it has something to do with the virus.
Perhaps someone is spreading it.
Ah... this is a smoke-free section.
He's testing us.
Are you sure this is safe?
Even if it's not, you're coming with me.
l got it!
Bio-terrorism...
Spike, look at this.
l have no choice, huh?
Just to let you know,
my information isn't cheap.
l know
Hurry up and show me.
lt's very rare information.
Can you do it for us, Ed?
Alrighty!
This is the hacker, Lee Samsung.
He has a bounty of 5,000,000 wulongs.
and l've found his fake money card.
How did you do that?
l hacked into the card company.
Someone used it,
and the truck suddenly exploded.
The guy that was on it wasn't Lee.
Maybe he was an ally.
l can't really tell.
What wonderful information...
You think we can catch him
with that messed up picture?
What are you saying?
l remember his face perfectly
Here you go!
Use this pen.
You can write on the monitor with it.
On top of that, how can we be sure that
he's the criminal?
By being there without using a gas mask,
he'd already be dead.
That man is not dead.
How can you tell?
l just know...
You just know?
lt's done.
Huh?
What's this?
An Abangld's face or something?
This is great!
lf you can catch him with this drawing,
l'll pay the bounty!
ls that so...
lt doesn't matter anymore.
l 'll go catch him myself.
Ah, well that was a waste of time.
l'll go look around.
You do something?
What's the world coming to?
A woman's hunch can't be ignored
But...
Besides, sometimes l like to eat something
that's not inside a cup.
Back in the day,
there were planes flying all over the place.
Yeah, there sure were.
l used to fly a military transport
What are you talking about?
You flew a crop duster!
Really?
Do you have a moment?
l have some questions.
We're too deaf to hear anything
so that's impossible
Do you know of a seed shop?
They sell seeds everywhere around here.
A store that doesn't sell seeds around here...
Police aren't welcome.
Do l look like a cop?
More like a Yakuza...
Same thing.
l'm a bounty hunter.
So you're a cowboy, huh?
l loved them a long time ago...
Then you know what l'm here for.
You're welcome even less now.
Are you the one looking for the seed plant?
Do you have one that can't be seen
by the naked eye?
Of course.
You can get anything on a Moroccan street.
lsn't that why you came here?
Do you want bean starch? Almonds?
This one's Carbaru seed,
to get back at your wife when she's unfaithful
To see if it's a good or a bad seed, eat it fast.
lf it's poisonous,
you can throw it back up.
lf you eat it slowly,
the poison will go through your body,
and kill you before you can throw it back up.
l don't have a wife.
You're living in bliss then.
What l want to know is...
That seed is bad.
Pitacras died because of it.
You can't make light of seeds.
The one l'm looking for is the virus
used in the tanker incident.
Do you believe in demons?
Huh?
ln this world, there are things
that exist an things that don't.
Why do people worry about things they can't see?
Why do people love the air
and want to fly into space?
lt's because we all used to be able to fly.
So this place is a path to the heavens?
Anything you can see in your mind can exist.
Even if you can't see it.
So there is a virus.
That's nothing like a virus.
Reachio! l've got something good.
This one suits you perfectly.
No, this pot fits perfectly for his man.
Huh?
Yes, this pot fits you perfectly.
How does it suit me perfectly?
You should always take what suits you.
Hey! l'm not here to shop.
You just bought something
Good bye
Hey, wait a minute!
En Chara!
Hey!
Wait! Hey!
20th century games are really good,
Games from this century are getting boring.
l'm enjoying old school games like this one.
Back in the day,
games like this were enough for everyone,
Hackers are the same.
lt was better when there weren't many.
Small things like that got you left
in the history books.
Now, protection is tighter everywhere.
lf you don't do something big,
no one will recognize you.
That's why l'm grateful to you, seriously.
l always wanted to
try being a terrorist,
Aww, l died.
Let me see your license.
Where are you going?
From this point on there's only storage space.
Aww, he died.
lf they can actually see the enemy,
Sheriffs can take care of things easily,
Well, what was inside the tanker?
Nothing.
What's that suppose to mean?
That's what it means.
lt seems they've never heard of,
or seen it, before.
This is ?
Near the asteroids, we found a space truck.
The driver died instantly.
He was a convicted criminal.
A run-away?
The truck's owner was from a company
called Cherious Medical,
but they didn't even file a theft report.
There was a rumor that they had something critical
inside the truck that no one could find out about.
Then the tanker incident happened soon after.
Smells fishy,
Even for a medical corporation
they have a heavy guard.
Why don't you forcefully investigate?
You can use any reason to get in.
Things have changed since you left.
The lSSP is full of corrupt hyenas
who are just looking for money.
The higher ranks want more power.
The low lifes just get in with the Yakuza.
lf we get picked on,
it's not gonna be pretty.
Stinks like shit...
lt hasn't changed.
That's why l quit.
Do you know about Dengoku?
The place between Heaven and Hell.
lt is a place where people are left behind
and cannot ascend into Heaven.
Yes, lt is about this world.
ls this all?
ln this one capsule,
there is 30,000 of them.
lf you open the capsule it will
create copies of itself.
Hey, be careful with it!
What about the money?
lsn't this different from your offer?
You'll get the other half after the party.
You can do with the rest as you please.
uh, yeah...
l'll be saying good bye to this cheap life.
Can l ask you a question?
Why on Halloween?
ln the old days,
Halloween was a day when people prayed
for souls to go to Heaven.
You should pray.
Amigo!
Everyone in the Milky Way wants
to get that 300,000,000!~
Just like every day, it's time for the Big shot!
Like always, we'll be giving out information on bounties!
Today, we'll be on air twenty minutes longer then usual!
All because of the main target
of you bounty hunters,
and because he's worth 300,000,000 wulongs!
He's the galaxy's highest bounty ever!
The only problem is that we don't know who he is,
or what he looks like!
Don't we have any information to give out?
Nope!
We don't even know what was spread out
from the explosion!
There's no one living who saw the incident!
Then what are we supposed to be doing?
Because of this, we'll be taking calls!
We'll be giving this gift to anyone
with information!
You can call us with this number!
First come, first served!
Ahem...
Well, for now, commercial break!
Well, that was useless.
Faye! Faye!
Huh?
Can you look?
The previous shot.
Tattoo?
l looked for the same mark,
Which one is it?
Which on is it...
lt's this one.
ls that right?
Yeah, it's this one for sure.
Mars Special Force Fleet number 7.
Special Force mark, huh?
A military man...
lt was disbanded three years ago.
Do you have any date on this Force?
Yeah.
Huh?
What' this?
They're almost all dead.
Go to the next one.
What's wrong, Ein?
Really?
What? Hurry up!
Ein said it's him.
How does Ein know?
Look, he died in the Titan War.
Damn it l quit, Clean it up.
Okay...
Finding information this way doesn't suit me.
Living life easily and not doing
much suits me a lot more.
Faye!
Why do l have to be with these people
and lose my beautiful 20's years?
Faye! Faye!
l wonder... where did l go wrong?
Lee used the card again!
Oh! l forgot about that!
Hey, What's that, pottery?
Yeah, something like that.
Oh? ls my gift an octopus pot?
Well, yeah...
Who's this?
Ein said it's this person,
but Faye doesn't believe him.
Huh?
She says it's one of these five.
Vincent Boraju...
Spike...
Did you find anything?
What's this thing?
lt's the pot''best suited'' for me.
How about you?
The western was really good.
Hey...
Let Ed see too!
Very amusing.
We should sell her to the circus.
l asked the detective,
but l only found out that
there's a weird chemical place
There's something inside.
What's this?
Hey, you're pretty good.
Here they come.
Are you alone?
lf you want, l can play with you.
You're right,
but not these virtual games,
l prefer reality.
Reality?
We finally meet, hacker boy.
l was only 500 points away
from meeting Spooky Donkey.
Are you listening?
Damn it.
You almost never get to him.
How are you going to pay for this,
bounty hunting lady?
Do you have any idea what kind of
situation you're in now?
Game over, boy.
Revenge for Spooky Donkey is great.
Huh?
What? What's going on?
Wait!
What? Wait!
lt's a weird shape.
So, what's inside?
lt's a lyn lyn lymphocyte.
Lymphocyte? The ones that are in your blood?
This one has a weird shape though.
How so?
l don't really know anything about these.
This is the real lymphocyte,
but this one's a bit different.
How is it different?
Zoom in.
l still don't understand.
Then let's microwave it.
What?
lt's a really weird shape.
What's that?
Hello? Total Clean Corporation?
Please continue with your report.
The lSSP is investigating this incident
as a terrorist attack.
They have no idea who's behind it though.
The ''object '' they're investigating is a virus.
They won't be able to find out anything for a while.
However, we must be cautious.
ln the Moroccan street, there was
some information given about the accident.
We have encountered the spy,
but Mendel went into hiding.
We must solve every problem for this case.
lt's a problem that will affect
the whole nation.
Did Vincent really use ''that?''
That is a demon that can't be seen.
lt's something that shouldn't exist,
and is forbidden from living.
Vincent and Mendel...
Do you understand?
Yes.
Do you know where my car is?
Didn't you just leave?
Put your hands in the air.
l've seen that face before.
You look pretty good.
That doesn't make you look good.
ls that so?
Look backwards.
What do you know?
Do you want to pick?
lf it's heads, l'll speak honestly.
For a medical lab office lady,
you're pretty strong.
Knowing too much is sure to shorten your life.
Strong girls are my type.
Hurry!
Happy Halloween, trick or treat?
lf you don't give me something good,
l'll do something bad.
l'm smaller then what you know
l can't be seen by your eyes.
Flesh and bones are also made from me.
What does he mean?
l don't understand, but in biological terms,
there are a lot of meanings.
Did you guys see an out of fashion hat?
This is more important.
There was a message from the bounty.
Maybe it's a trick.
l would have thought the same way,
if l hadn't seen what was in the pot.
Pot?
From its appearance,
it looks like a lymphocyte.
ln reality, it's made up of thousands
of tiny machines.
These are what they call ''nano-machines.''
Nano-machines?
l see...
What do you know about it?
Nothing.
What was that?
Well, it's a machine so small that
it can't be seen by human eyes.
On top of that, they are made of proteins.
Your favorite proteins.
They can't be eaten, and are only used
for medical purposes...
Why was that thing inside the pot?
Anyway, lymphocytes aren't suppose
to be made of protein.
And?
Whoever wrote this message
knows exactly what this is.
And?
That's it.
You have no idea what it is.
This was a waste of time.
How was the medical lab?
lt's one great place.
They make some powerful medicines there.
All of their guards are equipped with G-21s.
G-21s? Those are military issue machine guns!
The public can't buy them.
There was a girl with
the same tattoo as Vincent.
That girl...
What about her?
She's pretty fine.
Anyway...
lf it involves the Army, the story changes a lot.
Solving one mystery has only made
the whole thing more mysterious.
Hey, what are you doing?
At times like this, it's best to sleep.
Hey...
Treasures should sleep and wait.
Oh yeah, l forgot.
l came here to look for a hat.
Do you know anything about it?
No.
Where did it go?
Smells weird...
Do you know, Ein?
l wonder if it's here.
Trick or treat? Give me something
or l'll do a trick.
Shut up! Halloween's tomorrow!
That's not it.
l'm going to do a trick.
Oh really? Go ahead.
Gimme!
Maybe l should do a trick, little boy.
l'm not a little boy.
l'm a girl.
What? l have no use for girls. Go home!
lt's not this one either.
Found him!
Yes? Yes? Hello?
Found him! l found him!
What?
Ed, what's going on?
l found Lee! l found him!
Great job.
l always knew you weren't just an average kid.
Where are you now?
l'm sending you my current location.
Stay there and don't move. l'm on my way!
Okay, got it.
Bye bye!
l finished level one.
Easy as cake.
You're playing the same game?
is it fun?
What kind of game is it?
She's just a little kid, damn it.
Those morons... Which building?
Which room?
ln solitaire,
every ball you jump gets taken away.
Then, if you are left with
only one ball, you win.
Ah, it's over.
So you win?
The game's climax is about to start.
What are you talking about?
Wait a minute, is that ball...
lt is only a game.
lt can't be...
You're kidding, right?
There is only one left.
l can't meet...
Spooky... Donkey...
Hey!
lt's not good for me if you die!
Get up!
Please restart...
Emergency call from Alpha One.
We have located Humpty Dumpty.
Current location is 24 point one five.
He's moving.
l'll come right over.
Don't do anything until l get there.
But l will.
He's entered between one seven
and one eight.
He's heading towards the central station.
This way! l'll go with you!
l'll be fine alone.
But...
Take care of my car.
Vincent!
l don't know your face.
but l can tell by your smell,
you reek of blood.
You're a bounty hunter?
Don't think badly of me.
lt's your fault for getting
a 300,000,000 bounty put on your head.
Why don't you shoot?
What?
What's wrong?
You only talk at the start?
Do it.
l won't kill you.
l don't want to lose the bounty.
l do not fear death.
You quietly watch a dream.
A dream that continues forever.
What a messed up guy.
ls that all?
What is your name?
Spike...Spiegal.
l'll meet you at the end of this world.
Vincent!
Vincent...
You...about me...
Why?
Vincent...
You know what, Spike?
That was a close call.
He died.
No. He was already dead.
Just like you.
The man who sank his body in the river.
His eyes found you.
Thanks.
What did you see?
Your eyes are half closed.
l was... watching a dream.
l never knew what a dream was,
and for the first time l tasted fear.
Just a little something was off.
l was dead.
lt wasn't a good day for you to die.
A swimming bird.
Those blue dreams see through everything.
The past, the future,
and also now.
Everything flows and everything is connected.
These eyes aren't looking at reality.
lt's feeling the truth.
Open the true eyes.
You have nothing to fear.
Yeah, l know...
Seems like you're alive.
What about him?
Vincent...
He disappeared,
as though he was never here.
We put ourselves in great danger.
Yeah.
My father use to say this:
A ship that goes out to sea either
goes on sailing or sinks.
We're only bounty hunters.
This is something that we can't handle.
We can still get out now.
Our involvement in this case is over.
Alright, Spike?
Hey...
You sure do sleep a lot.
Don't you want to answer?
Because of your selfish act, doesn't it feel
like it's your fault for this incident?
l'm sorry, sir.
l'll be asking you not to do anything for a while.
We'll give you further information later.
You're excused.
Watch her.
Yes, sir.
From the victim's body, the monorail incident,
and the tanker accident,
That is the same
What does the analysis of the substance tell us?
lt's currently being researched.
The virus itself acts like nothing we've seen before.
A hacker named Lee created it.
We're investigating his hack routes and information.
ls there a possibility that he's already dead?
There's a possibility that this has something
to do with a terrorist group.
What are their motives?
A random killing? Or is it for money?
That's being looked into.
So, basically everything
is under analysis or investigation?
How long are you going to keep us waiting?
The physical exam results will be ready in 12 hours.
ls it my imagination, or does my leg feel heavy?
He's been found.
A circle is a tadpole.
a circle is very beautiful
Even black grapes taste
very, very sweet.
l found it.
Cherious Medical...
Search for a truck delivery made on October 15 th.
Alright.
Spike, just to let you know...
l know. l'm just researching.
l can't sleep because l'm really curious.
You sleep too much.
Truck...truck, Cargo...cargo.
Macademia nuts inside!
Macademia nuts?
Most likely an undible seed.
Search!
Macadamia Nuts Surveillance Group.
Macadamia Nuts Research and Development.
That's an awful lot of power for just a seed.
Ed, go to Macadamia Nuts Research
and Development.
Alright.
Can you find out what they were doing in this area?
Ed's hacking program has been destroyed.
What?
When you've come so far?
Use another route to find out
about this guy, Ed.
Alright.
Doctor Mendel Alphedia.
Ex-SlT Professor and the first to research nano-machines.
As we thought,
that's not a normal water plant.
They're making nano-machine weaponry in secret.
Now Vincent, who's dead, brought it out.
ln the military,
using nano-machines was forbidden.
lf he's going to try something with it,
the military won't be sitting around.
He's still alive...
Steve...
Hey Electra.
Need something?
What's this?
Someone's blood?
l want you to research this in private.
Then you'll accept my date?
Eh?
Alright.
Good, reserve your Halloween dinner.
What's going on?
Why am l still alive?
What did you do to me?
l gave you my blood.
Now, you can live even if
the world goes wild.
Just like me...
That time will soon come.
Did you find what you wanted?
Nope.
l didn't want any of them.
The world is just like that.
People often make stuff we don't want.
That one that someone made...
The demon...
Why did you give something like that to me?
Because, the pot was meant for you.
The present inside...
A nano-machine shaped like a lymphocyte.
Dr. Mendal...
A man came to this town three years ago.
He said to himself,
l've made something horrible.
lt's designed to be transferred physically,
or aerobically.
Then, it goes into the blood
and creates more of itself.
lt moves onto a lymphocyte,
and moves wherever it pleases.
lt gets into the brain and destroys it.
Then it destroys itself and becomes protein.
lt doesn't leave any trail behind.
That's what it's programmed to do.
l just want to know one thing.
Why is Vincent alive?
Why did you do this?
For the money?
Some sort of revenge?
Or are you having fun?
l'm just looking...
Looking for a door.
A door?
l was dreaming, and l knew it was a dream.
l didn't wake up though.
Have you experienced that before?
From that time, when l was on Titan,
it's been like that always.
Vincent was an experiment.
He put anti-nano-machines in his blood.
Anti-nano-machines?
Just like the other nano-machines,
it spreads and creates more of itself.
lt kills the others, though.
ln other words, he was an experimental vaccine.
The man who was supposed to stop
the unstoppable became unstoppable.
l don't know Vincent's true objective.
He may not even have one.
Maybe he'll just wait until the end of
the Earth to receive his judgment.
Doesn't Dr, Mendal have everything?
The nano-machines and the vaccine?
He erased all the data and left the military.
He didn't have any use for
a vaccine since there was no virus.
So he thought...
That man is no longer here.
He doesn't exist.
No one can stop Vincent now.
l lost two things on Titan.
One was my past.
At that time, l had no friends or enemies.
ln the nano-machine experiments,
everyone was killed.
l was sent as a guinea pig.
Just myself to live on,
but l've lost my memories
l don't even know who l was
What's the other one?
l saw a butterfly.
l saw many butterflies.
Butterflies that were unimaginable.
When the nano-machine reaches the brain,
it seems you can see a light.
As though they were...
The world's most beautiful butterflies.
l think l've said too much.
Rachido, will you give this to the doctor?
lf l see you once more...
Let's leave it at that.
Goodbye.
Can you explain this?
Commander?
The one who should explain is you, Corporal.
About the anti-nano-machines in your blood.
Rumors spread around and fast.
Why is something that only Vincent
had in his blood now in yours?
Did you come in contact with Vincent?
For hiding information,
you'll be arrested.
Commander! lf there's a vaccine inside me,
We can produce more and give it
to the civilians!
You don't seem to understand.
Our goal is to destroy everything that
has to do with the nano-machines.
lf it's not there, it shouldn't exist.
Hey.
l wonder what kind of relation
we have with them.
lt's not that l want
to be protective of my friends
l don't have those kind of relationships.
Everyone just does whatever
they want and comes back,
and l'm being swung around all the time.
l've had it with this,
l miss the days when l was alone.
One more move and l would have won.
Hey! No! Ein!
l wouldn't care...
l wouldn't care if they come home or not.
Just like the bet.
l told myself that if the coin
toss was tails, l'd date you.
Well, this isn't a great place for a date...
Aren't you afraid?
Afraid?
By the time we get out,
we'll lose our memories or be killed.
Either, way, our daily life will be removed.
Even if you're alive, it's like you're dead.
Like Vincent?
lf you're still alive even after
the monorail incident,
it's in your body too, The vaccine...
You seem to know everything.
lt's just like you said:
Knowing too much shortens your life span.
You're notjust an average bounty hunter,
Spike Spiegel.
lt's waste of time,
just calling yourself a military unit.
My name is Electra Obilwon,
Figures...
Your name sounds strong.
l never knew that l had something
like this inside me.
Vincent is... That man has been all
alone since he was born.
From his youth, the only thing anyone
gave him was honour and hatred.
No one ever loved him.
That's why l wanted to save him.
l thought l could do it.
lt was all a misunderstanding
on the monorail.
Vincent looked at me as though
he was looking at a stranger.
l was already gone from his memories.
You loved him?
l don't know.
l didn't realize those feelings
were inside me.
l didn't know, and l lost myself.
My heart was aching, and it hurt.
Have you ever experienced anything similar?
Of course,
Maybe the one that wanted to be saved was me.
Long ago...
l was younger then...
l wasn't afraid of anything.
l didn't think about dying for a second.
l thought l was invincible.
Then l met some girl.
l wanted to live.
l started to think like that.
For the first time, l was afraid of death.
l'd never felt it before.
Where's that person now?
Gone somewhere...
lt's amazing.
You're the first person l've ever told this to.
Why are you after Vincent?
He smells just like me.
So l want to meet him.
That man, he's called Spike or something?
So he is your friend.
What do you know?
What are you going to start?
l came here to end it.
The last party is about to start.
The next trick is a special type
of nano-machine.
lt doesn't destroy itself,
it continues to reproduce,
Soon the world...
Taking the world with you?
You're insane.
Do you think so?
No one can draw a line
between sane and insane.
You have to change the border
when you think it's right.
No one else can.
You'll understand soon,
the one that's insane is the world.
Do you want to come with me?
The only ones left will be you and me.
You've got to be kidding.
l don't know what the world's going to be,
but l'd rather not live with you.
You should live all by yourself
for an eternity.
Vincent!
l told you not to come here.
l finished installing inside the jacks.
l want to go now.
The police are starting to get suspicious.
So can you give me the rest of the money?
Did you pray?
The bridge that connects
the Earth and the Heavens.
That's where l am.
The only one in the world.
You can watch as l do it.
What's going to happen to me?
lf you're a soldier,
you should be prepared,
Can you give me a cigarette?
You can at least spare one right?
Doesn't matter if you do.
Wait!
Don't shoot, don't shoot!
Throw down your weapon,
Open the door, Harris,
l'll be taking one.
So where is it?
lt's a water plant.
We were investigating,
and found Lee's hacking trace.
l understand, they're going to put it in
the water and spread throughout the city.
Send men out to post a guard.
Yes sir!
Just watch
Sir, we should get permission from the department,
in case something happens later.
This is a no-smoking facility.
Even if you act well,
nothing will ever get solved!
Lets take a little side trip.
What?
Where's your blood?
This way...
lt's open.
Put the containment suits on.
There's no use.
They'll be following us soon.
Where's Electra's vaccine?
lt's inside the third case, No, the second.
This?
Yes.
The yellow packs inside.
lt's true.
Just that the whole production isn't over yet.
ln 20 hours, every pack will contain
about 10,000 of them.
Electra, l'm sorry.
You should take the level 3 disposal path.
Thanks.
l have to wait until another time for my date?
Hey you!
We are lSSP, We are going to be borrowing this place.
We didn't hear anything about that!
We'd like for you to help us.
l don't think l can show myself like this to people.
Please go to Heaven.
Are you waiting for a phone call?
No, not really.
So you're not waiting for
Spike or Faye's phone call?
Come to think of it, l don't see them.
l didn't really notice.
Hello?
Vincent left.
Where have you been all this time?
He seems like he's going to go all out.
Seems like there's going to be a big party.
How do you know about this?
Spike? You moron,
Where have you been all this time. Huh?
The lSSP seems to have gone to a water plant.
Water plant?
Squad 4: Completed analyzing gate number 2.
Squad 2: There's nothing like it in tank 3.
Squad 3: There's something suspicious
at the entrance to plant 4.
Good, we'll be sending a analysis group.
What does it look like?
Well...it's a pumpkin-shaped balloon.
lsn't it weird to dress like a magician
to go to a water plant?
To hide a leaf in a forest, eh?
He's going to do it inside the city?
How?
His ally came and told him something about a jack,
Jack?
l see...
Jack-o-lantern.
Jack's Lantern...
We'll be starting the analysis.
Hey! What?
What's going on?
All squads, report in.
Shit!
Go tell everyone below about the situation!
Yes sir.
Chief!
What's wrong?
These are the Marines!
Chief!
Who's in command?
l didn't hear about an Army movement.
This is an undercover investigation.
The Army will be taking over this area.
What? What kind of action is this?
l have no need to tell you.
What did you say?
The analysis is complete.
The results... tell me the results now!
Didn't you hear me to stay out?
Shut up!
The substance is...
Oxygen, Carbon, Carbon Monoxide,
lron, Neon, and Krypton, Meaning...
lt's just air.
The place is all filled with people.
He said it himself, he's at a place
where Heaven and Earth are connected.
What did you say?
Jet, can you get a plane ready?
Like 20 or 30?
What?
Where are you going?
l'll be going ahead with the Swordfish.
Hey wait!
Faye , can you go to
the Environment Control Center?
Hey wait!
He lives even if the world
doesn't exist anymore.
We can't win against him.
l owe him something.
lt's impossible!
lf he just wanted to destroy the world,
he'd already have done it.
Huh?
This is an invitation from him.
lf there's no guests, there's no party.
Go, if you don't go, this won't work.
l'm counting on you.
Ah...
Damn it.
Morons never learn until they die.
Hmm?
Damn Army doesn't have anything better to do.
l don't have time
to be playing with you guys.
lt's an emergency!
Can't you do something about it?
Even though you say so,
all the fighter planes are rented
by a company and there are none left.
l don't have time.
l don't care what it is as long as it flies.
Anything that flies?
l'm still early for the party.
Well, even old planes are good.
Do they actually fly?
Leave it to us. All we have
to do is spread this around, right?
Talking badly about an old man isn't good.
Where are we going? Outer space?
You moron...
We're spraying pesticides,
why would we go into space?
To the city! To Aruba City!
We already know that...
We were just joking.
Wow, they actually flew.
What?
l don't know about the engines,
l haven't flown them in ages.
Hey you old piece of shit!
Huh?
Hey, taxi.
Who's in charge?
Who are you?
Can't you tell? l'm an average terrorist,
What are you going
to do at a place like this?
What do you want?
l want you to make it rain.
What? Why?
Lets see... because it's a party.
Ah, this isn't good.
The roads are packed
because of the parade,
The bridge that connects
the Heavens and Earth...
Hey, wait, the taxi fee!
Did the party already start?
Just now...
l remember when we shot down
those old planes...
We're almost there. Get ready.
l knew you'd come, bounty hunter.
l barely missed killing you.
lt looks like that eye
isn't just an ornament.
Did you come to save the world?
You're too late.
Too bad, l'm a bounty hunter.
l don't care what happens
to the world.
l just came here to pay back the debt.
Do you think l'm joking?
l'll really do it.
Do it.
Before you depart this world,
can you show me something?
l'm already dead from Titan,
and this world the butterflies
are showing me...
ls it a dream?
Or is their world the real one,
and the world where l was the dream?
l don't know.
Vincent!
l won't let you get away!
Electra, don't.
Let's go, together.
Vincent!
Why didn't you shoot?
l remembered
l wanted to get out of there.
l wanted to find a door to do it.
l finally know now.
There was no door.
You should have known before.
You were afraid to open your eyes.
Yes...
Electra, from the time l lived,
Being with you was
the only time that felt real.
lt's good to meet you before l go.
What did the rain do?
Before the nano-machine could spread,
the rain made the vaccine spread faster.
lt was a blessing.
After the rain, there's a rainbow.
Hey! Wanna go see some horses?
You'll never get tired of that.
all alone.
He couldn't enjoy a game with anyone else.
Like living inside a dream...
That's the kind of man he was.
ARE YOU LlVlNG lN THE REAL WORLD