Grandma.
Your eggs.
It's Billy.
Come on.
Fuck!
You been playin' my records,
you little twat!
I never played naught.
Ow!
Knob head!
If Dad knew you smoked
that stuff, he'd go mental.
Fuck off, will ya?
Twat.
Here we go, Dad!
Come on, man.
Dad!
Hurry up, Dad.
We'll be late.
The whole friggin' world's
gonna be on that picket line
this mornin'.
Oi! You tidy our room.
Dad!
There's not much
of this coal left.
It's fine. We'll be digging
it up again next month.
Don't kid yourself.
I'm not waitin' for youse.
Tony. Tony!
See you down
the picket line, Dad.
Leave it, Billy.
Mam would've let us.
Your 50 pence
is on the fridge.
Scab! Scab! Scab!
Are you sure
you're not going to come?
Am I fuck.
It's a load of bollocks.
No, it's not.
It's a load of shite,
kickin' people in.
Anyway, l don't know
why you bother.
- I'm good at it.
-Are you shite? Them gloves--
They went out with the ark.
- They're me dad's, these.
- Exactly.
Right, lads.
Listen up here.
Hold it!
Oi, oi! Here!
Now, because
they're using downstairs...
as a soup kitchen
for the strikin' miners,
I'm going to let
Mrs. Wilkinson...
use the bottom end
of the boxin' hall
for her ballet lessons.
So no hanky-panky.
Understood?
Yes.
Elliot, you're late.
Get changed
and get in here.
All right then, lads.
Give it all you got!
Round one.
Well, don't just
stand there, Elliot!
Oh, no! Not again!
This is man-to-man-combat,
not a bloody tea dance.
What're you doin', man?
Hit him!
Greavesy, he's pissin' about.
Get stuck in and
give him a belt.
- He's like a fanny in a fit.
- Billy, hit him!
Jesus Christ,
Billy Elliot!
You're a disgrace
to them gloves, your father...
and the traditions
of this boxin' hall.
You owe us 50 pence.
Ho! Liberace,
will you give it a rest?
Billy, punch bag.
You're not goin'
until you do it properly.
Give these to Mrs. Wilkinson
and her dance class
when you've finished.
I'll see you next week.
Okay, girls.
Left hand on the barre.
Thank you,
Mr. Braithwaite.
And--
Pretty arms.
Bottoms in.
Where are you lookin',
Susan?
Lift. Feel the music.
Feel it.
In time, Debbie, please.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, and five,
six, seven, eight.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, five--
And hold.
Hold it.
Support your selves!
Don't look at me. Look ahead!
Where's your confidence?
Come on.
And down.
Lovely.
Oh, God.
And, Debbie, eyes front.
And five, and six,
and seven, and stop.
For God's sake.
Thank you, Mr. Braithwaite.
Right into the center,
girls, please.
Miss?
Miss, the keys.
Not now.
Right, Mr. Braithwaite.
"The Sun Will Come Out
Tomorrow."
Fat chance.
Ready, and--
Port de bras forward.
And up.
Why don't you join in?
Port de bras forward.
And up.
And up,
and hold.
And three, and four.
And, Debbie, straight leg.
Seven and eight.
And one, and two, and three,
and four, and five.
Boots off.
Seven and eight.
What size are you?
Miss, what about
the keys?
Into the center.
Go on. I dare ya.
Prepare.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, and five,
and six, and--
And eight, and hold.
Hold it.
Ooh, what have we got
here, then?
Heel out.
Drop your hip.
Nice... straight leg.
Good arch.
Turn that leg out.
Right. Class dismissed.
Home time.
Debbie, get the 50P's.
You owe me 50 pence.
No, I don't!
- You do. Why don't you
bring it along next week?
- Can't. I'm goin' to boxin'.
- But you're crap at boxin'.
- No, I'm not!
Shut up.
Thought you enjoyed it.
Please yourself, darlin'.
I'm stepping out, my dear
To breathe an atmosphere
that simply wreaks with class
And l trust that
you'll excuse my dust
When l step on the gas
For Ill be there
putting down my top hat
Mussing up my white tie
Dancing in my tails
He was your mam's favorite,
was Fred Astaire.
We used to watch him
at the Palace Picture House...
and then dance round
the front room like lunatics.
Marvelous!
Mind, they used
to say...
I could've been
a professional.
Come on, Grandma.
Not now.
Ooh!
Grandma!
It's this one here!
It's over here!
Tony, do you ever
think about death?
Fuck off!
Night-night, then.
Plenty of boys
do ballet, you know.
Do they now?
What boys do ballet?
Nobody around here,
but plenty of men do.
Poofs.
Not necessarily poofs.
Who, like?
What about Wayne Sleep?
He's not a poof.
He's as fit as an athlete.
Bet he couldn't beat
Daley Thompson.
Maybe not in a race,
but in stamina.
Why don't you come tomorrow?
You can just watch.
I can't.
Gotta go to boxin',
haven't I?
Please yourself, then.
See you around.
Aye. See ya.
Ta-ra.
Right, lads. Look sharp.
Everybody, out!
Turn, turn and stop.
One, two, three.
Arms are in fifth.
Turn, turn and stop.
One, two, three.
Where are those arms?
I don't know what to do.
Follow the orders.
Shut up, Debbie!
One, two, three.
Nice pretty arms.
And stop.
See?
I told you it takes
loads of practice.
Debbie.
What, Mam?
What do you call me?
Miss.
Shove off.
So, do we get the pleasure
of your company next week?
It's just-- I feel
like a right sissy.
Well, don't act like one.
Fifty "P," please.
If you're not comin' again,
give us your shoes.
Nah. You're all right.
Right.
What're you doin', goin' round
here like creeping Jesus?
Naught.
We found your nana
in the Spar stores.
Where have you been?
Boxin'.
Where do you think?
What're you doin'?
I forgot me gloves.
They were
my dad's gloves.
You better take
better care of them, okay?
Copy that diagram.
We only have five minutes left.
Ow!
Hurry. This way.
You go to ballet every week?
Yeah, but don't
say aught.
Why do you take lessons?
Why do you think?
To get better, you diwy.
Do you get to wear
a tutu?
Fuck off!
They're only meant
for lasses.
I wear me shorts.
You won't ask
for a tutu?
What for?
To dance in.
I'd look
a right dickhead.
I think you'd look wicked.
I don't know why
you're lookin' at that.
You can't take that out
on a junior ticket.
See you, then.
Take me
Okay, Billy Elliot,
into the center.
I want you to watch
carefully, girls.
First, arabesque.
Drop your shoulders.
Look forward,
beyond your finger tips.
There!
Spin it, Mr. Braithwaite.
Spin it!
Come on. Spin it!
Now, focus!
Look at yourselves!
Look in the mirror!
Ahh!
Christ Almighty,
what was that?
Oi!
What's goin' on?
Uh, nothin'.
Prepare, one and two.
Strong position.
Weight on both legs.
And... pirouette.
-And down.
Up you get.
Find a place
on that bloody wall...
and focus on that spot.
Then whip your head round
and come back to that spot.
Prepare.
One, and two, and--
Fuck it.
Have you got
the spot?
Prepare!
- Prepare.
Prepare.
Go!
Go! Go!
Go, Billy!
What have l told you
about that arm?
Right.
Back to the barre.
You look like
a right wanker
to me, son.
Listen, Jackie.
It was just 50 pence
a session, you know.
I can do without it.
I do not do it for the money.
What are you talkin' about?
The boxin', man.
I haven't seen hide nor hair
of your Billy for months.
I was gonna say something,
but I thought
it might be embarrassin'.
First I knew about it.
He's never got his gloves off.
Send him round to my house,
and I'll sharp knock some sense
into him.
Scab! Scab!
Step open and balance.
Balance, balance.
Scab! Scab! Scab!
Right.
Let's do it again.
Open...
and lift your chest.
Let's do it again.
Thank you,
Mr. Braithwaite.
Step open.
Open your arms. Do it.
Pay attention.
Arms. Like this.
All right?
Thank you, Mr. Braithwaite.
Step really open!
Powerful! Proud!
You're not
concentratin'.
Yes, I am concentratin'.
You're not even tryin'.
- Can we have a go of it, Miss?
- Let's do it again.
Have you noticed
anything weird about
our Billy lately?
What, are you after
like a list?
Aye, aye.
Got enough food there,
scab?
What're you doin'?
Eh?
Scabs eat well, eh?
You're me best mate.
First rule of a union, Gary.
You never cross a picket line.
Fucking hell.
We're all fucked
if you forget that!
We're fucked anyway!
In a speech to
Tory M.P.'s yesterday,
Prime Minister
Margaret Thatcher...
referred to members of
the striking National
Union of Mine Workers...
as "the enemy within. "
The speech comes following
several months
of violent clashes...
between police officers
and striking miners--
See you, then.
Wait! Y- Your breakfast--
What the hell's he up to?
One, two, three.
Pas de bourree.
And a one, two, three.
And a turn.
Pas de bourree.
And a one, two, three.
You, out! Now!
I beg your pardon?
Please, Miss,
don't.
All right, which way
are we facing?
Come on.
And a one, two, three.
Pas de bourree.
- Ballet.
- What's wrong with ballet?
- "What's wrong with ballet"?
- It's perfectly normal.
Perfectly normal?
I used to go to ballet.
See?
Aye, for your nana.
For girls.
Not for lads, Billy.
Lads do football or...
boxin' or...
wrestlin'!
Not friggin' ballet!
What lads do wrestlin'?
Don't start, Billy.
I don't see
what's wrong with it.
You know perfectly well
No, I don't.
Yes, you do.
No, I don't!
Yes, you bloody well do!
Who do you think l am?
You know quite nicely!
What?
What are you tryin'
to say, Dad?
You're askin'
for a hidin', son.
No, I'm not. Honest.
You are, Billy.
Billy!
It's not just poofs, Dad.
Some ballet dancers
are as fit as athletes.
What about that Wayne Sleep?
He was a ballet dancer.
- Wayne Sleep?
- Aye.
Listen, son,
from now on you can forget
about the fucking ballet.
You can forget about
the fuckin' boxin' as well.
I'm bustin' my ass for those
50 pences, and you're-- No!
From now on you stay here
and look after your nana.
Got that?
Good.
They used to say
I could have been
a professional dancer...
if Id had the training.
Will you shut up?
I hate you!
You're a bastard!
Get off!
Billy! Billy!
Billy!
But you won't fool
The children
of the revolution
No, you won't fool
The children
of the revolution
No, no, no
Yeah
Aah!
You won't fool the children
of the revolution
No, you won't fool
The children
of the revolution
No, you won't fool
The children
of the revolution
No, you won't fool
The children
of the revolution
No way
Oh, hello.
My dad'll kill me
if he knows I'm here.
He stopped you
comin' to classes.
It's not his fault, Miss.
- That's all right
with you, is it?
- I suppose so.
- You should stand up to him.
- You don't know what he's like.
Well, that blows it.
Blows what, Miss?
Debbie?
I've heard a lot
about you.
Durham's little
Gene Kelly, eh?
Your dad work
down the pit, then?
Yeah.
Must be hard for the family
being out on strike.
He is out on strike,
isn't he?
'Course.
I shouldn't worry.
It won't last long.
Tom, don't.
If they had a ballot,
they'd be back tomorrow.
It's just a few
bloody commies
stirrin' things up.
Let's face it.
They haven't got a leg
to stand on.
Who doesn't?
The miners.
It stands to reason,
doesn't it?
Some pits are just
uneconomical.
If it costs more money
to pay everybody...
to dig the coal out
than you get for the coal
when you sell it,
what does that
tell ya?
Don't know.
You wanna think about that,
don't you, son?
Tom.
If it was up to me, I'd shut
the lot of'em down tomorrow.
For God's sake.
What do you do,
Mr. Wilkinson?
He's been made redundant.
I thought he was gonna
hit me or somethin'.
Don't be silly.
He's just under
a lot of pressure.
That's what mam says.
I think it's because
he drinks too much.
Does he drink too much?
He's always pissed.
Once he pissed himself.
Your dad?
Because he's unhappy, because
they sleep in separate beds.
Why do they sleep
in separate beds?
So they can't have sex.
Do they not have sex?
Dad did it with
this woman from work,
but they don't think
I know.
Do you miss your mam,
then?
Don't really miss her
as such.
It's more like
just feelin' sad.
Especially when I remember her
all of a sudden.
When I forgot that
she was dead and that.
What about your mam?
Does she not have sex?
No, she's unfulfilled.
That's why she does dancin'.
She does dancin'
instead of sex?
Your family's weird.
No, they're not.
They are, though.
They're mental.
Ow! Get off!
Wow
See?
You're a nutter, you.
Debbie! It's time
for Billy to go home!
Come on, Billy.
I'll drop you off at the corner.
I'll see ya, Debbie.
Okay, then.
Miss,
what have I blown?
This'll sound strange, Billy,
but for some time now...
I've been thinkin' of
the Royal Ballet School.
Aren't you a bit old,
Miss?
Ooh, not me. You!
I'm the bloody teacher!
They hold auditions
in Newcastle.
I'd never be good enough.
I hardly know aught.
They're not interested
in how much ballet you know.
They'll teach you that.
That's why they're a ballet school.
It's how you move and how you
express yourself that's important.
Express what?
I think you're good enough
to go for it.
It would mean
an awful lot of hard work.
But I'm banned.
Then maybe I should have
a word with him.
No, Miss!
I could teach you
on your own, if you want.
We couldn't afford it.
I'm not doin' it
for the money, Billy.
But what about Dad?
He doesn't need to know.
What about me boxin'?
Oh, for fuck's sake, Billy!
If you want to piss about
with your little mates,
that's fine with me.
All right,
don't lose your blob.
"Blob"?
So we could do it
private-like?
Just you and me.
Miss, you don't fancy me,
do you?
No, Billy, funnily enough,
I don't. Now, piss off.
Piss off, yourself.
See you Monday, then.
- Are you comin' in or what?
- What are you doin'?
Nothin'.
Just dressin' up.
Whose dress is that?
Come on.
It's me sister's.
Did she give you it?
She doesn't know.
Do you wanna try?
You can have one of me mam's.
Nah.
You're all right.
What're you doin'
that for?
I'm just tryin' it on.
Christ.
Come here.
Stay still.
There.
Won't we get
in trouble?
Don't be stupid.
Me dad does it all the time.
He dresses up
in your mam's clothes?
Only when he thinks
everybody's out.
Have you got
a tutu yet?
Do you think being
a ballet dancer...
would be better
than being a miner?
I dont know.
It's just, I've got
this audition in Newcastle
in a couple of weeks.
What for?
For to go
to ballet school.
- Ballet school?
Is that in Newcastle?
- London.
You'd have to move,
with your Tony and everybody?
No. By me self.
That's a bit steep.
- Can't you be
a ballet dancer here?
- Don't be stupid!
So, when you goin'
there, then?
I don't know.
I haven't even got in yet.
What does
your dad say?
He doesn't know.
Fuckin' hell!
- Are you not going
to tell him?
- Not yet, anyway.
He might be pleased about it.
He could rent your room out.
He couldn't.
What about our Tony?
What do you reckon?
I think
you shouldn't bother.
Why not?
I'd miss you.
Fuckin' hell.
Brought your things?
I don't know
if they're right, Miss.
If they're special to you,
they're right.
What are they for?
To give us some ideas
for a dance.
Come on, then.
Let's see' em.
What's that?
It's a letter.
I can see it's a letter.
It's me mam's.
She wrote it
for when I was 18,
but l opened it.
Here.
"To my son Billy.
"Dear Billy.
"l know l must seem
like a distant memory to you,
"which is probably
a good thing.
"It will have been
a long time,
"and I will have missed
seeing you grow.
"Missed you crying,
laughing,
"Laughing...
and shouting."
"l will have missed
telling you off.
"But please know
I was always there...
"...with you
through everything."
"with you
through everything,
"and I always will be.
"And I am proud
to have known you,
"and I am proud
that you were mine.
"Always be yourself.
I love you forever."
"Mam."
She must've been a very
special woman, your mother.
No, she was just me mam.
I brought tape and all.
What is it?
"l Love to Boogie."
It's one of our Tony's.
Spin it! Go on!
And tap. Go!
Grandma, tea time.
Where are you goin'?
Go back to sleep.
It's 4:00.
You weren't thinkin'
of taking it with you?
You just wanna stand around
getting the shit
kicked out you,
that's your funeral.
But some of us are ready
to fight back for once.
They're already after you.
- You're no good to us in jail.
- I don't plan
on getting caught.
- What's going on?
- You, get back to bed!
- Both of you!
- Fuck you.
Put it down.
You gonna stop me?
I'm warnin' you.
You haven't got it in you.
You're finished!
Since mam died, you're nothing
but a useless twat! What the
fuck you gonna do about it?
Stop it!
What the fuck
are you lookin' at?
You haven't been practicin'.
Prepare. One, two.
And one, and two--
Get up.
Miss, I can't do it.
That's because
you're not concentratin'.
I am concentratin'.
- You're not even tryin'!
- I am, Miss!
- Do it again.
- Can't.
You do it again.
No!
Shit!
I'm sorry.
It's all right
for you.
It's not you
who has to do it!
I know.
You don't know anything!
What do you know
in your posh house...
with your husband
that pisses his self?
You're the same as
everybody else. All you want
is to tell me what to do!
Now wait a minute!
Look, I don't wanna do
your stupid, fucking audition!
- You only want me to do it
for your own benefit!
- Look, Billy--
Because you're a failure!
Don't you dare talk to me
like that!
You don't even have
a proper dancing school!
You're stuck in
some crummy boxing hall.
Don't pick on me 'cause you
fucked up your own life!
Can I put a tape on, Miss?
All right,
if you must.
It's cush, isn't it?
So, is there a story,
then, Miss?
Of course.
It's about a woman
who's captured
by an evil magician.
Sounds crap.
And this woman--
this beautiful woman...
is forced to be a swan.
Except for a few hours
every night...
when she becomes alive.
She becomes real again.
And then one night...
she meets this young prince,
and he falls in love
with her.
And she realizes...
this is the one thing
that will allow her...
to become a real woman
once more.
So then what happens?
He promises to marry her
and then goes off with
someone else, of course.
- So she has to be
a swan for good?
- She dies.
Because the prince
didn't love her?
Come on.
It's time to go.
It's only
a ghost story.
Come on!
No! No, no.
It's me.
It's Billy.
Oh, little one.
Oi, little one.
What have I told you
about drinkin'
out of the bottle?
Sorry, Mam.
Well, put it back.
One.
Lift and reach.
Down, and one.
Breathe and stretch.
Stretch, and one.
Lift and stretch.
Back, and one.
Lift, and
lengthen that foot.
And it's one.
Extend.
Reach out.
Lift and breathe.
And one.
Lift out...
and close.
And one.
Lift.
When's the audition,
then?
Tomorrow mornin'.
I'll miss you
if you go away.
Who do you think's better?
Fred Astaire or Ginger Rogers?
Billy, do you not
fancy us, like?
Don't know.
Never really thought
about it.
If you want,
I'll show you me fanny.
No. You're all right.
Get down!
Thanks, pet.
Shit!
Here they come!
Tony!
Tony, go back!
Go on. Get in there!
Off you go, mate!
Miss, I've got a problem
with the audition.
Hello?
Hello!
Listings for court four.
Tony Elliot, George Brunton.
Gary Cummings.
What's the time ?
Colin Woodward.
Ten past 10:00.
Oh, Billy!
Hello.
Can I help you ?
I was lookin' for--
They're out.
Sorry.
Billy.
Please, Miss.
Don't.
What's goin' on,
Billy ?
Who the fuck are you ?
I think we better
go inside.
I know this might be
difficult for you,
but today Billy missed
a very important audition.
Audition?
For the Royal Ballet School.
The Royal Ballet?
School. It's where
they teach the ballet.
You've got to be jokin'.
No, I'm perfectly serious.
Have you any idea
of what we're goin' through ?
I've been in
a fuckin' cell
all night,
and you come around here
talkin' shite!
And you!
Fuckin' ballet!
What are you trying to do,
make him a fuckin' skirt
for the rest of his life ?
Look at him!
He's only 11 , for fuck's sake!
- You've gotta start trainin'
from when you're young.
- Shut it!
I'm not havin' any brother
of mine running around like
a twat for your gratification.
Excuse me.
This is not for my gratification.
What good's it gonna do him ?
You're not takin' him away.
He's only a bairn. What about
givin' him a childhood ?
I don't want a childhood.
I want to be a ballet dancer.
What do you know about it ?
What qualifications
have you got ?
I haven't come here
to defend meself.
For all we know,
you could be some fuckin' nutter.
Get the fuckin' Social
on to you.
- You should calm
yourself down, son.
- You say he can dance.
Well, go on, then.
Let's see
this fuckin' dancin'.
- This is ridiculous.
- If you're a fuckin'
ballet dancer,
then let's be havin' you!
- Don't you dare!
- What sort of a teacher
are you, eh ?
He's got the chance to dance.
Now you're fuckin'
tellin' him not to.
Dance, you little twat!
No?
So piss off.
He's not doin' any more
fuckin' ballet,
and if you go near him again,
I'll smack you,
you middle-class cow!
You know nothing about me,
you sanctimonious little shit!
He won't grow up
to race whippets or grow leeks...
or piss his wages up the wall.
Billy! Billy!
Billy!
Billy, come on!
Hurry up.
Merry Christmas,
everybody!
Here we go, here we go
here we go
Here we go
Here we go, here we go
here we go
Do you think she'll mind ?
Shut up, boy.
She's dead.
Well,
merry Christmas,
everybody.
Merry Christmas.
Merry
Christmas.
Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun--
Fuckin' great Christmas
this has been.
Go on.
Have some.
Where'd you get it ?
Me dad's got loads
in the kitchen.
Won't he notice ?
He never knows
how much is there.
Tastes like piss.
You get used to it.
Here.
Maybe you could
run away or something.
You know,
join a dancin' troupe.
Don't be
so stupid.
Well, maybe it's
all for the best.
What do you mean ?
You won't have to
go away or nothin'.
Me hands
are freezin'.
Give us'em here.
What are you doin' ?
Nothin'.
Just warmin'
your hands up.
You're not a poof
or aught ?
What gave you
that impression ?
Aren't your hands cold ?
I quite like it.
Just 'cause
I like ballet...
doesn't mean
I'm a poof, you know.
You-- You won't
tell anyone, will you ?
Come on.
It's fuckin' freezin'
in here.
Here.
What's this ?
Just put it on.
A tutu.
...and as he's walking
through the bush there,
George. George,
there's somebody
in the club.
this kangaroo,
he's walkin' away
over it, right ?
And he's called Norman.
And then round the corner
came this wallaby--
Plie, first.
What's a plie ?
It's French.
Why's it French ?
I don't know.
Second.
Like a princess.
Second, and down.
And first.
Carry on. Fifth.
Shoulders down,
long neck.
How do I look ?
Fuck off.
Shut up, you poof.
Second,
and down.
And first.
Fifth. Second.
Down.
First.
Fifth.
Jackie.
Jackie, man.
Here.
Give us your hand.
Dance!
Dad!
Go home, son.
It is a friend
of yours, then.
How much
is it gonna cost ?
And a happy Christmas
to you too.
Not as much
as you might think.
Maybe two grand.
But there's a good chance
the council's--
Two grand?
I was talkin'
about the auditions.
Look, if it's just
a matter of the trip
to London,
I'll give you
the money
for the fare.
I didn't come here
to be patronized.
Oh, no one's tryin'
to patronize you.
You're bein' ridiculous.
Am I ?
Yes!
Thanks for everything
you've done for Billy.
But he is my son,
isn't he ?
I'll handle this myself.
Hey, fellow.
Name. You.
Paul.
Surname.
Felton.
Shorty. You.
What ? Thorpe.
Thorpe.
Smith.
Glenton.
Glenton. Kerner.
Kerner.
Is that the lot, then ?
Fuckin' hell.
Never thought
I'd see you down here.
Things change, eh ?
Right,
you, name.
Jackie Elliot.
Well, glad to see
you've come
to your senses.
Who's a big man now, eh ?
Right. Okay, you lot.
Over here.
All aboard the sky lark.
Look lively.
Can't smoke on here, mate.
These are private buses.
Scab! Scab! Scab!
Fuckin' prats! Scab!
Scab! Scab! Scab! Scab!
Scab! Scab! Scab!
Scab! Scab--
Fuck off!
Dad! Dad!
Give us a hand.
Dad!
What the fuck
you doin' ?
Dad, you can't
go back! Not now!
Look at the state of us.
What we got to offer
the poor sod ?
You can't do this!
Not now!
Not after all this time!
Not after everything
we've been through!
It's for wee Billy!
He may be a fuckin' genius
for all we know!
Fuck!
For fuck's sake, Dad!
You can't do this!
Dad! Dad!
Tony!
He's only 11 ,
for fuck's sake!
He's a kid. He's just
a fuckin' little kid!
I'm sorry.
Please.
We're finished, son.
What choice
have we got, eh ?
Let's give the boy
a fuckin' chance!
Please.
Please, don't do this.
Dad, we'll find him
some money.
We'll find it
for him.
What the fuck
is he doin', Tony ?
It's okay.
He's gonna be okay.
Just get him
out of here, Tony.
Away. Leave it.
Go on.
Leave us.
Let's go home, Dad.
Dad's right,
you know.
Mam would've
let you.
All them 50 pences.
Here. It was a toss-up
between a new punch bag
or you.
It's not even enough
for the bed
and breakfast.
Forget about it.
You're dreamin'.
Look at youse.
Fuckin' scrabblin' round
for 50 pences.
You've got to do
better than that.
How ?
I'm gonna have
a raffle at the welfare.
And Im gonna organize
a concert.
Thanks, George.
Sheila's not got
that kind of money.
She can't even keep
her soup kitchen open.
George said we can have
another whip-round.
Billy, there's
no money left. Get that
through your head, man!
The lads
will always dip into
their buckets if we ask them.
George, you know
there's nothing left.
Stop putting ideas
in his head, man!
Come on, lads.
Dig deep for the miners.
Is that
absolutely necessary ?
Walk normal,
will ya ?
So what's it like,
like ?
What's what like ?
London.
I don't know, son.
I never made it
past Durham.
Have you
never been, like ?
Why would I want
to go to London ?
It's the capital city.
Well, there's no mines
in London.
Christ.
Is that all
you think about ?
Can I help you ?
Billy Elliot.
We've come for an audition.
Oh, you mean
William Elliot.
Yeah, William.
Can you
go upstairs, please ?
This way ?
Thanks.
Yes.
This your first time ?
Yeah.
I've been doing this
for two years now.
Hello.
Nerve-racking,
isn't it ?
Where are you from ?
Everington.
County Durham.
Durham ? Isn't there
an amazing cathedral ?
Don't know.
Never been.
Up on the box,
please.
All right,
bend over.
Right down.
And come up.
Come up.
Head down.
Tiny curvature here.
Head down!
How tiny ?
Might not be
a problem.
Come on.
Keep coming.
Relax. All right.
Jump up, William.
It's Billy.
Billy Elliot.
Two,
three and four.
Dad. Dad!
Dad,
for fuck's sake!
I changed me mind.
Get back in there!
Don't be so stupid!
And you are ?
Billy Elliot
from Everington.
l beg your pardon ?
Billy Elliot.
Ah, yes,
of course.
Come to the barre,
please, Billy.
Left arm
on the barre.
Feet first.
Arms second.
Demi-plie
and... hold.
Now, Billy,
we'd like to see you
move to some music.
Do you have
a piece prepared ?
Thank you.
You all right ?
What's the matter ?
It was a waste
of fuckin' time!
Don't be upset.
It's only
a stupid audition.
It's all right.
Fuck off!
There's always
next year.
Look. Fuck off,
will ya!
Oh--
You bent bastard!
What on earth's
going on here ?
How did it go ?
Shit!
Mr. Elliot, I'm afraid
that mutual respect...
and self-discipline
are absolute prerequisites
for any pupil in this school.
Such displays of violence
cannot be tolerated
under any circumstances.
Do you understand?
I realize we shall
have to consider this
very seriously...
and it will be
bound to affect
our final decision.
Yes, well,
just a few questions, then.
Billy, can you tell us...
why you first
became interested
in ballet ?
Don't know.
-Just was.
- Well, was there any...
particular aspect
of the ballet which...
caught your imagination ?
The dancin'.
He dances all the time.
Every night after school.
Yes. Well, we have
a very enthusiastic letter...
from Mrs. Wilkinson,
and, uh,
she has told us...
of your personal
circumstances.
Mr. Elliot, are you
a fan of the ballet ?
I wouldn't exactly say
I was an expert.
You do realize
that all pupils...
must attain
the highest standards,
not just in ballet
but in their ordinary
academic work.
No child can succeed
without the 100% support
of the family.
You are completely
behind Billy ?
Are you not ?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
Do you want to ask us
some questions ?
No, not--
Not really, no.
Well, in that case,
we shall let you know
in due course.
Just one last question.
Can l ask you, Billy,
what does it feel like...
when you're dancing ?
Don't know.
Sort of feels good.
It's sort of stiff and that,
but once I get goin',
then l, like,
forget everythin'.
And...
sort of disappear.
Sort of disappear.
Like I feel a change
in me whole body.
Like there's fire
in me body.
I'm just there, flyin'...
Like a bird.
Like electricity.
Yeah.
Have a safe
journey home.
Mr. Elliot,
good luck
with the strike.
Toast!
I think you should
get yourself a trade, son.
Somethin' useful.
I could have been
a professional dancer.
What happened
to the dinosaurs, miss ?
They were crushed
as well,
and the pressure of all
of this caused the plants
and trees to change into coal.
Ow!
That's what must have
happened to her.
MichaeI Caffrey,
if you have got
something to say,
you can say it
to the class.
Sorry, miss.
So, gradually,
over hundreds
of thousands of years--
Post!
This is it.
Have you heard
anything yet ?
Not yet.
You'll have
no problem, man.
Fingers crossed, eh ?
I got in.
He did it!
He fuckin' did it!
Jackie,
have you not heard, man ?
We're goin' back.
Strike's over, Jackie.
The union caved in yesterday.
l think Im scared, Dad.
That's okay, son.
We're all scared.
If I don't like it,
can I still come back ?
You kiddin' ?
We've let out
your room.
Whoa!
Whoo!
...four, five, six,
seven, eight.
And one, two,
three, four,
five, six, seven--
Keep going,
girls!
Three, four, five--
Miss, I just came
to tell you.
It's all right, Billy.
I heard it from Debbie.
Look, it was just--
Well, you know,
after everything.
I'll miss you, Miss.
No, you won't.
I will. Honest.
This is when you go out
and find life...
and all
those other things.
The best of luck, Billy.
Right. Back to
the barre, girls.
And again.
Thank you.
One, two,
three, four--
Debbie, eyes front.
Seven and eight.
And one, two,
three, four,
five, six, seven.
Was she there ?
Yeah.
You'll miss
the bus.
We're off.
I'll take it.
Give us the bag.
Okay, we're late.
We've no time for that.
I'll take it.
Good-bye, Billy.
See ya.
Oi, dancin' boy!
We'll miss the bus, Billy.
Will you stop being
an old fuckin' woman ?
See you, then.
- I'll miss you.
- What ? Can't hear you.
Dad. Come on, man.
We're gonna be late.
Dad!
Come on!
Show's just started.
Excuse me.
Can you tell Billy Elliot
that his family's here?
Sorry, mate.
It's all right,
Tony.
It's me, Michael. Remember?
It's Michael.
What the bloody hell
you doin' here?
I wouldn't have
missed it for the world.
Standby, please.
Billy, your family
are here.
Thanks.