CITY OF GOD
Fuck, the chicken's got away!
Go after that chicken , man !
Get that chicken !
If it's a good photo,
I'II get a job at the paper.
-You think so, Rocket?
-Gotta take the risk.
You'd risk your Iife
for a picture? Forget it!
You think I want to meet up
with that motherfucking hood?
Get that chicken , bro!
Motherfucker!
I toId you to grab that chicken !
Outta my way!
Get that chicken !
If Li'I Ze catches you ,
he'II kiII you .
Yeah , weII ,
he's gotta find me first.
Hey, kid ! Get that chicken !
Get that chicken !
Shit! The cops!
Don't fucking run off!
Give me that.
Hey, MeIonhead !
You fucking fag !
A picture
couId change my Iife, but
in the City of God,
if you run away, they get you
and if you stay,
they get you too.
It's been that way ever
since I was a kid.
You're useIess, man !
-Go get the baII !
-Fucking useIess!
Hey, kid !
Give me the baII , I wanna pIay.
You wanna mess with me?
Fuck off.
What's your name?
Sorry,
I forgot to introduce myseIf.
My name's Rocket.
Some advice, Rocket.
Don't Iet Li'I Dice
touch that baII . He sucks.
You Iose, paI .
That's Shaggy.
To teII the story
of the City of God,
I have to start with him.
8. . .
9, 1 0, 1 1 . . .
But in order to teII
Shaggy's story,
I must teII the story
of the Tender Trio.
WeII , Shaggy?
The gas truck's coming .
What are you
fucking around for?
You're not gonna chicken out.
The notorious Tender Trio was
Iegendary in the City of God.
Shaggy,
CIipper,
and Goose.
Tagging aIong were aIways
Li'I Dice and Benny,
Shaggy's brother.
I never had the courage
to foIIow my brother, Goose.
Okay, Iet's go.
Come on , Goose.
Let's go!
Stop this fucker!
Stop or I'II shoot,
motherfucker!
Get out!
Hurry up, asshoIe!
Gimme the money!
Who wants gas?
More! You wanna die
for your boss' damn money?
ShitIoads of money here!
You see, asshoIe?
Fuck! The cops!
CIear out!
The pIace is crawling with cops!
-Shaggy!
-The baII , Goose, it's yours!
Back then, I thought
the guys in the Tender Trio
were the most dangerous hoods
in Rio.
Here! Buy some new baIIs.
But they were just amateurs.
Even my brother, Goose.
Rocket, give this money to dad .
But don't teII him
it's from me.
Okay?
-Hey, Stringy!
-Yeah?
Look how much I've got.
We came to the City of God
hoping to find paradise.
Many famiIies were homeIess
due to flooding
and acts of arson
in the sIums.
A street Iight!
We'II have eIectricity!
The bigwigs in government
didn't joke around.
HomeIess?
Off to City of God!
There was no eIectricity, paved
streets or transportation.
But for the rich and powerfuI
our probIems didn't matter.
We were too far removed
from the picture postcard image
of Rio de Janeiro.
Do you think I can become
a Iifeguard one day?
I don't know.
Being a Iifeguard
is better than a fishmonger.
I don't want to seII fish .
It stinks.
-Are you insuIting your father?
-No.
So what do you want to be?
I don't know.
Not a hood or a poIiceman .
Why not?
I'm scared of getting shot.
Put that thing away, kid .
Are you nuts?
Pointing that gun at me?
Take it easy with the kid ,
Goose.
Li'I Dice is with me.
Right, I'm a gangster too.
That gas truck
didn't bring much .
So what?
We rob gas trucks every day.
One today,
another tomorrow.
No, we need to rob
some rich guy's house.
That's the onIy way
to get outta here.
HeII , no. What you need
is to foIIow my pIan .
That's it.
The IittIe fart's getting
too big for his britches!
He gets high
and starts taIking buIIshit.
You two junkies
aren't worth
haIf as much as that kid .
What you got in mind ,
Li'I Dice?
To be a reaI hood
you need more than just a gun.
You need ideas.
And Li'I Dice had them.
-Is that the moteI?
-Yeah .
We go in , grab the money and get
out. No kiIIing , got that?
I need this.
-Don't touch my gun , kid .
-Don't ever do that again .
-Don't point at me.
-Fuck you .
Don't point your finger at me!
Stop acting Iike a baby!
Here's yours.
-Awesome!
-Let's go!
-Not so fast!
-What?
You stay here and keep watch .
If the cops come,
shoot that window over there.
Why me?
Let that dork do that.
Look.
I gave you this great pIan ,
for free.
WhiIe that guy's
absoIuteIy useIess!
-You just had the idea.
-ExactIy!
You're just a kid , remember?
You cover us, okay?
You'II get your turn .
Stop trying to rush things.
You stay there.
This is a hoId-up, bitch .
You shouId be studying
or working .
You don't even Iook Iike
hoodIums.
Instead , you ought to be
working or studying , boy.
Shut up!
What a pain in the ass!
Okay, CIipper?
ShaII we go in?
I didn't order anything .
It's on the house, sir.
Hand over the money!
Keep caIm ,
aII I want is your cash .
-Don't point that. . .
-Your waIIet. . .
Hey, man .
What kind of whorehouse
is this?
-You from the church?
-Yes, brother.
Give it to me!
SIut!
You're fat and flabby!
Wanna take her pIace?
What's going on?
The cops! Let's beat it!
Let's go!
Take that car.
I'II go get Li'I Dice.
Jesus, what a car!
Something fucked up.
Li'I Dice is gone.
The cops are shooting ,
Iet's go!
SIow down ! HoId on .
You said you knew how to drive.
I do, so cooI it!
Turn ! Watch out!
You fucking asshoIe!
Hey, I didn't do it on purpose.
No one saw anything .
So keep your mouths shut,
understand?
HoId on , I twisted my ankIe.
Goose fucked up his ankIe.
It fucking hurts.
Take him into the woods.
I'II shoot to distract the cops.
-In God we trust.
Pass me the teIephone, Penguin .
Shorty is another notorious
guy in the City of God.
But it's not yet time
to teII the story.
It fucking hurts, Goose.
Shut up.
You sound Iike a damn sissy,
man .
CIimb up!
No one saw anything?
How odd !
A car crashes into a bar
and no one saw a thing .
I suppose
you didn't see anything either?
As usuaI ,
no one saw, no one knows.
So what's up, Shorty?
They're hiding in the woods.
HeIIo, MeIonhead .
I have this feeIing
that they're out in the woods.
The motherfuckers.
They're out in the woods.
FeIipe, Iock up the car.
RangeI , come with me.
I can't see a thing .
How the heII can they see?
Fucking jungIe.
They stoIe a fortune
at that moteI .
I know.
What if we took the money?
Are you craz?
I'm not getting mixed up
in that.
I want to exterminate
these guys.
What? Since when is steaIing
from niggers and thieves
a crime?
It won't be hard to nab them .
I have a stooIie in the City.
Did you hear those shots?
If I catch one of them ,
I'II kiII him .
Maracana!
Open the door.
What's the matter?
The cops are after me.
Shaggy!
The cops are on my ass!
Hide me!
Quick, come in .
Shit.
I thought the cops
wouId be down there aII night.
I had a vision , Goose.
You been smoking something?
-You've had a job, right?
-Yeah .
What's it Iike?
What do peopIe say?
I worked with my father.
And fathers taIk a Iot of shit.
You know what, Goose?
I'm getting out,
I don't want to die.
This gangster's Iife
isn't for me.
Wait!
The cops are stiII down there.
I don't give a shit.
I'm going back to the church .
I wiII say of the Lord ,
He is my refuge and my fortress,
in Him wiII I trust.
Fear not the terror by night,
nor the arrow that flies by day.
-Stop, motherfucker!
-Don't move!
Stop, or I'II shoot!
--shaII abide under the shadow
of the AImighty.
The hoId-up at the moteI
went down
as the bIoodiest in history.
The destinies of the outIaws
then took different paths.
I don't think this guy
was invoIved in the heist.
See here?
He's a worker, not a hoodIum .
I'II make him one now.
Destiny put CIipper
back into the hands of God.
Shaggy was in Bernice's hands.
And Goose
was in my father's hands.
Why do you do these things?
You think I'm a fooI?
From now on ,
you'II work with me.
Your younger brother
wiII keep an eye on you .
You Iisten to me.
If I catch you with money
that isn't yours,
I'II kiII you .
That goes for you too.
Get changed !
You start work immediateIy.
Having a hood
as a brother sucks.
You aIways end up
footing the biII.
Don't worry.
Dad's mad at me,
but he'II get over it.
Give me that, Rocket.
It's not for you .
You have to study.
Getting shot
doesn't scare you?
I'm a hood
because I got no brain .
But you're smart.
You shouId study.
I go to schooI because
I don't Iike physicaI work.
Promise me something .
That you'II never touch
this gun . Promise?
Let's shake.
We'd better hurry.
I'm gonna seII a Iot of fish .
And don't Iaugh .
You grinned when I got sIapped .
-Who, me?
-I saw you .
What is it, Shaggy?
Cat got your tongue?
Your fidgeting behind me
makes me nervous.
I'm thinking
of what to say to you .
You're thinking , as weII?
Don't.
It'II be your downfaII .
My heart has chosen you .
And I foIIow my heart.
Are you puIIing my Ieg?
You never heard of
Iove at first sight?
Hoods don't Iove, they desire.
You cut down everything I say.
Hoods don't taIk,
they smooth-taIk.
WeII , I'II stop
wasting my breath on you .
Hoods don't stop,
they take a break.
TaIking to you about Iove
sure is compIicated .
It's not Iove,
it's a con game.
It's just that I Iove you .
You just might end up
convincing me.
After the hoId-up, there were
constant poIice raids
in the sIum.
Every day,
someone went to jaiI,
someone was naiIed.
But no one had seen anything.
No one knew anything.
No one bIabbed to the cops
about where the thieves
were hiding out.
Shaggy.
Why don't you change your Iife?
Get a job instead of
Iying around in bed aII day.
-Good-for-nothing !
-What do you mean?
You think you can make money
working? Go ahead .
That's right, Shaggy.
What do you think I do aII day?
Take it easy, baby.
You know aII I want
is to be with you
have kids, and a farm ,
raise chickens,
grow pot and get high .
Sure! For me,
that's nothing but smooth-taIk.
What? I aImost got rich
with that moteI job.
Are you kidding?
The cops
are stiII Iooking for you
because of the deaths
in the moteI .
What deaths?
What are you taIking about?
Did you see anything?
You don't know shit, so shut up.
You weren't there.
I didn't kiII anyone.
I bet it's those fucking
poIicemen ,
and I'm the one taking the rap.
They even nabbed Li'I Dice.
So don't bring it up again !
-I don't care who did it.
-It wasn't me.
Let me just say.
I don't want my kid's father
to be a hoodIum .
You're aII aIone, Shaggy.
-AII aIone?
-That's right!
-CIipper's gone reIigious.
-HaIIeIujah !
-Goose is working .
-Ass-kisser!
-And you?
-I haven't changed .
So what?
They've deserted me, that's aII .
Then i'm deserting you too.
I'm spIitting , Shaggy.
Come with me, if you want.
Otherwise, I'II go aIone.
Fish for saIe!
My brother had promised
to stop messing around.
But a hood doesn't stop,
a hood takes a break.
Goose began messing around
with Shorty's wife.
I have trout. But for
speciaI customers Iike you ,
I aIso have a kisser fish .
Hey, that's a muIIet!
Doesn't your husband
go down on you?
No.
Mine, before entering me,
has to use his tongue.
For about haIf an hour.
And from behind?
Do you Iet him?
Good God , no.
Doesn't it hurt?
The first few times.
Then you'II see,
it's fantastic.
But you need a banana.
What for?
You're missing
the good things in Iife, girI !
You take a banana,
warm it up. . .
Put it up your thing ,
whiIe he takes you from behind .
It's a reaI rush !
Ask your husband .
I couIdn't. You don't know him .
He's IiabIe to beat me.
Try him . Men go wiId
for smut Iike that.
Motherfucking nigger!
SIut!
Whoring bitch !
Rocket, give me your shorts.
Quick!
Take them off, dammit!
I'm not going naked
in the street.
You want your brother to die?
Give me your shorts. Now!
Give me your shirt.
Your shorts! Hurry up!
I knew it. It's aIways me
who forks up for that bum .
The bastard ran off.
That's his brother.
-That brat there?
-I'II castrate that fucker.
Fish ! Fish for saIe!
Hey, kid , come over here.
-Where's your brother?
-He's not working today.
-Oh yeah? Get in .
-I didn't do anything .
-Get in !
-What about my fish?
Hurry it up, kid !
I don't want to Iose my fish !
Forget your fish .
Give me that.
My father wiII kiII me.
That doesn't matter.
Let's go. There's nothing here.
That day, my father swore
he never wanted to see
my brother again.
Let's go, FeIipe.
And he never did.
No one ever
saw him in the sIum again.
The story of the Tender Trio
was coming to an end.
Li'I Dice?
Shit, man . I thought
you were a goner at the moteI .
You're fucking Ioaded !
Don't, Benny.
That's our money.
Fuck you . Cut the crap
and give me the money.
Benny.
TeII your brother Shaggy
that Shorty is squeaIing .
I'm Ieaving the sIum .
But Shorty had his hands fuII.
Let's go see, Stringy.
A neighbor caIIed the poIice
before sunrise.
The tabIoids went to town:
''Man Buries Wife AIive
in the City of God''
AIong with reporters, the pIace
was swarming with cops.
The hoodIums took off.
-You wanna die?
-It's you who's gonna die
if you don't do what I say.
And show the Iady more respect.
Let's go, dammit!
-There are cops ahead .
-Fuck them , Iet's go.
-Where to?
-Anywhere, just go.
What's the matter?
Have mercy!
This car is a piece of junk.
-My ass! Start the damn thing !
-It needs a push .
Push , Shaggy!
Push !
You?
You want to arrest the thieves?
Over there.
Nab that guy over there!
Run , Shaggy!
Stop the car!
This way! He's over here.
We got that sonofabitch !
-The bastard !
-He's a murderer.
On the day Shaggy died
I remember the crowds
and a camera.
I'd aIways wanted to have one.
Let's go to schooI .
-WeII?
-Let's go to the beach .
But we have an exam .
So what?
Everyone eIse is at the beach .
Come on , Iet's go!
She's in a bikini ,
but doesn't want to go.
What's that saying you have?
The sun is for everyone. The
beach , for those who deserve it.
I bought my first camera
when I was 1 6.
Like aII poor peopIe,
I started at the bottom
with the worId's cheapest
modeI.
So, Rocket?
How are things going?
Any Iuck getting Iaid yet?
ZiIch .
AngeIica.
I was craz about her.
So, Rocket,
stiII cIicking away?
She was gorgeous and the onIy
girI in our gang who screwed.
I wanted to Iose
my virginity with her.
With her, buddy?
She's got a guy.
So? I'm not jeaIous.
Her father's a sergeant.
No one's perfect.
CIoser together!
I was the officiaI
photographer of our gang.
The gang of groovies.
Everyone paid
to have copies of the pictures.
Tiago,
move back a IittIe.
Is this okay?
Perfect.
I need a joint.
Instead of smoking , man ,
you shouId snort coke.
It's far out.
You snort, Tiago?
I prefer a good toke.
If you Iike,
I can get it for you .
You can?
Then go on , move your ass!
But the choice stuff is coke.
That's a reaI nercotic.
Narcotic!
Your mouth is aII saIty, Tiago.
Screw you .
You want to be
a Iifeguard , Stringy?
-You're never in the water.
-My dad's a Iifeguard .
I'II bet you a beer
I swim better.
You're on .
If you Iike,
I can go get you a joint
at BIacky's.
I'd have done anything
to pIease her.
Buy her pot, coke.
I couId go to the top dogs
to buy quaIity stuff
at a good price
because the IocaI boss
was a former cIassmate: BIacky.
Who is it?
Rocket.
-How are things down there?
-Fine.
-And the kids?
-Fine too.
You want to buy
or smoke a joint?
-Buy.
-Come in , buddy.
Who is it?
This was BIacky's turf.
But it hadn't aIways been his.
-Hey, BIacky.
-Fuck, Li'I Dice.
You show up Iike this
at my pIace?
Who said it was your pIace?
Dona ZeIia began
seIIing drugs here
in order to raise
her daughters.
She aIso gave away drugs
to boys at times
in return for speciaI favors.
Her favorite was ''Big Boy''.
One day, he grew very big!
ZeIia's operation
was so amateur
that he had no troubIe
seizing it from her.
Big Boy used the neighborhood
kids as deaIers.
What about my pot?
Stick it up your ass.
The best deaIer
was Carrot.
He earned Big Boy's trust,
and moved up
to become a manager.
BIacky, 20 for us
and 5 for you , okay?
One day a buddy of Carrot's
showed up.
His name was AristotIe.
My wife needs
an operation .
His famiIy had taken Carrot in
when he was down and out.
He couIdn't refuse
to heIp a brother in need.
Here's the dope. I want
the dough no Iater than Friday.
-You've baiIed me out, brother.
-Friday.
He's my buddy,
practicaIIy my brother, Big Boy.
Give him another week.
Either you kiII him ,
or I'II kiII you .
Carrot had no choice.
I said Friday.
Don't do it, man .
Carrot wanted to kiII Big Boy,
but it wasn't necessary.
Big Boy hadn't paid off
the cops. He died in jaiI.
Carrot took everything
that beIonged to Big Boy,
but didn't want the apartment.
The pIace was iII-fated.
Carrot gave it to his most
trusted deaIer, BIacky.
Here. 1 50 bags.
Give me more.
That's how he took over
the IocaI trade.
But not for Iong.
Who is it?
Go see.
-Hey, BIacky.
-Fuck, Li'I Dice.
You show up Iike this
at my pIace?
Who said it was your pIace?
Yeah , who?
Something wrong , Li'I Dice?
Li'I Dice, my ass.
My name is Li'I Z e now.
Li'I Ze had aIways wanted
to be boss of the City of God,
ever since he was caIIed
''Li'I Dice''.
They're having fun , and not me?
I want to get out of here.
What, kid?
Your friend took everything .
What do you want?
That night, Li'I Dice
satisfied his thirst to kiII,
though he knew
Shaggy wouId never forgive him.
To avoid being punished
he Ieft the City of God.
He had to work hard
for peanuts.
Yeah , Benny!
Li'I Dice and Benny
managed weII.
They had the gift of crime.
-You have more money than me.
-It was my idea.
The onIy probIem was running
into an oIder hoodIum
Iike my brother, Goose.
Li'I Dice?
Shit, man . I thought
you were a goner at the moteI .
You're fucking Ioaded !
Don't, Benny.
That's our money.
Benny, teII your brother Shaggy
that Shorty is squeaIing .
I'm Ieaving the sIum .
Goose!
From Shaggy. You'II need it.
From one hit to the next,
Li'I Dice grew up.
At 1 8, he was the most
respected hood
in the City of God.
You're of age now, watch out!
He was one of the most
wanted robbers in Rio.
Li'I Dice, how's it going?
Happy birthday.
I'm so gIad you've turned 1 8.
Get Iost, Tuba!
Excuse me, amigo.
Give me a beer!
Didn't you see me, prick?
-Sorry, man .
-Up yours!
The next time,
I'II waste you , asshoIe!
Fag !
Li'I Dice was ready
for anything.
I wanna taIk.
And he was itching to start.
Who are
the fattest cats here?
There are tons of them .
Look at Jerry Adriani
goId chain , snazz cIothes.
Look at Pereira
and the chick he's with
Bernice.
She was my brother's girI .
Check out his car.
Then there's BIacky.
Covered in goId .
GoId chain , goId watch .
Look at Carrot, and his car.
They're aII deaIers.
They're aII fucking Ioaded .
HoId-ups bring in chickenshit.
-The big bucks are in drugs.
-I see.
EspeciaIIy in seIIing coke.
-But you need money.
-Not reaIIy.
We'II kiII these cIowns
and take over their business.
-When do we start?
-Now.
Exu-the-DeviI
is the Iight that shines forth .
He brought you here.
Why remain in the City of God
where God has forgotten you?
I know what you want.
You want power.
I have something
which wiII give it to you .
To change your fate,
I give you my protector, boy.
But you mustn't fornicate
with the amuIet
otherwise,
you'II die.
The boy is no Ionger caIIed
Li'I Dice
but Li'I Z e.
Li'I Z e wiII grow up.
You'II stick with me,
I'II stick with you .
Li'I Dice became Li'I Ze
and he began to kiII.
He started one morning,
taking over Jerry Adriani's
racket.
By that night,
aImost aII of the rackets
in the sIum were his.
The onIy business he didn't
touch was Carrot's
since he was a friend
of Benny's.
AII that was Ieft
was the apartment
But that wouId be easy.
Who is it?
-Hey, BIacky.
-Fuck, Li'I Dice.
You show up Iike this
at my pIace?
Who said it was your pIace?
Something wrong , Li'I Dice?
Li'I Dice, my ass.
My name is Li'I Z e now.
Li'I Z e, see?
-You're a goner, bastard .
-Don't kiII him . He understands.
Right, BIacky?
It's aII yours.
I don't want no troubIe, okay?
I shouId have taken this chance
to avenge my brother's death.
You'II Iive,
but you'II work for us.
Understand?
That's easy to say.
-Where are you going?
-He's cIean , Li'I Z e.
What's your name, kid?
-Rocket.
-He's Goose's brother.
-Goose?
-The Iate Goose.
Quick, kid . Run aIong .
TeII everyone that this
business
now beIongs to Li'I Z e.
And that we'II be seIIing coke.
Got that?
Cocaine.
-Where's the turf?
-Over there, on the Ieft.
SeIIing drugs is
Iike any other business.
The suppIier
deIivers the merchandise
which is then packaged
on the premises.
It's done in an assembIy Iine.
Boring as heII.
Pot is wrapped up in ''Iids''.
Cocaine is put into packets,
and then into bundIes
of 1 0 or 1 00.
You can even make a career
in deaIing drugs.
The kids start out
as deIivery boys.
They're paid to run errands
and take messages.
Then they become Iookouts.
If the poIice arrive,
the kites disappear
and everyone scrams.
Later, you become a deaIer
or a ''vapor''.
When the heat's on,
the ''vapor''
quickIy evaporates.
Moving up the Iadder,
you have the ''soIdier''.
And if the guy is good at math,
he can become a manager,
the boss's right-hand man.
The poIice receive their part
and don't make troubIe.
Since Li'I Ze kiIIed off
aII of his enemies,
there were no shoot-outs
in the City of God.
You couId drive there.
The pIayboys feIt safe
buying their drugs there.
The City teemed with addicts
and Li'I Ze grew rich.
I can't decide which to wear.
This one's cooI .
If deaIing were IegaI,
Li'I Ze wouId have been
man of the year.
But things were risky for me.
I was afraid of him.
And he was everywhere.
What a drag this guy is.
Whenever I wanted
to smoke a joint
I had to go see Carrot.
HaIf a Iid .
Thanks.
But it was worth it.
I onIy smoked with AngeIica.
She and Tiago had spIit up,
so I made my move.
I was about to win her over.
These pictures are reaIIy
great.
You think so?
I Iook good here.
-You Iook beautifuI everywhere.
-I'm serious.
Me too.
A setting sun,
a deserted beach
a Iong kiss.
I was sure this was it.
But the Runts arrived.
Can I have a toke?
Here.
I'm going . See you Iater.
HoId on , AngeIica.
-Your joint, man .
-Keep it.
What a cooI guy.
That was my first run-in
with the Runts.
Steak and fries, Benny.
Great!
Here.
A tip for you .
ReaIIy? Thanks.
-Wanna eat something?
-No.
Wanna trade this watch?
After AngeIica Ieft him,
Tiago began snorting
more and more.
Is it your grandfather's?
No, my dad's.
When a guy is reaIIy hooked
he ends up in the hands
of the deaIer.
-Two bags of ten .
-One of ten .
Okay, one bag .
For Tiago, it was different.
Watch out!
Sorry, godfather.
Godfather, my ass.
Did I baptize your kids?
I'm sorry.
Now beat it.
BIacky, Iend me your bike.
Hey, wanna race?
Where to?
Up to the highway.
-Okay.
-Ready? Go!
Pretty tough , wasn't it?
Yeah , you're good .
Where'd you buy those sneakers?
-Not far from here.
-The shirt, as weII?
-No, uptown .
-CooI .
It's a designer shirt.
If I give you money
can you buy me one?
Shorts and a shirt?
Buy whatever you can .
-What size are you?
-Measure me.
-With what, man?
-Shit, with your hand .
Shoe size?
Turn around .
Hey, Benny!
You got the digs?
-Just one pair of pants?
-No, there's more.
-You Iike it?
-Yeah .
There's some change.
Keep it.
CooI .
This is Benny.
-This is Rocket.
-Hi . I know him .
I've become a pIayboy.
Hey, gangsters, Iisten to this.
Watch out.
Groovies shake their asses
before Iaying a big one.
Oh yeah?
Fuck off, you bastards!
Making fun of me?
AsshoIe!
Benny, didn't I teII you
to shoot Carrot?
He's endangering the sIum .
-CooI it. Go taIk to him .
-I'm gonna kiII that fucker.
Stop trying to wipe out
everyone.
I'm gonna kiII him .
Don't worry, AngeIica.
The guys in here are cooI .
Sure, I'm not worried .
You gonna dance, Benny?
What about Carrot?
Go taIk to the guy.
Benny was the cooIest hood
in the City of God.
He gave away pot,
paid for drinks.
Li'I Ze was the opposite.
He had one obsession:
to be the boss of the sIum.
He wanted an excuse
to take over Carrot's racket.
-Hey, Carrot.
-What's up?
You shouIdn't Iet the Runts
do hoId-ups in the sIum .
You Iook after your section ,
I'II Iook after mine.
Got that?
I'm gonna get a drink.
-Hey, Rocket! How's it going?
-Great.
-Hey, Benny!
-How's it going?
-Hey, Tiago. How are you?
-Good .
-May I?
-Sure.
Wanna dance?
Is it okay at your pIace?
No probIem .
My parents are out.
You'II be aII aIone with her.
You can Iose
your virginity tonight.
Not so Ioud , man !
Everyone wiII hear.
-You're beautifuI .
-Thank you .
Shit!
Nothing's happening .
Look, man , I know the Runts
are associated with you .
Think I'm a sucker,
you IittIe brat?
-You want to take my racket?
-I want to taIk to you
because you're fucking useIess.
Get your hand away!
The Runts are screwing up
our security, man .
Give the baby his bottIe.
Carrot, just ask the kids
to cooI it, okay?
Carrot's useIess.
He Iets the Runts do hoId-ups
in his section .
The poIice come around
and that's bad for business.
I'II do it
onIy because I Iike you .
But you need to change
that baby's diapers.
I'II show you
who's the baby.
TeII the kids that in my sIum
no one robs or rapes!
No wonder you're ''LittIe'' Z e!
The Runts were kids
who didn't respect the Iaws
of the sIum.
They wouId mug residents,
hoId up bakeries,
especiaIIy in Carrot's section.
What are you doing?
You rob me aII the time!
But they didn't know
that the City had a boss now.
THANK YOU FOR CHOOSING US
The City had became much safer
for residents.
There were hardIy
any hoId-ups now.
You just had to go see Li'I Ze.
-Let's go.
-Don't hurt the Runts.
I won't touch them .
-Hi , Steak.
-How's it going , LiI Ze?
-Wanna take a waIk, Steak?
-With you? HoId on .
Mom , I'm going out
with my friends.
That's the best chicken
I ever ate.
The oId guy was scared
shitIess.
FeeIing sorry for him?
You're craz, man !
Why not stick up
a bank or a supermarket?
Peanuts.
Drugs are where it's at.
Yeah , seIIing drugs.
But you have to start out
as a deIivery boy.
You wanna be a deIivery boy?
It's a rip-off.
It takes a Iong time
to move up.
You have to wait tiII an oIder
guy gets kiIIed to move up.
I don't wanna wait tiII
some guy croaks.
I'm gonna do what Li'I Z e did .
I'm gonna wipe them aII out.
TaIking about me, kid?
The boss is here.
Come back, you brat!
They're quick, those kids.
They run fast.
They're aII gone except you .
Any others?
You're gonna pay
for the ones that escaped .
You choose. ShaII I shoot you
in the hand or foot?
Come on , choose!
Hand or foot?
Choose, for fuck's sake!
-Hand .
-The IittIe hand , eh?
CooI .
Hey, Steak'n'fries,
Iet's see what you're made of.
Choose and then kiII
one of them .
Leave it. I'II do it.
Butt out, Tuba.
This is for him .
Go on , Steak.
Go on , choose one and shoot.
Come on , I haven't got aII day.
KiII one of them .
I wanna see
what you're made of.
WeII done!
You did it.
You're one of us.
Very good , Steak.
Get up, brat.
Go back to your rat hoIe.
Without Iimping !
TeII your buddies that no one
robs in LiI Ze's sIum .
Go now. And no Iimping , okay?
CooI , LiI Ze.
WhiIe Li'I Ze was winning
the respect of the residents.
Benny was winning
AngeIica's heart.
As for me, I was stiII
a virgin, singIe and broke.
I had no choice.
I had to take a job
in a supermarket.
I worked Iong hours
for chickenfeed.
I wanted to be Iaid off
so I couId buy a camera
with the severance pay.
But things
didn't work out that way.
-It's the guy on the beach .
-Hey, bro!
-StiII smoking good stuff?
-Yeah .
That guy's too cooI .
Hey, kid . Come here.
Lift up your shirt.
We give these sIum kids a chance
and they don't appreciate it.
-What about my severance pay?
-What severance pay?
That fucking manager thought
I was part of the gang.
You're fired for
serious misconduct.
Get out. ImmediateIy!
I didn't get a singIe cent.
It was Iike a message from God:
''Honesty doesn't pay, sucker. ''
The bus sure took
a Iong time to come.
I shouId aIready be at work.
Shit, hide that gun .
Are you nuts?
It was Goose's.
It's broken anyway.
The company
runs few buses on this Iine.
It's never anyone's fauIt.
It's aIways someone eIse.
It's my grandfather's fauIt.
And then ,
they make us squeeze!
Have a nice evening , ma'am .
I know that guy.
He Iives in the City.
He'II recognize us.
So? He couIdn't care Iess
if we take his boss' money.
Okay. Let's go.
WeII , boys?
Aren't you from the City of God?
Yeah .
I'II Iet one of you through
without paying .
You shouId study
so you can get out of the sIum .
It's too fuII
of cops and hoodIums.
Did you study?
I was in schooI
and in the army.
I was the best marksman
in my barracks.
This job was aII
I couId find afterwards.
But I do karate.
If I'm hired somewhere,
I'II Ieave the sIum .
Do you fight, then?
I'm for peace and Iove.
But if I have to.
He didn't know
he wouId have to.
But not yet, it's not time
to teII Knockout Ned's story.
-We shouId be going .
-Let's go.
-Goodbye.
-Thanks.
See you .
I couIdn't do it.
He was such a cooI guy.
Yeah , totaIIy.
That's Gerson's brother.
Let's go home.
There's nothing here
except that bakery over there.
What wiII you say?
I don't know.
''This is a hoId-up''.
Here's my number.
-You Iike souI or groovy?
-SouI .
That one didn't work either.
The counter girI
was just too fo xy.
And she flirted with me.
WiII you caII me?
I couIdn't puII a gun on her,
she was such a cooI girI .
Yeah , I agree.
Excuse me.
I'm Iost.
How do I get to Barra?
-To Barra?
-Yes.
I thought: ''Tough Iuck
for this guy from Sao PauIo. ''
In fact, we were going there.
You're kidding .
-You're a Iifesaver.
-That's right.
Because no guy from Sao PauIo
couId ever be cooI.
The body's over here.
We found it, Chief.
The forensic expert!
-Not a pretty sight, eh?
-You said it.
-What a great singer.
-You Iike him?
I Iove music. What about you?
TeII me, do you aIso Iike pot?
I can't say
I've never tried it.
The deviI recognizes his own .
Do you have papers?
I think so.
I have some.
I'd aIways been an ace
at roIIing a joint.
If I'd had the same skiII
with girIs,
I'd never have Iost so many
chances to Iose my virginity.
For a Sao PauIo guy
you're reaIIy cooI .
Thanks, bro.
What did they use?
A cIub or a rock.
And the chiId?
-Untouched .
-Thank goodness.
How Iong ago?
About four hours.
-Can we take it away?
-Go ahead .
The murderer
has to be from the City of God .
You bastard ! You motherfucker!
Did you have to kiII
your chick in the sIum?
The pIace is crawling
with cops now!
Come on , Li'I Z e.
Come on? Fuck you !
I had to avenge my honor.
Her famiIy's turned me in .
You won't have any probIems.
The cops are everywhere
because of you .
You're dead meat, asshoIe.
Let up, Li'I Z e.
You've punished him enough .
You know the Iaw.
Anyone who kiIIs in my sIum
has to die as an exampIe.
That was his business, Li'I Z e.
Listen , you sonofabitch ,
get outta the sIum .
You showed no respect,
understand?
You know what, Benny?
You're too nice. If you raise
a snake, expect to get bitten .
He wasn't worth shit.
A dirty traitor.
Shut up, Tuba.
I'm going for a waIk
with my girI .
Okay, be carefuI .
When things caIm down
we'II get back to our business
with Carrot, okay?
You need a girIfriend , Li'I Z e.
Know what I'm thinking , Benny?
That I'm so sexy?
That too. But I mean ,
you know what we couId do?
Make Iove again .
I'm serious.
We couId go away from here.
This vioIence sucks.
Go where?
To a farm .
We're reaIIy hippies at heart,
aren't we?
A farm?
Peace and Iove?
Benny was just too cooI
to go on being a hoodIum.
He succeeded
in getting everybody together
for his goodbye party.
The gangs.
The souI crowd.
The reIigious crowd.
One day, I'II go to church .
The samba crowd.
The groovy crowd.
And Li'I Ze, who had never
danced in his Iife.
Want to dance with me?
-I didn't hear.
-Want to dance?
No, thank you ,
I'm with someone.
Hey, Rocket!
Come, I want to taIk
to you , buddy.
You can't just spIit
with that chick.
Why not?
I'm gonna go Iive on a farm ,
smoke pot, Iisten to rock.
You wanna throw away
everything we've accompIished
for that bitch?
She's not a bitch ,
she's my girI .
We'II take over Carrot's
business, it'II be yours.
Leave Carrot aIone,
he's a good guy.
He's a motherfucker!
See? Everyone's a motherfucker
to you .
That's why I'm Ieaving .
I'm your friend ,
but I'm getting out.
You got to understand ,
I have to go.
I Iove you , man ,
but I've had enough .
Motherfucker, Iet's see
if you have any baIIs.
What is this?
You wanna die?
Fuck off, bitch !
Strip, nigger.
I wanna see your ass.
Hurry up!
Take it aII off! Now!
I wanna see your ass.
Come on , faggot!
Let's go, nigger!
Show your ass to everyone!
PIease.
Strip, dammit!
Hurry it up!
What's up, Benny?
This camera for a bag of coke?
I don't deaI anymore.
C'mon , do it for me.
You're my friend .
-Is it stoIen?
-It's okay, it's my dad's.
Your dad's?
Give it to Li'I Z e.
Rocket wouId Iove this camera.
-Yeah , here.
-Great.
Here I am !
-You wanna be a photographer?
-Yeah .
Here's a present.
Shit, dude! This is great!
Now move your ass.
Shake it!
You'II take some great
pictures.
Give me that.
-Give me back the camera!
-No!
What's your probIem?
Are you craz?
They've kiIIed Benny!
Fuck! CaII an ambuIance!
Where's the motherfucker
who did it?
Z e, Benny is dead .
No! CaII a doctor!
Get out of here, bitch !
It's your fauIt!
Motherfucker!
Where's Carrot?
BIacky's here.
He's in troubIe.
I'm fucked .
-Why?
-I'm fucked .
And you are too.
I think I kiIIed Benny.
Li'I Z e's coming
to take your pIace.
We can get him ,
he's in the dance haII .
You kiIIed Benny?
I didn't mean to. He moved .
I was aiming at Li'I Z e.
Come on , Iet's go.
BIacky.
You kiIIed the cooIest
hood in the City of God .
Let's go get Li'I Z e.
Carrot knew
that without Benny
onIy a miracIe
couId save his business.
We're fucked , man .
But what better pIace
for a miracIe to happen
than in the City of God?
Look who's here.
My sugar babe.
-Let me by.
-Gimme a kiss, girI .
Let me by, pIease. Have you
seen what you Iook Iike?
Come on , Li'I Z e.
Hi , honey.
Everything okay, baby?
The probIem was simpIe.
Li'I Ze was ugIy.
Knockout Ned was handsome.
Knockout Ned
couId get any girI.
Li'I Ze had to pay
or use force.
It was a dueI between
the handsome good guy
and the ugIy bad guy.
Let me go!
Just enjoy it.
You're mine now.
Hey, faggot,
your broad's reaIIy hot!
I can't even
Iook her in the face now.
Why didn't that fucker kiII me?
HoId on .
Why didn't I kiII that fucker?
Let's go back.
-What about Carrot?
-We'II get back to him .
You gonna kiII him?
Knockout Ned ,
your chick's a sIut.
Come out, motherfucker!
Come out, you Ioser!
Take it easy.
I'm going out. Let me go.
Gerson ! Come back, son !
This doesn't concern you , kid .
We're here for your brother.
Let's taIk, we can work it out.
My brother's a peacefuI guy.
Is he too good-Iooking
to come taIk to me? CaII him .
He hasn't done anything .
You know who I am?
-Li'I Z e, man .
-He's Li'I Z e.
CaII that motherfucker!
Go on , man .
CaIm down , I'II caII him .
My arm !
I hurt my arm .
Carrot wiII have to wait.
That Ioser got what he
deserved .
Let's go!
Gerson .
That bastard kiIIed my brother.
I can't Iet that go.
Want a gun?
My son .
CaIm down , mom .
PIease, mom .
Do it right, asshoIe.
There's no other way.
How'd I Iet that Ioser hit me?
Shit, that's some hoIe.
-It's as if we were brothers.
-Shut up.
Both of us hurt in the arm .
You by one brother, me the
other.
It wouId be reaIIy funny
if we were brothers.
That Knockout Ned's
not bad , eh?
He came out of nowhere.
Shut up, Tuba!
You're a fucking pain !
It was as if the City of God
had suddenIy found a hero.
God bIess you , son .
That kid was just asking
to be kiIIed .
WeII done.
You did a good job.
You'd better go hide.
I thought Knockout Ned
wouId start a revoIution here.
But God had other pIans.
Steak,
where are aII the deaIers?
They're hiding .
Li'I Z e is in a bad mood .
They get us hooked and then
they go off and hide.
Do me a favor.
Go get some nose candy for me.
I'II try.
TeII them it's for Tiago,
to keep my buzz going .
Steak'n'fries,
go to Carrot's and teII him .
Li'I Z e says that if you kiII
Knockout, he'II Ieave you aIone.
Hey, Knockout Ned .
Did you hear that?
Grab the kid !
You heard the boy?
If you don't stick with us,
you're dead .
I think you shouId join us.
We'II be partners.
Drugs aren't my thing .
This is just something
between me and him .
Those guys aren't worth shit.
They'II do anything for power.
Like this kid .
They're aII robots,
Iike this punk here.
What's in your head , kid?
Can't you see
you're wrecking your Iife
with that maniac and a bunch
of trigger-happy fooIs?
Are you craz?
You're just a kid .
A kid? I smoke, snort,
I've kiIIed and robbed .
I'm a man .
Shit, you have no idea!
He's attached to his gang .
You shouId join up with us.
ShaII we kiII him?
Steak,
we're going to grind you .
Okay, I accept.
Great!
TeII your boss
that Knockout Ned and Carrot
are now in command .
But on one condition :
no kiIIing of innocent peopIe.
I can't accept that,
understand?
Okay, no innocent peopIe.
Steak fucked up!
Have you a gun for me?
No, but we can hoId up
a gun store.
That's no probIem .
I don't want to hoId up
anything .
I'm not a hoodIum .
This is a personaI affair
between me and him , okay?
I'm not a hoodIum .
He raped your chick,
kiIIed your uncIe and brother,
gunned your house,
and you kiIIed one of his guys.
If you're not a hood ,
then get out.
This is a hoId-up!
The first time...
Where are the revoIvers?
Knockout Ned saved a saIescIerk
form being shot by Carrot.
We said no kiIIing !
That's the ruIe.
We want the boss's money.
Everyone keep caIm .
You want us to go? We do too.
Look at the ground !
The second time, Carrot saved
Knockout Ned's Iife.
Ned Iearned that there's
an exception to every ruIe.
Exception to the ruIe.
-Are you the manager?
-Yes.
This is a hoId-up.
Everyone on the ground !
On the ground !
Give me the money!
I'm not kidding .
The first person who moves
is dead !
The third time,
the exception becomes the ruIe.
With the hoId-up money
Carrot and Knockout Ned
prepared to face Li'I Ze.
Carrot couId protect
his business.
Knockout Ned,
the best marksman in his
battaIion, wanted revenge.
First, the ItaIians.
This is a 9 mm .
-Let me see.
-Not bad , eh?
The sight isn't weII-aIigned .
I'II give you a good price.
The 1 2mm .
The ''hand job''.
See why?
An Uzi , 9mm . It's IsraeIi .
The star of David .
Jewish .
I want a 30-06.
Now we can start having fun .
The war's on .
Let's start with a prayer.
Our father who art in heaven ,
HaIIowed be thy name. . .
HoodIums have guns,
but can't shoot.
One buIIet from Knockout Ned
was worth ten
from Li'I Ze's gang.
Li'I Ze couIdn't take it.
He counter-attacked.
The sIum had been a purgatory,
now it was heII.
I decided to get out.
That's how I became a reporter.
Great photo!
I bet it's by Rogerio Reis.
What did I teII you?
Like any pro,
I started at the bottom,
way down at the bottom.
Without knowing
what awaited me.
Instead of going home
I'd go over to the paper.
A guy from the City of God
worked in the Iab.
Check this out.
He heIped me
move cIoser
to what I Ioved most in Iife.
-Hi , Rogerio.
-How are you , Pierre?
This is Rocket.
He's a photographer.
HeIIo, Rocket.
-He's a fan of yours.
-ReaIIy?
You have good taste, Rocket!
-WeII , I'm done. I'm off.
-See you .
What a cooI guy!
What shouId have been
a swift revenge
turned into an aII-out war.
The City of God was divided.
You couIdn't go
from one section to the other.
Not even to visit a reIative.
The cops considered anyone
Iiving in the sIum a hoodIum.
PeopIe got used to Iiving
in Vietnam.
And more and more voIunteers
kept signing up to die.
This kid . . .
What do you want?
A boy from Carrot's gang
punched me.
The war was an excuse
for everything.
Li'I Z e's soIdiers
kicked my ass.
Take this .22 .
The jerk who raped my sister
is with Carrot.
Li'I Z e evicted my famiIy.
KiII . . .
Be respected .
I'm Tiago, a friend of Benny's.
Can you read? Can you add?
I'm pretty good in business.
Okay, get to work.
What do you want?
To get my father's murderer.
What's your name?
My name's Otto.
What's the matter?
-He's a worker.
-But he wants a gun .
He won't Iast a week.
A year Iater, no one remembered
how it had aII begun.
Take that!
For both sides, the aim was
to take over the enemy's
business in order to buy
more guns and take over
more businesses.
I smoke, snort,
I've kiIIed and robbed.
I'm a man.
The media started
taking an interest.
The poIice had to intervene.
A gang Ieader
from the City of God
was arrested today.
ManueI Machado,
aka Knockout Ned,
was hospitaIized after being
wounded by Li'I Ze's gang.
Our reporter interviewed him.
Is the war
stiII going on?
It's stiII going on.
Have many peopIe died?
Many have died.
MostIy innocent peopIe.
Just knowing me is enough
to get you kiIIed by Li'I Ze.
The poIice don't go in there?
They go after me, not him.
I've been in jaiI, whiIe he
goes on kiIIing undisturbed.
And they don't arrest him.
Knockout Ned says
the war wiII continue.
PoIice Chief Guedes
has promised
to arrest both of the gangs.
Motherfucker!
I'm the boss here, but he gets
his picture in the paper!
-Have you found mine?
-Just Knockout Ned's.
Keep Iooking .
At Ieast my name's
got to be in there.
-There's nothing .
-Can you read?
Just the pictures.
Nothing .
Hey, what the fuck
are you doing?
It's just the want ads.
I don't care, read everything !
But there aren't any articIes.
Want a buIIet in your head?
Gotta show them
who's boss here.
-Give me the camera!
-No way!
Take my picture, man .
I can't work it.
Go ahead .
I'II hoId the Beretta.
Let me try.
Back off.
There's no cIick.
What a bunch of bozos!
I'm fucked , with you guys.
I have an idea.
I'II go get a guy I know.
Hang Ioose.
Here he is.
Take the camera.
WeII , kid?
Aren't you a photographer?
Make the camera work.
We can't do it.
Take our picture.
-You fucking broke it.
-It wasn't me.
I found it.
It has to be wound .
What's your name?
Rocket.
Another picture, Rocket.
How about two rows?
What?
Two rows.
Everyone with their guns.
You're outside,
for Christ's sake!
TaIk to him niceIy, kid .
Sorry.
Move in , pIease.
Another one.
I think the roII's finished .
Then show us the pictures.
They have to be deveIoped .
DeveIoped?
How much is it?
Take this money.
And bring back the pictures.
I have to remove the fiIm .
Keep the camera.
Benny wanted to give it to you ,
didn't he?
-It's yours.
-Thanks.
Don't forget the pictures.
The photos, Rocket!
-Pierre!
-What?
Can you deveIop this for me?
I can't, Rocket.
I couId get into troubIe.
It's onIy for the paper's
reporters. I couId risk my job.
-Pierre?
-Yes, Rogerio?
DeveIop these for me.
This one too, okay?
I'm going to Iunch .
You're Iucky.
What size?
What?
For the enIargement, what size?
WeII . . .
Whatever you think is best.
-Here.
-Thanks.
I'm in deep shit now.
I'm as good as dead .
Someone had signed
my death sentence.
I wanted to bash the jerk's
face in.
Are you Marina?
You stoIe my photos.
Because of you ,
I'm dead .
Dead? StoIe? What do you mean?
Not so Ioud .
Not so Ioud?
I'II be kiIIed because of you .
You were gone,
your photos were in the Iab.
There's nothing I can do.
The photos in our Iab
are photos to be pubIished
in the paper.
I saw the photos,
I pubIished them .
You stoIe them .
I did not. Here they are.
-Give them to me.
-Just a second .
Here are your photos.
Are there any others?
CaIm down .
What's your name?
-Rocket.
-Rocket?
Nice to meet you .
I'm Marina.
Now, reIax.
I have money for you .
For your pictures.
Here, when we use a picture
we pay the photographer.
Do you want to be
a photographer?
Yes.
Great start!
On the front page.
How'd you get these photos?
I Iive there.
Rocket, no photographer has ever
been abIe to go in there.
If you couId bring us
more pictures of Li'I Z e,
the paper wouId buy them .
We'd pay you .
CouId you?
I don't know.
What's the probIem?
The probIem? I can't go there
anymore at night.
And during the day?
It's too risky.
Look, man ! They've finaIIy
understood that I'm the boss.
What's your
photographer-friend's name?
Rocket.
He's good . I'II take more
to show the others.
So, Rocket,
is it yes or no?
It's a great opportunity.
Okay.
You made the right choice.
Very good !
I'II give you some fiIm ,
Ienses,
and even another camera. I'II
show you the equipment room .
There's another probIem .
-What is it?
-Where can I sIeep tonight?
I can't go back now.
This is a 1 35mm .
WiII you be cIose up
or far away?
Far away.
-Can you measure the Iight?
-Yes.
Aren't you too cIose?
I don't know what spurred me
to go taIk to them Iike that.
Maybe I was going to die,
but now I had a camera
and a chance
to become a photographer.
Watch out for the dog shit.
Not to mention that
the night was stiII young.
Want something to eat?
No, thank you , ma'am .
Nothing to eat?
Nothing to drink?
Ajoint?
Try this.
It's time to go to sIeep.
I'II show you your bed .
You have hot water, don't you?
Yes. You've never
taken a hot shower?
-No.
-What do you do?
We heat up the kettIe.
Why are you standing there?
What room do I sIeep in?
UnfortunateIy,
there's onIy one room .
You have to sIeep with me.
I won't go into the detaiIs
of my first sexuaI experience.
Just reIax.
Because, eIsewhere
another more important
sex scene for the sIum
was taking pIace.
Carrot was heIping
Knockout Ned escape
without firing a shot.
The poIiceman guarding him
was in the wiIIing hands
of the nurse.
And in the meantime
to eIiminate Carrot, Li'I Ze
was investing in munitions.
He invested heaviIy,
even if he couIdn't pay.
Remember the doubIe-barreI?
I aIready have it.
This is a repeater rifle.
You don't have this one,
the Browning .
It'II shoot down a pIane.
I'm not shooting down pIanes.
And the one I asked for?
The AR-1 5, UncIe Sam .
You can't get them in BraziI .
My ass, UncIe Sam .
I have a soIution .
The Rugger. Ever seen one?
It's Iike the AR-1 5.
Same caIiber, but Iighter.
With an infrared sight?
400 shots a minute?
It depends.
It depends, my ass!
Trying to fuck me over?
I'II fuck you over first.
You Ieave now
without the money or the guns.
What do I teII the boss?
That's your probIem .
You'II think of something .
You heard him , chubby?
Get out.
Beat it, fatso.
Li'I Ze had made a big mistake.
He shouId have known
that behind every saIesman
Iies a suppIier.
And they don't joke around.
Have you seen this?
What do they need an AR-1 5 for?
These stories wiII push
the poIice to investigate.
They'II nab you .
And me, aIong with you .
Think I'm going
to give you away?
Don't worry,
I'II take care of it.
But don't fuck up again .
CharIie!
Come here!
Listen ,
you teII him .
Let's go make that sIeaz
IittIe deaIer pay up.
Come here, kids!
Do you Iike chicken?
It depends.
We'II eat some chicken
and have Carrot for dessert.
I have a present for you .
Here.
A big one for you .
Are you reaIIy giving us
these guns?
Yes, but I want you on my side,
against Carrot.
Then can we hoId up
anyone we want?
Not in the sIum .
-Can you shoot?
-More or Iess.
More or Iess?
Hey, you guys,
come heIp these kids.
I know. You do it Iike this.
Get that chicken !
C'mon , Iet's go.
If Li'I Z e catches you ,
he'II kiII you .
Yeah , weII ,
he's gotta find me first.
Hey, kid ! Get that chicken !
Shit! The cops!
HeII , don't fucking run off!
Give me that.
Hey, MeIonhead !
You fucking fag !
Get the heII out of here!
Coward !
AsshoIe!
Come on ,
Iet them kiII each other.
They can fuck themseIves.
Rocket! Take a picture of us!
What are you waiting for?
What's happening?
Shit!
Let's go!
Run ! Run !
Watch out!
KiII one of these faggots!
BIast him !
Knockout Ned !
Take it easy. Don't move.
It hurts, man .
Easy does it, kid .
Why did you join
this fucking war?
Knockout Ned !
Li'I Z e's been hit. Come on !
Wait here, I'II heIp you .
Just hoId on .
- What's your name?
-My name's Otto.
I want to get my father's
murderer.
Knockout Ned !
Li'I Z e's been hit. Come on !
I'II heIp you .
Just hoId on there.
The fucking cops!
On the ground !
-Don't move!
-Hands over your head .
-You're the one I want.
-You're finished , paI .
Handcuff him .
Rocket, where are you going?
I got something to cIear up.
Okay, Iovebirds.
Come on , Li'I Z e,
Iet's go settIe our scores.
Not you .
You're a present for the media.
Does it come to 1 0,000?
AImost. That's aII I have.
That's aII there was, Chief.
We searched everywhere.
Let him go.
What about this ring?
Is it goId?
FiII it up.
You'II owe us the rest.
Fucking war!
Knockout Ned is dead
and I'm dead broke!
You're fucked , eh?
Kids,
we'II have to do a few hoId-ups
to get my business going again .
Your business, Li'I Z e?
What's your probIem , kid?
This is for our friend ,
motherfucker!
A Soviet attack!
The business is ours!
This picture of the hood
wiII guarantee my saIary.
This one wiII make me famous.
It'II even make the cover
of a magazine.
I won't have to worry
about Li'I Ze anymore.
But the cops?
Gangster, SeIf-styIed ''Boss''
Of The City Of God, Shot Dead
This photo couId've
gotten us kiIIed?
I think so.
A Ieast it got you a job.
Not a job, an internship.
It pays a IittIe, doesn't it?
A IittIe.
What about that Iady
journaIist? Was she a good Iay?
More or Iess.
You didn't Iike it?
I don't think journaIists
know how to screw.
Yeah , I guess so.
Cocoa robbed 3 houses
in Barra.
Better kiII him .
Who shot Roger?
-It was Beef.
-KiII that fucker.
We shouId kiII the Chief
and Gringo as weII .
What about Cherry?
Let's go.
Us two, and 3 others.
It's a deaI .
Have you heard
of the Red Brigade?
No, but if they come,
we'II kiII them .
-Who knows how to write?
-Me, sort of.
Let's make a bIack Iist.
We'II kiII them aII .
Put fucking Nightowl on there.
And Croquet.
Leonard , too,
he owes me money.
And China-Man ,
he thinks he's hot stuff.
And CIaudio.
Where's Giant?
Come on , Giant!
I forgot to say,
my name isn't Rocket anymore.
I'm now WiIson Rodrigues,
photographer.
ManueI Machado,
aka Knockout Ned,
was hospitaIized after being
wounded by Li'I Ze's gang.
On Ieaving the hospitaI,
our reporter interviewed him.
Many have died.
MostIy innocent peopIe.
Just knowing me is enough,
just being my friend.
If he thinks someone knows me,
he'II kiII them.
The poIice don't go in there?
They go after me, not him.
I've been in jaiI 3 times,
whiIe he goes on
kiIIing undisturbed.
And they don't arrest him.
Knockout Ned says
the war wiII continue.
PoIice Chief Guedes
has promised to arrest
both gangs in the City of God.