JANG Dong-gun
WON Bin
LEE Eun-joo
Memorial Site for souls
of the Korean War
We're contacting the families
of those we've identified
We'll call you soon
Who received the file for
LEE Jin-seok, number B-38?
LEE Jin-seok?
I did, Why?
I checked the list of
remains and the photos
He's not on K.I.A.
or M.I.A. list
Not even on
the survivors' list?
LEE Jin-seok...
Identity search for participating soldier
the list of participants...
Still alive?
Grandpa!
The Army Headquarters
is on the phone!
hello?
I'm with the Korean War
excavation team
I'm calling to
confirm some information
Are you LEE Jin-seok
who fought at the battle of Dumillyong?
That's right
We've identified some remains
as LEE Jin-seok's
Oh... you did?
But I am LEE Jin-seok
Is there any chance...
it is LEE Jin-tae?
No, it's definitely
LEE Jin-seok
I'm sorry to have
bothered you, sir
It's probably someone
with the same name
What did they say?
Was it about your brother?
I thought it would be since
it was a call from the army
Grandpa, can I help
with the garden?
Could you drive for me?
I can drive him
Don't worry, Mom
The site is on a mountain and
you aren't well
I'll call her later
You got sick after your trip to China
to look for your brother
Yes
Why don't you go
start the car
- Yeah
- Make sure you've got an ID
It's a restricted area
Don't worry
I've got enough IDs
OK then
Are you going to wear
your sneakers?
I'll shine shoes instead
Jong-Ro, Seoul 1950
Shoe shine!
The middle ones are new from Italy
They're beautiful
It's a work of an art
The heels are high and
the stitching is superb
Well... I like low heels better
They look more comfortable
- Really?
- But
I bet you can make
so much better than those
It'll take a few more years
I'll be so proud when you make shoes
at a shop like this someday
- What did you buy this for?
- You wanted to have one
You look great!
Thanks, Jin-tae
Ice cream!
- Hey, ice cream!
- Yeah!
- Give me a real cold one
- Why don't you buy two?
- Just one is enough
- OK
Here's one, nice and cold
Take it
- You've already spent too much
- Take it!
- Yours?
- I don't want my teeth to rot
- How much is it?
- It's 2 won
- Thank you
- Have a nice day!
- Take a bite first
- No way!
- Come on, it's melting!
- You eat it
Jin-tae! The tram!
Shoe shine
Where are you going?
We have to go home!
I've finished
the math homework
I'll teach you
something new
You have to teach me tomorrow!
Mom!
You haven't finished yet?
What does it look like to you?
We're busy!
- Jin-seok's here, too
- Hi, Young-Shin!
Stop that
I'll put some on a plate
It's okay, Young-Shin
I told you not to do that
Come here
- Come on, I'm not a child
- Come here
Thank you!
See you next time!
Where did you get
this barley?
I got it for signing up for some
kind of National Correction League
- National Correction League?
- I think barley
for my name is
a good deal
I wish mother had done it, too
Nothing's ever free
I could kill for free food
Hurry up and close the shop
Dad's waiting!
Dad, Jin-seok scored the
top for his last exam
Isn't that a good job?
He'll make your dream come true
Please help him enter the
best university next year
And please keep him healthy
He was very sick last spring
No, but I'm fine now
Young-shin, Mom says
to come in!
Remember her, dad?
Jin-tae is going to marry
her this fall
Mom's worried about such a nice girl
marrying such a rough boy
It'd have made
you so proud...
Mom, the kids must be hungry
Jin-seok, let's clear
the table
Why don't you
go help mom
Open the pot!
Again!
Here, use this from now on
I made it from my skirt
Don't lose it
What did you like
the most?
The meat!
- I liked the cookies
- I liked the fruit!
Can we go swimming?
No, it's too late
We have to go home and sleep
But tomorrow is Sunday
We have no school...
It's too hot to go to bed
- No...
- Please, please...
You look really happy
I wish everyday were like this
No more, no less
I know, Jin-tae is a little rough
but has a warm heart...
Don't worry. It's not cold
Shall I show you?
Jin-tae, I don't want to do it!
Why are you changing the heels?
The high ones look great!
They look great!
Are you gonna sell them?
You wanna buy them?
If the price is right
I just might
You'll never have enough money
to buy those shoes!
Hey, why is this pronunciation
different form the spelling?
Didn't I tell you not to ask me
about spellings?
You don't know the
second grade's stuff?
Shut up and go
get more shoes
Okay, I was going to
Hi, you're gonna teach me
math today, right?
- Why aren't you at the library?
- You haven't heard?
A war has broken out
Any soldiers on leave are
to report to duty right away
This morning the armed forces of
North Korea attacked South Korea
But our brave soldiers are fighting
courageously and pushing them back
Citizens should not be deceived by
the groundless propaganda of the north
Informing you once again
at the 38th parallel...
What are all these?
Are we moving?
We have to carry all these
Only food and clothes
I told you!
Don't worry
I won't ask you to carry
Uncle's house is way too far
- Put that stuff back
- No, I'll carry them
We can't carry all these!
I'll carry them!
I'll carry them all!
Don't be stupid!
I told you I will!
We'll be back soon
I told you
How do you know that?
No one knows what will happen!
The shop is just
starting to do well
Somebody will take it
while we're gone
What about the KIMchi pots
buried in the yard?
And the vegetables
I planted in spring?
They all will be fine
until we get back
What if you're drafted?
Only if they need their boots shined
We have to hurry
The North's solders
are getting close
And the streets are
packed with refugees
Hurry up, Young-ja
Let's go
Mother!
Mom says we must
stay together all the time
- Put Young-min on here
- Young-min
Hold on tight
We won't be long, okay?
Jin-seok, come on!
Jin-seok!
Hold hands tight!
Young-ja!
Dae-gu, July 1950
What the hell is that train
sitting over there for?
I told you
trains for civilians are not running!
Where's a pharmacy?
I don't know
Let's go to the war front
And destroy the communists!
We must protect our country!
I think we have to
give up the train
- What about that one?
- It's leaving for the front
- Is Jin-tae back?
- Not yet
Jin-tae will bring you
some medicine in a minute
Salute!
Excuse us, but we're
on official business
Men between 18 and 30
step forward
Between 18 and 30!
It's nothing serious
Just step forward
- What's going on?
- It's nothing serious, don't worry
- What year were you born?
- I was born in 1921
Step forward then
It will be over soon
so please cooperate
Between 18 and 30!
How old are you?
- Ei... eighteen
- Step forward
- What's going on?
- and also people at the back...
step forward
- Men between 18 and 30
- Don't go
You don't need to follow
their orders
Don't worry, It's just some
questions, I guess
- It's going to be okay
- Come on, let's go
Everything will be fine
I'm still a student
- I'll be fine
- No, Jin-seok!
You aren't allowed to go
- Jin-seok!
- No, Jin-seok!
To position!
- Salute!
- student soldier
Loyalty!
Back to position!
Don't worry
It's going to be Okay
Give this to Young-min
- What happened?
- Jin-seok...
What happened to Jin-seok?
The soldiers took him
with all the young men
he's not back yet
Jin-tae!
- We'll go
- We'll fight
We'll win!
- student soldier!
- volunteer soldier!
Brave volunteer student soldiers
long live Korea
but now brave soldiers
Where are you going?
I'm looking for my brother
You're not permitted in here
You'll have to leave
- Jin-seok! Jin-seok!
- Stop right there!
Jin-tae!
Let's go!
This isn't the train to uncle's house
We're leaving soon
Sit down
My brother got on the wrong train
We're getting off
I said sit down
You must be mistaken
We're refugees
not soldiers
You've just been drafted, too
Then who's gonna look
after my mother? You?
Sit down!
That is an order
You order your soldiers
We are leaving
I told you to sit down!
You must be mistaken
Why can't you understand
Jin-seok
get off now!
go, now!
Stay still!
Jin-tae!
My brother has a problem
with his heart
He can't even run
Tell that at the
training camp
Only those without arms or legs
or who can't talk or hear
At war, they're
called patients
Jin-seok, Jin-tae!
Jin-tae!
What are you doing, you bastard!
Mom!
- Mom!
- Mom
Jin-seok, Jin-tae!
Mom, Young-shin!
- Jin-tae!
- Mom, here, here!
Mom!
Mom, here!
- Jin-seok!
- Here, here!
- Mom! Mom, here!
Mom!
Go to uncle's home first
We will meet you later
I'll take care of Jin-seok
Don't worry!
- What happened to your face?
- Take care of mom
Don't worry about us
You take care of yourselves
You must come home!
Jin-tae...
Mom!
Jin-tae! Jin-seok!
Hey, help me
Fucking bastards!
Pour that all over!
You communist dogs...
I should have burn them
to death Fucking bastards...
- KANG Yong-jin!
- Yes sir!
- KIM Ki-tae
- Yes, sir!
- LEE Jin-seok!
Excuse me, sir
- May I have a word with you sir?
- Go ahead
This is my younger brother
Please let us stay close
He's just a student and
knows nothing about war
I'll teach him
Please
Alright
Here, Nakdong River
is our last line of defense
If this place is taken
the next is Busan, and then...
we've got nowhere to go
but into the sea
If you retreat
I'll kill you myself
This is where we
live or die
Write your wills and
whatever you wanna leave
put it in here, Got it?
- Attention, salute!
- Sir!
Damn young punk
What does he know about
death and wills?
Okay, let's say hello
- I am GO Yong-man
- I am LEE Jin-tae
Let me ask you something
Are you two related?
- He's my older brother
- You're brothers? Damn!
I thought they were only supposed
to take one per family!
Who's going to carry on
the family name?
Is the country going to?
Those bastards
Forget the will!
Forget it!
You never know when
the next meal will come
Eat this shit
Just call me Uncle Yang
He's the eldest
in our platoon
He's a self-proclaimed fortuneteller
but he's never right
Welcome
Don't ever take your helmet off
Many get their heads
blown off while sleeping
I'm Sergeant LEEM
I hate anything red
especially the reds!
I am Tae-soo, I escaped
from North Korea
But don't mistake me as a commie
I'm Seung-chul
I was a student but
I volunteered to fight
Say 'Hello', PFC Jo
Whatever for, We'll all be
dead soon anyway
- I'm PFC Jo
- I am Yong-goo
Just call me radio man
I am KIM Cheol-soo
I go by Ban
They are asking me
to fight, eating this?
No water or soup at all?
And mine's so damn small!
You don't want it?
Give it to me
Eat it
Jin-seok!
Jin-seok, are you okay?
Jin-seok, you okay?
Stay right there
Stay put
Jin-tae
I told you to
stay there!
Jin-seok, Jin-seok!
Hang on, Jin-seok!
Please keep breathing!
Jin-seok, You can do it
Jin-seok, breathe in!
Now breathe out
More, more!
Spit it out!
Now breathe in!
Jin-seok, You can do it
Deeper, deeper, Jin-seok!
You're okay!
Okay, okay
You're fine
Please send my brother
to the hospital
I'll blow up their tanks or
bring you their commanders
I'll even carry a bomb
- into their camp
- There is one with an epileptic
Another has pulmonary tuberculosis
One in 3rd platoon has rheumatism
Another with with heart disease
And one with pulmonary tuberculosis
Need more?
Should I send them all?
Who'll fight then?
Life and death crosses
here every second
If you do
what you've said
and I can even send
your brother home!
I'll do whatever I can do
if I can send him home
That's the spirit we need
You have to give to
your country
before asking for something
Just for your information
it's been done before
There, a father and son
were in the same unit
who could send his son home
Wanna know how?
Wills are for dying people
You've got to be strong
I wish all this
would just be a dream
I want to wake up in my room
I'd tell you about this
over breakfast
I would tell you that
I had a strange dream
Then I would go to school
and you and mom would go to work
Don't worry
We will be just fine
Urgent call from
the battalion bunker, sir!
What is it?
The 2nd and 3rd have
lost their positions
Damn it!
- Wake them up!
- Yes, sir!
Everybody, wake up!
Everybody up! Up!
Area 721 and
area 734 have
fallen into the enemy's hands
Additionally, our supply route
has been cut off
This means
we're isolated
Remove all the rocks
They're shrapnel
waiting to happen
Area 731 and 732 are gone
We're next!
The bastards are gonna
hit us hard, like dogs
There won't be anyone
left to bury us
Let the commies come!
I'll kill everyone I can!
Attention!
Sergeant HUH, KOH Yong-man
LIM Tae-soo, KANG Hyo-Yul
YANG, JANG, LEE Seung-chul
Get armed and come with me
What's going on?
There's an order to plant mines
on the defense line
Shit, that's right
under their noses
So what?
I have to go there?
I'm going, too
Yong-man is out
Jin-tae is going, instead
Rest of you get back to
what you were doing
Yes, sir!
- Damn, I always get the shit
- Jin-tae!
- Hurry up!
Those commies will
take over anytime
They slaughter the families
of soldiers and cops
That's why we've got to
win this war!
If we lose, the commies
will kill us all!
Win to live
Win how?
Eating mud?
Get back to work!
Aimed fire!
Hide yourselves quick!
- Get down!
- Seung-chul! Don't move!
Be careful of the land mine
Seung-chul!
Yang and I will
go get him!
Cover us!
Seung-chul, hang on
hang on there!
I'll be there soon
so don't move!
crazy bastards, don't shoot
don't shoot!
the kid's gonna die!
we have to go quick!
Let's go!
Where's private LEE
you bastard!
I don't know sergeant
- Jin-tae!
- Only a few left
Let's finish them!
Jin-tae!
No, retreat! Now!
Jin-tae! are you
out of your mind?
Hey! LEE Jin-tae
Quick, you bastard
He was shot in the stomach
and on his leg
Hold on
- Hurry up!
- Hold him tight!
Hold tight, you bastard
Take it easy
Seung-chul!
We must take him
to the hospital
Hey, you bastard! There's
no way to carry him out!
Sew him up right now!
- Hurry up
- Sew him up!
- What should I do with this?
- Hold on, bastard!
You okay?
LEE Jin-tae
I'll kill you if you
do that again
I mean it
One more minute
he would have died
Got it?
Why the hell did you
go for that mission?
Tell me
You weren't on the list
but you volunteered for it
Why is that?
I don't understand
why you did that
Just forget it
What if it was you
laying there
with your guts open!
Promise me
you won't do that again
Promise!
Alright
All I need is
just water
Why the hell are they
playing that music?
They know we're isolated
They're gonna drive us crazy
Remember the ice cream?
It was so good
Back home, you can eat it
till your teeth go numb
I wonder what mom
and Young-shin are doing...
I bet... Mom is really
worried about us
Uncle would be taking
good care of them
I miss them all
Young-guk, Young-ja
Young-min...
I should've...
set the dog free
- Seung-chul
- What's wrong?
Okay there?
Make him lie down
Uncle Yang...
my stomach hurts
Don't worry
You'll be okay
Where's my leg?
You call yourself doctor?
Don't see the maggots?
What are you good for?
Food?
Why no more?
Damn! It's about time!
Give us more!
Stop, you bastards!
My ears are exploding!
Are you gonna make us
go through hell?
You want to give up
Nak-dong River?
Seung-chul!
Seung-chul
Put it down
Why couldn't you wait
just a little longer?
Dismiss
- Go back to the trench
- Shit!
We're going to die
here like dogs?
Starve to death
or shot to death
Who says we're gonna die?
They haven't given us food
or water for days!
We'll die
an honorable death
Soldiers are human, too!
What's the honor when
starving to death?
- Shut up!
- You crazy bastard
You'd go to them for
a piece of bread
It's better than
starving to death
Okay then, go on!
Go join the commies
I'll kill you before you get there
Surrendering is better than
starving to death like animals!
Who gives a shit who wins!
Is that ideology
important enough
to kill each other over?
You finished?
This is totally different from
our fight against Japan!
You damn communist!
Fuck, give back your badge!
you crazy fuck!
Stop it, son of a bitch
- Let go, let go!
- You son of a bitch!
Stop it, son of a bitch
Okay, let's die, you bastard
today, okay?
We're gonna die anyway
- Die, fucking bastard!
- Take it easy!
The communists slaughtered
- his entire family
- I didn't do it!
This ain't circus!
Go back to the bunker!
This is it?
Let's attack them
We're so weak we can
- barely lift our guns
- One more day
and we'll be eating corpses
Or surrender to
the commies
They wouldn't expect us
to attack them
We've got nothing to lose
haven't we?
Let's go in and
wipe them out
I will fight!
I will, too!
I will follow too
- I will go too
- I will go along
- I will go
- Hey, count me in
- I'll go too
- Me too
One mistake can
- kill us all
- Let's go and kill 'em all!
Sir!
I don't understand
why I'm out of the mission
You're not qualified
I am!
Let me join them!
- I have to be with my brother
- It's too late
I'm begging you, I want to
fight with others
Your brother begged me to sit you out
and now you wanna go?
What are you risking
your life for?
- You need a medal, too?
- What medal, sir?
Attack!
Fucking bastard!
Fuck, kill 'em all!
Die all of you...
die!
Please... don't kill me
I'm only 15
I just got drafted
Please don't kill me
Please...
Die...
Die!
Watch out!
They are coming from side!
Jin-tae, where are
you going?
Come back, Jin-tae!
Jin-tae!
I said come back!
Son of a bitch!
If they take this bunker
we are finished, Got it?
Yes, sir!
You fucking babies
How dare you betray us
like that?
Hurry up!
You are lucky to be alive
Jin... tae!
Jin-tae!
- Jin-tae!
- Jin-seok!
Are you okay?
Good
Let's go get some water
Jin-tae...
Why do you volunteer for
every single risky mission?
For a Medal...
To send me home?
What the hell are you doing?
You think you're bulletproof?
Every second I see
someone killed!
Are you mad?
Suppose you get the medal!
I'd be happy to go home
with leaving you dead?
How could I look at
mom and Young-shin?
You're still young and ill
But I'm a soldier now
Don't ask them to sit
me out again
You and I should be together
We live and die
together
Ifyou do this again
I wont' forgive you
Don't get me wrong
Already 15 dead
from our unit alone
but no one knows
who's gonna die next...
If I can live
staying behind
I will stay behind
- Please understand me
- No way!
You want me to
watch you die?
I won't die, until I get you
back home safely
- Let's go
- Jin-tae!
You know
I want both of us to live
But if only one gets to go
I want it to be you
You alright?
You all did a great job!
Besides our victory
there is one more good news!
The U.S marines made
a successful landing
at Incheon
We'll push in as they make
the 2nd attack into Incheon
Your bravery exemplifies
the men of this battalion
Raise this flag on Mt. Baekdu
by the Chinese border
Yes, sir!
Seoul, September 1950 Mr LEE, Could you look
at the camera when you are taking the picture?
Mr LEE, Could you look at the camera
when you are taking the picture?
Why were two brothers from
the same family in the same battle?
We had no other choice
but to volunteer the army
in order to protect
our country
from danger
We heard you did
a great job at Nak-dong river
Any other motivation
for fighting so bravely?
My only motivation
as a soldier
is to fight to prevent
my family from
suffering under
the oppression of
the communists!
Jin-tae!
I'm going to send
a letter home
Tell me what you
wanna write
We have to send it
with a local
Do I have to do it now?
- Sergeant LEE
- Yeah!
Let's do it later
I have to go to the reception
We've got to ask one of
the people on the street!
- Sergeant LEE
- Yeah!
You write something for me
See you later!
Jin-tae!
What is this?
Are you kidding me?
Give me some eggs!
Give me the eggs
Behave yourself!
Come on YANG!
Come on, an egg!
Is there anyone from
in Manri-dong?
Who lives in Manri-dong?
I don't remember
the last time I ate like this!
Nothing but vegetables!
Where's my egg?
So, do you like it?
You know, Jin-tae is
really going to be on TV?
You saw him
with the American officers
and the cameras flashing
That's Sergeant LEE
as of today
And he's squad leader
of the 1 st
He was talking well
'For the families oppressed by the reds... '
A hero is born
You envy him?
Then kill the communists!
He sure does have
a face for TV
My gosh, this guy
doesn't know anything
What do you know
about photogenic?
That kind of face is
good for nothing practical
He's nothing
compared to this
Damn, what a knock out!
How did you get
a wife like this!
I told you to look at
my son, not my wife
I saw you looking
at her breasts!
Give it to me
My son'll be a General like
MacArthur someday
I also have a wife in
the North
- MacArthur!
- When'll this
damn war be over?
I thought it'd last
only a week
When you go home
you go back to school
It'll be soon, since
the U.S has joined
Yeah, right
Your home is near here
isn't it?
If your mom's back in Seoul
she'll be searching for you two
Just one each!
- Congratulations
- Thank you
Jin-seok!
You know what this is?
This is the chocolate
you wanted so much
Just tell me
if you want more
They will
give me more
any time I tell them
Yes, I drank a little
Don't worry
You'll be home soon
It's only a matter of days before
I put this flag on Mt. Baekdu
You should be sleeping
It will get rough
from tomorrow
- Did you send the letter?
- I asked someone
I don't think
they're back in Seoul
It's getting cold
at night
You should go inside
You felt like
a stranger today
I kept worrying
I've been thinking
about things
There's one thing
I want you to do
Please forget about the medal
It's not worth it
You're the only
brother I have...
And we have to
go back alive
You know, right?
I was so scared
when dad died and
mom couldn't speak anymore
But you helped me
get through it all
Jin-tae
The day after tomorrow
You were supposed to get
married to Young-shin
I hope you think about Young-shin
And all our family
not only me
Pyongyang, North Korea
October 1950
3rd unit, block off the back road
He surely didn't get out yet
2nd unit, 2nd unit!
You can't let him go!
You must get him alive, got it?
The commies are
hitting back hard!
Where's their captain?
Shit, sons of bitches!
- Cover me
- What?
Sergeant LEE!
Jin-tae!
A few more up there!
I saw them!
- Cover me
- Too dangerous!
- My brother's in danger
- Sit down!
Get down
It's dangerous!
Come with me
Yong-man and KIM
come with me!
- What's going on?
- The captain is escaping
This isn't your business
The 3rd platoon is
here for that!
The 3rd is waiting
on the way out!
This is an order!
- Don't go
- Come on!
Sergeant LEE!
Damn!
Stay still, don't move
you son of a bitch
Stay still, don't move!
you son of a bitch!
Yong-man
- Don't move!
- Shoot me
Not now!
You think I'm gonna
say a thing?
Get up!
Yong-man, please wake up
Yong-man!
Am I gonna die?
Yong-man
Medic!
Kill me now!
Yong-man, don't give up!
I won't let you go!
Yong-man! you okay?
- Yong-man, come on!
- No, Yong-man!
Yong-man!
- Get up!
- He is the captain!
I got him!
I got him alright!
- Yong-man
- Yong-man!
- Come on!
- Yong-man...
GO Yong-man
To position, salute
Back to position
We'll continue over
to Aprok River
near the Chinese border
I hope every one of you get
there safe and alive
Let's leave
What's wrong?
The medal... who are you
really doing this for?
You love being a hero
don't you?
Promotions, parties
interviews...
Who knows? You might even
be battalion commander, right?
Keep this in mind
Yong-man's son, Min-seok
will grow up without
a father
And bear a grudge
against you forever
- Stop it
- If you'd listened to me back there!
He wouldn't be dead!
Do you know why he died?
Do you know what you
were doing
while he was dying?
What good is the medal
when people are dying for it!
Not another word
What the...
This is Seagull One
The communists have
slaughtered all
the villagers
Roger
Report to headquarters
Let's take care
of the bodies
This is Seagull One
We will take off after recovering
the bodies at Dongjin, Over!
Help me
Please find my mom
- Don't cry, I will help you
- Help me
Medic! Medic!
They even left traps!
Don't let even one of
those bastards live!
Get up, you communist bastard
Son of a bitch!
Die!
You dirty pawn of
American imperialism!
Please, don't kill me
Fuck, son of a bitch
Get up, you fucks!
Go on and sit down!
I surrender
- Hey, you!
- I surrender
- How many are in there?
- There are five
They'll come out, too
Please don't kill us
You killed them, right?
No, they were dead
when we came
One more lie, you're
dead, got it?
You killed them?
- Don't shoot!
- Shut up!
Don't lie to me!
Oh, please!
Yong-seok!
Jin-seok!
- What happened?
- Jin-seok!
I was forced to join the North
Korean army or be killed
Now it's okay
don't cry
Drink this
Should I report?
Jin-tae!
Report that all the enemies
were killed in battle
- What are you talking about?
- They'll be excess baggage
This is Yong-seok!
He was like your own brother!
All I see now is
a communist
I am Yong-seok
your friend!
I know shoeshine boy Yong-seok
but that's not you
PFC LEE, move away!
We're not communists
He was forced
to come here!
You step back!
- Did you kill them?
- No!
we didn't! Really!
He says he didn't!
- I don't believe a commie
- They are animals!
- Get out of the way!
- Jin-seok!
- Come out!
- Let go!
Don't kill me! Jin-tae
Please don't kill me
Jin-tae... Jin-tae
Get your hands off!
Kneel down!
- You dirty pig!
- Don't kill me
Go ahead
and I'll report that you kill
unarmed soldiers
We're no better than
the commies killing civilians!
You are all crazy!
They're hostages!
You saw what they did!
They're animals!
If we kill them
we are animals, too
It was them who
started the war!
We're the same
No better, no worse!
Okay, kill them
Shoot!
What are you waiting for?
Shoot, shoot!
Go on and shoot!
Today's your lucky day!
Get up!
go, you bastards
Hye-San-Jin, far northern Korea
November 1950
Yong-seok
Jin-seok!
Take it
Boys! Have some
- Are you okay?
- I feel fine
Take your time
I filed a report about you
with the regimental office
Thanks a lot
Jin-tae is... not who he was
He's so changed
Just before I left, I met
your mom and Young-shin
Really?
How are they? When did
they come back home?
Just after you
were drafted
She wanted to be home
in case you came back
She asked people about you
Whenever she saw me
she cried
I reminded her of you two
And the noodle stand?
Frankly... she isn't well
What's wrong?
Is it serious?
I don't know exactly...
but she couldn't move well
Young-shin was
having a hard
time, caring for everyone
The commies wouldn't
let her run the stand
She attends rallies all day long
It's the only way
to get food
Don't worry, though
Things may be
getting better
I miss the noodles
your mom cooks
The loser doesn't eat
for two days!
Do it right, bastards!
- Won't you do it right?
- Kill him! kill him!
Do it right, bastards!
2 days aren't bad enough?
You want 5?
You ain't hungry?
You crazy bastard
do it right!
You see now?
Like this! Like this!
Think of him
as South Korean pig
Like this!
Fight until one gets
knocked out
If not, I'll kill
both of you
You got it?
You got it!
Who's going to be
the damn South Korean?
You do it!
You don't need to
You don't have to
It's you and me now
- What the hell are you doing?
- Isn't this a game?
Fight, or you'll die
of starvation
- Stop it!
- Come on
Come on, son of a bitch!
Come on!
There you go
that's the way
We're not done yet!
We fight until one
of us can't get up!
We fight until the end!
- You are killing him
- Let go!
Anyone tries to stop me
I'll kill you, too!
Get up, or you'll
starve to death!
Come on!
Fight or you're dead
I said, fight, you pig!
Bring it on!
Bastard!
Many of our brave soldiers
sacrificed their lives
for their country
And the long awaited victory
Is very close
- Just stay still!
- It hurts!
I can't help it
When the hell can we go home?
And General MacArthur
has ordered
UN forces to advance
to the north
The victory is ours
You all did a great job
Reunification is right before us...
Victory!
2nd battalion!
What's going on over there?
We're going home!
home!
Ok, let's kick some ass!
It looks like the war
may be over soon
I wouldn't be so sure
I heard Chinese will back the north
That's just commie propaganda
Uncle Yang
what do you think?
The Sunspot and Great Bear
are losing energy now and...
We will be home
before the New Year
You really sure this time?
What the hell!
Okay, I believe you
Sergeant LEE
Congratulations!
He'll get the Medal of Honor!
I expected it
you would get it
You got it for catching
the captain alive
The commander is
really pleased
- What is that medal of honor?
- You idiot!
Any time 'honor' is in
the medal's name, it's good
Tomorrow the commander will
award it himself tomorrow
Let's give him a big hand!
Sergeant LEE, now you can
be a soldier forever
Jin-seok!
Let's talk
Make it short
I'm on duty
You can go home soon
Then go back to school
right away
You missed a lot
You're the one that needs
to go home
You're sick
I'm not going home
You'll do what I say
- I don't want anything from you
- Listen to me
What's wrong with you?
I worked my ass off
for that medal!
This is a great chance
for us!
For you, not for me
Have you thought about
what the medal means?
I don't care
I needed one to
send you home
That medal costs Yong-man's life!
I won't go
You have to go to college!
What good is college now?
I hate everything
you stand for
Don't tell me what to do
Do you really mean that?
I will make my own decisions
Don't tell me what to do
You really want
either of us to die?
Then, you go home instead!
What did I risk my life for?
I didn't ask you to!
I want... you to go home alive
I also want to go home
y'know
But you are our family's...
dream and hope!
I never regretted
giving up school
and shining shoes for you
Mom happily broke
her back for you
Do you know our sacrifices?
I know all
Why am I the only one you
think about?
If you think about
Young-shin and
Yong-man, you couldn't have done it
I don't care what you think
as long as you can go home
The command post will leave first
Take the classified documents
and burn the others
Yes, sir!
One more telegram
Retreat to 2nd rendezvous point
Date of Order 09:00 hours
Regiments 12, 13 and 25
are already retreating
US army is retreating, too
How many Chinese
reinforcements are coming?
For Woon-san city alone
at least 100,000
They'll fire on
us any minute, sir
Hurry, they're
getting close
Sergeant LEE
what are you doing?
What the hell!
Everything was going so well
People of Chosun fucking liberated
We'll never get home
before New Year!
We're just gonna leave?
How stupid!
Shouldn't we die here?
This is wrong!
We should be fighting
Stop bitching and hurry up!
I wanted to believe your shit
but look at this!
Hey, make it fast!
Get the jeep ready!
How far are we
gonna carry them?
- Don't move!
- Who the fuck are you?
Get him!
Oh fuck!
Hold!
- Sergeant Huh!
- I'm alright, retreat
Medic!
Call the medic!
Sergeant Huh!
Bastards...
Where's my arm?
Stay back
or I'll kill him!
- Put the dagger away!
- You come closer and I'll kill you!
Kill them all!
Don't come any closer
Hurry, just kill them!
Shoot him!
Step back!
Ifyou come closer
this bastard is dead!
No!
Yong-seok, come on!
Yong-seok! Yong-seok!
Are you crazy?
How could you...
How could you do that to...
You bastard!
Stop this!
Bring him back!
You're a murderer!
What the hell are you doing?
You two knock it off!
We're all gonna die!
We've got to get out of here!
How come... we're
retreating without fighting?
Jang-Dan, near the 38th parallel
December 1950
Line up, line up!
Staff Sergeant LEE Jin-tae
You're awarded the Medal of Honor
for your actions
in Pyongyang your remarkable bravery
and actions at many battles
and for going beyond
the call of duty
'December1 st 1950
President RYEE Syng-man'
Staff Sergeant Lee Jin-tae!
Congratulations
you've finally made it!
Thank you!
This should have been
a formal occasion, Sorry
1 st battalion, proceed
to the 3rd rendezvous site
2nd, 3rd and 4th battalions
to the 5th rendezvous point
Be at your locations
by 18:00 hours tomorrow
All forces will be
reorganized there
Now you'll go to your
assembly areas
Dismiss
See you at the next site
- Sir, may I have a word with you?
- Go ahead
Sir, it's about my
younger brother
I'll make an official request
with the division commander
Thank you, sir
I'm afraid we'll be
pushed down to Seoul
I'm afraid we're going further
to the south, across Nakdong
You know where Jin-seok is?
He left a minute ago
- By himself?
- Yes
He said he was going to
see your mom
She is sick
- Get on quick!
- Let's go!
Mom!
Jin-seok!
Young-shin!
Jin-seok...
Thank God, You're alive
This isn't a dream, is it?
I'm on my way
to reassemble
I ran into Yong-seok
He said mom is sick
She's feeling much better now
She's back at work
How is Jin-tae?
Why didn't he come?
He's fine
He's really busy right now
That's good
Mother is so worried
Are you KIM Young-shin?
Yes, I am but?
Come with me
You're under investigation
For what?
What?
- What's this, who the hell are you?
- Jin-seok!
- Tell me what this is about
- Step away!
Stop!
Stop right there!
Shoot if you dare
Put her on
Put the son of a bitch on!
Check if he's a communist
Young-guk, go home!
Don't follow me!
Get off!
- Young-shin, Young-shin!
- Jin-seok, Jin-seok!
What is this place?
This is where we investigate
commies like Young-shin!
You're making a mistake
We'll see about that
Get in there!
LEE Jung-ja, JUNG Kook-sup
KIM Young-shin
Get up!
Aim!
Don't even think about it
Let's not hurt each other
Get up, Young-shin
Jin-tae...
Where is Jin-seok?
He was taken into
the front building
What's going on?
They just said I was under
investigation and took me here
We're executing traitors
according to the law
I don't care what you're doing
- I'm taking her
- Then you're a commie, too!
- I don't think so!
- KIM Young-shin, 23
signed up for the communist
party on June 23
We have her signature!
I did it only for food
I didn't know what it was!
She worked for
the communist party 35 times
And participated in
numerous communist rallies!
We were starving
I have to get food somehow!
The South Korean government
gave us nothing!
Shut up!
You step away
- Don't be stupid
- You're dead, too
Touch her you're all dead!
This is the last warning
Step aside
Don't move!
Or you won't walk
out of here in piece
Do you know what
you are doing?
I'm stopping you from
killing innocent people
Get her out of here!
You wanna save a whore?
She was with every single
North Korean officer!
Shut your damn mouth
before I'll blow it off!
That's why she isn't fleeing
- That's not true
- Don't pretend you don't know
- It's no use denying it
- No, that's a lie
- Go now!
- Last warning
If you take her out of here
you two are commies too
No, Jin-tae
Jin-tae, believe me
Get the hell out of here!
Bring them out and go!
- Now!
- Stop right there!
Young-shin!
Young-shin, hold on!
Hold on, Young-shin!
You... still have
the handkerchief
You don't know...
how much I missed you
I... didn't do anything
shameful, Believe me
Nothing, Jin-tae
Young-shin!
I can't die now...
How can I die now?
Our young brothers...
people...
Jin-tae...
Young-shin!
Young-shin...
Why did you question her?
You know you killed her
you killed her, you...
You killed her
you murderer...
You shot members of
the Anti-communist Federation?
The Medal of honor doesn't give
you the right to shoot anyone
How can we fight this war
with screw ups like you?
What happen to contact with
the headquarters?
I'm still trying, sir
How can we hold out for
72 hours with those losers!
Send my brother home!
My former commander
promised to
What kind of
bullshit is this?
You earn a damn medal and
your brother is discharged?
You only have to report it
I don't believe this!
I don't give a shit
what he promised you!
You think this is
a business deal or something?
He started it
How dare you talk back?
Think of what you've done!
Lock him up!
What a waste of Medals!
Urgent message
from the 1 st company!
Put him in the cell!
I don't give a shit about
the order. Just retreat!
I'll take responsibility
All companies, retreat!
God damn!
- Open the cell
- You're crazy!
Give the order!
Those commies will
kill you first
I only want my brother out
Not until we finish examining
your heads first
Give the order, Now!
One more thing...
the hostages...
Burn them!
- Change that order!
- Put the gun away
- I said, change the order!
- This is an order, Remove the gun!
Change the order!
Burn the warehouse down
it's an order!
Medic! Medic!
Open the door!
Jin-seok...
Let go, you bastards
I'm the chief
Military Hospital, Tae-Jeon
South Korea, July 1951
Jin-seok!
You look well
Thanks, You saved my life
I thought I was dead
in that cell
I did too when you got shot
as we were coming out
Someone up there likes you
- When do you get out of here?
- Next week
How nice to be discharged!
I bet your mom needs your help
This damn war should be over
The battle around the 38th
parallel is still bloody
Everyday so many lives are lost
but we can't take any ground
I bought them on my way
Thank you again
And... your brother sent...
This letter home... but it was
returned to the camp
You keep this
I doubt he retreated then
I've searched everywhere, but...
I don't want to know
- I don't care
- PFC Lee Jin-seok!
You're wanted
in the counseling room
Thank you
Our decorated hero
turned into a communist
It's a serious problem for us and
a good propaganda tool for them
At first we didn't believe it
But his fiancee was executed
as a communist
That must have affected him
He doesn't know what
communism or democracy is
Then how come he
turned into a communist!
He wouldn't have done this
If he thought of his family
I suppose there must be a reason
You, too are a suspect, unless
you give us a good explanation
I don't care about Jin-tae
The Jin-tae I knew was just
an innocent shoeshine boy...
who loved his family
especially his brother
The one who's got the medal
and leads 'Flag unit'...
He is not my brother
What happened to Jin-tae?
I was questioned, too
You had lunch?
How can you eat right now?
Unthinkable!
We expected him to
become a captive, but
how can he become a communist?
After seeing his fiancee
shot to death and then...
He must have thought that
you were killed in the fire
He loved you so much
I don't care about him
He's crazy about medals
they must have offered him
a good post!
Maybe the damn commies
Offered him a better post!
You see?
Dear Mother
I miss you every day
Please stay well until
we get back
And don't worry about Jin-seok
I will definitely keep Jin-seok safe
War is tough but Jin-seok
is doing fine, don't worry
Please say hello
to Young-shin
When I'm back home
I'll make you happier
I promise
Be careful in this
cold weather
It's very cold
Take care of yourself, mom
All these patients came from
the battle near
the 38th parallel
Your are crazy
to go back there
How can you be sure that
you'll even find him?
You'll be discharged in a week
Think about your mom!
Please listen to me, Jin-seok!
See you soon
You've to take care of
Young-shin's brother and sisters!
Jin-seok!
PFC LEE Jin-seok!
Take care, you bastard!
We attack up the middle of hills
931 and 851 dividing them
Then battalions 1 and 2 flank
the hills from both directions
As I said before
in this strategy
We have to take out
'Flag unit' at all costs!
Don't forget we've moved
the operation up 1 day
A question?
When will PFC Lee join the mission?
He'll sit this one out
Since the Americans
moved the attack up 24 hours
there's no time
He'll speak over
the microphone
- Sir!
- What is it?
I'm LEE Jin-tae's brother
It's an honor to meet
the brother of the traitor!
Unless he sees me, he won't
believe it's me
I have to go
We start the attack
in an hour
There's not enough time
If he sees I am alive
he'll come back for sure!
- Please let me go
- Out of the question!
Sir, please!
Answer me one question
Is this for your country
or your brother?
Just read the script
over the speaker
40 minutes to go!
No enemy movements
detected, sir!
F-86 Sabres are standing
by Artillery units
are standing by
- Loyalty!
- Where is the script?
- It's not been delivered yet
We thought the Headquarters
would give it to us
Wait a moment
Check personal arms, a dagger
grenades, extra magazines
- To position!
- One, two, four, eight, six
- one, two, four...
931 Highland
move military power
K-9 Osan first arrival formation
landing begun
Military power and all present
stationing complete
Sir, PFC Lee is running
toward the enemy unit
- What's going on?
- He just surrendered
What?
Surrendered?
If you lie, you're dead
Why are you here?
I came here to see my brother
The leader of 'Flag unit'
- What!
- Please let me see him
I'll kill you
if you're lying
Check it out
A yellow dog is here saying
he's the brother of mother owl
Confirm
- Let me talk to him!
- Confirm
- He doesn't know I'm alive!
- Shut up!
Negative
Says his brother is dead
Please, let me talk!
Jin-tae, it's me
Jin-seok!
You're a damn spy
What's your mission?
Spit it out before
I blow your head off!
Let me talk to him
He'll know it's me
Stop screwing with me!
- I'm begging you!
- What are you here for!
- Oh, please!
- Speak up!
- I'm begging you
- Sir!
We've got an order to
bring him to the security unit
Get him out of here!
Dearfellow North Korean citizens
despite months of struggle
our army is stil
holding on strong
- How far away is 'Flag unit'?
- Ask the security!
Reckless behavior will
only bring death
Alert!
Air attack!
- Hurry up, let's go!
- You're Goddamn crazy!
Where is 'Flag unit'?
Fix bayonet! Fix bayonet!
Where the hell are you going?
He's a dog from the south!
It's 'Flag unit'!
I'm gonna kill you, you crybaby
Kill 'em all!
Kill 'em!
Son of a bitch!
Jin-tae!
You southern bastard...
- Die!
- It's Jin-seok, Snap out of it!
Bro! I'm Jin-seok!
- Wake up!
- I'll kill you all
Jin-tae!
Jin-tae, please!
Please, brother!
Jin-tae!
Sons of bitches!
You South Korean piece of shit!
- Jin-tae, please!
- State guard bastards!
Please come to your senses!
Look at me, I am Jin-seok
your only brother!
- Die!
- I am your brother!
Die, all you pieces of shit!
- Retreat!
- Bastards
Retreat!
State guard bastards...
Jin-tae, get up!
You have to come with me!
Let's go, we have no time!
Bro, get up! We have to go!
We have to go now!
We have to get out of here
Please, get up!
Don't you think of mom?
You have to take care of
Young-shin's grave!
You promised many things!
You can't die here!
You have to live to see me
go to college, come on!
- Jin-seok?
- Jin-tae!
You're really alive
Go!
No, Jin-tae!
I won't go alone
- Just go
- No way!
- Get up and come with me
- Listen
I will surrender and
come home after the war
I was making shoes I'd give
to you when you go to college
I haven't finished them
so I won't die, Hurry!
- I won't!
- I am okay
- Do as I told you, go!
- I wont' go without you
- Go!
- Let's go, we must go together
Then both of us will die
- No!
- Listen to me!
Look at me, Believe me
I found this after the fire
Give it to me...
when we meet again
You have to come back...
You have to come back!
You promised... to come back
and finish the shoes...
But what are you doing here?
I've waited for so long!
What happened to your promise?
Say something!
Please say something...
I've been waiting to see
for 50 years!
Please say something
I shouldn't have left
you alone back then!
Jin-tae...
Jin-tae!
Jin-seok!
Jin-seok
Let's go to get some water
Go!
How have you been?
We are going back
to school, y'know
- School?
- I can't wait to go to school
- How about you?
- Me too, of course