Who are you?
Jesus.
You ok?
Do I look ok?
If you were any thinner, you wouldn't exist
No...
Trevor...
You still got half an hour.
I can fix you some eggs.
I am tired but thanks.
Let's go, monkeys.
Watch your work, not your ass.
Come on guys, keep it moving.
Yes sir, yes sir,
Master Tucker, motherfucker
Hey, why is that machine down!
- I am cleaning this.
- It takes 7 minutes to power up that mill
Where am I going to make up
that 7 minutes? Miller?
Your paycheck?
- Back off Tucker, you don't sketch regulations.
- What regulations?
Lock out devices must be in place during cleaning
and maintenance of all heavy machineries,
Ya! Write to your congressman and hurry that up.
Congratulations, Reznik.
You just made my shitlist.
And he's like, you know, babe this babe that...
Chatting like mother fucking Barry White.
Talking about what he is going to do to her,
and how to make her Cucci feel and all that.
That is right.
So then, she stopped
She looked back at him with these
big puppy eyes she's like...
That sounds good puppy,
but me no have no Cucci
So, my man said, what?!
He looked down and realised that SHE IS A HE!
Man, that's bullshit!
You meant to tell me that this whore was wearing nothing
but a thong and this fool can't tell no difference.
Hey, man. he had one of those "tuck jobs".
Come on Jones, you know how to do that.
You might, I don't!
Yeah, whatever.
You Reznik, you wanna go for some cards tonight?
Can't, got plans.
Shit! See, this nigger say the same thing every poker night.
Hey, what is up with you? you used to be alright.
Well, he used to hang but he ain't never been alright.
Hey, Jackson, you need to realise that
some men prefer the company of women.
Who! hotty duty, he ain't get no booty.
Maybe he has got a date by the name "tuck jobs"
No, your mother said she couldn't make it.
Oh! Reznik talking smack,
I can't even respond to that.
You ok?
Do I look ok?
If you were any thinner, you wouldn't exist.
What's wrong?
I don't know, deja vu.
You are tired, you need to sleep.
How do you do it?
What?
Sleep so little and still look so good.
Are you flirting with me?
Commiserating
- Try to fatten me up?
- What if I am?
Suppose I wanted blueberry.
You had that last night.
You don't fool me, Trevor Reznik.
I have you figured out.
- You do, huh?
- Muhmmm
What else do you know about me?
That you are lonely.
When you work here as long as I have,
you get to know the type.
Hey, everyone gets lonely, Trevor.
It is nothing to be ashamed of.
How can I be lonely,
when I have you to keep me company?
Check please
You, Reznik, Furman's office. Now!
How are you doing, Reznik?
What is this about?
Frankly I am concerned about you.
To be honest, I think you look like toasted shit.
I felt a lot on my mind lately.
- Anything we can help with?
- No, thanks. There's nothing I can't handle.
- Wanna see a doctor?
- It is not necessary, I am fine really.
Are you doing drugs Reznik?
Where is Stewart?
He couldn't make it
- Shouldn't even be in here with an union
- See what I mean.
Look, Trevor, I understand how you feel, but believe me,
there is absolutely nothing to worry about
Then I will just get back to work
Er... Trevor, not yet.
I need to ask you for a UA
Look like rain.
Radio says there is a storm on the way.
they said right.
I'd say it's already here.
You are on the first shift?
- Yeah
- Me too
Funny I never seen you before.
I've been here.
I work in the pit
I just picked up Reynolds's shift.
Where is Reynolds?
Feds picked him up.
On warrant.
I am Ivan.
Trevor
Well, I guess I'd better begin by...
I hear that Tucker guy can be a real prick.
You got that right.
I will see you around.
what is wrong?
I just want to lie here.
We can do that.
I'm... so... tired
You can fall asleep if you want, off the meter.
That is the problem. I can't sleep.
Nothing helps.
Don't worry about it honey.
Everyone get insomnia every now and then.
Stevie
I haven't slept in a year.
Jesus Christ!
I tried him too...
I am sorry.
Hello?
Yeah. No I can't.
I can't talk now. Okay.
My ex, he's a fucking Psycho.
Trevor, I am worried about you.
Don't worry, no one ever died of insomnia.
I hope not, you are my best client.
Can't afford to lose ya.
Geee... thanks
Reznik, I need a hand
Gotta get this dead level here, help me out
- Safety on?
- Oh Yeah
How is that?
A little to the left.
Do I need more?
Hey, you sleep on your own time, need some help here.
Better, now try the other side.
I hate this bitch.
Hey! what did you do?
I am hooked up here.
Kill it, will ya?
- Come on, kill it.
- Not working.
Damn it! Reznik!
Shit!
- Kill it!
- Not working
God! Jesus!
- Hit the breaker!
- What?
Hit the breaker!
Hey, hey, hey!
We some help over here!
We need some help
- Come on man, come on.
- What's happening here, man?
Call an ambulance!
What happened here?
I was helping him with the belt.
I thought the safety was on.
You thought?!
Somebody kill that fucking machine!
Shit!
Hello, Mrs. Shrike. I come to give you the rent.
And so early. Oh Mr Reznik, I only wish
all my tenants are considerate as you.
I will give you a receipt in the morning
Good night mr. Reznik.
Err... Mrs. Shrike, Forgive me
but... if you noticed anyone
hanging around my apartment?
- Has there been a burglary?
- No, no, no, I just wondered if...
You know errr... if you noticed anything unusual lately?
Unusual?
Ah, never mind, Mrs. Shrike.
I am sorry... to disturb you so late.
Good night.
What we know is this:
One: Miller was operating the mill in long sleeves.
Two: Miller's arm was in the cutting zone
of mill while it was off.
Three: the mill suddenly activates,
catching Miller's sleeve, resulting in this.
What is the fucking point?
These accidents are never pretty, Mr. Reznik.
Our job is to investigate these events
from every possible angles...
So that we might prevent their reoccurrence.
So we'd appreciate it if you are a bit more co-operative.
I knocked into the fucking activator by mistake.
What caused the mistake, Mr. Reznik?
I was distracted.
By what?
What distracted you?
It was Ivan,
I was watching Ivan on the pit.
The whole thing is my fault, okay.
Who did you say?
The new arcwelder,
I don't know his last name.
- What new arcwelder?
- Ivan, the guy from the swing shift.
Reynolds was picked up on a warrant
This guy got his place.
What the fuck are you talking about, Reznik?
Reynolds is right over there
on the pit as usual, busting his ass.
There is no Ivan in National Machine, Reznik.
What is this?
Mr. Reznik
Have you recently suffered any head injuries?
Ever hear of pumpkin pie?
No
- Trevor
- Yeah
Can I ask you a question?
Sure
Why do you go all of your way
to come here every night?
Is it all the way?
An airport? For coffee and pie?
Suppose I went to Danni's...
Suddenly I get an overwhelming urge to skip town.
Could I do that just in any diner?
Is someone chasing you?
Not yet. But they will
when they find out who I am.
Oh really! Who are you?
Can you keep a secret?
To the grave.
I am Elvis Presley.
I ran away from home
to pursue my blue-collar aspirations.
I thought you looked familiar.
Got plans for mother's day?
I am taking my little boy to the amusement park.
Suppose to be my day and he gets all the fun.
That is ok, when he is older
I will let him make it up to me.
A little guilt goes a long way.
How about you?
Cemetery
- Oh, I am sorry
- Thanks
I lost mine too. Still hurts.
I am not so good at losing family.
Who is?
What's weird is that it did not hit
until I picked out her burial dress.
I pictured her while buying it...
...Not knowing it would...
You know, be the one.
Seems unfair, isn't it?
Not knowing things like that
Hey, how about spending the day
with me and Nicolas after the cemetery?
Sounds dreamy
Hey Reynolds, what did the Feds want you for?
Armed robbery.
Oh yeah, that is right, because I and Jackson
had you packed and pantified... ain't that right, Jackson?
HEY, I don't see what is so fucking funny.
You clowns think this's fucking like some big joke
but it ain't!
Personally, I don't feel too comfortable working with you.
You made me nervous.
You look like shit, acting all crazy.
What is up with you?
Nothing is up with me.
It was an accident and I am the one
who gotta live with it, not you.
You ain't hearing me, man.
Nobody wants you here.
Nobody.
See you tomorrow.
Hey
Howdy, partner.
You gotta go back to the shop.
Tucker needs to see you.
- What about?
- I don't know, but it seemed important.
What! He's ganna have to wait,
it is Miller time.
We need to talk.
Follow me.
Come on!
Another Bourbon.
Make it double.
You shooting coke or something?
You look like a dope fiend to me.
No offence.
I don't use drugs.
I mean I don't even drink.
How about abnormally?
I see Reynolds is back to work.
Gets to me bail
I will tell you one thing,
If I dig, You are showing carbon to it.
Would you? never trust a con, cowboy!
They ain't get to live to be honest.
Where they hiding you these days?
Around
Hey, you wanna see something?
Look at that. Lost them on a lake.
They took a big toe from the left foot
and a finger from my right.
That is why I walk with a gimp.
Yeah, I can't shuffle my cock like I used to
but the ladies sure like it.
Oh, no. You look like you have seen a ghost.
Funny you should say that.
The guys from work don't think you exist.
- That is why I can't get a raise.
- According to Tucker, you are not even on the payroll.
You believe that?
- Why would they lie?
- They just have a little bit of fun with you.
I am not laughing.
Quit fucking around, a guy lost his arm.
He could have died.
That ain't my problem.
You caused the accident, not me.
Where are you going?
Take a leak, you wanna watch?
I will be right back, don't just bail me now.
- Hello?
- Hey Reynolds, it's Trevor.
What time is it?
How are they biting Reynolds?
- You, you are drunk, Reznik.
- The game's over. I got proof on you.
I could use it.
You better watch your fucking ass buddy,
before you lose it.
Trevor?
I need to see you, Stevie.
- Well, Jesus, Trevor, I am not exactly alone here.
- Please, Stevie.
- I think I am falling apart.
- Can you come back in an hour?
No, no, no, no, I need to see you now.
In case of something happens,
I need someone to know.
Ok, give me a minute.
I appreciate you making time for me,
you are the only one I can talk to.
My pleasure.
Most guys don't come here for my conversation.
Something is happening to me, Stevie.
Some kind of... plot.
There was an accident at the shop.
A man was nearly killed thanks to me.
- Oh, my god!
- Now the guys at work are against me.
They want me out and I don't blame them.
Just the way they're going about it...
Their eyes, their little games.
What?
E R.. E R..
- T U C K E R
- Trevor?
TUCKER?
Maybe err you take this accident thing a bit too hard.
I mean...
If they wanted you out,
they could just fire you.
I am not worried about being fired.
Then what are you worried about?
I don't know yet.
There you go, made to order.
- Thanks.
- Surprise!
Got ya! That one's going on the fridge.
Here, let me get one of you and Nicolas.
By the carousel.
Just a minute.
Okay, ready.
Smile!
It helps if you push the button.
Trevor? What is it?
- This place, brings back memories.
- Good memories I hope.
Yeah, I haven't been here since I was a kid.
My ex, probably phone
to ruin a happy Mother's Day
Could you...?
- Yes, no sweat. I will take Nicolas for a ride.
- Thanks.
How long have you known my mother?
About a year.
How did you meet her?
We just kind of met.
Are you going to see her again?
I hope so.
Would you like that?
I guess so
Hey, you wanna know a secret?
What?
My father left us when I was your age.
You wanna know something else?
Made me realised what a wonderful mother I had.
You will realise that too some day.
What is that?
Monster ride.
Route six hundred and sixty six.
What does that mean?
Well, a route is a road you take
when you're on a long journey.
Can we go in?
Well, Nicolas, maybe we should wait for your mother.
What for?
You are going straight
to hell on route 666.
Ride here if you dare!
You are going straight to hell on route 666.
Look like someone had a bad crack up.
Fill her up, cowboy.
We wouldn't be eating in there
anytime soon, Nicolas?
Eww.. look at that.
You should close your eyes.
Jesus!
- Boy, this is one heck of a ride.
- Yeah.
Shady Lady
Oh, my God.
Stop!
Woo
Take a right, Nicolas!
Right, a right!
Nicolas, Nicolas!
Hey, Nicolas!
I need some help here.
Okay, somebody gets a doctor.
Hang on Nicolas, I'm going for help.
Nicolas!
I swear to God, I don't know what happened.
He is epileptic.
I should have told you.
- I will call an ambulance.
- No, thanks.
It is ok, baby.
It hasn't happened for a while.
I didn't think to mention it.
I could have killed myself
for taking him on that ride.
It's ok, it's not your fault.
He won't even remember it,
as if nothing ever happened.
Wanna come in?
I think you could use a drink.
I hope wine is okay with you.
That'll work.
What good is it at home
if you can't relax in it.
I will have to remember that.
Trevor? Can I ask you something?
Should my lawyer be present?
Why are you always leaving such generous tips?
- Do I?
- 20 dollars for coffee and pie?
And entertainment.
- Entertainment?
- You.
Trevor, you don't have to buy my companionship.
Sorry, I wasn't meant that way.
If you really wanna spoil me,
take me to a movie sometime.
Hmmm?
That is a deal.
My goodness, there must be a hole in this glass.
I will get it.
- You wait on me.
- Thanks
It is the last door on the left.
Reznik
I want you on the Swansea-leave today.
- Where is Sanchez?
- That is an irrelevant question, Reznik, I'm asking you.
Shit!
- If there's anything else we can do for you, let us know.
- Thank you, Mr Furman.
Bye. See you now.
Hey, look who it is.
Bombay Miller, you ok?
- Good, good.
- You be easy now.
Yeah, man, take it easy.
My God, Miller.
I don't know where to begin.
Nah, don't sweat it, kid.
There is nothing to say.
I wish there is someway I can repay you.
Well, for a start, you can give me your left arm.
In fact, that is why I came
by here today. Isn't it, Tucker?
Fair is fair
We are just razzing you, kid
You keep your left arm,
I will keep my settlement.
Hell! How can a guy lost an arm
end up like getting a deal like this?
So, I guess you can call me lucky.
Well, Miller,
if there is anything I can do...
Nah, forget it.
No hard feelings, huh.
I will see you around, pal.
Ah!
Hey!
Help!
Someone help me!
Reznik
Ah...
I got ya, I got ya.
Be cool, be cool, alright?
Who did it, huh?
Why did you turn the fucking braker!
Was it all of you?
Was it you, Jones?
Was it you? Was it you?
Or was it you?
You sick bastard,
you're imagining things again!
Oh yeah? You've been fishing
with Ivan lately, Reynolds?
How's that... How's that tuna biting?
Let's see how you talk yourself out of this one!
Where is it?
Right, what the fuck now, Reznik!
Get him off me!
Pick up your shit and get the fuck out of here.
You are fired.
This motherfucker's crazy.
You lost it, man.
Shit!
Damn it! Where is it?
Asshole!
What the fuck did you do with it?
Idiot!
Hey! Fuck you!
Get out!
What?
It's an occupational hazard.
So, Trevor, are you gonna rescue me from
this miserable life or what?
I could give it up for the right guy.
Oh, that came out wrong.
What I mean is...
I would, you know,
stop hooking if you wanted me to.
I mean, there are lots of
pancakes out there, right?
I think I'd like that.
Mr. Reznik.
I am sorry, I thought it was somebody else.
You leave me in such a scare.
What are you doing in my apartment?
There is a leak in my ceiling.
It's coming from your apartment.
That's impossible.
I'm gonna leave a note.
A note? What kind of note?
About the leak.
What's that terrible smell?
There is no leak in this apartment.
Now if you would excuse me...
You're sure you're alright, Mr. Reznik?
Yeah, I'm sure. If you need anything,
please call first.
Miller!
Hey, Reznik.
It's a pleasant surprise.
We need to talk.
Take a look at this, huh?
Picked it up at Grossens, top of the line.
Let's not trim anyting for a while.
I need to be doing something.
Can't just watch the soap opera all day.
That hydro will be here tomorrow.
You won't. Listen to the doctor.
Margie, this is Reznik.
The man who cost me my arm.
How do you do, Mrs. Miller?
I've been better, Mr. Reznik.
Is there some place we can talk?
Check it out.
It's a beauty.
8 cylinders
Speed sensitive steering
ABS breaking with road texure and tension
Defence lock-up helps you
maintain control in emergencies.
Of course, it's automatic.
Hell I wanted a stick...
but I figured my shifting ability
wouldn't be so hot.
You know I am not at
National any more, right?
Yeah, I heard about it.
It sounds like you almost
lost one yourself, huh?
Did you find that a bit ironic, Miller?
Ironic?
I'm sorry kid, I never got over sixth grade.
I'll break it down for you, Miller.
Moments after you left the shop,
someone powered up my machine.
With my arm in it.
I nearly got killed.
Accidents happen.
It wasn't an accident.
Accidents happen out of negligence
This happened down the spike.
That's some vocabulary you got kid.
Spike.
It wields vengeance,
vengeance means revenge Miller.
I am sure you know
what revenge means, don't you?
I am onto you Miller.
Despite your stupid jokes,
you secretly balme me for the accident.
New car, huh? You despise me for it.
How did you get into my place?
Duplicate keys? credit card? What?
Fuck you, Miller!
This shit is gonna stop!
Get off my property, punk!
Bastards.
Shit.
Come on.
7-4...
...3-C-R
It's 743CR.
What?
Shit.
Fuck!
I'm sorry sir, but we don't provide...
...motor's information to the general public.
I'm not just a memeber of the general public.
This guy is a friend of mine.
But you don't know your firend's address?
We just met, I don't know him that well.
Sir, this is the DMV, not the dating service.
I just want talk to him.
I'm sorry sir, I can't help you
unless a crime has been committed.
Has a crime been committed?
Please, I wouldn't ask
if it weren't extremly important.
Sorry sir. No crime, no information.
What if I told you I was hit by this car?
I don't see any bruises.
If you did,
would you give me an address?
No, but the police might.
I want to report a hit and run.
Bring it back when you are finished.
Fill it out over there.
Mr. Reznik.
You sure about these plate numbers?
743CR. All right, that's the one.
Do you ever have a car stolen?
No, what?
Cause the car that
allegedly hit you was your own.
1969, red pontiac viper
registered to your name.
Nearly a year ago you reported it
as being totally wrecked.
Do you know it is a felony
to file a bogus police report?
Hey, wait a minute.
You got some explaining to do.
Hey! Hey!
Jesus, Reznik. Just wanna talk to you.
Hey come back. Reznik, Reznik!
Trevor?
Oh, no.
Trevor, what do you want?
Trevor, it's okay.
Oh God, what happend?
I was crossing the street.
Lights changed on me.
Did he stop?
No, he just kept going.
He fucking hit my drivers man.
He gotta be hanged.
It was my fault.
I wasn't paying attention.
Trevor, we got get you to a hospital.
You may have some internal injuries.
it is just bruises.
Okay, you see this?
This is a bruise,
and this is a train wreck, alright?
What is it with you and doctors?
Don't you trust anyone?
I trust you.
Now I know.
You are crazy.
Can I stay here tonight?
Babe, you can stay here every night.
You know that?
What?
What,Babe,
what's going on in that crazy head of yours?
I really want this to work, Stevie
But?
You know so little about me.
What if I turned into a warewolf or something?
I will buy you a flea collar.
I love you.
Stevie
Yeah.
Thanks.
I set out some clean cloth for you,
your stuff is not dry yet.
You always keep men's cloth lying around?
Some of my regulars.
They like to keep their clean change cloth here.
I probably just throw
them out now, alright?
Hey, perfect fit.
Yeah, whatever Trevor.
I don't have a size 26 waist here.
Hey, how about that idea.
I can get a job selling man's wear.
Those chicks got paid vacations too.
I'll settle for that.
That's not a bad life.
Could be worse.
You know whatelse I want to do?
I want to clean up this place,
just get rid of all the fucking junk.
Probably look like I'm a terrible housekeeper,
which I sometimes am...
...but I can also be very very,
you know, organised and neat.
And I wanna do more of that.
I would love to paint a place.
Just make it nice, just be organised,
and neat and paint it white.
What I would also like is a decent stove.
This one is covered in fat.
Just like a white, beautiful place
and a decent stove.
Not a lot to ask.
Wow, don't look so surprised.
A call girl scrambling eggs...
Yeah that's funny,
I dont think I ever cooked for a guy before.
Not even my husband.
Jesus Christ.
Where is he?
Who?
You know who.
- Trevor.
- Don't.
Jesus, Trevor, what's wrong?
This, Ivan.
He's your ex, isn't he?
What?
Why is he doing this?
Just becuase i'm fucking you, isn't it?
Now it all makes sense.
I'm fucking you, so he's fucking me.
Where is he?
Hiding in the closet, beneath the bed?
I don't know what you are talking about, babe.
Ah, don't babe me.
Yeah, babe.
I'll change my whole fucking life for you.
I'll do anything you want, babe.
You know what, I don't deserve this.
What did you do?
- Hey!
- Slip this from my wallet from me while proposing to me?
Fuck you!
- You left it in my tip jar the other night.
- Bullshit.
- I thought you wanted me to have it.
- Cut the crap, Stevie.
- What is a big deal about a goddamn picture?
- They said that the guy in the photo doesn't exsit.
- This says he does.
- Trevor, I don't understand what the fuck you are talking about.
I'm talking about your ex!
Ivan.
- Who? This guy standing next to you with a fish?
- I'm not in that photo.
Trevor, I'm looking at a picture of you.
You are stading next to some fat guy
with glasses holding a fish.
That's not me.
Trevor, it's you.
Look.
You lying whore.
You get the fuck out.
Fucking freak.
You are a fucking pig
You fucking whore
You are a fucking freak.
You are a fucking psycho.
Fucking psycho
Where is Marie?
Who?
You know who.
Marie my waitress.
My! You are chatty tonight.
Darling, I am your waitress!
What's going on here?
I've never seen you before.
What are you talking about?
You come here every night, stay on that same stool, staring at your coffee.
Honest, I am starting to think that you are mute.
I wanna see Marie!
Mister, there is no Marie that works here.
Is everybody at it?
Let's have a laugh on Trevor.
Whatever Ivan was paying you is wasting his money.
Go home, Mister.
Get some sleep.
How could you!
You have to pay your utility bill, partner
You know how difficult it is to shave in the dark.
What have you done with Nicholas?
What have I done with Nicholas?
He can't hear you now, pal.
Oh, come on what know what you is dead. heya
You going to do something with that faulty memory of yours. Pal
Might make life a little bit easier.
by the way, I just loved them no chilly myself
That one on the refrigerator just kills me.
Where is your hospitality, partner?
If some had walked in, he might get the wrong idea.
Who are you?
Oh hell, look like you got
some explaining to do, partner.
I know who you are.
You going some where, Mr. Reznik?
Yeah, Mrs.shrike, I'm moving.
I didn't receive notice.
Your lease requires you
to get 30 days notice in writing.
It wasn't planned,
something came up.
You can keep my security deposite.
I won't be needing it anyway.
Really? Mr. Reznik.
You used to be such a good tenant.
I just don't understand it.
Oh, isn't that pretty?
Would you care to sell it?
No, it was my mother's.
I made all arrangements. Don't move my things.
A truck will be coming by this afternoon.
You just want to get away...
If you are going to give it away...
Mrs. Shrike, If you'll excuse me.
I like to report a hit-and-run.
Some one will record your statement.
Later, right now I just want to sleep.
Just want to sleep.