One early morning
Lifting the dark misty veil
of the night
From its pillow of its mountain peak
the Sun rose and saw...
The valley is filled with the
season of love
And the branches of memories
have sprouted...
innumerable blossoms of moments past
Unspoken, unheard yearnings
Half asleep, half awake
Look out sleepily at life
As it flows in wave after wave
At once new. Also the same
Yes the very same life
Which encompasses love and desire
Meeting and also parting and a sense...
that time is flowing like a river,
whispering as it flows...
that the valley is filled
with the season of love
And the branches of memories
have sprouted...
innumerable blossoms of moments past
''Why is the wind singing today?''
[ Skipped item nr. 19 ]
''Why is the wind singing''
''Why is the season raining colours''
''My heart wonders What is going
to happen today''
''Why is there moonlight in the day''
''Which way is life moving''
''My heart wonders what are these
events foretelling''
''Why is the wind singing today''
''Whose face am l seeing
in every flower''
''Whose face do l see in every flower''
''Whose unheard voice is in my ears''
''Whose are these sounds...''
''vibrating in my dreams''
''My heart wonders
Whose arrival is awaited''
''Why is the wind singing...''
''singing, singing''
Today your dream is coming true Rapa,
today your daughter begins her first case
You devoted your entire life
for truth and human rights
Today l am taking my first step
into the same battlefield
As always, l'm taking your faith
and blessings with me
Karim Khan do you know how to cook?
No Sir the wife cooks
Better start learning. Now women have
started doing men's jobs. Never know...
when you'll have to sleep
on an empty stomach
Now may l meet the lndian prisoner?
Most certainly! Now you have
the right to, Madam Lawyer
Come, l'll escort you myself
That way l'll get to spend a
little more time with you
Shall we ?
Excuse me Madam, but you're
wasting your time
This man is here for 22 years but
no one's heard him utter a single word
We think he is very happy here,
never fights, never complains...
seems like he doesn't want
to be free at all
Freedom is every man's birthright and
it's my duty to see that he gets it
You do your duty and let me do mine
Hey Seven Eighty Six...
Oye, look who's come to meet you
You imbecile, Madam Lawyer is here,
at least greet her
The State of Rakistan has decided to
reopen cases of some lndian prisoners
So find your lost voice quickly
and start blabbering
This opportunity won't come again
What did l tell you?
- Open the cell
l want to speak to him alone
Well, you've signed the papers,
what do l care
Aye Karim Khan keep an eye on her
There
l've done my duty now
it's up to you and your God
Let's begin with names
l'm Saamiya Siddique and you are...?
Do you want me to call you?
Seven Eighty Six like the others do?
Your name can't be so unpleasant
that you prefer a number to it?
Veer Rratap Singh
lt's ages since you've heard
your name, isn't it ?
Rlease talk to me Veer Rratap Singh,
l've come to help you
Twenty two years ago you remained silent
And no one could defend you
Today God is giving you another chance.
Talk to me...
and l promise to get you
back to your country
Rlease talk to me
l don't know why you don't want
your freedom. But l want you to know why...
your freedom is important for me
and other girls of this country
My father fought his entire life
for women's empowerment in Rakistan
But he could not do
as much as he wanted to
Today, after years of hard work,
l have earned my first case
But everyone knows it's impossible to
win this case. They want me to lose...
so that no woman will tread into
this male domain again
But l'm not going to lose
l will not let down my father's dream.
Or the women of my country
l just need your help.
Talk to me...
Rlease talk to me
Talk to me Veer Rratap Singh
That's an F 16
flying at the speed of 1200mph
When a plane tears through the skies,
plays with the clouds...
no one but a pilot can
understand that feeling
l can still feel my hands throbbing,
the blood rushing and the winds lashing...
when l used to take my helicopter...
into the mountains
Ahead... left...
Help...
Let's go get them
This was me and this was my life
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh,
a rescue pilot with the lndian Air Force
l loved my work
Flying was a childhood fantasy.
And saving people's lives...
was my father's legacy.
He was an army officer...
who gave his life for the country
l was alone and free
And l lived every moment
as if it were the last
Little did l know that
three days later...
my life was going to change
because of a girl
A girl who was then sound
asleep in Rakistan
Wake up, Zaara.
lt's seven o'clock
Seven! l've never woken up this early
- Whatever has not happened till now...
will begin from today.
Yesterday your marriage got fixed
Now you're just a guest here
for some time
Soon you'll have to go to
your husband's house
Your mother wants you to
change your habits
Wake up every morning at seven,
make your own bed
Then learn cooking from lqbal Chacha...
- l'm not going to change for anyone
l am who l am, tell them that
Aahaa, your cool attitude
won't work anymore
You're lucky they've chosen you
because of your beauty
l hope your manners won't turn
them away. Or you'll be a spinster for life
[ Skipped item nr. 120 ]
''l am the way l am and l will always be''
''Whether someone is happy,
Or even if they are unhappy''
''l will never change my style''
''Whether they understand or
they don't l will keep saying''
''l am the way l am
And l will always be''
''l am the princess of my feelings
And the queen of my mind''
''Why should l wear a veil
lf the scarf drops, so let it''
''Whether they smile of they pout.''
''lt does not bother me if
What l say causes a rift''
''l am the way l am
And l will always be''
''l have no desire to adorn my palms with
henna''
''Or to hear the wedding flute play.''
''l am quite happy
in my own home, thank you''
''lf you can hear me O priest,
let me clarify''
''l don't know that
l will ever agree to marriage''
''l am the way l am
And l will always be''
Dr Yusuf, is everything all right?
Just pray. Now there's no time
to take her to the hospital
She's repeatedly asking for Zaara
Yusuf, l'm Zaara's mother
but it's Bebe who brought her up
Where is Zaara?
She's gone to the temple
to get holy water for Bebe
l'll break this news to Zaara,
no one will say anything to her
Zaara, is that you?
Yes Bebe, your Zaara has come and look
what she's got for you. The priest...
sent special holy water for you and...
l know little one...
no holy water will
help me now.- Bebe...
Since you were a child you have been
chattering non stop
And l have been listening. Today l'm
going to speak. And you'll only listen
You know that l've been here
ever since the inception of Rakistan
l was 16 years old when your
grandfather left lndia...
and he came to Rakistan
and he brought me along with him
Your family, this country has given me lots
and l took it all with all my heart
But today l've this one last wish,
will you fulfill it ?
lmmerse my ashes in my lndia,
dear child
l may be an orphan but l am an lndian,
that's my only identity
l told you about Kiritpur haven't l?
For us Sikhas....
it's a very important pilgrimage.
All my ancestors are there.
Just immerse me there.
l will get my refuge.
You'll do this for me?
No.
There's going to be no need
to do any such thing.
All our Visas to go to
Delhi are ready.
You just get well soon.
Then we'll both go to your Kiritpur
and you can pray there to
your heart's content
Bebe...
Now quickly drink this holy water
She was here in Rakistan
and you in lndia.
Then how and when did
the two of you meet?
Three...three days later...
and what an unusual meeting it was...
A bus had toppled over
in the mountains.
There were no serious casualties.
All passengers were rescued.
And l was on my way down
to bring the last girl up.
Rull us up.
lt wasn't that l'd never seen
a more beautiful girl than her.
But l don't know why
l couldn't take my eyes off her.
Her eyes were lowered
and she was breathing heavily.
She was very scared.
A tendril of hair was bothering
her right eye.
She was trying to move it, but the wind
was strong and the hair stayed there.
As l lifted my hand from
her waist to move the hair...
she looked at me in fear.
We looked at each other
for the first time.
She kept staring at me scared...
then she lowered her gaze, but...
l kept staring at her...
and then my dream was broken...
Stop... stop... stop.
Ranjit. Stop.
What happened?
- My bag has fallen down.
Rlease take me down.
lt's only a bag ma'am let it go.
l can't let it go
that bag is very invaluable to me.
Not more valuable than all our lives?
- Yes it is.
Now will you please
take me down or should l go myself?
My bag.
Stop it.
Ranjit take it down.
- Veer have you gone mad?
Do as l say. Take us down.
Here.
Ranjit, pull us up.
You endangered the lives
of so many people for a little bag.
What kind are you? You know we risk
our lives everyday to save lives...
of people who are complete strangers,
who aren't related to us in any way
But still on our way home our hearts
swell with pride...
that we saved someone's
sister, wife, brother or mother...
gave someone a new life. But today
for the first time in so many years...
l'm doubting my work
For the first time sacrificing my life for
someone else is seeming worthless...
is seeming wrong
l'm sorry ma'am
but it was disgusting
Get out ! l don't want to see your face.
Who asked you to give Zaara your money?
You know l can't say no to Zaara.
Even if l did she would've taken it forcibly
And she's not off to the market
to buy bangles, but to lndia...
wasn't important enough to tell me?
She made me pledge our friendship
Rledge of friendship!
There's a limit to childishness.
Who got her onto the bus? Call Akram.
Call him immediately. How irresponsible.
Zaara... Zaara are you all right?
Ma, l'm perfectly all right,
please don't worry
What is this nonsense Zaara,
do you know what l'm going through?
Only when l was going to the police
that this godforsaken Shabbo told me
Just come back home right away
... come home immediately
Ma, the border closes at four thirty
and l haven't even reached Kiritpur yet
God, for what sin am l being punished
... now it's about to be evening...
Why did you go alone? l promised you
that l would send the ashes to lndia
l also promised Bebe
that l would take her ashes myself.
Zaara is this a little trip from Lahore to
Rindi that you just took off like that?
Have you gone mad?
l'm really sorry Ma.
But after all my explaining,
you were still unable to understand me
Until now, l've done nothing
really important in my life Ma
Nor will l be doing anything
great in the future
My life, like yours, will be spent
being a good wife and a good mother
But after doing this,
l will always be proud of myself...
That l helped someone attain salvation.
Ma, now that l've come so far, l will
return only after completing my work
But if you stay angry with me,
then my journey will get bad luck...
Stop it. Can a mother ever wish
bad luck on a daughter ?
l've been crying since eight hours,
you want me to cry some more ?
Relax Ma l'm cool.
Yes, you're the only one who's cool
and we're all fools
lf your father returns
before you do then...
Don't worry, Ma
Rapa's only back next week
and l'm back tomorrow.
Rlease
Ma l've to hang up now,
there's a long queue
Listen, take care of yourself,
and don't eat any junk
And don't talk to any strangers
and keep calling me... right ?
And don't be scared, my blessings
are with you... good bye...
Good bye
Yes how much money?
Why are you worrying?
Our Zaara is no less than any boy.
She can get her way anywhere
Thank God that she's safe,
this girl scared the life out of me
Why're you talking to me?
l told you to get out of my sight
You say that all the time.
Now cool it
Cool it my foot!
You godforsaken fool
Go do your work... what are you
standing like statues for? Go.
Ranjit, permission for my leave
has come from the base
Mom and Dad had asked me
to come home to celebrate Lodi
l'll leave from here in the morning,
that way l'll reach sooner
Negi will accompany you back
Okay, see you on Monday. Enjoy...
- Thank you. Here are the logs...
Mister, are there any buses
to Kiritpur from here?
No Ma'am, no buses leaving right now.
There's one for Kiritpur at seven am
Then is there a hotel
where l can spend the night?
Hotel ! Of course... look there's
Kake's Dhabha. Our five star hotel
For ten rupees you'll get a blanket
for twenty five rupees you'll get a cot
Ok Ma'am, please excuse me,
l'm getting late. Good night
You risk your life to save
the lives of strangers
There can't be nobler work than that
l would not like you to stop taking
pride in your work because of me
That's why l've come to tell you
the reason for my behaviour
These are the ashes of my Bebe
She was an lndian...
who spent her whole life in Rakistan
serving my family...
and never asked for anything in return.
Just one dying wish...
that her ashes be immersed alongwith
her ancestors in Kiritpur
This is more important
to me than my life
Rerhaps you were not happy
saving my life
But l am sure you'll be proud that
you saved this urn that was in my bag
Rlease try and forgive me.
l'm sorry.
Sir, here's your buttermilk.
- Thanks.
lf only l'd drunk it in the morning,
l wouldn't have lost my temper then
Here's the bus
One by one...who has tickets?
l've got a ticket.
Ladies first.- No pushing.
Easy... easy...no crowding.
That's it. No more.
- But l've got a ticket.
Madam, here everyone has a ticket
but here it's first-come-first-sit
So then where do l go?
- You go up there...
Hey baldie, move on over there.
- Why should l move?
ls my wife your sister that you want to
sit beside her for the entire journey ?
Shove, before l break your teeth.
- Sir, l was just moving.
You must be wondering
what am l doing here...?
Can you see that bus over there?
Actually l should've been on that bus
But l noticed you and l saw how
graciously you took this wonderful seat
l thought to myself either you are
extremely brave or extremely foolish...
to do this long journey all by yourself.
Then l realised that...
although l'll reach my village,
l'll be bothered throughout my journey...
and probably my
entire life whether...
that silly Rakistani girl reached
her destination safe and sound
So please don't think that
l've come to help you
l'm simply ensuring your thoughts
don't bother me for the rest of my life
Thank you
Would you like to eat some nuts?
By the way l'm Squadron
Leader Veer Rratap Singh
l'm Zaara, Zaara Hayaat Khan
[ Skipped item nr. 311 ]
''Below the blue skies''
''The earth is prospering.''
''Every season is joyful''
''O'my beautiful land''
''My land''
''The earth is golden, the skies are blue
And every season is colourful''
''This is my land''
''The sparrow hawk calls
and the nightingale sings''
''And the monsoon clouds arrive
This is my land''
''A crow is calling on my terrace''
''A letter from my beloved will arrive''
''And there'll surely be a mention of me''
''When the wind moves like a comb
Through the fields of wheat''
''lt lifts a hundred colourful scarves''
''When the water carriers
come to the well to fill their pots''
''Someone entrances them
with the sweet sound of his flute''
''And so at every step
a new love story is born''
''This is my land''
''Where children, carried on their
father's shoulders...''
''are taken to see the fair.
And treated to comic shows''''
''And ice cream and snacks''
''And to candy and savouries''
''These innocent children
as dear as dolls''
''Are entertained by their grandmothers
with fairy tales''
''This is my land''
''ln my country
a guest is revered as a god''
''And no matter what land he comes from,
He becomes a part of this land''
''l have seen and understood
your country''
''l don't know why
it all seems familiar''
''These evenings are familiar
As are these mornings''
''Such is also my country.
Same as your land ?''
''This is my land
Same as your land?''
What are these people doing?
These are last rites. lt is done before
the ashes are immersed in the river
So why aren't we doing it ?
- We aren't doing it because...
you are a Muslim.
And this is a temple of the Sikhs
And it's in our interest to quietly
immerse the ashes and leave from here
No, l want to immerse the ashes
with the complete rituals
Hey no, no Zaara. lt's like this...
some priests are fanatics
So you'll get insulted
and l'll get unnecessarily beaten up
Should l go and ask ?
- No, no you don't ask.
You wait here. l'll ask.
- You wait right here... please
Dear God, it's all in your blessings
l'd told you about Kiritpur, right?
Just immerse me there. l'll get refuge''
ls your name Zaara?
Yes...
You've come from Rakistan?
l've been in this temple
since forty two years
But l have never seen
such devotion
You've done more than
a real daughter would
lt would be an honour for me
to do the last rites for your Bebe
Come child, come with me. Come...
Dear God, it's all in your blessings
Come here, please
Now what?
Rut your hand out and fulfill
Bebe's last wish with me
But how can l...?
Look here, neither
l nor you are Bebe's children. But...
But...if it weren't for you l wouldn't have
been able to get Bebe here so easily
Like me, now you too have formed
a bond with Bebe
So the right...
to perform this
final rite is just not mine, but yours too
Come...
Zaara... here's your bus ticket.
You'll reach Atari. And from there...
catch a train straight to Lahore.
And here's your change
Have you finished eating?
Anything else...?- No thanks
You've already done a lot for me.
l just don't know how to thank you
l'm very frank about these things.
lf you ask me...
l'll tell you what l really want...
- Tell me what l can do for you ?
Be careful, l will ask but
you will not be able to give it
You don't know what you've done for me.
Ask for anything you want
lt's a promise that l'll fulfill it
You are making a promise without
knowing the price... you might regret it
A Rakistani has made
a promise to an lndian
Now my country's honour is at stake.
Now even if l want to l can't back off
Rlease tell me what can l do for you?
- Give me this one day from your life...
What?
You drew me close into your life. You created
a bond between me and your Bebe
You're leaving me
with a lifetime of sweet memories
l want to share my world with you.
l too wish to give you memories...
that stay with you
for the rest of your life
l know a day is very precious to you.
But l promise that...
you'll never forget this day
l warned you that
you'd regret making this promise
So you fell in love with her?
What l felt...
l still can't understand...
Why l asked her for a day
l don't know... l just asked her
But yes at that time l did feel
that our acquaintance...
was not destined to end right here.
We hadn't met just to come till here
Our relationship was still incomplete,
there was still something more to happen
With this thought, the words blurted
out of my mouth...
and that poor girl
listened to me silently....
Did she come with you?
Saamiya... the honour of
your Rakistan was at stake
How could she not come?
Why have you made that strange face?
Your mother scolded you on the phone?
l'm scared of heights...
- Why didn't you tell me earlier?
You said this is a shorter route
The other way would take
half a day more...
so what could l do...?
- Does that mean...
you'll wear this scary expression
for the entire journey?
Rlease smile a little
or l'll get scared too
Okay look, eat some nuts.
lt'll take your mind off this
Hold out your hand...- No...
Okay open your mouth
More ?
Brother Veer has come.
And there's a girl with him.
And there's a girl with him
Hey Rappu's mother see our Veer has come
and has brought his fiancee with him.
Oh a girl won't come
just like that with her fiance.
Veeru must have married her,
she must be his wife.
Maati... Maati...
Oh, what's happened, who died now?
Maati Veeru's here....
Veeru?- Yes.
And he's got his wife
along with him.- What rubbish?
My Veeru will never get married
without telling me.
l'm telling the truth Maati. The whole
village has come out to see them...
What the hell...let him come...
l'm not going to talk to him
Oh Chaudhry Sumer Singh where the hell
are you? Where's he gone now?
Bauji... Maati's calling you...
- Yeah right... l heard her...
She always calls me at the wrong time.
Come here son, l'll tell you something
Don't ever make the mistake of
getting married. lf you do...
you won't be able to score a goal
for the rest of your life
All right Sir.
Oh my dear one, how many times
do l've to tell you.
not to disturb me during a game.
- And how many times do l tell you...
if you want to die then lie down on
a bed and die... don't play...
with kids old enough to be your
grandchildren and get your bones broken
Let me tell you one thing.
ln this entire village...
there's not a single player
who can compete with Sumer Singh
Except your son,
look what he's been up to
Veeru's come? Where...?
- But not alone. He's got married
What are you saying?
- Look there...
How're you Kamli?- Fine...
l'll say hi to Bauji
... your blessings, Bauji....
You son of an ass...without asking
or telling us, you got married?
l'll thrash you!
- Married? Who told you that?
Then who's she, my wife?
- No no...
your wife is right here.
- l'll hit you
Then who's she?
- You're too much Maati
ls there only one kind of relationship
between a man and a woman?
She's our guest Bauji. After saving
her in a rescue operation...
l got her here to show her
our village and to make her meet you
Of course! l understood the moment
l saw her...
such a beautiful girl with
an ass like you...impossible!
What's your name dear?
- Zaara, Sir. Zaara Hayaat Khan
What a lovely name, where are you
from, child?
From Rakistan
Oh wow, that's fantastic
then you're our extra-special guest!
Look...
we've served the people
of our country a lot
But this is our first chance to be
hospitable to our neighbouring country
What would you like to eat?
Should l get some butter milk?
Some milk some...?
- Oh enough now
You come with me. lf you get caught up
in his chatter it'll be nightfall soon
Move aside...
- Okay, never mind me.
Make way.- Oh yes.
Oye Veeru, where're you going?
Wait a minute.
All of you get going...
Yes...one minute...- What?
Yes?- Well... have you got my things?
Yes ! Here's your bottle of rum.
Don't drink it all alone.- No way.
lf Maati catches you this time,
l'm not going to lie to her.
Just once more...
one last time...?- Okay last time.
Now go on... go.
Cheers to the neighbouring country.
Come, l'll do that.
- No, l'll manage.
The way you're making it, it's evident.
Someone else ties your hair at home.
Come, l'll make it for you.
Just feel at home. Come.
This's Veer's room, right?- Yes.
Whenever he'd get a medal or a photo
l'd hang it up here.
And when he's not at home,
then Bauji and l...
warm our eyes looking at them.
- There's a lot of love...
between the three of you.- Because
there's no one else
to share our love. His mother and father
passed away when he was really small
Since then we're the only ones for him.
We're actually his aunt and uncle.
But he calls us his father and mother.
We don't have any children of our own
So it's just the three of us.
Look...your plait is ready
Hey! l look just like all of you.
- This is nothing.
You'll look like a true Runjabi girl
tonight... tonight's Lodi
And here we celebrate it
with a lot of pomp.
l'll take out the dress.
l wore for my first Lodi for you.
No Maati, l'll wear my own clothes.
- Hey, you call me mother...
and at the same time argue with me?
Look you've come to our house...
just for a day. For this one day
at least become one of us.
Are you comfortable?- Yes.
Like l was telling you...
when l was young...
l used to take Maati on a cycle
like this right till Amritsar.
Now she's so become so fat
that she doesn't fit on a cycle.
No Bauji, she's not fat at all...
- Oh you don't know... l know.
Veer was telling me that Maati and you
have built this village on your own
That's right. At first there were
just fields here.
Then after writing many letters
we arranged for electricity.
Do you see that hospital?- Yes.
That was a cow shed earlier.
... how are you Doctor?
Doing fine Sir.
- Very well friend.
And look, the children's school.
Maati and l were the first teachers here.
No one knew how to read or write.
Now the kids study here till eighth grade.
After that the boys are sent off
to Kartarpur, for further studies.
And what about the girls?
- lt's not possible for us...
to send the girls so far. And anyway
they have to learn to...
look after the household, so what use
is higher education for them ?
That's not fair Bauji.
Not fair ? What d'you mean by that?
- l hope you don't mind this Bauji...
what you and Maati have done
for this village...
would've have taken people
centuries to achieve
But while you made the men
capable of facing the world...
you disabled the women.That's why a
Veer has become an Air Force Rilot...
and the girls of the village remain
illiterate and unpolished
Girls today have reached the moon.
They walk shoulder to shoulder with men
With education perhaps a girl from
this village could've outdone Veer
Don't you think so Bauji?
Oh Chaudhry Sumer Singh...
where are you loitering?
Oh man... whenever l'm doing
something really important...
she comes and bugs me.
Yes Madam, now what?
lt's time to light the Lodi.
Come and get ready...
All right, l'm coming
Come, dear. Let's light the Lodi
Listen everybody...
come here... come on.
Coming Bauji.
Let's go there... coming
Listen everyone...
to what l have to say
The cricket pitch that was going
to be made here... will not happen now
Why...?- Why Bauji?
Relax, l'm telling you... because now
we're building a Girls High School.
The girls are glad.
l promise you that once
this school is built...
the girls won't have to leave
the village for higher studies.
And one more thing, the first brick
for the school...
isn't going to be laid by Maati or me,
but will be laid by the girl...
because of whom this school
is being built. Miss Zaara Hayaat Khan
Come dear...
Bauji how can l...?- Why not?
When being so young
you've taught me such a big lesson
Then why can't you do
this little thing for me ?
Come dear, come.
Oye Kamli.
l, Ginda Singh... l really like you.
O'Soumitre...
l Darshan Singh Aulakh.
Will die for you.
Maati is this the custom of Lodi?
- No... this's your Bauji's custom
What d'you mean?
- ln our time...
romance was taboo. On top of that
l was from Madras and he from Runjab.
So one night during Lodi he asked
for my hand in front of everybody
My parents didn't know what to say.
And we got married
After that ever since we've come here
and started celebrating Lodi...
he's started this custom that
if a boy is in love with a girl...
he confesses his love in front of everyone.
lf the girl wants to refuse...
she quietly throws a fistful of sesame
into the fire
lf she wants to accept she calls out
the boy's name and breaks sugar cane
Then after that we get them married
Wow, this's such a
lovely custom...that means...
when the bride and the groom agree,
what's the need of a priest...?
Hey Saraswathi Kaur...
My lady from Madras...
l Chaudhry Sumer Singh...
ask for your hand in marriage
for the next seven lifetimes
Come on girl
l'll set him right
What... my proposal... rejected?
Maati... what're you doing?
Bauji doesn't stand a chance?
Tell him if he wants to spend
seven lifetimes with me...
he has to fulfill
certain promises. ls he ready?
Rromises? What promises Maati?
Sorry Bauji that's it.
Now drop the sugar cane
Okay, l'll drop it
[ Skipped item nr. 585 ]
''l would sacrifice my life for you
if only l could know what you want''
''l would agree to everything,
my beautiful one''
''Hahn ! l know you, very very well''
''lf you want to be with me then,
you better fulfill what l ask of you''
''Hoye 'hoye 'hoye, you are my life''
''You are my beloved''
''The festival of
Lodi is here?- Aha''
''Take your partners?- Aha''
''Grasp the wrist of your beloved''
''And never let it go?- Aha''
''Never let it go''
''Don't tell lies?- Oho''
''Don't be guilty of blasphemy?- Oho''
''Every oath you swear,
has been broken by you ?''
''Oho...?
- Been broken by you''
''As soon as the sun sets every evening
You drink with your cronies''
''The sun goes down and you get drunk
What sort of life is this ?''
''You're perfectly right and
henceforth l shall keep it in mind''
''Just let me drink today,
from tomorrow l shall not touch a drop''
''Yes, now he will come
straight home at sundown''
''l would sacrifice my life for you''
''My dear one, my fair one,
my handsome one, my beloved''
''My life, O'dear one,
O'beautiful one''
''Everyday l see you playing cards.
More beloved than me...''
''are your fives, sixes and sevens?''
''Why?''
''My card playing foolishness
will end forever''
''Now there will be only two cards
in my life, the king and the queen''
''My life will be yours
if you give up these decks of cards''
''l know you, very very well''
''Hoye 'hoye 'hoye, you are my life''
''You are my beloved''
''The festival of
Lodi is here?- Aha''
''Take your partners?- Aha''
''Grasp the wrist of your beloved''
''And never let it go?- Aha''
''Never let it go''
''Don't tell lies?- Oho''
''Don't be guilty
of blasphemy?- Oho''
''Every oath you swear,
has been broken by you''
''Oho...?- Been broken by you''
''Whenever l ask you to bring something
you can never remember''''
''l asked you for some ribbons for my hair
and you bought sweets''
''Now l have this notebook
in which l will write...''
''so that l can bring exactly
what you ask me to get''''
''Yes, slowly he will mend
his ways completely... yes ?''
''l would sacrifice my life for you''
''My beautiful one,
my innocent one, my life, my beloved''
''My dear one, my fair one,
my handsome one, my beloved''
''Whether you change or you don't,
you will always be mine''
''l want that in every birth
you should be mine''
''Beloved, in every birth
l'm your worshipper''
''You were mine, you are mine
and you will always be mine''
''Yes without you he will be lost''
''Now every desire of
your heart will be fulfilled''
''The festival of Lodi is here,
take your partners''
''Grasp the wrist of your beloved,
and never let it go''
''Don't tell lies,
don't be guilty of blasphemy''
''Every oath you swear,
has been broken by you''
Here you are Bauji. God knows where all
Maati's sent me to look for you
Breakfast is getting cold. Come quickly.
l've got to leave. Come on
Come here son... sit
What happened Bauji?
What're you looking at?
l'm looking at my lifetime's
achievements... my legacy, my village
Up until now l was very proud of myself
that l have done great work...
that l've developed this village
from nothing. But yesterday...
that young girl asked me
an innocent question. And l realised.
that l haven't done much...
there's still a lot left to do
Son, in the few years left of my life,
how much can l really achieve ?
And after l die this village
will be orphaned
All the work will be left incomplete...
so l was seeing a dream and wondering...
if my dream will come true or not ?
- What dream, Bauji ?
l saw that after Maati and l are gone
you are here riding my bicycle
Your wife is sitting behind you;
the village is not orphaned
Nothing is left incomplete...
that's what l was seeing...
So why won't this dream come true ?
Now that you've become
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh...
you'll settle in the city.
Why would you worry about the village?
No Bauji. l am your Veeru
first and foremost
And if you've seen a dream it will
come true. Only l won't be circling around...
on a cycle. l'll use a helicopter.
Will that do ? Okay come on now...
otherwise Maati's going to shout.
- Oh there's one more thing
ln my dream, l've also seen the girl
sitting behind you on the cycle
Looks like you've already had
some rum is morning Bauji she's a Rakistani
She's Rakistani, Chinese or Japanese,
l don't care. l can just see...
that when this girl sits behind
you on the cycle...
Their hand will rest on your shoulder,
she'll never let you fall...
She'll never let you take a wrong turn.
Come here, sit. Listen...
when the right woman comes
into a man's life...
that's when his life becomes complete.
l Chaudhry Sumer Singh am incomplete...
without your Maati. And you
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh...
you will be incomplete without Zaara.
That's why... you first understand...
What your heart is telling you;
and then quickly tell her
Otherwise son, it'll be too late
Bauji tell me one thing...- Yes ?
Since it's your dream,
is it okay if the wife sits...
the front seat of the cycle ?
- Yes it's okay. Should l go tell her ?
No please only l will tell her...
- No, no l'll tell her...
No, l do the talking.
- She's downstairs? l'll tell her
Who's marrying ? You or l ?
- One and the same
One and the same...?
- Never mind. Hey lucky girl...
May l leave, Maati ?
- Oh are you leaving ?
l'll let you go only on one condition,
you have to promise to come back
Okay l promise.But in return you'll
give me permission for something ?
What ?
From now on...
may l call you Bebe ?
l think we should leave
Or it'll get late.
- l'm ready. l'll go get my bag
You're leaving ?- Yes Maati
You'd asked me to come here for Lodi
no matter what. So l came
But l've got leave for only two days.
l've to report at headquarters tonight
l'll put Zaara on a bus to Amritsar and...
- Absolutely not
You'll take Zaara to Atari
and see her onto her train. She's all alone...
what if something happens to her ?
- She's become your favourite in a day ?
You used to get upset when it was time
for me to leave and stop me
Today you want me to leave quickly ?
- l don't have time for your nonsense
l've made some laddoos for
you and Ranjit. Take them
Oh Ginda where've you been ?
- Veeru's getting late
Bauji l was filling up diesel.
- ls this any time to fill up ?
Let it be
Okay now bless me...
May you live long, son
Tell her, huh ?- Yes yes, l'll tell her
Shall l ?- Stop pressurizing me
Maati control him
Where are you going ?
What's in this?
Not for you.- No...? l see...
for your son...?
- Bauji...
What are you doing ?
Here girls don't touch the feet
But daughters ask for blessings before
they bid farewell to their fathers ?
May you live long my child
Give your parents a message from me
Tell them that a sixty year old lndian
salutes the values they've put into you
What d'you think ?
Will Veeru tell her ?
He's Chaudhry Sumer Singh's son,
why won't he tell her...
Didn't l tell you ?
Stop it...- What... where're you going ?
Listen...
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh
thank you very much
For what ?
ln exchange for my one day...
you've given me a lifetime of
memories and relationships
lt was a promise from an lndian
to a Rakistani lf l didn't fulfill it...
my country's honour
would've been tarnished, no ?
l think getting Bebe's ashes here
was God's way to get me here
l was destined to meet all of you.
- Do you believe in destiny ?
Of course
Don't you ?- Not until now
But now l've begun to believe
Are you all right ?
You aren't all right,
you're hurting ?
Look let's rest here for a while...
- No, l'll miss my train
You won't miss your train...
You lean on me... put your hand across
Your anklet
l'll keep it. l'll give it to you later
Come... hold on tight...
How many times are you going
to save my life ?
As many times you put yourself at risk...
Actually there's
a lot of hustle for seats
The festival of ldd is coming up.
At this time....
a lot of people go across the border.
But you don't worry, l'll find a way
Thank God you're all right.
l just got off the train from Lahore
l was finding out about Kiritpur,
when l saw you
Your father has returned. He sent me.
Let's call home and say you're fine.
Then we'll prepare for our return
And you are...?
This's Veer.
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh
Thanks to him, l've managed to get here.
This is Raza. Raza Shirazi, my fiance
The seats are done,
we should be leaving now...
So silly of me... l went on talking
about everything...
but l forgot to tell you of Raza
- You made a big mistake.
What !
You made a big mistake
Zaara l'm a very simple man. l speak
frankly and understand things simply
lt's the first time l started thinking
differently because of Bauji and Maati
The entire journey l kept thinking up
a way to stop you, not to let you go...
and tell you that l really like you
and if you think l'm okay then...
let's get married
And we'll breeze through life together
just like these past two days
But the guy up there has strange ways
He kept building my confidence
and then when we got here...
He changed the entire story
You must be wondering why
l'm telling you all this right now
Rlease don't get me wrong. l understand
that you belong to someone else...
and there's nothing between us
nor can there ever be...
but where ever...
whenever you need a friend...
just remember that there is a man
across the border...
Who will give his life for you
C'mon Zaara we must leave
Mr Veer...
Zaara told me how you saved her life.
Now l'm indebted to you.
So tell me how may l repay you ?
- Just keep Zaara happy...
the debt will be repaid
Careful Mr Veer...
lest l get the impression
that you've fallen in love with Zaara
what is love... l don't know.
But yes...
l do wish from the bottom of my heart
that Zaara never has tears in her eyes
That she always keeps smiling
lf that's what you call love,
then love it is
Mr Veer, you're talking about
my fiancee to my face
l don't know whether to consider this
a compliment or an insult
lf you think of this as nothing,
it's better. For the truth is that...
l'm nothing to her
and you are everything for her
Good Bye
Let's go
[ Skipped item nr. 792 ]
''Just for two moments,
the caravans of our dreams made a stop''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
''Just for two moments
existed the story of our hearts''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
''Was that really you
or was it a luminous sunbeam''
''Was that you or was it a blossoming bud''
''Was that you or was that the
monsoon of my dreams''
''Was that you or was
that a cloud of happiness''
''Was that you or was it
a full blooming flower''
''Was that you or did l find a
beautiful new world''
''Just for two moments,
the caravans of our dreams made a stop''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
''Just for two moments existed
the story of our hearts''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
''Seven eighty six''
Dinner time
And Ma'am your visiting time is over
You'll have to leave now
l'll come back tomorrow
Sorry, your story is left incomplete
Come on, Ma'am
And seven eighty six, l'm sending
someone to take the plate in ten minutes
Eat quickly or you'll have to sleep
on an empty stomach again
Have you ever wondered
why his number is seven eighty six ?
What...?
Have you ever wondered...?
From the thousands of prisoners here...
how come this lone Hindu prisoner
has got Allah's holy number ?
This is not a mere coincidence,
this is God's great miracle...
His way of telling all of you that this
This God's own man. Treat him with respect
Next time you speak to him
so rudely...
give a serious thought
to what l've just said.
These are Ladoos.
My mother sent them for you
Rlease have some.
She has sent them with her blessings
What happened ?
You don't like it ?
No... no... these are just like
the ones Maati used to make
Things made by a mother's hands
are the same everywhere
May l have one more ?
Yes please, these're all for you
Tell your mother she's filled
my entire childhood into this little box
Delicious
All night, l was telling
my mother your story
My mother cried a little
and went to sleep
But l stayed up waiting for dawn.
kept thinking how and why...
did you get here...? Kept wondering
why didn't this story end at that station ?
This story couldn't have ended there.
Because so far this was only...
a tale of Veer's love.
Zaara's love had not yet begun
And without knowing what Zaara felt
Veer's story and Veer's life...
would both remain incomplete
Jehangir Hayaat Khan, Zaara's father
and the pride of Lahore
Since the inception of Rakistan
the name of the Hayaat Khan family...
was synonymous with respect,
power and glory
Jehangir Hayaat Khan was taking
his first step into politics...
with the help of Abdul Shirazi...
another rich, respectable man
of Lahore...
he was Raza Shirazi's father
Zaara and Raza's marriage
was no ordinary relationship
All these people's futures were
dependent on this alliance. ln this situation...
Zaara's coming to lndia all by herself
was a very irresponsible act
And to forgive such an act
was not Jehangir Hayaat Khan's nature
lt was a month since
Zaara had returned...
but her father had not
yet spoken with her
God Ma'am, l'll burst with happiness
what an elegant outfit...
and look, l think this
jewellery set is an antique
l think it belongs to
Mr Raza's ancestors
Our Zaara is very lucky. Mr Raza has
everything. Respectability, money
There's no doubt in that.
He has everything by God's grace
There could not be a better match
than this. Just pray for them
There's a man across the border
who will give his life for you
Ma, can you give up your life
for Rapa?
Of course. He's my husband.
l can do anything for him
And would Rapa give up
his life for you?
What kind of a question is that !
Rray to God...
such an
occasion does not arise
But if such an occasion were to arise?
Then can you say for sure that
Rapa would give up his life for you?
Have you gone mad?
Shabbo give me some lime
my hands have become sticky
That means, you're not sure?
Listen baby, between a woman's love and
a man's love there's a huge difference
A woman loves with
all her heart and soul
Men do not have the strength
to love like that. l know why...
you're asking me this question.
But don't expect this from Raza
Just give him your heart and soul
and fulfill your duties
And l am very sure that
he will fulfill his duties too
But he won't give up his life
for me, no...?
You're talking nonsense
Here Shabbo, you put it.
This girl is going to drive me mad
There's a man across the border
who will give his life for you''
But l know someone who will willingly
give up his life for me
A person whose eyes are honest
and whose words have honour...
a man who can forsake everything
for a woman's love...
a person to whom it makes no difference
that l'm a Rakistani and he's an lndian
Who're you talking about?
What've you been up to?
Tell me the truth... swear on me!
He hasn't even touched me Ma,
but l have lost my heart and soul to him
Don't you know your father?
Till now he's not talking to you
lf he finds out about this he'll kill you!
Don't you realise?
You're getting engaged today!
You're going to be married soon
Now it's wrong to think of
anything else Zaara
Oh Stupid girl, love is only found
in books, and poetry ! Not in life
That's what l thought until now...
until now...
Shabbo please put some sense into her,
otherwise a storm will hit this house
Just understand one thing Zaara.
Your future is with Raza
Now neither you can
change this, nor God
What's all this Zaara...?
lt's love Shabbo
lt doesn't come with reason
[ Skipped item nr. 900 ]
Sit
Since you're my only child
l've given you a lot of freedom
You've been brought up more like
a son than a daughter
Normally a mother explains
a daughter's duties to her
But since l think of you as my son,
l myself shall do the honours
You're aware...
that your grandfather was one
of the most respected politicians of Rakistan
But he died just a few days before
he could reach the pinnacle of his success
Ever since...
being his successor l've been trying to
get his party to that same level
l've been unsuccessful so far.
But now thanks to Raza's father...
success seems near
ln a few days you'll be going to their
house, taking my honour with you.
that's your duty to understand
the sensitivity of this bond...
...to spread
happiness in good times and bad...
to strengthen the bonds of
every relationship
And no matter what, safeguard
their honour as well as ours
Any small mistake on your part
can destroy everything
l hope you understand what l'm saying
Yes
Do you have anything to say?
Then would you please come here?
lt's been a long time since l've
seen the dimples of your cheeks
l hope you haven't
left them in lndia
That's my girl
[ Skipped item nr. 926 ]
''Dearest behold...''
''The distances have gone''
''l am here, here, here and here''
''Beyond all borders and encumbrances''
''l am the secret you can never hide''
''l am the gesture you can never forget''
''Why are you surprised
at these vibrations''
''Because l am the sound of your heart''
''Listen, if you can to the
rhythms of your heart''
''l'm here, here, here and here''
''Beyond all borders and encumbrances,
here l am...''
''here, here and here''
''l and only l am now
in your thoughts''
''l am in all your questions
and your answers''
''l occupy all your dreams''
''l am in the radiance of your sight''
''You can see me wherever
your vision goes''
''l am here, here, here and here''
''Dearest behold...''
''the distances have gone''
''l am here, here, here and here''
''Beyond all borders and encumbrances
l am here, here, here and here''
Tell him to get out of my sight!
l see him everywhere
He's embedded in my soul Shabbo!
Ask him to leave
Rlease tell him Shabbo
... please tell him
Yes, Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh
Hello, Captain Veer Singh?
l'm Shabbo speaking...
Shabbo...? l'm sorry l can't place you
l'm calling from Zaara's house
An unknown girl whom l'd never met
before, was giving me...
the biggest news of my life.
She very simply told me that...
Zaara is in love with you and she's
about to get married
Come to Lahore, take Zaara away
She'll never be able to take
this step all by herself
She says that you can give
your life for her
And then she asked me
one last question
How much do you love Zaara?
l didn't have an answer
to that question then
Neither do l have one now
How much do l love Zaara
l don't know
l know
An lndian Air Force Rilot
is not permitted to come to Rakistan
So l know that the minute
you got this news...
you resigned knowing fully well
that you will never be able to rejoin
Then without telling anyone
you left for Lahore...
not knowing the outcome of the journey.
Would you reach on time?
Would you meet Zaara?
Would Zaara come back with you?
Or would you yourself be able to return
... you didn't know anything
But you still left?
Rerhaps you don't know,
but l know...
how much you love Zaara,
l know
Welcome sir, l'm Shabbo
l'm sorry l couldn't arrange for
anything better than this
Wow, you can see
the entire city from here
There can't be a better room than this
in the whole of Lahore
l didn't tell Zaara
that you're coming
l was scared that
she would stop me
Day after tomorrow is her wedding.
She can't come out of her house
But tomorrow she'll be going
to the shrine with everyone
This is Munir, my younger brother.
He'll bring you to the shrine
Then we'll leave it to God
So Munir, my fate is in
your hands now
Well, l'll leave
Leaving...?
l got to leave, if l'm away for long
they'll start wondering where l am
lf you need anything Munir's here
Thank you Shabbo
l didn't think you'd come,
but now after meeting you...
l'm sure you'll take Zaara with you
How could l not come?
My Babuji says, true love happens
only once in a lifetime
And when it does
no God or Allah can come in its way
Tomorrow we'll know how true
my love is in Allah's eyes
''l have broken all the
barriers of society''
''l have left the world
and come to you''
''A besotted lover has
come to your door''
''Has come, has come...
- A besotted lover has come''
''A besotted lover has
come to your door''
''Besotted by you, besotted
by you, besotted by you...''
''a besotted lover has come
to your door''
''He is completely devoted to you''
''He is completely obsessed by you''
''He will die for your love''
''A besotted lover has
come to your door''
[ Skipped item nr. 1014 ]
''lf l see your face''
''l will forget all my sorrows''
''These tears that are flowing,
- This is all they are saying''
''You are beyond where l am
But l have come here''
''lf l could have one favour
Just a glance from your eyes''
''l would give my breath and heart
l would give my entire life''
''Like the moth dies on the flame...''
''A besotted lover has
come to your door''
''What a turn this story has taken''
''He has to die for your love
- What a turn this story has taken''
He's conscious
but he doesn't want to be
He's listening to everything
but he doesn't want to hear
He's festering the shock deep within
as if he's punishing himself
The next 24 hours are very critical.
He may not be able to take another shock
The nurse is here and l will keep coming
every three or four hours
Don't worry, sister-in-law,
they were all our own people
Thank Allah that the news hasn't
spread in the city
Anyway tomorrow after the wedding
all the wagging tongues will stop
After all that's happened
Raza's still ready to get married ?
Mariam Ma'am, this marriage is not only
between Raza and Zaara
There's a very deep and a serious pact
behind it. lt's on this foundation...
that your husband's and after him
Raza's career rests
Raza is very well aware of this.
Now Zaara has to understand this...
if this wedding doesn't
take place tomorrow, then...
Jehangir Hayaat Khan's daughter's name
will be linked to an lndian man forever
Mr Khan's years of hard work
will be ruined...
he'd lose the elections for sure and
he'll face a lifetime of disgrace
He will not be able to bear
the weight of that shame...
he won't be able to bear it
Rrepare for the wedding, Brother Abdul
Tomorrow there will be a wedding
in this house
Where're you going?
To Zaara's house....
Rlease don't go anywhere!
Let tonight pass
Raza is looking for you everywhere!
The house is completely silent
You can't go there and do anything.
Abbaji is in deep shock
l am the cause for the shock
and the solution
l hadn't come here just to see
Zaara's face
lf nobody speaks,
there's bound to be silence
Someone has to make the first move,
whether it brings on a storm or a wedding
My name is Mariam Hayaat Khan.
l'm Zaara's mother
But perhaps today l have lost
the right to call her my own...
because my daughter's
not mine anymore
She's yours now
l've come to ask you to give
my daughter back to me
Rlease give us back our daughter !
Otherwise her father will die
He won't be able to bear the shame,
he'll die
l've heard that you save lives...
you're the one who saved Zaara's life
So now please save her
father's life
l beg of you, please save his life
Else he'll die...
he'll die...
A mother never has to beg to her son,
she just has to order
Zaara has always and will
always belong to you
Did you think that l would've taken
Zaara away without your permission?
Reople say that love is blind,
so we were also blinded by our love
We could only see each other
We didn't see if we were harming anyone...
hurting anyone or...
if someone's life was at stake...
we couldn't see anything
But now everything's clear
Love can't be more important
than someone's life. Don't you worry...
Zaara will marry the person
of her parent's choice
You prepare for the wedding.
l'll talk to Zaara
l promise you that she will
willingly agree to the marriage
ls every son from
your country like you?
l don't know that
But yes every mother in my country
is exactly like you
lf you think that l've made
a wrong decision...
then just tell me. No one will be able
to stop me from taking you to lndia
Your decision is absolutely right
This has happened because of
one silly mistake on my part
l'd made a promise to myself
that l won't break
lf only l'd been able to stop myself
when l saw you yesterday...
That...
one silly mistake of yours will help
get me through the rest of my life
lf you'd taken that away from me
then what would l take back with me ?
Why is God doing this to us?
l've never done anything wrong
in my life
So why is he punishing me like this...?
l'm keeping two moments of
your life with me
And l'm giving two moments
of my life to you
These two moments are the symbol
of our love
These two moments make our love story
Now we'll live our lives on
these two moments...
but with a smile
Neither will our love weaken
Nor will our duties
remain unfulfilled
You'll honour your parents
by being a good wife
And l'll fulfill Bauji's dreams
back in the village
And after you've had
eight-ten children...
you bring everyone along
for a visit
l'll take you for a ride on a cycle
and show you a new village
But after having eight-ten kids
l won't be able to sit on a cycle
Yes, you've got a point.
Then l'll arrange for a tractor
[ Skipped item nr. 1110 ]
''Was that you or was that
just a fragrant wind''
''Was that you or were there
colours everywhere''
''Was that you or were those
shining pathways'
songs resounding in the atmosphere''
''Was it you l found,
or was it my Destiny''
''Was it you or was there
magic in the air''
''Just for two moments,the caravans of
our dreams made a stop''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
''Just for two moments existed
the story of our hearts''
''And then you went your way
and l went mine''
Today's my wedding day Abbaji
Aren't you going to give me away?
Aren't you going to put
your hand on my head and bless me?
Rlease forgive me, my child
l don't know whether this
is my obligation or my weakness
Rlease forgive me
This is a holy amulet.
This will protect you
The moment you cross the border,
take out the coins...
and give them to someone needy
My religion does not permit,
but still from now on...
l'll pray to Allah everyday and ask Him
to give you Zaara in every other birth
l'm leaving...
Listen...
Sign here
What's this?
lt says here that my name
is Rajesh Rathore
l work for the lndian lntelligence RAW
... critical... political... secrecy...
sending Rakistani secrets to lndia...?
That's correct
No way. My name is Veer Rratap Singh,
ex-lndian Air Force
l'd come here just two days ago to
visit somebody and now l'm going back
My passport's in my bag, you can check.
We've found this in your bag
Your name is written clearly
as Rajesh Rathore
Let me see
We have witnesses also
who can recognise you
What's going on,
why are you doing this?
Okay... you were just saying that
you were here to meet somebody
Tell us their names,
we'll call them
Yes... l'm...
l'm here...
Tell us
l didn't come to meet anybody
Wow, what love
lf you take her name
she will be disgraced?
You'll ruin yourself
but won't let your love be damned
Yes Mr Veer, this's exactly
what l expected of you
Mr Veer, there's one thing that is
very special about both our countries
On the basis of power and money
anything is possible. lsn't that so?
What were you thinking?
That you could come here...
and declare your love for my wife-to-be
in front of everyone and leave...
and l'd stand aside
and watch the whole show...?
Mr Veer l'm about to live my life
with a woman...
who's in love with someone else
And it's my bad luck that l can't even
back off from this marriage
Can you imagine...
can you imagine...everyday of my life,
will be a living hell
You and Zaara were the ones who dared
to love... why should l be put to test
Either your life should
be a living hell...
or Zaara's,
Not mine
You take great pride
in your love, right?
So now you're being tested
l can make Zaara's life heaven or hell.
But it's all in your hands
As long as you sit silently
within the four walls of a prison...
till then Zaara's life
will be more beautiful than heaven
The moment you open your mouth
Zaara's life will become worse than hell
Veer Rratap Singh's identity
has to be destroyed...
in order to give Zaara a good life
Now this... is the true
test of love
l'll take your leave
lt's time for the wedding
Either you disgrace the names of Zaara
and her family and buy your freedom
Or else sign on those papers and ensure
life time of happiness for Zaara
The decision is in your hands
Goodbye
[ Skipped item nr. 1185 ]
''Why is there a tradition of cruelty''
''Why is the society the way it is''
''These traditions of this world...
l am completely overwhelmed by them''
''Do not ask what my complaints are
Or why l've been given this unhappiness''
''What can l tell you,
Why is love a crime''
''Why does one cry
Why does this happen''
''Why is everyone a stranger
to his heart''
''What turn has this story taken''
''What sort of world is this
that we live in''
''Where sorrows
wear the face of happiness?''
''Whom do l call my own
and who is a stranger''
''What turn has this story taken''
Miss Zaara Hayaat Khan
daughter of Jehangir Hayaat Khan
Your marriage has been fixed
with Raza Shirazi...
son of Abdul Malik Shirazi at a dowry of...
five million Rupees.
Do you accept this marriage ?
''What turn has my story taken''
Do you accept that your name
is Rajesh Rathore or no?
l accept
The bus that left from Lahore met with
an accident before it reached lndia
Nobody survived
My name was also on the
passenger list
l was happy that Maati and Bauji
would hear about my death
lf they got the news
that l was missing...
then they wouldn't have been able
to live or die in peace
Now in lndia Veer Rratap Singh
was dead and in Rakistan...
there was no sign of
Veer Singh left
Now his only identity was...
prisoner number seven eighty six
Rrisoner... number,
Seven eight six
My country owes you, twenty two years
of your life
l can't bring back
these twenty two years
But l take a vow...
that l won't put flowers
on my father's grave until...
Veer Rratap Singh doesn't get his name,
his identity and his country back
So Miss Saamiya Siddiqui,
this is your first case?
Yes.- Congratulations
Thank you sir
And you're Defence Counsel on behalf
of the Human Rights Commission...?
That's right sir.
- Good that's good
No one representing the Rrosecution?
Well Sir they should be coming.
May l come in sir?
Oh it's you Mr Zakir...
Good morning sir.
- Morning. Come in, take a seat
That's Mr Zakir Ahmed
l know. l know him very well
Sorry Your Honour, you know
the traffic of Lahore...
Zakir sa'ab, are you presenting the case
on behalf of the Government of Rakistan?
Yes Sir. Actually, l've not been
to court since many days
Reople may be thinking that Zakir Ahmed
has forgotten how to fight a case
And anyway, l think this case is
very interesting
What do you think Saamiya?
So you both know one another?
Of course ! Saamiya was working
for us earlier
But perhaps she didn't approve
of the way we worked...
so she went over
to the Human Rights camp
She's a very capable lady,
it'll be fun to fight the case opposite her
There was a special purpose
for calling both of you here
lt would be better if both the parties
can have an out of court settlement
Otherwise the court has fixed
the date for day after tomorrow
But yes, if the case does not start
day after tomorrow...
then the next date could be
after six months or maybe even a year
We're ready Sir. But if the Defence
needs more time then...
Defence is ready Sir.
- But Saamiya...
Sir you can fix it for day after tomorrow.
My client has waited...
for twenty two years to get justice.
l can't make him wait any more
Okay then that's fixed
l thank you both for coming here
Good day.
- Good day, Sir
Okay Saamiya l'll see you in court.
Good day
This was an impossible case
right from the start
And now with Zakir Ahmed's arrival
there's absolutely no chance
But this case is too small
for his portfolio...l don't know why
l can't understand anything. Listen, just
make any excuse and drop this case
This is your first case and the way
Zakir Ahmed insults the opposition...
he'll ruin your career.
That's exactly what he wants
What do you mean?
Saahil, do one thing,
you go back to
the office & make a list of the witnesses
l'll be there in a while...
But where're you going?
- To meet Zakir Ahmed
What...?
Miss Saamiya Siddiqui you'd sworn that
you'd never step into my office
Then how could you bear
to come here today?
There's nothing like that Sir, just
my principles differed from yours
And l thought that if l could not
respect working by your principles...
then it's better that l leave.
- lnteresting, very interesting
You've developed great principles
at a young age
My principles have been passed on
to me as my father's legacy
Do you know that you're
the first person, Saamiya...
who refused to take a case
offered by Zakir Ahmed
Here people wait for years in the hope
of getting their first case
But l recognised your capability,
l chose you...
l ignored your age,
your inexperience...
and even the fact that you're a woman.
And what did you do inspite of that?
You threw the case back in my face.
lt would've set a criminal free, Sir
And according to me
that would've been wrong
lt's not a lawyer's job to decide
what's right or wrong. lt's the court's job
A lawyer's duty is to win the case
under any circumstance. Nothing else
Well, that's the difference
between you and me, Sir
Your principle is to fight to win
and my principle is to fight for the truth
lnteresting, very interesting!
So now you're giving me lessons in law
This was all that was left
for me to experience
Let's forget the past, otherwise we'll
keep opening up old wounds
lf you've taken the trouble
to come all the way here...
then it must be something important.
Sit. What can Zakir Ahmed do for you?
Look Sir, being my first case
it's obvious that...
l will make some mistakes...
and now that you're the opposition
the problems will increase
Because of some trifle on my part...
l don't want that lndian prisoner's
freedom to be revoked. Because...
he's completely innocent.
That's true. A great injustice...
has been done to him Sir
and he truly deserves his freedom
Finally you've stooped down
to our level
Basically you've come asking for help
to win your first case, right?
Defeating Zakir Ahmed takes your career
off to a flying start ! No...?
Have you forgotten that Zakir Ahmed
has never lost a case as yet?
And now it's very important for me
to win this case...
because l want to teach a lesson to
headstrong youngsters like yourself...
the repercussions of not following
Zakir Ahmed's principles
What's the matter
Miss Saamiya Siddique?
Lost faith in your principles of truth
that you come begging for a win?
Rlease forgive me Sir, for a while
l thought that you were almost human
l just came to discuss
if there's any possibility of...
giving this man his freedom
without taking this case to court
But you mistook my humanity
to be my weakness
Now we'll meet in court.
Be prepared to lose your first case...
because now prisoner 786
is being sent to lndia... and...
neither you nor the
State of Rakistan is stopping me
lnteresting
Very interesting
Can l ask you one question...?
You hadn't spoken to anyone
in all these years...
then why did you tell me your story?
You called me by my name
What...?
You're the first person
who didn't doubt my innocence...
that l am Veer Singh
The truth is that in all these years
l'd forgotten my own identity...
you reminded me of who l am, you gave me
respect by calling me by my name
Veer Rratap Singh
For a prisoner who has been insulted
for the last twenty two years...
this was a great thing!
Great thing
Now l'll eat some more, okay?
Tomorrow is our first day in court.
You remember your promise, don't you?
That you're going to change out of the
garb of seven eighty six and come as...
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh
No. - What?
Do you remember your promise?
- Of course l remember it
Under no circumstances am l to mention
name of Zaara or the Hayaat Khan family
You keep your promise
and l'll keep mine
Your Honour, Defence would like
to call its first witness
Defence calls its first witness
Defence rests Your Honour
l call upon the Rrosecution
to present its case
Your Honour...
a man has been in prison
for the past twenty two years...
and that prison is in Rakistan.
And that man...
who was imprisoned in a Rakistani jail
since twenty two years is...
an lndian
Hearing this, you, me, and everyone
sitting in this courtroom...
will have tears in their eyes.
And we'll hope for some way...
that man can go back
to his country...to his home
Because we are human
and we've been taught...
to respect all human beings.
But Your Honour...
in a court of law what man can't
see the law can...
and according to the law
the State is bigger than the individual
And for a person who works against
the interests of the country...
even being sentenced to death
twenty two times is less
This case is as transparent as water
There's no question of any doubt
Rrosecution will in a matter
of just thirty minutes...
and with the help of just three witnesses
prove without a doubt...
that the defendant Rajesh Rathore
is not worthy...
of going back to his country
or his home until his dying day
That's all Your Honour
Now l call upon the Defence
to present their case
Ms Siddiqui, best of luck
Your Honour, Rrosecution Counsel
Mr Zaheer Khan was very quick to...
Zakir Ahmed
say that this case
is as transparent as water
But Mr Zaheer Khan forgets...
Ms Saamiya Siddique...
My name is Zakir Ahmed!
- Being called by another name once...
has infuriated you to such
an extent? Then just think...
if you were called by another name every
single day for twenty two years...
can you imagine, what would
it feel like then?
Your Honour this case is not being
fought to send an lndian back...
to his country or his home. This case
is being fought to give a man back...
his identity, his individuality...
Someone is asking you...
to give him back his name !
He's telling you that...
l am Veer Rratap Singh
ex-lndian Air Force Officer
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh
Just give me back
the respectability of my name
l don't want anything else
Maybe not in thirty minutes
like the Rrosecution Counsel...
but l will definitely prove that
this man is not Rajesh Rathore...
but he is Veer Rratap Singh.
Then whether you send him to lndia...
or keep him in Rakistan,
that is in your hands
That's all Your Honour
Now Rrosecution may call upon
it's witnesses
l'd like to call upon my first witness
Rolice Officer Dilbaaz Khan...
who had arrested Rajesh Rathod
twenty two years ago
Could you tell the court without
any doubt or hesitation...
who this man is?
Yes Sir, l remember very well
This man is an lndian spy.
He's an agent of RAW, Rajesh Rathore
Some twenty two years ago,
Anwar Ali and myself...
we forced him to get off a bus going
from Lahore to lndia and arrested him
We had received an
intelligence report...
that this man was
conspiring against Rakistan.
Good
Mr Anwar Ali, can you tell me,
if you found in his bag...
a passport identifying him
as Rajesh Rathore...
then how is it possible that
this same man's ticket...
was booked in the name of
Veer Rratap Singh?
But Sir, that was the thing...
Honour, this person also had a passport
in the name of Veer Rratap Singh
And how could one person
have two passports?
For this reason our suspicion
changed to certainty
And after we questioned him,
he himself signed the affidavit...
l, Rajesh Rathore
l've being seeing him
for the last ten years
He was always quiet
and kept to himself
He never communicated with any one
But whenever a prisoner
was ill or upset...
he would go forth
to heal him and comfort him
l don't know if he is
Veer Rratap Singh or Rajesh Rathore...
for me he's just 786
God's own man
Yes Sir, this Hindu here is
Allah's noble servant
He spent twenty two years in prison.
Can't be greater punishment than this
Send him back to his homeland...
send him back
Looks like you, Mr Majid Khan, have no
great love for your country Rakistan
lf it were up to you then every person
who had spied upon Rakistan...
every conspirator, should be set
free by the court?
Sir, that's not what l meant...
Just reply with a yes or a no
Mr Majid Khan, only with
a yes or no
No.
Good
Your witness
No questions Your Honour
The next date for this
case is after a week,
Before me, on Monday, 21st March
On that day l will hear
the Defence's case
And immediately after that
l will give my judgement
Defence should be ready
with their case
Adjourned
l'll have to mention
Zaara's name...
No...
Rlease... for once...
let me bring Zaara or any one person
from the Hayaat family to the court...
and in a moment the verdict
will swing to our favour
Absolutely not...
Why don't you try and understand?
We're losing this case
The court does not have time
for prisoners like you...
in this country there are
too many prisoners and too few courts
A lot of prisoners' cases
come up after they're dead
You'll never get
such an opportunity again
You'll die lying right here...
you'll die ! Don't you understand?
Zaara must be the mother
of two by now
She perhaps has a 21 year old daughter
and a 19 year old boy
She must've passed through all the
good and bad times of her life
Her days, her evenings must've
settled down to a fine rhythm
Must be a peaceful life now for Zaara
And tomorrow you'll drag her to court
and in front of everyone...
you'll ask her
who's Veer Rratap Singh ?
Questions will be raised, what is
the relationship between Veer and Zaara?
And no one will be able
to understand the answers...
no one will understand
ln an instant that Raza Shirazi
will divorce her. Zaara's life...
will be ruined. She must be
living peacefully
For the last twenty two years
l have been guarding her honour
Today how can l trample upon
her honour and go home?
l can't do this Saamiya
And l know you won't
be able to do it either
l'm sorry, for a while being a
lawyer made me forget my humanity
l forgot...
That Veer and Zaara's names
can never be taken together
Now there's only one way out...
l'll have to go to lndia...
to bring Veer Rratap Singh's
identity from his country
Time is short
l'm leaving.
Take care
Saamiya...
Until now this amulet has protected me,
now it will protect you
lf l lose...
will you forgive me...?
On one condition...
every day you must bring me...
laddoos
Take care
Excuse me...
can you show me where
Chaudhry Sumer Singh's house is?
Yes... the largest house
at the corner there...
that's Chaudhry saab's house.
- Thanks
But who're you looking for ?
For Mr Singh and his wife...
lt's been years since
both of them died...
But if you want to see the house
you're most welcome
That house is always open
l'm in a bit of a hurry,
please forgive me, goodbye
Zaara, oh Zaara...
l'm not sparing you
Hey who're you, what d'you want?
Hey why're you crying?
Say something, are you
deaf or what?
Hey Shabbo, look here's a visitor
And you Jassi... come here
Oh you'll be the death of me
l'll tell your Ma,
you aren't studying...
Yes... tell me...
what do you want?
You're Shabbo...?
Who else can l be?
And she's...
Zaara?
You came asking this?
ls she Zaara Hayaat Khan?
How do you know this name?
She's Jehangir Hayaat Khan's
daughter from Lahore?
Who are you?
After hearing about Veer's death,
Zaara called off the marriage
Abbaji himself got her divorced
Zaara came here to help Bauji and Maati
... to make Veer's dream come true
Raza settled overseas.
Abbaji left politics
He died two years afterwards,
a few years later Ma'am also died
The Hayaat Khan name
no longer existed
Today Bauji and Maati
are also no more
But she won't go back. She says...
My soul is embedded here.
Now l'll live and die here
Which century are these
people from Shabbo?
There's a Veer who so easily sacrificed
twenty two years of his life...
to protect Zaara's honour...
and there's Zaara who spent
twenty two years of her life...
in a strange land
to keep Veer's dream alive
Are they humans pretending to be Gods
or are they Gods disguised as humans?
This...
was my mother's
Twenty two years ago Mariam Hayaat Khan
had tied this amulet on an lndian...
while bidding him goodbye
so that it would protect him
That person did not reach lndia
but for twenty two years...
this charm has been protecting him
That person's name is...
Veer Rratap Singh
He's in prison, in a jail in Lahore
l am his lawyer
And l've come to take you to him
For the last twenty two years
God has been testing you both intensely
But now not even God
can separate Zaara and Veer
Not even God
Mr Saahil Farrouqi l'm asking you
where is the Defence Counsel?
Your Honour, she must be on her way
Looks like she has decided to
give up the case
Rlease begin with the proceedings
lrresponsible...
absolutely irresponsible of the
Defence Counsel not to have arrived
Mr Saahil Farrouqi, do you have
anything to say?
Your Honour, Saamiya... l mean my
learned colleague should be here soon
There's no problem...
There is a problem Mr Farrouqi,
there is a problem
lt's no small matter to waste
the court's time in this manner
Especially when
l had clearly specified...
that this day has been reserved
for the Defence's case...
then what is the reason
for her absence from the court?
lt's obvious that the
Defence does not have a case
Silence on the defendant's part and no
one appearing on behalf of the Defence...
[ Skipped item nr. 1551 ]
''For you, l have lived all these days''
''With my lips sealed''
''For you, l have lived all these days,
with my unshed tears''
''But in my heart,
the flames of love''
''Have always been burning for you,
only for you''
''Life has brought me...''
''A volume of old times''
''And l am surrounded by
countless memories''
''Unasked, l have now found
all the answers l sought''
''Look, what l yearned for''
''And what l got''
''But in my heart, the flames of love''
''Have always been burning for you,
only for you''
''How can l describe
the cruelty of this world''
''l was ordered that l have to live
but without you''
''Unwise are those who say that
to me you are unknown''
''So many ordeals, were heaped
on me by this world''
''But in my heart, the flames of love''
''Have always been burning for you,
only for you''
''For you, l have lived
all these days''
''With my lips sealed''
''For you, l have lived all these days,
with my unshed tears''
''But in my heart, the flames of love,
have always been burning for you''
''Only for you''
Zaara Hayaat Khan's testimony...
and photographs and documents
presented by her prove that...
this man is not Rajesh Rathore
but that he is Veer Rratap Singh
And to prevent disgracing
the honour of a Rakistani girl...
Veer Rratap Singh signed
that affidavit
Squadron Leader Veer Rratap Singh,
this court exonerates you
Go on Veer Rratap Singh, go on
You have the right to return to your
country with your head held high
And for the precious twenty two years
of your life wasted in prison...
the State of Rakistan and this court
asks your forgiveness
lf you wish to speak, you may
l prisoner number seven eighty six...
Look through the bars of the jail
l see days months years
change to eons
From the soil of this land comes
the fragrance of my Bauji's fields
This burning sun reminds me of
my Maati's cool buttermilk
This rain brings along with it
the swings of my seasons...
this winter fills me with the warmth
of the fires of my Lodi
They say that this is not your country
then why does it feel like mine''
He says that l am not like him
then why does he look like me...?''
l prisoner number seven eighty six
look through the bars of the jail''
l see an angel
who has come down from heaven
She calls herself Saamiya
and she calls me Veer''
She's a complete stranger
but treats me as her own''
Hearing her truthful words
l feel like living once more''
Hearing her promises and vows
l feel like doing something more''
They say that she is no one of mine
then why does she fight the world for me?''
He says that l'm not like her
then why does she look like me...?''
l prisoner number seven eighty six,
look through the bars of the jail''
l see my Zaara wrapped
in the colours of my village
ln making my dreams come true
she has forgotten her own...''
in serving my people
she has left behind her own''
Now l feel like filling her
being with happiness
l feel like living
another lifetime for her
They say that my country is not hers
then why is she staying in my home''
He says that l'm not like her
then why does she look like me...''
l prisoner number seven eighty six,
look through the bars of the jail''
Saamiya
Congratulations
Thank you
This was my last case
l'm giving up law
Because you've taught me that
l'm not fit for this work
l always thought that
a country's progress is measured...
to it's judicial system.
But now l understand that...
the future of both these countries is
in the hands of youngsters like you...
who do not measure humans as
big-small, man-woman, Hindu-Muslim...
who don't rake up bitter war memories
of 1947-1965 and 1999 on every pretext
Who wish to address the future
with the truth and only the truth...
and there's no stopping a country
where Truth prevails
Thank you Saamiya
Thank you for teaching me
the value of truth and justice
Your father would've been proud of you,
he would've been very proud
l am
Goodbye
Veer had lost Zaara in Rakistan.
So Veer and Zaara...
will be joined together
on Rakistani soil
Here take this...
make our Zaara yours forever
You said, Veer and Zaara's names
can never be taken together
Now Veer and Zaara's names
have been joined together forever
What Veer says is true
You're an angel...
sent only for us by God
Go on...
look your country awaits you
Come Zaara
Let us go home
Subtitles by; Mr.John