During the late Qing Dynasty period, China
was crumbling under foreign oppression.
Weak and unable to resist, the Chinese were
bullied, and branded "Sick Man of the East".
No one could stand up to the humiliation.
Attempting to further crush China's spirit,
the Shanghai Foreign Chamber of Commerce
planned a martial arts exhibition,
pitting the champions of four nations
against the Chinese.
One man took on the challenge...
and his name is Huo Yuan Jia.
"1910, Shanghai"
"Biarya Theatre, French concession"
"The competition's arena..."
Dearest guests! Today, four representatives
of the Shanghai Foreign Business Association...
will be challenging the
Jing Wu Sports Association's Huo Yuan Jia!
The competition's only rule is:
the outcome will be determined
by either a knockout or surrender.
"England's King of Boxing, Peter Smith"
Begin!
What's going on?
"Head trainer of Belgium's Royal Cavalry, Hans Hassel"
Excellent!
Good job, master!
"European fencing champion, Anthony Kasier"
And for our final round,
Japan's master of the Nine Demon
Gods style, Anno Tanaka...
will be taking on the Jing Wu Sports Association's
Huo Yuan Jia!
"30 years ago, Tianjin, Huo family household"
Young master!
Come on, let's go now.
Stop!
How dare you!
Who let you in?
I came to bring you some tea, father.
How many times have I told you to
never come in here?
Go back to your calligraphy.
Continue!
Hmph, I have to write for you every time...
If your father ever knew about this,
he'd beat you to death for sure!
You don't tell, I don't tell, who'll know?
Hey, I want to show you something...let's go!
-Nong Jing Sun, hurry up!
-I'm coming!
Why are they fighting again?
They're beating the drums again!
On this day, Huo En Di
of the Huo family style...
and Zhao Zhong Qiang
of the Zhao family style...
will pit their skills against one another
on this stage!
Sure! Good!
What are you two doing? Wanna die?
Your dad's gonna lose today, for sure!
You just watch!
Your dad's gonna get a taste of the Huo fist!
The Life-Death Pact has been signed!
Victory or defeat is determined amongst men.
Life and death is decided by God!
Masters! The competition shall begin!
Zhao Jian, NOW your dad knows
the real power of our Huo's fist!
And today's victor is...
Zhao Zhong Qiang!
Thank you, thank you so much!
Yuan Jia, Yuan Jia...
Let's go, Yuan Jia.
Yuan Jia, let's go back.
Yuan Jia...
Weren't you real brave just now?
What's the matter?
If you've got guts, don't shy away like a rat.
Come on, get up!
Stop your bullying, Zhao Jian!
Shut your mouth! You're useless, and
the same goes for your family.
Fight me if you've got the guts!
I wanna show you just how tough the Zhao fist is!
On the stage!
Stop fighting, Yuan Jia!
Stop, now!
Yeah! You won!
Today, you got schooled by the Zhao fist.
Don't ever mention your puny Huo fist again!
I won!
Yuan Jia...
Get up, Yuan Jia.
Let's go now.
I swear! Huo Yuan Jia won't let himself
be beaten down by anybody again!
Master, you...
Let me apply some medicine for you.
-Lai Fu, leave us.
-Yes.
What happened? Angry?
Mum, why won't Father let me learn martial arts?
That's because he loves you.
You were born with asthma...
and your body's weak. You couldn't
possibly take the vigorous training.
But, doesn't learning martial arts
strengthen the body?
So you want to learn martial arts
just to make your body stronger?
No, I want revenge!
I want Zhao Jian to know how good our Huo fist is!
Child, the most powerful part of martial arts
is not beating others down,
but controlling one's own desires.
No matter what, you mustn't forget about your virtue and morals.
Martial arts is for strengthening yourself
and helping the needy,
not for causing trouble,
and certainly not for revenge.
Emm.
The way to interact with others
is to respect one another,
then, others will respect you in return.
Who'd dare to disrespect the strongest?
Others' fear and respect
are two completely different things...
Alright, keep writing.
Otherwise, your dad'll punish you again.
"Death Fist Stance"
I won!
Come on, fly, fly now!
Uh-oh...
You gonna fall! Fall fall...
I won't fall! I won't fall!
Then I'll make you fall *boom*
I won't fall!
Come on!
Just move faster!
Oh!
Be careful!
-Good morning, Mom.
-Yuan Jia, you forgot your medicine again this morning.
Don't worry! Ever since I started training at West Lake,
my asthma hasn't acted up.
Wait, little miss!
Just look at your child...
Without a mother's care since young...
You've spoiled her completely.
You should marry again,
so that someone can help you take good care of her.
I've been busy building our reputation.
I want everyone in Tianjin to know and respect our family!
How would I have the time to remarry?
Come catch me! I wanna go hunt with you, Dad!
Although you've never been defeated this whole time,
your biggest opponent is yourself...
-And what you must conquer is really yourself.
-I understand.
"Writ of Challenge"
Master...
All right.
Mom, rest well.
Father, your fist was neither
fast nor vicious enough.
But don't you worry, 'cause I'll make sure
that the Huos won't be defeated again!
"Life-Death Pacts"
-I WILL become First in Tianjin!
-Dad!
-My li'l Tsui!
For me?
-No, I can't!
-Gimme?
No, I won't.
-Then, what do I have to do?
-You can only have it after you win today.
-Really?
-Emm.
Pinky swear?
"1900, Tianjin"
We're counting on ya, Master Huo!
-Master Huo!
-Hey, Huo Yuan Jia!
When're ya gonna be Tianjin's No.1?
-I don't know! What says you?
-It'll be today! Today!
Master Huo...
Hey, Zhao Jian!
Where've you been hiding all these years?
I've travelled Jiang Nan's 17 provinces, 38 prefectures...
and I've got nothing but skill.
I'm invincible now!
-Bullcrap!
-You're the bullshitting one!
The Life-Death Pact has already been signed.
Now begins the competition!
Come on up!
Hahahaha! What? Scared?
Come up! Come fall to your death!
You just wait!
Master, you're too good!
Ha! My stance is as firm as tree roots!
I WILL beat your Huo fist today!
Well, I'll give you a chance
...to lose!
Well done!
-Pussycat claw?
-Tiger Claw!!
Down!
Well done, master!
So you want me to fall, huh?
-Pussycat claw, definitely.
-It's Tiger Claw!!!!
You've already lost!
Ay! Careful!
Master...!
Master!
-You alright?
-I'm fine!!
-Huh. Tough guy!
-Don't touch me!
-The winner...
Huo Yuan Jia!
-Excellent, master!
-Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, everyone...
Congratulations! This way.
-Good job, Master Huo!
-Thank you!
We've reserved a table for you upstairs, Master Huo.
All right...
Yuan Jia!
Jing Sun!
Why so late?
Let's go, the usual spot.
Congratulations, Master Huo!
Hello, everybody.
Come on, now.
Jing Sun...
This Gu Yue Resturant of yours is getting more and more popular.
It's all thanks to my friends' support.
Still remember when we were kids?
You were such a bookworm...
I never expected you to excel in business!
Hey, we live in some bad times.
If a bookworm like me hasn't got a small business,
I wouldn't have many choices, would I?
Eat up, Yuan Jia.
These were made by the region's culinary masters.
Come on, try 'em!
All right, let's dig in!
After you, Master Huo.
Who are they?
-My name is Xia Shan.
-My name is Xu Da Shan.
We hope Master Huo will take us in as your pupils.
Master, we're most willing to serve you.
Sure! You two look like tough guys.
Serve'em wine!
Drink the wine, and we're brothers.
Cheers!
-Congratulations, Master Huo!
-Thank you, master!
-Such a happy occasion. All the drinks are on me!
-Thank you! Thank you!
Let's eat!
Li'l Tsui, don't wait anymore. It's bedtime, ok?
Take the young lady to her room.
-Li'l Tsui, come on.
-My good child, listen to me. Time for bed.
Come.
-What the heck is this?
-It's called coffee. Western stuff.
Not used to it, huh?
These are chaotic times..
If the common people want to live better,
then they have to learn from others' advancements.
Even a businessman like me
can't always just focus on profits.
And martial artists can't just
fight in arenas all day long.
-National affairs are important, too.
-National affairs? You scholars can worry about that.
Me, I'm a fighter.
I only want to be First in Tianjin!
Is that title really so important?
Hey, come with me.
Jing Sun, you've always been an offstage spectator.
Now that you're onstage,
can't you feel the difference?
-What's so different about this?
-As long as you're offstage,
the life-and-death struggle onstage has nothing to do with you!
You're just enjoying the fight, right?
But once you're standing here,
there's no other choice besides victory!
Well...you can choose not to go onstage.
Jing Sun, listen...
Listen to what?
I don't hear anything.
-Yes...I can hear it...
-(Master Huo, you're our hero!)
(Well done, good!)
(Good job, excellent!)
(Master Huo is champion of the world!!!)
Agh....here comes the Iron Head Stance!
-Thank you.
-Good job, master!
Look, let's save ourselves the trouble.
Whoever's signed the Pact, can all come on up!
All challengers, onstage!
-Huo Yuan Jia, when will you be Tianjin's No.1?
-What do you say?
Today's the day!
Hey, what do you people want?
We'll do anything to be Master Huo's pupils!
Good, good! You all look like tough guys.
Serve'em wine!
Drink the wiine, and we'll be brothers.
Bottoms up!
-Let's drink!
-Congratulations, Master Huo!
Thank you, do come again.
Boss, these are all Huo's bills.
Ok, I'll see to it.
You haven't defeated my foster father, Master Qin!
Come on, drink!
Yuen Jia, you've already won 38 straight rounds.
There are no more opponents for you in Tianjin.
Wrong. There's still one...
Must you still fight?
To really be Tianjin's No.1, yes!
What about outside of Tianjin?
Beijing? Lianguang? Shanxi? Hunan?
When is it over?
I know what you're getting at.
But I can't stop. Fighting's all I've got!
Only by fighting can I prove
that I'm stronger than others.
Even after you've proven yourself, so what?
Yuan Jia, stop and give it some thought.
What's this?
-The tabs your pupils and friends ran up this month.
-I'll pay for them.
They're all just using you!
Just how many of them treat you like a brother?
It's called personal loyalty.
And...
Fine, I'll send someone with the money tomorrow.
Yuan Jia, I didn't come here for money.
Accepting pupils and friends,
you should look at their moral qualities,
not how well they can drink!
Watch your step, Master Huo.
Morning, Master Huo.
Hey, Master Qin, morning.
Aren't you Master Huo,
the self-proclaimed champion of Tianjin?
-What a coincidence!
-Master Qin, I thought you've long since
retired to Shanxi due to old age!
There's a long list of people
waiting to be my students.
-It's quite puzzling.
-Hmph. I'm also puzzled...
that you've prepared such a "large gift" for yourself.
Congratulations!
You're most welcome.
Actually, I bought it for you.
Go help your master!
Welcome, Master Qin.
Master, your income isn't enough
to even support the household,
and those pupils of yours are running up more and more bills.
-And what about our savings?
-It was used up 3 months ago.
Used up? Empty...
Master!
Fine, Fine. I told you to train diligently,
but no one listens...
-Who did it?
-Master Qin!
Master!
Today's Master Qin's birthday...
-I wish Master Qin long life and happiness!
-Well done!
Father, I sincerely wish you longevity also.
Good!
-Let's drink to your health, master.
-All right...
Master Huo, today's my foster father's birthday.
He's booked this resturant.
If you're here to drink,
kindly find another place.
I beseech you...
You have no place to speak.
Hey.
Today is my birthday.
I don't wish to fight. If there's a problem,
let's talk it over some other day.
Being the senior, have you no shame,
injuring my pupils?
-I, Huo Yuan Jia, have come for an explanation.
-What do you want?
I've already signed.
Put your name down, if you dare.
Otherwise, bow down and apologize!
Out of the way! YuanJia!
You're overreacting! His guests are all here.
Can't you just discuss this another day?
-I can't put up with that kind of insult.
-No matter what, I won't let you cause trouble
at his birthday celebration!
-You accuse me of troublemaking?
-Yuen Jia...
Afraid I'll smash up your restaurant?
I, Huo Yuan Jia, will pay for any damages!
I can't believe you've said such things.
Leave now. Consider our years of friendship
null and void!
Just like that?
All these years,
and now you don't want me?
You're blind!
Get out! All of you!
I want to avoid hurting any innocents...
Let's get going!
Master!
Master won again!
Let's go drink!
Not drunk, no return!
Careful...
Let me serve you a drink.
Come on, again!
Master's the most feared man here!
He's unbeatable! Just look at him!
Esteemed Huo!
Congratulations.
Your longtime dream has come true.
You're number 1.
But let me tell you;
Two hours ago, Master Qin died!
Heheheh....Huo Yuan Jia...
When'll you be Tianjin's No.1?
It's today!
Heheh...Huo Yuan Jia...
it's today...
Huo Yuan Jia,
First in Tianjin...
It's today...heheh...
Mother!
The young lady's room, quick.
I'm the one who killed them.
I'll take full responsibility for my actions.
Take care, foster mother.
Tell Master what you did!
-Tell him!
-Master...
I'm so sorry!
It's all my fault...
I had a relationship with Master Qin's concubine...
He found out and punished me!
Master, the others knew...
I thought they'd have told you!
Master! Master!
Master!
He has a fever.
I'll go fetch some medicine.
After he takes the medicine, he'll
sweat a little, and then he'll be fine.
He'll be fine...
Let's go...
He needs to rest. Let's go!
When I was 13, I started to not
see things so clearly.
In my eyes, there always seemed
to be this fog that couldn't be lifted...
Back then, I cried day after day.
Grandma told me,
when you're unhappy inside,
you should cry.
When the crying's done, you still
have to move on.
But, in my heart, I saw it all.
Can you believe it?
How about I wash your hair?
After a while, hair gets knotty very easily.
Wash it often, and it'll stay clean and silky.
Grandma always says,
People should always keep themselves clean.
Only then can you live with clarity in the world.
There are no knots that can't be unravelled.
Ah Niou!
Ah Niou, you can really sleep!
You sleep as much as our dog, Ah Huang.
So, I named you Ah Niou.
Come, come, come, follow me!
Ah Niou, you're up!
Let's go catch dragonflies and butterflies!
Tomorrow, bring him to the fields.
Some work will be good for him.
Sure!
Ah Niou...
Follow me, hurry.
Go, come... come here...
Look, you wasted your day's efforts.
Miss Yue Tzi won't let us say anything,
but she's redoing it all for you.
Seedlings have life, too.
They can't stay too close,
or it'll hinder growth.
Just like us humans...
In life, we must learn to respect each other.
Only then can we live peacefully and happily.
I'll remember that.
-Grandma, come, let's eat!
-Sure.
Grandma!
Yue Tzi.
Grandma...
In a couple of days,
it'll be time to visit the graves.
-Go pay your respects to your parents.
-Yes.
Grandma said that I should go visit my parents' graves.
Have some water.
I'd like to discuss something with you.
Are you leaving?
I'd also like to go pay my respects
to my parents' graves.
Filial piety is important.
You should go.
I'll be coming back afterwards.
You've been here for many years...
I've always known that you'd
leave this village one day.
Actually, I...
Here is a change of clothes for
your journey. Please take them.
I haven't told you my name yet.
You need not tell me.
Where you came from...where you're going...
I need not know, either.
Remembering you as Ah Niou is enough for me.
My name is Huo Yuan Jia.
I'll remember.
"1907, Tianjin"
(Goodies!...)
(Money...Money...)
(God's Word must be trusted...)
(Trust God, and receive eternal life...)
(It's true, true...)
(The words He speaks are all in here...)
(God's Word is here...)
Huo Yuan Jia!...First in Tianjin!
Huo Yuan Jia!...Huo Yuan Jia!
You're back to fight again!
Huo Yuan Jia's back to fight again...
-Master...
-Uncle Lai Fu.
You're back!
Allow me, allow me.
Sorry I haven't kept your home in proper order.
Master, accept my apology...
I've always thought...for when the Master returns...
everything in here, not a bit's been changed.
-It's been hard on you.
-It's my job, sire...
After you left, the creditors came every day,
demanding their debts.
All the things in the house,
they took, one by one.
In the end, they even wanted the
house to pay off the debt.
Every single thing in this room
were retained only
because, luckily, someone
sent us some money.
Afterwards, I thought about it.
I believe Master Nong Jing Sun might
be the one who helped.
I don't need them anymore.
And, I believe my parents don't want
to see these things again, either.
Honorable Father, I have been unfilial.
Only now do I understand...
Back then, that moment on the stage...
why you didn't deliver that final blow.
You are, indeed, the real "First in Tianjin".
Honorable Mother,
You once taught me the principles of being a person.
Your son was foolish, and didn't understand.
Don't worry.
I, your son, shall not disappoint you again.
My child, I didn't take good care of you
when you were in this world.
I even let you suffer such a disasterous fate.
I'm not a good father.
Madam, I once did an unforgivable thing.
Today, I've come to pay my respects to Master Qin.
Mum! Mum!
Extra! Extra!
A foreign strongman named Hercules
O'Brien has challenged all China!
With 32 consecutive wins,
and 25 contestants seriously injured,
He has not yet been defeated...
He scorns the Chinese as the
"Sick Men of the East"!
No one dares to challenge him!
Jing Sun...
I'm indebted to you.
So many times...I only realized
my mistakes after the fact.
My errors have caused so much pain
in my heart.
I don't wish to mention past things.
They're all over and done with.
Jing Sun, It's hard for me to ask,
But you're my only hope.
I need to borrow some money.
-Still after your fighting competitions?
-Yes.
I don't have a friend like you.
What reason do I have for lending you money?
-Master...
-Master Huo, this is from my master.
Your master is...?
His surname is Nong. Nong Jing Sun.
1909, Shanghai Racetrack
Ladies and gentlemen...
The person appearing before you today
can move a train single-handedly,
can put a hole in the Great Wall
of China with one punch!
What bullshit!
He can crush a Chinese
fighter with his little finger...
-Idiot!
-Please welcome the greatest strongman in history...
Ao...Bi...Ying! (O'Brien)
Today's challenger is...
Tianjin's very own, Huo Yuan Jia!
Good! Good!
Sign the Life-Death Pact first.
Tell him: wagering one's life in a fight
is one of China's more questionable traditions.
But, we have another kind of tradition,
making friends while exchanging pointers.
(Excellent! Well said..)
Uh...he wants to kick your butt.
Start the competition!
Come on! Yeah!
All right!
-Excellent, well done!
-Boo!
I yield kindly.
...Thank you.
"Huo Yuan Jia defeats Hercules;
Shocks Shanghai"
"Huo Yuan Jia rallies various kung fu sects"
"Huo gathers the nation's best martial artists,
Establishes Jing Wu Sports Association"
"Shanghai Foreign Journalists' Club"
Master, someone called for you.
Jing Sun...I really didn't expect you.
You still consider me a friend.
I can't forget you as a friend.
I cannot possibly forget.
Come, have a seat, Yuan Jia.
I've prepared your favorite wine!
Come!
What's the matter?
I gave up wine. I gave it
up many years ago.
But wine was like life to you!
I don't want to repeat the mistakes
I've made in the past.
Good.
Then, we'll drink tea instead.
Yuan Jia, you've stirred up the spirits
of our countrymen with that fight.
What with the Westerners having
oppressed us to this point,
it's about time a Chinese person
stood up to them.
As a friend,
I'm truly happy for you.
Try this!
Jing Sun,
when are you leaving this time?
Me? Since I've decided to come,
I'm not leaving.
What about your restaurant?
-Sold it.
-Sold?!
Your business has always been good, hasn't it?
You want to start the Jing Wu Sports Association.
How will you do it without money?
But, the Gu Yue Restaurant meant everything to you...
Compared with your aspirations, my restaurant
isn't even worth mentioning.
Yuan Jia, I'm not the martial arts type.
I can only give you this meager contribution.
May you succeed.
This is drafted according to what we've discussed
earlier--the school's rules and regulations.
See if this is what you wanted.
The Jing Wu Sports Association
has 3 objectives:
To educate the body, wisdom, and morals.
Martial arts is the way to become stronger.
There will be no segregration of clans.
Only through the exchange of arts
will one improve oneself.
By having a healthy body and alert mind,
our people will be able to prosper again.
We shall not harm the innocent!
We shall not abuse our martial arts!
Virtue and morality will be our motto!
To constantly strive to better ourselves!
"1910, Jing Wu Sports Association officially established"
-Ready!
"Shanghai Foreign Chamber of Commerce"
-Well, gentlemen, it's too rich for me.
I only bet on sure things.
Then perhaps you'll be interested in joining
our little wager
against this..."Hua Yuan Jia" fellow.
He better lose this time. He cost me
6000 Francs when he beat this O'Brien.
Mr. Mita here will ensure that you win back everything
that you've lost, plus a litte bit more.
I'm set to stage a competition of four matches, between
our countries' best against him.
We'll beat him, and leave the Chinese with nothing
to brag about.
Four against one? What makes you so sure
he's going to accept that?
Pride. Honor. The prestige of his school.
It's of no importance. He has already
accepted the challenge.
Then, gentlemen, I'll take you up
on your wager.
And to make it a little more interesting,
I'm gonna back the Chinese.
You're certain Wong Ji Wah will lose?
With what I have in mind, our victory is guaranteed.
Yuan Jia.
Among the competitors this time...
There's a Japanese man named Anno Tanaka.
He'd like to meet you.
But, I heard that he's a master among masters.
We can only improve by fighting with the best.
Yuan Jia, this challenge from the foreigners...
I don't think it's as simple as it looks.
If it is, why would they want you
to take on 4 fighters at once?
I'm guessing, they want to use
the chance to wipe the floor with our pride,
so that our association will lose its
influence in Shanghai.
Indeed, and we must win all four
matches to conclude the challenge.
It's not fair in any way.
But as long as we live in this world,
who can promise that all matters in life are fair?
For the Jing Wu Association,
I have no other options.
But what if...
Jing Sun!
I have something to discuss with you.
What's it about?
After this challenge,
I want you to become the school's president.
Why?
I want to take some time off in the countryside,
to see Yue Tzi and Aunt Suen.
I've made a promise.
If Sir says so...do you truly
not understand tea?
Not that I don't understand,
I'm just unwilling.
I don't want to rank the tea.
I'm fine as long as it's tea.
But, tea has differences
in smell, and in grade.
What is good? What is bad?
They all grow in nature,
without rank or distinction.
It seems you still have not understood.
Otherwise, you'd naturally determine a rank
from the first taste.
You are right.
So I realized that
the quality of tea
is not derived from the tea itself;
it's decided by people.
Different people have different choices.
Me, I'm unwilling to make this choice.
Oh? Why?
Appreciating tea depends on your emotions.
If you have a happy state of mind,
does the quality of tea matter?
Oh, I've never thought of that.
According to Sir, there are numerous
factions of martial arts;
Is there no superiority or inferiority among them?
Yes, those are my sentiments.
In that case, Sir, I'd like to
pose a question to you.
Since there are no distinctions
between martial arts,
why, then, are there competitions?
I meant that all martial arts are equal.
The distinction lies in the strength
or weakness of those who practice them.
Through competitions, we can further improve,
and discover one's true self.
Because, quite possibly, our real opponent
is ourselves.
Only through competition can one
recognize one's true self.
Does Sir mean that the worst battle
is found within one's own heart?
I'm honored to be having this conversation with you.
Well, today, we met to appreciate tea.
Let's not talk further and thus forget about the tea.
-Come, try it.
-Yes, the tea.
"1910, Shanghai"
"Theatre Biarya, French concession"
"The competition's arena..."
Esteemed guests,
the last fight of the day...
will be Anno Tanaka of Japan's
Nine Demon Gods style...
versus the Jing Wu Sports Association's
Huo Yuan Jia.
What's the matter?
One versus four?
Why did you not tell me before?
We've already discussed this.
You need not be surprised.
Is this a competition?
-This is murder!
-You worry needlessly.
Huo Yuan Jia is the king of the arena.
Outstanding fighters from all over
were arranged to meet him today...
Ita-san...
What are you?
Is this for Japan's honor?
Or is it for personal gain?
To me, martial arts itself means the most.
Your mission is to win this competition.
Begin!
Brother Yuan Jia,
this contest is unfair to you.
I have no objections
if you choose to fight another day.
I appreciate your good intentions,
but since I'm already standing in this arena,
there must be a conclusion.
Please!
Begin!
Haha! Excellent!
Master is too good!
A draw.
The next round will be unarmed freestyle combat!
Both sides, please prepare yourselves...
Mita, where have you been?
We're going to lose.
Don't worry, gentlemen.
I have it under control.
Yuan Jia!
-Stop!
-What happened?
Tanaka, why are you stopping?
Yuan Jia!
-Tanaka!
-Go down, go!
Yuan Jia, what's wrong?
How are you?
-I've been poisoned...
-Poisoned?!
How can it be?
Just exactly what happened?
-What are you doing?
-Water!
Your cup!
What happened to your drink?
The drink's poisoned!
They've already removed the evidence!
Yuan Jia, let's go to the hospital!
Master, we'll go to the hospital.
I've over-exerted myself...
-Too late...the poison is making its way to my heart...
-Master, I'll avenge you!
Zhen Sheng!
What you must do...is not seek revenge.
Hatred...will only beget more hatred.
I don't want to see hatred.
-What's important is the strengthening of oneself.
-Yuan Jia!
-Master!
-Yuan Jia, let's stop the fight.
-I'll take you to the hospital, let's go!
-Jing Sun...
I'm just a brute fighter.
It took me many years...to truly
understand what martial arts is...
and what I have done with it?
This competition isn't finished yet...
We cannot choose the way life begins...
but we must have the courage
to walk that last step.
Master...
-What is this? What are you doing?
-What do you mean?
You ask too many questions!
(I must win this fight.)
Just win the competition!
Never cease to improve oneself!
See for yourself...
Don't keep fighting.
Staying alive
is more important than anything!
Listen.
Living...isn't just for one person.
If we must fight...I will not hold back.
This will be my honor.
Master...
He's down! Huo Yuan Jia is down!
Go! He lost! Go! Go! Make the announcement!
Wait!
Huo!
Yuan!
Jia!
Yuan Jia!
Huo Yuan Jia...
Master!
Tanaka! Look what you've done!
-I lost!
-Says who? Witnessed by who?!
I saw it myself.
-I've lost by virtue of martial art ethics!
-Who are you to decide?!
How can you make decisions just like that?!
You...
You're an embarrassment to Japan!
Huo Yuan Jia died from the poison shortly after
arriving at the hospital. He was only 42 years old.
After his death, his teachings have
continued to flourish.
To date, the Jing Wu Association has
expanded to over 50 countries all over the world.
Dr. Sun Yat-Sen penned these words
in memory of Huo Yuan Jia's spirit:
"Essence of learning martial arts"
Directed by:
Ronny Yu