No, you've already had some.
Go away!
AFTER THE WEDDlNG
Are there only rich people
where you are going?
If I was rich, I'd be happy.
You hate all the rich, Mr. Jacob.
Is it because the houses are
far apart that people are far apart?
You're not coming back.
I know it.
Why do you have to go?
Do you promise to come
to my birthday?
Okay?
"ln the yard, a flock of sparrows
saw him and began to shout:"
"Tit tit! Tit tit!
Oh, look at Nils Goosey-boy."
"Look at Thumbietot!
Look at Nils Holgersen Thumbietot!"
"Cock-a-doodle-do,
cried the cock."
"Cock-a-doodle-do!"
"Then the hens came.
Peck, peck, peck..."
We'll stop here for tonight.
You have to sleep.
Into bed with you.
Sleep tight.
Good night.
Good night, Morten.
Good night, Martin.
It'll be fun to see
what important thing I forgot.
Yes, it will be lovely.
As long as there's food and wine...
- You're not nervous at all?
- No, I'm looking at it as a test.
- Of what?
- Anna will marry many times.
The first wedding is always hard.
With a little luck, it will be okay.
Jorgen... Jorgen?
Yes?
Mother, aren't you in bed?
I can't get online.
Don't speak to me like I'm senile.
Why can't I get online?
There's poker in three minutes.
Why did we have to get
that damn wireless network?
But it's working now... Thank you.
- Sleep tight.
- Don't stay up all night.
Sorry.
Could we teach her to knock first?
I've tried, but she's senile.
Only when she wants to be.
- I'll send her to a home tomorrow.
- Promise?
That's me.
- May I take your bag?
- No, thanks.
Please step inside.
Main switch.
The bedroom. B&O television.
The first of the suite's two bathrooms.
There are also three toilets.
Mini bar. Safe.
Larger bottles here. If there's anything
else you'd like just say so.
Flat screen. Air-conditioning.
B&O stereo in the corner.
Sauna. Adjustable temperature.
Timer. On/off button.
The same goes for the Jacuzzi.
On and off.
Private rooftop terrace.
The old university.
The cathedral where the Crown Prince
got married. The Round Tower.
If you need anything else,
press three.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, sir.
- Jacob Pedersen?
- That's me.
Christian Refner,
I'm here to pick you up.
Do you have a coat?
No? Then let's go.
- The room's okay?
- It's fine.
It used to be a department store.
Funny isn't it?
- So, Jacob with a C or a K?
- It's with a C.
I'm Christian with a C too.
- So you're meeting Jorgen?
- Yes.
- Do you know him well?
- He's my father-in-law.
- Or will be on Saturday.
- Congratulations.
Jorgen's fantastic.
He's brilliant, really brilliant.
- People often fear him, but don't.
- Good.
He's worth over a billion
and started out flat broke,
but you can't tell.
That he started flat broke?
No, no...
- Jacob Pedersen is here.
- Have a seat. Just for a moment.
- It was nice to meet you, Jacob.
- Same here. Good luck.
Give my regards to Jorgen.
- Hi.
- Busy?
- A little.
- That looks nice on you.
- Thanks.
- Have a nice day, okay? Bye.
- Bye.
Jacob.
Welcome.
My name is Jorgen Hansson.
- Jacob.
- This way.
Was the flight okay?
Good.
This is where we live.
You can see Sweden on a clear day.
If you feel like it, that is.
A drink?
No, thanks.
Cheers.
You have a video
that can give me a sense
of what goes on there.
It will take more than
a video to show you that.
Meaning?
Bombay has over
a million child prostitutes.
Four or five times that
suffer from malnutrition.
They're not on the video.
Then there are those who die
every day of... Well, what...
Minor illnesses, minor infections...
Completely minor things-
that could be cured for tiny sums
if one only had the will.
We've developed a sort
of priority list...
You're an angry man. That's good.
It gives you a lot of drive.
The educational supplies we need
include books, tables, chairs, beds...
but what we need most
urgently is medicine.
Eventually we'd like to...
Yes...
We'd like to take twice
as many off the streets.
- Would you like one?
- No, thanks.
We'd like to take in twice as many
and vaccinate them-
which could be done all for less
than five kroner a day.
And we'd like to change
our food program...
- Do they all sleep in the same room?
- We have 45 at the moment.
We go to an area, and in two minutes,
40-50 kids gather, who we then feed.
But after five minutes,
there are 500 kids.
- I don't need to see more.
- The new kids...
It's an extremely impressive project
you have established.
Very impressive.
I've looked at different ways
I might be able to help.
Thank you very much.
In all, I found five different projects.
Yours is one of the most interesting.
Thank you. We're glad to hear it.
But may I ask you why?
Like I said...
It's a good project.
I was thinking of an annual donation
of one million dollars for four years.
But I need more time
to think through
which projects I want
to get involved with.
So don't get your hopes up
too high.
Okay... I was given
a different impression.
Then let's look at the papers
again, because...
No, no. Let's forget the boring
paperwork until Monday.
We'll have lunch and I'll let
you know what I've decided.
- I've got a busy weekend coming up.
- So I've heard.
I spoke to the guy that drove me here.
He's marrying your daughter?
- Yes, Christian. You're not married?
- No.
- Got any family here?
- No, I don't.
Then come to the wedding tomorrow.
It's a huge wedding.
I don't know half of the guests myself.
- It would be nice.
- I need to...
You don't have any other plans.
We're through.
See you tomorrow?
We're looking forward to it.
- Then I can get to know you.
- Thanks for your time.
- Hey, Dad!
- How are you?
Were you jumping on
the trampoline? Can I see?
Everything okay?
Except that Annette
can't cope with the stress.
Then now's not the time
to say another guest is coming.
A business contact from lndia.
You better do it gently... in stages.
Have you changed your mind?
There's still time.
- Yes, come on... You've got time.
- You're just jealous.
Yes, of course.
You're much too beautiful for him.
Will you love and honor her,
for better or for worse,
in good times and bad,
as husband and wife
till death do you part?
Yes.
And now I ask you,
Anna Louise Hansson:
do you take Christian Refner
as your lawfully wedded husband?
- Yes.
- Will you love and honor...
- I'm very sorry.
- That's okay.
Those who before us have pledged
to live as man and wife,
confirming before God
and those assembled here
their solemn vows,
I therefore pronounce you
man and wife.
Don't throw them yet.
Come here. I'll show you...
- Hi.
- Hi, Jacob.
- Doing well?
- Yes.
- Hi. Welcome.
- Thank you.
- This is my wife.
- I see.
Have you met Anna?
You must.
- This is Jacob, who I told you about.
- Congratulations.
- Christian.
- Hi, Jacob.
This is Christian's mother.
There you are.
Care for a drink?
Yes, please.
- Cheers. Welcome.
- Thanks.
- Can I play?
- Yes! Are you any good?
Good?! I'm the best.
Aren't you playing together?
I stand not just before you, Anna-
but also my boss
and father-in-law, Jorgen-
and Helene and, of course,
the rest of you.
Anna, we met at Jorgen's firm
when it was in the suburbs.
I didn't dare speak to you because
you were the boss's daughter.
Then one day you needed
to borrow 1000 kroner.
Jorgen wasn't there
and so I had to lend it to you.
You'd think he was marrying Jorgen.
But Jorgen and Helene,
I would like...
to thank you for the way you've
welcomed me into the family.
I know you think it's early
for Anna to marry
but please know
that it feels very right to me.
Anna, I love you more than all
the world. I'm thrilled you'll have me.
Please toast to my beautiful bride
and her fantastic family
who have welcomed me so kindly-
Jorgen, Helene, the twins...
Cheers.
Christian's lovely, don't you think?
He's nice.
- He's so cute.
- Cute? Maybe.
- I dated him before Anna.
- Was he your boyfriend?
But Anna gets whatever she wants.
It's not traditional for the bride
to give a speech
but everything's gone
so well so far.
I know Mom's waiting for something
to go horribly wrong.
I'll do it now
so that you can relax.
My speech isn't for you, Christian.
I love you and you know it.
I couldn't be happier than I am today.
And don't worry,
I'll pay back the 1000 kroner.
But I'd like to thank
Mom and Dad.
Mom, I know we argue
now and then
but you are the best,
the most loving
and the most loyal person
I have ever met.
And Dad...
When I turned 18
a few years ago,
you had to tell me that you weren't
my real father... genetically.
You told me how Mom
had known another man
and we didn't talk for
almost six months.
It wasn't until I met Christian
that I began to understand
why you did what you did.
You did it to protect me, so I'd have
a mother and father like everyone else.
I've had a dad.
You've been the best father
anyone could ever wish for.
And if I could have chosen,
I would have chosen you, Dad,
whether you're my father or not.
So I'd like to say thank you.
Thank you for today
and for everything.
And thanks for being the way you are
for as long as I can remember.
So I'd like to propose
a toast for Mom and Dad-
the loveliest couple here tonight.
- Cheers.
Why are you sitting here
all by yourself?
Because I want to.
Weren't you ever taught not to
abandon a lady with 7 old maids?
Listen, I've got a plan.
If you wait a little
and I wait a little-
we could go into town
after they dance.
You and me. I know a place where
they make fruit with drinks in them.
- You could come along.
- I don't think so.
I'd like to be alone
for a while, okay?
- I mean it.
- Yes.
I won't tell anyone if you come along.
I won't tell Anna.
- I don't want to talk to you.
- No.
- Are you angry?
- Are you stupid?
Go away!
I don't know what
the hell to think, Helene.
- About what?
- Too much fits together too well.
But then I think,
you wouldn't have
done that to me.
I'd like to talk,
but not right now.
I simply can't believe
you've done this to me.
I haven't done anything.
What have I done?
Is she my daughter?
Of course not. She is mine and Jorgen's.
What were you thinking?
- Is she my daughter?
- I'll call tomorrow.
- I asked you a question!
- I'll call you tomorrow!
Won't you come to bed?
- Why did you do it, Jorgen?
- Do what?
I didn't know it was him, Helene.
It's just too much of a coincidence.
- He shouldn't have come.
- No.
But we can't control
everything in the world.
Hi, it's 602 again.
Do I have any messages now?
Thanks.
- That's nice.
- Let me have a look?
- It's got small swastikas on it.
- They're not swastikas.
It's wonderful.
It's from...
- It's from Allan and Kristina.
- One of our really good lawyers.
He'll be fired for giving
such an ugly vase, right?
- Put it over there.
- It goes in the basement.
I have to talk to Helene.
Listen, I don't like this either,
but I need to talk to her now.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
Wait here.
Helene, we have a guest.
- Wanna play football?
- Hi.
- Thanks for coming yesterday.
- My pleasure.
- Can we offer you something?
- No. Helene, can we talk?
- I was going to call.
- But you didn't. Do you have a minute?
Of course.
Yes.
- Let's go out to the kitchen.
- Good idea.
- Or would you rather be alone?
- No, I'd like you to come.
Boys, stay with Anna
and grandmother.
- Jorgen, is everything okay?
- Yes, unpack your presents.
All this running to and fro.
You old grump...
- Did you lose again?
- Yes.
Don't come here like this. You should
have waited for me to call you.
- You didn't call!
- Don't come here and intimidate me!
I waited all day. Who are you?
How can you stand yourself?
Jacob, we tried to contact you several
times, but we couldn't find you.
Come on. You're filthy rich.
You could have hired an army.
It obviously took more
than an army to find you.
To find a junkie drinking
in lndia with hookers.
You hid my daughter for 20 years
because I cheated once?
Do you really think
that's why, Jacob?
Because you cheated once?
You're a very small person.
- What are you telling me?
- You're not listening.
- Then tell me. Tell me!
- Let's all calm down a little.
Why didn't you tell me
you were pregnant?
- We'd have figured something out.
- I didn't know until I got back.
I met Jorgen and...
No, Jacob, I don't owe you anything.
You don't owe...
Aren't we talking about your daughter?
- Shouldn't she know her father?
- She has a father, a good father.
I don't know what the hell to say.
What you did is so wrong.
You know that, right?
But you have to tell her.
You owe her and you owe me.
She doesn't give a shit.
You are so infuriating.
Is that the language you use
in this house?
I just think that it would be good
if you told her.
If you don't, I will.
I'm going to see what's going on.
We thought he was dead.
- We didn't think he existed.
- You're still lying.
I'm not lying. Jorgen tried to
find him in lndia lots of times.
He never reacted so we
assumed that he wasn't...
- I don't have time for this, Mom.
- Jacob was a big, immature child!
He fucked everything with a pulse.
He was drinking himself
to death.
He did drugs. He had grand ideas,
but did nothing.
He probably means well,
but you can't trust him.
- He wants to save everyone, but...
- I don't care if he's fucked a goat.
I have a right to know
who my father is.
- You can't manipulate people like that.
- We're not.
Fuck off and leave us alone!
Not right now.
You're far out.
What's Jorgen's reaction?
Anna...?
- Should I come along?
- No.
I'll wait here, okay?
Would you like to come in?
I mean, please come in.
Thanks.
I don't know what to say.
It's a little new to me.
For me too.
Didn't you know I existed?
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't say sorry. You're
the only one who can't be blamed.
- Would you like a Coke?
- Yes, please.
I think we've got one here.
- There aren't any more. Some water?
- That's fine.
- He's nice... Christian.
- Yes, Christian.
He's waiting in the car.
- Mom said you were dead.
- Well, okay.
But apparently I'm not.
Would you like a glass?
It's a little tight. It needs a...
How long are you staying?
Do you have time to meet?
Yes.
I'd like that very much.
- I'm here all the time.
- I could call.
Yes.
- Or I could give you my number.
- If you've got one, I'd like that.
- Now you know I exist.
- Yes.
I've got a pencil and some paper.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
I better go now.
Bye.
I'll be home very soon.
Do I have any brothers or sisters?
- No, not really.
- What do you mean?
There's a little boy
at the orphanage called Pramod.
- Pramod?
- Pramod, yes.
I've taken care of him
since he was a baby.
- How old is he now?
- He'll turn eight in precisely a week.
He's this big. He's tiny,
but he wants to be a footballer.
Maybe it's stupid, but I brought some
pictures, if you'd like to see them.
Yes, please.
Here I'm taking a bath.
That's Lennart,
my first boyfriend.
He had a moped.
- But he didn't want me.
- Why not?
Because I beat him at table tennis.
It destroyed him.
You can't do that!
That was in ltaly.
That's Da... Jorgen.
Was I silly to bring them?
No, I'd like to see them all.
What happened back then?
Why didn't you come home?
I just didn't.
We had broken up.
And you were drunk
all the time, right?
Yeah.
And you did her friend?
Yep, I think I actually did that.
- Would you like dessert?
- Yes, please.
Jacob, I am glad you came anyway.
I thought it all through yesterday
and I became convinced
we must continue.
You would like to continue?
As though nothing's happened?
Yes, it fits even better now.
- Well, let's try then.
- Are you hungry?
We need some lunch.
We're going to lunch.
Wasn't it strange meeting
her again... Helene?
Yes.
Don't you think she's ageing well?
She's still extremely beautiful.
Cheers!
Cheers.
Why was I at that wedding, Jorgen?
You knew.
I didn't know.
I didn't know you were that Jacob.
- I don't believe that.
- Well, I can't change anything now.
What do you want?
- The honest or the official answer?
- I'd like the honest answer.
I'm just a good person.
There's not much in this.
We better complain.
- I don't need any more.
- We need another bottle.
It's the best way to get to know
people. Another bottle.
- I don't think that would be wise.
- You're not paid to think.
Either bring another bottle
or bring your boss.
Understand?
Or should I ask him to translate?
- I need to go.
- Why? We'd like another drink.
- What's the problem?
- We need a bottle of schnapps.
We can't serve you
when you're so drunk.
So drunk?
I've only just gotten started.
- It's a policy we have.
- A policy?
A policy?
That's a damned bad argument.
If you want to get on in the world,
you need to make decisions.
When you break policies,
you show decisiveness.
Yes, and I think you should go home.
You stupid little asshole.
Who do you think you're talking to?
- Run off and get another bottle.
- Jorgen, we'll go somewhere else.
I'm not the only one that's drunk.
Coming?
I'm sorry.
Empty already?
Those silly little bottles.
- Mother helped too.
- That's good.
Helene, I would like to have a party
on my birthday. It would be nice.
Sure, but is one bottle
of whiskey each enough?
Jorgen, would you please tell me
what this is all about?
I couldn't be bothered.
We're getting up early tomorrow
and driving far.
Why won't you let Jacob go home?
You can't just run our lives
in your sick head.
Do you know what really
doesn't suit you?
- When you feel sorry for yourself.
- Don't talk to me like that.
But I don't understand
what you're talking about!
What have I done wrong, Helene?
Can't you tell me what
I've done wrong?
I've made a deal with Jacob.
You should be happy.
If you're so bored,
get another job or a hobby.
Instead of going around
making my life hell.
Fine, as long as I get peace.
Helene!
I must admit it got a little wet.
- I hope I didn't scare you.
- It takes more than that.
- How about a drink?
- It's a little early.
I've changed the plans a little,
so it will take a few more days.
Why? I can't do that.
I need to be back in two days.
Listen.
Instead of an annual donation...
I've talked to my advisors
about establishing a fund.
It means something to all of us
that you're Anna's biological father.
So I'm establishing the fund
in Anna's and your name.
You two will decide
how the money is spent.
So you've chosen my project?
- I just said that.
- And you want me to do it with Anna?
Yes, why not? She has shown
a great interest in aid work.
My advisors have gone through
everything and agree
that a sum of 12 million
dollars is realistic.
- 12 million dollars?
- I know the dollar is low.
All kidding aside.
You can quickly see
that it will cover a whole year
for 65,000 children.
Including room, board,
school and administration.
65,000 children.
That's more than are born
in Denmark in a year.
Think of what that money could do.
You could really do something.
- What do you get out of this?
- Nothing. I keep my good life.
I buy remission for my sins.
And we're almost family.
- Why are you doing this?
- I'm assuming you're interested.
Yes, damn it.
Of course I'm interested.
Jacob, stay here.
You'll get to know Anna better.
You could take out Helene for dinner.
I'm going to to Sweden
with the twins. We're going fishing.
You're a strange man, Jorgen.
She has to eat.
She's a terrible cook.
- Take care of yourselves, okay?
- We will, Mother.
- Don't lose too much online.
- I won 235 dollars last night.
Congratulations.
Try and hang on to them.
- Mom did it up wrong.
- We can't have that.
There. Hop inside.
Thanks.
I want to come with you.
No, out of the question.
You don't want to, Helene.
It's sons and their father in the woods.
Or else they'll turn out gay.
Promise to use a life vest and
water wings. And the boys too.
- Bye bye!
- Bye.
- Can we talk?
- What do you want to talk about?
- We could start with Jorgen?
- Stop already.
Listen. Can I come in?
Thanks.
- So talk about Jorgen.
- Can we sit down?
We could find a chair.
This is fine. May I sit here?
Okay...
Did you know Jorgen asked me
to administer a fund?
- No. What fund?
- It's aid work. With Anna.
- You'll run it with Anna?
- With Anna.
It's a very generous offer,
but he's dragging things out.
I want to know what's going on.
If it's one of your games,
I want it to stop.
Stop being paranoid. You don't have
to be poor to have good intentions.
There are people
with money and ideals.
- Really? I'd like to meet one.
- Hello, Jacob.
Give me a break.
You never had any ideals.
I could be rude about your ideals
and we could go on and on.
- We could go on being rude...
- Then tell me what he wants.
He doesn't care about the orphanage
or humanitarian work.
It's bad business.
What does he want?
I don't know what he wants to do
with the orphanage and Anna.
I don't understand it, Jacob.
Then let me ask you a different way:
Do you know something I don't?
No, Jacob, I know nothing.
That's all I wanted to know.
- May I offer you a cup of coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Dare I offer you a glass of wine?
- Only if you've got enough.
Right.
Dare I ask how you've been?
The last twenty years?
They've been a bit up and down.
And you?
I've been fine.
Also a bit hectic.
- I just got a daughter.
- Congratulations.
- Do you have a wife?
- No.
- You haven't married?
A girlfriend?
No.
- Is it rude of me to ask?
- No, no.
- Why don't I get that wine?
- Good idea.
When I went home,
I thought you would follow me.
I thought so too.
I thought you would come back.
You did?
But we didn't.
We should go to lndia.
- Why?
- It's warm.
They've got good hotels.
Stop it.
Why?
Look at this apartment. We're lying
on a mattress. There's lots to do.
- It doesn't matter.
- It does.
- And we're going to Val d'lsere.
- We can go there, but not lndia?
Give me a break.
Ever since you met
your real, holy father
you've been really
irritating to be with.
What about us? It's always
Jacob, Jacob, Jacob, all the time.
You can't change things now, Anna.
Hello.
Why are you sitting here?
Sweetheart!
It's lovely to see you.
- I can't stand it when we fight.
- Me neither.
But we need to talk
about this properly.
- Yes.
- Like grown-ups.
- Of course, sweetie.
- So stop calling me sweetie.
- What can I call you then?
- You could call me Anna.
Okay.
Did you marry Jorgen for my sake?
So that I had a father?
No.
I love Jorgen.
Do you?
A lot.
So everything with Jacob
was a mistake?
- No.
- What was it then?
I was very in love with Jacob,
but I was also very unhappy.
About what?
About being in love with him.
We just hurt each other all the time.
When you told me
Jorgen wasn't my father-
why didn't you say Jacob was?
Maybe because...
because I wanted to forget him.
Did you?
Well... I thought so.
- Who drove off last night?
- It was Jacob.
I thought Johannes drove him,
but he couldn't have.
- Jorgen lent him to Jacob.
- He never lends out Johannes.
He did to Jacob.
It seems he is giving it all
to that Jacob.
Helene Hansson. I'd like to speak
to Doctor Phillipsen.
Remember to lie.
How big was it?
You have to agree or she won't
believe it... Good, off you go.
- We caught one that was this big.
- No way!
It's true, but it got away.
I have to go to town.
Jorgen?
Won't you stay for lunch?
We ate on the way.
I'll be home in a few hours.
- Jorgen? I spoke to Doctor Phillipsen.
- Yes.
Phillipsen's under confidentiality.
That's totally unacceptable.
He promised me.
He's betrayed my trust.
You had promised him to tell me
after the wedding, right?
You've known for five months.
I want to let it be for now, Helene.
You don't have the time.
What will you do?
Anna and the boys must not know
before it's absolutely necessary.
Are you listening?
Not before it's absolutely necessary.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
We'll figure something out.
There's always a solution.
There's always something
in America...
- There's nothing to do.
- Yes, there is.
There's nothing to do!
- There's...
- No!
- There's nothing to do, understand?
- You can't die!
We don't get to decide, damn it.
Let go. Get out.
Get out of the damn car
before I throw you out!
Shut the door!
How long will you stay there?
So, here you are.
Please excuse the formalities.
You only need to read
the last three pages.
Did Helene invite you
to my birthday?
- No.
- You can't rely on her.
- Then I better do it.
- Thanks.
There are a few things I don't
understand. Can we look at it?
What does that mean?
It means that you and Anna have
100% control of the fund.
No, not that. Here it is.
The part where it says
I have to live in Denmark.
Yes, we haven't talked about that yet.
To build an organization like that
you have to live in Denmark.
Can't I just come to board meetings?
No, it's a demand on my behalf.
Why should I do that?
Because I said
it's a demand on my behalf.
You mean that? I can't spend half
a year here and half a year there?
Have I said anything I don't mean?
Maybe everyone else
kisses your ass, but I won't.
- What do you mean?
- You've lost your mind. What is that?
Is that why I came? To meet Anna
and see Helene? You want to buy me?
- I don't want to buy you.
- That's what it says here.
Fine, then let's say that.
Think of what you could do
with the money.
How many you could help.
Wouldn't you sell yourself for that?
- Come on. I know you would.
- You don't know shit about me.
I know all about you.
You're a good person.
Naive, but well-intentioned.
Except for some water projects
and some schools in Bangalore
not one of your projects has
succeeded in the last 15 years.
You're good at finding people to help,
but not at financing it.
- You've been checking me out?
- Your orphanage has to close.
All your sweet little kids
will be on the street again.
You fat pig.
Is it fun playing God,
you big, fat pig? It's not true.
I'm just saying that
you're lying to yourself.
You're an idiot
if you don't take this chance.
You can kiss my ass, Jorgen.
- Jacob, wait.
- I don't want to talk to you.
You're right, Jacob.
Don't touch me!
I don't have time for this.
I am sick, damn it!
I'm the one that is out of time.
Jacob, I am dying.
You have to stay and do
what we have decided.
- Nothing has been decided.
- Anna will need you.
And Helene...
And the boys...
They're so young, Jacob.
Look at me, Jacob!
Don't you see that
there is a point to all of this?
You have a responsibility here, Jacob.
Do I have to live on the other
side of the world to get your help?
Hi, Anna. It's Jacob.
Would you please call me?
I need to speak to you.
Call as soon as you can.
I'm leaving now. I have to go
take care of my hubby.
Is something wrong?
- Can I sleep here?
- Yes, of course.
Anna, what happened?
There.
Hi, sweetheart.
- Are you managing?
- I'm okay.
He's been calling all morning.
- I don't ever want to talk to him.
- No.
- Would you like some breakfast?
- No, thanks.
- I need some breakfast.
- Yes, you do.
- Want anything?
- A glass of juice maybe.
What a little asshole.
What a stupid little boy.
- Thank you for coming.
- Of course I came.
I'll get a room though,
so I don't have to commute.
I brought my teddy bear pajamas,
some cookies and a glass of water-
sloshing about in my bag.
I haven't been in Copenhagen this often
since university.
I delivered papers.
- You did?
- I sold flowers pretending to be blind.
Helene, you have to tell her.
Jorgen doesn't want us to.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Here comes breakfast.
It turns out I was hungry after all.
May I see?
You look so beautiful.
You're so lovely.
Yes, you are.
And you're so soft.
And you smell so nice.
I forgot your juice.
That's all we needed.
That dumb juice.
I'm sorry...
There. Jacob.
Right there.
- There.
- Thank you.
Jorgen, here you go.
Thanks.
Does anyone have a pen?
Anna signed yesterday,
so now I'm a poor man.
Almost.
- Your daughter is here.
- Anna?
Then show her in.
- Well, thank you for your time.
- You're leaving and she's coming?
I don't think she came
to talk to me.
- I didn't expect her to come today.
- Me neither.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
He had to hurry to the bank.
- Hi. Good to see you.
- Hi, Anna.
I didn't think you were
coming today.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why haven't you told me yourself?
Why do you keep lying to me?
Sorry, Anna...
I didn't want to make you sad.
Did you think I wouldn't be sad
if you just died one day?
- No...
- What?
I didn't want you to see me...
as a dead man before I was.
I wanted us to be together as much
as possible before anyone knew.
If I knew you were dying, I wouldn't
spend my time doing other stuff.
And I want you to tell me
these things.
I want you to tell me.
Anna, you mustn't cry now.
It will hurt...
but it will pass,
just like everything else.
And now Jacob will be with you.
I don't care about Jacob.
You're my father and you
didn't tell me you're dying.
I don't want anyone but you.
If you don't tell me you're dying,
I can't say the things I want to say.
To say that...
I love you...
and that I don't want you to die...
and lots of other things...
Come over here.
I love you.
Shouldn't you hurry up?
They'll be here soon.
You look great.
Thank you.
There, come on.
- Are you still up?
- It's skateboarding.
Is it skateboarding?
Is it exciting?
- Move!
- It's really exciting.
Move!
Then you have to go to bed
in half an hour.
Sleep tight.
Jorgen was a diplomat,
so he was sent down there.
He sat down in the chair
and he didn't say a word.
Finally Baunsgaard asks,
will they do it by 3
or will we have to pay overtime?
Jorgen said, you won't have
to pay overtime at least.
I just fired all 42 of them.
This story gets better and better.
Last time it was 32.
I don't know the cost in dollars and
cents, but we almost went bankrupt.
But we had integrity.
Integrity, Jorgen.
- And cheers to that, Jorgen.
- Thanks.
Cheers.
- You're not drinking much tonight.
- I probably shouldn't get drunk.
I'll just start crying.
I feel obliged to say thank you
for all the kind words.
Now I'm not the type that likes
to hear my own voice
in such a well filled room.
But I am turning 48 after all.
And there was so much I didn't
manage to say when I turned 40...
and much has happened since,
so I think it's reasonable
that I be allowed to steal
ten minutes of your precious time.
Because it is. Time is precious.
The years have taught me that.
Helene...
I could stand here and brag
about you for hours.
But don't worry.
I know you don't want me to.
But I will say, that even though
you can't always feel it
I am extremely happy
that you're with me.
You are night and day,
the heaven and the seas for me.
The time I'm with you
and our wonderful children
confirms exactly
what I would have said.
Every acquaintance,
every friend, every person
who has a place in your heart...
It is the time with them
that really means something.
Nothing else matters.
Apart from the firm, of course.
We've expanded a lot recently.
We will continue to,
far into the future, I hope.
Already today, cranes stand
in London, New York and Singapore.
It shouldn't be long before
we can sleep in our own buildings
when we visit
Houston and Manila...
I'll anticipate things a little
and invite you all to the opening
of our new headquarters in Singapore
on January 5th next year.
I'm sure my ten minutes are up,
but I am very grateful to you
for wanting to spend
the day with me.
And I would like to propose
a toast to the future. Cheers!
Jorgen?
I talked to the boys' teacher
about separating them
after the holidays
and moving Morten
into a different class.
It sounded quite reasonable.
Because they're more...
There are not so many cliques and...
- Why are you telling me?
- Would you like a glass of water?
Helene, come here.
Why are you telling me this?
Because we have to decide.
You don't need me anymore, Helene.
Everything is taken
care of now, right?
Anna and the boys...
I'll just slow you all down.
- Stop.
- No.
I'm the only one stopping for now.
I just mean...
Do you think you and Jacob
will get together? Do you?
Stop it.
I would like to know.
I just didn't want...
you to see me... Iike this.
This is only the beginning, Helene.
It will get worse from now on.
- Can you manage?
- Yes.
I'm so damned pathetic...
I don't want to...
I don't want to die!
I don't, Helene.
I don't want to, damn it!
I don't want to die!
I don't!
Damn it!
God damn it!
I don't want to!
I don't want to die, Helene.
Why...?
Praise be to God,
our Lord Jesus Christ
who by his great mercy
has granted us hope
in the resurrection of Jesus Christ
from the dead.
Jorgen Lennart Hansson...
we commit your body to the ground.
Ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
And to dust thou shalt return.
Goodbye, Dad.
Then go.