Happy Thanksgiving!
- Here!
- Right here!
Here you go, fellas!
Come! Come here.
This is the problem.
This is what's wrong with America.
It's gotten so big
you just can't find your way.
The grocery store
on the corner is a now a supermarket.
The candy store
is a MacDonald's.
And this place...
a super fucking discount store.
Where's the pride of ownership?
Where's the personal service?
See what I mean?
Shit...
What right do they have
of cutting out the suppliers?
Pushing out all the middlemen.
Buying direct from the manufacturer.
Sony this.
Toshiba that.
All them Chinks...
put Americans out of work.
...plans to take place
in Quang Tri Province.
From Laos...
That's the way it is now.
You're all right ?
You can't find the heart of anything...
to stick the knife.
Anybody here?
- Can I help you?
- Call an ambulance.
Forget it, Frank.
There's no one in charge.
Call an ambulance!
Some say Bumpy Johnson
was a great man,
according to eulogies,
a giving man.
A man of the people.
No one chose to use
in remembrances
the word most often associated
with Ellsworth Bumpy Johnson :
Gangster,
whose passing has brought
a Who's Who of mourners
on this chilly afternoon.
The KC mob boss,
Dominic Cattano.
Harlem crime figure,
Nicky Barnes.
From the political arena,
the Governor has come down.
The Mayor of New York,
the Chief of Police and Commissioner.
Sports and entertainment luminaries.
Bumpy Johnson,
age 62 when he passed
was a folk hero among Harlem locals
for over four decades.
Regarded by some as
the Robin Hood of Harlem,
by others as a ruthless criminal.
I would've thought that Warnfield
put out a better spread.
- Want some ?
- No, thanks.
I want chicken wings on mine.
Who is that ?
He didn't know what hit him.
I just kept poppin'
him in the face.
You got a light?
That's very good.
Hey, Frank !
Get me a light while you're at it.
Appreciate it.
Don Cattano.
How you doing, Rossi?
- Good.
- A drink, Sir?
Give him a scotch.
Come on.
I know you're hurting, Frank.
So am I.
I'm all right.
- You going to be all right?
- Yeah.
I'm sure Bumpy didn't tell you,
but he made me promise
if anything happened to him...
I should make sure
that you're want for nothing.
I appreciate that.
Half the people here
owed Bumpy money when he died.
They think I'll forget to collect,
but I'll get that money.
Well... that's the spirit.
Go get them.
Mr. Roberts!
Taking the prosecution side,
give us U.S. vs. Meade,
subject, issues,
what the determination was
and what it means to us today.
Class shall be critiquing,
Mr. Roberts, so pay attention.
I hate hearing my name,
ya know ?
Means I gotta get up
in front of the class,
I gotta turn around,
and I know everyone in there,
they know more than I do.
The N1 fear of people...
it ain't dying.
It's public speaking.
I get physically ill.
Wanna throw up.
And you wanna do that
for a living.
I don't like being like that.
I want to beat it.
- Should I do this?
- No, he'll take it from me.
He knows me since high shool.
- High school?
- Good morning.
He doesn't take it, just throw it in.
- That's good service.
- Throw it in?
- What's up, Suzie?
- Hi, Jay.
- How you doing, baby?
- All right.
You, punk !
You bit me, asshole !
I swear to God, Richie.
I didn't know it was you.
I'd never slam a door
on your hand, knowingly.
You bit my fucking hand.
What you doing
serving subpoenas anyway?
- We're on loan to County.
- County?
- How's that working for you?
- Fuck you.
I'm sorry.
Consider me served.
Can we leave it there?
Assault on a police officer?
I don't think so.
For old time's sake, what can we do,
what do you want, what can I give you?
What do you get for assault
with a deadly weapon, Jay?
- 5 years minimum.
- 5 years.
Guys, c'mon ! No.
Guys, what do you want?
Who do you want?
- Who do you got ?
- You want...
Big Al's bookie, his accountant?
I'll give him to you.
Stop, stop.
There he is.
That's him. The bookie.
All right. Get lost.
- Right here?
- Right here. Get out of the car.
- This is nuts.
- Come on.
Let's go.
Take it easy.
We stay with him or the car?
Let's see who comes for the car.
Think he made us?
You called in a warrant, right?
So where are they?
I just called, man!
I called and walked back here,
and ten seconds has gone by.
We saw him with the slips, Jay.
You saw policy slips?
You saw grocery bags.
- You don't know what's in them.
- I do, and so do you.
Don't give me that bull.
What's the rush, Richie?
- Half an hour, the warrant'll be here.
- I got night school.
Guess you're gonna miss it.
- Fuck this. Come on!
- You sure?
Yeah, let's go.
Fuck!
- It's not just a couple of bucks.
- It's the same thing, in principle.
We're talking principles?
A cop who turns in
this kind of money...
says one thing.
He turns in cops who take money.
- We'll be fucking pariahs.
- We're fucked both ways.
Not if we keep it. Only if we don't,
then right, we're fucked,
but not if we keep it.
Goddamn it, man!
Did we ask for it?
Did we put a gun to someone's head
and say : "Give us your money"?
Cops... kill cops
they can't trust.
We can't turn it in, man.
You believe that?
How much is there?
Nine hundred
and eighty seven thousand.
What happened to the rest?
What the hell are you doing counting it
in front of everybody. Are you nuts?
Get it back in the bags, seal'em up,
and down it to the property room.
Fucking boy-scouts.
So nice to see you here this evening.
What?
Detective Trupo.
Sign here.
You guys ready
to make a lot of fuckin money?
- Always.
- Hell yeah.
Here you go!
All right. Look at this.
- Fucking dealers.
- Here's three more boats.
Hey, don't lose any of that shit.
- I know.
- Be careful.
Just enough for the reagent test.
A little less.
This is the French Connection dope.
Kilos of the same dope Eddie Egan
and Sonny Grasso took from us!
The cops seize it, arrest everyone,
and they start taking it out
of the evidence room,
whacking it down to nothing
and selling it back to us.
They basically
control the market with it.
Mr. Rossi.
A surprise.
They've been doin this for years.
They live off it.
- Our dope.
- Many thanks.
What the fuck is happening
to the world, Frank?
Fuckin crooks.
Sad about Bumpy.
Things are never gonna be the same
in Harlem.
You walk down the street.
Nobody bothers you
cause Bumpy was making sure of it.
Here, Frankie.
How is it there now?
It's chaos.
Every gorilla for himself.
Who can live like that?
There has to be order.
That would've never happened
with Italians.
More important than
any one man's life...
is order.
Frank.
Come on in.
Sit down.
- How y'all doin?
- Good.
- So, you seen Nate over there?
- Yeah, all the time.
Nate is everywhere.
- He's good.
- He's still over there.
Got himself a club now.
Where, Saigon?
Bangkok.
I don't think he's ever comin home.
Come on.
On the house
for our boys in uniform.
Thank you, sugar,
that's very kind.
Thank Frank.
Thanks, Frank.
Just relax.
You gonna have to boot this,
shoot a couple times.
Cops keep cutting it.
Selling the shit.
I won't say anything
cause the price is right.
But that shit in Nam
is way...
way...
heavy...
Didn't you see the jar, Frank?
I think you walked right past it.
The money jar.
What I gotta do?
Put a fuckin sign on it?
What are you thinking?
You know,
Bumpy don't own 116th no more.
He don't own no real estate
in Harlem right now. I'm the landlord,
and the lease is 20 %.
Well, don't sell dope then, Frank.
Get a real job.
Need a fuckin job, Frank?
Is that what you need?
You come work for me.
You can drive me around.
You open my doors.
Yes sir, no sir, right away sir.
Anything you want, Master Johnson.
20 %.
20 % is my profit, Tango.
I give you that, what do I got left?
Nothing.
20 % puts me and everyone you know
out of business.
There are legitimate ways
of doing things,
and there's this way.
Not even Bumpy took 20 %.
Bumpy's fuckin dead.
My man.
20 %?
20 %.
Doc! Let's go.
The drug problem in Vietnam
is more
than marijuana.
At this point,
it is estimated that one third
of American troops are experimenting
with opium and heroin.
The authorities say they've confiscated
large quantities of marijuana,
heroin, and pills.
Every person and every vehicle
going through the gates
is subject to a thorough shakedown.
Soldiers have access to the drugs
at many rest and relaxation spots
in Bangkok, Saigon, and other areas
throughout Vietnam and Thailand.
Officials say the easy availability
of relatively cheap cost
of high purity heroin
throughout Saigon and the Far East
is leading to an epidemic
of heroin addiction
among U.S. soldiers.
- Operator.
- Yeah, international.
- What city?
- Bangkok.
You know the country code?
Yeah, 376.
- For the first 3 minutes, it'll...
- I got it, I got it.
- Sawadeekap.
- Hello?
"Soul brothers".
Can I help you?
Nate!
- Do I know you?
- It's me.
- Who?
- Me, Frank! Your cousin, negro.
Go get yourself a new suit.
Look, I'm sorry.
Please, Richie.
Couldn't be avoided.
I'll take him next weekend, OK?
We're moving.
What? Where?
The St. Regis.
What do you care?
My sister's.
Your sister's. In Vegas?
- Yeah.
- You're not moving to Las Vegas.
Not with Michael.
What am I supposed to do with him?
Leave him with you?
There's a picture.
Hey, guys!
Be cool.
Laurie, Las Vegas
is not the kind of place
to raise a kid.
Oh, like this is a good environment?
And around your friends?
When am I supposed to see my boy?
This weekend, last weekeend.
I asked you nice to shut up, right?
Now I'll have to kill you.
I swear
I'll pull out my gun
and put a bullet in your fuckin head!
Stop what you're doin,
and pick up the glass!
Calm down, man. Be cool.
He's fuckin crazy.
You don't have a gun.
You sure?
You're crazy, Richie.
You don't have room for us.
I'll see you in court.
Come on, Michael!
Say bye to your dad.
Hey, kiddo!
See you next week.
We'll do something.
Let's get you an ice cream.
You have 10 minutes remaining.
10 minutes.
Girl, don't talk.
I wanna do a little funk.
How much you want?
Tell him I want a 100 kis.
Ain't nobody I know
who can get you that much.
You have to piece it together
from different sources.
And it's not gonna be 100 % pure.
I don't want that.
I know what you don't want.
But you'll need to get
to the Chi-Chou syndicate, all right?
In Cholon, Saigon.
If they'll deal with you at all.
I understand, but
by then, it'll be too late.
It'll be already chopped up.
I want to get it where they get it from.
The source.
- And get it yourself?
- Why not?
I came this far.
- You'd go into the motherfuckin jungle?
- I'm in it. Look around,
They're eating these roaches,
whatever that is.
Nigga, I'm talking about snakes.
Tigers, Vietcongs, mosquitos
that'll fuckin kill your ass.
- You wanna go into the jungle?
- We're going.
- Fuck it, let's go.
Why not?
Hey, Frank.
This whole spot's locked down
by the Kuomintang.
General Chang Kai Chek's
defeated army.
How would you get it into the States?
You ain't got to worry about that.
- Who do you work for in there?
- Don't worry about that either.
Who are you really?
Frank Lucas,
like it says on my passport.
- I mean, who you represent?
- Me.
You think you're going to take
a 100 kilos of heroin into the U.S.
and you don't work for anyone?
Someone's going to allow that?
That's right.
After this first purchase...
if you're not killed
by Marseilles importers...
or their people in the States...
then, what?
Then there'll be more, much more.
I guarantee you.
And if it's all the same to you, I don't
have to drag my ass here no more.
Of course not.
My man.
- Soul brothers?
- Soul brothers.
Fifty grand. It'll cover them,
the pilot and the boys on the other end.
Give them a hundred.
Fifty will cover it.
Give them a hundred, the whole thing.
And look.
That's all I got.
If that dope don't arrive,
for any reason...
Listen.
Cousin or no cousin,
I'm a busy man, all right?
I got no time to go
to nobody's funeral.
I'll let you know
when it's in the air.
My man.
Richie?
Fuckin guy made me,
don't know how he did,
but he did.
He went for his gun!
I had to do it, man!
A hundred people out there heard
the shot. You gotta help me,
you gotta do something!
Where are you, Jay?
That's the problem.
Dispatch, I got a 10-13.
I got a 10-13.
Copy that. What's your 20?
Tower 2.
Floor 1G.
Canton West, in the projects.
- Identify yourself, please.
- Detective Richard Roberts.
Negative, I got no units in that area.
Bullshit.
Please put the call out again.
I'll need assistance.
Det. Roberts, I got no units
in that area, that's a negative.
Why you goin' thru, motherfucker?
Be cool!
Be cool, all right?
I'll find out what's going on in here.
Richie.
Open the motherfuckin door!
Where's your backup ?
You got no backup?
Why is that?
Bandage his neck.
- Richie, he's dead.
- I know he's fuckin dead, right?
Bandage his neck, clean up his head.
Prop him up on the gurney
so he's sittin,
and open his fuckin eyes.
- All right? Let's go!
- Fuck.
OK, clean him up.
Give me your gun.
Your gun!
You have your badge?
You guys ready?
Just keep moving forward.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
It's OK!
Injured man coming out.
Step back.
Let them do their job.
He'll be all right.
Step back.
That's fine.
That's it.
He's alive.
What happened inside?
Thanks, man.
Fuck.
The asshole pulled a piece on me.
Can you fuckin believe it?
He pulls a piece on a cop?
Had to do it, man.
Kill or be killed.
Fuckin crazy world, right?
What the fuck were you doing
on the projects?
Investigating stuff, man,
you know.
Just like you taught me.
Checking on guys,
following things up,
putting the pieces together.
The guy was a fucking dealer.
Scum of the earth!
That guy
didn't pull a gun on a cop, Jay.
That guy pulled a gun on a junkie.
The junkie was trying to rob him.
What the fuck you sayin?
What the fuck you doin, man?
- What the fuck is that?
- That money's mine, man!
I earned this shit!
It's mine!
I earned it doing good cop work.
- I got it doin good cop work!
- You murdered him!
- And gettin shot at!
- You murdered the guy!
You murdered him,
you robbed his money,
then you called me to get you out.
Makes me an accessory after the fact.
I'll tell you the facts,
just write the report
the way i see it happened.
And then that's the way it is.
And that's how it'll all be.
I can't do that.
I'm a leper because I listened to you
and turned in a million bucks.
No one will work with me after that.
I can give up this shit, Richie!
That's easy.
Just write the report.
Between us.
As partners.
I can't do that.
Stop!
Open the trunk.
Get out!
Get out of Vietnam!
As loud as we can
that the Vietnam war should stop,
and that the best way to stop it
is for the United States
to simply pack up
and get out of Vietnam right now!
How are we looking?
Typically what I see
is 25 to 45 % pure.
There are no adulterants, no alkaloids,
no dilutents.
It's a hundred percent.
- May I?
- Take it with you.
Thank you, Frank.
I'll take it.
No contingencies, no loan,
no nothing.
Cash.
Fabulous.
Im not talking
about your proclivities.
Those I only know too well.
Im talking about being a cop.
You talking about taking money?
I don't do that.
Not my thing.
And your friends from the hood,
still hang out with them?
Yeah. Play baseball on the weekends.
Wise guys?
It's gonna look good.
Guys I went to school with, so what?
What about Joseph Sadano?
What about him?
Im just trying to understand
things your wife has said.
- If they're not true, tell me.
- Yeah, hes one of them.
Is he also your sons godfather?
He's definitely fucking her.
Do you really care about this?
Or do you just not want her
to win ever?
You know there's an interview room?
On the second floor.
- That's what I thought.
- Door locks from the inside.
All rise!
Fuck me like a cop, not a lawyer.
Don't answer!
- Richie Roberts.
- Hey, Norm!
- Hi, Det. Norman Riley.
- Hi, Norman. How are you?
- Good.
- Is that him?
- Yeah.
Nice night to come out, huh?
It's like Grand Central around here.
It's been like this.
I'm lucky if I get home by midnight.
It's like nothing we've seen before.
Something I gotta sign?
Yeah, this way.
I'm taking this with me.
I'll register it, all right?
America's public enemy number one
in the United States
is drug abuse.
In order
to fight and defeat this ennemy,
It is necessary to wage
a new all out offensive.
Federal authorities
have announced their intention
to establish special
narcotics bureaus in Washington
New York, Los Angeles, Chicago...
A detective without the support
of his fellow detectives
really can't do much.
You know why I don't have it.
Doesn't matter.
You do what you have to do.
The greatest city in the world
is turning into an open sewer.
Everybody's stealing.
Dealing.
You can't work
because you did your job!
Good news is you're not
the only honest cop in town.
This special narcotics bureau
in Washington
is not a dog and pony show.
They're sincere.
I know it because
they want us to orchestrate it
and I want you
to head up things here on our end.
If it's federal,
who do I answer to?
- Post office?
- You answer to me.
Me and the U.S. Attorney,
nobody else.
You never step foot
in a police station again,
work out at your own place.
You pick your own guys,
Guys that you know wouldnt
take a nickel off the sidewalk.
- Huey.
- Huey!
- What of what?
- Who's this?
Who you think, boy?
- Frank!
- Frank who?
Your brother, negro.
- That's right.
- Marvin!
- Where's Ma?
- What?
Where's...
Frank's on the phone!
How you doin, Frankie?
Frank, on the phone!
- Say what?
- Ma, Frank on the phone!
Oh, my Lord!
Yo, when?
You just say it, man.
I'll call you back
at 6 o'clock.
Get everybody together, all right?
Mama, everybody.
How you doin, Uncle Frank?
Get out of the car!
It's here.
Look at this!
My Lord!
So glad to see you, boy.
I'm telling you,
some piece of land you got here.
- I wonder what the Boro people'd say.
- And whose house is that?
That is your house, Mama.
- Mine?
- That's yours.
And who else?
Listen!
I wanna tell you how happy I am.
Seeing all my children at the table,
and the grand children
at the same time.
I'm so happy!
- Right on, Grandma!
- Enjoy yourselves.
I hope you got a job,
the way you eatin all this.
That boy, he got an arm on him.
A Major League arm.
- Oh yeah?
- Right?
Right on, Pop.
After dinner,
let's see him throw around a bit.
You can't catch him, man.
I'm telling you,
he throws harder than Gibson.
We're talking 95 miles an hour.
Can you catch him?
He'd go catch the grass.
He might have catched that thing
when I was about 5 years old.
Since then, he can't keep up.
This is your room.
Perfect.
Look at this.
It's beautiful.
Real beautiful, this.
How did you...
I had it made.
From memory.
You were 5 when they took it away.
- Right.
- How could you...
How could I forget, Mamma?
I thought you did.
It, it... is perfect.
It's all perfect.
I can't tell you
how much I love you.
I love you too, Mother.
It's okay.
Both these guys, good with wires.
They got solid informants.
They're honest.
And fearless.
They're insane, Richie,
like you.
Where are they?
That's Jones,
with the skinny white broad.
Best I've ever seen on the street.
He knows dope,
but he's together.
He's a stand up guy, all around.
That's Abruzzo
with the two black fat ones.
He loves a big ass, man.
He's a bulldog.
He don't fuck around,
he got a bit of a temper yeah, but,
you could trust this guy
with your grandma.
Listen.
We work together. You want me,
you got to take them, too.
When do we start?
The man I worked for
ran one of the biggest companies
in New York City for more than 50 years.
15 years,
8 months and 9 days
I was with him every day,
protected him, looked after him.
I learned from him.
Bumpy was rich,
but wasn't white man rich.
He wasn't wealthy.
He didnt own his own company.
He thought he did.
He just managed it.
White men owned it,
so they owned him.
Nobody owns me though.
- How you doin, babe?
- Good.
Cause I own my own company,
and my company sells a product
thats better than the competitions.
At a price thats lower
than the competitions.
What are we selling here?
How you doin, Red?
My brothers,
just got here from North Carolina,
Guys, this is Redtop.
- How you doin?
- And the ladies.
Nice family.
What? Ya'll niggas
never seen hoochie before?
Why they all naked?
So they can steal nothin.
Most important thing in business
is honesty.
Integrity, hard work.
Family.
Never forgetting
where we came from.
Thank you, Charlene.
See, you are what you are
in this world.
That's either one of two things.
Either you're somebody.
Or nobody.
I'll be right back.
I need this fresh,
cause if I come back here,
you'll know what it is.
- You don't play that.
- I hear you,
you won't have to come back.
There will be no problem.
Where's my money?
Redtop gave you the package,
you supposed to hand me my money.
Here's a jar right here.
20 %.
- You got the jar?
- That's right.
Get the fuck outa here...
What you gonna do?
What the fuck you gonna do?
What you doin?
You wanna shoot me,
in front of everybody?
Huh? Come on!
Shit.
Here you go.
20 %.
So, what was I sayin?
This is the newly formed
Essex County narcotics squad.
Our mandate is to make major arrests.
No street guys.
We're looking for the suppliers
and the distributors.
Heroin, cocaine, amphetamines.
No grass under 1,000 pounds.
No powder under 40 kilos.
Less than that,
someone else can waste their time.
We'll be handling big shipments,
big money,
and big temptation.
I heard a story about you.
That you found
a million $ in unmarked cash.
And you gave that shit back.
Is that true?
Yeah, I did.
Anyone got a problem with that?
So do I.
I think about it everyday.
I should be down in Florida with
a 68 full cruiser dual, fishing sharks.
- You and me both.
- But you know...
I didn't, so here I am, and...
We'll try to land
some other kinda sharks.
- All right?
- Bingo.
See that?
And this stuff is everyday's stuff.
But this Blue Magic,
twice the potency.
The purest thing
I've ever seen in the street.
Strong enough to smoke.
That's for those suburban
white kids scared of needles.
You paid 10 bucks for that?
And it's everywhere,
on every corner.
So how's that possible?
Who can afford to sell shit
twice as good for half as much?
Hey man, good to see you!
- Doin good?
- Yeah, just got back
from a trip to the south of France.
Know what I'm sayin?
Here you go!
Who is that?
Ladies and gentlemen.
The Proud Bomber, the champ.
Mr. Joe Louis!
Who's that with Joe?
Miss Puerto Rico.
Puerto Rico?
- She a beauty queen.
- Real. The beauty queen.
My main man.
Excuse us for a minute, please.
Sure, Frank.
Thank you.
What's goin on?
What you smiling about?
- I dunno.
- What is this?
What's what?
- What?
- Come here.
What's that you wearin?
What's what?
That, what you got on?
A very, very, very nice suit.
Very, very nice suit, huh?
That's a clown suit,
a costume, man,
with a big sign that says:
"Arrest me".
Understand? You too loud,
you're making too much noise.
Look at me.
The loudest one in the room
is the weakest one in the room,
I tell you that.
- You tryin to be like Nicky Barnes?
- What's the problem with him?
- I like him.
- I got no problem. You like him?
You wanna be like him?
You wanna be Superfly?
You wanna work for him?
Share a jail cell with him?
Cook for him?
- He wants to talk to you.
- So, you talkin to him about me now?
What about?
- It ain't like that.
- Then what is it?
- Your name came up.
- About what?
I don't know, I told him I'd tell you.
You know, boy...
If you wasn't my bro', I'd kill you.
You know that?
I'd blow your fuckin brains out.
- Don't be like that.
- I'm taking you shoppin this week.
- I can do it alone.
- I can tell.
You still owe me that dance.
Doc, come on.
Frank.
Check this.
- How you doing?
- Hi.
- Frank Lucas.
- Eva Jendo.
Nice to meet you, Eva.
Nice to meet you, Frank.
You're Frank,
and this is your place.
That's right, I'm Frank
and this is my place.
Why is it called Small's?
Why not Frank's?
When you own something,
you call it what you want.
Small's.
Or Frank's.
Frankie Small's.
Small's Frankie.
That's right.
You want to let my hand go?
Okay.
You're leaving?
No, I was going to my table.
You need someone to go with you?
Yes?
Wash your hand?
I got one print of that.
You'll smudge it.
- Here you go.
- What about him?
- Who's that?
- Joey Sadano.
Don Cattano's nephew.
- Put him up there by the big man
- He looks like you, Abruzzo.
- Not as handsome.
- Looks more like your sister.
- Where's Ice Pick Paul?
Funny. You guys should
take that show on the road.
So we need...
Ice Pick Paul.
There you go.
He goes near the top.
No, Ice Pick Paul is a soldier,
this guy is a lieutenant.
"...you have passed the
New Jersey Bar Examination."
That guy is a soldier.
This guy's a lieutenant.
No way he's on top.
You're thinking Benny the Bishop.
Benny Two Socks,
- Cattano's deadbeat son-in-law.
- Jonesy's right.
Which one of you has actually seen
Ice Pick Paul selling drugs?
Actually,
- seen it go down?
- Yeah, seen it go down,
been in his place,
seen him handle drugs?
That rat Rickie has told us.
He's fuckin dead!
About 4 weeks ago.
He's dead.
Well, we can take him
off the fuckin board.
I don't think
we got any solid evidence
on anybody on that board.
What you saying?
This is weeks and weeks of work, man.
I say take it down.
We start again from the street.
That's considerably more
than one year's salary.
If it disappears...
we'll not be able
to get it for you again.
That's yours.
Sign on my life for you again?
For a lousy twenty grand?
It has to be Blue Magic, OK?
It's gonna be Blue.
- Pick it up here tomorrow.
- $ 20,000.
Just leave it there.
- How did it go?
- Good.
Here he comes.
- That's him?
- Yeah.
He's quick.
- He goes into the City. What do we do?
- Stay with the fuckin money.
We stay with the money, all right?
- We can't go there!
- Yes, we can.
That's 20 grand in there
that I'm responsible for.
- I ain't losin it, follow the money!
- It's out of our jurisdiction!
- Follow the money!
- All right!
He's pulling over.
All right, here we go.
Let me out here.
- Don't disappear, all right?
- I'll circle the block.
Sit down!
Happy birthday, gentlemen.
How you doin?
You're up to something, huh?
He's going bowling.
Look at that.
Right between the legs.
- What's in the bag?
- Nothing.
Get the fuck up!
- It's my bag.
- Shut the fuck up! What did I tell you?
- Keep your your head down!
- What you doin?
- Sit down and shut up!
- Don't you move!
Hey guys!
Guys! Officers!
I'm Richie Roberts.
Newark.
That's... my money.
What the fuck?
What money?
The bills are sequenced,
they're registered with the Essex
County Prosecutors Office.
Check them up.
They all start with CF3500.
Have a look.
Fucking registers.
I thought I had a fucking Chris-Craft
sitting in my driveway.
Honest mistake.
I'll just get the money.
This time.
When's the last time I was in Jersey?
Let me think.
Never.
Whatre you doing coming over here
unannounced?
You know you can get hurt
doing that?
You got your fucking money.
Richie.
And never ever
come into this city again unannounced.
You come in to see
a fuckin Broadway show?
You call ahead first to see
if its okay with me.
No problem.
- Go hit some ball.
- Great suits.
Is that your car?
Fucking great car.
Have a nice fuckin trip
back to Jersey.
All right.
Come on, I got a tea time.
Let's go.
This is your father?
That's Martin Luther King.
- It is not.
- Yes, it is Martin Luther King.
- You know, "I have a dream".
- Of course.
No, that's...
He was just as important
as Martin Luther King.
- To me.
- What did he do?
A lot of things, he was a...
friend.
Served New York,
New York served him.
He was my boss.
My teacher.
What did he teach you?
He taught me a lot of things. He...
Taught me how to take my time.
That if I was going to do something,
to do it with care, love.
Anything else?
Taught me to be a gentleman.
That's what you are?
That's what I try to be.
Come here.
Come sit here.
Look at me.
I own about five apartments
in Manhattan.
Homes all over the East Coast.
Could've taken you to anyone of'em,
but I didn't.
I brought you here.
- I was looking for you, boy.
- Cause I want you to meet my mother.
How you doin, Ma?
- Is this her?
- Eva,
- this is my mother.
- Hi, Eva.
Nice to meet you.
She's beautiful.
Look at her.
She's an angel
come down from Heaven.
Thank you.
Mr. Roberts.
I'm here for our appointment.
- Morning.
Sorry, our appointment?
Child Social Services.
She did mention your name though.
- The stewardess?
- No, not her.
The lady from Social Services,
she mentioned your name.
Right after she asked me
if I associated with any criminals.
- All right, go!
- You want to see this?
Hey, boys!
Joey!
Get in the pool.
Come on!
How'd she get my name?
Laurie.
She's been saying a lot lately.
A lot.
When you asked me to be
your son's godfather,
- I took it very seriously.
- I know.
And I appreciate that.
And I said yes, I would take on
that responsability
to take care of your son, if God forbid,
something happened to you.
Jo, the things she said
to Child Social Services
make me look really bad.
You know.
All kinds at the house at night time,
low life informants around.
Women...
Old friends like me.
Old friends like you, yeah.
Uncle Joey!
Watch me!
I understand.
They ask me, I'll tell them
what you want me to tell.
- I'll lie for you.
- Don't lie.
You don't have to lie.
Just... omit certain details.
Sure, all right.
I have something else to ask you.
You don't have to answer
if you don't want.
Blue Magic.
Anything?
A lot of sorrow, misery from guys
getting put out of work. That's all.
What, your guys?
His guys.
You know where it's comin from?
Guys down south,
that's all I heard.
- Cubans?
- I dunno.
Or Mexico?
Don't know.
You're telling me
it's from South America?
I don't know!
Whoever it is, they're upsetting
the natural order of things.
That's all there is.
- What's up?
- My man.
How's it lookin?
I want you to meet Mike Sobota.
- How're you doing?
- How're you?
- What can I get you?
- A left hander, Charlie told me
- about your nephew.
- Oh, Mr...
- Yankees.
- Yeah, yeah! Hey, Steve!
- Come here.
- Excuse me.
He's good. Put him in the team.
You're good enough, right?
I'm a Lucas.
Good enough on a bad day.
So don't make it a bad day,
make it a good day, you understand?
Excuse me. Police department.
Now back out, baby.
I'll take your ass in, Jimmy.
You can't take me in for that.
I got a licence for that, motherfucker.
You got a licence for this?
Excuse me, all right?
Shit, all right!
I got to arrest you.
Shit's too good to be on the street.
- What you doin, man?
- You ain't arresting nobody.
You bribing me now?
I tell you what,
I'm arresting everybody. All of you.
You first!
- How can that be?
- What was that?
Get this fuckin...
what's the matter with you?
- What was that?
- What?
- What the hell's wrong with you?
- What's your fuckin problem?
I just shot him in the leg.
Damn, Jimmy!
Get up!
Everybody, get out!
Get out!
- Frank, it was an accident.
- Wasn't no goddamn accident.
He don't feel shit cause he's coked up
all the motherfuckin time!
He's your driver,
get rid of him.
He's your cousin!
He ain't shit to me,
he means nothin.
- What'll he do, go back home?
- I don't give a damn!
Send his ass home!
Don't rub on that.
You'd block that.
You understand?
That's alpaga, $25,000 alpaga.
You'd block that shit.
Don't rub, put club soda on it.
Listen, from now on,
don't nobody talk to me directly,
understand?
You got business with me,
you talk to Huey,
Huey talks to me, got it?
- All right.
- Never on the phone, got it?
And take them
goddamn sunglasses off!
- Take the goddamn sunglasses off!
- Damn it, man!
Simple-minded ass motherfuckers.
The whole place was imported
brick by brick.
Gloucestershire.
- Who?
- Quite famous.
Yours.
Here you go.
Pull!
Come, Eva.
I'm sure you're dying to see
the rest of the house.
Of course. Excuse me.
Thank you for a wonderful lunch.
It was delicious.
What do you think of monopolies?
- You mean, like the game?
- No, I just think
monopolies are made illegal
in the country, Frank,
cause no one wants to compete.
Nobody wants to compete,
not with a monopoly.
Let the dairy farmers do that,
half of them'd
go out of business tomorrow.
- Im just trying to make a living.
- It's your right.
Everybody's right. It's America.
We just can't do it
at the unreasonable expense of others.
Cause it becomes un-American.
That's why the price we pay
for that gallon of milk
never represents the true cost
of production
cause it's gotta be controlled.
It's gotta be set.
It's gotta be fair.
Controlled by who?
I set a price I think is fair.
- I don't think it is.
- You don't?
I don't.
I know your customers
are happy, Frank.
Bunch of fuckin junkies
that they are.
What about your fellow dairy farmers?
Are you thinking of us?
You thinking of them?
The dairy farmers?
I'm thinking of them, Dominic, about
as much as they've thought about me.
I'm just thinking out loud.
If you took some of your inventory,
and you sold it wholesale.
Sit.
We could work.
You could use some distribution.
I dunno, I'm pretty good.
I got 110th to 155th,
river to river, I'm all right.
It's kind of a mom and pop store
next to what Im talking about,
and that's bigger than K-Mart.
I'm talking about L.A.,
Chicago, Detroit, Las Vegas.
Let's go nationwide.
I'm gonna guarantee you
peace of mind here.
You don't want that?
You gonna need it.
I don't know how you feel me.
I'm kind of a Renaissance man.
The people I deal with on a daily basis,
they're not enlightened.
You talk to them about civil rights,
they don't know.
They're not open to change.
Not from the way things are done,
and who's doing it.
I can talk to them,
so there's no misunderstanding.
That's what I mean
by peace of mind.
Here
You're paying what,
75, 80 thousand a kilo?
I'm a Renaissance man too.
I'd consider 50,000.