- USS Kelvin, go for Starfleet base.
- Starfleet Base.
We sent you a transmission.
Did you receive it?
Kelvin, can you double-check
those readings?
Our gravitational sensors are going
crazy here. You should see this.
It looks like a lightning storm.
What you've sent us
doesn't seem possible.
Yes mam, I understand.
That's why we sent it.
- Report.
- Still outta visual range. 20 seconds.
Alert captain Robau that Starfleet
advised to proceed with caution...
Polarize the view screen.
- Whatever this is... Klingon origin?
- Captain, we have visual.
- Repeat. Could this be Klingon?
- Negative, lieutenant.
You're 75000 kilometers
from the Klingon border.
Captain, are you seeing this?
My God.
I have a reading.
They've locked weapons on us!
Red alert!
Torpedo locked on us
at 320'- 2! Arm weapons!
Evasive pattern delta 5!
We're being cut like grass.
Fire all phasers!
Damage report.
Warp drive's been knocked out.
Never seen anything like this.
Weapons offline.
Main power at 38%.
- They're firing another!
- All power to forward shields!
Help me...
maneuver has been lost.
Are shields even on?
decks 17 and 13, we have
confirmed casualties.
11% and dropping. 10%.
Shields at 9%.
All remaining power
to forward shields.
Prepare shuttles
for evacuation.
Hello.
My commander requests
the presence of your captain...
in order to negotiate
a ceasefire.
You will come aboard our ship
via shuttlecraft.
Your refusal would be unwise.
Walk with me.
If I don't report in 15 minutes
evacuate the crew.
- Sir, we could...
- There is no outpost out here.
Use autopilot and get off this ship.
Aye captain.
You're captain now, Mr. Kirk.
His heart rate is elevated.
Look at the ship.
- Are you familiar with this craft?
- Who is your commander?
- Is that him?
- I will speak for captain Nero.
Then ask captain Nero: What gives him
the right to attack a Federation vessel.
Do you know the location of
ambassador Spock?
I'm unfamiliar with
ambassador Spock.
- What is the current star date?
- Star date?
2233.04.
Where are you from?
Terminated.
- Sir, they have a lock on our signal.
- They're launching again.
Bravo 6 maneuver fire, full spread!
I'm initiating general order 13,
we're evacuating!
Sir.
All decks, this is the captain speaking,
evacuate the ship immediately.
Get your... to the shuttlecraft.
Begin evacuating...
- That's George's voice. What's happening?
- We'll deliver it in the shuttle. Go!
- George.
- You're OK, thank God.
I have medical shuttle 37 standing by.
Get to it now. Can you do that?
- Yes.
- Everything's gonna be OK.
- Do exactly as I say, shuttle 37.
- George, it's coming.
- Our baby. It's coming now.
- I'm on my way.
Autopilot function has been destroyed.
Manual operation only.
Clear those decks now! Get to
the shuttles! Move! Move! Move!
- That was a big one!
- Just keep breathing. You'll be fine.
- And the baby too, right?
- And the baby too.
Right here.
Captain to shuttle 37.
Is my wife on board?
- Yes sir, she is.
- I need you to go now. Do you hear me?
- We're waiting on you sir.
- No, just go, take off immediately.
- That's an order.
- Yes sir.
Wait. We're not going yet.
Please stop.
George, the shuttle's leaving.
Where are you?
Sweetheart, listen to me.
I'm not gonna be there.
- No.
- This is the only way you'll survive.
Please don't stay on the ship.
Come to me here.
The shuttles will never make it if I don't
fight them off.
George, I can't do this without you.
OK, I need you to push now!
SYSTEMS FAILING
COLLISION COURSE
ENGAGED
- What is it?
- It's a boy.
A boy?
- Tell me about him.
- He's beautiful.
George, you should be here.
Impact alert.
- What are we gonna call him?
- We can name him after your father.
Tiberius, you kiddin' me?
No, that's the worst.
Let's name him after your dad.
Let's call him Jim.
Jim. OK. Jim it is.
- Sweetheart can you hear me?
- I can hear...
I love you so much.
I love you!
Hey, are you out of your mind?
That car is an antique.
You think you can get away with this
just because your mother's off planet.
You get your ass back home now!
You live in my house buddy.
You live in my house
and that's my car.
You get one scratch on that car
and I'm gonna whip your ass...
Hey Johnny!
Citizen, pull over.
Noooo...!
Is there a problem officer?
Citizen, what is your name?
My name is James Tiberius Kirk.
What is the formula
for the volume of a sphere?
4/3 PI times the radius cubed...
1.26...
What is the dimensionality...
Dimensionality equals the
logarithm of n divided by...
non-excludability
and non-rivalry...
...4/3 PI times the radius...
...is morally praiseworthy
but not morally obligatory.
Spock.
I presume you've prepared
new insults for today?
Affirmative.
This is your 35th attempt to illicit
an emotional response from me.
You're neither Human nor Vulcan and
therefore have no place in this universe.
Look, his Human eyes.
They look sad. Don't they.
Perhaps an emotional response
requires physical stimulae.
He's a traitor you know? Your father.
For marrying her. That Human whore.
They called you a traitor.
Emotions run deep within our race.
In many ways more deeply than in humans.
Logic offers a serenity humans
seldom experience.
The control of feelings...
so that they do not control you.
You suggest that I should be
completely Vulcan?
And yet you married a Human.
As ambassador to Earth it is my duty to
observe
and understand Human behavior.
Marrying your mother was... logical.
Spock.
You are fully capable
of deciding your own destiny.
The question you face is:
Which path will you choose?
This is something only you can decide.
Spock. Come here, let me see you.
- No.
- Spock.
There's no need to be anxious.
You'll do fine.
I am hardly anxious, mother.
And fine has variable definitions,
fine is unacceptable.
Okay.
- May I ask a personal query?
- Anything.
Should I choose to complete the Vulcan
discipline of Kolinahr.
and purge all emotion?
I trust you will not feel it reflects
judgment upon you.
Oh Spock.
As always, whatever you choose to be,
you will have a proud mother.
You have surpassed the expectations
of your instructors.
Your final record is flawless.
With one exception.
I see that you have applied to
Starfleet as well.
It was logical to cultivate more options.
Logical, but unnecessary. You are hereby
accepted to the Vulcan Science Academy.
It is truly remarkable Spock
that you have achieved so much...
despite your disadvantage.
All rise.
If you would clarify, minister?
To what disadvantage are you referring?
Your Human mother.
Council, ministers, I must decline.
No Vulcan has ever declined
admission to this Academy.
But as I am half-human, your
record remains untarnished.
Spock, you have made a commitment
to honor the Vulcan way.
Why did you come before this
council today?
Was it to satisfy your emotional need
to rebel?
The only emotion I wish to convey
is gratitude.
Thank you, ministers,
for your consideration.
Live long and prosper.
- Hi.
- Hey there.
Hi. I'd like a Clabmin fire tea...
3 Budweiser Classics,
2 Cardassian sunrises and...
- Try the Slusho, it's good.
- A Slusho mix, thank you.
That's a lot of drinks for a woman.
- And a shot of Jack, straight up.
- Make that two. Her shot's on me.
Her shot's on her.
Thanks, but no thanks.
Don't you at least wanna know my name
before you completely reject me?
I'm fine without it.
You are fine without it.
It's Jim, Jim Kirk.
If you don't tell me your name,
I'm gonna have to make one up.
- It's Uhura.
- Uhura? No way.
That's the name I was gonna make
up for you.
- Uhura what?
- Just Uhura.
They don't have last names
in your world?
Uhura is my last name.
Well then you have...
your first name's Human?
Excuse me buddy.
So, you're a cadet, your studying.
What's your focus?
Xenolinguistics. You have
no idea what that means.
The study of alien languages.
Morphology, phonology, syntax.
Means you've got a talented tongue.
I'm impressed.
For a moment there, I thought you
were just a dumb-hair colonial
who has sex with farm animals.
Well, not only.
This townie isn't bothering you, right?
Oh, beyond belief.
But it's nothing I can't handle.
You could've handled me.
That's an invitation.
- Hey. You better mind your manners.
- Oh relax cupcake, it was a joke.
Hey farm boy, maybe you can't count.
There are 4 of us and 1 of you.
So get some more guys and then it'll
be an even fight.
Guys. Stop it.
Stop it!
Enough!
Guys, he's had enough.
Outside. All of you.
- Now.
- Yes, sir.
- What...
- I just bought a drink.
You all right, son?
You can whistle really loud,
you know that?
You know I couldn't believe it when
the bartender told me who you are.
- Who the hell am I, captain Pike?
- Your father's son.
Can I get another one?
For my dissertation
I was assigned USS Kelvin.
Something I admired about your dad,
he didn't believe in no-win scenarios.
Sure learned his lesson.
Well that depends
on how you define winning.
- You're here, aren't you?
- Thanks.
You know that instinct to leap without
looking, that was his nature too...
and in my opinion
something Starfleet's lost.
Why are you talking to me man?
Because I looked up your file while
you were drooling on the floor.
Your aptitude tests are off the charts, so
what is it?
You like being the only genius level
repeat-offender in the mid-west?
Maybe I love it.
So your dad dies, you can saddle for
less than an ordinary life.
Or do you feel that you were meant for
something better? Something special?
- Enlist in Starfleet.
- Enlist?
You guys must be way down on your
recruiting quarter for the month.
If you're half the man your father was
Jim,
Starfleet could use you.
You can be an officer in 4 years,
you can have your own ship in 8.
You understand what the Federation is,
don't you? It's important,
It's a peacekeeping and humanitarian
armada.
We done?
I'm done.
Riverside shipyard. Shuttle for new
recruits leaves tomorrow - 08:00.
Your father was captain of a starship
for 12 minutes.
He saved 800 lives, including your
mother's and yours.
I dare you to do better.
Nice ride man.
It's yours.
4 years? I'll do it in 3.
At ease gentlemen.
Never did get that first name.
- You need a doctor.
- I told you people,
I don't need a doctor,
damn it. I am a doctor.
You need to get back
to your seat.
I had one, in the bathroom
with no windows.
I suffer from aviofobia. That means
fear of dying in something that flies.
Sir, for your own safety, sit down
or else I'll make you sit down!
- Fine.
- Thank you.
This is captain Pike, we've been cleared
for takeoff.
I may throw up on you.
- I think these things are pretty safe.
- Don't pander with me kid.
One tiny crack in the hull
and our blood boils in 13 seconds.
A solar flare might crop up,
cook us in our seats.
And while youre sitting pretty
with a case of Andorian shingles,
see if you're still so relaxed
when your eyeballs are bleeding.
Space is disease and danger,
wrapped in darkness and silence.
Well I hate to break this to you,
but Starfleet operates in space.
Yeah, well...
I've got nowhere else to go,
the ex wife took the whole
damn planet in the divorce.
All I've got left is my bones.
- Jim Kirk.
- McCoy. Leonard McCoy.
Three years later.
Captain Nero. You've been
requested on the bridge, sir.
Ayel says it's time.
Sir, we've arrived at the
coordinates we calculated.
There's nothing here. What
are your orders?
We wait.
We wait for the one who allowed
our home to be destroyed.
As we've been doing for 25 years.
- And once we've killed him?
- Kill him?
I'm not gonna kill him.
I gonna make him watch.
Capture that ship.
Welcome back, Spock.
- Why are you so happy?
- I do not know what you're talking about.
- No, I don't suppose you do.
- Hello ladies.
- I'm taking the test again.
- You've got to be kidding.
Yeah, tomorrow morning.
And I want you there.
You know I've got
better things to do...
than watch you embarrass
yourself for the 3rd time.
I am a doctor, Jim. I'm busy.
Bones, it doesn't bother you
that no ones ever passed the test.
Jim, it's Kobayashi Maru.
No one passes the test.
And no one goes back
for seconds, let alone thirds.
I've gotta study.
Study, my ass.
Jim, I think I love you.
- That is so weird.
- Lights.
- Did you just say that is so weird.
- Yeah, I did, but I...
You don't love me too?
Oh, no, my roommate.
I thought you said
she was gone for the night.
Obviously she's not, quick, you
gotta... just get under the bed.
- Under...?
- Look, just get under the bed.
- She can't see you here.
- Why not?
Because I promised her I'd stop
bringing guys back to the dorm.
- Well how... how many guys have y...?
- Just d... just down.
- Hey.
- Hey. How are you?
- Good.
- Strangest thing...
I was in the long range
sensor lab.
Yeah, I...
I thought all night...
I was tracking solar systems and I
picked up an emergency transmission.
- Really?
- Yeah.
From a Klingon prison planet.
- No.
- Yeah.
A Klingon armada
was destroyed, 47 ships.
So, you're not going back
to the lab tonight?
- Gaila, who is he?
- Who's who?
The mouth-breather
hiding under your bed.
- You could hear me breathing?
- You.
- Big day tomorrow.
- You're gonna fail.
- Gail, see you around.
- Get out.
If I pass will you tell me
your first name?
No. Good night.
I think the fact that you picked up
a transmission is very impress...
We're receiving a distress signal
from the USS Kobayashi Maru.
The ship has lost power
and is stranded.
Starfleet command has
ordered us to rescue them.
Starfleet command has ordered
us to rescue them... captain.
Two Klingon vessels have
entered the neutral zone...
and are locking weapons on us.
- That's okay.
- That's okay?
Yeah, don't worry about it.
Did he say
don't worry about it?
Is he not taking
the simulation seriously?
Three more Klingon war birds
decloaking and targeting our ship.
I don't suppose this
is a problem either?
They're firing, captain.
Alert medical bay
to prepare to receive...
all crew members
from the damaged ship.
And how do you expect us
to rescue them...
when we're surrounded
by Klingons... captain?
Alert medical.
Our ship is being hit.
Shields at 60%.
I understand.
Should we,
I don't know, fight back?
- No.
- Of course not.
What is this?
What's going on?
Hm. Arm photons. Prepare to fire
on the Klingon war birds.
- Yes, sir.
- Jim, their shields are still up.
Are they?
- No, they're not.
- Fire on all enemy ships.
One photon each should do
let's not waste ammunition.
Target locked an acquired
on all war birds.
Firing.
All ships destroyed, captain.
Begin rescue
of the stranded crew.
So, we've managed to eliminate
all enemy ships,
no one on board was injured,
and the successful rescue of the
Kobayashi Maru crew is under way.
How the hell did that kid
beat your test?
I do not know.
This session has been called
to resolve a troubling matter.
James T. Kirk, step forward.
Cadet Kirk, evidence has been submitted
to this council,
suggesting that you violated the
ethical code of conduct
pursuing to regulation 17.43
of the Starfleet code.
Is there anything you care to say
before we begin, sir?
Yes. I believe I have the right
to face my accuser directly?
Step forward please.
This is commander Spock. He is one
of our most distinguished graduates.
He's programmed the Kobayashi Maru
exam for the last 4 years.
Commander.
Cadet Kirk, you somehow managed to
install and activate a subroutine...
in the programming code, thereby
changing the conditions of the test.
- Your point being?
- In academic vernacular. You cheated.
Let me ask you something I think
we all know the answer to.
The test itself is a cheat, isn't it?
You programmed it to be unwinnable.
Your argument precludes
the ability of a no-win scenario?
I don't believe
in no-win scenarios.
Then not only did you
violate the rules,
you also failed to understand
the principle lesson.
Please, enlighten me.
You of all people
should know, cadet Kirk,
a captain cannot cheat death.
- I of all people?
- Your father,
Lt. George Kirk assumed command
of his vessel...
before being killed in action,
did he not?
I don't think you like the fact
that I beat your test.
Further more you have failed to
define the purpose of the test.
- Enlighten me again.
- The purpose to experience fear.
Fear in the face of certain death.
To accept that fear
and maintain control of oneself
and one's crew.
This is a quality expected in
every Starfleet captain.
Excuse me, sir.
We've received a distress
call from Vulcan.
With our primary fleet engaged
in the Laurentian system,
I hereby order all cadets to report
to hangar 1 immediately.
Dismissed.
- Who was that pointy-eared bastard?
- I do not know.
But I like him.
Bracer, USS Farragut.
McCoy, USS Enterprise.
McGrath, USS Walcott.
Spader, USS Hood.
Welcome to Starfleet.
Godspeed.
He didn't call my name.
Commander, sir, you didn't call
my name, Kirk, James T.
Kirk, you're on academic suspension,
that means you're grounded
until the academy board rules.
Jim, the board will rule in your favor.
Most likely.
Look Jim, I've gotta go.
Yeah. Yeah, go. Be safe.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah. Yeah. Sorry.
Damn it.
Come with me.
Uhura, USS Farragut.
Petrovsky, USS Antares.
Go to your stations and good luck.
- Bones, where are we going?
- You'll see.
- Commander, a word?
- Yes, lieutenant?
- Was I not one of your top students?
- Indeed you were.
And did I not on multiple
occasions demonstrate...
an exceptional oral
sensitivity, and I quote...
"an unparalleled ability
to identify sonic anomalies...
in subspace transmission tests"?
Consistently, yes.
And while you were well aware
that I'm qualified...
and desire to serve
on the USS Enterprise,
I'm assigned to the Farragut?
It was an attempt to avoid
the appearance of favoritism.
No. I'm assigned
to the Enterprise.
- Yes, I believe you are.
- Thank you.
- What are you doing?
- I'm doing you a favor.
I couldnt just leave you there
looking all pathetic. Take a seat.
Let me give you a vaccine
against viral infection...
from the Ovaran mud flies.
- What for?
- To give you the symptoms.
What're you talking about?
You're gonna start to lose
vision in your left eye.
Yeah, I already have.
Oh, and you're gonna get a really
bad headache and flop sweat.
- You call this a favor?
- Yeah, you owe me one.
Kirk, James T. He is not cleared
for duty aboard the Enterprise.
Medical code states the treatment
and transport of a patient is...
to be determined at the discretion
of his attending physician.
Which is me.
So I'm taking Mr. Kirk aboard.
Or you would you like
to explain to captain Pike...
why Enterprise warped
into a crisis...
without one of its
senior medical officers?
- As you were.
- As you were. Come on.
I might throw up on you.
Jim, you've gotta look at this.
- Jim, look.
- What?
We need to get you changed.
I don't feel right.
I feel like I'm leaking.
Damn, it's that
pointy-eared bastard.
- Mr. Spock.
- Captain.
- Engineering reports ready for launch.
- Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, the maiden
voyage of our newest flagship
deserves more pompon circumstance
that we can afford today.
The christening will just have to
be our reward for a safe return.
Carry on.
All decks, this is Captain Pike.
Prepare for immediate departure.
Helm, thrusters.
? retracted, captain, dock
control reports ready.
Thrusters fired.
Separating from space dock.
The fleet's cleared space dock, captain.
All ships ready for warp.
- Set course for Vulcan.
- Aye-aye, captain.
Course laid in.
Maximum warp. Punch it.
- Lieutenant, where's helmsmen McKenna?
- He has lung worms sir.
He couldn't report to his post.
- I'm Hikaru Sulu.
- And you are a pilot, right?
Very much so, sir. I'm...
I'm not sure what's wrong here.
Is the parking brake on?
No.
I figured it out, I'm just...
Have you disengaged the external
inertial dampener?
- Ready for warp, sir.
- Let's punch it.
- Where are we?
- Medical bay.
- This isn't worth it.
- A little suffering's good for the soul.
Hi, how are you?
- My mouth is itchy. Is that normal?
- Well, those symptoms won't last long.
- I'm going to give you a mild sedative.
- Oh, I wish I didn't know you.
Don't be such an infant.
How long is it supposed to...
Unbelievable.
Engines at maximum warp captain.
Russian whiz kid, what's your name?
Cheikov? Chirpov?
- Ensign Chekov, Pavel Andrejevic, sir.
- Fine.
Chekov, Pavel Andrejevic,
begin ship wide mission broadcast.
Yes, sir. Happy to.
Ensign authorization code
95 Wictor Wictor 2.
Authorization not recognized.
Ensign authorization code
95 Victor Victor 2.
Access granted.
May I have your attention please.
At 22:00, telemetry detected an anomaly
in the neutral zone.
What appeared to be a lightning
storm in space.
Soon after, Starfleet received a distress
signal from the Vulcan high command
that their planet was experiencing
seismic activity.
Our mission is to assess the
condition of Vulcan
and assist in evacuations
if necessary.
We should be arriving at Vulcan within
3 minutes. Thank you for your time.
Lightning storm.
Aah Jim, you're awake. How do you feel?
- Good God, man!
- What? Aah!
- What the hell's this?
- A reaction to the vaccine. Damn it.
Nurse Chapel, I need 50cc
of cortisone.
Yes, sir.
May I... Appeared to be
a lightning storm in space.
We've gotta stop the ship.
Jim. I'm not kidding. You need
to keep your heart rate down.
Computer, locate crew member Uhura.
I haven't seen a reaction this
severe since medical school.
- We're flying into a trap!
- Damn it, Jim! Stand still.
Stop it!
- Uhura, Uhura...
- Kirk. What're you doing here?
Transmission from the Klingon prison
planet, what exactly did it say?
Oh my God, what's wrong
with your hands?
Who is responsible
for the Klingon attack?
- And was the ship Romu...?
- Was the ship what?
- What's happening to my mouth?
- You got numb tongue?
- Numb tongue?!
- I can fix that.
- Was the ship what?
- Romulan.
- What?
- Romulan?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- Yeah!
Prod Nero seven Federation
ships are on their way.
- Jim!
- What's going on?
- Jim, come back.
- Captain!
Captain Pike, sir,
we have to stop the ship.
Kirk, how the hell did you get
on board the Enterprise?
Captain, this man is under
the influence of a...
- severe reaction to a vaccine.
- Bones, plea...
He's completely delusional...
Vulcan is not a experiencing
a natural disaster,
it's being attacked
by Romulans.
Romulans? Cadet Kirk, I think you've
had enough attention for one day...
McCoy, take him back to medical.
We'll have words later.
- Aye captain.
- Sir, that same anomaly...
Mr. Kirk is not cleared to be
aboard this vessel, captain...
Look, I get it, you're a great...
I'd love to do it again
with you soon...
- I can remove the cadet...
- Try it!
This cadet is trying
to save the bridge!
By recommending a full stop
mid-warp doing a rescue mission?
It's not a rescue mission.
Listen to me. It's an attack.
Based on what facts?
That same anomaly,
a lightning storm in space
that we saw today, also occurred
on the day of my birth.
Before a Romulan ship attacked
the USS Kelvin.
You know that, sir.
I've read your dissertation.
That ship, which had formidable
and advanced weaponry...
was never seen
or heard from again.
The Kelvin attacked a place on
the edge of Klingon space.
And at 23:00 last night
there was an attack.
47 Klingon war birds destroyed
by Romulans, sir.
And it was reported that the Romulans
were in one ship, one massive ship.
And you know
of this Klingon attack how?
Sir, I intercepted and translated
the message myself.
- Kirk's report is accurate.
- We're warping into a trap, sir.
The Romulans are waiting for us.
I promise you that.
The cadet's logic is sound.
And Lt. Uhura's is unmatched
in xenolinguistics.
We would be wise
to accept her conclusion.
Scan Vulcan space. Check for
any transmissions in Romulan.
Sir, I'm not sure I can distinguish
the Romulan language from Vulcan.
What about you?
Do you speak Romulan, cadet?
Uhura. All 3 dialects, sir.
- Uhura, relieve the lieutenant.
- Yes, sir.
Hannity, hail the USS Truman.
All the other ships are out of warp
sir and have arrived at Vulcan,
but we seem to have lost all contact.
Sir, I pick up no Romulan transmission
or transmission of any kind in the area.
It's because they're being attacked.
Shields up. Red alert.
Arrival at Vulcan
in 5 seconds.
4... 3... 2...
- Emergency evasives.
- Running, sir.
- Damage report.
- Deflector shields are holding.
All stations.
Engineering, Olson, report.
Full reverse. Come about starboard, 90.
Drop us down underneath them, Sulu.
- Sir, there's another Federation ship.
- Destroy it too.
Fire torpedoes.
Captain, they're locking torpedoes.
Divert auxiliary power from port
nossel to forward shields.
- Sulu, status report.
- Shields at 32%.
Their weapons are powerful, sir.
We can't take another hit like that.
- Get me Starfleet command.
- Captain.
The Romulan ship has lowered some
kind of high energy pulse device
into the Vulcan atmosphere.
It's signal appears to be blocking our
communications and transporter abilities.
All power to forward shields.
Prepare to fire all weapons.
Weapons ready.
Wait!
- Gohol, magnify!
- Yes, sir.
Captain, we're being hailed.
Hello.
I am the captain Christopher Pike.
To whom am I speaking?
Hi Christopher. I am Nero.
You've declared war against
the Federation. Withdraw...
and I'll agree
to arrange a conference...
with Romulan leadership
at a neutral location.
I do not speak for the Empire.
We stand apart.
As does your Vulcan crew member.
Isn't that right, Spock?
Pardon me, I do not believe that
you and I are acquainted.
No, we're not.
Not yet.
Spock, there's something
I would like you to see.
Captain Pike, your transporter
has been disabled.
As you can see, by the rest of
the armada, you have no choice.
You will man a shuttle. Come aboard
the Narada for negotiations.
That is all.
- Theyll kill you, you know that.
- Your survival is unlikely.
Captain, we gain nothing
by diplomacy.
Going over to that ship
is a mistake.
I too agree. You should
rethink your strategy.
I understand that.
I need officers who've been trained
in advanced hand to hand combat.
I have training, sir.
Come with me.
Kirk, you too. You're not
supposed to be here anyway.
- Chekov, you have the con.
- Aye, Captain.
Prepare the red matter.
Yes, sir.
Without transporters
we can't beam off the ship.
We can't assist Vulcan.
We can't do our job.
Mr. Kirk, Mr. Sulu and engineer Olson
will space-jump from the shuttle.
You will land on that machine they've
lowered into the atmosphere...
that's scrambling our gear, you'll
get inside, you'll disable it...
then you'll beam back
to the ship.
Mr. Spock, I'm leaving you in
command of the Enterprise.
Once we have transport capability
and communication back up
you'll contact Starfleet and report
what the hell's going on here.
And if all else fails, fall back...
and rendezvous with the fleet
in the Laurentian system.
Kirk, I'm promoting you
to first officer.
- What?
- Captain?
Please, I apologize. The complexities
of Human pranks escape me.
It's not a prank, Spock.
And I am not the captain, you are.
Let's go.
Sir, after we knock out that drill,
what happens to you?
I guess you have to come
and get me.
Careful with the ship, Spock.
She's brand new.
- Dr. Puri, report.
- It's McCoy.
Doctor Puri was on deck 6.
He's dead.
Then you have just inherited his
responsibility as chief medical officer.
Yeah, tell me something
I don't know.
Shuttle 89, USS Enterprise,
you are clear...
- You've got the charges, right?
- Oh yeah.
Can't wait to kick
some Romulan ass.
- Yeah.
- Oh yeah.
So what kinda combat training
do you have?
Fencing.
Pre-jump.
Shuttle commander, you are clear
from USS Enterprise...
Gentlemen, we're approaching
the drop zone.
You have one shot
to land on that platform.
They may have defenses, so pull
your chute as late as possible.
3... 2... 1.
Remember, the Enterprise won't
be able to beam you back...
until you've turned off
that drill.
Good luck.
Away team is entering
the atmosphere, sir.
20000 m.
Approaching the platform
at 5800 m.
Kirk to Enterprise.
Distance to target 5000 m.
4600 m from the platform.
4100 m to target.
4000 m.
3000 m.
2000 m.
Pull the chute.
- 2000 m.
- Pull your chute, Olson.
No, not yet. Not yet.
- 1500 m.
- Open the chute!
- Olson, pull your chute!
- 1000 m.
Olson!
Olson is gone, sir.
Kirk has landed, sir.
Gimme your hand.
Olson had the charges.
I know.
- What do we do?
- This.
The jamming signal's gone. Transport
abilities are reestablished.
Transporter control
is reengaged sir.
Check all gravitational sensors. I wanna
know what they were doing to the planet.
Aye, Commander.
Captain. Sorry, captain.
The drill's been sabotaged sir but
we have reached the planet's core.
Launch red matter.
Kirk to Enterprise. They just
launched something at the planet...
through the hole
they just drilled.
- Do you copy Enterprise?
- Yes, sir.
Captain, gravitational sensors
are off the scale.
If my calculations are correct,
they're creating a singularity...
that will consume the planet.
They're creating a black hole
at the center of Vulcan?
Yes.
How long does the planet have?
Minutes, sir. Minutes.
Alert Vulcan command center to
signal a planet wide evacuation...
all channels, all frequencies.
- Spock, wait.
- Maintain standard orbit.
- Yes, sir.
- Where are you going?
To evacuate
the Vulcan High Council.
Their task is to protect
our cultural history,
- My parents will be among them.
- Can't you beam them out?
That is impossible. They will
be in the Katric ark.
I must get them myself.
- Chekov, you have the con.
- Aye.
Kirk to Enterprise.
Beam us out of here.
Stand by, locking on your signal.
- Retract the drill. Let's move out
- Yes, sir.
Fold up.
I can't lock on to them.
Don't move. Don't move!
Hey, Sulu!
Sulu!
Hold on.
I've gotcha.
Now pull my chute.
Kirk to Enterprise!
We're falling without a chute!
Beam us up!
I'm sorry I can't lock on
to your signal.
- Beam us up!
- You're moving too fast.
I can do that. I can do that!
- Take the con.
- Aye, sir.
The black hole's expanding.
We won't reach minimum safe distance
if we don't leave immediately.
Move. Move... I can do that.
I can do that. Move. Move...
Give me manual control,
I can lock on. Beam us up!
- Enterprise, where are you?
- Hold on. Hold on! Hold on!
Now! Now! Now! Do it now!
Now! Now! Now!
Hold on. Hold on. Compensating
gravitational pull. Aaand...
Gotcha.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Clear the pad. I'm beaming to
the surface.
The surface of what?
What, you're going down there?
Are you nuts?
- Spock, you can't do that.
- Energize.
Spock?
The planet has only
seconds left, we must evacuate.
Mother, now.
Spock to Enterprise.
Get us out now.
Locking on to you. Don't move.
Stay right where you are.
Transport in 5... 4... 3... 2...
- Mother!
- I'm losing her! I'm losing her!...
I've lost her! I've lost her.
Acting captain's log,
star date 2258.42.
We have had no word
from captain Pike.
I have therefore
classified him a hostage...
of the war criminal
known as Nero...
Nero, who has destroyed my home planet
and most of its 6 billion inhabitants.
While the essence
of our culture has been saved...
in the elders who now reside
upon this ship...
I estimate no more than
10000 have survived.
I am now a member of
an endangered species.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
What do you need.
Tell me. Tell me.
I need everyone...
to continue
performing admirably.
Okay.
You must have
a lotta questions for me.
I only have one for you.
I need the subspace frequencies of
Starfleet's border protection grids.
Specifically those
surrounding Earth.
Christopher, answer my question.
No, you answer for the genocide you just
committed against a peaceful planet.
No, I prevented genocide.
In my time, where I come from,
this is a simple mining vessel.
I chose a life of honest labor.
to provide for myself and the wife
who was expecting my child.
I was off planet doing my job...
while your Federation
did nothing.
And allowed my people to burn
while their planet broke in half.
And Spock, he didn't help us.
He betrayed us.
No, no... you're confused.
You're misinformed.
Romulus hasn't been destroyed.
It's out there right now.
You're blaming the Federation for
something that hasn't happened...
It has happened! I watched it happen!
I saw it happen!
Don't tell me it didn't happen!
And when I lost her.
I promised myself retribution.
And for 25 years I planned my
revenge against the Federation.
And forgot what it was like
to live a normal life.
I did not forget the pain.
It's a pain that every surviving
Vulcan now shares.
My purpose, Christopher,
is to not simply...
avoid the destruction
of the home that I love...
but to create a Romulus that
exists free of the Federation.
You see only then
will she be truly saved.
That is why I will destroy all
the remaining Federation planets.
Starting with yours.
Then we have nothing
left to discuss.
You will give me the frequencies
to disable Earth's defenses.
Centaurian slugs. They latch
on to your brain stem...
and release a toxin that will
force you to answer.
Frequencies please, sir.
Christopher Pike, captain of
the USS Enterprise...
As you wish.
Have you confirmed that Nero
is heading for Earth?
Their trajectory suggests no
other destination, captain.
Thank you, It.
Earth may be his next stop,
but we have to assume...
every Federation planet's a target.
Out of the chair.
Well, if the Federation is the target,
why didn't they destroy us?
Why would they? Why waste a weapon?
We obviously weren't a threat.
That is not it. He said
he wanted me to see something.
The destruction
of my home planet.
How the hell
did they do that, by the way?
And where did the Romulans get
that kind of weaponry?
The engineering comprehension necessary
to artificially create a black hole...
may suggest an answer.
Such technology could
theoretically be manipulated...
to create a tunnel
through space-time.
Damn it man, I am a doctor,
not physicist.
Are you actually suggesting
they're from the future?
If you eliminate the impossible,
what ever remains, however improbable...
must be the truth.
How poetic.
Then what would an angry future
Romulan want with captain Pike?
As captain he does know details
of Starfleet's defenses.
What we need to do is catch
up to that ship,
disable it, take it over
and get Pike back.
We are technologically
outmatched in every way.
A rescue attempt
would be illogical.
Nero's ship would have to drop
out of warp for us to overtake it.
Then what about assigning engineering
crews to try and boost our warp yield?
Remaining power and crew are being
used to repair radiation leaks...
- on the lower decks.
- Okay. Alright. Alright.
The damage communications.
Without it...
- There's got to be some way.
- we cannot contact Starfleet.
We must gather
with the rest of Starfleet.
To balance the terms
of the next engagement,
There won't be
a next engagement.
By the time we gather
it'll be too late.
Look, you say he's from the future
and knows what's gonna happen...
then the logical thing is
to be unpredictable.
You're assuming that Nero knows
how event's are predicted to unfold.
The contrary. Nero's very presence
has altered the flow of history...
beginning with the attack
on the USS Kelvin,
culminating with the events
of today,
thereby creating an entire
new chain of incidents...
that cannot be anticipated
by either party.
An alternate reality.
Precisely.
Whatever our lives might have been
if the time continuum was disrupted
our destinies have changed.
Mr. Sulu, plot a course for the
Laurentian system. Warp factor 3.
Spock, don't do that.
Running back to the rest of the fleet for
a con fab is a massive waste of time...
These orders were issued by
captain Pike when he left.
He also ordered us to go back and get him.
- Spock, you are captain now. You have...
- I am aware of my responsibilities...
Every second we waste Nero's
getting closer to his next target.
That is correct and why I'm instructing
you to accept the fact that I'm...
I will not allow us to go backwards...
... instead of hunting Nero down.
Security, escort him out.
- No.
- Jim!
Get him off this ship.
Computer, where am I?
Location: Delta Vega.
Class M planet. Unsafe.
There is a Starfleet outpost 14km
to the northwest.
- Remain in your pod...
- Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
Star date 2258.42.
...for... for... Whatever.
Acting captain Spock has
marooned me on Delta Vega.
What I believe to be a violation
of security protocol 49.09
governing the treatment of prisoners
aboard a starship.
James T. Kirk.
- Excuse me?
- How did you find me?
How do you know my name?
I have been and always
shall be your friend.
Look, I don't know you.
I am Spock.
Bullshit.
It is remarkably pleasing to see
you again old friend.
Especially after the events today.
Sir, I appreciate
what you did for me today
but if you were Spock, you'd know
we're not friends at all.
You hate me. You marooned
me here for mutiny.
- Mutiny?
- Yes.
You are not the captain?
No, no... You're the captain.
Pike was taken hostage.
By Nero?
What do you know about him?
He is a particularly
troubled Romulan.
Please. Allow me.
It will be easier.
- Whoa, whoa. What are you doing?
- Our minds, one and together.
129 years from now, a star will explode
and threaten to destroy the galaxy.
That is where I'm from Jim.
The future.
A star went supernova.
Consuming everything in its path.
I promised the Romulans that I
will save their planet.
We outfitted our fastest ship.
Using red matter
I would create a black hole
which would absorb the exploding star.
I was on root
when the unthinkable happened.
The supernova destroyed Romulus.
I had little time.
I had to extract the red matter
and shoot it into the supernova.
As I began my return trip
I was intercepted.
- He called himself Nero,
- ... collapse of Romulan Empire.
In my attempt to escape, both of
us were pulled into the black hole.
Nero went through first.
He was the first to arrive.
Nero spent the next 25 years
awaiting my arrival.
But what was years for Nero
was only seconds for me.
I went through the black hole.
Nero was waiting for me.
He held me responsible for the
loss of his world.
He captured my vessel and spared my life.
For one reason. So that
I would know his pain.
He beamed me here so that
I can observe his vengeance.
As he was helpless to save his planet
I would be helpless to save mine.
Billions of lives lost because of me, Jim.
Because I failed.
Forgive me. Emotional transference
is an effect of the mind meld.
- So you do feel.
- Yes.
Going back in time
you changed all our lives.
Jim! We must go.
There is a Starfleet outpost
not far from here.
Wait.
Where you came from...
did I know my father?
Yes.
You often spoke of him as being your
inspiration for joining Starfleet.
He proudly lived to see you
become captain of the Enterprise.
Captain?
A ship we must return you to
as soon as possible.
- Warp 3, sir.
- Course 151-3.
- Laurentian system, sir.
- Thank you gentlemen.
- You wanted to see me?
- Yes. Doctor.
I am aware that James Kirk
is a friend of yours.
I recognize that supporting me as
you did must have been difficult.
Is that thank you?
I am simply acknowledging
your difficulties.
Permission to speak freely, sir.
- I welcome it.
- Do you?
Okay then. Are you out of
your Vulcan mind?
Are you making a logical choice sending
Kirk away? Probably. But the right one?
Back home we've got a saying. If you're
gonna ride in the Kentucky derby...
you don't leave your
prize stallion in the stable...
A curious metaphor, Doctor,
as a stallion must first be broken...
before it can reach its potential.
My God man. You could at least
act like it was a hard decision.
I intend to insist
in the effort...
to reestablish
communication with Starfleet.
However, if crew moral
is better served...
by my roaming
the halls weeping...
I would gladly defer
to your medical expertise.
Excuse me.
Green blooded little goblin.
What?
You realize how
unacceptable this is?
- Fascinating.
- What?
I am sure
you're just doing your job,
but could you not come
a wee bit sooner?
Six months I've been here.
Living off Starfleet botty nips
and a promise of a good meal.
And I know exactly
what's going on here.
Ok? Punishment, isn't it? Ongoing. For
something that was clearly an accident.
- You are Montgomery Scott.
- You know him?
Yeah, it's me. You're in the right place.
Unless theres another hard working
equally starved Starfleet officer around.
- Me.
- Getup, shut up.
You aren't doing anything. You can
eat, like, a bean and you're done.
I'm talking about food, real food.
But you're here now.
So, thank you. Where is it?
You are in fact a Mr. Scott...
who postulated the theory
of transwarp beaming?
That's what I'm talking about.
How'd ya think I wound up here?
I had a little debate with my
instructor on the issue...
of relativistic physics...
and how it pertains
to subspace travel.
He seemed to think that
the range of transporting...
something like a grapefruit...
was limited to about a 100 miles.
I told him that I could not
only beam a grapefruit...
from one planet
to the adjacent planet...
in the same system,
which is easy by the way...
I could do it with a life form.
So, I tested it on
admiral Archer's prize beagle.
I know that dog.
What happened to it?
I'll tell you when it reappears.
I don't know.
I do feel guilty about that.
What if I told you that your
transwarp theory was correct?
That it is indeed possible to beam onto
a ship that is travelling at warp speed?
I think that if that equation had been
discovered I'd have heard about it.
The reason you haven't
heard of it, Mr. Scott,
is because you haven't
discovered it yet.
- Are you from the future?
- He is. I'm not.
Well that's brilliant. Do they
still have sandwiches there?
Well, she's a wee bit dodgy.
Shield emitters are...
totally bum jacked as well
as a few other things.
In you go.
So, the Enterprise has had
it's maiden voyage, has it?
She is one well endowed lady.
I'd like to get my hands
on her ample nossels,
if you'd pardon
the engineering parlance.
Except, the thing is,
even if I believed you.
Where you're from,
what I've done...
Which I don't, by the way.
We're still talking about
beaming aboard the Enterprise...
while she's travelling faster than
light without a proper receiving pad.
Get off there.
It's not a climbing frame.
The notion of transwarp beaming...
is like trying to hit a bullet
with a smaller bullet...
whilst wearing a blindfold,
riding a horse.
What's that?
Your equation for achieving
transwarp beaming.
You're out of it...
Imagine that.
It never occurred to me...
to think of space as the thing
that was moving...
You're coming with us, right?
No, Jim. That is not my destiny.
Your dest...
He. The other Spock is not gonna
believe me, only you can explain...
- what the hell has happened.
- Under no circumstances...
can he be made aware...
of my existence.
You must promise me this.
So you're telling me
I can't tell you...
that I'm following you're own
orders, why not? What happens?
Jim, this is one rule
you cannot break.
To stop Nero, you alone must
take command of your ship.
How? Over your dead body?
Preferably, not.
However, there is
Starfleet regulation 619.
619 states that
any command officer...
who is emotionally compromised
by the mission at hand...
must resign set command.
So, you're saying that I have to
emotionally compromise you... guys?
Jim, I just lost my planet.
I can tell you,
I am emotionally compromised.
What you must do
is get me to show it.
Aye then lady. Live or die.
Let's get this over with.
You cannot come with me. Go on.
Coming back in time,
changing history, that's cheating.
A trick I learned
from an old friend.
Live long and prosper.
Mr. Scott?
Mr. Scott, can you hear me?
Hold on a second.
No. No!
RELEASE VALVE.
Purifier release valve activated.
You all right? You all right?
My head's buzzing and I'm soaked,
but otherwise I'm fine.
Captain Spock, detecting unauthorized
access to water turbine control board.
Bring up the video.
Security, seal the engineering deck.
We have intruders in turbine section 3.
Set phasers to stun.
Halt!
Come with me...
cupcake!
Who are you?
- I'm with him.
- He's with me.
We're travelling
at warp speed.
How did you manage
to beam aboard this ship?
You're the genius,
you figure it out.
As acting captain of this vessel
I order you to answer the question.
Well I'm not telling,
acting captain.
What?
What now? That doesn't
frustrate you, does it?
My lack of cooperation,
that doesn't make you angry?
- Are you a member of Starfleet?
- Um... yes. Can I get a towel?
Under penalty of court martial
I order you to explain to me...
how you were able to beam aboard
the ship while moving at warp?
Well.
- Don't answer him.
- You will answer me.
- I'd rather not take sides.
- What is it with you, Spock?
Hm?
Your planet was just destroyed,
your mother murdered,
and you're not even upset.
If you are presuming that these
experiences in any way...
impede my ability to command
this ship you are mistaking.
And yet you were the one who said
fear was necessary for command.
I mean, did you his ship?
Did you see what he did?
- Yes, of course I did.
- So are you afraid or aren't you?
I will not allow you to lecture
me about the merits of emotion.
- Then why don't you stop me?
- Step away from me Mr. Kirk.
What is it like not to feel
anger or heartbreak?
Or the need to stop at nothing...
to avenge the death of the woman
who gave birth to you.
- Back away from me.
- You feel nothing!
It must not even compute for you.
- You never loved her!
- No!
Spock.
Doctor, I am no longer
fit for duty.
I relinquish my command based on the fact
that I have been emotionally compromised.
Please note the time and
date in the ship's log.
I like this ship.
You know it's exciting.
Well congratulations, Jim.
Now we've got no captain...
and no God damn first officer
to replace him.
Yeah we do.
- What?
- Pike made him first officer.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- Thanks for the support.
I sure hope you know
what you're doing, captain.
So do I.
Attention, crew of the Enterprise,
this is James Kirk.
Mr. Spock has resigned commission
and advanced me to acting captain.
I know you're all expecting
a regroup with the fleet,
but I'm ordering a pursuit course
of the enemy ship to Earth.
I want all departments at battle
stations and ready in 10 minutes.
Either we're going down
or they are.
Kirk out.
Speak your mind Spock.
That would be unwise.
What is necessary
is never unwise.
I am as conflicted
as I once was as a child.
You will always be
a child of two worlds.
I am grateful for this.
And for you.
I feel anger for the one
who took mother's life.
An anger I cannot control.
I believe, as she would say...
do not try to.
You asked me once
why I married your mother.
I married her
because I loved her.
Whatever the case we need to
get aboard Nero's ship undetected.
Just can't just go in there
guns blazing, Jim.
I'm telling you to...
- Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk.
- Yes, Chekov. What is it?
Based on the Neradas course
from Vulcan...
I have projected that Nero
will travel pass Saturn.
Like you said we need to stay
invisible to Nero or he'll destroy us.
If Mr. Scott
can get us to warp factor 4...
and if we drop out of warp behind
one of Saturn's moons, say Titan.
The magnetic distortion from
the planet's rings...
will make us invisible
to Nero's sensors.
From there, as long as
the drill is not activated...
we can beam
aboard the enemy ship.
Aye, that might work.
- Wait a minute kid, how old are you?
- 17, sir.
Oh good, he's 17.
Doctor.
Mr. Chekov is correct. I can
confirm his telemetry.
If Mr. Sulu is able to
maneuver us into position
I can beam aboard Nero's ship,
steal back the black hole device
and if possible bring back
captain Pike.
I won't allow you
to do that Mr. Spock.
Romulans and Vulcans
share a common ancestry.
Our cultural similarities
will make it easier...
for me to access
the ship's computer...
to locate the device.
Also my mother was human.
Which makes Earth
the only home I have left.
I'm coming with you.
I would cite regulation, but
I know you will simply ignore it.
See? We are getting to know
each other.
Prepare the drill.
All stop in 3... 2... 1.
Give me 1/4 impulse burst
for 5 seconds.
I'll do the rest with thrusters.
On my mark.
Aye.
Fire.
Transporter room. We are in
position above Titan.
Really?
Fine job Mr. Sulu, well done.
How are we Scotty?
Unbelievably sir.
The ship is in position.
Whatever happens Mr. Sulu,
if you think you have
the tactical advantage...
you fire on that ship even if we're
still on board. That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Otherwise we'll contact the Enterprise
when we're ready to be beamed back.
Good luck.
- I will be back.
- You better be.
- I'll be monitoring your frequency.
- Thank you, Nyota.
- So her first name's Nyota?
- I have no comment on the matter.
Oky doky then. If theres any common
sense in the design of the enemy's ship
I should be putting you somewhere in the
cargo bay, shouldn't be a soul in site.
Energize.
Captain, we have Starfleet officers
aboard the ship.
- One of them is Vulcan.
- No.
Ayel!
- I'll cover ya.
- Are you certain?
Yeah, I've gotcha.
Do you know where it is?
The black hole device?
And captain Pike.
Move.
They have activated the drill.
Communication and transportation
are inoperative.
Sulu, please tell me
you have them.
Otherwise we won't be
able to beam them back.
Kirk and Spock
are on their own now.
I foresee a complication.
The design of this ship...
is far more advanced
than I have anticipated.
Voice print and face recognition
analysis enabled.
Welcome back ambassador Spock.
That's weird.
Computer, what is your
manufacturing origin?
Star date 2387. Commissioned
by the Vulcan Science Academy.
It appears that you have been keeping
important information from me.
You'll be able
to fly this thing, right?
Something tells me
I already have.
- Good luck.
- Jim.
The statistical likelihood
that our plan will succeed...
- is less than 4,3%.
- It'll work.
In the event that I do not return
please tell Lt. Uhura...
Spock, it'll work.
Fascinating.
Startup sequence initiated.
Nero, order your men to disable
the drill or I will...
I know your face
from Earth's history.
James T. Kirk was considered
to be a great man.
He went on to captain
the USS Enterprise.
But that was another life.
A life I will deprive you of
just like I did your father.
Captain Nero. The Vulcan ship's been
taken. The drill has been destroyed.
Spock! Spock!
- Open a channel.
- Yes, sir.
Spock, I knew I should have
killed you when I had the chance.
I hereby confiscate
this illegally obtained ship...
and order you to surrender
your vessel. No terms.
That ship... take it out.
- Sir, if you ignite the red matter..
- I want the Spock dead now!
- He went to warp.
- Go after him.
Yes, sir.
Your species is even weaker
than I expected.
You can't even speak.
What?
I got your gun.
What's he doing?
Ambassador Spock, you are
on a collision course.
Fire everything.
Incoming missiles. If the ship is hit,
the red matter will be ignited.
Understood.
Captain, I've picked up
another ship.
- What are you doing here?
- Following orders.
Enterprise now!
Nice timing Scotty.
I've never beamed three people
from two targets
onto one pad before.
- Jim. - Bones.
- I've got him.
That was pretty good.
Captain, the enemy ship is loosing
power. They're shields are down.
- Hail them now.
- Aye.
This is captain James T. Kirk
of the USS Enterprise.
Your ship is compromised. You're
too close to the singularity
to survive without assistance
which we are willing to provide.
Captain, what are you doing?
Showing them compassion
may be the only way...
to make peace with Romulus, Spock.
It's logical, Spock.
Thought you'd like that.
No, not really. Not this time.
I would rather suffer the end
of Romulus a thousand times,
I would rather die in agony
than accept assistance from you.
You've got it.
Arm phasers.
Fire everything we've got.
Yes, sir.
- Sulu, let's go home.
- Yes, sir.
- Why aren't we at warp?
- We are, sir.
Kirk to engineering.
Get us out of here, Scotty.
You bet your ass captain.
Captain, we're caught in
the gravity well. It's got us.
Go to maximum warp. Push it!
I'm giving it
all she's got captain.
All she's got isn't good enough.
What else you got?
Ok, if we eject the core
and detonate the blast...
could be enough to push us away.
I can't promise anything though.
Do it! Do it! Do it!
- Clear the area. Go!
- Yes, sir.
Father?
I am not our father.
There are so few Vulcans left we
cannot afford to ignore each other.
Then why did you send Kirk aboard when
you alone could have explained the truth?
Because you needed each other.
I could not deprive you of the revelation
of all that you can accomplish together.
Of a friendship
that will define you both.
In ways you cannot yet realize.
How'd you persuade him to
keep your secret?
He inferred that universe
ending paradoxes would ensue
should he break his promise.
You lied?
- Oh. I implied.
- A gamble?
An act of faith.
One I hope you will repeat in
the future in Starfleet.
In the face of extinction it is only
logical I resign my Starfleet commission
and help rebuild our race.
And yet you can be
in two places at once.
I urge you to remain in Starfleet.
I've already located a suitable planet
on which to establish a Vulcan colony.
Spock, in this case
do yourself a favor...
put aside logic,
do what feels right.
Since my customary farewell would
appear awfully self serving...
I shall simply say good luck.
This assembly calls captain
James Tiberius Kirk.
Your inspirational valor and
supreme dedication to your comrades...
is in keeping with the highest
traditions of service.
And reflect at most credit to yourself,
your crew and the Federation.
It is my honor to award you
with this commendation.
By Starfleet order 28455, you are hereby
directed to report to admiral Pike...
USS Enterprise,
for duty as his relief.
I relieve you, sir.
I am relieved.
- Thank you, sir.
- Congratulations, captain.
Your father would be proud of you.
Thrusters on full.
Firing thrusters and impulse
engines at your command, sir.
Weapon systems
and shields on standby.
Dock control
reports ready, captain.
Bones.
Buckle up.
Scotty, how we doin'?
Dilithium chambers
at maximum captain.
Get down!
Mr. Sulu,
prepare to engage thrusters.
Permission to come aboard, captain.
Permission granted.
As you have yet to select
a first officer,
respectfully I would like
to submit my candidacy.
Should you desire I can provide
character references.
It would be my honor commander.
Maneuvering thrusters Mr. Sulu.
- Thrusters on standby.
- Take us out.
Aye aye, captain.
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE
HER ONGOING MISSION: TO
EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE FORMS
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO ONE
HAS GONE BEFORE.
Captions made possible by:
STAR TREK FAN #1 NW.