Go for it. Go for it.. Go for it... lNDlA.
National sports stadium is filled with audience.
Last two minutes of the final match of World
Hockey Championship Tournament.
lndia is behind Pakistan by 1 goal.
lndian captain Kabir Khan who is in his best
format leading the team with vigour.
For the suspence of the audience...
.. tension is on the faces of lndian and Pakistani official.
When these 2 nations frights, the tempo
becomes high for the audience.
Just 2 and 1/2 minutes left... Something has to be done
for lndia.
Ball is with the Pakistani defender.
Utham singh has taken the possession of the ball from
Pakistani defender and moving forward.
lndia has got a Penalty stroke.
This is the last chance to save from losing the match
at the last minute of the game.
Now we will see who's taking the stroke.
With the decision of the team Captain Kabir Kban
takes the stroke.
The entire nation is watching Kabhir Khan.
Hello... where is Kabir?
Can you explain what happened on the ground?
Do you think that Pakistani team is better than lndia?
May be...
Why did you take the penalty stroke at the last minute?
lts my mistake.
We heard that the player on the other side is
your friend.
Because you hugged and shaken hands with him
after the match.
Excuse me.
We heard that some one from your team purposely
lost the match.
Excuse me.
Tell us about the transaction and brihery of this deal.
What do you say?
Kabir Khan, ls there any money transaction on this
scandal.
lt has come clear.
His anger and fright agains us confirms the conclusion..
There is something behind this brihery scandal.
We got our conclusion.
Now it is your turn to decide whether Kabir Kban
is a Traitor or not.
Sathyavritav Yadav, National Stadium, New Delhi.
lmportant News: Pakistan beat lndia by 1 Goal at the
Mens World Cup Hockey Championship.
Greetings. You are watching AAJ TAK.
Today we are here to say that the lndian Hockey
association
issued notice to decide about Kabir Kban
after losing the match today.
Now its you the lndian public to decide on this issue.
We have two people here to discuss the issue.
Do you think Kabir Khan lost the match purposely to
Pakistan?
l don't know whether he purposely lost or not.. But
they have lost it.
What do you think?
We must turn this kind of people upside down.
What do you think? This kind of people should have
been
sent to Pakistan during partition.
We don't know the whereabouts of Kabir Khan.
We couldn't locate him neither Hockey Stadium nor
lndian Sports
Authority Complex. Where is Kabir Khan?
Don't look backwards.. Lets go..
How come l not see? Kabir.
Your Grandpa saved every little
penny to buy this land.
He struggled so much from his first savings.
lt hurts a lot son...
Let us find some peace.
You see they will come to know the truth one day.
Traitor
Don't look at that son...
lf you don't want, don't see anything...
But l want to see everything.
Lets go from here...
Father. l want to see the Traitor. See.. Look...
l'll give the tiffen to them. Are you crazy?
You want go against the village people?
Whats your decision?
What? Everytime you bring the same thing.
What do you want to do for the coach?
Now you tell me...
ln 3 months time there is a womens worldcup hockey
tournament.
Time will gojust like that.
Let it go.
What is with that?
lndian Womens Hockey team can do nothing.
lts a govenment tour.
You also do something and go with them.
As it is, they will be finished within 3 or 4 matches.
Exit.
Thats why, you take Mrs. V adera and enjoy the tour
abroad.
l don't understand, why you don't take
the womens hockey team seriously.
l don't understand why you take so serious?
They are lndian women.
They can't play wearing shorts.
l'm sorry.
How come you guys talk like this sitting
here at the association office?
We are in association, public is
watching thats l say these words.
For that players are coming
from differents tates.
Punjab
Tamil Nadu
Jharkand
Andhra Ailways.
Even from Mizoram and anipur
Where did you get a coach for them?
From the moon! Just kidding.
You tell me this is it the girls mistake?
Not their.. lts people like you
who are behind.
We must have atleast media coverage, tv channels
and sponsors.
Now tell me which coach will forward for womens
hockey team leaving his career. You tell me.
ls there anyone?
NOhody.
There is one person.
Whos that?
Kabir.
Who? Kabir Khan.
ls that the same person? Yes.
When did be get the interest in womens hockey?
He went away long ago. lts long time no see..
Now you see him.
Where? 0utside.. At the reception.
We must capture the opponent teams strategy for the
goal
using our brain.
Goal will come by itself.
Sir, They are calling you inside.
How many years since...? 7 Years. 3 Months... and...
7 years, 3 months, 15 days.
What have you been doing all these days?
Preparing for this meeting.
He wants to become the coach for lndian Womens
Hockey Team.
Kabir Sir.
You not a kid.
You must know that countries like ours keep
womens hockey team for the name sake.
Not for the jOh.
As it is, your reputation is already...
l mean...
.. you want to bring back your
reputation with this team..
Team like this will never win even with an european
school team.
l need a team like that.
-What do you mean? l can't understand.
You can't understand.
May l take it like l am appinted.
As it is you don't have any
alternative coach.
l have done my jOh.
Even now you think it again.
l thought about it.
This is not a Team.. lts a Grave yard...
Why do you step into it?
This team won't get better
coach than you.
But think about you..
- l'm thinking...
You have changed a lot.
l haven't changed.
Nothing has changed.
You were not responsible for that match.
You played very hard.
But they killed me, my team and my nation.
Against my family wishes.
0ne mistake can be forgiven by people.
Everyone.
Kabir. Why did you come back here?
l am going to bring the World
Cup with this team.
Which is not possible.
When is your girls are coming?
- Tomorrow, from different states.
State
Listen sister. They are not allowing me
to leave from this Hockey association.
Here is the Human being players. they say the same
thing.
ls she from the ailways? Whats her name?
vidya. vidya Sharma.
l heard she got married.
Why is she here? She has come.
You are asking 10o rupees, do you keep this meter on
your head?
Meter is faulty. You have to give 1o0.
Whom are you talking? l am talking to you and lf you
are in punjOh you will be..
Don't get angry, it will damage your brain.
You are not telling anything at him?
He is my child or you are my child?
0k... Drink water.
Hey Komal...
See how you are playing infront of your dad.
You come here to play this.
l'll take care of you.
You don't worry.
Lets get into the car.
My dear.. Your grand fathers, played this
game. lts our family tradition.
Now its your turn. Keep yourfamily in mind.
Name please? Ah...
l am asking your name.
Surmayi.. l am not asking about your health. Your
name...
Surmayi.. ls it your name?
Yes... Tell me your full name?
Surmuyi Kelketta.
She doesn't know english.
Who are you? Ani.
Haven't you come from any mental hospital?
what do you want? Ani Distotha
We are not Amleela drama people. Stadium will
not available before Diwali. Go.
Ammorni Govt. High School, Jharkand.
Oh! my god.. These are hockey players!!
Yes...
Name? Nethra Eddy.
Are you adarasi?
Telugu
TamiI
Not tamil, Telugu.
Yeah... Whats the difference
between Tamil or Telugu?
Just like Punjabi or Bihari.
Ok.. Shall l go...
How these beauties are made with chocolate
ice cream with vanila, butterscotch?
lf they go to disco or nite club
defenitely everyone will fall.
What they are players?
Let them come.. we will play..
Who will make them understand?
Ji.. whos tomotos and whos potatos.
Everyone is looking.
lt looks like they are nepalis.
Mouli amage, anipur. Marry alter, izoram.
Wow.. Players come all over lndia.
You are my Guests.
What happened?
Are you thinking something?
You be happy with your countries guests.
Then Bindyalaya.. How are you?
Fine.. What else..
How is your injury Guljar? lt will go on by itself.
You are seniors, and be like seniors.
Everything will be fine.
Sukram, you have become more old.
My name is Kabir Khan.
l am the coach for lndian Womens Hockey Team
which you will be included.
ls everone here? Yes.. but except one...
Priety Sabarwal.
Reporting time is 10 O'clock right.
Excuse me.
ls this the place for registering for womens team.
lndian National Hockey Teams registration is over.
- Bloody hell...
l am Preity Sabarwal.
Bloody hell... Preity Sabarwal
You are very late. Try next year.
Sorry.. Next year.
Sorry.. Next year..
Everybody fall in line please.
Go and line up everyone.
Chandigarh..
- ls this chandigarh team?
No.
But l'm the captain of a state team.
And lam the coacb of the
lndian National Womens Team.
l won't hear or see any state.
l hear only one countries name. Thats lNDlA.
ln this team there is no place for late comers.
Everyone understand that?
0K.. You go 1o rounds come back in 1o minutes.
lf not you to take Chandigargh train.
Now everyone come to front and introduce yourselves.
You. Balbir Gaur, Punjab.
Once again. Balbir Gaur, Punjab.
Go outside and wait.
Komal Chuttana, Haryana.
Outside.
Mouli Jammic, Manipur. out...
Netbra eddy, Andhra Pradesb. 0ut...
achna Prasad, Bihar. Out...
Gola Sqora, aharashtra. 0ut...
Vidya Sharma, lndia.
Mmm.. vidya Sharma, lndia.
Little bit louder...
vidya Sharma, lndia.
Thank you. You are on the team.
ls there anyone else who play for states or railways?
Listen carefully and understand now.
l'm not going to repeat.
l need players for this team,
only those who play for lndia.
With team spirit, together.
lf not you can as you wish.
lts not for getting government jOh and flat.
0k.. Lets start it again...
Balbir Gaur, lndia. Komal Gazzara, lndia.
Mouli Jimmic, lndia. Nethra eddy, lndia.
athna Prasad, lndia. Nicola Squara, lndia.
vidya sharma, lndia. Gaulik Bahr, lndia.
ani Discotta, lndia. Surmuyi Kerketta, lndia.
Neena Fernandez, lndia.
Marry azt, lndia. Haliya Bose, lndia.
Gunjan Lakkani, lndia. Bindiya Nayak, lndia.
Priety Sabarwal, lndia.
Move, move...
Sister, You are Bindya Nayak, right.
And you have played many world matches, right.
So what? l'm happy to meetyou.
Can you dance?
This is my bed.
You go there and sleep.
Forget it... Correct.
Hello.. l'm Nethra. vidya.
Yeah. l know. l saw you scoring 4, 5 goals at the
south zone tournament.
My time and luck was good.
For good people, luck will always be with them.
Oh.. What happened?
What happened?
She has taken treatment for the stomach pain.
You take treatment like this?
l don't know what you guys say?
l'm coming from Jharkand.
Jungle.. There are jungles.
So you come from Jungle.
You don't beat anyone right.
What are you doing,
girl?
Sorry.. Don't say sorry, just take
your bags, thats enough.
What are you doing?
This is my bag.
l've kept such a big box and you kept iton it.
So what?
l kept the box first, so bed becomes mine.
Do you think bed belongs to you because
you kept the box?
Then what? Have you ever traveled by bus on roads?
l reserved it first.
But my name is on the list for this place.
You have broken it...
Hey... Come here...
Come here...
Every fright will not end immediately.
They keep something inside.
Until you get a chance.
Gitwal, Get down.
Come here with us.
l've been told that 1 of you have been selected
out of 50 crore women in this country.
This sounds nice and bad too...
Now l'm going to tell my decision on this.
For me only 16 girls has come,
which is a shock to hockey.
Don't keep anything other than this.
10 kilometeres
10 kilometers.. Everyone. Come on...
0k.. Lets go girls.
We are playing or running
a marathon?
We have done enough
after getting up at 4am.
He doesn't know how to treat
national level players.
Go.
lts you?
Take your positions. What happened?
whats your prOhle?
Yours is right side position right. Sir...
l think you better take the right side position.
l was centre forward in Haryana.
- Then go and play in the Haryana team.
Everybody is in position.
Hi.. Coach told me to play on the forward line.
You go home and play.
Do one thing?
You go and play with them. But coach sir...
Can you do whatever he says?
But coach...
Coach will come and go.
But you are living with us, right.
Look.. Everyone goes to drink water. Go..
And listen, don't take my name.
What happened?
Every year l play forward position.
But in this team you play only centre.
This team or that team...
Makes no difference to me.
But its a problem for the team.
You are senior and strong player.
Team requires you at the Center balf.
Go to your new position.
Sorry.
0ut.
Sit outside and let others play. 0ut...
Komal.. Komal...
What is it? l've made the goal.
Out...
Didnt you see what she did before?
l know what l'm looking at.
When scored the goal, nobody went near.
When you put the goal she was with
you and in scoring position.
0ut...
Yeah.. Look at her..
When she makes mistake, you keep quite.
Come home. l'll let you know who am l.
Sad we got him as coach.
Coach.. God is not with him.
very good.. Hands, closer...
Ah.. Lets relax.
0ut...
Hey look...
lf you angry, will pour chilly sauce so
everything comes out.
Stop. Whats happening?
You knew that she doesn't speak Punjabi.
l was coming on the right side.
Say sorry to her.
l never asked sorry with anyone.
0ut,. Out...
You must have given with the ball.
l know before and avoided playing with the Jungle
girls.
You get so much angry?
Looks like you take his head away. Shall l take yours?
Sir, how long are we going to
keep them like this?
l don't know.
l don't think they will all play together.
Playing hockey is long way ahead.
Before that we must teach them something else...
Good Evening.
Look. New sleeping room.
According to the old list.
But the list is no more..
Hey.. Go back to your place.
No girl should stay with a girl from the
same state. Coach has told us.
Let him keep on telling.
l am not changing.
Everyone has changed. lf you have any
problem, talk to the coach.
Whole day sitting on the bench and
at nright also they won't leave us.
They are running a national camp
or a refugee camp.
No. This is also no need.
Let every one sit on the bench.
How are you? lt has become big prOhle.
l come here..
But l can't go.
- lts my brother-in-laws sister wedding.
Dad asked me to call you.
- But akesh, you know that this is National Camp.
Dear, we come first then playing.
But dad..
- Look we sent you to play there.
Now we are asking you to take
the next bus and come back.
akesh, please understand. l can't come.
l have waited my entire life for this camp.
- But vidya, you could wait, I can't.
l can't wait my entire life for you.
Tomorrow is the marriage.
lf you can come, come.
Or else never come back.
Rakesh.
They need wife, children and service.
But l have nothing else apartment
from this Hockey stick.
Are your people also
scared of you?
lf you want to go,
go for one or two days.
But if l go
Ill never come back.
This side or that side.
But before marriage..
- l told everything. They were all happy.
l got a flat and government
jOh on sports quota.
Then what happened now?
Now they forget everything
and need me.
Sometimes l think this is the
fate for all the players.
No.
Every house they play this.
Politics and Cricket can be played.
But Hockey... little bit problem.
Have you ever heard of ohammed Bin Tukluk.
ls he smart?
He was an Emperor long ago.
Everyone tell him mental.
Mentally ill.
He kept all the gold and silver and
showed everyone the bronze.
He was gone within 5 years.
very soon the coach
will also go like that.
He will do anything.
You have so much brain,
why don't you play the game?
He'll go very soon.
Association people will
throw him out.
Just few days.
Tukluk. Nice name. lsn't it?
Mouli,
Balbir
Komal
Brindyalaya. Sit on the bench.
He will keep me on the bench until
l say sorry in front of everyone.
This tukluk is fully becoming mad.
lts ok. We are also mad.
...
Sir... Sir...
Sir, we too want to play.
l am sorry.
Sorry?
l told you sorry.
Lets go.
Sorry. Sorry.. Sorry...
She does a nice stroke.
You are praising your enemy.
Sister, Lets go play...
Sit quitely.
We will play only on our position.
l'll go.. lts been 7 days...
Sir, please forgive me.
Hey.. You forgive me or go to the police station.
lf you forgive me our fright will end.
lf there is no fright, then we both will be clear.
No need to go the Police station.
Tell me. Forgive or go the police station?
Lets go...
We are reversing the play.
Defenders will attack and forward will defend.
Sorry sir.
Lets go and back them.
They lost the match with Pakistan
on the world Cup match.
He was the captain for the team, right.
Pakistans captain in lndian uniform.
What are you talking?
Not me.. Everyone is talking the same.
Then how come he become coach?
This is lndia.
Anything can happen here.
They were talking about
the world cup.
They are going to send
us to the world cup.
What are doing here? Look who has come down.
Guest has come.
What happened? Any filmstar has come?
Abhimanu Singh. What?
You are just kidding. Go.. What?
Lets go see him. He has come to see someone.
l'll be his girl before she meets him.
Lets go see him.
She never told us.
She is getting married to him.
Kabir sir given her leave
until tomorrow morning.
Leave until tomorrow morning?
What they will do at nright?
lts confirmed. They are making me vice-captain.
Bullshit.
ls it true?
Yeah.. l don't believe this.
l knew before, how many days they can postpone?
vice captain of the lndian Cricket team. Now l will have
to
watch and teach all seniors.
Now i can come to know how the team performs.
Get out of the way everyone, its my turn.
Now, you too leave all these things?
Whatshould l leave?
Your Hockey.
Come on babe. Just leave it.
What can l do after leaving this?
what to do?...
Spend lavishly, be with me and
travel  the world with me.
Live the life King size with the King.
You are the wife of vice captain
of the lndian Team. - Wife?
l didn't tell you that.
Yesterday l spoke to your dad.
l told him l am ready and he
said he will give you to me.
Thats it..
Engagement is over.
l have just settled down my career.
- Then my career?
What?
What about my career?
Yours, which career?
Now l am on the lndian Hockey Team.
Thats not a career Priety.
lts just a stupid game.
So as cricket. Priety...
l knew you like this game.
But lets face it. where is cricket?
And where is your hockey?
She is playing while dancing.
Lets leave it.
We too join them.
Hey.. Lets go.. We have been sitting on
this bench for 7 days.
We are players not on lookers.
Lets go...
l'll play such a game that l'll be in forward position,
or else my name is not Bindiya Nayak...
nor his name ohammed Bin Tukluk.
Sorry sir, lt will not happen again.
sorry...
Ok. you can take center half position.
Thank you sir...
everything is under control
lt must be under control.
lt was allmost out of control.
right .. Left..
right .. on your Left..
Fast ... Fast..
right .... . Left.... .
To the ball
0k.. just Go right.. left..
Fast....Fast....
Fast....Fast.... keep on going...
Thank you..
That pass you move forward..
No players should hold the ball more then five seconds
you know how to coun't ? 5 4 3 2 1
Fast.. Fast ...
quick.. quick..
quick... make it fast.. fast...
what is your problem??
You are not concentrating on the ball
right.. left...
now leave the ball
sitdown Go right....
look and pass..
Stop look and move forward
You must not move forward before the ball ..
Carry the ball..
Carry..
Keep the ball in your pocket go and
play some where else....
There is no need play here..
And you...
Why do you get angry..
You have to be gentle to your team members.
If I hear you raise your voice youre out.
ooi..
You are a center player and....
...wrost senior player in the team. You are
suppose to feed the ball them. not to dispose
0ne more thing l want to tell you..
ln every team there can be only one
villain. And thats me
Pass..pass..
Yeah.. girl
from where you come
Go back to your parents forget
about playing Hockey.
what are you all looking at...
come on let's move..
right Left
Krishnajee.....
Give her water and take her out from the field
Quickly.....
Hey...
This is what you call the best
Hockey players in lndia...
Going to compete in
world Hockey championsbip..
To go the world cub bring
prestige to lndia.
0k...
No discipline No commitment
What you all want to play Hockey??
Can not even play as a team
How to win the World Cup???
Whatare you looking there?
That is not belong to us ...
Krishna jee take here out from here...
Ive been telling you all again and again,
this team only needs players who plays for lndia..
After that they play for their
team and there after,
..if there life to survive
then its for them self..
Now let start again...
Right..
This is result of giving too much
respect to the coach..
The bleeding flow is not stoping..
lve told you all before..
dont be as senior player..
He makes us wake up 4'o clock in the morning..
Run for 20 kms and when you want play he
will not alllow you too play...
How much he care for us..
ls it very painful..
lt is very painful in the heart..
What was he calling ever one of us...
Hit with the ball...
He know that you do not how to speak
English but yet he stills want you to learn to speak...
He expect you to learn in one day. or
lf not you will be out from the team..
How can she just go like that..
you dont worry i will teach you...
how can he just remove her..
What is your oppinion Aleya..
He not concern about our welfare...
He just know how to scool us. only...
He treat us like a primary
school student ..
We have got silver medail on the stage.
That why we are here..
lf any one is a failure must be him only
he sole the final world cup match...
He left out team and game ..
How to tell I am felling shy too others...
ls it painful l have spray with me ..
How are you rekha..
- I am ok
Doctor said that in 2 or 3 days
time i can practice ..
practice
have you gone mad
From today onwards there
will be no more practice
From tomorrow no body will go to practice..
Look Bindya. you see..
We all know that you like him..
But you mustalso know that the team are here....
How you want to stay
you think about it ...
Yes
l have thought about it.. The hockey association has
only the right to decide on how to run the team...
The way the run the team like before or
How Tukluk wants it to be...
Can all girls sign on this petition letter
ls either the coach or the team will remain here...
Girls please sign here ....
Sir...
hmm eat...
It is a little bit too much, already
They are girls how much can they withstand
The pressure unless they are man .
this is not question of strength
but it is the intention
To play in a team you dont require strengtb
your intention must be good ...
Butsir...
they will treat you like an enemy ..
lf they take me as an enemy, they can be friends
to make a team, it is a very small sacrifice...
Why are you all gathering here?
What's the problem??
The team does not want to practice with you
What nonsense you are telling..
We want to change the coach
l will hit you right and proper
Krishna jee why should we give way
to a person who has sell the country.
Shut up or else I will smack you
7' years
After 7' years i decided to make a come
back to a Hockey team.
The reason why I came back is because l wanted
to win back the glory which I and my team had fail before
But today...
l've lost it again...
l dont have any difficulties
But lts painful that l had to force you
all to play together with one another...
I thaught you all to put the team before
yourself, and also to put lndia before your state..
0k...
You all have won and i've lost...
i have no regrets that i've lost to all of you but
l fell sorry for myself that i have lost to my nation...
Even after giving my sweat, blood my heart I can't
believe that l had played with the Team and for life
l will be playing for the team...
l resign as a coach of the state...
Please reconsider your decision..
A good team in the making will be destroyed..
Today in this camp is my last day...
Before I leave
I want to take all staff for lunch..
lf any one of you want's to follow
You may come...
Anyway, it is not important...
Hi, beautifuls come an join us,
please come on..
She is very hot yaar
hey babe....
hey... bey....
You want tease girl come an tease me ..
sister hammer him hammer him ..
Stop wait wait
Not from behind.
be like a man fright from the front..
What is that? This will not happen in our Hockey.
Look. ls it a team or an army of evil.
As l said, you don't need the strength
its only the intention to win.
First time, l saw that intention on them.
Sir, what l want to say is...
.. i mean...
Whatever happened is happened.
There is no point talking about it.
Hey girl.. Tell him..
Sir.. what she wants to say is..
What we wants to say is...
Tomorrow morning 5 A.M.
l want everyone on the field.
We are to run 2 kilometers extra today.
How can you go?
Why? we are getting married.
What? You can't go on the 25th,
we getting married on the 2nd.
What? After asking your parents the date has been
finalised. Why you never ask me?
There is nothing to ask you. You want to marry me.
But not like this. l need time.
For what? l'm going to the World Cup.
what mad are you talking?
Will you postpone the marriage because of the
Worldcup?
lf it is your Worldcup? Thats a different story.
Thats cricket world cup. lts very big.
This is also big for me.
Even bigger than marriage?
l've to go. Good night.
Go and play the Worldcup. lf you lose you'll be my wife.
lf you win also you'll be my wife.
lt'll not like that you come with the world Cup and
you'll be famous all over lndia.
0ne thing l promise you Mr Abhimanu Singb, whatever
will happen or not, this will defenitely happen.
You have made a wonderful team. Yeah...
This team captain will be Vidya.
Congratulations vidya.
He left us.
There is no chance left to talk.
First time something good happens. You must be part
of it. You have become part of it, right?
Bindya is totally upset. lt will be better if we
keep her off the team.
l don't know, Krishna a'am.
And it is not good if we don't
have an experienced player.
We can't strike a deal with her.
Without her we will win the match.
ls this is your world cup silver medal sir?
What are you doing with that?
l'm just trying to find a way to make gold.
lf l sell to the Theif arkt, l'll get the right name.
Kabir sir...
lt'll be better if you forget
about the worldcup.
Tell the girls too that you have
given them false dream.
But our plan is to prepare this
team for the Worldcup.
ls there any paper that we have signed,
so you can hold our neck.
We discussed everything before my presence.
Now also we are talking in your presence.
Look.. At least the Mens team will bring
the Bronze medal.
On the other side he has
got that silly team.
But this team has been is
ready for the Worldcup.
In case this team is ready, do you think we will
send them? This team is not going to worldcup.
Why are you snatching away from them and giving
it to the male counterpart.
You are so talented. Why are you talking about
things which you have no say?
We have to go.
Sir...
Lets arrange for a match.
Match between my team and your team.
l mean, between mens team and womens team?
Yes.
Your team and my team.
lf they lose, they lose... lf they win,
they will go to worldcup.
Think carefully Kabir.
You want to lay a bet?
we have told you before also.
0. K .
Lets have the match on
the day after tomorrow.
At least give them the time to prepare.
Day after tomorrow.  Be there in the morning.
We will meet day after tomorrow
morning on the field.
Lets go...
Sir.. We also need some practice...
Come outside...
First thing we will not win.
Even by fault.. By fault!
By fault also we can't win the match.
Think by how many goals are we going to lose.
Once we lose, they will talk forever.
Why are you putting us into big trouble?
Trouble...
l've all the confidence on the team.
Do you all have the confidence of yourselves?
Come on... Lets go...
Look...
You all are not playing against the Mens wishes.
Come on, Get ready... Lets go...
Don't think that the match is against 1 men.
You must sbow the entire nation that women can
perform better than man.
How good are the men also,
that they don't do work.
They can'teven make simple decision.
Your match is against tbose fools...
They have forgotten, that the women has more power
that they can do anything.
Anything... mmm...
lts such a big match that
it is bigger than you and me.
Thats why l want to tell you all
''Play without fear''
Join bands and play together.
Play with all your strength.. Play like this,
Play like that... But...
l want to say one thing.
Go for it...
Foul... This is foul...
Come on girls.. Well played...
lf it is enough, we can stop the match.
Sir, the match is not yet over.
Your girls can't even reach the mens area.
What they will do? Sir What are you....... Krishna ji...
He is telling the truth.
We already told you, where this indian women wearing
these shorts can play the match.
where? You ask them?
What can you do? What will you do?
Sir, You had a big fall?
Can you get up? or you need the girls for assitance?
Well done sister... Well done..
You all played very well.. Good defence...
Well played girls...
Where should we send them to?
Oh.. Them.. Yeah...
Send them.
Yes.. Yes... Kabir.
World Championship. Yes...
Greetings. l'm Kapil varma welcomes you.
We are at the elbourne's Hockey Center and the first
match is between lndia and times world champions Australia.
Both teams are infrontof each other.
Australian team look like true champions.
Coach Kabir Khan with his contingent of players.
For the excitement of Audience,
the match is about to start.
Within the first minute Australia
got their firstgoal.
What are you doing? She will get the Card.
Balbir Kaur got an Yellow Card and the Australia got
a Penalty Corner which is dangerous for lndia.
Did you see, how rude She was?
lts not her... lts you...
No point in that. Give her some water.
Coach Kabir Khans lastchance to save
the match by replacing one player.
Sister.. Sister... Where should l pass?
Why are you asking me? Ask your Captain.
Komal.. Pass it on to me..
What are you doing?
This is the whole lndian Sickness...
Because of the confusion, australia
got another Penalty Corner.
Match is over. Autralia 7, lndia 0.
This is very shameful for lndia.
Bindya.. Bindya...
What were you doing? Me.. Where?
What were you doing on the field?
Nothing.
From now on, you will not play
the World Cup Match.
Whats so great about her?
What?
What is great she has
that l don't have?
who?
Your Captain, sir.
Since we have come so far on this issue,
lets talk freely.
There are no kids here.
Neither you nor me.
Whatever she can do for becoming captain,
l can also do the same.
Much more than that.
Now tell me sir...
Why can't l be a captain?
You have given the answer by yourself.
After the first match thrashing by Australia, lndias
chance of surviving in the tournament, looks very slim.
The only chance they have is to beat England
in tomorrows match.
Looking at their team form, there is no
hope for them to win the match.
You all must keep on
passing to one another.
You've got 2o more minutes for practice.
Welcome to Melbourne. ln today's England
from Group A playing with 2 points.
But lndia must win to save their hope
to be in the Worldcup Tournment.
The English has challenged, they will score
more goals than Australia.
Thats why, there is not enough audience on the
stadium.
lndian players got better coordination than the
previous match. But Englands forward is still attacking.
0nly 2o minutes left in the 1st balf. England has got a
Penalty corner and its a danger for lndia.
This time, lndia make no mistake.
Second half begins, against all the odds lndia
has  not conceded any goals.
Well done.. Well done...
Oh.. Unbelievable Goal...
Chautala set the ball for Priety. Long live..
Preity Long Live...
Last 20 seconds of the match...
Without anyones expectation, lndia won the match
and kept alive the chance to be in the tournament.
Well done.. Well done...
We don't know what will happen next,
but lndia has survived.
Sister.. Water please?
You want me to give you a glass?
Priety going ahead. Komal, don't let her go ahead.
Take your revenge on the next match.
Coach Kabir Khan's lndia team has surprised everyone
by going
top of the table in the tournament.
lf they win the Quarter Finals, they will
advance to the semi final. lf not they are out.
Tomorrows clash is against Argentina, a team
that plays very rough and tough and they
had injured many players in the tournament.
Take water and clean the wounds.
From this second, ball must be in our bands.
Balbir, you play your game.
Sir, l will crush them. Then you break them.
lf they beat two, you beat 4 of them.
lf they beat 4, you beat 8 or 9 of them.
Beat them nicely so that they must be scared of
holding the hockey stick.
lf anyone of them and block the way of Komal and
Preity they should dare to come again.
We will attack.
Keep on attacking until they
are broken or we.
Coach Kabir Khan's lndian team has
entered into the semi finals.
Now lndian team will be meeting Korea.
So far, no team scored against them.
Man to man marking?
Behind every opponent they keep their players.
thats is their style of game.
lf it is like that, we can't even move also. Forget
our playing the game.
lf they play like this, who will be able to break them.
There is one player.
what you say is true?
You have something extra ordinary
thats something She doesn't have.
Even others in the team don't have that.
Take this.
Why?
At this moment, lndia needs such an
experienced player like you.
Only you know how to break the
man to man markings.
The match is about to start.
Go and break them.
As expected, korean team kept their players atevery
indian forward position to lock them up.
Komal, Preity, Haliya Bose three of them can't move
forward.
Substitution. No.5 Bindya Nayak come to the field.
Suddenly the lndian team changed the game totaly.
lndian defenders moving forwad and started attacking
which has confused the Koreans.
lts a Goal...
lndia enters into the worldcup final.
From the condition of the stadium you may guess
the feelings of the lndian National Team.
and also the feeling of the coach
few months ago the indian sports authorities
refused to send them to the world cup.
Who knows the bestcentre forward of india can
make such an impact in this semifinal.
You are the one who can get high scorer
of the world championsbip trophy.
How can it be like that? Komal scored 8 Goals and
moving ahead.
You all having your own worldcup championship or
what?
Hello.. Mr. Sukhlal, please speak little bit louder.
Sister, you have done magic.
The team has done wonders. Your
blessings always with the girls.
Sister, that amleela group has come here. l told them
clearly that this is lndian Women Hockey Team's ground.
We are waiting for our team. We won't give to
anyone else. Only Hockey practised in here.
Mr. Sukblal, please talk to them.
r. Sukhlal, we always rememher your curd rice. You
bring the world cup and i'll make curd rice for the rest
of your life
Please don't lose.. Don't lose... No r.Sukhlal, we'll
come back dead but we will not lose the world cup.
Sir, what are you doing here?
Look at that.
First time l'm looking at an Englishman bringing
up the lndian flag. We have come to the final
and its not a dream.
What do you feel? lt must be a dream.
lts also a dream for you, right.
Today is an official reception nright for both the
finalists.
lnternational Hockey Federation is
hosting tonrights reception.
Tonight they will forget of winning or losing in
tomorrows final to show the world the true
spirit of sportsmanship.
ls it necessary to wear this saree?
l'll thrown water to save you from bad luck.
Nethra? What is that?
Sir is calling her.
What is it?
You mean...
Why did you call me here?
Me?
lts you who called me.
Am l crazy to call you here.
l called you all...
ls that you?
Why did you call us?
To inform you that we lose
tomorrow's match.
Why?
Because, two of our players
will make Australia to win.
No sir, Nothing like that. What do you think?
Australian coach or players are stupid?
Can't you feel that they knew two of our farward
players do not pass the ball to each other.
What do you think?
Won't they take advantage of it?
l don't know about her, but l'm with
the team. - Komal...
She also can't cheat you. Atleast
you don't cheat yourself.
You left your family and come
to delbi to play Hockey.
But you are playing
something else.
She was the one who started first.
- And you finish it on tomorrow's match.
Hey, ls this your plan?
And you...
Preity Sabarwal.
Captain of Chandigarh team
You was fainted when you wanted
to come into the team.
But now you have lost
all your sense? Why?
You are all not a child.
You know very well that, if you both don't play together we will lose the match.
The same thing happened to an lndian team at
the final that they have lost the match.
How heavy is the burdon of the lose?
You will not be able to understand.
But when you understand
You can't take it.
Both of you don't have the strength.
And no one else has that kind of strength.
You both knew whats the problem between you.
l only know that whether you
play together or not...
.. the restof the team will fight
together with australia.
lf necessary they will also
go against you.
Now both of you will play
together with the team.
Or against your team.
Whatever happens,
l'll be the leading scorer.
So, What do you want
to show me?
l am not showing it to you.
l want to show to a man, what a woman can do.
l'll be the leading scorer.
l'll see how it will happen.
The night has come for which
we all have been eagerly waiting for.
Tonright is the Womens Hockey
World Championship final.
0ne month before no one could have predicted
that such a final would happen.
Because current and times world champion team
Australia will clash with a team that has come as a
wonder...
and that team has captured heart of the
people with their performance..
A lot of difference between winning peoples
hearts and winning the world cup championship.
This is coach Kabir Khans team's biggest test.
ln today's final test what would
be Coach Kabir Khan's strategy.
will it be a magic or dream?
How could the lndian team going to win
against 6 times world cup winner
70 minutes. You only have 70 minutes.
May be this 70 minutes is
something special in your life.
Today you play well or lousy, you will rememher
this 70 minutes for the rest of your life
l'm not going to say how you
are going to play today.
l'll only say this.
You make most out of this 70 minutes.
ln outside world you may succeed or you fail, you win
or lose this tournament, nobody can take away that 70 minutes
from you.
Nobody.
l've thought that l'll not tell you how to play this match
but you are going to tell me how are you all going to play.
By playing...
Because l know in this 70 minutes, if everyone
plays hockey to the best of their life...
.. then this 70 minutes,
god also not ask you back.
Go by yourselves in this life,
from your god, and also to the person who
did not trust you take that 70 minutes.
lndian team has showed everyone at
the first minute of this match...
that they will not play like any
other underdogs team.
lts very important to score the first
goal to keep the moral
of the team, which is very clear on
the face of lndian coach.
Australia counter attacks.
Australia is notan easy team to give up, they will put
pressure which will be uneasy for indian team.
Preity...
Go and show it to the man...
End of Extra time.
We can see the smile on lndian camp because
they brought australia in this tie-breaker.
Now there is a genuine chance for lndia
to win this match by penalties.
l am reminding you that both team will be
taking 5 penalty strokes.
Whichever team scores the most, they will
be crowned as World Champion.
Preity, Bindiya, arry, Nethra
come.. Quick...
When you take the penalty,
rememher one thing.
lnstead of concentrating on the goal post,
you have to read the goal keepers mind.
The Goal will come by itself.
Come on girls... Well done..
Sir, l want Komal to take my stroke.
Komal.. Come on.. Quick.
Preity wish that you take her stroke.
lndian Teams first stroke is taken by
Nethra eddy from Andhra Pradesh.
lndia missed the first chance.
ln this shootout, every stroke is very crucial.
This is Australias turn to take the first penalty against
the lndian
Goal keeper vidya Sharma.
The short was very fast. No chance for the
goal keeper to save the goal.
Haliya Bose.
Second penalty miss for lndia.
The gap has become wide and
their hope looks slim.
0ne more goal... Australia
lead is getting higher.
lf lndia wants to stay they can't afford
to lose even single stroke.
And they have to stop the penalties
by australian side.
Komal Chauttala is coming to take the stroke.
Komal is Haryana teams Center Forward
and lndian teams right band.
lts Goal...
Vidya Sharma is ready to stop the stroke.
Raechal Taylor is ready.
There no chance for mistakes.
They can't afford to miss any of the two strokes.
lndia's nextstriker Marry alte is a
penalty shootoutspecialist.
lndia and Australia are now equal.
Now australia has two strokes and
india has got 1 stroke.
lndias last chance.
lts very important to score thats why lndias well
experienced senior player Bindya Nayak has come
to take the stroke.
This is what you call an experience player.
Not its the last stroke of this penalty sbootout.
lf australia takes this penalty properly,
this shootout will continue.
lf vidya saves this stroke,
this team will be on the lndian history.
She will shoot the ball on to the left.
But her foot is on the right side and she can
shoot the ball onto the rightside.
l think she will take the centre shot.
Vidya.. Look at me...
Ladies and Getlemen, We present to you
the new World Champions: Team lNDlA.
The lndian Womens Hockey team, who brings the
world cup came back with heroes welcome.
The man bebind their is non other than the
countries best Center Forward Kabir Khan.
Every one is jubilantand we can see on their faces.
Where is Kabir Khan?
As a tax payer, what do you want say about
r.Kabir Kban who has left 7 years ago?
As long as our country has a player like Kabir Khan,
lndian Hockey will nourish and will be recognized.
lts difficult to find such a cali her player.
Now let us hear from the Public, what they think about
Kabir Khan?
He saved our National Hockey Team. Kabir
Khan has shown us what is it to be true Hindustani.
Go for it. Go for it.. Go for it... lndia.
Go for it lndia.
Resync, Revision: M3rtins