- Happy Bayram.
- Thanks. Same to you.
- Shall I fill her up?
- Please.
Happy Bayram.
- Happy Bayram.
- Thanks. Same to you.
Can you make me one with cheese?
- What's the music?
- Its Kazim Koyuncu.
- Don't you know him?
- No.
His music is very popular
here on the Black Sea Cost.
- I've never heard of him.
- He was from Artvin.
He died of cancer two years ago.
He was young. Like you.
All because of Chernobyl.
It's only now that's becoming clear.
120, Brother.
- And a toast?
- yes.
That makes 130.
YETER'S DEATH
PROLETARIANS UNITE!
- Hello!
- Hello.
It's 50 euros for half an hour.
- What's your name?
- Jessy.
Jessy, do you do French?
French, Italian, Greek.
I'll do it international for you.
Bravo! Bravo
- Is music all right?
- Yes, why not?
- Have you got the 50 euros??
- Yes!
- Take your clothes off.
- Yes.
Are you Turkish?
- Could be...
- Now I'm ashamed.
- What's your name, girl?
- I told you: Jessy.
- And your real name?
- Yeter. That's enough.
- What's enough?
- "Yeter" means "that's enough", right?
I'm the youngest of seven sisters.
The baby of the family.
- What will you have to drink?
- Water. Water.
Where are you from?
Uncle, have you come here
to chat or to fuck?
Don't call me uncle,
that's embarrassing.
What shall I call you, then?
"My divine lover"?
Please call me Ali.
- Ali?
- Yes.
- Can you still get it up at your age?
- God willing.
Show me..
- Goodbye, my rose!
- Take care, Brother Ali!
She was speaking Turkish!
Ladies and gentlemen,
in ten minutes
we will be arriving in Bremen.
we would like to say goodbye
to all the passengers leaving us here,
and wish you a good onward journey.
Hello, Papa!
Hello Nejat. Sit yourself down.
I'm still frying the fish.
- How are you?
- Good.
- And how are you?
- Fine.
I've brought you a book.
Whats it about?
Just read it.
Are you having some raki?
- Sure, and you?
- Of course!
I've got this Iranian friend, Mahmut.
He's given me a tip
for the fourth race.
- Which horse?
- "Ofliff Sunshine"
"Ofliff Sunshine"?
Yes.
The fifth horse in the fourth race?
Do you mean "Sunshine of Life"?
- What does that mean?
- The sun of life.
It would be nice if the sun of life
would shine for us someday.
It's an outsider, Papa.
We'll see, shall we?
Yes! Yes!
the odds were at least 70 to1!
100, 200, 300, 400, 500, 600, 700, there you are.- Thank you!
Come on, I'll treat you
to ice cream, with chocolate.
Who are you screwing at the moment?
A gentleman
doesn't talk about such matters.
I didn't know that!
It's impossible to talk to you
about anything, anyway.
Take care, Papa!
Read the book, okay?
Yeah, yeah..
Goethe was opposed to the revolution.
Not on ethical grounds.
but because it seemed to him
to be too uncontrollable.
Two quotes illustrate this.
"Who wants to see a rose bloom
in the depths of winter?"
"Everything to it's own time.
Leaves, buds, flowers.
"Only a fool could want
this untimely intoxication."
Come on now, old man!
I'm not 14 any more.
I don't come that quickly.
-I'll have to charge you extra.
- I'll give you another 50!.
Talk, talk!
Tell me to grab your arse!
- Grab my arse!
Come on now, my lion!
I want to ask you something:
are you happy with your job?
I can't complain.
Look, I live on my own.
m a pensioner, and a widower, too.
What's the saying?
"Only God is entitled to solitude."
- Bravo.
m looking for a woman to live with me.
I would pay you
as much as you earn here.
In return, you'd sleep only with me.
Agreed?
Have you fallen for me, old man?
You don't have to say anything now.
Here's my cell phone number.
Call me whenever you like.
Peace be with you.
No understand.
Don't lie to me!
We heard you speaking Turkish
Or are you ashamed of being a Turk?
You're both a Moslem and a Turk,
understood?
- I'm not deaf.
- Don't try to be funny
You are on the false path.
Repent!
I repent!
Don't let me catch you there again.
It would be a shame about you.
Peace be with you.
-Peace be with you.
- And peace be with you.
He's made his move too soon.
I'm glad you came
Will you treat me to a coke?
- Of course.
Are you hungry?
When you said you'd pay me
what I earn in the brothel,
were you being serious?
How much do you earn?
I'm left with 3,000 a month.
Do you have that much?
I'll get it.
- How?
I get a pension
and I have a bit of money in the bank.
I've got
some land and property back home.
And I have a son.
He's a professor at a German university.
He earns good money.
If the worst comes to the worst, he'll help me.
- Where are you from?
- Trabzon.
Look, I won't make any demands.
All I want is for you to live with me
and sleep with me.
I am hungry after all.
Take me out to dinner!
Fine, let's go!
-The soup is delicious
- Enjoy
Where did you learn to cook so well?
I taught myself.
I was both mother and father to the boy.
I raised him.
I'll do that.
- You've brought him up well.
- Like a girl.
Here you are.
It's fish cakes. You'll love them.
Tuck in!
- How old were you when your mother died?
- He was six months.
Didn't you ever remarry?
I did, A widow with a daughter.
It didn't work out.
They're long gone.
I'm a widow too
My husband was shot in Maras in 78.
- You're from Maras?
- Yes.
More coke?
- I'll get it.
Sit yourself down.
I'll fetch it!
- Are you really a professor?
- Yes.
I'll fetch the dessert.
- I'll go.
- No, youre a guest.
- If I'm to live here, I'll have to.
- Don't drink so much, Papa.
-I'm not drinking so much.
You got me drunk deliberately!
Keep your hands off her!
Are you okay?
- Piss off!
Yeter! Where are you, Yeter?
How did you two meet?
He came to me.
How?
Hasn't he told you?
I'm a lady of easy virtue.
What does that mean?
A whore. A hooker if you like.
Good night.
Nejat!
Papa!
Hello, I'm Doctor Ozada.
Your father
has had a serious heart attack
His condition is critical.
He'll be in intensive care overnight.
We'll have to open up an artery.
When his condition improves,
we II keep him in for observation.
Do you have any questions?
Can we see him now?
- I'm afraid not.
Any excitement
isn't good for him right now.
Come back again in the morning, okay?
Do you have any children?
I have a daughter.
How old is she?
-27.
II
Does she know what you do?
She thinks I work in a shoe shop.
I often send her shoes.
I'd do anything for her.
I didnt t want her to be uneducated
I wanted her to study
and become like you.
Getting old is evil.
There's absolutely
nothing good about it
It's completely pointless.
- You'll soon be okay.
- Right...
Don't forget to water the tomatoes.
Nejat,
the tomatoes are ripe for plucking.
Do you want one
- Just to try.
Let's take him some!
What's wrong?
I miss my daughter.
haven t heard her voice for so long.
I can't get hold of her for some reason.
Did you screw her?
Ive made some borek.
Would you like some?
Take that away.
I don't want any borek.
Don't look at me like that.
The doctor said   "No pastry"
- Then eat shit!
You won t eat borek, but you smoke.
Are you taking the piss?
Don't get involved in my life.
You have yours and I have mine.
You re leaving?
Wait!
Here, for the journey.
Yeter!
Get me a raki, girl.
We will soon be arriving in Hamburg.
Your connections...
Did you screw him?
I asked you a question.
You're drunk.
No, I'm not.
Don't touch me!
Stop that!
I've paid you,
and I'll fuck you whenever I like!
You don t own me
- Yes, I do.
I own you!
Go on, give me a French job.
You can shove your money up your arse.
Where are you going?
Where?
I'll go wherever I want.
You're not going anywhere!
You're not going!
-I'll say it again: I'll go wherever
I want. Ive seen plenty like you.
Yeter?
Yeter!
Then here to the right
And stop
So, then you go in here, please.
It's small.
- Yes, I'm afraid so.
So, in you go.
You II be given
your personal items later.
So, goodbye
We haven t seen Ayten for a long time.
She's disappeared.
- Since when?
- A few months.
That's her.
Don't you have a more recent photo?
- No.
I'm afraid not.
have A look yourself.
Very sweet.
- What was she studying?
- Economics...
- Medicine...
- No, sociology.
- Economics or medicine?
- To be honest, I don't know.
Enough now!
- Can I have the photo?
- But that s her mother...
Take it.
- Where will you stay, cousin?
- In a hotel.
Stay at my place.
It's okay.
- I'm serious!
- I'm happy of my own.
How long will you stay
- Until I've found her.
With 20 million people in Istanbul,
you're sure to run into her.
Name? '
- Ayten Ozturk.
Place of origin?
- Either Maras or Istanbul.
Kahramanmaras.......
One moment, please!
Name?
- Ayten Ozturk.
I meant your name.
- Nejat. Nejat Aksu.
Why are you looking for the girl?
I want to finance her studies.
Why?
Because knowledge and education
are human rights.
Well put.
Listen, Nejat.
The streets, these case files,
are full of Kurdish children.
We deal with them every day.
They are illiterate
and have to turn to violence.
Wouldn't you rather
help one of them?
What good will this do?
- Maybe someone will get in touch.
.
FOR SALE
Shall we have a look inside?
I don't understand books.
Especially not in German.
I'm off to my workshop.
If you need me, give me a call.
I'll take the things with me.
See you soon!
Good afternoon.
Is this your bookshop?
- Yes.
Do you like it?
- Yes
..a lot.
I'm glad.
- My name's Markus Obermuller.
- I'm Nejat Aksu.
Would you like a cay?
-  Thanks.
Or rather a mocha?
- Cay is fine.
Cengiz,
can you bring us two teas, please?
Please have a seat.
Why do you want to sell such a lovely shop?
- You know...
I've been here for about ten years.
And all of a sudden...
find myself missing Germany,
and the language as well,
Even though I'm surrounded by it here,
with all this literature.
But it's...
like a museum here.
Extinct. Like Latin.
And I've been feeling...
homesick.
I understand.
How much would it cost?
What was your name again?
Nejat Aksu.
What's your occupation?
m a professor of German in Germany.
- That would be funny, if...
A Turkish professor of German
from Germany
ends up in a German bookshop in Turkey.
That fits!
Yes, maybe...
So you're staying in Turkey
for the time being.
Yes.
What about your work?
Maybe teaching isn t my calling.
What about your father?
A murderer is not my father.
LOTTE'S DEATH
Ocalan, we are with you!
Long live the partisan struggle!
The rights of people
cannot be stopped!
A cop!
Pursuing person with gun
Reinforcements to Dilek Cafe!
Fuck!
Who's been arrested?
Ozlem, too?
Police!
Down on the floor!
Don't move!
What's up? You can't just...
Long live our resistance!
My name is Oznur,
Oznur Kulak!
My name  is Gokce Tuna!
I am Nurhan Ertas!
- Hello.
- Welcome!
- What's the name in your passport?
- Gul Korkmaz.
Always use that name,
never your real one.
if you use the bus or subway, never
ride black. -What does that mean?
You have to buy a ticker
If you get stopped by the police,
you don t know us.
All right.
If you want to shower.
go to the swimming pool.
The girls will show you.
The cheapest food is at the university.
You can eat there for three euros.
This is where you sleep.
Do you have money?
About 20 euros.
You could work for me.
- As what?
- You look like a waitress.
- is Bremen far away from here?
- About an hour on the train.
Can you lend me some money?
I'll give it back tomorrow.
How much do you want?
- 100 will do.
Thanks.
Foot...
Shoe...
SHOES
So now what?
You owe me money.
You'll have to work for me now.
Call yourself a comrade?
Get all uptight about 100 euros!
Who do you think you re talking to?
- How would I know?
Throw her out right, now!
- Clear off
Okay. I'll go on my own.!
To hell with the lot of you!
"Who wants to see a rose bloom
in the depths of winter?
"Everything to its own time.
Leaves, buds, flowers.
"Only a fool could want
this untimely intoxication."
Secondly:
"I am opposed to revolutions
for they destroy as many good old
things as they create good new ones".
Hello, Mama.
This is Gul.
She'll be staying with us for a while.
Very, generous of you, letting a stranger
come and stay with us.
We have to help her, Mama.
- You don't even know her.
That's so German, Mama.
She's illegal here.
She's persecuted in her country.
Then she should apply for asylum.
yeah, and what if she's not granted it?
You know that is punishable.
Would you be kind enough
to make her bed??