And let Columbus lost his way and
not the first discovered America.
Anyway .. he is my hero.
He courageously held his tiny
ship through the vast ocean.
And now, the day of Columbus,
we do not go to school.
Thank you, Heather. Ronnie?
Tell us about your hero.
What is he writing?
Hatiko dog was my grandfather.
Many called Hati dog puzzle.
Because no one knew
where it came from.
Perhaps it escaped from a dog shelter.
Maybe - jumped from the car
somewhere far away.
In Florida or New Jersey.
No matter how, but Hati lost.
No matter how it happened.
But once, long ago, in the city,
lived grandfather
Hati appeared on the station.
They began their history.
Six days? A lot.
I'll miss. Yes.
Excellent, a lot of music.
No, no, I'll walk on foot.
Yes, I love you, too. While.
Hey, buddy, lost?
Come here.
Come ...
Lost, kid.
Certainly, you are looking for.
He then ran from you.
- What platform?
- Yes, on the platform.
Good thing you found it.
Yes. Well ...
You know, there was a box, broken.
I do not know whose it was, but ...
Some of them certainly will.
- Yes, clearly. - Let it foe you.
While it does not take away.
But ... No, I can not.
- What? - I can not, Professor.
He ran here.
Such dogs do not throw it ...
Yes, of course not. This is not quitting,
someone will follow.
Take it to him. And those who show up --
I say that dog you have.
But something will come to you.
You do not understand. He will
hold here, maybe all night,
If no one comes.
No one will be, I'll lock it, it will
safe until morning, but ...
Tomorrow I have to hand it to the shelter.
Well, that Friday today.
Know where you went ... Meanwhile
stay with me.
In a warm house, plenty of company.
Getting It Right.
What? Yes, you like it.
Sh-sh-sh ...
So.
Here, sit here.
Only here, okay? Yes, that's it.
Ok. Lie, lie ...
Rui, it can be.
Hello, handsome.
- Hello. - Hello.
- How was it? - Excellent.
- I am glad I missed?
- Not a bit, and you?
No, not remembered.
And for you a surprise.
Yes, I also have a small
surprise for you.
Come on, it's time to catch up.
Catch up - it's great.
Heard anything?
Probably, the branch is knocking at the window.
- Quiet, quiet, quiet, all right.
- Parker!
- We agreed! - I know, I know ...
- Have you forgotten that?
- Well, nothing I have not forgotten.
No, I just found him at the station,
he lost.
Karl wanted to send him to doggy
shelter and I thought ...
Bring the puppy home and to persuade me
leave it, right?
No, no, I do not want him to leave, no.
Tomorrow morning I'll find out where exactly
he was taken, right?
I promise you I will do that.
Here, these were the things Lucas.
Now, now.
So, we climb.
Look how many interesting things here.
Warm on.
Here is cool.
Like it? Luke loved her very much.
Look, there's water.
You could tell a lot, yes?
Could?
Okay, buddy.
Not bad.
Zasypay.
You need a very doghouse.
I love the finger does not bite, I promise.
Hey, puppy, puppy!
Hey, baby, smile.
Excellent! UUU, beautiful doggie!
Dad, I like him.
He has a name?
Yes. Temporary Guest.
Leave him alone, the house was empty since
as Lucas is not.
Ask your mother.
Mom!
Yes?
Come here, please.
He is on your music taste.
Really? Incredibly, it Bunder-dog!
And I must leave him.
Do not pass. And you - do not get it.
I will not.
You besides.
Dad, he will jump out of here, here.
Yes, it's better.
You got, boy?
So, well, well, class.
With Michael met?
Yes, we went to the observation seen
starfall. It was beautiful.
How romantic.
Very.
And you do not ...
Something to help?
Yes, I found yesterday this kid on
station, not hold, until the owner ...
Hold? No, this is not an inn,
a dog shelter, buddy.
I just found it, what should I do?
Give a look.
Cute, new owners find
can, but ...
We give them two weeks.
Two weeks?
Yes, there is no place.
Sorry.
I'll call you in a week,
well, not yet.
- Hi, Maryann.
- How are you, Parker?
Wonderful. To be honest, I would
you something to ask.
Anything.
Oh, well, I must!
Hey, baby, hello, Priva-o!
He's handsome! Where are you from?
Yes he was there yesterday, I wandered to the station ...
I do not know, it's all very strange.
Really? He is so cute!
I want to hang it from you.
Yes, well, well.
Parker, this puppy is just fabulous!
You would not want that?
What, me take?
Such a beautiful puppy.
What do you think, Anthony?
How do you like the new neighbor?
Impossible, Anthony!
Sit quietly.
Good morning, Professor.
Jess.
You a sugar, 2 servings of cream ...
Oh, who are you?
A new friend, do not take?
I prefer cash.
Grow a great guard dog.
This is to guard the hot dogs?
I do not think so.
Ha-ha, and I do not think so.
No, who will now take the dog, eh?
Its because I have to feed, to walk, wash,
pick her ...
I'll take it for him?
On the house.
Take a little more.
Yeah, right, thank you, Jess.
Health.
There is news?
No, there was nobody who would come
or call.
Nobody?
Strange, really strange.
Do not hold?
Kate has published ads
hang help?
Oh please.
Well, I'll help hang.
You have a sensitive soul.
I know.
And in a backpack he likes.
Professor in the train any dog.
- No dogs.
- I hope.
For a moment, I have something to show.
Skip to repeat the first part and immediately
go to the lyric.
Okay.
Better so.
But it does mean that you have to play
faster in pace.
And come to the lyrical part, then ...
They need a deep sigh.
Hi.
Excellent.
Puppy will not take?
- Well, let's go again.
- Yes, at first.
This is all that is left on the box.
"Yamanashi", the rest is torn off.
- What is it?
- The area in central Japan.
- Unusual dog, Parker.
- Exactly.
This Akita, Akita, as they say you have.
- A special breed.
- Yes?
- And what's this?
- Hati.
- What?
- In Japanese, it is 8, a lucky number.
And, happy? Lucky.
Hati ... Hati, good name, agree?
Evidently, he's eighth in a litter was born.
In the mystical meaning of number 8 - stretching
to the heavens, falls to the ground.
Well, as you take?
Himself? No. I think he made a choice.
In what sense?
The fact that now he's your problem,
not my brother.
You are not a problem, right?
Well, maybe you found it
can - it you.
Who knows? Hence, it should be.
And he said that the shoguns grew
Akita for fighting and hunting.
In a sense, this royal breed.
Ken did not tell you where to find
His Majesty's house?
I hung for 10 ads.
Someone will take his Hati.
Hati?
This ... It was on the collar, a symbol.
You gave him a name?
- No, I ...
- You want him to leave.
- Do you want you want.
I do not want him to leave, I just ...
Confess yourself - do you want
take it to us.
I did not even think not.
Hati?
Where you go?
Lord
Oh no ... Parker, a few months
hard work!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
He will be on the streets all night, Parker said.
These do not let you hear me?
No objections!
I hear, I hear you.
I heard all good.
- It's two months of work!
- Believe me, I'm sorry.
The work is important not only for me,
it is important for the city!
For mnya too.
I am over this model 4 months worked.
No, you do not care what I do.
Yes, you just spit on it!
Kate, this is not true.
Not calmed me!
Hati.
Come on, buddy, come to me. Me.
Yes, you'll go to the house.
And it will take with them.
Akita.
So, where are you?
Yes. Here's what you have.
Your breed at least 4000 years
maybe more.
Yes? What else here?
How did you do?
They write that the first animal,
became friendly with people, you were.
You knew about this? I knew it, tell me.
You know, yes, you know, of course he knew.
Well everything off.
It is necessary to find a place for you.
Thus, there seems to be bad, eh?
Okay, go. Stay here, okay?
Sit quietly. Now ...
essence combination is
not to give beats to knock
ball infel.
Let's see if this works
tactics this time.
All right, sit with you.
bad. The gap decreased
to one point.
Catch!
Come on.
Forgive me, please.
Just do not need ...
- I just climbed up.
- Yes, yes, of course.
For one night, only one, okay?
Let's sleep?
Stay here, everything will be fine.
Unbelievable. He is a fan of "Yankees."
No.
- Yes, honestly.
- Really?
Oh, it will be fun.
Thus, Hati, will play.
This is a ball. Ball.
Throw, you bring it to me
back, okay?
Yes, ready?
Come on, catch.
No, no, no, the ball.
Hati, Hati! Hati, no. Hey, Hati!
I'll throw, and you bring it, okay? Come on.
Brought.
Hati, no, take the ball!
Hati, to me! To me, Hati!
Come on, take, take. Hati, Hati!
Come on, this ball, you take.
Come on, Hati. Me. You also can,
I'm sure.
You know, you're too harsh with them.
Dog in trouble, and the father wants
do a good deed.
Okay, let's see.
Mam.
Ball, ball, ball, ball! You have to take.
See how.
He sdurel.
Hello?
You are on your ad, yes? Are you a dog owner?
No, no one has yet declared. We
want to see it was in good hands.
But what if you leave your number
My husband will call you back.
One second, I'll find a pen, right?
Hello.
No, the puppy is already taken.
Yes, I'm terribly sorry.
Ow! No, no, no, Hati!
Hati! Hati, Hati!
Well, come on, bring it here. Bring.
No, you can not. Not.
I'm going to work.
See you in the evening, yet.
Good morning, Professor.
You are now delayed.
I've already done - one sugar
Two cream.
before train left for 3 minutes
asked passengers to take their seats.
Sorry, sorry.
Hati!
What are you doing here? What are you doing?
What?
Go home, okay? Go.
Yes, I know, go, go on. "
Home, come on, I must go, go, go.
Come on, come on, I gotta go. Come.
Hey, Professor. Want detain
administration?
And you can?
30 seconds.
Thanks.
Home, home! Okay? Rather, go home!
Hey, Chuck, will hold a little train, okay?
Home, home! Go, go! Come home!
That's Training, yes?
Good girl!
E. .. professor.
Oh, no.
Okay.
- Nothing, thank you.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, yes, thank you.
Okay, let's go, send.
Maybe call a taxi?
No, I'll walk, all right.
Oh, God.
Parker? You've gone to work.
- Gone.
- And so in the garden, dig?
He ran away and I came back.
Do not say, do not, I know
you say.
Stained, I myself finishing touches.
I will bury, and you go.
Okay, thank you.
And you - wait here.
- We'll wait.
- Until the evening before.
Help yourself.
Well, okay, I will give another.
One, not more.
Wait, wait.
Well? Tasty, yes?
Well, well, now ... is the last.
Here, chew. Clever, Hati.
Persuaded, the most recent.
Keep all.
Well, I'm proud of you, fine.
- Finally.
- And the ending to be repeated.
- And forgive me for being late, okay?
- No problem.
- No penalty will be?
- No, we will not.
Well, thank you.
Hey, Hati! What are you doing here?
You with sugar?
- Chuck.
- Good luck.
Hey, Hati!
How did you get here was?
Station Beydridzh.
Yes, yes, Mom, there is a train at 7:30.
- He was there all day?
- No, 2 minutes he came and got there.
Are you kidding? With it Kate?
I have not seen it.
A. .. Okay.
Ok. Then go home.
That same wretch.
Come on, come home, baby.
Mom!
Yes, dear? I'm here.
Hey, hello!
- I brought the chips.
- Excellent.
Mrs. Wilson, glad to meet.
Oh, Michael, I too! Call me Kate.
Ok.
Looks appetizing.
Take this to the Pope.
- Now?
- Yes, he was in the backyard.
Well, there you have a grill?
Grill there, yes. Glad to see you.
I am glad.
- Cut?
- Yes, less often, my dear. And where is ...
You know, I wanted to play the guitar
learned this in childhood.
Seriously?
Yes, I was nine or ten years.
But brother pinched my fingers
car door and I threw it away.
Came out by accident, but after that
I stopped studying.
I do not know, probably nothing. Because I
love music
... and am with great respect to
musicians and everyone who plays.
Michael, do you love my daughter?
Yes, sir ... Yes, very.
Ok. This is something that will help you
in the hard days.
Right.
Hati is Michael. Michael, Hati.
Glad to meet you.
Hati, hey, want to play, eh?
Yes? Okay, ready? Catch the ball!
Come on out, bring it over there!
Next, Hati! Run after him!
Come on, bring the ball!
Michael, you want to return the ball - go down
him myself, Hati not bring.
He is the sword does not run.
Sunny.
How are you, Michael?
All is well.
Darling, are you all right?
Play.
Not hurt, exactly?
Not at all.
I'm all right, look.
- The leg is not sprained?
- To play without me.
Ok.
I throw the ball half a meter,
you bring, eh?
Even if I throw a ball alongside,
it still will not bring?
I died.
Ball?
Yes, the ball. I throw that he brought
but he does not want.
Not Akita, Parker.
They have something against the balls?
No, but that the ball ran - head
collie or sprinter-spanielya.
No, Hati quite suits me,
I am satisfied.
Well, because the Akita did not seek
someone like.
And what do they want?
He comes to the train, because
special connection between you.
And then, "Hey, buddy, bring the ball!" --
why?
Well, for fun. And maybe for cookies.
To me, please, finally.
They do not buy - they are Japanese,
not the Americans.
Yes, all this nonsense.
If he brings the ball - on this he
be a special reason.
I told him find her.
No, no, no, no, Hati, home.
You stay, I'm sorry, not me.
No, wait.
Okay, let's go.
It is possible, let's go.
- Good morning, Milton.
- Good morning.
I am glad to see.
- Moira.
- Hey, Parker.
Hiding from the sun?
Caution, next.
- Good morning, Professor.
- Good morning, Parker!
But he did not grasp?
No, no, he was brought up.
To me, kid.
And now you go home, yes, home.
Do you understand me?
See you in the evening, and now go home.
Clever.
- Have a nice day, Karl.
- Both sides, professor.
Hati.
Take it. Only sh-sh-sh ...
Do not say Milton, okay?
Welcome to Hati.
You're waiting for me all day and think
"Oh, how good I am, how good I am!
Hey, Hati!
More champagne!
Let bring champagne.
I could, well ... I do not know.
Should be in the kitchen.
As if other than us at the wedding
no one.
Boy, girl, boy, girl.
You love the snow, huh?
Let's take a walk, you and me.
Only two of us, we go.
Tell me about something.
Hati!
That's great, Jake.
Thanks.
Kate! Not seen Hati?
He was not at the station.
No, I did not see in the morning ...
Come here.
Look at her.
30 years she was hidden from the eyes.
Beauty, eh?
Yes, good.
- I schedule lag.
- You catch up.
Imagine opening night, it's you bent take flight.
The young singer goes on stage
sings an aria from La Bohme.
More ballet, of course. Then, rock,
rap, hip-hop, jazz and ... Hamlet!
Then, of course, all the citizens
leapt from their seats, applauding
and rave of happiness.
Mayor finds you, takes the stage
puts at the center and thanked
for what you have done the impossible.
Yes?
Yes.
I like it.
Hati!
To me, baby!
Hati?
Ha-atm.
What are you doing here?
So ... right.
Sit down, sit, Hati, quietly.
Sh-sh-sh, do not bother me.
Hey, go, go, get out!
Well, okay.
Let's go, go, go, go!
Parker!
We were attacked skunk.
Not want to join?
No, I will refrain.
Well, okay.
Better open the window at night.
From us true stinks?
Perhaps you're right.
Mom!
Oh, hello, dear!
What happened?
I must have something to say.
Guess.
What?
Okay, wait.
Do you see changes?
No.
Yes!
It's wonderful, darling!
Oh, what wonderful news!
I called my grandmother, immediately!
Where is Dad?
Where normally.
Dad!
Father!
What are you doing?
This full body massage,
everything by the book, see?
You will soon become a grandfather.
It is necessary to dive deeper into the muscle ...
Father, father!
I will soon be a child.
I am pregnant.
You ...
What, seriously?
Yes.
You'll have a baby?
I'll be a grandfather.
Kathy, I can not believe it!
Hello, dear.
Hi, I'm sorry I'm late.
Oh, what is it?
A lot of useful products for you.
Fresh vegetables, raspberries, pita with mare's milk,
germinated cereals ...
When I was pregnant with you, I'm chasing
your father for a pizza with anchovies
and red pepper, and ate, ate, ate ...
He's not able to watch.
You yourself believe something that lived
with his father 25 years?
We are together longer than separately.
Wow.
Dad told me that after the first
Good-bye, returning to the car,
managed so bored that he returned
to see you back.
I remember watching him from the window.
She saw that he turned back and barely
not rushed out the door to hug him.
- Vain restrained.
- I know.
But I always think too much.
Yes, exactly. As no one.
- So do not do.
- I will not.
Ok.
Hey, Hati! To me, Hati, to me!
He always greets him there?
Look.
Is not it strange?
Hello, Professor.
Good evening, Parker!
Good evening, Mary.
How do you teach this dog?
Surprisingly, and in fact every day.
Parker!
You are too gorgeous.
Well, I can still somehow
correct.
Thanks.
Would you like something else, madam?
It depends on what you have.
All.
All?
Yes. All.
You're a lot to me had such a time, I know.
I do not remember if I thanked you at least once.
I love you so much.
And I love you.
Strange.
Especially when you do not smell
as a dog or a skunk.
What happens not too often
and it pleases me.
Okay? Yes, it smells of you
so constantly!
- I love you.
- And I love you, yet.
Okay, Hati, go!
Hati, go!
Come on, Hati, what is?
What's wrong?
To me, me! Come on.
Tell me, what's wrong.
Do you have something wrong?
Looks good. What, eh?
Are you well? Yes. Well, are you going?
What is wrong with him?
I do not know.
Hati, decide. I have to leave
working day. Come on, buddy.
I left.
- No, dear.
- So long, until the evening.
Last chance.
Bye!
- Hi, Maryann.
- And, Jess, good morning.
- I brought you coffee and donuts.
- Fine, thank you. - Health.
Where Hati?
Hey, Hati!
Ah, here it is.
Oh, how glad I am to see you.
What do you bring your ball?
Where do they get the ball?
Want to play? Look.
Ready? Come on.
Take it, take it.
Excellent, bring it to me!
Oh, I must! This is what I wanted.
Come again, farther away. I'll give up on.
You're doing fine! That way, bring back.
Oh-oh, how clever! Good girl!
You're just a lad! Did you see?
Hmm?
I threw the ball, and it brought!
First time offered! He brought the ball! Yes!
Big day.
Thanks. Good dog!
Okay, I went. Take them, it's yours.
For the first time brought.
Heh, first time!
No, no, no, wait, Professor!
I'll instantly make you a coffee!
Ok.
Sorry, that was delayed.
We saw what he did?
I threw him the ball and he brought.
No, not seen.
Take the ball.
Do you want me to take? I can not play,
I must go. At work time.
Take it with you, okay?
Done.
- Yes, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- See you at 5.
- I will be in place.
Home, Hati! Home!
OK, go here. To me, baby, to me.
All right, all right.
See you at 5, go?
Yes, clever. All run home.
Now things are better there?
Laughter.
- much! - If such
possible. - We would do!
Ok. Remember, we talked to you about
John Philip Suso?
Writers marches, who lived
at the turn of the century.
He was famous, but did not recognize
recording.
And his music no one is allowed
record.
Beginning with Thomas Edison
when he brought him to his new
invention - the phonograph.
But Edison's ban did not stop and he
secretly recorded his march to the performance
orchestra at the parade.
It seems that this was the first
pirate recording.
So what do you think?
Was Suso rights?
And what now? Perhaps today
implementing adequate leave,
plugging in your CD-player to the amplifier
on stage ... And? Enough?
I do not know.
I am a lot older than you, but is inclined to believe
that there is something special in music.
Defies record. Life can
record, the heart can not be written.
The moment of creation is elusive in nature.
Lord
What's wrong with him?
It looks like a heart attack.
Welcome to Hati. How are you?
Hello, Hati!
Until tomorrow, Hati.
So far, Hati.
Hey, buddy.
Will you go home?
Hey, Hati.
How are you, kid?
Not so, as he did?
Forgive me, I learn.
Andy! We must go, dear.
Well, boy, wait here, okay?
We return.
I said that the soul is not more than the body.
And I said, that the body is no more
the soul.
And nobody, even God, no higher than
each of us for himself.
In every thing I hear and see God.
But do not understand it.
I can not just believe that there is
Someone wonderful to me.
I see God in the faces of men and women,
and on my face in the mirror.
I find letters from God on the street
and each has his signature.
But let them remain where they were.
For I know that wherever I go, I
will accurately deliver the same.
Forever and ever.
Listen, do not have to wait for him.
He did not return.
Well, Hati. You better know
what to do.
Come on, buddy, come on, come on.
Come on, baby, come.
Come on, Hati, go here. You will
live with us. Come on, come on.
It's time to go, Ronnie's been waiting for.
Come on, Hati, jump, jump here.
What a good boy.
Done, Hati.
Hey, my stalwart! Andy?
Hati!
Andy!
What, dear?
Hati! Hati, come back!
Another four will no longer be climbed.
Hey, think you have the first guest.
Hello, friend, went to the performed
our new house?
We started from the top, where almost everything is ready.
Yes, but something with a basement do?
Cellar has long been ready.
Donut with chocolate icing.
No, I do not like chocolate.
Hey, Hati, what are you doing here?
Just take a look ...
See, goes to his place.
- I thought it was taken away.
- So it was.
- Probably hungry.
-Oh, good-natured you, Jess.
We must give him a little.
Hey, Hati! Hot dog are you?
Here, eat a hot dog.
Maybe he does not like your kitchen?
Berry, delicious. This Jess prepared,
you like.
From here he come from?
Just come. Come on, baby, eat.
Be careful, Hati. Some
its hot dogs older than you.
And, no, do not listen to him.
Hati!
Oh, God.
Hi! Oh, how I was worried about you ...
I need you.
And what is it revolves around him?
This professor's daughter.
He probably lived with them.
And Hati ran out?
Appears.
Oh, dear God ...
Let's go home.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, she drags him along!
Quietly, they own.
- Come on.
- Come on, buddy.
Thank you very much.
It will be better. Pour me some coffee.
Jess, come on, pour me some coffee.
I also remember him. Every day.
Hey.
Hati, you know that we love you
and we want you to stay with us.
But if you need to go, we understand.
Ok.
Farewell, Hati.
Good day, Hati.
Hey, Hati! Here, take this. Only
not tell Myra, okay?
Good night, Hati.
- Good morning, Jess.
- Hello, what now?
- I think a big hot dog and two donuts.
- Good.
Be careful, hot.
Lucky, me!
Come on, sweetie. Hey, Lucky!
Your coffee, enjoy your meal.
Oh, excuse me, sir. That dog ...
Yes?
This accident is not the dog, which
all say?
And what do you care?
Oh, sorry, I am Teddy Bartz, reporter.
Yes, I have heard a lot about him from fellow travelers.
I do not know, but you can do
good story.
I Boliens, Carl Boliens.
B-to-i-l-i-e-n-a.
- Not through E.
- Got it.
This I found him and handed over to other hands.
Yes?
And where now, Charles ... Where does he live?
Well ... Nobody knows exactly
somewhere comes.
- He does not chase away?
- No, I used to.
He does everything as needed.
And I can take a picture? For reportage.
Oh, I do not mind.
Hati, you do not mind?
Thank you, very well.
E. .. First, a single shot.
No dog? Okay. Sit.
Hmm ... No, I ...
And, yes, okay, as you know.
I am grateful to you, you are very kind.
Well, now, together.
About! Yes, well.
Look there, do not turn away.
Smile ... Wonderful.
"A devoted dog waiting for the return
deceased owner.
Hey, Hati.
The lad from Delhi has sent you money,
that he was given for breakfast.
So I bought you food.
This is the third week.
If it goes, I'm in the bank
account is opened.
Just do not say that I'm not fed.
Doggie something we succeed.
Look, is not it dear?
Welcome to Hati.
- Where are you going to do with the money?
- I am his guardian.
- I am now.
- Thank you.
Hati. Hello. How are you?
You are here, Hati. This is for you.
Hungry, and.
Yes, it's so cold to eat.
I'm Jess, keep a stall here.
Ken-Fyuts Esi, a friend of Professor Wilson.
A friend of the professor?
One sugar, two of cream.
You must have read the article.
Read.
Saw my name there?
Yes, I did. This ...
Twice.
Can I help with the costs?
No, I beg you, do not need money.
And if he falls ill? For treatment.
Let us collect. Passengers will, sellers.
We all take care of him.
This area became home to Hati.
He comes into place in time.
Every day.
Look closely behind him.
We are behind him?
Sure.
Okay, go. And then hotdogs me
waiting for.
Glad acquaintance.
Me too. And thanks.
A year has passed, right?
Sometimes I wake up in the night
and remember Parker. He was a good
another.
I understand how you feel.
Hati, my friend Parker never
not return home.
But if Hatiko want to wait, then
Hatiko to wait.
You do want?
Dolgikh old are you, Hati.
Well, mister, for now, eat.
Good boy.
Want more? Here, take this.
Here you go, baby, the last piece.
Tasty, yes?
This is where you all bought it?
Oh, thank you, that you met me ...
Until tomorrow, Hati.
Chao, Hati.
Thanks.
As usual, eh?
Why you ever not take
chicken wings?
Hey, this ...
Mustard?
Mrs. Wilson? Glad to see you.
Hello.
Hey, this is the professor's wife, yes?
Today
The Merchant of Venice
Parker Wilson
A loving husband and father
Kate.
Ken ...
Much time has passed.
Yes, a lot.
10 years. It is hard to believe.
Welcome to Hati.
Good day, Hati.
Coffee without sugar, and do not put in hot dog
mustard. Ketchup is the best.
Well, here's the best.
Hati?
Hati ...
Oh, old man, are you still waiting for? ..
Good boy.
All true.
Can I wait with you
the next train?
Yes?
Thanks.
Oh, Hati ...
Tiny.
Like it?
Yes.
But look here.
Oh, it's me.
This I remember well. I remember the day,
when did this picture.
What is he wonderful.
Oh, is he at the wedding.
Yes, here it is. And.
And where my grandfather found Hati?
Ronnie, in fact it is found Hati
your grandfather.
How so?
One evening my grandfather
returning home.
Came out of the train and the platform,
among ...
Hey, wake up.
Hey, baby.
Hey, let's go. Rather, come on!
Hati!
Hey, kid!
I do not remember his grandfather, he died
I was very young.
But when I hear a story about him and Hati,
I think I know him.
They taught me to appreciate their loyalty and
never forget those whom you love.
So Hati forever my hero.
Look how he was glad to see you.
Go you?
To me, Hati, let's go.
This Hatiko was born in Japan
Odate city in 1923.
Its owner, Dr. Isabura Ueno,
professor of Tokyo University,
died in May 1925.
Hati returned to the station Shibui
and waited for him there 9 years.
Hatiko died in March 1934.
Today a bronze statue waiting Hatiko
standing at the railway station Shibui.