Made by Dragos
OK
Thanks.
Could you help me?
Did Marius gave you this fish bowl, like this?
There are other fish.
What a weird picture.
Listen, can you ask Daniela to feed them while we're away?
They're just fish. Nothing can happen if they are not fed a couple of days.
Did you take the toothpaste?
Yes, and some cotton absorbent too. You'll get another.
-Do you have some soap left? -Check in the drawer.
-There is no more.
-I'll get it for you. I'll be out for cigarettes anyway.
-Get some Amo or Lux. No more Palmolive, I got dandruff because of it.
-Could you go to Petronela and get my hairdryer?
-You're packing as if you're mountain tripping.
-Do you have any money left?
-Check the jeans. It's a wallet in the backpocket.
-That's where you keep your money, in a wallet?
-Better than hanging out of the pockets like you're used to.
-Close the damn door. It's draught.
-Did you see Petronela? -She was in the shower earlier.
-Hot water? -Yup
-Petronela? -Not in here.
-Otilia? -Yea.
-What is it?
-The teacher noticed you were not around on Thursday.
-Didn't I ask you to bail me out?
-I tried. But she said she heard that one two weeks ago.
-She said you'd better bring a waiver. -I will
-Does she smoke? - Vikent.
-It's open.
-Morning. Did you start already?
-It's wednesday. With the lecturer.
-'The thorn birds' with Richard Chamberlain. Tonight if you want.
-How is Gabi? -She's depilating.
-I want an Assos and a Kent. -Don't have Kent.
-Where can I find some? - You can't, I got some Marlboro instead.
- What am I to do with it? Give me an Assos and a Lux.
-Anything else? -A Tictac. An orange one.
-That's on me. -Thanks.
-If you change your mind, you're wellcome tonight. Ramona is coming too.
-Not really.
-They're so cute. Are they yours?
-No, I found them yesterday near the powerstation. Do you want one?
-I can't. Gabi is allergic to cats.
-What do you feed them? - Some dumplings yesterday night.
- I'll get some powder milk for them. - Thanks.
-Hey girls. Tell Gabi her father phoned and said he'll be here tomorrow around 10.
-I'll tell her. -Thanks.
-Your father called. He'll be here. -Damn.
-Did you tell you parents? -Tell them what?
-He's supposed to be here at 10.
-I can't figure out what to do about this exam.
- You'll take it another day.
-Should I take some notes to read?
-No point to do that.
-Didn't you have some powder milk? -It's in the nesscaffee can.
-How much do I owe you? -80.
-Here is the powder milk.
-Is it a girl? -Yup.
-How much is rexona? - 50
- Do you have Kent? -No, ask Radu.
-And the blister? -25.
-Progesterol. Is it good?
-German, made in Hungary under license.
-How come you know?
-My cousin told me. She uses them, not me.  I'm too fat anyway
-Expensive. Do you find any buyers?
-No doubt about it. Instantly.
-I'm leaving. I have to dye my hair. Red head
-Really? -Kidding, actually I put on nut concoction cause my hair is thinning
-Hey, can you tell Petronela to bring the hair dryer?
-She's taking an exam. I'll bring it later.
-Bye, good luck. -Bye
-When are you going to meet Adi? -At 11.
-I think I have fever. -Take an aspirin.
-I think it's my bad tooth. I need painkillers. Vial painkillers.
-Check the kit. Maybe there is some left.
-What a bad timing. I have an appointment at the dentist.
-No time for that.
-Can I ask you something? -Say it.
-Could you deal with the money part? You know I am not even able to bribe a ticket collector.
-I'll deal with it.
-Here is the money, count it.-2700, right?
-Yes.
-My stomach aches. -Eat something.
- Eat what?I can't eat anything.
-Don't worry. Everything will be allright.
-Come on, enough. Bye
-Don't turn back. It bodes bad. -I forgot the adress.
-Stop being superstitious. You're not from the country side.
-You know something, I'll bring some notes with me after all.
-Then bring them.
-Tickets please! Let me see your tickets please.
-Do you have a spare ticket? - No.
-Tickets please
-Excuse me. Did Ady get in?
-What are you doing? Learning?
-Perusing those abstracts.
-Did anyone get in?
-It started late. They couldn't find the key to the classroom.
-Stop. Your classmates can see us.
-So what? - I'm embarrassed.
-Listen, Diana asked if we wanted to swap the trips.
-So that she goes to Izvor and we go to Costinesti.
-The same timetable? -Not really.
- 7-14 Izvor, 15-22 Costinesti,
-I have the last exam on the sixth.
-Then I'll have to go home for a week and then return.
-I don't know, it's rather complicated.
-You did remember about the money, didn't you? -Yea, sure.
- You give it  to me in an envelope or what?
- I wanted to keep it separated from the money for the flowers.
- 300, right? - I'll give it back when I get my scholarship.
- Are you hungry? Do you want me to get you something?
- My mother packed some cookies for me.
-She woke up in the morning to make cookies for you?
-She woke up to prepare the merengue cake, cause after 8 the gas pressure drops.
- Please get the flowers for my mother. I think I'll be stranded here all day.
- I don't think I...  can make it.
- Where...?  Are you telling me you won't be able to attend my mother's birthday?
- Don't be angry with me. - I am. She's making your favourite cake and you don't come?
- You told her to make it for me? -I did, and she made the cake.
- It's just that I can't, not that I don't want to.
- What do you mean you can't? What is it you have to do? Say it.
- I can't tell you now. You can't tell me now?
-Don't you trust me? Say it if you don't.
- It's not about that. I just don't understand why you can't come. Do you keep secrets from me?
- I have no secrets. I'll tell you later, that's all.
- Why is it such an issue?
- Ok, if you don't find it an issue, I don't know what else to say.
- If I had to come to your place for the first time and I had forgotten about it, that would have been an issue.
- Come on, I don't want to argue with you.
- Who started it? I asked to get some flowers for my mother and you say you don't want to come.
- Fine, I'll come. I 'll find a way and I'll make it.
- You're making me a favor now. - Hey, will you stop? do you want me to come or not?
- The professor would like you to speak a little lower, ok?
- What kind of flowers do you want? - Don't take  anything.
- Tell me. Do you want carnations?
- Get some gladioles. - How many?
- 48. - I can't, they're even.
- Then how many? - Don't now. 49 maybe.
- She'll say I don't her age if I get 49.
- Who's counting, anyway? - You don't know my mother.
- Get 47 then. I don't know. Do as you please. I'll just take how many you want.
- Listen, we won't get too formal, are we?
- Don't worry. Some friends of my father will come, but that's all.
- We'll have a glass of champaigne and then go to my room.
- Ok, I'll manage one way or another and I'll come.
- No, you'll come good and proper. At 5.
No delays
- You're starting to annoy me. I'm never late.
- Unless something unforseen pops up, in wich case everybody is late.
- Ady,do you your report card with you? They won't allow us without it. - Yes
- I'm leaving.
-  What's the time? - Past twenty. Do you need mine?
- No, no , keep it.
- See you later.
- Don't you kiss me? - No, cause you've upset me
- Don't upset me anymore. - You too.
- Bye. - Bye.
- How can I get a pack of Kent cigarettes?
- Why didn't you tell me. I would have brought it for you.
- I need it for Gabi. Go to Unirea, you'll find some black marketers.
- Bye.
- Hello.
- I'm listening.
- I have a booking. On the name Dragut.
- You have a booking here. Since when?
- Today. Tonight, I mean.
- What I want to know is when did you made it?.
- Since last Tuesday.
- There is nothing here.
- A friend of mine made it. I know for sure it was Monday, or Tuesday.
- Do you know who did she talked to?
- No, but I 've heard she gave her name and adress.
- What was the name again?
- Dragut.
- Nope. There is no Dragut in here.
- Listen, go find Nelu for me.
- Maybe my colleague knows you.
- I told you it wasn't me who booked the room.
- My friend called and a man answered.
- On the phone. So she didn't come here personally?
- I don't know exactly. I guess she called.
- Anyone can call.
- Was the reservation confirmed? Yesterday?
- What to confirm it for?
- I would really like you to talk in a civilised manner.
- The resevation has to be confirmed at least 24 hours prior.
- The man she talk to didn't mention anything like this.
- I doubt he didn't.
- Nelu....
No... It hurts.
There is someone here who says you've booked a room for her yesterday.
- Not yesterday, tuesday.
- Or tuesday.
- Ok, What was the name again?
- Dragut.
- Dragut(Nice), ha, that's the name allright.
- Yea, thanks.
- Listen, could you call me if they send the pay check?
- Ok, fine.
- No, if the reservation had been made I would have find it.
- So, what do we do now?
- Do what now?
- Is anyone serving in the shop?
- In a minute.
- We really need a room. Please, let's tackle this
- Tackle what miss? There is a delegation from Bucharest who arrived yesterday. The whole place is full.
- Do you understand?
- Anything. I don't mind if it has 3 beds.
- Can't you understand Romanian? It seems you don't.
- Do you have Kent?
- 80, a pack.
- We have a delegation on the way. See what you can do.
- Ok, I can't talk anymore. I call you back. Bye, bye.
- I'm listening.
- Hello. I'd like a room starting tonight.
- Tonight?
- Yes, please.
- Everything is taken.
- I don't mind if it has 3 beds.
- Can you call Marcu here, please.
- How many nights?
- Two, but it could take longer.
- Today... not really.
We have a room but startig tomorrow
- But we really need it tonight, please.
- How many? - Two.
- With double bed. - Doesn't matter.
- Yes? - Go to the bar and get two coffees to that table.
- Is it neckezol or ness?
- Just go. She knows what to give you.
Tell her it's for me.
- So, can you help me?
- I don't really know. He hasn't confirmed the resevation until now, but still...
- Please, I'm begging you.
- It's a double bed, did I tell you?
- It's ok.
- Do you have an ID?
- You have a temporary adress here. Are you a student?
- Yes
- If you stay at the student hostel why do you need a room here?
- We're six in the room. During exams it gets kind of crowdy.
- Two persons.
- Yes
We have another room with 4 beds if you'd like
But if you don't pay the whole room I might have to bring in someone else.
- No need to, really. - It's better with 4.
- No, thanks. - As you wish.
- I can't spell the name, Miha...  - Mihatescu with a T.
- You better change this ID. The Police won't be happy with this.
- I forgot it in the jeans when I washed them, that's why it's not clear.
- The other person? Dragut(Nice).
- That's the actual name, Dragut.
- Is she a lady also?
- Yes,
she has that problem at school too... Dragut Gabriela.
- 186 lei. -How much?
- 186
- Excuse me, how much you charge a night?
- It's there for all to see. Double bed, 62 lei.
- Can't we pay for only one night?
- I've already given you someone else's reservation. If you don't like it...
- Fine, fine.
- Your day starts at 12. When your not in the room, you leave the key at the counter.
- Ok.
Thanks.
- P 14. Hello.
- I'm not sure she's here anymore.
- Ok , I'll go. Will you wait over the phone?
- Gabitza?
- I've got the room
- But not at Unirea, at Tineretului.
- She said it was no reservation, nothing.
- I told them, but...
- That's the way it is.
He'll understand.
- Listen, the room costs here 186 lei.
- It's a double bed. I couldn't find anything better.
- Why didn't you look for a room yourself? You're starting to annoy me.
- Listen, find someone to lend you another 200 lei.
You're a big girl,you'll manage.
- Just go and ask. Go.
- I'll leave the key at the counter, ok?
- Listen, how can I recognise that man?
- How can he recognise me?
- Are you insane, Gabitza?
How is he going to recognise me, if you described yourself?
- You are something, you know.
Ok, I'll see what I can do.
- Be sure you have your ID with you.
- Bye, bye.
- Excuse me. No 24?
- Who are you looking for?
- I'm supposed to meet someone here. He gave me this adress. Decebal, 24.
- Did you see anyone waiting here?
- No.
- Is there a man called Bebe working here?
- Bebe who?
- Don't know. All I know is he's mr. Bebe.
- Don't know. Ask the boys at the service.
But I don't know any Bebe here.
- Excuse me. Mr Bebe?
- Miss Gabi?
- She couldn't make it. She's not very well
- My name is Otilia.
- We agreed on the phone she will come.
- I know. That's why I was afraid we won't recognise each other.
- I tried to ask some people.
- Ask what?
-If there was someone waiting for me.
- Cause I was late and I thought I lost you.
- We're going with your car?
- Where is she? - At the hotel, she's waiting for us.
- Shut the door properly.
- Do you work here?
- Where do I work?
- Just asking.
- May I smoke in here?
- Miss, listen here.
- I have nothing to hide.
- You've seen, I've come with my car, you can note the license plates if you want.
- But, let me tell you something. I work by trust here.
- I look at the person and I can tell if it's going to work or not.
- You can trust me, really.
- She didn't feel allright and she couldn't come.
- We tried to contact you through Ramona, but she went home.
- And we had no phone number of yours to contact you.
- It doesn't matter. I just told you.
At what hotel are you lodged?
- Tineretului.
- Listen, When I talk to your friend, I had a request.
- To book a room at Unirea or Moldova.
- She told me. But if there weren't any room what was I to do?
I had a hard time even at Tineretului until  I got the room.
- Has your sister done this previously?
- My sister? No.
- How old is she?
-22, She'll be 23 this march.
- Many happy returns of the day
- Do you live together?
- Yes.
- You're not from here, are you?
- No.
- Where are you from?
- Campulung.
- Never been there.
- You didn't miss anything.
- Do you have a rented room?
- No, at the hostel.
- How is it there?
- Lot of noise. You can hardly learn.
- Where do you studying?
- Polytehnics
- Not bad, you don't have to go to the country side.
- Yea, right.
- I have to make a detour to drop something.
- Wait here.
- What are you doing outside?
- How many times did I tell you not to go out when I'm missing?
- Why did you have to go out?
- Miss Iancu told me they brought sugar at...
- Forget the sugar. What do you need that for?
- It's not for me.
- I don't any sugar, understand?
- I just don't want to see you out, you drive me crazy.
- It's the third time this month you lock yourself outside.
- The wind slamed the door.
- The fucking draught, huh?
- Here it is. Lose this one too, cause this is the last I have.
- Don't worry son, I won't lose it.
- Why do you have to get in the street, what do you need?
- Do you want to catch a cold or what?
- Miss Iancu had to go to the complex so as not to lose her place in the line.
- So why didn't she let you in the house?
She was afraid you'd steal from her?
- No, no.... - I'll have a talk with her too.
Now get in the house.
-But she kept a place in the line for me.
- Forget the line. Go inside.
- Ok, I'll go. - Right now. So I can see you getting in.
- Don't you need anything to eat?
- Just go in and forget the rest.
- Viorel, someone called you on the phone.
- On the phone?
How many times do I have to tell you not to answear the phone when I'm away?
- Hey, where do you think you're going?
- 206, It has already been paid for.
- Didn't anyone tell you to leave the key at the counter when you leave the hotel?
- There is someone in the room waiting for us.
- What's the number? -206
- Dragut Gabriela? -Yes.
- She's already in the room.
- And him? - He's visting.
- Didn't they tell you visits have to be anounced? Do you think you can come in just like that?
- I thought only after 22.
- Your colleague told me
- You didn't understand. If he stays after 22 he has to pay the room.
Visits have to be anounced regardless.
- Do you have an ID?
- May I take these?
- You take it when you come down.
- 206.
- Gabitza?
I'm with mr Bebe.
- Hello. Gabriela. - Hello
- Come in.
- Did you get the money?
- When?
- Want a coffee? - No, thanks.
- Some cookies? - No.
- They are good, home made.
- Take a seat, please.
- It's good you've meet.
- I thought you wouldn't recognise each other.
- Miss, I think we've started all wrong.
- I've head two requests over the phone.
- Firsly, book a room at Unirea or Moldova.
- Secondly, to show up alone.
- Do you think I told you this, just to....
- No. I understood what you asked, but I couldn't find anywhere else.
- Miss, you couldn't find. Then we should have meet when you found.
- Now, my ID is downstairs.
- I'm sorry.
- You can be sorry all you want but my ID is at the counter.
- I thought I'd better not postpone it anymore. I already did that too many times.
- What month are you?
- The third.
- You said the second on the phone.
- When we talked I was in the second. Now I'm in the third.
- What blood type do you have?
- 0 I
- Are you hypotensive?
- No... I don't...
- Are you allergic to anything?
- Just to cat hair. Not to much. Some redness around the neck, that's all.
- Are you going to use anaesthetics?
- Miss...
- I'm asking cause I don't really know how it's done.
- A friend of mine who also... interrupted that she has been administered anaesthetics
- Have you ever had an abortion?
Let's get something straight. I'm not going to rake you.
We didn't agree to that and it's no need for that.
I just place a probe in and a spontaneous abortion ensues.
Of course, there is some bleeding, we have to be cautious with the haemorhage
but there is no anaesthesia involved
I mean it doesn't hurt that bad so it doesn't need anaesthetics.
And more there are no facilities here.
You make perform anaesthesia in a hospital, not whereever you like.
It's very important to stand still all the time the probe is in.
so as not to break off or fall cause I'm not inserting it again.
I put it once and that's it, understood?
How did you think it's going to be?
I thought you made up your mind since you've called me.
- I did, but...
- But what?
Miss, we're not playing here.
We could end up in jail for what we're doing here.
You get in but I do as well.
Just that I' ll be worse.
We're not playing, ok?
Once we let it roll there is no turning back.
If everything goes right, after I place the probe, bleeding will occur,
and you will expel the foetus.
It's very important how you act afterwards
You need someone to help you, because the haemorhage may be heavy.
And God forbid you spill blood all over the place, cause we're in big trouble then.
That's why I asked you to bring some oilcloth.
- I... forgot it at the hostel
-You forgot it at the hostel.
Then...put a plastic bag or something, I don't know.
And again, don't let anyone come in
Room sevice, anyone, keep the door closed at all times
- Do you know how much time it takes?
I mean since you place the probe until...
cause we've rented the room for 3 days.
- It depends. It can take 2 hours as well as 2 or 3 days.
It dependson how the human body will react.
-What if I need to go to the toilet?
- Can't you understand it'very important not to move out of the bed at all?
If the probe fell, we achieved nothing.
I'm not putting it again, I told you.
That's why I told on the phone it's very important to have someone to help you.a friend or..
because when you feel contractions and the bleeding starts it doesn't matter at that point.
But until then, you must not budge.
Be ware of infections.
When I insert the probe, I sterilize it.
I have alcohol, all I need, but afterwards there is an infection hazard.
You know the blood is kind of favorising it.
I'll give you some ampicilin to prevent it.
Have you ever taken ampicilin?
- Yes
- Is there any danger... or can the foetus not be expelled?
- Anything can happen, I told you, but usually it  is expelled.
- Forgive me for asking, but what if, God forbids, she faints or gets fever
or she loses blood, what do I do then?
Do I call an ambulance, do I call you?
- If you call the ambulance, we're half way in prison, all of us.
And be careful. If you call the ambulance, don't say you're not pregnant,
cause they'll figure it out anyway
Just say, I don't know, you saw something coming out but you couldn't tell what it was
Nobody will believe you but it doesn't matter.
At least thet'll be covered.
It's best that we don't resort  to the ambulance.
How is your period?
Do you lose a lot of blood?
- Kind of yes.
-Lay down so I can palpate you.
Unzip.
Don't leave.
Miss, what month did you say you were?
- 3 month
- I'm going to ask you one more time and I want you to pay attention.
When was your last period?
- December. It was due on 20.
- It was due on 20 but it didn't come?
- No
- So the last time it came was... november.
- Yea, I guess so.
- Let's calculate. November, december, january, february
How much is that?
But it last came in december.
You have to calculate from november.
It may be a little over 3 months.
- A little? It's way over 3 months.
Miss, I want you to gather yourself.
What month are you?
Because there is a different set for 3 and a different set for 4 months
- It could be the fourth.
- The forth?
Or the fifth?
Miss, you better be careful with this things...
- It can't be the fifth.
Most probably the fourth.
I have an irregular period.
- You kind of playing with the months.
Could be fourth, could be fifth.
Do you realise that from 4 moths on it's not an abortion anymore,
it's homicide.
5 to 10 years of jail.
Did you know that?
You better not know it onwards.
- I don't have a regular period.
Sometimes it comes in 2 and a half months
That's why I didn't bother.
-Miss, please...
- You may not believe me...
-Well, I don't.
If you have an irregular period go to someone else, not me.
That's how people are.
They ignore the problem on, and on and on.
And then come to me for help.
You want someone else to pay for what you did?
It's not me who had fun.
- Miss, I don't know...
It's very dangerous.
Who do you think will perform an abortion in the fourth month?
Or the fifth or whatever it may be.
- Please, I beg you.
- You may beg, but...
everything in this world has a price.
- But we're paying you.
- Really?
- How much do yu have?
- Look. We had to book the room for 3 days cause they wouldn't have given it otherwise
- So?
- We manage to get 3000 in the first place,
but the room being so expensive, we ended with 2850.
Is there a problem?
- Miss did I mention anything about the money?
Did I mention about the money on the phone?
- Well, is just that you didn't say, so we asked Ramona
how much it would be and we asked oyher people as well
and that's what everybody told us. It's at most 3000.
-Ramona told you it's 3000?
-She said that what she knew.
-Then let Ramona perform it, if that's what she knows.
- Miss, do you remember what we talked on the phone?
I said I was sympathetic and if you want, I can help.
Ay or nay?
Did I say anything about the money?
- You said we'll get along somehow.
- Of course, that's why I asked you to come personally at the meeting
So we can agree on every aspect from the very begining.
Look now. I'm not being judgemental for what happened to you
Every one makes mistakes in life.
I didn't ask for your name, nor where is the father of the baby, nothing of that
It's not my bussiness.
I said I can help you and as you can see I have nothing to hide.
I came with my own car, my ID is at the counter
If Militia shows up, I'm the first they bust.
So I'm risking my freedom....
You should know I have children too
I'm being nice to you and I help you
So you should be nice to me as well
That's how I see things.
- Hold it a bit cause I don't think I follow you
- I'm not going anywhere.
I think you're the one hurrying.
What the part you didn't understand?
I was very clear and I don't like to repeat myself.
What did you think?
That I risk 10 years of jail for 3000?
That what you thought?
What do you think I am, a street beggar?
Did you see me searching in the dumpster?
Look now,
while I go to the bathroom, you'll do some thinking
and when I come out you'll tell what you decided.
If you want to go along, then you tell me whose the first one
If not I get my things and I leave
- You're the one who asked for my help, not me.
- God, I'm sick
I can't believe what's going on.
- Why did you have to tell him you're in the second month?
- That's what Ramona told me.
Otherwise he might not want to.
- So that's how he want to.
- Why the hell did you have to wait for so long?
- What am I to do now?
And we paid for the room too.
- The room is your major worry, now?
Damn Gabi, you really annoy me sometimes.
I told you many times to be careful. But not you. You know better.
- I don't know what to do.
Don't worry, you don't have to be involved in this.
There is one thing to help me, and come with me and totally different to...
Give me the money.
- You tell us how much. Is 4000 ok?
4500, 5000, how much?
- Do you have that kind of money?
- Why are we talking then, just for fun?
- We can make it.
- You can make it.
- You tell me what a burden the room was
and then you say you can come up with an aditional 2-3000
Come on lady.
How can you make it?
- We'll borrow.
- Really?
And how do you give it back?
- That's our bussiness.
- So, now you're getting tough on me.
- I didn't say that, I was explaining...
- And how much time will it take to get the money?
- At the most next Saturday.
I'll have it all.
- Until next Saturday you'll have all the money?
- Ok then, if you say so.
You call me when you have all the money and we'll see then.
- No, please don't go.
I beg you to do it today.
The room is paid and all...
- How to do it? Is it you that is doing it?
- -No..., please forgive me
I meant you do it.
- So, how do we do it?
- Here's 2800 we got so far and I promise you I'll have another 2000 by Tuesday.
Will this do?
You must trust us, we won't...
- Trust? What trust? Do I know you? Do I know who you are?
You can take the train tomorrow and leave town. How do I know?
- We wouldn't do something like that.
I'll give you my ID
- What am I to do with it? Look for you in the middle of nowhere?
- We're students here, where could we go?
Look, I'm going to phone home and get the money til Monday
- Girl, are you bullshiting me?
I am asking you once more: are you bullshiting me?
- I'm not bullshiting you, but...
- But what?
- I've explained it plain and clear. Don't make me repeat myself cause I don't like it.
- Believe me, if I had that money I would have gone home and get it for you.
But we don't have it. I gave you my word that next Saturday...
- Girl, what the fuck do you think?
You think you can fool me like a fucking idiot?
I have scums like you for breakfast.
Smarter assholes tried to fuck me and they couldn't do it.
Do you think you can fool me?
Like you're some smartasses and I'm a stupid fuck?
Fuck you and all this!
- Please, please, you have to help me.
It doesn't concern her. It's about me.
And please let's do it today.
Like you said.
- What do you mean, I said so?
- If you make mistakes, you pay.
It's my fault. She has nothing to do with it.
- I didn't require that, do you understand?
- I understood very well.
She's not my sister, I'm sorry I lied to on the phone.
She's just my room mate.
- So what? Did I ask you whose sister is she? I don't think so.
I've explained it to you very clear
- Yes. That's the best I can do. What I can do?
My room mate has no obligation
- That's why I was suggesting...
- You don't suggest anything to me , clear?
You come to me and ask me something.
And I told you I can help and I told you the conditions
If you don't understand, its ok, nobofy is forcing you.
- I'm having my period.
- What did you say?
Please repeat. You said it low and I couldn't hear.
- She's having her period.
- I'm out of here. I had enough of this.
-Please, please don't leave.
- Ok, ok. Put the damn probe and...
- And?
So how am I to put the probe?
Do you think I was born yesterday?
- Excuse me...
Do you have a cigarette?
Thank you.
-Lye down.
- Are you making a shot?
-No
- What is it?
- Water.
- If nothing happens till tomorrow, you can add some yourself.
- Give me the probe.
- Don"t be tensed.
- When you feel something stinging let me know.
- Did it sting?
- Yes.
- When you feel it comes out, you go and sit on the closet.
Cause it comes out easier.
Give me the bandage.
Hold this.
Important. Don't cut the cord until the placenta is out.
If it remains inside, it's bad.
You just stay still until it comes out, ok?
Sit still!
- Can I cover myself?
- Yes.
- I forgot to tell you something important.
Don't throw the aborted fetus in the closet, cause it will jam. Ok?
Not by pieces not as a whole.Don't get any ideas.
And don't bury it so that the dogs will find it and all
You wrap in a cloth, you go whatever neighborhood you chose
You get in the first apartment building you see
and you throw it in the dumpster from the 10th floor. Got it?
- Yes
- Check her temperature in the morning and in the evening.
If it's 37-38, it's ok
If it goes beyond 39 you gave her aspirin and these.
If you want I can come and see you tomorrow at 2, or tonight after 8
- No, you don't have to...
- Come on, don't...
As you wish.
If you're ill or you need me, then call me.
Don't move, ok?
Questions?
Ok, I'll be on my way.
Good luck.
- Listen
- Thanks.
- I'm  curious to know...
How come Ramona recommended this guy to you?
- Luciana had an interruption with him recently.
- So it's not her that had the interruption?
- No.
- Then why did she recommend him?
What if it's an asshole?
She thought she was making you a favour, right?
- She said this guy will do it even if the pregnancy is over 3 months.
- Then why did you tell this jerk it's 2 months?
- I thought it was better this way.
- Really? Well, stop thinking.
And if you are going to lie, at least tell me about it.
Why the fuck did you tell him I'm your sister?
How did it cross your mind?
- He told me I should come and you went instead of me
what could have I said?
- Then why didn't you go?
- I've asked you to go, haven't I?
- Gabitza, are you following me?
Why didn't you go?
- Because I was reluctant, that's why.
- So you lied your sister would come.
- I didn't lie to you.
- It doesn't matter who you lied to.
- I just forgot to tell you, but I didn't lied to you.
- It doesn't matter anymore.
- I'm just upset that because of some stupid mistakes you've made
things had to happen this way.
We could have gone to Miss Jeni, the one Dorina told you about.
And things would have been allright.
-  Sure, now it's easy to say that.
It was your opinion it doesn't matter it's a man as long as it's cheap.
- Did I say that?
I said to do it where it's cheaper, of course,
but not that it doesn't matter if it's a man or not.
I didn't even think that....
- Do you think I did?
- God damn it.
If that that bitch from the hotel had kept my resevation
maybe none of this would have happened.
- What were you thinking, making the reservation over the phone?
- I told her I was from another town.
- Did you?....
Whatever.
- Are there any cigarettes left?
- No.
- This still nature painting sucks.
- Comfortable?
- Yes.
- Does that thing hurt?
- Stings a bit.
It hurt when he put it.
- I have to go to Adi's.
It's his mother's birthday and I promised I would go.
Should I turn on the lamp?
- No, leave it like this.
-I'd like a glass of water here.
- I'll be away for an hour.
- Do you want me to bring you something to eat?
- I'm not hungry.
- You'll be later.
- No. I have the cookies.
- I couldbring some beef salad from Adi.
- No, I won't eat.
- Ok, I'll see what I'll do.
- Look, I'll leave the number here.
If you need something, call me.
- Don't leave it, I won't call you there.
- I'll call you anyway but it's better that you have it too.
- I'm leaving. Be careful, don't let anyone in.
- Are you leaving or what?
- What about the key?
I'll lock you in and take the key.
Don't worry, you'll be allright.
- Bye.
-Miss. Miss.
- The person who visited you forgot his ID.
- Don't tell me that you forgot the flowers on top of being late.
- If you talk to me like this, I'm leaving.
- You're late and angry?
- Good evening. I'm Alin's mother.
- Otilia. Happy birthday.
- Thank you dear. I'm so glad you came.
- Are those pickles coming?
- Go, go inside. I have to get some pickles.
- I have to make a phone call.
- Good evening. 206, please.
- Otilia, my dad.
- Dad? That's how you introduce me?
- Otilia. - Nice to meet you
- Happy Birthday. -Come in.
- You don't have to.
Ady, give her your slipers.
Put them on or you'll catch a cold.
- You take mine and take the shoes.
- But I don't want to.
- Come in, don't be shy.
- Good evening.
- She is Ady's girlfriend,
Otilia.
- They are the Rusu, Ady's godfathers'.
She is doctor Aldea, doctor Racoviceanu, cardiologist, his wife
- Let her sit down, she's dizzy with so many new people.
- He went to cardiology but his problem resided in the upper story. -ha, ha
- We'll see who's the doctor when the prostate gets nasty.
- Where is the toilet?
- Excuse me.
- The toilet? - Down the hall. Turn on the light.
- I won't be able to stay much longer.
- What are you saying. You've just arrived.
- Did you wash your hands?
- You said it was just passing by and saying Happy birthday
not having dinner with your folks.
- We wait till they pop off the champagne and then we go to my room.
-Let me go, I'm all sweaty
- Here comes the soup.
- Please, go ahead.
- Come on, come on.
- Whenever you see eachother you start all over again.
- So, what's the problem?
- What would you like to drink?
- Some juice please.
- Very good, those meat balls.
- They're with frozen meat.
- It's not that I don't drink, but I don't feel like now.
- It's very good that she is not drinking.
- Not even vermouth?
- I don't mind, but not now, really.
-Maybe the girl is fasting.
- So what if she's fasting?
- I'm not fasting.
- I've heard you're from Galati county.
- Galati city, actually
- Galati city, you say.
- Do you happen to know Dr Ivanov, the surgeon?
He's very professional.
- Not really. After highschool I left the to go to university.
- He was my student.
- Straight A student.
- Yes, 9,80  9,70
- And it was hard back then. If you grabbed a 7 in Anatomy you were celebrating all day.
Now they churn out '10' on the conveyor belt.
- Even 10,50. I know a student straight '10' till the sixth year.
The Party gave him another 0,50
And now he's 10,50. How about that?
- Don't forget 0,25 if you start a family.
- Yes, that too.
- Maybe your son will take that 0,25 next year
- Look, he blushed, ha ha.
- Oh, leave my boy alone.
- It's time...
- Are your parents teaching, too?
- No, my father is in the military and my mother is retired, she's sick.
She was working when she was younger, but now...
-Sometimes, simple folks are better raised than a lot of people with high education.
- Not really. It depends much on the environment.
Take this Dima for instance. He's from the country side. The Party
promoted him on account of his 'worker origins' and now he's a big shot.
- Forget that. Let's have a toast better.
- Happy birthday, happy birthday.
- Turn the volume a little higher, I want to hear what The All-Too-Knowing is up to.
- Is this pork?
- It's very hard to cook in this house
Ever since Ady was a little boy, he didn't eat pork
Whenever he saw a bit of fat on his dish, he refused to eat
no matter how insignificant that piece of fat was
- Our Valentin would do the same.
- In the soup too. The same refusal.
Even his school lunchbox. If I put chicken in he would give it to his friends.
And I couldn't stand that. Because we weren't so well put back then.
I had to stay up to 3 hours in a line for a pound of meat.
And he was picky.
- It's better the children be acustomed to hardships since they are little
cause no one is going to grant them any favours later in life.
-That's true
- They sent me to take care of the cattle when I was a little boy
and I did my homeworks at the light of a gaslamp.
And we were 9 brothers
My mother was putting the 'mamaliga' (polenta) on the table
and some were lucky to snatch a piece, and some weren't.
-But you managed to snatch.
- Not here. My husband is very picky.
- If I didn't prepare the mash potatoes the way his mother did, he wouldn't eat.
- And still, it's not as good as my mother's.
- But it's good. - Ok,ok it's good allright.
- Nowadays, people are too spoiled.
- My grandmother used to add some milk.
- Me too.
- And some water in wich to boil the potatoes.
- It depends on how you're used to.
- We didn't have any butter. But my mother used to put potatoes in the 'mamaliga'
It was awesome.
- We ourselves, we had differences with our parents when we were young.
- Stop taking their side. They take everything for granted.
Look at them. Hostel, scholarship, mom and dad feed them. Man...
- It's not quite like that
Think about the allotment of jobs in medicine
If they end up in some far away hamlet, they're through.
- What's the problem with the allotment?
I myself had to work 8 years in Cotnari
And I was fine.
- Please, have some more
Don't wait for me to serve.
Doctor, what would you like?
- If girls aren't smart enough to mary during faculty years
they end up in the countryside and marry eather the teacher or the priest
And the priest is usually the biggest drunk in the village.
- Come on. Thre are serious priests as well.
- Those are exceptions.
- Most of them have colour TV, VCR, and if you're looking for them they are busy.
- What are they busy with?
- Busy with confessions.
- We're going to the church on Easter.
They can arrest me if they like. I don't care.
- Who's going to arrest you?
- The priest, ha ha ha
- Don't laugh. Guess what colleague I bump into on Easter at the church.
He was sneaking behind a column. ...Hutonas
- Aurel went straight to him and ask him 'where is your notebook?'
- No, it wasn't like that. I told him 'why don't you take that notebook out and write clearly?'
He played it down,  'come on Aurel, don't say that' and things like that
- You did the right thing.
- You know, my sister in law gave last Easter egg paint from Germany.
And some marzipan. It was a delight.
- Last year all my eggs cracked during boiling. I can't imagine what happened.
- Mine were just fine
- If you use good paint I'm sure they were fine
- I use a bit of oil. Makes them shine.
- I use butter.
- I don't have to smear anyting. This german paint does the trick.
I had yellow and green paint. And orange.
And blue.
- No, I got blue from yellow and green.
- After we use the paint, we share the rest of the paint with neighbours.
-That's a good did.
- Would you like a cigarette?
Come on, have one.
- Thank you.
- Where are you studying?
- Polytechnics.
- When I was young, girls went to medicine and boys to polytechnic.
- The same thing today.
- The main adavantage at polytechnics is you don't get stuck in a village.
- It's not easy to spend a lifetime in a factory, either.
- You stay at the hostel?
- Yes.
- How many in the room?
- Usually 4, But I pulled some strings and I moved together with a friend of mine.
- Resourceful girl.
- Miss, excuse me, but I...,
well, it's not proper for a young lady to smoke in the presence of the boy's parents
- Emilian! - Don't interrupt me.
I was 43 when my father passed away but I've never smoked when he was around
Never.
- That's very healthy
- As if yor father didn't know you were smoking.
- Get the champagne from the refrigerator.
- Of course he knew. But it's about respect.
The children are now openly defiant.
- Even my Valentin...
- Who's defying you?
- Well, it may not be the right word but....
you know what I mean
- I, for one, didn't aprove of my son not serving in the army.
Why shouldn't he ? He has to, he's got to learn what life is all about.
Not smothered, because sooner or later he's got to find out what a real man is..
- That's right, our son behaves the same way...
- I don't agree...
What? You think that if you spend nine months there and they brutify you
you'll come out a man?
-That's right.
- I wouldn't tolerate for my son to suffer like that.
What for?
-You should see the ones that serve sixteen months! Poor guys...
-It also depends where you're serving.
-Boarder police is the worst.
- But it's satisfactory.
- No, no...the disciplinary batallion is the hardest.
- Yes, but that' not what we were talking about!
- No, listen here...
- We didnt't exempt Adi because his father didn't want to.
No, God forbid, his father has principles.
That's why the boy is studying chemistry now.
- Chemistry is good, dear. You'll see, I'll take him in as my assistant
and you'll see he'll grow to like it.
- We'll keep him at home to learn for an year and he'll have another go.
-The army, only the army is the real school of life.
- Allright, where's that champagne? Let's pop the cork!
- Happy birthday to you, happy birthday to you
- Congratulations, dear!
- Happy birthday! Cheers!
- Could you please get me the phone?
- Ya, sure.
- Adela is on the phone.
-  Now, are you going to tell me what is going on?
You've been out of it since you came.
- I'm not in the mood to talk about it.
- Are you going to tell me?
- Are you sure you want to know?
- What do you mean? Of course I do.
And please tell me no matter what.
- I had to go help Gabitza have an abortion.
- And that's what you needed the money for?
- Do you imagine that an abortion is 300 lei?
- Then what did you need them for?
- Don't worry, I'll give them back on Monday and that's the end of it.
- Look, my father had a colleague, a doctor, that got 3 years detention for an abortion.
- What if I get pregnant? what are we going to do then? Have you thought?
- Cut it out!
- No really, it can happen.
And again, what would you do if I got pregnant?
- Don't roll your eyes. Have you thought?
- What exactly am I supposed to think about?
- What are we going to do if I get pregnant?
- But you won't .
- How do you know I'm not already?
- Are you?
- You have no idea when I'm due for my period.
- I do know. Sometime these days, right?
- What do you care? It's not your problem.
- Why are you saying that?
- Did it ever happen while we were together?
- Take Thursday, I asked you to take care, and come outside.
Remember? And you, you couldn't care less.
- How can you talk about this?
- You're not ashamed to do it, but you're ashamed to talk about it?
- I don't see the point of talking as long as you're not pregnant.
- I want to know what to expect of you.
- Don't worry, if it happens, I'll take care of it.
- Yeah, right... - What do you mean?
- Did you ever need anything and I didn't help?
- Do you at least know how many times I needed help?
You have no idea.
- It's not my fault that you don't talk about it!
Do you want me to take a guess about your problems?
- And the thing with Gabi, why didn't you tell me? I would have helped.
- Helped me? You can't even conceive the idea and you'd have helped?
- The main thing is for you to take care not to get pregnant.
- Don't bother, I wouldn't count on you anyway.
At least Gabitza, as plain as she is, would help me.
- Oh, and I wouldn't, or what?
I just said I don't condone abortion because it's very dangerous.
- So what would, according to you, be the solution?
- I don't know, I'd marry you.
- So if I get pregnant...
- Just cut it out!
- Come on, I'm not spending the rest of my life cooking mashed potatoes for you.
- Otilia,did my parents' friends annoy you or what?
- They annoyed me too, but that is not the point.
I know that you also yhink my parents are simple people, without higher education.
- Did you ever hear me saying that? Did I ever say that to you?
- You didn't, but I know your opinion.
Actually, you did say it once.
- What did I say?
- Can I come in ? I brought you some creme broulee.
- Thank you.
- Save some space for the merengue cake.
- Why are the lights off?
- Could you please get me the phone?
- Look now...
I'm sorry if I made any mistake.
You know I love you and I want for us to be together.
- Please get me that phone.
- Look, I appologized.
- You said you were sorry.
And do you at least know what for?
Tell me, do you know what you're sorry about?
- I see that you're upset, and I don't want you to be upset over me.
If I made any mistake, it wasn't on purpose.
I want us to get along, ok ?
- Until what?
Until I get my allotment and I leave by myself?
I asked you not to touch me now.
- It's going to work out.
We're going to leave for camp, it'll be just the two of us and we won't fight anymore.
- Please get me the phone.
Could you please give me some privacy while I talk to Gabitza?
It won't take long.
Good evening. Room 206, please.
Could you tell me, did anybody go up to 206?
I'm Mihartescu, you talked to me in the morning.
No, no, you don't have to go up.
Thank you.
I have to go.
- What is it, did something go bad with Gabi?
Stay around for just  5 minutes, they're cutting the merengue cake now.
- I'd like to, but I really can't.
Sorry.
- Then at least go in and say  " bye".
- You go in and tell them for me. I really can't stay anymore.
- Do you realize how shitty I'll feel in front of them?
- I'm sorry.
Bye.
-Please don't walk me out. You really don't have to.
- Get inside. It's embarassing to sit here, waiting for the elevator.
- Good evening. 206 please.
- Your ID.
- You have my ID. I showed it to the receptionist this morning.
- I need your ID.
- I think it's upstairs.
- Call the room, to bring it to you.
- I called the room earlier, and my friend was sleeping.
I'll be right back with it, I don't want to wake her up.
- Why don't you have your ID anyway?
- I just went out for some cigarettes and met someone, that's all.
- You went out...
- I'll be back with it.
- Gabitza?
Gabitza?
What's wrong?
Why didn't you pick up the phone?
- It got out.
It's gone.
- Pick it up.
Tell them I'll be right down.
Do you have a bag?
Tell me, do you have a bag or something?
- Will this do ?
- It's too small.
- Burry it, ok?
Do you promise?
- Don't worry, I won't throw it away.
- You will be back, right?
- Cut it out.
Lock the door.
- If the receptionist comes, tell him I went down.
- Do you know at what time the last bus comes?
- In about an hour, I guess.
I don't know.
- A cab around here?
- You won't find a cab in this neighbourhood Miss.
- Thanks.
- You're wellcome.
- Gabitza?
Gabitza?
Gabitza!
- What's going on ?
- Oh, they had a fight, at the wedding.
Your friend is waiting for you at the restaurant.
- My friend is waiting for me at the restaurant?
- Yes, she came down 5 minutes ago.
Take the other way, because there's the wedding here.
- Thanks.
- What are you doing?
I didn't know where you where.
- I was very hungry.
I think I have a bit of a fever.
- Did you take an aspirin?
- I took an ampicilin.
- Did you burry it?
- You know what?
We'll never talk about this, ok?
- Are they serving anything at this hour?
- Yes, he's coming right away.
- What's that supposed to be?
- So, the menu from the wedding that it is : beef, pork, steamed liver, bread-crumbed brain.
- Could you bring us a bottle of mineral water, while we think about the order?
-= convert to srt and resynch by aziraphale =-
visit opensubtitles.org