- Watch it.
- Sorry, Darling.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Come here.
Mind if I join you?
Can I have the same?
I should introduce myself, my name is Gandalf.
- Gandalf the Grey.
- I know who you are.
Well, now, this is a fine chance.
What brings Thorin Oakenshield to Bree?
I received word that my Father had been seen
wondering the wild near Dungland
I went looking,
found no sign of him.
Thorin, It's been a long time since
anything but rumor was heard of Thrain.
He still lives.
I am sure of it.
My father came to see you
before he went missing.
What did you say to him?
I urged him to march upon Erebor.
To rally the seven armies of the dwarves.
To destroy the dragon and take back
the lonely mountain.
And I would say the same to you,
take back your homeland.
This is no chance meeting, is it, Gandalf?
No. It is not.
The lonely mountain troubles me, Thorin.
That dragon has sat there long enough.
Sooner or later the darker
minds would turn towards Erebor.
I ran into some unsavoury characters while I was
traveling amongst the green road,
- they mistook me for a vagabond.
- No matter, they regretted that.
One of them was carrying a message.
This is Black speach
- A promise of payment.
- For what?
Your head.
Someone wants you dead.
Thorin, you can wait no longer,
you are the heir to the throne of Durin.
Unite the army's of the dwarves.
Together you have the might and power to retake Erebor.
Summon a meeting of the seven dwarf families.
Demand they stand by their oath
The seven armies swore that oath to the
one who wields the king's jewel, the Arkenstone.
It is the only thing that will unite them, and in case you have
forgotten, that jewel was stolen by Smaug.
What if I were to
help you reclaim it.
Oh. The Arkenstone lies half a world away.
- Buried beneath the feet of a fire breathing dragon.
- Yes, that's right.
That is why we're going to need a burglar...
12 MONTHS LATER
Re-sync & translation:
ArthurM
How close to the pack?
- To close.
Couple of leagues, no more, but that is not the worst of it.
- The orc's picked up our scent.
Not yet, but they will do. We've another problem.
- Did they see you?
They saw you.
- No, that's not it.
What did I tell you,
Quiet as a mouse.
Exelent burglar material.
- Will you just listen!
I'm trying to tell you there is something else
out there.
What form did it take, like a bear?
Y... Yes. But bigger, much bigger.
You knew about this beast?
- I say we go back.
- And be run down by a pack of orcs?
- There is a house.
It's not far from here where we might take refuge.
- Who's house?
Friend or foe.
- Neither.
He will help us or he will kill us.
What choice do we have?
None.
Come on!
This way, quickly!
Go!
Bombur, come!
To the house!
Run!
Come on, get inside!
Open the door!
Quickly!
Push!
Come on!
What is that?
That is our host...
His name is Beorn.
And he's a skin changer.
Sometimes he is a huge black bear and sometimes
he's a great strong man.
The bear is unpredictable,
but the man can be reasoned with.
However, he is not overfund of dwarves.
- He's leaving.
- Come away from there!
It's not natural. None of it!
It's obvious, he's under some dark spell.
Don't be a fool. He's under no enchantment but his own.
Well, now, get some sleep, all of you.
You'll be safe here tonight.
I hope.
Attack them now.
Kill the dwarf filth while they sleep.
No
The beast stands guard.
We will kill them on the road.
They are gathering in Dol Guldur.
The Master has summoned you!
We grow in number.
We grow in strength.
You will lead my armies.
What of Oakenshield?
War is coming.
You promised me his head.
Death will come at all.
Do we call off the hunt?
Bolg!
I have a task for you.
Do you still thirst for Dwarf blood?
So you are the one they call Oakenshield
Tell me, why is Azog the Defiler hunting you?
- You know of Azog, how?
- My people were the first to live in the mountains.
Before the orcs came down from the north.
The defiler killed most
of my family.
But some he enslaved.
Not for work, you understand, but for the sport.
Caging skinchangers and torturing them
seemed to amuse him.
There are others like you?
Once there were many.
And now?
Now there is only one.
You need to reach the mountains before the last day of
autumn.
- Before Durin's day falls, yes.
- You're running out of time.
- Which is why we must go through Mirkwood.
- A darkness lies upon that forrest.
Foul things creep beneath those trees.
There is an alliance between the orcs of Moria and
the Necromancer in Dol Guldur.
I would not venture there,
except in great need.
- We will take the elven road. That path is still safe.
- Safe?
The woodelves of Mirkwood are not like their kin.
They're less wise and more dangerous.
But it matters not.
What do you mean?
These lands are crowling with orcs.
Their numbers are growing.
And you are on foot,
you will never reach the forest alive.
I don't like dwarves.
They are greedy and blind, blind
to the lives of those they deem lesser than their own.
But orcs I hate more.
What do you need?
Go now, while you have the light.
Your hunters are not far behind.
The elven gate
Here lies our path through Mirkwood.
No sign of the orcs.
We have luck on our side.
Set the ponies loose,
let them return to their master.
This forest feels sick.
As if an disease lies upon it.
Is there no way around?
Not unless we go 200 miles north,
or twice that distance...
South.
Come back to me...
Something moves is the shadows unseen.
Hidden from our sight.
Every day it grows in strength.
Beware the Necromancer...
He's not what he seems.
If our enemy has returned we must know.
Go to the tombs in the mountains.
The high fells.
So be it...
Not my horse, I need it.
- You're not leaving us.
- I would not do this unless I had to.
You've changed, Bilbo Baggins.
You're not the hobbit as one left the Shire.
I was going to tell you...
I...
...found something in the goblin tunnels
Found what?
What did you find?
My courage.
Good. Well that's good!
You'll need it.
I'll be waiting for you at the over-look.
Before the slips of Erebor.
Keep the map and key safe.
Do not enter that mountain without me.
This is not the Greenwood of old. The very air of the forest is heavy,
with illusion. It'll seek to enter your mind,
and lead you a strait
- Lead us a strait?
What does that mean?
You must stay on the path, do not leave it.
If you do, you'll never find it again.
No matter what comes, stay on the path!
- Come on we must reach the mountain...
...before the sun sets on Durin's day.
- Let's go.
It's our one chance to find the hidden door.
The path turns this way.
This way.
Air... I need air!
My head, it's spinning, what's happening?
Keep moving.
Dori?
- Why Have we stopped?
- The path, it's disappeared.
- What's going on?
- We've lost the path.
Find it!
All of you, look...
Look for the path!
I don't remember this,
none of it is familiar.
Attercop...
Look... A tobacco pouch.
There's dwarves in these woods.
Dwarves from the blue mountains,
this is exactly the same as mine.
Because it is yours.
You understand? We're going around in circles,
we are lost.
We're not lost, we keep heading east.
But which way is east?
We've lost the sun.
The sun... We have to find the sun...
Up there.
- We need to...!
What's that? Enough! Quiet!
All of you...
We're being watched...
I can see a lake...
...and a river, and the Lonely mountain!
We're almost there!
Can you hear me?
I know which way to go.
Hello?
Hello.
No, no!
Their hide is tough...
There's good juice inside...
- Stick it again, stick it again!
- Finish it! It's alive! Kill 'em, kill 'em now, let us feast.
Feast... Feast... Feast...
What is it?
Fat and juicy...
Just a little taste.
Where is it?
Here.
It stings!
Stings!
Sting?
That's a good name.
Sting.
- Alright...
- Where's Bilbo?
- Bilbo.
- I'm up here!
Come on!
Where is it... Where is it!
Where is it?
No!
Gloin kill him!
Kill them all!
You die!
Mine.
Come on, keep up!
Do not think I won't kill you, dwarf.
It would be my pleasure.
- No!
- Kili!
Throw me a dagger!
Quick!
You think I'm giving you a wapon, dwarf?
You're mistaking.
Search them.
Give it back! That's private!
Who is this?
Your brother?
That is my wife.
- And what is this horrid creature? A goblin mutant?
- That's my lad, Gimli.
Yeah...
Are the spiders dead?
Yes, but more will come.
They're growing bolder.
This is an ancient Elvish blade.
Forged by my kin.
Where did you get this?
It was given to me.
Not just a thief but a liar as well.
Take them!
- Thorin where Bilbo?
- Let's go!
Close the gate.
Aren't you going to search me?
- I could have anything down my trousers...
- Or nothing.
Why does the dwarf stare at you,
Tauriel?
Who can say?
He's quite tall for a dwarf.
- Do you not think?
- Taller than some...
...but no less ugly.
Leave it!
There is no way out.
This is no orc dungeon.
These are the halls of the woodland realm.
No one leaves here...
...but by the king consent.
Some may imagine a noble quest is at hand.
A quest to reclaim a homeland,
and slay a dragon.
I myself suspect a more prosec motive...
Attempted burglary, or something of that ilk.
You have found a way in.
You seek that which would be stole upon you the right to rule.
The king's jewel.
The Arkenstone.
It is precious to you beyond measure.
I understand that.
There are gems in the mountain
that I too desire...
White gem's, pure starlight.
I offer you my help.
- I am listening.
- I will let you go.
If you but return what is mine.
A favor for a favor...
- You have my word.
One king to another.
I would not trust Thranduil, the great king,
to honor his word, should the end of all days be upon us!
You have a lack of honor!
I've seen how you treat
your friends.
We came to you once, starving,
homeless, seeking your help.
But you turned your back.
You turned away from the suffering of my people.
The infernal that destroyed us!
Do not talk to me of dragon fire.
I know it's rot and ruin.
I have faced the great serpents of the north.
I warned your grandfather
of what his greed would summon.
But he would not listen.
You are just like him.
Stay here if you will, and rot.
A hundred year is a near blink in the life of an elf.
I'm patience. I can wait.
- Did he offer you a deal?
- He did.
I've told he could go...
And can all his kin.
Well, that's that then.
The deal was our only hope.
Not our only hope.
I know you're there.
Why do you linger in the shadows?
I was coming to report to you.
I thought I ordered that nest to be destroyed
not two months past.
We cleared the forrest as ordered my lord,
but more spiders keep coming up from the south.
They are swarming from the ruins in Dol Guldur.
If we could kill them at their source...
That fortress lies beyond our borders,
keep our lands clear of those foul creatures. That is your task.
And when we drive them of?
What then? Will they not spread to other lands?
Other lands are not my concern.
The fortunes of the world will rise and fall.
But here in this kingdom we will endure.
Legolas said you fought well today.
He's grown very fond of you.
I assure you my lord, Legolas thinks of me as
no more than a captain of the guard.
Perhaps he did once.
Now I'm not so sure.
I do not think you would allow your son to
pledge himself to a lonely Sindrin elf.
No, you're right. I would not.
Still, he cares about you.
Do not give him hope where there is none.
The gates are guarded.
Not all of them... Follow me!
The stone in your hand,
What is it?
It is a talisman.
A powerfull spell lies upon it,
if any but a dwarf reads the runes on the stone...
...it would be forever cursed.
Or not...
Depending whether or not you believe in that kind of thing.
It's just a token.
A ruin stone.
My mother gave it to me so I'd remember
my promise.
What promise?
That I will came back to her.
She worries.
She thinks I'm wreckless.
Are you?
Sounds like quite a party they're having up there.
It is Mereth Aderthad
The feast of starlight.
All light is sacred to the Elda.
But woodelves love best, the light of the stars.
I always thought it is a cold light.
Remote, and far away.
It is a memory.
Precious and pure.
Like your promise.
I have walked there sometimes...
...beyond the forest and up into the night.
I've seen the world fall away.
And the white light forever fill the air.
I saw a fire moon once...
It rose over the path near Dunland, it was huge.
Red and gold it was and it filled the sky.
We run an escort with some merchants from Ered Luin,
they were trading in silver work. We took the green way south.
Keep the mountains to our left.
And then it appeared.
This huge firemoon. Lighting above.
These empty barrels should have
been sent back to Esgaroth hours ago.
The bargeman has been waiting for them.
Excelent tasty wine...
Come, Elros, try it.
- No, I have the dwarves in my charge.
They're locked up, where can they go?
I think that the sun is on the rise,
must be nearly dawn.
We're never gonna reach the mountain, are we?
Not stuck in here, you're not.
Bilbo.
There are guards nearby.
- Come this way, Ori.
- Not that way, down here.
Easy thou.
This way...
Come on.
- I dont believe it we're in their cellars!
You're supposed to lead out not, not further in.
- I know what I'm doing.
Come on, this way.
Everyone, into the barrels,
quickly!
- Are you mad? They'll find us.
- No, no, they won't! I promise you. Please, you must trust me.
Do as he says.
What do we do now?
Hold your breath.
Hold my breath? What do you mean?
Where is the keeper of the keys?
Welcome, master Baggins.
Come on, Let's go.
Hold on!
No! Help me.
Shut the gate!
Quick shut the gate!
Do not let them escape.
No!
Watch out!
Slay them all!
Get onto the bridge!
Kili!
Kili.
Kill her! Kill the She-Elf!
Stop fighting!
After them!
Follow them!
Killi?
Dori!
Come along!
Catch!
Tauriel,
wait!
Tis one we keep alive.
After them! Cut the off!
Oh it's you!
- Why am I here Gandalf?
Trust me, Radagast.
I would not have called you here without good reason.
This is not a nice place to meet.
Not...
It is not.
These are dark spells, Gandalf.
Old, and full of hate.
Who's buried here?
If he had a name,
it's long since been lost.
He would have been known only,
as a servant of evil.
One of a number.
One of nine.
Why now Gandalf?
I don't understand.
- The Ringwraiths have been summend to Dol Guldur.
- But it can not be the Necromancer.
A human sorcerer could not sommun such evil.
Who said it wat human?
The Nine only answer to one master.
We've been blind, Radagast.
And in our blindness the enemy has returned.
He's summoning his servants.
Azog the Defiler...
...is no ordinary hunter.
He's a commander. A commander of legions.
The enemy is preparing for war.
It will begin in the east.
His mind it set upon that mountain.
We're you going?
- To rejoin the others
- Gandalf?
I started this...
...we cannot forsake them, they all live in great danger.
- If what you say it true...
...the world is in grave danger.
The power, in that fortress,
will only grow stronger.
You want me to cast my friends aside?
- Anything behind us?
- Not that I can see!
- I think we've rode down the orc!
- Not for long. We've lost the current.
Bombur is half drowned!
Make for the shores!
Come on, let's go!
Come on.
Move.
I'm fine.
It's nothing.
Get on your feet.
- Kili's wounded. His leg needs binding.
There's an orc-pack on our tail.
We keep moving.
- To where?
- To the mountain, we're so close.
A lake lies between us and that mountain.
We have no way to cross it.
- So the we go around.
- The orcs will run us down. As sure as daylight.
We have no wapons to defent ourselves.
Bind his leg, quickly.
We have two minutes.
Do it again,
and you're dead!
Excuse me, but uhm...
You're from Laketown, if I'm not mistaking.
That barge over there,
could it be available fore hire, by any chance?
What makes you think that would help you?
Those boots have seen better days.
As has that coat.
No doubts you have some
hungry mouths to feed.
How many?
A boy and two girls.
- And your wife, I imagine, she's a beauty.
Ay, she was.
- Oh sorry, I didn't mean to...
- Come on, enought of the niceties.
What's your hurry?
What's it to you?
I would like to know who you are.
What you are doing in these land.
We are simple merchants
from the blue mountains.
Journeying to see our kin
in the Iron hills.
Simple merchants, you say.
We need food, supplies, weapons.
Can you help us?
I know where these barrels came from.
...but I don't think it ended well.
No one enters Laketown but by lead of the master
All his welth comes from trade
with the Woodland Realm.
He wouldn't see an alliance before
risking the wrath of king Thranduil.
I wage there ways to
enter that town unseen.
Ay...
But for that,
you would need a smuggler.
For which we would pay double.
Keep moving!
Such is the nature of evil.
Out there in the vast, ignorance of the world,
it fastens and spreads.
A shadow that grows in the dark.
A sleepless malice as black
as the oncoming wall of night.
So it ever was.
So will it always be.
In time all foul thing come forth.
You were tracking a company of thirteen dwarves.
- Why?
- Not thirteen, not anymore.
The young one,
the black head archer.
We stuck him with a morgul shaft.
The poison is in his blood.
He'll be choking on it soon.
- Answer the question, filth.
- I do not answer to dogs, She-Elf!
I would not antagonise her.
You like killing things, Orc?
You like death?
- Then let me give it to you!
- Enough!
Tauriel, leave!
Go now!
I do not care about one dead dwarf.
Answer the questions.
You have nothing to fear.
Tell us what you know, and I will set you free.
You had all this to kill them.
Why? What is Thorin Oakenshield to you?
The dwarf never rant never be king.
King? There is no king under the mountain, nor will there ever be.
None would dare enter Erebor...
...whilts the dragon lives.
- You know nothing.
Your world will burn...
- What are you talking about?
Speak!
Our time, has come again.
My master serves the one.
Do you understand now, elfling?
Death is upon you.
The flames of war are upon you!
Why did you do that?
You promised to set him free.
And I did.
I freed his dreadful head from
his miserable shoulders.
There was more the or could tell us.
There was nothing more he could tell me.
What did he mean by "the flames of war"?
It means they intend to unleash a weapon
so great it wil destroy all before it.
I want the watch doubled to our borders, all roads, all rivers.
Nothing moves, but I hear of it.
No one enters this kingdom,
and no one leaves it.
Close the gate!
Keep it sealed by order of the King.
What about Tauriel?
- What about hier?
- She went into the forest...
...armed with her bow and blade.
She has not returned.
Dwarf blood!
They were here!
- There is another scent...
Man flesh!
They have found a way to cross the lake.
Watch out!
What are you trying to do?
Drown us?
I was born and bred on these waters, master dwarf.
If I wanted to drown you,
I would not do it here.
Oh I had enough of this lake-man.
Let's say we throw him over the
side and be done with him.
No, Bard...
His name is Bard.
How do you know?
- I asked him!
I don't care what he calls himself.
I don't like him.
We do not have to like him,
we simply have to pay him.
Come on now lads,
turn out your pockets.
How do we know he won't betray us?
We don't.
There is uhm... A problem.
We're ten coins short.
Gloin, come on.
Give us all you have.
Don't look to me...
I have been led dry by this venture.
And what have I seen for my investment?
None but misery and grief.
Blessed my beard...
Take it...
Take all of it!
- The money, quick, give it to me.
- We wil pay you when we get out but not before.
If you value you freedom
you do as I say.
There are guards ahead.
What's he doing?
He's talking to someone.
He's pointing right at us.
- Now they're shaking hands.
- What?
He's selling us out!
Quiet!
We're approaching the tollgate.
Hold! Goods inspection!
Papers please.
- Oh, it's you Bard.
- Morning Percy.
Anything to declare?
Nothing! But I am cold and tired.
Ready for home.
There we are, all in order.
- Not so fast.
Consignment of empty barrels
from the Woodland realm.
Only... They're not empty. Are they, Bard?
If I recall correctly, you're licensed as a bargeman.
Not a fishermen.
That's none of your business!
No, it's the masters' business.
Which makes it my business.
Come on Alfrid, have a heart.
People need to eat.
These fish are illegal.
Empty the barrels over the side.
- You've heared them, in the canal.
Come on.
Folk in this town are struggling.
Times are hard. Food is scarce.
- That's not my problem.
But when the people hear the master
is dumping fish back in the lake,
when the rioting starts,
will it be your problem then?
Stop..
Ever the people's champion, ay, Bard?
Protector of the common folk.
You might have their favor now,
bargeman, but it won't last.
Rise the gate!
The master has his eyes on you.
You do well to remember. We know where you live.
It's a small town, Alfrid,
everyone knows where everyone lives.
All these talk of civil unrest.
Someone has been stirring the pot, sire.
Cold playing up, sire?
It's the damp. It's the only possible explanation.
Get me a Brandy.
The mood of the people, sire,
it's turning ugly.
They're commoners, Alfrid,
they've always been ugly.
It's not my fault that they live in a
place that stinks of fish oil and tar.
Jobs, shelter...
...food, it's all they ever pleat about.
It's my blieve, sire,
they're being led on by troublemakers.
Then we must find these troublemakers
and arest them.
- My thought excactly, sire.
- And all this talk af change must be surpressed.
Can't afford te let them rebel band together
and start making noises.
The next thing they do, they start...
...asking questions, falling committees,
launching queries!
Out with the old, in with the new.
What?
That's what they've been saying, sire.
- There is even talk, of an election.
- An election? That's absurd. I won't stand for it.
I don't think they'd ask you to stand, sire.
Rabble-rouser. Who would have
the nerve to question my authority.
Who would dare? Who...
Bard.
You mark my words, that trouble making
bargeman is behind all this.
Get your hands off me.
You didn't see them.
They were never here.
The fish you can have for nothing.
Follow me.
Dad, our house, it's being watched.
You can tell the master I'm done for the day.
Dad.
Where have you been?
Father, there you are. I was worried!
Yes, here.
Bain, get them in.
If you speak of this to anyone,
I'll rip your arms off.
Get off.
Up there!
Dad? Why are there dwarves climbing out of our toilet?
Will they bring us luck?
They may not be the best fit,
but it'll keep you warm.
Thank you.
A dwarvish wind lance...
You look like you've seen a ghost.
He has, the last time we say such a weapon...
...a city was on fire.
It was the day the dragon came.
The day that Smaug destroyed Dale.
Girion, the lord of the city...
...rallied his bowman to fire upon the beast.
But a dragon hide is tough.
Tougher than the strongest armour.
Only a black arrow,
fired from a wind lance...
...could have pierced the dragons hide.
And few of those arrows were ever made.
His stock was running low
when Girion made his last stand.
If the aim of the man,
would have been true that day...
...uch would have been different.
You speak as if you were there.
All dwarves know the tale.
Then you would know that
Girion hit the dragon.
He loosen a scale under the left wing.
One more shot and he would have killed the beast.
That's a fairy story lad, nothing more.
You took our money.
Where are the weapons?
Wait here.
Tomorrow begins the last day of autumn.
- Durin's day falls morning after next.
We must reach the mountain before then.
And if we do not?
If we fail to find the hidden door
before that time?
Then this quest has been for nothing.
What is this?
A pike hook.
Made from an old harpoon.
And this?
- A crowbill, we call it fashion from a smithy's hammer
It's heavy in hand, but in defense of your life,
these will serve you better than none.
We payed you for weapons.
Iron forged swordes and axes!
It's a joke.
You won't find better outside the city armoury.
All iron forged weapons are held
there witch lock and key.
Thorin,
Why don't we take this offer and go?
I have done with less,
so have you.
I say we leave now.
- You're not going anywhere.
What did you say?
There's spies wathing this house
and probably every dog and wolf in the town.
You must wait till nightfall.
Thorin?
Dad?
Don't let them leave.
I thought you were an Orc.
If I were an orc you would be dead.
Tauriel,
You can not hunt thirty orcs on your own.
But I'm not on my own.
You knew I would come.
The king is angry Tauriel.
For six hundred years my father has protected you.
Favorited you.
You deviate his orders.
You betrayed his trust.
Come back with me...
...he will forgive you.
But I will not.
If I go back, I will not forgive myself.
The king has never let orc filth from our lands...
That he would let this orc pack cross
our borders and kill our prisoners.
It is not our fight.
- It is our fight.
It will not end here.
With every victory this evil will grow.
If your father has his way,
we will do nothing.
We will hide within our walls,
live our lives awayfrom the light.
And let the darkness descend.
Are we not part of this world?
Tell me, friend,
when did we let evil become stronger than us?
Hello Bard,
where are you after?
There was a tapestry, an old one. Where is it gone?
- What tapestry are you talking about?
This one.
There were dwarves I tell you,
apeared out of nowhere.
Full beards, their size.
I've never seen them like.
What are dwarves doing in these parts?
It's the prophecy.
- Prophecy?
The prophecy of Durin's folk.
Prophecy?
Prophecy.
The old tales will come true...
- Vast halls of treasure!
Can it really be true?
Has the lord of silver fountains returned?
The lord of silver fountains, the king of carven stone.
The king beneath the mauntain,
shall come into his own.
And the bells shall ring in gladness
at the mountain kings return.
But all shall fail in sadness
and the lake will shine and burn.
Dad, I tried to stop them.
- How long have they been gone?
Keep it down...
As soon as we have the weapons,
we make straight for the mountain.
Go, go, go.
You're right?
- I can manage.
Let's just get out of here.
Run!
What is the meaning of this?
We caught the stealing weapons, sire.
Enemies of the state.
I gues they're a bunch of mercenaries,
if ever there was, sire.
Hold your tongue.
You do not know
to whom you speak.
This is no common criminal...
...this is Thorin,
son of Thrain, son of Thror.
We are the dwarves of Erebor.
We have come, to reclaim our homeland.
I remember this town
in the great days of old.
Fleets of boats lay at harbour,
filled with silks and fine jems.
This way no forsaken town on a lake,
this was the center...
...of all trade in the north.
I would see those days return.
Do we, like the great forgers of the dwarves,...
send welths and riches flowing
once more from the halls of Erebor.
Death!
That is what you'll bring upon us.
Drago fire, and ruin.
If you awaken that beast, it will destroy us all.
You can listen to this naysayer, but I promise you this.
If we succeed...
...all will share in the welth of the mountain.
You will have enough gold te rebuilt Esgaroth ten times over!
All of you, listen to me! You must listen.
Have you forgotten what hapenned to Dale?
Have you forgotten those who died in the firestorm?
And for what purpose?
The blind ambition of a mountain king.
So riven by grief,
he can not see beyond his own desire!
We must not, any of us,
be to quick to lay blame.
Let us not forget that it was Girion, lord of Dale,
your ancestor...
...who failed to kill the beast!
It's true, sire, we all know the story.
Arrow after arrow he shot. Each one, missin it's mark.
You have no right...
...no right to enter that mountain.
I have the only right.
I speak to the master of
the men of the lake.
Will you see the prophecy fulfilled?
Will you...
...share the great welth of our people?
What say you?
I say onto you...
...welcome!
Welcome, embrace,
welcome, king under the mountain!
You do know we're one short?
Where's Bofur?
If he's not here, we leave him behind.
We'll have to. If we want to find the door before nightfall.
We can risk no more delays.
Not you.
We must travel at speed,
you will slow us down.
What are you talking about?
I'm coming with you.
Not now.
I'm going to be there when that door is opened.
When we first loop upon the halls of our fathers...
- Kili...
Stay here.
Rest. Join us when you're healed.
I'm staying with the lad,
my duty lies with the woonded.
Uncle?
We grew up with tales of the mountain.
Tales you told us.
You can not take that away from him.
Fili
- I will carry him if i must!
One day you will be king and you will understand.
I can not rist the third of this quest
for the sake of one dwarf.
Not even my own kin.
Fili, don't be a fool. You belong with the company.
I belong with my brother.
By my beard...
Is that the Time?
No!
Did you missed the boat as well?
Kili? Kili!
I'm done with dwarves.
Go away.
No one will help us. Kili is sick.
He's very sick.
What is this place?
It was once the city of Dale.
Now it is a ruin.
The Desolation of Smaug.
The sun will soon reach midday.
We mus find the hidden door in the mountain before it sets.
This way.
Wait, is this the over-look?
Gandalf said to meet him here...
Did you see him?
We have no time to wait upon the wizard.
We're on our own.
Come.
Dol Guldur... The hill of sorcery.
It look completely abandoned.
As is it ment to.
A spell of concealment lies upon this place.
Which means our enemy is not yet ready to reveal himself.
He has not regained his full strength.
Radagast, I need you to carry a message to the lady Galadriel.
Tell her we must force his hand.
What do you mean?
I'm going in alone.
On no account come after me.
Do I have your word?
- Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Wait Gandalf!
What if it's a trap?
- Turn around and do not come back.
It's undoubtedly a trap.
The evil that is hidden here...
I command it come forth!
I command it reveal itself!
And now come here.
The Wizard has come.
He is lifting the spell...
He will find us!
Yes... he will.
Anything?
- Nothing!
If the map is true,
the hidden door lies directly above us.
Up here!
You have keen eyes, master Baggins.
This must be it.
The hidden door.
For all those who doubted us... Rule this day!
Right! Whe have a key...
Which mean that somewhere, there is a keyhole.
The last light of Durin's day
Will shine upon the keyhole.
We're losing the light, come on!
Be quiet. Can't hear when you're stomping!
It's not here!
Break it down.
Come on.
It has to break.
- It's no good. The door is sealed...
...can't be opened by force.
There is powerful magic on it.
No.
The list light of Durin's day...
...will shine upon the keyhole.
That's what is says.
What did we miss?
What did we miss, Balin?
We've lost the light.
There is no more to be done.
We had but one chance.
Come in, it's all fine.
Wait a minute...
Where are they going?
You can't give uo now!
Thorin?
You can't give op now.
Stand by the grey stone...
...when the thrush knocks.
The setting sun...
...and the last light of Durin's day will shine.
The last light?
The last light.
The last light!
The keyhole!
Come back! Come back!
It's the light of the moon!
The last moon of autumn!
Where's the key? Where's the...
It was here?
It was just...
Erebor...
Thorin...
I know these walls...
These halls.
The stone.
Do you remeber it, Balin?
Chmbers filled with golden light.
I have a memory.
Here in lies the seventh kingdom
of Durin's folk.
May the hart of the mountain unite
all dwarves in defense of this home.
THe throne of the king...
And what's that above it?
The Arkenstone.
Arkenstone?
And what's that?
That, master burglar...
...is why you're here.
Can you not do something?
- I need herbs.
Something to bring down his fever.
We have nightshade, some feverfew.
They are no use to me,
do you have any kingsfoil?
No, it's a weed, we feed it to the piggs.
- Piggs?
Weed... Right!
Don't move.
You want me,
to find the jewel?
A large white jewel, yes.
That's it?
I imagine there's quite a few down there.
There is only one Arkenstone.
And you'll know it when you see is.
Right.
In thruth lad...
...I do not know what you'll find down there.
You don't need to go if you don't want to.
There's no dishonour in turning back.
I promised I would do this.
And I think I must try.
It never seizes to amaze me.
- What's that?
- The courage of Hobbits.
Go now.
Get as much luck as you can muster.
Oh and Bilbo...
If there is in fact a...
...life dragon down there,
don't waken it.
You have come too late, Wizard!
It is done.
Where is your master?
Where is he?
He is everywhere...
We are legion!
It is over.
Run him down.
There is no light, Wizard...
...that can defeat darkness.
Arkenstone... Arkenstone...
A large white jewel.
Very helpfull.
Well, thief...
I smell you... I hear your breath.
I feel your air.
Where are you? Where are you?
Come now, do not be shy.
Step into the light.
There is something about you...
Something you carry.
Something made of gold.
But far more precious.
There you are, a thief in the shadows.
I did not come to steal from you.
Oh Smaug, the inaccessibly...
...welthy. I nearly wanted to gaze upon your magnificence.
To see if you really were as great as the old tales say.
I did not believe them!
And do you now?
Truly...
The tales and songs...
...fall utterly short, of you enormity.
Oh Smaug, the stupendous.
Do you think flattery will keep you alive?
No...
No, indeed.
You seem familiar with my name.
But I do not remember smelling your kind before.
Who are you?
And where do you come from?
May I ask?
I...
I come from under the hill...
Under hill?
And under hills and over hills my path has led.
And through the air,
I'm he who walks unseen.
Impressive, what else do you claim to be?
I am...
Luckwearer...
Riddlemaker!
- Lovely titles...
Go on.
- Barrelrider.
Barrels? Now that is intresting.
And what about your little dwarf friends?
Where are they hiding?
Dwarfes? No...
No, no Dwarfes here.
You've got that all wrong.
- Oh I don't think so.
Barrelrider. They send you in here to do their dirty work,
while they skulk around uitside.
Truly, you are mistaking, oh Smaug,
chiefest and greatest of all calamities.
You have nice manners. For a thief...
...and a liar!
I know the smell and taste Dwarf.
No one better.
It is the gold, they are drawn to treasure
like flies to dead flesh.
Did you think I would not know this day would come?
That a pack of dwarves would come crawling back to the mountain?
Was that an earthquake?
- That, my lad...
...was a dragon.
- Dad?
- It's coming from the mountain.
You should leave us, take your children,
Get out of here.
And go where?
The is nowhere to go.
Are we going to die dad?
- No, darling.
The dragon, it's going to kill us.
Not if I kill it first.
The king under the mountain is dead.
I took his throne.
I ate his people, like a wolf among sheep.
I kill where I wish, when I wish.
My armour is iron!
No blade can pierce me.
A black arrow, why did you never tell me?
- Cause you did not need to know.
Listen to me carefully.
I need you to distract the guards.
Once I'm at the top of the tower,
I'll set the arrow to the bow.
There is her! Bard!
- After him!
Quickly, donw there. Go!
Stop him!
Bain...
Keep it safe. Don't let anyone find it.
I'll deal with them.
- I won't leave you
Braga...
- You're under arrest.
On what charge?
- Any charge the master choses.
What about Bilbo?
- Give him more time.
Time to do what?
To be killed?
You're afraid.
- Yes, I'm afraid.
I fear for you.
A sickness lies upon that treasure court.
A sickness which drove your grandfather mad.
- I am not my grandfather.
You're not yourself.
The Thorin I know would not hesitate to go in there.
I will not risk this quest for the life of one burglar.
Billbo.
His name is Bilbo.
It's Oakenshield...
That filthy dwarfish unsurper.
He sent you in here for the arkenstone, didn't he?
No. I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't bother denying it.
I guessed his foul purpose some time ago.
But it matters not. Oakenshield's quest -
Will fail. A darkness is coming.
It will spread to every corner of the land.
You have been used, thief in the shadows.
You were only ever a means to an end.
The coward Oakenshield has weighted the
value of your life.
Found it worth nothing.
No.
No, you're lying.
What did he promise you?
A share of the treasure?
As if it was his to give.
I will not part with a single coin.
Not one piece of it.
My teeth are swords, my claws are spear.
My wings, are a hurricane.
So it is true.
- The black arrow found it's mark.
- What did you say?
I was just saying, your reputation proceeds you.
Oh Smaug the Tyrannical.
Truly. You have no equal on this earth.
I am almost tempted to let you take it.
If only to see Oakenshield suffer.
Watch it destroy him.
Watch it corrupt his arms and drive him mad.
But I think not,
I think our little game ends here.
So tell me thief... How do you choose to die?
Da'? Is that you da'?
No!
Guard!
Okaneshield has gone!
Fall back!
Regroup on the bridge!
You killed them all.
There are others. Tauriel -
Come.
We are losing him.
Dahlia.
Atheros.
What are you doing?
I'm going to save him.
- You're alive.
- Not for much longer.
- Did you find the Arkenstone?
- The dragon's coming!
Did you find it?
Yeah, we should get out.
Thorin.
Thorin!
You will burn!
- Come on!
- Come on, Bilfur!
Come on.
Hold him down.
- We've given him to the slip.
- No, he's still coming for that.
- So where to now?
- The western guard room.
- There may be a way out.
- It's too high
- There's no chance that way
- It's our only chance.
We'll have to try.
I care to tell of the wonders of elvish medicine.
That was a priviledge to witness.
Tauriel.
Lie still.
You cannot be her.
She is far away.
She is far, far away from me.
She walks in starlight in another world.
And it was just a dream.
Do you think she could've love me?
- That's it then.
- There's no way out.
The last of our kin.
They must've come here, hoping to beyond hope.
We could try to reach the mines.
Might last a few days.
No.
I will not like this.
Cowering. Clawing for breath
- We make for the forges.
- You're serious?
- We're as sure as dead.
- Not if we split up.
Thorin, we'll never make it.
Some of us might. Lead him to the fortress.
We kill the dragon.
If this is to end with fire,
then we will burn together.
This way!
Flee! Flee! Run for your lives!
There is nowhere to hide.
Behind you!
Come on!
Run!
Hey you! Here!
Send word to Dol Guldur...
Oakenshield has reached the mountain!
Go!
You! Come with me.
This way! Come on!
Thorin!
Follow Balin!
Come on!
Thorin!
Hold on!
Come on!
Go!
The plan's not gonna work.
These furnaces are stone gold.
He's right. We've no fire hot enough
to set in a blaze.
Have we not?
I do not look to see you so easily outwitted!
You have grown slow and fat.
In your dotage. Slug!
Take cover!
Bombur! Get those pillows working!
Go!
Bilbo! Up there. On my mark, pull that lever.
- Balin, can you still mix a blast flame?
- Alright. Come on!
We don't have much time.
Pass the spell power!
Make sure you know what you're doing!
Come on!
Now!
We head for the Gallery of the Kings.
Keep going, Billbo!
You think can decieve me -
Barrel rider?
You have come from lake town.
This is some sort of scheme between these
filty dwarves and those miserable lakemen.
Those sniveling cowards with their
long bows and black arrows.
- Perhaps the time I paid them a visit.
- Oh no!
This isn't their fault! Wait!
You cannot go to Laketown!
You care about them? Do you?
Good.
Then you can watch them die!
Here! You witless worm!
- You.
- I am taking back what you stole.
You will take nothing from me, dwarf.
I laid low your warriors of old.
I am still terror in the hearts of men.
I am King Under the Mountain!
This is not your kingdom. These are dwarf lands.
This is dwarf gold.
And we will have our revenge.
Preparing for your death!
I'm going to die? Amazing!
I will show you revenge!
Listen to me! Do you not know what is coming?
I am fire.
I am...
...death!
What have we done?
Re-sync & translation:
ArthurM