God, I am sorry for Dorothy, Walt.
She was a real peach.
Thanks for coming, Al.
Spectacles, testicles, wallet and watch.
Look at the Old Man glaring at Ashley.
He can?t even tone it
down at Mom?s funeral?
What do you expect? Dad?s still
living in the ?50s.
He expects his granddaughter to dress a
little more modestly.
Yeah, well your kid?s wearing
a Timberwolves jersey.
I?m sure Dad appreciates that.
The point I am trying to make is that there?
s nothing anyone can do that
won?t disappoint the Old Man.
It?s inevitable.
That?s why we stopped doing Thanksgivings.
the deal with the boat motor, the
broken bird bath,
It?s always something.
What are we going to do with him?
Don?t you think he?ll get in trouble over
there all by himself in
the old neighborhood?
Why don?t you have him move in with you?
Death is often a bittersweet
occasion to us Catholics.
Bitter in the pain.
Sweet in the salvation.
Bitter in the pain it causes the deceased.
... and their families
Sweet to those who know the salvation that
awaits.
And some may ask,
what is death?
Is it the end?
Or is it the beginning?
And what is life?
What is this thing we call life?
All these questions can frustrate you at
times like this.
And that's why you have to turn to the Lord.
- Jesus ...
Because the Lord is the sweetness.
Is that dad?
- No, that's grandpa Walt.
There is a platoon, E-Company,
March 2, 1952.
Korea?
- Where's Korea?
Well, people showed up after
the service, huh?
Yeah, well, I suppose they heard
there?d be a lot of ham.
I?ll go down the basement and get some
chairs.
Oh, I can do that, Dad..
- No, we need them now
not next week.
Cool, I found a medal.
Look at this.
How much longer do we have to stay?
This ghetto is a dead zone for my cell
and I?m bored.
Ashley, honey. Why don?t you help
Grandpa Walt with the chairs?
Me?
- Yes, you.
Grandpa Walt, would you like some help with
these four chairs.
No, you probably just painted your nails.
Your dad is driving me crazy.
Why didn't you guys make him a hint we're
leaving soon?
Come on, let's go.
Jesus Christ, how many swamp rats
can get in one room?
Grandpa, when?d you get the
vintage car??
1972.
I never knew you had a cool old car.
Yeah, it's been here since
before you were born.
So, what are you going do with it when you
like...
die?
Then what about that super cool
retro couch that you have in the den
Cause I was thinking I?m going
to State next year,
and I think it would look really
good in my dorm room.
And I don't have any furniture at all.
God.
Who are you? - Hi, I am Tao. - What do you
want?
I live next door.
- Come on, get the shit out of your mouth.
I am ...
- Tell me what you want.
Do you have jumper cables? My
uncle?s car is old and.....
- No we don't any jumper cables .
And have some respect, zipper head, we?re
mourning  here..
How you holding up, Walt?
Mr. Kowalski.
Huh?
- Mr. Kowalski, that's my name.
Right, Mr. Kowalski.
Your wife and I became quite close these
last few months.
She asked that I
watch over you when she passed on.
I told her I watch out for my
entire flock.
But she made me promise I?d keep an extra
sharp eye on you.
I appreciate your kindness you've shown to
my wife.
Now that you?ve spoken your piece,
why don?t go and attend
some of your other sheep?
Ok?
Dorothy mentioned specifically that it was
her desire for you to go to confession.
She said she couldn?t remember the last time
you went.
Is that so?
- It is.
Well, I confess that I never really cared
for church very much.
The only reason I went was because of her.
And I confess that I have no
desire to confess
to a boy that is
just out of the seminary.
Wish I could help dad, but gotta get kids
home.
Kids getting restless.
- Yeah, fine, just go.
I?ll call in a few, see how you?re doing.
- Alright.
Kill you to buy American.
Huh ...
Did you see the way he looked at the truck?
Jesus. It?s always Rice-Burner this or
Jap-Burner that. You know.
Even at Mom?s funeral, he can?t let it go.
At least he didn?t say anything this time.
-He didn?t need to.
Well, what do you expect, Mitch? The man
worked at a Ford plant for a lot of years.
I suppose that?s my goddamned fault?
Just give it a rest. Drive. Ok?
Kids, do you want the radio on? Yes.
You want to listen to some music? Good.
Damn, barbarians
Oh, Jesus ...
Polarski would roll over in his grave if he
could see his lawn now.
What the hell the chinks had to move in
this neighborhood for?
Have you gone completely deaf or something??
Hi there, Walt.
I kind of not a friend of yours.
Why do you insist on calling me Walt?
Sorry , Mr.Kowalski.
What are you peddling today, padre?
- Nothing.
Thought I?d drop by and
see how you are doing.
I haven?t seen you in church in a while
Okay. Well now when you
tipped on your good deed,
now why don?t you just
take off down the road?
I?d really like to talk, Mr. Kowalski.
- Not in this lifetime, sonny.
Why?
Do you have a problem with me, Mr. Kowalski?
- You don't want to know.
No, I do.
Well I think you?re an  overeducated,
27-year-old virgin
who likes to  hold the hands of old ladies
who are superstitious
and promises them eternity.
Is you a boy or is you a girl, I can?t
tell
Hey, Chicito.  If you was in pink, I would
fuck you and your ass would be my bitch.
What you reading, jackass
and The rice stalk?
That?s right, you keep walking.
Look at me when I am talking to you.
-Fucking slopes everywhere you look, man.
Fucking pigs
Look at that, man.
That's my little cousin, over there.
- You sure that's your cousin, man?
Fuck yes, that's my little cousin.
- He tight with anybody?
No he is flying solo, man.
- Flying solo?
Let's go down and see what the fucking
they're doing to him.
I love your jungles too.
Hey, they fucking with you?
They fucking with you?
We can do this right now.
You go fucking back here, don't you?
Yeah!
You are fucking rise niggers!
Ok go!
Tao, come on man, get in the car.
Dog, get in the car.
We just bailed your ass out, dawg.
Come on, dawg, get the fuck in here.
Get in the car, man, come on.
Chill with us, man.
We just bailed your ass out!
Come on.
Come on, Tao, man.
- Fuck him, man, let's go.
Come on Spider.
- Fuck it.
Get it man, let's go.
fuck his ass.
Tomorrow, I have to see your ass.
- Don't be like a little girl!
Tomorrow.
Come let's go, man. We've got a gun, man.
Let's get the fuck out of here. Let's get
this strapped.
Pussy!
Hey, Tao.
Hey what's up?
What's up, Tao?
What are you doing little man?
Why are you doing woman's work?
What do you want?
What? We can't just come and talk to my
little cousin?
He doesn't want to talk to you.
I am here right.
- Hey, Spider, who is that?
What's up?
- Spider?
Is that what he just
called you, Fong?
Spider?
- Is there something wrong with Spider?
What are you doing here?
Hey, so how old are you anyways?
Mentally, I am way too old for you.
- What?
You are just stupid.
I am going inside.
Sue!
How your little brother, do this gardening.
Fine, stupid.
Hey, you will roll with us man, come on?
Come on ride with us.
- Chill with us.
You need somebody to protect you, man.
That's what your big cousins are for.
Look, dawg. I've been there, I've done it
and I've seen it.
Back in a day everybody wanted to beat me,
dawg.
But now look, nobody wants to fuck with me.
Come on man, let's go.
- We are cousins right?
Come on.
We are a family.
Look, I am brother to Spider, as he is
brother to me.
Come on.
Take this shit off.
That's a woman's work man.
- Come get your hands dirty, man.
So what do I have to do?
Spider told that old boy next door had a
bad ass whip.
Told you we got him.
Come on.
Nice.
- Ya, my little cousin being little man.
Yo, that's a nice car.
1972 Gran Torino,  Fastback.
Cobra jet engine.
- Yo man it can still in mint condition.
Yo man, it's in mint condition man.
I've got one.
A Mexican, a Jew and a colored guy go into
the bar.
The bartender looks up and says:
"Get the fuck out of here!"
So, here?s where my flock
congregates when they?re not in church..
Hey Father J.
- Hey, Mel. Hey, Darrel.
Hey father.
- Hi, Walt.
What brings you in here, father.
Meat raffle?
No, I just came down to talk
Walt if that's ok.
Damn, padre.
You are persistent, aren't you?
I promised your wife.
All right, let's get booze.
I'll have Pabst and a shot of Jack.
And whatever he's having.
I'll have a  Diet Coke.
- Bullshit. This is a bar. You have a drink.
I'll have a  gin and tonic.
- Attaboy!
So, what you want?
I promised your wife I?d get you
to go to confession.
Now, why would you do that?
- She was very insistent.
She made me.
Well you're kinda found of promising
things you can?t deliver on, right, father?
Let?s talk about something else.
- What?
Life and death.
Life and death. What the hell do you know
about life and death?
I?d like to think I know a lot.
I?m a priest..
Yeah, you get up and preach about life and
death.
But all what you know is what you learned
in a priest school.
Right out of the rookie Preacher's Handbook
I don't know about that. I think...
That is bittersweet.
Sort of bitter in its pain. But
sweet in its salvation.
That's what you know of life and death,
and that's pathetic.
What do you know, Mr. Kowalski?
I know a lot. I lived there almost three
years in Korea. Thanks.
We shot men.
We stabbed them with bayonets, hacked
seventeen-year-olds to death with shovels
Stuff I'll remember till the day I die.
Horrible things,
but things I live with.
And what about life?
Well, I ...
I survived the war.
got married... and had a family.
Sounds like you know more about
death than you do living.
Maybe so, father.
Maybe so.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, man, get in a car!
- Tao, what the fuck, get in!
Come on Tao.
- Come, let's go,man, get in!
Fuck man, get in!
Hello?
Morning, Dad, it?s your number one
son, Mitch.
Morning? It's after one in the afternoon.
It's not morning.
Oh, right.
Afternoon, then.
So what do you want?
- What?
Me? Nothing. I mean, what would I want?
Well, I don?t know. Your wife has already
gone through all of your mother?s jewelry.
No, dad. I was just calling to see how are
you doing?
Well, anything new with the old
neighborhood?
No.
- Great. Smooth sailing then.
Yah.
- Ok, good, good, then.
Oh, hey, dead.
- Yeah.
You wouldn't happen to still know that guy
from the plant who has Lion season tickets?
Dad?
Ain't she sweet?
Come on.
Hey, what's up?
What are you doing here, man?
- Nothing.
Minding our own business.
- Just hanging out.
What are you guys doing here?
What?
Can I just come here to hang with my little
cousin?
We have good new for you.
- Really, and what's that?
Only for guy talk.
- I don't think so.
Why not? - Come on, man, we are going to
give you another shot.
Don't go, Tao.
- Mind your own business girl.
Come on, let's go
- Come.
What the hell is this?
Get up.
- G?t off my lawn.
Listen old man, you don't want to fuck with
me.
Did you hear me?
I said get off my lawn, now.
Are you fucking crazy?
Go back in a house.
Yeah, I'll blow the hole in your face
and then I'll go in a house.
And I'll sleep like a baby
You can count on that.
We used to stack fucks like you five
feet high in Korea,
used you for sandbags.
Ok.
You better watch your back...
Thank you.
Get off my lawn.
What the hell is this?
No, no, no, no more.
Stay right there.
Why can't you people just leave me alone?
We brought you some shallots to plant in
the garden.
I don't want them. They?re perennials, they
come back every year.
Look, why are bringing me all this garbage
anyway.
Because
Because you saved, Tao.
I didn't save anybody. I just. I kept a
bunch of jabbering gooks off of my lawn .
You are a hero to the neighborhood.
I am not a hero.
Too bad, they think you are and that?s why
they're keep bringing you the gifts.
Please take them.
- All they are wrong.
I just want to be left alone, thank you.
- Wait!
This is my mom, Vu, I?m Sue and
that's  my brother, Tao.
We live next door.
- So?
Tao wants to say something.
I am sorry.
- Sorry for what?
For trying to steal your car.
Let me tell you something boy.
You step on this property again, you are
done...
Good afternoon, Walt.
I  told you I?m not going to confession..
- Why didn't you just call the police?
What?
I do work with some of the Hmong gangs and I
heard there was some trouble
in the neighborhood.
Why didn't call the police?
Well ...
You know why, I've prayed that they would
show up, but..
.. nobody answered.
- What were you thinking?
Someone could have been killed.
We?re talking life and death here.
When things go wrong, you gotta act quickly.
When we were in Korea and a thousand
screaming gooks came across our land..
... we didn't call the police. We reacted.
- We are not in Korea, Mr. Kowalski,
I?ve been thinking about our
conversation on life and death.
About what you said.
About how you carry around all the horrible
things you were forced to do
Horrible things that won?t leave you.
It seems that it would do you good to
unload some of that burden.
Things done during war are terrible.
being ordered to kill ...
killing to save yourself,
killing to save others.
You?re right, those are things I
know nothing about.
But I do know about forgiveness.
And I?ve  seen a lot of men who
have confessed their sins,
admitted their guilt and left
their burdens behind them.
Stronger men than you!
Men at war who were ordered
to do appalling things...
and are now at peace.
Well I got to hand it to you, padre, You
came here with your guns loaded this time.
Thank you!
- And you're right about one thing.
About stronger men than me,
reaching their salvation.
Well, Hallefuckinlujah.
- But you are wrong about something else.
- What's that, Mr. Kowalski?
The thing that haunts a man the most is what
he isn?t ordered to do.
There, finally, you look like a human being
again. .
You shouldn?t wait so long
between haircuts, you cheap son of a bitch.
Well I am surprised you are still around.
I was always hoping that
you die off and they get
somebody in here they knew what
the hell they are doing.
Instead you just keep hanging around, like
the dump wop dago you are.
- That?ll be ten dollars, Walt.
- Ten bucks, Jesus Christ, Martin.
What are you half-Jew or something?
You keep raising the prices all the time.
It?s been ten bucks for the last
five years and you hard-mellows,
Pollack son of a bitch.
Keep the change.
- See you in three weeks, prick.
Not if I see you first, dipshit.
That's cool, you know.
Look at this.
You tight ass over here.
Come here girl.
You can't say hi?
Or are you acting like stuck-up and shit.
What are you supposed to be man?
- Yo, it's cool dog.
The fuck are you doing in my neighborhood,
boy?
None, Just going to the corner spot, you
know get some CDs, sound good, bro?
He called, you bro!
- Come on sound good, bro?
Sound good.
- Shut the fuck up.
Call me bro again, and I'll bite your
motherfucking face off .
Yeah, motherfucker.
- Now what the fuck you come down here for?
You here to bring this little present?
Oriental yummy? Don't worry, I'll take a
real good care with her.
Fuck out of here, .
- Fuck out of here, man!
Oh shit, you have a bitch with you.
Keep your ass right here.
Oh great.
Another asshole who has a fetish for Asian
girls. God, it gets so old.
Oh, shit, what's your name girl?
My name?
Get your ass out of here, okay.
It?s 'take your crude,
overly obvious come-on to every woman
who walks past and cram it.'
That?s my name.
Who do you think you are talking to?
Who does it look like?
Man she's tough.
- What? You gonna hit me now?
That'd pretty much complete the picture.
You need to keep your bitch on a leash.
Put a choke chain on her and
yank that motherfucker.
Oh, of course, right to the stereotype
thesaurus - Oh yeah
Call me a whore and a bitch in the same
sentence. -Bitch is crazy.
I like her like that
- Now take that bitch.
You don't know when to quit do you, girl?
- Let me teach you a lesson
Stop! Let me go!
Take your ass over there.
What the fuck are you looking at old man?
What the hell are you spooks up to?
Spooks?
You'd better get your ass on honkey, while
I still let you.
That's you'd better do.
What the fuck he thinks he is?
Have you noticed how you come across
somebody once in a while  ...
... you shouldn't fucking with?
That's me.
You are fucking crazy, get out of here, man.
Why don't you get your ass out of here
before we kicked your wrinkly white ass.
What's wrong with him man?
The motherfucker's crazy!
-What is this thing? What the hell?
Get in a truck.
Crazy motherfucker.
- What's wrong with him, man.
Hey pops come on now.
- Shut your fucking face!
You don't fucking listen, do you?
Now get in a truck.
- Go get in a truck girl.
Let her go, old man!
Shut up pussy.
What is this 'bro' shit anyway?
You want to be superb page, or something
These guy don't want to be your bro and I
don't blame them.
Now get your old faint paddy ass on down
the road.
Take care now.
You too.
Oh, yeah.
Why didn't you do nothing?
Man you fucking!
Shit man.
If he had cannon at your fucking face, you
would do nothing.
What's the matter with you, for Christ sake?
Trying to get yourself killed?
I thought you Asian girls were supposed to
be smart.
Hanging around in the neighborhood like that
is the fast way to get
you in the obituaries.
I know, I know. Take it easy.
And what about that goofball guy you were
with.
Is that a date or something?
Yeah, kind of. His name is Trey.
- You should be hanging out with them.
You should be hanging out with your
own people.  The other Hummongs.
- You mean, Hmong?
Hmong, not Hummong
- Whatever.
What the hell is Hmong, I mean Mong anyway?
Wow, you so enlighten you know that?
No, Hmong is not a place,
it is a people.
My people come from different parts
of Laos, Thailand and China.
Well how you ended up in my neighborhood?
Why didn't you stay there?
It's Vietnam thing.
We thought on your side
And when American quit ...
... the communists started killing all the
Hmong.
So we came over here.
Yeah, well I don't know how
you ended up in Midwest.
Snow on the ground six months in the year.
What is it? Jungle people wanted to be
on great frozen tundra?
Hill people. We are hill people. Not jungle
people. BOO-ga, ga-Boo, BOO-ga!
Yeah, whatever ...
Blame the Lutherans. They brought
us up here.
Everybody blames the Lutherans.
Well,  you'd think the cold will keep all
the idiots out.
Thanks for the ride.
You know something kid, you are all right.
But what about that dimwit brother of yours?
He is little slow or something?
Tao is actually really smart. He just
doesn't know what direction to go in.
Poor toad.
- It is really common.
Hmong girls over here fit in better.
The girls go to college
and the boys go to jail.
That old hag hates my ass.
Your birthday today, Daisy.
This year you have to make a choice between
two life paths.
Second chances come your way.
Extraordinary events culminate in what
might seem to be an anticlimax.
You lucky numbers are: 84, 23, 11, 78 and
99.
What a load of shit.
Yea.
What the hell is it with kids nowadays?
All right.
Let me help you with those.
- Oh, thank you.
How about that?
How about that, Daisy?
It's too heavy for a bag.
- No problem.
Good, Karen, give it to him.
-Here you go.
Well, what is it?
-It's a Gopher.
So you can reach stuff.
It makes things a lot of easier.
This is from me.
It's a phone.
Oh, I can see that.
I just thought...well, we thought
that it would make things easier.
Thank you, Karen.
There?s nothing wrong with making
things less hard on yourself.
You know Karen?s right, Dad. You?ve worked
hard your whole life.
Maybe it's time you start thinking about
taking it a easier?
And some other thing, Dad. You really
should get rid of the coffin nails.
We were thinking about the house.
You know, when Mom?s gone, it?s got to be a
lot to maintain around here.
Let alone clean.
And you are here all alone ...
Yeah, you know, there?s these great places
now, you know, these communities
Where you don?t have to worry about mowing
the lawn or shoveling snow.
You know, People who are like you, active
and alert, but are alone.
And would benefit from being around folks
their own age.
Yeah Dad, look. You got to check it out. We
brought some brochures.
These places are nothing like that you
think they would be. They are great.
- No, they are beautiful.
They are really nice
They really are.
These are top-notch like resorts.
It is like staying in a hotel, practically.
- They're beautiful.
They really are.
- Yeah.
They care of everything.
They clean up. They're really nice.
Oh, there are wonderful stores, where you
can buy new shoes.
They are amazing, they really are.
You have a good time, play some golf maybe.
Meet other people.
Son of a bitch. Kicked us out on his
birthday. I've told you that was a bad idea.
I know, you were right
- He  won?t let anybody help him.
Well, we tried. Now can we just drop it?
No one can say we didn?t try
What the hell with him,
we shouldn't have done it.
We should?ve stayed home with Josh and
Ashley.
At least they were smart
enough to not come here.
The goddamn kids have more sense than we do.
We miss mom, don't we Daisy?
Hey, Walt.
What are you up to?
We?re having a barbecue. You want
to come over?
What do you think?
- There's tons of food.
Just keep you hands off my dog.
-No worries. We only eat cats.
Really?
- No I am kidding, you moron.
Come on you can be my special guest.
-No, I am fine right here.
Yeah ...
Son of a bitch.
- Okay, so, what have you had to eat today?
I had a piece of cake.
And a little beef jerky.
Come on over and get something to eat.
We've got beer too.
Well ...
I might as well drink with strangers better
than drinking alone. It is my birthday.
Really. Happy birthday Wally
- Don't call me Wally.
You have no Pabts among the beer.
- As they say, "when in Hmong."
What am I doing wrong? Every time I look at
somebody they always look at the ground.
What is she saying?
- She said welcome to our home.
Oh no, she is not.
- Yes, she didn't.
She hates me.
Yeah, she hates you.
Okay.
What?! What are all you fish heads looking
at anyway?
I think we should go to other room. Sorry.
All the people in this house are very
traditional.
Number 1. Never touch a Hmong person on the
head,
not even a child.. Hmong-people
believe that the soul resides on the head.
So, don't do that.
- Sounds dumb, but fine.
And a lot of Hmong people consider looking
at someone eye to be very rude.
That's why they look away, when you look at
them. - Anything else?
Yeah, some Hmong people tend to smile or
grin when they?re yelled at.
It's a cultural thing.
It expresses embarrassment or insecurity,
it's not that they?re laughing
at you, really.
You people are nuts
But the food..
It looks good, smells good too.
-Of course, its Hmong food.
Okay, and I come back in few seconds.
Here you go.
- Thanks. You mentioned about..
looking at people, he's been staring at me
the whole evening.
That's  Kor Khue.
He is the Lor's family shaman.
What's that some sort of witch doctor or
something. -  Something like that.
Boeki Boo.
- You're funny, Wally.
Kor Khue's interested in you.
He heard what you did.
He would like to read you.
It would be rude not allow him this.
It's a great honor.
Yeah sure. It's fine by me.
- All right, take a seat.
He says people do not respect you. They
don't even want to look at you.
He says the way you live, your food has no
flavor. You wearied by your life.
You made a mistake. And you past life
is like a mistake what you did.
You are not satisfied with.
He says, you have no happiness in your life.
It's like you are not at peace.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I am fine.
Fine, I am fine.
God,  I?ve got more in common with these
gooks than I have with my
own spoiled-rotten family.
Jesus Christ ...
Happy Birthday.
Are you ok?
Yeah, I am fine.
You were bleeding.
- No, I bit my tongue.
It's nothing.
Why don't we get down and get some of that
good gook food. I am starving.
Okay.
You ladies are wonderful.
That stuff is really good.
Come on you glutton!
- What's up?
Let's go.
- What for?
To mingle.
- We can mingle right here.
No. You told me not to leave you alone.
Thank you very much.
I have to go now.
I'll be back.
Don't let me go right of it .
Well, well, look he is over there.
- Yeah, the kid who steal my Gran Torino.
My brother Tao.
- Tried to anyway, yeah, toad.
It was wobby a bit.
But it should fix it.
What's this?
Little rice liquor
Here, try it.
All right.
My friends and I were just
wondering what you?re doing here?
That's a good question. What am I doing
here?
My name is Walt.
- Hey, Walt. I am Wa Xam.
Wa Yum?
- No Wa Xam.
Wa Xam, Ok.
- So what do you do?
I fix things. Stuff like that.
- Like what?
I've just fixed that dryer over there.
I fixed my wife's friend sink.
I took old aunt Merry to doctor to get a
prescription. Fixed up.
I've even the fixed the door, what had't
even broken yet.
You're funny
I've been called a lot of things, but never
funny.
Well, I have to take off. Enjoy yourself.
- Okay, Yum Yum. Later.
Come on.
Relax, zipper headed.
I am not gonna shoot you.
I'd look down too if
I was you.
You know, I knew you were a dipshit the
first time I ever saw you.
You?re worse with women than
you are with stealing cars, Toad.
It's  Tao.
- What?
It's not toad, it's Tao.
My name is Tao.
You were blowing it with that girl who was
there.
Not that I give two shits about a Toad
like you.
You don't what you are talking about.
You are wrong egg roll.
I know exactly what I am talking about.
I may not be the most
pleasant person to be around.
But I got the best woman who was ever
on this planet to marry me.
I had to work at it. That was the best
thing that ever happened to me. Hangs down.
But you ... you know
You let Click Clack,  Ding Dong and Charlie
Chan just walk out with what?s-her-face.
She likes you, you know. I don't know why.
Who?
Yum yum!
You know that girl in the purple sweater.
She's been looking at you all day, stupid.
Do you mean, Wa Xam?
- Yeah, Yum Yum.Yeah.
Nice girl, very charming girl.
I talked with her.
But you let her just walk right out.
With the three stooges.
And you know why?
Cause you are big, fat pussy.
Well ...
I gotta go. Good day. Puss cake.
No, no more.
Okay, put them over there.
No. No. No more
No more. No more.
No more, please ...
Is that chicken dumpling thing you brought
before?
Alright.
Better than beef jerky all the time.
What's going on?
-Tao is here to make amends.
He is here to work for you.
-No, he isn't.
He's not gonna work for me.
My mom said dishonored the family.
And now he has to work off his dept.
He starts tomorrow morning.
- Oh not tomorrow, not any time.
I don't even want him on my property
I thought we went over all that.
It is very important to my mom that you
accept.
And that would be an insult if you refuse.
Why is it being put back on me, all of this?
He is the one who tried to steal my car ...
all of the sudden I am a bad guy in this
thing.
Look my family is very traditional
and would be very much upset if you don't
let Tao repay.
If you doesn't want to do it, then let's
just go.
Shut up!
Yeah, shut up.
All right, tomorrow, tomorrow.
Thank you.
Jesus, Joseph and Mary. These Hmong broads
are like badgers.
Son of a bitch. I never thought he'd show.
All right, what are you good at?
Like what?
- That's what I am asking.
You gonna work for me, I gotta know what
you are good at.
I gotta know what you can do.
- I don't know.
That's kind of half way what I expected you
to say.
See that tree right there?
You just go over there and count the birds.
You want me to count the birds?
- Yeah, you can count?
All you slopes are supposed to be good at
math, right?
Yeah, I can count.
- Good.
One, two ...
So, what do you have for me to do?  You
want me to watch paint dry
or maybe count the clouds that pass by?
Don't get flip with me, boy.
I am not the one who is trying to steal,
don't you forget that.
Go ahead.
I don?t care if you insult me and say
racist things.
Cause you know what? I'll take it.
- Of cause you'll take it.
Cause you have no teeth, you have no balls,
kid.
Look, I am stuck here. Why don't you find
something useful for me to do.
Unlike you, I am not useless. And I
maintain my own property.
These swamp rats, on the other hand, you
just can help it.
How long do I have you for?
Toad, how long?
Till next Friday.
All right. Go get the ladder out of the
garage.
When you got finished with that roof there.
You can take that gutter,
and nail it back up.
I am tired looking at it for the last three
years.
Yeah, you said it, brother.
Hello.
Grandpa says he want to know if
you can have Tao clear out the big
wasp nest under our porch?
Wasp nest?
That's terrible.
I think we can handle that after the lunch.
Lord All Mighty, knock it off.
It's my last day. What else do have for me
do?
Take a day-off. You did enough.
Toad!
Nothing.
Nevermind.
Kowski?
Mr. Kowalski?
Good morning.
I looked over your paperwork and I think we
should immediately start
a full battery of tests
I feel that this would be the best way to go
about checking all the
issues that you've had.
Excuse me, what happened to Dr.Felmon, my
regular doctor?
Dr. Felmon retired three years ago. I am
his replacement Dr. Chang.
It's grandpa Walt.
- Pick it up.
You talk to him!
Mitch.
I'm doing bills here.
- You talk to him, he is yours father.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, Mitch.
It's me your dad.
Yeah, I know.
What's up?
Oh, nothing, nothing much really.
How is everything going?
I am fine, fine.
How about Karen and the kids?
Fine, everybody is great. Doing fine.
Good. How about work?
Busy.
Yeah, I suppose...
In fact, um, speaking of busy.
I got a lot on my plate right now,
so if it is not something pressing.
No, not it all.
Why don't you call me this weekend?
Sure.
Ok, It was nice talking to you. Thanks for
talk.
Thanks.
This kid doesn't have a chance.
What do you know about faucets?
I know a lot about them, boy.
Tender side.
Jesus. For the love of Pete.
- What?
It must be a hundred degrees here.
Just, turn on the fan.
This place is wobbling apart.
Where did you get all the stuff?
What are you talking about?
- All the tools and stuff.
Well, may come as surprise to a thief,
but I bought this stuff. Everything in here
with my own money.
Yeah, yeah. This is not what I meant.
I mean this is so much shit packed in here.
Yeah, well. Every tool in here has a
purpose. Everything has a job to do.
They are all used when necessary.
- Okay, so, what is that?
it is a post hole digger.
- That
Vice-grips.
Wire cutters, you know that's a trowel.
There is shears right there,
and that's a saw.
That's a tack hammer.
You can't fool me kid.
Alright, what's on your mind.
It's just.. I can't afford to buy all this
stuff.
Well, I guess, even a bonehead like you,
could understand...
that a man acquires it over the period of
50 years.
Yeah, but...
All right, look, here.
These three items right here, you can have
this.
WD-40, vice grips and some duck tape.
Any man who is worth his salt,
can do half of the house chores
with just those three things.
Anything else you need you just borrow it,
that's all.
Ok, cool.
Fuck me.
- What's with that?
Nothing.
What?
Nothing, huh? I just saw
you've coughed out blood.
That's not good. You should
really see a doctor.
Look..
Those guys over here, the other night ...
on my lawn, what a bout them? - Just a
gang. A bunch of Hmong gang bangers.
I assume that.
What they were doing here?
They were going to take me away.
They were kind of pissed, that
I blew my first initiation.
Yeah, well you are, you are a pussy. You
wanna hang out with guys like that.
What was your initiation supposed to be?
My Gran Torino?
Toad, you got a minute?
Here it is.
Here is the deal.
I take the top, cause that's the heaviest.
I'll pull on that.
And you stand right back here, and you push.
And help me push it up each step.
like that.
- Then, let me take the top.
No, no, I've got a top.
No, I'll take the top.
It looks pretty heavy.
Look I am not crippled.
I've got the top.
If you don't let me take the top.
I ain't helping. I will go back home.
Listen to me, zipper head.
No, you listen, old man!
I am here because you need help.
So it is either top of I am
out of here.
All right, you take the top and I'll push.
Don't let it slip off you little girl hands
and crush me.
Don't give me any ideas.
That thing weighs a ton.
Runs like a clock.
They don't make them like this anymore.
So what are you going to do with it?
- Sell it I guess.
How much?
- 60 bucks.
I am tired of having this sit around down
in the basement there.
Why?
You are looking for a freezer?
Our downstairs one kind of died.
- Okay, 25 bucks and it's yours.
25?
You've just said 60.
I know, it will save me money putting an ad
in the paper.
Come on, let haul it over your place.
Kind of ironic, huh?
- What?
Toad washing a car they tried to steal from
you.
Yeah, he misses one spot.
He is doing it all over again too.
It is nice of you to kind
look after him like this.
He doesn't have any real
role models in his life.
Well, I am not a role model.
But you are a good man, Wally.
I wish our father would have been more like
you. Don't go calling me Wally.
No, I am serious. He was really hard on us.
Really traditional...
and really old school.
Well, I am old school.
yeah, but you an American.
What's that supposed to me?
You like him, don't you?
- Are you kidding?
He tried to steal my car.
And you spend time with him,
teaching him how to fix things.
Saved him from a fucked cousin of ours...
- Hey, what you language lady.
And you're a good man
- I am not a good man.
Give me another beer, dragon lady.
This one is empty.
You know, Hmong consider gardening to be a
woman's work.
Yeah, that probably why I see in the garden
over there all the time.
Besides we ain't in Hu-Mong.
- Funny.
You know you should quit.
That's bad for you.
Yeah? So it is being in a gang, dipshit.
Didn't you hear what I've just said?
I saw you coughed out blood.
You should quit.
What's that emblem supposed to mean anyway?
Your ancient camp scout emblem?
1'st cavalry. I've had it since 1951.
So what you wanna do with you life kid.
I was thinking maybe sales.
So you wanna be in sales? What about going
to school, maybe.
But school costs money.
Maybe you should get a job.
You can't just sit there and spread mulch
in my garden for the rest of your life.
Maybe you can just pay me.
Yeah, very funny.
What kind of job could I ever get? - Yeah
you're right, nobody would ever hire you.
Look I am just kidding zip... I mean.
You can get a job. You can get a job
everywhere.
Like what?
How about construction?
- Me?
Yeah.
- Construction?
- Do you have Alzheimer?s or something?.
No, get a job in the construction. I know
people in the trades.
Of course I have to make a little
adjustment and man you up a little bit.
Man me up?
- Yeah.
And I think you ought to date
Miss Yum Yum too.
Do you little good.
Get carbon off the vaults.
Now you just gonna learn,
how guys talk.
You just listen the way Martin and I banter
back and forth.
You okay? You are ready?
- Sure.
Let's go in.
Perfect. A pollack and a chink.
How are you doing, Martin,
you crazy Italian prick.
Walt, you cheap bastard, I should have
known you?d come in,
I was having such a pleasant day
- What did you do?
Jew some poor blind guy out of his money.
Giving him a wrong change?
- Who's the nip?
He is a pussy kid from next door.
I am just trying to man him up a little bit.
You see kid?
That's how guys talk to one another .
They do?
-Do you have shit in your ears?
Now go out and come back in and talk to him
like a man.
Like a real man.
Come on. Get your ass out of here.
Come on back now. Sorry about this.
That's ok.
What's up you old Italian prick?
Get out of my shop before I blow your head
off you goddamn dick smoker.
Jesus Christ.
Shit.
Take it easy. What the hell are you doing?
Have you lost your mind?
That's what you said.
That what you said men say.
You don't just come in and insult a man in
his own shop.
What happens if you meet some stranger?
If you get the wrong one he's gonna
blow you gook head right off.
What should I've said then?
- Why don't you start with Hi or Hello.
Yeah just come in and say: 'Sir, I'd like a
haircut if you have a time'
Yeah, be polite but don't kiss ass.
In fact you can talk about the construction
job you just came from.
And bitch about your girl friend in your
car.
Son of a bitch, I've just got breaks fixed
and those sons of the bitches really nailed
me. They screwed right in the ass.
Yeah, don't swear at the guy. Just talk
about people who are not in the room.
You can bitch about your boss making you
work overtime when it is bowling night.
Right, my old lady bitches for two goddamn
hours about how..
they don't take expired coupons at the
grocery store.
and the minute I turn on a fucking game she
starts crying we never talk.
See now go out, come back and talk to him.
And it ain't a rocket science for Christ
sake.
Yeah, but I don't have a job, a car, or a
girlfriend.
Jesus, I should have blown his head off
when I had a chance.
Maybe so, I want you to turn around and go
outside
and come back and don't talk about having
no job,
no car, no girlfriend, no future, no dick.
Ok, just turn around and go.
Excuse me sir, I need a hair cut if you
ain't too busy.
You old Italian son of a bitch prick barber.
Boy, does my ass hurt from all the guys at
my construction job.
Fuck me.
All set to go through with this, right?
- Yeah, yeah.
Don't yeah, yeah me.
Just say: Yes sir and I'll do my best.
Yes, I'll do my best.
- Cause when I vouch for somebody
that means I am give them my word.
I don't want you making me look bad.
No I am good. Totally into this.
Don't lay down either.
Just look em straight in the eye. And a man
can tell a lot by your handshake.
Here, put those in your back pocket.
- Cool.
Don't blow this.
Hey, Kennedy, you drunken Irish goon.
How the hell are you?
I am shitty. But who's gonna listen?
- Not me, that's for sure.
Help yourself there, Walt.
You dumb pollack.
Ok this is the kid, I was telling you about.
Tao, this is Tim Kennedy,
he is super on this job.
What we got here, Walt?
Well he knows construction and he is a
smart kid.
He'll do anything you need him for.
You sure?
- Yeah.
You speak English?
- Yes, sir.
Were you born here?
- You bet.
I see that Walt drove you here.
You got a vehicle?
Not at the moment. Taking a bus for now.
- Bus? Jesus Christ. You don't have a car?
My head gasket cracked and the goddamned
pricks at the shop wants
to bend me over for $2100
Oh please. I just replaced the tranny in my
Tahoe
and the sons a bitches fucked me hard, just
under $3200.
Goddamned thieves. It ain?t right.
- You got that right.
Come on in on Monday and we?ll find
something for you to do.
Thanks, Mr. Kennedy.
That's Tim, and what's you name again?
- Tao.
T. .., okay.
You owe me one, Walt.
Well I'll buy a fruit cake for Christmas.
Fuck a fruit cake.
How about you just hand over the keys to
that Gran Torino.
What the hell does everybody want my car?
- Yeah, I am not surprised.
Yeah, you don't know a half of it.
Alright, come on, zipper head.
Let the Mick stay here and play with
himself.
What are we doing?
What do you want to do?
Carry you tools in a rice bag?
Here.
You can use one of these ...
and you'll need one of this here.
I can't afford any of this.
I'll cover it. You can pay me back with
your first pay check.
Cool
- Here, we need something like that.
This is what I am looking for here, tool
belt.
There you go.
Not to bitch. But won't I be needing some
tools.
Tools I've got but I am not going to lend
you my tool belt.
You can pick up tools as you go.
I really appreciate all this.
- Forget it.
No, I really do
Thank you.
What's up homeboy, what are you doing?
What up man?
- What you got, punk?
Checking up on my little cousin.  - Yeah,
man.
My little cousin ...
What's this?
Where you come from man?
- I am coming
Home from work
I know you guys don't know much about that.
So that's true, you got a job.
- You can't just leave me alone?
What?
He is scared, huh?
Who bought this shit for you? Your dad?
- What you guys want with me?
Your dad bought this shit for you?
- Keep your hands off my stuff.
What's the fuck is that shit?
- What the fuck, you make me look bad?
Keep your hands off my stuff!
This massive my job man.
Give me that, that.
- Hey come on, this is my stuff.
You wanna smoke man? Fuck it.
Let me go.
Give me that, man.
Give me that.
What's the phrase I am looking for?
Oh yeah, 'saving face'
Hey, there.
Hey.
I gotta run.
Haven't seen you for a few days.
Where you've been?
Been busy.
Busy, huh?
What the hell happened to you?
- Don't worry about it.
What do you mean don't worry about it.
Look at your goddamn face.
I said don't worry about it.
Okay, it's not your problem.
When?
Grabbed me a couple of days ago right after
I go off work.
Cowards.
I did everything I can possibly do.
But they broke some of your tools.
I will replace them.
Don't worry about the tools.
Where is your cousin lives?
No, Walt.
I'll be ok.
I don't want you to do anything.
- Right,.
You could need extra tools, you just let me
know.
Well, I could use a roofing hammer.
-Good, go in my garage and get it.
This should be the last stop.
Here is the deal.
You stay away from Tao, understand?
You tell your friends to stay away from Tao.
You want to fight with us than I could
sound don't want to see him anymore.
That's it, got it?
I'll take that as yes. Cause if I have to
come back here it is gonna get fucking ugly.
Get off of my way.
How do you want your dog?
I mean steak?
Funny.
I told you we only eat cats.
I've never seen you like this before.
Well I am feeling good.
I god beautiful women, great food.
And Tao.
And even Tao isn't bugging me.
You are having a good time, I see.
-Yeah.
And it never ends.
What happened to your knuckles anyways?
I slipped in a shower. No big problem.
Look Yum-Yum if he doesn't ask you out I
will ask you out.
Wa Xam, don't listen to him. He is a white
devil.
Yeah, I am. I am a white devil.
I've loved to Walt,
but he beat you to it.
Really? No kidding!
Dinner and a movie, or what?
Yeah, they are taking a bus.
No, you can't take a bus. You gonna get you
something more stylish that that.
Like what? Take a limo?
How about that?
The Gran Torino?
- Yeah.
You'd let me take the Gran Torino.
- Yeah, I let you take the Gran Torino.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Is everybody all right?
Tao!
It's all right.
Where's grandma?
Where is Sue?
- She went to our aunts.
To her aunts? Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Get on the phone and call her right now.
Sue ...
I knew, this was gonna happen.
What the hell am I doing here?
Maybe some of her friends called her and
she changed her plans.
Yeah.
At the war we just  all of us lost a lot of
friends but you gotta stand for it.
You can care to it.
Mr. Kowalski?
Are you Ok?
Yeah, I am Ok.
Police finally left, no one is talking.
One thing about Hmong, they keep their
mouths shut.
Yeah, I've noticed that.
You know, Tao and Sue will never gonna find
peace in this world
as long as those gangs around.
Until they go away. You know forever.
What are you saying?
You know what I am saying.
I took Sue to the hospital.
She is scared.
They are all scared..
Yeah
Tao especially. He?s sitting out there
right now staring at your front door.
You know what he expects, Mr. Kowalski.
What would you do?
What should Tao do?
I know what I would do if I was you.
Or at least what you think you should do.
- Really
If I was Tao I guess I'd wanted vengeance.
I'd wanted to stand shoulder to shoulder
with you and kill those guys.
And you?
- What would I do?
I'd come over here and talk to you I guess.
I know you are close with these people, but
this pisses me off too. Mr.Kowalski.
Wanna beer?
- I'd love one.
There some in the chest, right over there
behind you.
Damn all this.
It just isn't fair.
- Nothing is fair, father.
So what you gonna do, Mr. Kowalski?
Call me Walt.
All right.
What you gonna do,  Walt?
I don't know.
But I'll think of something.
Whatever it is, they won't have a chance.
What are you doing?
Thinking.
Thinking time is over.
Now it's time to knock shit out of these
pricks.
I know you don't want to hear this, but now
it's the time to stay calm.
Calm? You want me to be calm?
We stay calm or else mistakes will get made.
We have to step back from this thing.
No, don't let me down Walt. Not you.
This is gonna end today.
Sit down.
I don't want to sit. I said sit down.
Now, listen to me.
We gotta plan this and plan it very
carefully.
Can't make any mistakes.
You know I am the right man for this job.
I want to go home and stay calm, and come
back here at 4 this afternoon.
And this to be done will be done.
I say we go now, Right now.
And what? Kill that cousin of yours and the
rest of those zips.
Mr. Tough Guy is out for blood all of the
sudden. I know nothing about it.
Now go home.
You stay calm come back here at 4.
Ok?
Okay.
I know, I know. Give me a break,
please,  it?s the first time
I?ve ever smoked in the house.
Let a man enjoy himself,would you girl.
All finished. 10 dollars American.
I don?t suppose your guinea  hands are
steady enough
to do a straight shave?
- Straight shave?
You've never asked about straight shave
ever.
I know but I always wondered about it.
That's unless you are too busy.
No, just let me heat up a towel.
Here is 20.
Keep the change. It is just in case you hit
my jugular.
Yes sir, It gonna take about one hour. We
gonna shorten these sleeves little bit.
Gonna fix at the shoulder.
I never had a suited suit before.
Yes sir, look very good.
Yes, sir.
Look very good.
What can I do for you, Mr. Kowalski?
- I am here for a confession.
Lord Jesus, what have you done?
- Nothing you just take it easy now.
What are you up to?
Are you gonna give a confession or not?
How long has it been since your last
confession?
Forever.
Bless me father, for I have sinned.
What are your sins, my son?
In 1968, I kissed Betty Jablonski
at the factory Christmas party.
Dorothy was in the other room with the
other wives.
it just happened.
Yes, go on.
Well, I made 900 dollars profit selling a
boat and motor.
I didn't pay the taxes it is the same as
stealing.
Yes, fine.
Lastly...
I was never very close with my two sons.
I don't know them. I didn't know how.
That's it?
- That's it.
It's bothered me most of my life.
Say 10 "Hail Maries"
and 5 "Our fathers".
God loves and forgives you and absolves you
of all your sins.
In the name of the Father, Son and the Holy
Spirit.
Thank you padre.
Are you going to retaliate for what
happened to Sue.
I?m going over to that house today, Mr.
Kowalski.
Is that so?
- It is.
And every other day until you see the folly
of what you are planning.
Busy day, gotta go.
- Go in peace.
Oh I am at peace.
Jesus Christ.
So which one is mine?
You ever fired a weapon before?
- No
Why don't you put that one down.
I got something more to show you.
What?
In 1952 we were sent to take out a chink
machine gun nest.
They trod us up pretty good. I was the only
one who came back out there.
For that they gave me a silver star.
Here it is.
Here I want you to have it.
Why?
Because we all knew the danger that night.
But we went anyway.
That's the way it might be tonight.
There is always a chance you don't come
back. The hell we won?t.
We?re will  roll in there and tear ass.
Yeah, that's foolish. That's the exact
reaction they are waiting for.
Come on and close this up.
How many?
- How many what?
How many men did you kill in Korea?
13, maybe more.
-What was it like to kill a man.
You don't want to know.
Now close it up.
Walt! Walt!
What are you doing?
Relax, you can't get out of there.
You let me out right now !
Let me out. You fuck let me out, I'll
fucking kill you.
Shut the fuck up!
You want to know what is like to kill a man?
Well, that's goddamn awful.
The only thing worse is get a medal of
valor for killing some poor kids..
that wanted just to give up that's all
Yeah, some scared little gook just like you.
I shot them right in a face with that rifle
you were holding in there a while ago.
So if the day goes by that I don't think
about it. You don't that on your soul.
I got blood on my hands. I am soiled.
That's why I am going alone tonight.
Walt you take me with you right now,
let me out.
Look, you've come a long way.
I am proud to say that you are my friend.
But you got your whole life ahead of you.
But me, I finished things.  That's what I
do and I am going alone.
No, wait. Walt! Walt!
I need you to watch my dog.
Yeah I love you too.
Yeah, she is old too.
Her name is Daisy.
Hello.
- It is Walt.
The keys to my house are under the ceramic
turtle on the from porch.
Let yourself in. Your brother is in the
basement. I gotta go.
Sorry father, we have to go.
I am telling if we are not here there will
be a bloodshed.
We've been here for hours.
We can't afford to anchor a unit down to
one location.
I am bagging you to stay.
Just got a word from my sergeant, we're
pulling the plug.
I am staying. No you aren't.
We have specific orders you came with us,
you are leaving with us.
Watch your head.
Sue, over here, over here.
Unlock this right now.
He left without me.
He went to Smokie without me.
Tao!
Any swamp rats in there.
I didn't know your ass would came.
-Shut up, gook.
I have nothing to say to you, shrimp dick,
lizard like you.
Yeah, yeah. You go ahead watch out for your
boyfriend.
Cause it was either he or you or something
who raped one of their own family.
You own blood, for Christ sake.
Now go ahead and pull those pistols, like
miniature cowboys.
Go ahead.
So where's Tao at? That pussy motherfucker
not gonna come.
Don't worry about Tao.
Tao's got not one second for you.
Says who?
You?
What the fuck you gonna do, old man?
What are you gonna do? You bitch.
-
Kind of jumpy, aren't we?
- Shut the fuck up.
You should the fuck up!
Got a light?
- What the fuck?
No
Me.. I've got a light...
'Hail Mary, full of grace..'
Yes, sergeant.
What happened?
- You need to step back.
He is a friend of mine.
- He said step back.
Hey, did you hear him.
Step back.
What happened?
- Hey, step back.
He is my friend.
Officer Chang! get those people back.
- Hey, step back now, Ok.
Get the fuck out of here!
Walt Kowalski once said to me that I didn't
know anything about life or death.
Because I was an overeducated,
27-year-old virgin who held the hands
of superstitious old women and
promised they eternity.
Walt definitely had no problem calling
it like he saw it.
But he was right.
I knew really nothing about life or death,
until I got to know Walt.
And boy did I learn.
And I want to leave my house  to the church
becouse Dorothy would've liked it...
... now which brings to out last item . And
again please excuse the language.
in  Mr. Kowalski's will,  I?m simply
reading it as it was written.
And I'd like to leave my 1972
Gran Torino to ...
my friend ...
Tao Vang Lor.
Under the condition that you don?
t choptop top the roof like
one of those beaners
don?t paint any idiotic flames on
it like some white-trash hillbilly
and don?t put a big gay
spoiler on the rear end
like you see on all the other
zipper heads? cars
It just looks like hell
If you If you can  refrain from doing
any of that, it?s yours