Tommy?
Jesus!
Whatre you doing here?
I was just passing through.
And I figured,
why not have a belt with the old man.
She looks good.
Yeah,
shes hanging in there.
Well, you always did take good care of her.
Paddy Conlon.
Man of priorities.
Got a little something for ya.
Mom always said,
never go anywhere empty handed.
She did.
But thats not for me anymore, Tommy.
You change brands?
lets go inside, huh.
Tommy...
Cmon, lets go inside.
- WARRIOR -
Subtitle by d3xt3r
www.addic7ed.com
I like what youve done with the place.
-  Appreciate that.
- Theres not much of a womans touch around here.
- No more women for me, Tommy.
Yeah...
Must be hard to find a girl
who can take a punch nowadays.
- Here you go.
- Coffee?
You havent seen a guy in 14 years
and youre not gonna have a drink with him?
- I told you, Im off it. Tommy.
Im coming up on a thousand days.
- Cmon,
just a drink.
- No.
Hes a school teacher down in Philly.
Remember Tess?
Theyve got two beautiful little girls.
So you found God, huh?
Thats awesome.
Mom kept calling for him,
but he wasnt around.
I guess Jesus was down at the mill
forgiving all  the drunks. Huh?
Who knew?
So, you gonna ask about her,
or you just gonna sit there all sober?
I know.
Oh, you know?
What do you know?
Do you know it wasnt enough just to
drive west to get away from you?
Once, we hit the water we drove north, too.
- When I got sober
I hired a man to find you.
- Is that one of the 12 steps?
Or does a guy like you get 24?
- Just the 12.
- Did your guy tell you
what you needed to know?
- Just that your mother died in Tacoma.
And you were in the Marines.
That was all.
That was enough.
- Well, Thats too bad.
You couldve gotten some good details.
You couldve heard about her coughing up blood
on her kness,in a shit box with no heat.
Having me rub her down with holy water,
because she didnt have no insurance.
All the time.. waiting for your pal Jesus to save her.
Did your man tell you that?
- Im sorry, Tommy.
- Well, Its good to know youre sorry, Pop.
It goes a long way.
I think I liked you better
when you were a drunk.
Whats going on over here?
Well, Im not sure,
but I think Daddy is now a princess.
- Daddy, you look so handsome.
- Do I?
You want to open your presents?
This an awfully big box.
Its her birthday.
I know,
but thats why you call it a budget.
You set it, and you dont budge.
Hey babe, Im late.
Moms saying goodbye to the girls.
Shes gotta get on the road. Theyve been fed.
They just need a bath.
Im on it.
Can you get them in bed
at a reasonable time tonight?
After the party,
Theyre exhausted.
- Where's the rest of that skirt?
Babe.
Listen, if any guys give you a hassle in that joint tonight
you give me a call, okay?
- Yeah. Just like you gave me a call
when those Temple frat boys decided to smash up your face.
I told you, most nights
I sit on the stool and grade papers,
but every now and then
I need some action.
- Alright, well wait up for me tonight.
Ill see what I can do about that.
- Promises, promises.
JON ANIK (ON TV):
And we return here on MMA Live,
Jon Anik alongside
billionaire fight promoter J.J. Riley.
The Tapout crew is also here.
Punk and Skrape are in the building.
Now J.J., what led to this project that is
redefining Mixed Martial Arts here in the States?
- Well, Mixed Martial Arts is a sport that
Ive always been incredibly passionate about.
As for where the idea for Sparta came from,
Ive always kind of dug the Grand Prix format,
so I tracked these guys down to help me out.
- When J.J. came to us he said
he wanted to create the Super Bowl of Mixed Martial Arts.
And he decided to put up
the five million dollar purse, too.
Well, there you have it.
It shall be done.
Hedge fund king J.J. Riley,
going from the lions den of Wall Street to the cage,
promoting the biggest winner-take-all
tournament in MMA history. Sparta.
Fitzy still own this?
- Dont know no Fitzy.
Colt Boyd owns this gym.
Can I help you with something?
- Hows it work?
- Thirty five a month with locker.
Were open at 7, lights out at 11.
- So, You wanna join?
- Sure.
- Put your name and contact info on the card.
- Thank you.
Whoa whoa whoa!
Theres a lesson in this too, OK?
So we have a body at rest,
and you have the bat which needs--
Acceleration.
Acceleration, okay.
If you have enough acceleration,
you might have a chance
to break the body at rest.
Alright, There we go.
Dial it down.
So, have we got it?
Force equals mass times acceleration.
We got it.
Alright. The third law--
How many laws this dude got?
- The dude?
- Yes, the dude.
The dude has three.
Newton the dude says that
for every action, theres an equal and opposite reaction.
For example,
if KC does not stop the action
of sending texts in class...
...and tell her posse outside to beat it...
...then my reaction might be to
send her down to Principal Zitos office.
Thus setting our world back..
in proper balance.
Mr. C, I put it away.
Alright, before you go,
I have your tests from last week.
Where do you find these girls?
We got a tournament coming up. You
gonna kill every guy in the Burgh?
Fenroy. Get me some ice.
And call that Puerto Rican kid, the one that
fights outa the Bottoms.
If hes here in 20 minutes,
he gets 200 bucks.
Yo, Ill fight him.
Do me a favor guy,
go back to your bag.
We dont need anybody else getting hurt.
Take a walk.
Yo Rock, What did you do?
Did you leave Mick and Paulie at home today?
His phones disconnected.
Then go through the list.
find me somebody.
Get me Joe Bones.
All Im saying is...
if you need somebody to help you,
Im happy to keep your boy warm for you.
You ever fought before?
Yeah.
This guy sign a waiver?
All good.
Whats your name?
Tommy.
You get tuned up in here, its on you, Tommy.
Sure, no problem.
Come on in.
Gonna be a hero? Alright.
You owe me two hundred bucks.
This one here.
See, this is the new appraisal figure,
as they came in.
As you can see, that's just the way it is,
that puts you upside down .
Thats the problem. Its the country
that did the assessment, not the bank.
So, the numbers are
what they are, Mr. Conlon.
- Brendan.
The numbers are what they are, Brendan.
I mean, youre a Math teacher,
you can appreciate that.
Physics teacher.
I teach Physics.
Physics. OK.
But the bank has got
to go by the new appraisal figures,
According to these figures,
youre upside down on your mortgage--
You said that three times.
I get that.
But Im asking you if
theres something else you can do.
Not the bank, you.
Can you shift things around, restructure--
- Well, youve already refinanced twice.
Already,
- Because you advised us to do that.
I presented you with that option.
That was your choice.
Im also showing you netted a
substantial payout with the refi.
- We had that conversation.
I was paying medical bills.
Is that in your file?
Oh, right. Sorry.
Your daughters...kidney?
- Heart.
- Heart, right.
Sorry.
Lot of stories.
So my option is Ive got no options?
Youre not even gonna try to help me?
- I am trying..
Look, I can get you 90 days to get even--
- 90 days is not enough.
My wife and I have three jobs between us;
and that doesnt cut it.
So, what do you suggest?
Let me ask you a question:
Have you thought aboutbankruptcy?
Its a viable option.
Theres no shame in it these days.
- Thats not how I do things.
- Well, then youre looking at foreclosure.
TV- ANNOUNCER #1: Utter domination by Tommy Conlon,
the undefeated freshman from Pittsburgh...
...the prodigy has yet to yield
a single point in the entire tournament.
ANNOUNCER #1:
Tommy trained by his father since the age of five.
- Youre talking about Paddy Conlon.
- The controversial Paddy Conlon.
Say what you will about the methods
of the former Marine,
but hes led  his son
to six straight junior Olympic titles,
and now just moments away
from a high school state championship.
- And there it is!
Wow!
Theres just no limit to what the
future holds for this kid!
Tommy told me that hes chasing
the record of Theogenes,
apparently a mythical Greek fighter,
said to be unbeaten in over 1400 bouts...
How you doin, sir?
Im looking for Tommy Riordan.
- Who?
- Tommy Riordan?
My names Colt Boyd.
- What business you got with Tommy?
- None yet.
Thats why Im here. I manage fighters.
Tommys been working out at my gym.
He put a beating on the number one
middleweight contender in the world today.
I want to know more about the guy.
Maybe help him out.
I have a lot of contacts, Mr. Riordan.
- Conlon. Names Conlon.
And anything you want to know about Tommy,
you gotta ask him yourself.
- Look, Im just asking for
some general information here.
- Like I said,
anything you want to know about Tommy,
you gotta ask him yourself.
- Look, I dont mean to interrupt your night. Okay?
He just put this address down
when he signed up at the gym.
- He doesnt live here.
- Alright then.
- Goodnight.
Listen kiddo,
I need you put Mommy back on, OK?
I love you.
Hey, listen...Im just pulling in.
I'm gonna have to go.
Huh? Oh, theyve got this open mic night thing.
It's gonna be a quiet one.
Sleep well.
You too. Bye.
FIGHT ANNOUNCER:
Its time for our next contest!
Introducing first,
fighting out of the red corner,
from Ripley, West Virginia..
please welcome
Mike The Mutilator Moore!
And in the blue corner.
He fights out of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Please welcome
Irish Brendan  Conlon!
This bout is scheduled for
three five-minute rounds,
and when the action begins
your referee is Mr. Rick Fike.
REFEREE:
Fighters to the center!
I want you to obey my commands at all times.
I want you to protect yourself at all times..
If you have no questions,
touch gloves, back up,
and on my signal. Come out fighting!
Fighters, are you ready?
are you ready?
Let's do it!
How was work?
Oh my God.
What happened?
You said it was going to be a slow night.
Im not bouncing at a club.
What do you mean youre not bouncing?
Youve been lying to me?
I went in to apply.
They were only paying nine bucks an hour.
Then I saw a sign for this other thing.
Theyre putting us out of the house in three months,
were running out of options--
Then theyll put us out of the house in three months.
Id rather go back to the old apartment than
see you in the back of an ambulance again.
I thought we agreed that
we werent going to raise our children in
a family where
their father gets beat up for a living.
Were not giving up the house.
This is our home.
Were not going backwards.
Well figure it out.
But this is what were not going back to.
You wanted to talk?
- Yeah.
Im gonna start fighting.
- Is that right?
- Dont play babe in the woods with me.
I know that guy from the gym came to see you.
- Colt Boyd? yeah..
I didnt tell him anything, Tommy.
We wouldnt be sitting
here now if you did.
Waiter: Paddy, can I get you more coffee?
- No, thank you.
Alright. Look.
Theres this tournament.
It's a big tournament.
Top sixteen middleweights in the world.
Single elimination.
Winner take all for a lot of money.
Im gonna do that.
But if Im doin it,
then Im gonna need a trainer.
Now that much you were good at.
No, no, no.
This doesnt mean anything..okay?
Im serious.
We train. Thats it.
I dont wanna hear
a word about anything but training,
...you understand?
You wanna tell your war stories,
you can take em down to the VFW.
You can take em to a meeting,
or church, or wherever
the hell it is you go nowadays.
- What about Colt Boyd?
- What about him? I told him
I dont train with people I dont know.
- Ah, the devil you know.
- Excuse me?
- The devil you know is better than
the devil you dont.
- Yeah.
Chasing Theogenes.
Itll be kinda like old times.
- I just told you,
this doesnt mean anything.
Now, get that through your skull
right now or Im walking.
Alright. Alright.
But you get something through your skull, too.
You called me.
So dont go threatening
to walk every five minutes!
And since this is about training,
you dump whatever it is you need to dump
as far as those  pills are concerned.
I dont want to see em.
In fact, hand em over right now.
I know theyre on you, Tommy.
You sounded like a goddamn maraca
coming through the door.
Thats not gonna do.
When you came through that door
it was chhh-chhh-chhh.
Three.
And another thing,
you dont eat crap like this.
This is for losers and old men.
And were gonna have to bunk up.
If were gonna do this right,
you gotta stay at the house.
I watch your diet,
we follow the old regimen.
You copy?
Copy.
My brother said in the middle of night,
he was at the strip  club and saw Mr. C ...
You weren't there, you don't know.
Whats MMA?
Mixed Martial Arts.
Like, different styles of fighting.
Take your seats.
Now, please.
- Yo, Mr. C.
- uh Huh?
My brother was at the titty bar last night
and he said you was choking brothers out.
Whats up? Is it true?
Yeah, Mr. C. I mean, did you really
work on some fools or something?
You have to tell us.
- Yeah.
I want examples of 'forms of energy'.
Cmon, its not as bad as it looks.
- Are you being literal or figurative?
Because literally it looks bad.
And figuratively it looks even worse.
The superintendents coming by in a few minutes.
- Oh, Man!
- So, c'mon Brandon.
gimme a little help here.
Could you explain to me
what the hell you were doing?
- I need the money, Joe.
- Yeah, but this is...
We cant have this!
This isnt moonlighting at Applebees
for Christs sake.
Shit, Brendan.
Leaving everything else aside,
which we cant,
are you out of your mind?
Youre gonna get yourself killed.
I mean, youre..
youre a goddamn teacher.
Youve got no business
in the ring with those animals.
- Actually, I used to be one of those animals.
I fought for a living.
Guess I forgot to put that
down on my application.
- Yeah, I guess you did.
- Look, Im sorry, Joe. Its just--
- Look, look...the school districts not going to
tolerate school teachers cockfighting in strip clubs.
- It was the parking lot of a strip club.
- Wherever it was,
you cant be doing it, alright?
I mean this is a serious--
shit, hes here.
This is a serious problem.
The guy hasnt been inside a school since 9-11.
- What are we gonna do?
- You say yes, sir.
And you say no, sir.
And you say itll never happen again, sir.
And then we just
pray to God hes in a good mood.
- UFC?
- Yeah.
- Sonofabitch.
What are you doing?
- The girls have an important
piano recital in the morning.
Got an equipment malfunction.
Howd it go?
- Theyre gonna review your case
at the end of the semester,
but until then
youre suspended without pay.
Joe gave me the number of his attorney.
- How the hell are we gonna
pay for an attorney?
- He talked to me for free.
As a favor to Joe.
- That's nice.
- He said theres no precedent for this.
Youll be back by next semester.
- Next semester?
Look, Tess.
They have these smoker fights all over.
Theres one in Lancaster next week.
Theres two in Dover the week after.
Wilmington.
Camden. Baltimore.
It could keep us afloat.
- Youre gonna put yourself through this
over and over,
for five hundred bucks a pop?
- Some of them pay a little more than that.
I would have had to bounce for a month
to make what I made in two hours last night.
And these guys,
theyre not real fighters.
Theyre just guys
who have seen too much UFC on TV.
If you have a better solution,
Im all ears.
- What are we gonna tell the girls?
- Itll be fine.
Ill just leave the house as usual,
except only this time,
Ill be going to the gym.
Oh the duck goes quack - quack quack..
and the cow says moo, moo..mooooo!
But that rooster,
the old red rooster he knew everything...
cock-a-doodle-doo. Cock-a- doodle-doo.
Let's go kiddo.
Let's get moving.
Look what I found..
in that disaster of a basement.
What do 'ya say we sit down
and update this?
And you can fill me in on;
how close you got to that record.
Did you continue wrestling,
after you left with your mother?
Cmon, Tommy.
Tell me something.
- Yeah, Ill tell ya something.
You can take that back to where you found it.
And you can leave
the coffee in the pot.
I can pour that myself.
And  I can wake myself up, too.
- OK.
Hurt my knees coming up and down
those stairs anyhow.
I'll leave the coffee pots on til 0-500,
then I dump it.
Damn dude, thats brutal.
I give command to dismiss.
You'll wash your nasty bodies.
and square your gear away.
Damn dude, thats brutal.
- Whats that?
Dude, Mad Dog Grimes gettin tuned up
by some dude in a gym in Pittsburgh.
- Whos Mad Dog Grimes?
- Shit, Bradford.
The stuff you dont know amazes me.
Oh my god, did you see that?
- Wait, rewind that.
Right there...
pause, pause..pause.
What's up man?
Dude, what's his deal?
AV, I need to see the tape!
- What tape?
- The tape.
Get the camera.
Thats him.
Frank: Let the music sink in to you.
This is Beethoven.
And I want you to breathe.
I don't want you boxing like this.
No more stiffs...right?
You listen to the music.
You relax...you breathe.
Do I know you?
Long time, brother.
- I'm liking the place.
- You see this beast?
Marco Santos?
Im training him for Sparta.
- Oh Yeah, right.
- Not bad, right?
- It's amazing man.
You look good, brother.
- Thanks.
-  Howre the girls?
- Good.
I had another little one. Rosie.
- I know. Because, Johnny C. told me
she was in the hospital for a bit.
You know I uh..
I was gonna call you and then time went by.
Im a piece of shit.
I should have called you, I'm sorry.
No, Brendan. Im sorry.
- Its all good.
Shes good now.
- Its good to see you, man.
So everythings going...
It's great huh?
- Yeah. Well, Ive got a little problem.
The guys at the bank
want to take my house away.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Thats kind of why I came to see you, actually.
- Ive got most of my dough tied up
in this joint, but..
how much do you need?
- I didnt come here for a loan, Frank.
I mean...
I was hoping youd train me.
- Train you for what?
- I want to get back in the cage.
- Are you serious?
Come on, Brandon.
- I just won an event the other night.
- Ah, you won an event.
Thats what this is.
Let me guess,
it was in a parking lot.
DJ from the local radio station.
Couple of ring card girls...
you wouldnt bang on a dare.
Am I right?
- Ish.
-  Ish...
Brendan. I love you.
Why would I train you?
When you were in shape and on the right side
of 30 you were barely a .500 fighter. You never listened to me.
You never listened to anyone.
These guys are animals.
Youre a teacher, right?
Whatre you gonna do? Youre gonna come down
here for a couple days a week after detention?
Youre gonna skip out of the girls
volleyball game early?
- Ive got loads of time.
Times not an issue.
The parking lot thing
kinda got me suspended.
I need to keep working the smokers.
- Tess know about this?
- Mmm..hmm.
- Cause the last time you  fought, I got read the riot act
sitting in a hospital waiting room. You remember that?
- I was unconscious.
- You were more than unconcious.
Shes not gonna come down here with
the two puppies, screaming at Frank?
- Its not gonna happen.
What do you say, Frank?
- What do I say?
What am I gonna say to you? No?
I mean,
all my time is wrapped up with Marco.
You come down,
Ill throw you in the rotation,
you spar with these guys,
But I cant promise you
much more than that, Brendan.
- Thats all I need.
I appreciate it.
- Let me know when youre coming down.
Well, Im just gonna go
get my stuff from the car.
- Now?
Hey, Brendan.
Its me, Pop.
Whatre you doing here?
- I have some news for you.
- Something wrong with your hands?
If theres nothing wrong with your hands
then theres no reason for you not to phone.
- Thats the deal.
- I forgot.
- Phone or mail, Pop.
Non negotiable.
- Hey Brendan,
Have you ever seen my hands so steady?
Ever seen them?
- Im going inside.
- Ive got a thousand days, Brendan.
A thousand days sober today.
- Well, thats great, Pop.
But it doesnt change anything.
- What do you mean it doesnt change anything?
Have a heart, Brendan.
- You listen to me.
You take your have-a-heart bullshit
and you run it down the road.
Run it out on someone
who doesnt know you like I do.
- I thought maybe we could break bread.
Open some lines of communication.
- You got two lines of communication,
You got the telephone and the post office.
Just because you decide its a special day,
it doesnt make it one for me.
I got a wife and kids inside
and theyre waiting for me,
so I dont have time for whatever this is.
-  I know you got a wife and kids in there.
I got a grand-daughter in there..
and I havent seen in three years
and another I havent even ever met.
- Yeah, Why is that, Pop?
Why is that?
Do you remember having anything to do with that?
- Yeah.
- That shit you pulled.
Never again.
And all the shit I saw growing up?
That doesnt happen here.
Take care of yourself.
- Tommys back.
Hes in the Burgh.
- You say, Tommys in Pittsburgh?
- He came to see me.
- He came to see you?
- Hes over at the house.
Were doing a little training at Fitzys.
Remember Fitzys?
It aint Fitzys anymore.
- You and Tommy are training together?
Tommy Conlon?
- Riordan.
Hes using your mothers maiden name now.
I know what her name is.
- I thought youd want to know hes back.
Thats why I drove all the way over here.
- I thought you came
to break bread over a thousand days?
That too.
- Did he say if he wants to see me?
- He doesnt say much.
Hes just not that happy kid he was.
- Wow, look at you.
Mister inside man.
You and Tommy training together
like nothing ever happened.
This is unbelievable.
- Now I know what youre really doing here.
- Whats that?
- You came to gloat.
- I did not come to gloat.
I came to get my son back.
- Well, there you go.
Hey, You got your son back.
- Im talking about you, Bren--
- You got your son back.
You know,
Forget it!
I'll tell you, part of the reason
I stuck around was...
cause I thought Id finally get you all to myself.
But you didnt have any interest in training me.
Tommy was the one.
- Ah, Brendan.
I was a drunk.
I mean, you know.
Im sorry.
You were always a front runner.
You never had any interest in underdogs.
But I was your son.
- You are my son, Brendan.
- Am I?
- Yeah, you are.
Im just asking you to find...
a whoo bit of space in your heart to forgive me.
- Yeah. Alright.
I forgive you.
But I do not trust you.
So, tell Tommy...if he wants to see me,
this is where I am.
- But theyre not different things.
Youve gotta trust to forgive--
- Goodnight, Pop.
My God, is that Emily?
Shes grown, Brendan.
Is that Rosie?
- Daddy, who is that?
- Just some nice old man.
Tv Host: Huge news breaking here at ESPN.
Koba is coming to America
and will fight at Sparta.
Universally considered to be the greatest
pound for pound fighter that ever lived,
the mighty, mythical Russian
has never fought on U.S. soil in his legendary career...
Tommy?
Got some news for ya.
I got you into Sparta.
Took some doing,
but I made it happen..
Thank you and 10 percent is customary.
Bueno?
- Pilar. Its Tommy.
Tommy!
Dios mio!
I cant believe it!
How are you?
Good good. How you doin?
OK. You know me, Tommy.
I was getting really worried about you.
- Howre things?
Kids are good?
Theyre good.
Marias getting so big.
- Yeah?
She looks more like Manny every day.
- Hows little man?
Hes good. Hes a good kid, Tommy.
He takes care of his sister.
Hes a great kid. Everyones good.
- You know, Pilar,
I havent forgotten for one minute
what I promised you.
What I promised  Manny. Ive got an opportunity
coming up to help you guys out.
To take care of you guys.
Manny would really appreciate it.
You know what?
You worry too much.
Its OK.
Were hanging in there.
JON ANIK : With eight weeks left til Sparta,
J.J. Riley and the TapOut crew
take time out of their international press tour to join us.
- J.J., weve never seen this kind of Grand Prix
tournament in the country before.
Tell us, why the unique format?
- Well, Jon, you know as well as anyone
that in Mixed Martial Arts,
anyone can beat anyone on a given night...
...but with this type of format,
its gonna be tough to deny who the champion is.
Youve got four fights in two nights,
sixteen fighters down to one.
Winners gonna be the last man standing.
five weeks left til Sparta and the hype continues
for the War on the Shore.
Fourth of July weekend in Atlantic City
and you know what that means:
the great Koba, bringing his act stateside;
but I gotta ask you about the other guys.
What are they thinking
entering a winner take all tournament...
against a guy that seemingly cant be beat?
- Theyre thinking five million dollars,
and five million dollars is a lot of money,
but theyve gotta remember one thing:
theyre going against Koba.
Mission impossible.
Game over.
Go home.
The Pittsburgh Beatdown has become
one of the most watched videos on YouTube this year.
Now joining us via satellite
is the victim of the infamous incident,
Mad Dog Grimes.
Mad Dog, what is your response
to all the hoopla surrounding the video and Tommy Riordan?
- This guys a nobody.
It was just a sparring session.
It is what it is,
and hes gonna pay for it next month
in Atlantic City.
With Sparta now
just two short weeks away,
J.J. Riley and the TapOut crew returned
to the U.S. after a world tour;
that saw them visit
ten fighters in ten different countries.
They stopped in Philadelphia today
to check in on renowned trainer
Frank Campana
and top contender Marco Santos.
Frank: Youve gotta relax
and stay calm in there.
The cage is your home.
You set the pace.
You set the rhythm.
Feel the Beethoven.
Be smarter than him.
More patient.
Wait for him to make a mistake.
And when he does,
thats your moment.
No he did not tap you!
Physics teacher!
Thats the best in the world there, son.
Coach!
Hey,
I know this isnt a great time.
And its too bad about Marco.
But how about me?
- You talking about Sparta?
Brendan, You got a better chance
of starting a boy band.Ill talk to you tomorrow.
-  Its a grand prix tournament.
Which means anything can happen.
You know that as well as I do.
- Yeah.
- Theyll have to kill me
to get me out of that cage.
- Thats what Im afraid of.
- Frank, I need this.
Youre real tight with those guys.
You call them,
you're the guy they trust you.
- Brendan,
You realize what youre asking me to do here?
We go down to AC
and you get tapped out in five seconds,
how does that benefit  either one of us?
- Thats not gonna happen.
- Not gonna happen.
Wish I had a  nickel for every time I heard that.
- Its not gonna happen.
- Ill make a call.
- I love my coach!!!
Tess: Yeah, the girls are good.
Theyre good.
Yeah, you should. Youve been spending
so much time with Brendan these days..
its like youre part of the family or something.
Yeah, hes right here.
Its your boyfriend.
- Frank... Hey Man.
Thats unbelievable.
Frank, I cant thank you enough.
I dont know what to say.
Alright, listen,
Ive gotta call you back. Okay.
Alright, bye.
Im in. Im going.
- Really?
So thats your decision?
You decided?
Cause I really enjoyed that conversation
we just had about making that decision together.
You told me you were gonna fight
guys that watched too much UFC.
I saw that Koba dude on television,
and hes the guy theyre watching.
-  Its a lot of money, Tess.
- I dont give a shit about the money, Brendan.
I told you that.
Were gonna end up cashing in your life insurance
policy before we pick up that prize money.
- You dont think I can do it. Right?
- I think you can get killed.
- Im not gonna get killed.
- youre not going to get killed.
you promise me youre not going to get hurt?
Youre not gonna end up in the hospital?
Youre not gonna end up paralyzed?
Well have no prize money.
We'll have no house.
Payments for hospital bills--
- Listen, I promise you this:
if I dont try in three weeks,
theyre gonna take the house.
Hows that for a promise?
So, Im gonna go, OK?
But Id really love it
if youd be with me on this.
- Im not gonna watch you fight again.
Im not.
Im gonna get the girls breakfast.
Fourth of July weekend
doesnt officially start until tomorrow..
...but fight fans are already descending on Atlantic City
for the Super Bowl of Mixed Martial Arts,
Sparta.
J.J., youve made a fortune with your hedge funds,
yet you turned your back on Wall Street..
and dedicated your life
to making Sparta happen.
Tell us, why is this tournament
is so important to you?
- Growing up, we all wanted to know
who the toughest kid in the neighborhood was, right?
I wanna  know
who the toughest man on the planet is.
Thats why I put this together,
thats what all these people are here to see,
and come Saturday night,
thats what were gonna find out.
- Thank you, J.J.
And heres something
fans never thought theyd see: Koba is here!
The legend arriving to fight on U.S. soil
for the very first time...
Hey. Whered you go?
You cant leave me like that.
They wanna talk to you, not me.
...the only fighter missing from the event
was dark horse entry Tommy Riordan.
Recent revelations that Riordan
was not only a United States Marine;
but a hero in the Iraq War,
has cast an even brighter spotlight..
on a fighter who seems to
have come out of nowhere.
Lance Corporal Mark Bradfords web
testimony to Riordan,
who saved his life earlier this year in Iraq,
is spreading like wildfire
throughout the media.
Tommy!
You gotta see this.
BRADFORD:
The Amtrack was upside down.
Water was coming in from everywhere.
The water pressure was too much.
We couldnt get the back hatch open.
We were all drowning, man.
It was a death trap.
I couldnt have had more than another minute.
Suddenly the back ramp gets ripped off,
and there he was.
Before I could get out and thank him,
he was gone.
He just vanished like a ghost.
- Where are you going?
- Im takin a walk.
I just wanna say...
Thank You.
You saved my life, brother.
Anybody seeing this at Sparta,
anybody out in Pittsburgh,
You reach out to Tommy Riordan.
Tell him Mark said 'thank you'.
MICHELLE MOONEY (ON TV):
Footage taken from a helmet camera on the ground
captured the heroic incident...
Been looking all over for you.
Hows it going?
- Its going.
- I was thinking maybe we could grab a coffee.
- I dont drink coffee, man.
What 'ya want?
- You dont want to go sit down somewhere?
- Nah, Im good right here.
- Shit, Tommy.
How was I supposed to know
I was never gonna see you guys again?
- Yeah, well..you were briefed.
You had the information.
You chose the old man and the girl.
- She wasnt some girl.
I married her.
Shes my wife.
See.
Thats Tess.
And thats Emily and Rosie.
Theyre your nieces, Tommy.
- I dont know em.
- I know you dont know them.
Of course you dont know them.
- Why am I looking at pictures
of people I dont know?
- Because thats my family.
- And who are you exactly?
- Im your brother, man.
- You were in the Corps?
What?
- I said I didnt know you were in the Corps.
- I wasnt in the Corps.
- Then you aint no brother to me.
My brother was in the Corps.
- Jesus, Tommy.
I was a 16 year old kid.
What the hell did I know?
- I dont know what you know.
Why dont you go ask your girlfriend about it?
Shes my wife, Tommy.
So thats it?
I stay with Tess
and I never get to see you guys again?
Not a single phone call?
Nothing?
God, man,
I dont understand this.
So, you wont forgive me,
but you forgave Pop?
- Hes just some old vet I train with.
He means nothing to me.
From what I hear
he means nothing to you, either,
so you got balls
talking about forgiveness.
- Thats got nothing to do with forgiveness.
I've got children, man.
Ive got a family to protect.
Everything I do is for them.
But I forgave Pop.
Just like I forgave you and Mom.
- You forgave us?
- Yeah.
Im not surprised
you made the tournament, Brendan.
You got some stones, man.
- I fell in love,
What the hell was I supposed to do?
- You were supposed to stick to the plan.
You were supposed to come with us.
Mom needed you.
I needed you. You were my big brother
and you bailed on me.
Hey, Im glad you stayed and
everything worked out for you,
you leave, you get the opposite.
You leave,
you get to  bury people.
- Youre not the only one who suffered, Tommy.
I didnt even know she was sick.
I never even got the chance
to say goodbye to my own mother.
You had no right to keep that from me!
That was not your decision to make!
- You know what?
You walk around with your pictures in your wallet;
and youre all,
I forgive you, I forgive Pop.
I forgive everyone.
But you know what?
Youre full of shit.
Are we done, Brendan?
Are we finished?
You realize youre supposed to seek
my wise counsel when schools actually in session, right?
- Yes, Mr.Zito.
We want to use the auditorium
this weekend to watch Mr. C in Sparta.
What do you say?
So, you want to use the auditorium
to watch a  suspended teacher...
engage in the activity he was suspended for?
Am I hearing this correctly?
It can turn into fund raiser, you know?
I gotta talk to your parents.
Because, you guys might need
to be in summer school after all.
The gyms the only place thats big enough.
To fit everyone.
- Its never gonna happen.
- What if we get a petition signed?
I appreciate that you guys love your teacher.
I really do.
But there is nothing I can do for you.
The roof is about to blow clean off
Boardwalk Hall Arena!
It might be Fourth of July weekend,
but this is  Christmas Eve for fight fans!
This  is Atlantic City!
This is the War on the Shore!
And this is what everyone has been waiting for!
Sixteen of the baddest men on the planet
duking it out over a 24-hour period
for the largest purse in Mixed Martial Arts history.
In the town everyone knows
from the game of Monopoly,
weve got ourselves a winner-take-all affair.
Buckle your seatbelts,
roll the dice,
and take riiiiide
on the Reading.
Sparta.
Is. Here!
Welcome,
Im Bryan Callen;
along with best-selling fight author Sam Sheridan.
Sam, when J.J. Riley conceived Sparta,
he wanted to create, quite simply,
the biggest Mixed Martial Arts
spectacle in history.
- Five million dollars, Bryan.
Five million dollars.
J.J. Riley put his money
where his mouth is...
and put up the biggest purse
this sport has ever seen.
- Its unprecedented, Sam.
As is the hoopla surrounding Tommy Riordan,
the war hero---
who has become an overnight sensation...
and captured the imagination
and attention of....
Five minutes, Paddy.
okay.
It looks as though the moment of truth has arrived,
because here comes Tommy Riordan.
Tommy Riordans captured the medias attention,
but the question still remains:
who is this guy?
And more importantly,
can he compete in this talent pool?
Can he win?
- Ive gotta say the fact that I dont know is strange.
In an internet age
where there are no secrets,
this guy is a complete mystery.
I cant find out anything about him.
Tommy Riordan is officially Google proof.
- You gotta love this guy, Sam.
No walk out music,
no sponsors, no interviews.
He skipped out on the press conference.
Wouldnt have his picture take for the program.
Hes breaking every rule!
- The only reason that
Tommy is even in this tournament is...
because of a  video showing him beating up
Mad Dog Grimes in the gym.
- But the reason a lot of his fans
are in the stands is because of another video,
which is even more stunning than
the Mad Dog Grimes video.
Let me describe it for you folks
for the few who havent seen it,
but Tommy Riordan ripped the door off a tank
in the heat of battle,
saving lives in the process,
and then walked away without claiming a medal.
He ripped the door off a tank!
- Tommy Riordan is a genuine war hero,
Im not taking anything away from the guy.
Hes a very, very tough guy,
but the tank dont hit back.
Weve seen YouTube sensations
fail on the big stage before.
- Sam. He ripped the door off a tank!
Tommy Riordan definitely has his
hands full in his first opponent,
Francisco Barbosa.
Barbosa is nothing to scoff at.
Yeah, hes the real deal.
Very tough guy.
Very high caliber fighter.
Tommy Riordan came out of nowhere,
and I imagine hes going
to disappear just as quickly.
Gentlemen, youve been given your instructions.
I expect a clean fight.
Obey my commands at all times.
Defend yourselves at all times.
Touch gloves,
go back, lets do this.
Were about to get the big answer
to the big question: is Tommy Riordan for real? And here we go!
Barbosas gonna be looking for a take down.
Definitely gonna be looking for a take down.
Barbosa is down!
Barbosa has been knocked out!
Tommy Riordan is most definitely for real!
And now hes walking out of the cage!
Hes leaving the cage!
There goes another rule out the window!
Francisco Barbosa is out cold,
and he is out of this tournament, Bryan.
You can do this.
I want to hear you say it.
I can do this.
Then lets go do this.
Yeah.
J.J. Riley had less than 48 hours
to fill the spot,
and he basically had to rely
on the word of Frank Campana.
And he chose Brendan Conlon,
which quite frankly is something I just dont understand.
Brendan, Go get em.
I can understand coming out to no music,
by why in the world would you choose
classical music as your entrance?
This is Beethoven,
This is Ode to Joy, Bryan.
My apologies, Mr. Renaissance man.
You want to talk about renaissance
men, you gotta talk about Frank Campana.
Very unorthodox trainer,
and one of the best trainer in the game.
Hes well known for using classical music
to train his fighters to remain calm,
to remain patient,
and to remain composed under pressure.
Classical music is about as fitting
to this setting as Brendan Conlon is to this tournament.
In fact, let me show you something.
That my friend, is Brendan Conlon.
Brendan Conlon is about to get dropped into a shark tank.
Hes a feeder fish.
Cmon, give the guy a break.
At least weve seen him fight before.
He has been in the UFC. We remember him.
I remember him, too.
I remember him being very unmemorable.
Midnight Le getting ready to climb
into the cage and go to work.
When the brackets were announced,
He thought hed be going up against Marco Santos.
Hes gotta be thrilled to be seeing
Brendan Conlon standing across from him.
You asked for it.
Brendan retired from fighting some years ago,
hes actually a high school Physics teacher now,
and Midnight had some fun with that
at the press conference, yesterday.
He said he was gonna give
the teacher a serious lesson,
and that getting killed
was no way to spend a summer vacation.
Alright, guys, youve been given your instructions,
I expect a clean fight.
Obey my commands at all times.
Defend yourselves at all times.
Touch gloves,
go back, lets do this.
Have some fun, baby.
Move! You gotta move!
Midnight is all over Brendan.
This cant last much longer.
This wont last much longer.
The teacher just has no answers.
And now hes got the hooks in.
Beautiful! Beautiful!
He doesnt know what hit him!
Midnight is in big trouble!
This isnt happening!
This cant  happen!
Brendan Conlon tapped Midnight!
I cant believe it!
He tapped him out! He tapped him out!
He did it! He did it! He did  it!
This is what so great about Mixed Martial Arts.
Theres so many ways to lose.
One tiny miscalculation
anyone can win at any time.
Frank Campana embracing his man, I dont think
either one of them can believe what just happened.
Great show of sportsmanship from the teacher.
Thats a hallmark of Frank Campanas
philosophy right there.
Midnight Le is shocked.
He thought he had a free pass into the second round,
but instead hes going home.
He dominated the fight the entire way,
but fell prey to a very technical finish.
Very technical finish,
but come on, thats a fluke.
You call it a fluke.
I call it a guy maintaining composure
and waiting for his opportunity.
Conlon beats Midnight!
Unbelievable!!!
I hope you got a receipt for your goldfish.
I WON!!!!!!!!
Yes!
Were down to eight fighters,
soon to be seven
as Koba prepares to go to work
for the second time tonight.
Here comes the underdog, Brendan Conlon.
The teacher miraculously
passed his first test,
but now hes gotta face The Dane.
Brendan, You can do it.
Halfway through round three now
and the beating continues.
I honestly dont know
how Brendan Conlon is still standing, Sam.
He has been absolutely battered
in both his fights tonight.
Take him down!
Way to go, Brendan!
Im doing it !
OK, son.
The crowd catching fire
for war hero Tommy Riordan.
He doesnt seem to want anything
to do with all this adulation,
Hes just here to fight.
Gentlemen, you ready?
You ready?
Lets go to war!
Here he comes again like a buzzsaw.
He's is all over Diego Santana!
Tommy Riordan marching through the crowd,
and straight into the final four!
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Cant sleep, huh?
I know that other things...
bothering the hell out of you,
Im proud of you. Tommy.
What you did for that kid  in the tank?
That was really something.
How about deserting my unit?
Is that really something, too?
Yeah.
I was on my way outta country
when I  came across those guys.
What was I supposed to do, let em drown?
No.
Whatd you do?
Whatd I do?
I took off.
Thats why you go by Riordan.
Thats why they
cant find your service records.
What the hell happened over there, Tommy?
That is none of your business.
Come on, kiddo. Ive been there.
Ive done it. Ive seen it.
You can trust me.
Ill understand.
Spare me the compassionate father routine, Pop.
The suit dont fit.
Tommy, Im really trying here.
Youre trying?
Now?
Where were you when it mattered?
I needed this guy back when I was a kid.
I dont need you now.
Its too late now.
Everythings already happened.
You and Brendan dont seem to understand that.
Let me explain something to you, okay?
the only thing I have in common
with Brendan Conlon is that;
the pair of us,
we have absolutely no use for you.
Look at you.
Yeah, I was right.
I think I liked you better when you were a drunk.
At least you had some balls then.
Not like now.
Tip toeing around like some---
beggar with your cup out.
Take it somewhere else, old man.
In fact, you know what?
Heres a cup. Why dont you take this
and go buy some more of your shitty tapes?
Go back to the room and
you listen to some more fish stories..
no one gives a shit about.
Get outta here.
Get the fuck outta here!
Ishmael! God pity em!
Stop the ship!
Please stop the ship!
Ahab! You Godless sonofabitch!
You stop the ship,
you Godless sonofabitch!
Captain.
Oh captain. Stop the ship.
Were lost.
Were all lost, Tommy.
Well never make it back.
I always loved you.
You know that, dont you Tommy?
You and your brother.
My two  boys.
Tommy Riordan,
coming down the tunnel without his trainer.
Once again, no walk out music.
I wouldnt say no walk out music, Sam.
Bryan, It sounds like VJ Day in Times Square,.
Ive never seen anything like it!
Tommy acknowledging his comrades for the first time,
and climbing into the cage.
Mad Dog Grimes has been looking for revenge
ever since the day Tommy Riordan walked into his gym in Pittsburgh
and turned his life upside down.
Its been a very long, very miserable
few months for Mad Dog to say the least.
Mocking Tommy with a camouflage motif for his mohawk tonight
and the Marines are really letting Mad Dog have it.
Alright gentlemen,
youve been given your instructions.
I expect a clean fight. Obey my commands at all times.
Defend yourselves at all times.
Touch gloves, go back,
lets do this.
- Its not gonna happen again.
He predicted an early knockout.
Said he was gonna knock Tommy out with one punch.
Lets see what Tommy
has to say about that.
Gentlemen, you ready?
You ready?
Lets go to war!
And they are off!
Tommy tackles him and hes on top!
Hes raining blows!
Stop it! Stop the fight!
Thats the fastest knockout
I think Ive ever seen.
Mad Dog Grimes has been poleaxed.
He is not moving.
You do that to someone on the street and theyd
lock you up and throw away the key!
Break out the yellow tape, Sam.
This guy's walking away from the cage
like hes leaving a crime scene.
Brendan Conlon came into this tournament
as a 1000 to 1 underdog,
and now here he is in the final four.
The crowds showing their appreciation.
He's getting quite the reception.
Hes getting a huge reception.
I mean,
this guy shocked everybody!
Youve got a visitor.
Second row, 10 oclock.
You alright with that?
And here comes the great Russian Koba.
Koba is so intimidating.
His reputation is larger than life.
I want you to look right at him
when he comes in here.
Dont take your eyes off him.
Im proud of you brother.
This is your cage.
Alright, gentlemen, youve been given
your instructions. I expect a clean fight.
Obey my commands at all times.
Defend yourselves at all times.
Touch gloves,
go back, lets do this.
Should I be nervous for Brendan?
Cause I am. I want to stop the
fight before it gets going.
Gentlemen, you ready?
You ready?
Lets go to war!
Now the question is,
how long can Brendan Conlon stay alive?
Koba just pounding on Brendan Conlon!
Hes pounding on him like a side of beef!
Kobas got him in the air. Oh no!
How much abuse can one man take?
Lets go to war!
Uh oh, Brendans going for ride!
That one shook the entire building!
Sit down.
Breathe.  Breathe.
Look at me!
Why are we here?
Why are we here, Brendan?
You don't knock him out,
you loose the fight.
Do you understand me?
You don't knock him out,
You don't have a home.
Conlon somehow answering the bell for round three,
but Kobas all over him again.
Brendans giving back, Bryan.
There are signs of life in Brendan Conlon.
Hes starting to mix it up!
Kobas got him caught in an iron vice,
squeezing for all its worth and trying to choke the teacher out.
He just launched Koba!
Can you believe this?
Conlon just shook off a guillotine!
This is a fight!
Weve got ourselves a fight!
Conlon going for a knee bar!
Hes got it very deep!
Crank it! Crank it!
Brendan Conlon wrenching
that knee for all its worth!
Hes putting everything he has in it,
and Koba  is screaming in pain!
Brendan Conlon has tapped Koba!
I cant believe it!
Brendan Conlon has tapped the great Koba!
Thats gotta be the biggest upset in MMA history!
Brendan Conlon, the Physics teacher!
Brendan Conlon, the civilian!
Hes done the impossible!
Hes pulled off a miracle!
This  place is going crazy cause weve just seen a miracle!
This is CNN breaking news...
A surprising turn in the story of
Iraq War hero Tommy Riordan.
CNN has learned that Riordans true
identity is that of Marine Staff Sergeant Thomas Conlon,
who went AWOL from his unit earlier this
year following the friendly fire death of his brother-in-arms,
Sergeant Manny Fernandez.
Fernandez wife, Pilar Fernandez,
spoke with me in an exclusive interview moments ago.
Bombs started dropping.
They were coming from U.S. planes.
Tommy and Manny were waving their flags
to let them know they were Americans,
but they didnt stop.
Everyone died.
Everyone except Tommy.
You know, my Manny used to say,
Tommy was the brother he never had.
Conlon, who is fighting in the Mixed Martial Arts
mega tournament Sparta,
is expected to be taken into custody by military police
following tonights winner take all finale in Atlantic City.
If victorious,
he has pledged his five million dollar purse to the
widow of his fallen comrade.
Weve just got some incredible news
that Im having trouble putting into context,
but here it is:
the two men fighting for the championship tonight,
for the five million dollar prize,
for the middle weight championship of the world,
are brothers.
What are you gonna do?
Im gonna fight him.
I popped his shoulder.
Relax, breathe.
I heard it tear.
You popped his shoulder? Good.
I want you to pop his other shoulder.
Josh!
Hey! Hey! No Josh!
Look at me!
You got two rounds left!
You need both rounds!
Go in there, kick him in the head,
take him down, and finish  him!
Tommy! What are you doing?
Shut up! Cmon.
What are you that crazy?
Lets go to war!
Its over!
What are you doing?
Its over, Tommy.
Finish him! You finish him!
Break! Break!
Subtitle by d3xt3r
www.addic7ed.com