MALE POLICE OFFICER: Steady.
WOMAN: Pico Boulevard.
At Rene's Building Shop
in the building next to the location.
- (DOGS BARKING)
- Suspects are seen climbing out...
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
BOB SCHIEFFER: (ON TV)
Violent street gangs from Los Angeles
are now trafficking in drugs
in cities far from their own turf.
MAN 2: ...Crips, the bloods.
MAN 3: ...Has enabled the gangs
to become richer,
better armed and better organized.
RONALD REAGAN:
Drugs are menacing our society.
DAN RATHER: ...the war on drugs is focused
on crack, the super-addictive...
MAN 2: ...the Los Angeles police
department's crash program.
REAGAN: They will have
no dark alleyways to hide in.
OLIVER NORTH: (ON TV)
I, Lieutenant Colonel North,
I don't recall that conversation.
DR. DRE: You are now about to witness
the strength of street knowledge
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
TONE: I'm about to give
you this right here.
KEISHA: Yeah?
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
TONE: Who is it?
EAZY E: You know who it is.
Open the fucking door.
Open the door.
- Hurry up, man. Open the fucking door.
- (LOCKS CLICKING)
TONE: What's up, cuz?
EAZY E: What's up, homie?
A'ight.
E.
EAZY E: So, wassup with you
and this code knock
and asking me to say
my name at the door?
We don't trust you motherfuckers.
EAZY E: What y'all tryin' to do?
ROCK: Oh, you ain't heard?
Best runner got cracked.
Sent his young ass up to YA.
EAZY E: That's sad.
Fuck that gotta do with me?
TONE: Hey, Tasha!
TASHA: I'm right here.
Hey, get this dude a 40.
(SOFTLY) God.
Hurry up!
EAZY E: Nigga, I look thirsty?
I look thirsty to you?
Here.
Bitch, I just said I wasn't thirsty!
Hold up.
Why you gotta be so ruthless, Eric?
I'm straight.
What, y'all don't want something to drink?
(CHUCKLES) You want some pussy?
Not from these little strawberry
bitches you got up in here.
I want my fucking money.
Where the money at?
Fuck you being so disrespectful
in my house for, cuz?
Nigga, this a dope house
that you already disrespecting.
Yeah, we good.
(GUN COCKING)
ROCK: So bottom line is we short...
So you gonna have to let us hold onto that.
Oh, yeah?
Well, my people sitting right across the
street from your mama house right now.
Cause if I don't show up,
they gonna show out.
Greenleaf, right?
That's the street she stay on?
You really wanna take it there?
You already took it there.
(WHISTLING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Shit, it's one time.
They got a battering ram.
TONE: Get to the back, Rock!
Hey, man, get to the back!
They better not find a motherfucking thing!
Get all that shit up in the roof.
- Hurry up!
- (GRUNTING)
Man, get to the back!
(PANTING)
- You know what to do with it.
- Yeah.
ROCK: Keisha!
- ROCK: What's taking you so long?
- Shit.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
TONE: Hurry up!
Step up, girl!
(SIREN BLARING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(MUTTERS) Tasha!
(SCREAMING)
- (BARKING)
- POLICE OFFICER: Go, go, go!
(GRUNTING)
- (BARKING)
- EAZY E: Oh, shit.
(GRUNTS) Fuckin' dog.
(PANTING)
(FUNK MUSIC PLAYING)
My life, my life, my life
In the sunshine
Everybody loves the sunshine
Sunshine
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
What happened?
Whatcha mean? What happened with what?
Andre, boy, don't play with me.
Do you even care how it makes me look?
Called in favors to get
your thoughtless ass
- an interview and you can't even show up?
- (GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Look, I'm sorry, Ma. I just...
I got so caught up in this DJ stuff,
I forgot.
You have a child, Andre.
Spinnin' records ain't paying
none of the bills around here.
Whatchu talkin' about? I get paid.
$50. So that makes you rich?
It's a start. Damn!
Why you riding me so hard?
I'm not riding you, baby.
I'm trying to make you understand.
And you know how I run my house.
Now you gonna have to go to school
or you gonna have to go to work.
Now I don't even care if you are a janitor.
I don't care what the hell you do...
Long as I own the company. I know, I know.
VERNA: But you don't own the company.
- Lonzo does.
- Okay.
You think we're done here?
- Yeah, I mean, you keep...
- You got something to say to me?
You don't care what I'm fightin' for, okay?
I already know what
I want to do with my life
and it definitely ain't
sitting in some cubicle,
taking orders on a bullshit-ass job.
Shut up!
People used to tell me
I was too young when I had you.
Said I wouldn't be shit.
Said you wouldn't be shit.
Now, I worked my ass off to get us here,
and I refuse to let you throw it all away.
(DOOR SLAMS)
TYREE: Hey, I grabbed some of your stuff.
Good lookin' out, T.
(EXHALES)
When you comin' back?
Man, I don't even know.
Got a lotta things to figure out.
Can I come with you?
Really?
You've been crying this whole time
about us sharing a room.
- And now you wanna come with me.
- (LAUGHS)
Man, get out of here.
TYREE: You know Mom. She just...
She just want the best for you.
Hey, I know that, T.
But check this out,
I want the best for me too.
Ar'ight?
That mean I gotta go.
Look, when I get set up right,
I'mma bring you with me.
Don't even worry about it.
I'mma have you in Miami.
- (CHUCKLES)
- For real?
- You gotta get me in Miami.
- Yeah, man.
Don't play, man. Get me somewhere.
Hey, I'll call you later.
For now, stay your little
ass outta trouble.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, nah. For real.
- Ar'ight, bruh.
- Ar'ight.
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
What you been up to, Cube?
ICE CUBE: Shit, writin' rhymes.
You a poet now?
The flyest one you know, nigga.
(CHUCKLES) This nigga. Okay. I'll see you.
- Hi, Mr. Davis.
- Hi.
MALE STUDENT: I wish
somebody would try me though.
MAN: That's all I'm saying. You feel me?
- Hey!
- Shit, nigga! Come here!
Hey, what up, cuz?
What up, cuz? (LAUGHING)
Whatcha doin', nigga?
Hey, cuz!
What up?
Wassup?
What's good, nigga?
All good? Hey, what up, cuz?
Crip!
Get outta here, man. You old mark-ass.
You see that shit?
Shut it down!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Open up the goddamn door, man.
MALE BUS DRIVER: What's going on?
Shut the fuck up, blood.
Y'all niggas ready to die today?
Don't get quiet now.
All that shit
y'all was throwin' up out the window?
What's up with it, huh?
You didn't think we saw that, huh?
Let me see how you do that shit again.
Let me see.
I was just playin', man, I swear.
I was only playin', man.
You think niggas out here are playin'? Huh?
Niggas die every day.
I kill Crips for breakfast.
Don't you ever put your motherfucking hands
up on no school bus, nigga.
You understand me?
- Yeah.
- Huh?
(STUTTERS) Yeah.
Y'all motherfuckers need
to gang bang them books
instead of tryin' to be
somethin' y'all ain't.
Shit, you never know.
'Cause I might be the one
to kill your motherfucking ass.
Remember me.
O.G. Two Tone, Crenshaw Mafia, blood.
ICE CUBE: Yo, Dre and Jinx in there?
Yup, they in there.
(CHUCKLES)
- Hey, Auntie.
- Hi, baby.
- How you doin'?
- Just fine.
- Lavetta, where Dre and Jinx at?
- They're in the back.
Excuse me.
LAVETTA: Come on. Chill out.
- ICE CUBE: Hey, little mama.
- Take your nap.
Why didn't you say hi?
(BEAT PLAYING)
(TURNTABLES SCRATCHING)
- Wuddup, Cube?
- Wuddup?
Ooh.
Whoo!
JINX: Do that shit!
ICE CUBE: Damn, Dre!
Whoo!
JINX: Damn.
Yeah!
JINX: That's right.
Whoo!
- Whoo! Fuck that shit up, Dre!
- (CHUCKLES)
- Yo.
- That shit was dope, homie!
- What's up, Cube?
- Man!
I had some crazy shit
happen on the bus today.
I had a Crenshaw Mafia O.G. get on the bus,
pulled a gun out on us,
gave a fucking motivational speech
and then bumped out.
The shit was crazy.
(CHUCKLES)
You wanna avoid some more crazy shit,
you better not get up
on that stage and fuck up.
Ain't nobody gonna fuck up, man.
- You must be stayin' a while.
- JINX: Yup.
Mama kicked him out 'cause of that mouth.
(CHUCKLES)
DR. DRE: Shut your ass up.
She didn't kick me out. I left.
Whatever.
ICE CUBE: That's what
they all say, homie. Right?
You got them rhymes?
ICE CUBE: Man, I stay with the rhymes.
DR. DRE: Man, I'm talkin'
about that hard shit.
- All I write is that hard shit, Dre.
- Okay.
So wassup, man? You ready for Doo-to's?
Shit, is Doo-to's ready for me?
You know that's Compton, right?
They got body bags at the door.
Okay. (CHUCKLES)
Your ass better bring it,
'cause if you don't,
you might end up in one for real.
Body bag?
Man, I don't know about that shit.
ICE CUBE: Ain't nobody
fucking with you, Jinx.
Stupid, man.
Tell your moms to fix this fucking AC.
Man, what are you doing here, homeless?
(ALL LAUGH)
MAN: Get off of me, nigga!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
- Fuck you! Get the fuck off me.
- Stay down.
MAN: We didn't do shit!
The fuck you holding me for?
Get the fuck off me!
COP: Where the fuck you going?
Hey, man, I'm just trying to get home, man.
I'm not even doin' nothin'.
COP: Put your fucking hands on top of
your head. Interlace your fingers.
- (POLICE SIREN BLARING)
- Spread your fucking legs.
You need to stay the fuck down.
Man, this hood is fuckin' hot!
Shut the fuck up!
What the hell is going on out here?
Look, these boys,
they all grew up on this block, okay?
- You need to get back in the house.
- That's my son.
- That's my... O'Shea! That's my son.
- You need to get back in the house.
- Lady, I'm telling you...
- Damn.
You get back inside, or I promise you,
I will ruin your fuckin' night!
Man, you ain't got to talk
to my mom's like that.
Shut the fuck up! Motherfuckin' nigger.
Oh, I'm a nigger now?
Wait a minute my ass, motherfucker.
Okay.
ICE CUBE: Officer, can you explain
why you jacking us right now?
Man, I ain't explaining shit to you.
Get the fuck up off the street.
I'm on my property.
I can stand right here. You got that?
Son! We right here.
Where you got the fuckin' rocks, homeboy?
Not everybody's slangin' dope, man.
COP: I don't give a fuck! This LAPD.
- I'm the only gangster out here.
- All right.
They all check out.
Check out? Check what, man?
Y'all are just over here fuckin' with us.
- Get up.
- (GRUNTS)
We got cards on all of 'em anyway.
Pick your shit up.
Stay out of trouble, man.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Get your ass up!
Let's go. Head home.
WOMAN: Stay back.
We ain't doin' shit, man!
COP: Get the fuck outta here.
MAN: We didn't even fucking do shit!
Start fuckin' walking.
Hey. Hey. Head home!
(MOCKINGLY) O'Shea.
MAN: Fuck the police, homie!
COP: Get the fuck out of here!
MAN: Yo, this is bullshit!
(FUNK PLAYING)
You really want to be here?
This club full of Pirus.
We straight.
Yeah, thanks for the tip, homie.
These niggas.
DJ YELLA: I just wanna say this.
You should be a model.
- (WOMAN LAUGHING)
- Yeah, you look like a model.
Just sayin', you know.
I look in your eyes and I see a Capricorn.
You're a Capricorn, right?
I mean, I can look at a girl
and I know their sign, you know?
It's just something I do.
Uh... Mmm-hmm.
DJ YELLA: I hope I'm not
disrespecting you, right?
- Uh-huh. Not at all.
- Good.
- Yella!
Lonzo coming, man.
- DR. DRE: Nah, nah. Weak at the Knees.
-Huh?
DR. DRE: Weak at the Knees.
- Hey.
- Wassup?
LONZO: I'mma go outside and make sure
nothing's poppin' off, all right?
I want you to keep these fat asses shakin'.
Don't play none of that
street-ass rap shit, ar'ight?
I want these motherfuckers
to think about pussy, not pistols.
- Yella!
- Huh?
I saw you talking to my lady, man.
Keep your motherfuckin' hands to yourself.
DJ YELLA: All right.
Man, why you always fuckin'
with Lonzo's girl, man?
Why not?
I can't be afraid
of a grown man in high heels, Dre.
DR. DRE: Cube, you up.
Hey, yo, Compton!
I got my little homie.
He 'bout to come
and bust a little rhyme for y'all.
I want y'all to give it up
for Ice-motherfuckin'-Cube!
(RAPPING) Here's a little
somethin' 'bout a nigga like me
Never shoulda been let out the penitentiary
Ice Cube would like to say
That I'm a crazy mutherfucka
from around the way
Since I was a youth I smoked weed out
Now I'm the mutherfucka that you read about
Takin' a life or two
That's what the hell I do
You don't like how I'm
livin' well, fuck you!
This is a gang and I'm in it
My man Dre'll fuck you up in a minute
With a right left
Right, left you're toothless
And then you say goddamn they ruthless
Everywhere we go they say damn!
Ice Cube's fuckin' up the program
And then you realize we don't care
We don't just say no
We too busy sayin' yeah!
About drinkin' straight
out the eight bottle
Do I look like a motherfuckin' role model?
To a kid lookin' up to me
Life ain't nothin' but bitches and money
'Cause I'm tha type of
nigga that's built to last
If you fuck with me
I'll put my foot in your ass
I don't give a fuck 'cause I keep bailin'
Yo, what the fuck are they yellin'?
(CROWD CHEERING)
- Fucking right! I told you. I told you.
- Yes, you did.
That's what I'm talking about, man.
Now, see, I'm this close
to firing your monkey ass.
What, you trying to start
a riot up in here?
I told you. Didn't I tell you I don't want
that hardcore shit played in my club?
As soon as I turn my back,
you do that shit anyway.
I'm just trying to help
your business out, Lonzo.
You saw they went crazy for that shit.
Don't worry about my business, ar'ight?
You just remember,
the only reason you up on that stage
is 'cause I put you up
on that motherfuckin' stage.
Now, you a badass DJ, I'll give you that,
but you don't like to listen, Dre.
And I get tired of arguing all the time.
'Cause you know,
there's a lot of cats that'll come in here
and they'll play exactly
what I want 'em to play.
Like that shit right there.
Cats that understand that you don't
bite the hand that feeds you.
Now you take a backseat
to that shit, nigga.
These fucking marching jackets and shit.
LONZO: Marching my ass. You march
your ass and do what the fuck I say.
- (SCOFFS)
- DJ YELLA: Hey, Dre.
Don't even trip on him, homie.
Nigga ain't got no fucking vision, man.
That's why I'mma fuck his bitch.
After he leave.
(CHUCKLES) Not with that shit on.
(CHUCKLES)
How you liking this little spot? Hey!
Dr. Dre.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Wassup, E?
It's been a minute, man.
I love your jacket, by the way.
- You baggin' on me.
- (LAUGHS)
You know I don't like wearing this shit.
That's Lonzo's shit, man.
You know it's part of the gig.
Yeah. You remember
the homie Ren from Kelly Park, right?
- Wassup?
- Wuddup, Dre?
- Wuddup?
- Wassup, man?
EAZY E: Look, I heard you been, um,
spending some time at your auntie's house.
How's the couch life?
It's fucked up.
- I'm too tall for that shit.
- (CHUCKLES)
Plus I got my woman and baby livin' there.
It's hard, man.
But you know,
everybody can't do what you do.
Yeah, Dre. Well, what I do
gettin' played out quick, man.
Motherfuckers just getting locked up
and laid down out here, you know?
- Mmm-hmm.
- I gotta make some changes.
Changes ain't bad.
I'm thinking about
making a few changes myself.
Whatcha mean?
Whatchu think about
dumping some money into this music shit?
Look, I got some ideas.
DJ YELLA: Let's give it up for Dr. Dre.
Fuck! I gotta get back up there.
- That's your calling, man.
- (CHUCKLES)
Tell Lonzo I said, "Fuck him." Ar'ight.
DR. DRE: Hey, E.
Think about it.
Ar'ight.
TYREE: Wassup? Do I know you?
MAN: What?
- Get 'em up.
- Hell no!
Hey, don't be fuckin'
with my little brother, nigga!
What the fuck did he do?
Nigga lookin' at me
like he know me or somethin'.
Man, I told you about this shit!
- COP: Clear the parking lot.
-I told you to go the fuck home.
The fuck wrong with you, man?
- (SIREN BLARING)
- You better chill the fuck out.
One time.
Hey! We told everybody
to clear this parking lot!
We just standing here.
COP: Get outta here!
What's going on?
COP: Hey! Head home.
I fell.
You fell? He fell?
That's what he said.
I didn't ask you what he said.
Get the fuck home!
I am home.
Head home. Go!
If you don't start walking...
Or what?
Turn around. Hands on your head.
Come here.
(GROANS)
You have the right to remain silent.
Stop resisting, boy.
You already know what it is.
- What up, sucker-punch?
- You already know what it is.
Sucker punched that dude, man.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, man, nah, nah, nah. That was Tyree.
You know he got that temper and shit.
Always getting me into
fucking trouble, man.
So what they lock you up for?
I was literally just standing there, man.
That's it.
(CHUCKLES)
As far as they was concerned.
That's the gangsterist
shit I heard all week.
(CHUCKLES) Man, it's stupid.
But I was thinking about what you
was saying last night, though, man.
Oh, yeah? And?
It's interesting.
How long?
Really, like, how long do you think that shit
you doing out there gonna last?
'Cause it ain't no happy endings
in that game, man.
You saying a lot for a nigga
who just got bailed outta jail.
I'm just saying, if you can slang dope...
- Nigga!
- What, man?
Just tell the whole fuckin'
world I sell dope.
Yo, yo. You can slang dope,
you can slang records, man. It's easy.
You got a mind for that shit, E.
So whatchu talking about doing?
Lil' homie from last night?
Nah, man. He in a group.
You know, they a trip, but...
But that shit, the reality raps,
that's what I'm talking about, man.
That's it.
My boy, D.O.C.,
he coming in from Dallas, dope.
My little homie, Ren, rap too.
Oh, yeah?
Hey, look, I got these cats,
H.B.O., Home Boys Only
from New York, dope voices, man.
Some whack-ass lyrics, though.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'm saying, Cube,
he wrote this shit for 'em, it's crazy.
Shit, we could probably
do something with that.
That's what I'm saying, man.
Start a label or something, man.
A label?
That's kinda fucking far-fetched, Dre.
Yeah, but check this out,
what would you call a
record label like that?
Ruthless.
Ruthless?
- Just like these fucking police, nigga.
- Ruthless.
Let's get the fuck from around here.
Trying to get me sent to jail.
Get your simple ass in the car.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
What the fuck is "gankin"?
And what's a "6-4"?
- Yeah.
-It's a car. A 6-4 Impala.
"Ganking" is when you jack somebody, man.
It's not a big deal.
The shit just sound better.
Yo, man, it's too much
cursing for radio play.
I mean, besides, who gives a fuck
about Compton anyway? Right?
Hold the fuck up. Hey. Hold up, man.
Hey, y'all got something
to say about Compton?
'Cause we might have a problem
up in this bitch.
Huh!
No? Then do the lyrics,
'cause I'm really losing my patience,
ar'ight?
Stop fucking embarrassing me, man.
Hey, man. I ain't with this shit.
Yeah, man. Fuck this shit.
- Fuck this Jheri curl rap bullshit, man.
- Where y'all going?
Fuck you! Wearing a Kangol
don't make you LL Cool J, nigga.
What the fuck you gonna do about it?
Whatcha gonna do, mark-ass nigga?
Hey.
MAN: Let's roll, B.
B-street-looking motherfucker.
MAN: Fucking Jheri curl ass.
Keep talkin' that bullshit
on your way out the door, nigga.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Well, there goes the talent, Dre.
Shut the fuck up, E.
- I'm saying...
- Come on, man.
How the fuck we suppose
to make a record label and hit records
and we ain't got no talent?
I mean, you said, hold up my side of the deal.
You said, put some money up.
So, it's time for you to deliver.
Why don't you do this shit, E?
DR. DRE: Nah, for real.
Get in there on the mic.
You ain't got shit to lose.
It's your money. You paying for it.
No, I can't. 'Cause I'm not a rapper.
There's your rapper.
ICE CUBE: I'm in a group already, man.
Jinx and them
would trip on me if I do anything.
EAZY E: Look, I understand
that you wanna keep throwing your life away
with Jinx and the backyard
boogie band or whatever...
But I'm the Berry Gordy of this shit.
So, whenever y'all figure out
what y'all wanna do,
just let me know.
Come on, man.
Look, the song is about you, E.
Eazy-motherfuckin'-E. I'm telling you.
DR. DRE: Come on, man.
You the only muthafucka with a 6-4.
- You got a 6-4?
- I don't have a car.
You got a 6-4?
I got a po' Porsche, man.
DR. DRE: Nigga, come on, man.
You ain't doing nothing.
DR. DRE: But you the business man,
so, you know.
It's on you.
We got a cool-ass song, though.
I think you could hit that shit.
I'm not sold, Dre.
Whatchu mean, you not sold?
You just gonna sit there?
You're kinda being a ho right now, Eric.
- Fuck y'all, niggas.
- (ALL CHUCKLE)
ICE CUBE: Berry Gordy to save the day.
EAZY E: I ain't scared.
- You ain't scared?
- What's up then?
What are you doing?
DR. DRE: E, let me produce. Man.
Feel like it's getting weird.
Man, shut up and get comfortable.
Let's go.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(SINGING)
Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4
TOGETHER: Shit.
The fuck?
(CHUCKLES)
What the fuck is so funny?
Nothing. Oh, E, can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you
and how much y'all fucking laughing.
Hey, E, you good.
Just hit that first beat hard, man.
You gotta come in on beat.
(RAPPING) Cruisin' down the street
You cruisin'.
- You good, Eric.
- All right?
No, no, no, no. You good, you good.
It's dope. But on beat.
Again. All right? Let's go.
You cruising. All right?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING)
Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4
- Shit.
- That ain't it.
- It really ain't.
-Hey, hey, Dre.
He gotta go if we're gonna do this.
Cube, you gotta go.
Get the fuck outta here, Yella.
- He not talkin' to me.
-Nah, nigga, both of y'all.
You talking to me?
- Bye.
-Go, Cube.
- And Yella, get the fuck outta here, man.
- Me too?
Yeah, so we can get this shit done.
Write the song, Cube.
Shut the fuck up, Cube.
- Take these with you, Cube.
-What'd I do?
- For real?
- Yes, man. Come on.
You know what? Whatever. Whatever.
You motherfucker.
- Come on, E.
-You finished, Dre?
You wanna laugh too?
I stay in this bitch by myself.
Hey, just say the words, ar'ight?
What does that even mean?
Man, just say the shit with me.
Ar'ight? Cruisin'.
Cruisin'.
Yeah, "Cruisin'". Let's go.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAPPING) Dre, you know this shit
ain't gonna never work
A'ight. You trying to be funny.
But, you see how you said that shit, right?
Like you believe it.
Yeah, I believe that shit.
Then say this shit like
you believe it, man.
Like it's a motherfuckin' Sunday
and you cruisin' down Crenshaw
in a motherfuckin' 6-4.
Come on. Say that shit like you believe it,
man, like it's your words.
Feel that shit.
Stop playing around. Loosen the fuck up.
There you go.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(RAPPING)
Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4
Oh, shit. Hey, that was dope, E.
That shit was dope, man. Yeah.
That's what I'm talking about, man.
You feelin' that shit, right?
Now we only got 59 more lines
to punch in, but it's all good.
We gonna get through it.
Let's go on to the next one.
(RAP SONG PLAYING)
(RAPPING) My man didn't budge
Bailiff came over to turn him in
Kilo G looked up and gave a grin
He yelled out "fire!" then came Suzy
The bitch came in with a submachine Uzi
Police shot the girl but didn't hurt her
Both upstate for attempted murder
'Cause the boyz n tha hood are always hard
You come talking that trash
we'll pull your card
Knowing nothing in life but to be legit
Don't quote me,
boy 'cause I ain't said shit
DJ YELLA: Yes.
All right, Eazy.
Hell yes, Dre!
- Yeah?
- Yes.
Hey, D.O.C.
Whatchu think, man?
You think they gonna feel
that shit in Dallas?
Man, to be honest, man,
that shit is super dope, nigga.
- Hell yeah!
- For real, nigga.
Hey, Lonzo. Whatchu think?
Sound like some waste-of-time shit to me.
Look, trust me, this shit
ain't gonna work, ar'ight?
You ain't gonna get no radio play
with that shit right there.
- Oh, for real?
- LONZO: Oh, for very real.
Y'all need to wrap this shit up too
'cause I need you to get back
on that slow jam that we talked about.
This whole reality of rap
shit y'all tryin' to do.
Talkin' about low-riders and jail,
nobody wanna hear that shit.
Now you need to get back in there
and work on that slow jam that we worked on.
And I'm serious
about all you motherfuckers taking up
my time and that's coming outta your pay.
No disrespect, Eazy,
'cause I know you real.
But you, motherfucker,
I ain't gonna take that shit from you.
20 years from now,
you gonna fucking thank me. Watch.
DR. DRE: Nigga, 20 years
from now, you still gonna be
recording love songs
in this dusty-ass garage.
(ALL LAUGH)
Fuck outta here.
Wrap this shit up.
DR. DRE: Yeah. Okay. You got it.
No, you got it!
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Yes!
- I told you. Didn't I tell you?
You told me, man. I should've believed you.
What the fuck did you all get from that
that you're high-fiving and shit?
DJ YELLA: Cube. Man, if Lonzo think
it ain't gonna be shit,
we know we got a motherfucking hit!
- Exactly.
- For real.
'Cause he don't know shit about music.
DJ YELLA: He don't know good music
when he hears it.
Play that shit again!
EAZY E: Dre...
You a fucking genius. You a fucking genius.
(RAPPING) Went to the park to get the scoop
Knuckleheads out there
cold shooting some hoops
EAZY E: A car pulls up
Who can it be?
A fresh El Camino rollin', Kilo G
He rolled down his window
And he started to say
ALL: It's all about makin' that GTA
'Cause the boyz n tha hood are always hard
You come talking that trash
we'll pull your card
Knowing nothing in life but to be legit
Don't quote me,
boy 'cause I ain't said shit
(CHEERING)
Thank you.
GREG MACK: These phones are burning up.
This is 1580 KDAY.
This is Greg Mack with the Mack Attack,
and I gotta give it up to my boy, Dr. Dre,
who is coming
with Compton's very own Eazy-E.
And you're listening to Boyz-N-The Hood
the number-one requested song
for six weeks and counting.
Ar'ight. Guess I'll see you soon.
JERRY: Excuse me.
- Yeah?
- I heard your record.
I'm Jerry Heller.
Eric Wright.
Real pleasure to meet you, man.
Same here.
Uh, would it...
Here, let me get those for you.
Let me get those for you.
Would it be possible
to have a word with you for a second, Eric?
About what?
About music.
After you.
All right. Come on.
So, I thought your album was good, man.
Just good?
Mmm.
Hey, hey, hey, hey! No.
I thought it was exceptional.
- Exceptional?
- Yes.
Fantastic.
Please, just sit down, all right?
We'll start this again. Come on.
All right. I'm gonna try this again. Okay?
All right.
As a music manager,
let me tell you what I can do for you, Eric.
I will make you legit.
It seems as if I could
do something for you.
(CHUCKLES)
I see. You think because
I don't have some flashy office
I don't know what I'm talking about?
I worked with Elton John.
I worked with Otis Redding.
Let me see.
I worked with War. I worked with Styx.
- I worked with, uh...
- Have you worked with anybody this decade?
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
Let me tell you what I see here, Eric.
A lot of raw talent, a lot of braggadocio.
Bravado. Uh...
But if you think anyone's
gonna talk to you,
you think anyone
is gonna let you in the building
where somebody might listen to you or talk
to you, you think that's gonna happen?
You're crazy, man. I'm sorry.
That is what I can do for you.
I can make you legit.
I can get you in that building.
And I will protect you.
I will block out all the noise
of this crazy fuckin' business
and we can build something big.
But you gotta believe in me
the way that I believe in you.
The way that I believe in this,
because you have a unique talent, Eric.
Very special.
Don't fuck around.
But, you know what?
If you can't handle it,
if it's too much fuckin' pressure
for you, then fine.
Get outta here.
Wait. I'm listening.
You got more music for me?
- Absolutely.
- Good.
'Cause you are gonna
have to follow this up, quick. All right?
Now, what does N.W.A stand for, huh?
No Whites Allowed? Something like that?
Nah.
Niggas With Attitudes.
(LAUGHS)
You're fucking kidding me.
All right. We can work with that.
- Good. I like that. I like that a lot.
- You better.
(LAUGHS)
Fantastic.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
What up, what up? What's up, fam?
(CHEERING)
- Hey.
- What's up, baby?
Dre.
Hey, fellas, y'all got any idea
why I asked y'all to
wear all black tonight?
'Cause we a all-star group.
And to be a all-star group
we gotta look like it,
sound like it, dress like it.
You mind tellin' me
what the fuck happened in your situation?
Man, kiss my ass.
This the only clean shit I had left.
EAZY E: That's saying a lot
about how you live.
Are we getting paid to wear all black?
Look, I ain't lookin' out for your ass
no more, man. Put this on.
Oh, shit, there go Mr. Drummond.
Nah, nah. That's Mr. Furley
- from Three's Company.
- (ALL CHUCKLES)
Hey, that's good, Ren.
(CHUCKLES)
Y'all finished?
This man been out there
shopping our stuff around
trying to get money for Ruthless.
He tryin' to get us distribution.
He tryin' to get us on tour.
He could probably bring some real money
- to the table...
- Okay.
- So let's take this shit serious.
And then what, E?
All he do is take 20 off the top.
We cut 80, but that's how managers work.
Fellas, all right. I'm sorry I'm late.
How's everybody doing?
I'm gonna be honest with you.
We've had a lot of passes.
Uh, people are scared of you guys.
Big time.
They think that you're dangerous.
Uh, I happen to think
that that's a good thing.
These fucking guys,
they need some more convincing.
They're so fucking timid.
So I invited them here to the show.
So you've got to kick ass tonight.
- Can you do that?
- Hell yeah.
They're gonna be here.
Scare the shit out of them.
(LAUGHTER)
Blow the fucking roof off, all right?
Have a good show.
Hey, can this motherfucker
Jerry Heller bring in more pussy?
'Cause that shit's worth 20 percent.
(ALL CHUCKLES)
Hey, man. But, for real though.
They want N.W.A, let's give 'em N.W.A.
ALL: Hell yeah!
- Ar'ight?
- ALL: Ar'ight.
Let's go get this money!
(ALL CHUCKLES)
- (MUSIC BEGINS)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
MC REN: Now everybody say, "Yeah!"
CROWD: Yeah!
MC REN: Hell yeah!
CROWD: Hell yeah!
- MC REN: Louder! Scream!
- (CROWD SCREAMING)
(RAPPING)
It was once said by a man who couldn't quit
Dope man, please can I have another hit
The dopeman said,
"Cluck, I don't give a shit"
If your girl kneel down and suck my dick
It all happened and the
guy tried to choke her
Nigga didn't care
she ain't nothin' but a smoker
That's the way it goes
that's the name of the game
Young brothers gettin'
over by slangin' caine
Gold around his neck in 14K heaven
Bitches clockin' on the dick 24/7
Plus he's makin' money
keep the bassheads waitin'
Rollin' six-fos with the fresh-ass Daytons
Livin' in Compton California, C-A
His Uzi up your ass if he don't get paid
Niggas beggin' for credit
he's knockin' out teeth
Clockin' much dollars
on the first and fifteenth
Big wad of money nuttin' less than a 20
Yeah, you want a five-oh
the dopeman's got plenty
To be a dopeman boy, you must qualify
Don't get high off your own supply
From a ki to a G it's all about money
Ten piece for a champ base pipe comes free
If people out there are not hip to the fact
If you see somebody gettin'
money for crack he's the
Dopeman! Dopeman!
Sing that shit
Louder
Dopeman! Dopeman!
Just can't quit
Dopeman! Dopeman
Hey, suck this, bitch
Well, I'm the dopeman
Yeah, boy, I wear corduroy
Money up to here, but unemployed
You keep smoking that rock and
my pocket's getting bigger
Yo, got that five-o
Double up, nigga
Yeah, high rolling, big money I'm folding
Bitch on my tip for the dick I'm holdin'
Strung strawberry jocking me so early
Ho, you want a hit,
you gotta get your knees dirty
Well, that's my life
That's how it's cut
- Hey, dopeman
- Bitch, shut the fuck up
Gotta make a run
It's a big money deal
Gankers got the fake,
but you can get the real from the
- Dopeman! Dopeman!
- Yeah, that's me
- Can I get a "g"?
- Dopeman! Dopeman!
- I just can't quit
What do you think?
Jerry, you're my friend,
but Compton? I don't think so.
Queens, maybe.
Listen, if you find
the next Bon Jovi, call me, okay?
- Good luck.
- Thanks for coming.
- Sure thing.
- Yeah.
Somebody say "Do that shit
Do that shit, do it"
Do that shit, do that shit, do it
Say, "Do that shit, do that shit, do it"
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
All right.
You wrecked
these motherfuckers tonight, boy.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
The stage was shaking so much I thought
my needle's about to jump off the record!
Yo, I was trippin' off them knowing the words,
though. That shit was crazy.
Hey, y'all, I'm telling you,
Compton is definitely on the map, yo.
- Damn right.
- That's for damn sure.
Man, I figured you were gonna represent
tonight. Good shit, my nigga.
Wuddup? Whatchu been up to?
You still out there in Vegas?
- This is Suge.
- What's up?
Man, I just been back and forth, man.
Doing some security bodyguard work.
If y'all need my services, let me know.
Security?
I don't think we gonna need
no bodyguards, man.
We might got that covered.
(LAUGHING)
But you never know
what you need until you need it.
Look, I just came here to give y'all props.
I got people waiting on me.
JERRY: Excuse me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, okay. That was
- one hell of a show.
- (CHEERING)
Nice job.
Very, very nice, gentlemen. Outstanding!
You kicked ass, yeah.
You definitely did. You definitely did.
Okay, this is Eazy-E and N.W.A, obviously.
Guys, this is Bryan Turner.
- How you doin', fellas?
- Ice Cube.
- Pleasure.
- Bryan runs Priority Records.
And he wants to sign you.
BRYAN: Yeah, immediately.
Fellas, I got to say, I loved the show.
All right?
What you did with that crowd out there,
I mean, I've never seen anything like that.
So, I think, honestly,
if y'all wanted to, you guys
- would fit perfectly with our label.
- Yes.
That'll work.
Nah, nah, nah, nah. No, it won't. Nah.
Well, hold on, man.
I mean, Priority Records.
I've never heard of it.
I mean, what you got?
Like, is it Def Jam?
Like, the Beastie Boys? You know?
Run DMC? You know what I'm saying?
Or is it more R&B?
You know, Prince, Michael Jackson.
- It's, uh, a little more...
- More that end of the spectrum.
- More R&B as of right now, but...
- Yeah.
Yeah, we represent nothing big,
but mostly R&B.
DR. DRE: Who dat?
It's, uh, California Raisins.
Who?
BRYAN: It's the California Raisins.
The raisins from the commercial singing
"I Heard it Through the
Grapevine" and shit?
Yes, Cube, the little-ass raisins.
- BRYAN: That would be the one.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
JERRY: Hear it out.
Don't get ahead of yourselves, okay?
I was laughing, too,
I promise, then I started cashing checks.
So, look, I gotta tell ya,
those little fuckers, they went gold last year.
- Gold?
- Almost platinum. Yeah.
What do you say, fellas?
You wanna go make a record?
I mean...
- Yeah!
- ALL: Yeah...
(CLAMORING)
- Thank you. Appreciate it.
- Good?
He seriously dug it. He really dug it.
- We did it, Jerry.
- He did.
- Thank you, man.
- You did it.
(CLAPPING)
A'ight, so, look, your rhymes ain't tight,
it ain't makin' the record.
This ain't Lonzo's shit,
this the real deal. Ar'ight?
So your shit better be dope. Who up?
Ren up.
- Get 'em, Ren.
- Get that shit, Ren.
- I got this. Ready?
- Lorenzo.
All right. Let's see.
Hey, Yella. Play that shit.
(RAPPING)
Ruthless, plenty of that and much more
So at the party,
Ren is controllin' the floor
That you step and do your dance routine
It ain't a dream, my man
You're in a gangsta scene
I go to the party
I hip, I hop the spot
I dunno what it is but the girls get hot
Perspirin' like they're on fire and
Their so-called boyfriends
with 'em are retirin'
And for this reason I'm a walkin' threat
So when I'm on stage I want, shh...
Quiet on tha set
Express yourself
(RAPPING)
I'm expressin' with my full capabilities
And now I'm livin' in
correctional facilities
'Cause some don't agree with how I do this
I get straight meditate like a Buddhist
Express yourself
N.W.A take two
Yeah!
Hell yeah, Dre.
Yeah, man!
- You feel that shit, right? Hey, check this out.
- (BASS LINE PLAYING)
Fuck it up.
Yeah.
That's what I'm talking about, man.
But you hear the difference, right?
Yeah, way better than the shit
I came up with.
- I know.
- Fuck you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I thought you'd like to know
our deal with Priority Records is done.
- Yes! That's whassup, man!
- Money!
Contracts right here for you to sign.
- Thank you, my good man.
- Music keep sounding like this,
this album is gonna be incredible.
Well, you're welcome, Jerry.
Very strong lyrics too, Cube. Very strong.
- Appreciate that, Jerry.
- Mmm-hmm.
So what's up with our contracts, though?
They're getting done right now.
Lawyers are drawing 'em up.
Jerry on top of that,
but did you just switch all the straws?
Yo, Dre. There's something outside
you need to take care of.
Right now. Trust me.
- Serious.
- (MUSIC CONTINUES)
Uh-oh. Really?
- We can split that.
- Cube. Right there, hush.
- Not this time.
- You know what I got for you.
So let me get this straight.
You gonna do this right here, right now?
What am I supposed to do?
We're sleeping in a twin bed
at your auntie's house.
We have a baby, Andre.
You expect me to wait
for what you doin' in there?
And you in the streets fuckin' around?
- Are you crazy?
- What?
I'm out here bustin' my fuckin' ass
day and fuckin' night
tryin' to create something.
You gonna come up in here talkin' about
some fuckin' bitches? Are you crazy?
- You don't get it.
- No, you don't get it, Lavetta.
Daddy!
It's all right, baby.
Chill out, man.
Tyra, it's gonna be okay. All right.
- All right, baby?
- Bye, Dre.
Daddy love you.
(TYRA CRYING)
(GROANS)
- You cool?
- Fuck no, man. I'm far from cool.
- What happened, Dre? What she say?
- What'd you do?
- (SIREN BLARING)
- Shit! Here we go again.
Shit. One time, one time.
We cool. We ain't even doin' shit.
We not doin' shit.
You guys lost?
Nah.
You niggas supposed to be somewhere?
Yeah! Here. We working.
Oh, you working?
Yeah, I bet.
- What we do?
- We'll find out in a minute what you did.
- What's this?
- Shut the fuck up.
- The fuck?
- Get your ass on the ground now.
Get on the ground!
On the ground?
What am I supposed to do with this?
Get on the ground.
What we do?
Get down! Get on the ground, now!
Get your punk ass on the ground. Let's go.
Get the fuck down.
Hands behind your back.
Interlock your fingers.
- DR. DRE: This is fucked up.
- Interlock 'em!
The fuck you got us
on the ground like this for, officer?
For our protection.
There's seven of you and four of us.
So sit tight and let us do our job.
JERRY: Hey, officer, I'm sorry.
What is going on out here?
Sir, can you stay right there, please?
We're trying to check these bangers,
make sure they're clean.
All right, I'm sorry,
these are not bangers, okay?
These, um... These are artists.
- Excuse me. Artists?
- Yeah.
- Seriously?
- What kind of artists?
- Rappers.
And they're working with me
in the studio right now.
Well, see, rap is not an art.
And I'm sorry, who are you?
I'm the manager.
Well, you're wasting your time,
Mr. Manager.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- You're wasting your time.
- Really?
- These clients of yours, these rappers...
- Yeah.
- They look like gang members.
You can't come down here and arrest people
just because of what they look like.
What, are you crazy?
But, that's police harassment.
- You said you're a manager, right?
- Yeah.
- Not a fuckin' lawyer.
- JERRY: Does that matter?
You cannot come down here
and harass these guys
- because they're black! People have rights!
- Calm down.
Step back! Step back!
I'll step back, you let them up.
Get up, guys.
Come on. Eric!
- You don't tell them to get up.
- Get up.
- I'm stepping back.
- We will decide that.
You have no idea the people I know.
I'm gonna call the Mayor's office.
Step back.
Now get up.
Get up, now!
Okay. Come on, guys.
And you keep your people in line,
you understand?
And the fuck out of Torrance.
- JERRY: Good. Come on, guys.
- You got a problem?
DR. DRE: It's my jersey.
You ain't tough now, huh?
JERRY: Eric, come on. Let's go.
- You got a problem?
- Yella.
- I didn't hear you.
- JERRY: Let's go.
- Yous a fuckin' sellout.
- Shut up.
- Everything's fine. Okay?
- Yeah.
- You got something to say?
- JERRY: Cube.
You got something to say, boy?
Cube. Get inside. Let's get back to work.
You heard what your master said.
Get inside, boy.
You shut the fuck up!
Hey. Get the fuck back inside.
Get inside, Cube.
We're gonna go back and work. Okay?
Leave us alone. You know, leave us alone.
Fuckin' rap music.
Fuckin' disgraceful.
(BEATS PLAYING)
I got something for this beat.
Hey, yo, Yella, cut it.
What is it lookin' like, Dre? It's hard?
Yo.
- Hell yeah, Cube.
- Yeah.
This gonna start some shit,
but this what we need. Hell yeah!
(RAPPING) Fuck the police
comin' straight from the underground
A young nigga got it bad 'cause I'm brown
And not the other color so police think
ALL: (RAPPING)
They have the authority to kill a minority
ICE CUBE:
Fuck that shit, 'cause I ain't the one
For a punk motherfucker
with a badge and a gun
To be beaten on and thrown in jail
We can go toe to toe in
the middle of a cell
Fucking with me 'cause I'm a teenager
With a little bit of gold and a pager
Searching my car looking for the product
Thinking every nigga is selling narcotics
EAZY E: (RAPPING)
Give a little gust of wind and I'm jetting
but leave a memory no one'll be forgetting
So what about the bitch
who got shot? Fuck her!
You think I give a damn
about a bitch? I ain't a sucker!
EAZY E: This is the autobiography of the E
and if you ever fuck with me
You'll get taken by a stupid
dope brother who will smother
Word to the motherfucker
Straight outta Compton
MAN 1: Yo, Dre.
MAN 2: Hey, Dre.
(LAUGHING)
- EAZY E: They lovin' that shit.
- MAN: Hey, what's up, Cube?
GREG MACK: (OVER RADIO) 1580 KDAY.
This is Greg Mack of the Mack Attack.
I gotta tell you,
you are witnessing history.
LA's first super group, N.W.A,
with their new album Straight Outta Compton,
and they're taking the nation by storm.
BRYAN: Are you going
out there with them or not?
No. I had enough of that shit in the '70s.
But I'm gonna fly out there a bunch of times,
and I'm gonna check on them.
Can you just make sure
that everything goes smooth, please?
Of course.
I've got enough bad press
with Tipper Gore and the PMRC on my ass.
I know. It's a good contract.
- Getting ready to get outta here, guys.
- Excuse me. What's going on?
What do you have in that bag?
Oh, this right here?
Just a little of the shit
I was selling in Reno.
- Oh, fuck, put it down.
- Are you kidding me?
Are you fucking nuts?
Jesus, Eric. Are you out of your mind?
- What?
- You can't take that on the bus.
How am I supposed to protect myself
when I'm out there on the road
riding through Texas and fucking Tennessee
and shit where they lynch niggas?
- You got me?
- I got you, okay?
I'm not gonna let you take
an arsenal on tour, Eric.
Use your fucking head.
Jerry, look, just take care
of the business, a'ight?
And I'm gonna make sure
everything else good.
A'ight, look... Otis, get the bags.
Put them on the van.
You feel better? We're not even riding
with them no more, Jerry.
- Unbelievable. Jesus Christ.
- No, no, no, do not put those on the...
Bryan, it's fine. It's fine.
I got it under control.
I swear to you, okay?
DR. DRE: (RAPPING) Yeah, yeah
Can y'all hear that? Can y'all hear that?
CROWD: Yeah!
DR. DRE:
Well, clap your hands then! Come on!
CROWD: Eazy!
DR. DRE: (RAPPING) Everybody come on!
DR. DRE: Who'd y'all come to see?
CROWD: Eazy!
DR. DRE: A little louder, come on!
- CROWD: Eazy!
- DR. DRE: Get those hands in the air!
EAZY E: (RAPPING)
A miracle of modern creation
Eazy-E's on the set hyped up
With the bass and a little
bit of what ya love
From a brother who's smooth like a criminal
I mean subliminal
Otherwise known as a villain
Because I'm ruthless,
when I spot a sucka, I kill 'em
But most I think know not to deal with me
Yo, it's obvious,
tell 'em who you came to see
CROWD: Eazy!
MC REN: Easy!
DR. DRE: Everybody, come on.
CROWD: Eazy!
DR. DRE: A little louder
Say it!
CROWD: Eazy!
DR. DRE: Come on, say it, say it, say it
Gangster rap has become
incredibly popular and profitable
by selling lyrics about violence
to a young mainstream audience
that wouldn't dream
of going anywhere near a ghetto.
Not all music stars,
as you know, are model citizens.
Some have had run-ins with the law.
That's certainly nothing new,
but now a few musicians
have taken that to new heights.
Or to new depths.
(GRUNTING AND MOANING ON TV)
MAN: (ON TV) Baby, yeah.
(BOTH MOANING)
MAN: (ON TV) That is so good.
- Yella.
- Hmm?
You in there watching porn
with the door open?
Yeah.
Yo, that's what I said, man.
What the fuck?
No, it's not even like that.
Fuck y'all, man. I'm back here tryin' to write.
Fuck y'all, man.
- Oh, you tryin' to write.
- (OTHERS LAUGHING)
Good night, Lorenzo.
Fuck y'all sleep.
ICE CUBE: This shit is crazy.
DR. DRE: Yeah, man. This shit is dope.
DR. DRE: No, man. No. I gotta go.
All right?
TYREE: Yo, you gotta let me
come fuck with y'all in Miami.
Okay. So now you try and partake
into some of those fat asses?
Come on, bro, I'm tired of these same...
Man, I need something new.
DR. DRE: No, what you think Ma gonna think
about you comin' on tour, huh?
'Cause you know you got school,
and you know she ain't gonna
let you miss that many days, man!
- You did.
- DR. DRE: Come on, man. That's my point.
Hey. Hold on. Hold on.
- So, look, how Mom doing now?
- She good.
But, nah, you know her,
constantly working, man. Every day, man.
Make sure you take care of her, a'ight?
Hey, look, I'll tell you what,
you stay your little ass outta trouble.
I'll call you when I'm on the way to Miami,
see about getting you on a flight.
TYREE: I can come out there, though?
- DR. DRE: You can come out here, man.
-You promise?
DR. DRE: I got you. I got you, ar'ight?
Hey, bring the rubbers, T.
- Get off the phone.
- (LAUGHTER)
I still got the same ones
you gave me a long time ago.
- Hey, hey. Hold on, T. Somebody at the door.
- (KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Here.
Hello? Dre?
DR. DRE: Hold on!
Yeah, nigga, I'm lookin' for my girl,
Felicia.
I heard she was up in one of these rooms.
Ain't no Felicia in here, nigga.
Mind if I take a look?
DR. DRE: Get the fuck outta my room, man.
(BANGING)
This nigga just came
to my motherfuckin' door strapped, man.
Where are you going?
DR. DRE: I'll show that nigga strapped.
DR. DRE: Hey, where Felicia at?
- Where Felicia?
- Where's your homegirl.
MC REN: You Felicia?
DR. DRE: Hey, Felicia. You Felicia?
DR. DRE: Felicia? Her dude here.
DR. DRE: All right.
So none of y'all are named Felicia now. Okay.
Yella! Hey, Yella!
DJ YELLA: Your name Felicia?
- You forgot my name?
- No, wait!
- DJ YELLA: Valerie. Your name Valerie.
- Whatever.
Felicia! Girl, your nigga's out there.
She's suckin' dick, though.
He got guns, girl. Come on!
DR. DRE: The nigga is strapped.
I'll show this nigga right now.
Talkin' about gettin' strapped.
Hey, Ren.
Nigga outside talking about gettin' strapped.
Watch out, man.
DJ YELLA: Hey!
EAZY E: Show wassup now.
Talking about gettin' strapped.
EAZY E: Hey, Cube, you got me, man.
MC REN: Let's ride, nigga.
Time to go to work.
EAZY E: Hey. Y'all looking for Felicia?
She in there or what?
She kinda preoccupied
with some real nigga dick.
The fuck you say, little nigga?
I said, she got
a motherfuckin' dick in her mouth, nigga.
ICE CUBE: That ain't fun no more?
DR. DRE: The fuck y'all going?
DR. DRE: Nigga, she's trying to compensate.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Wow!
EAZY E: Fat niggas was bullshit!
DR. DRE: Punk-ass niggas, man.
ICE CUBE: Bitch-ass niggas.
Y'all wild.
EAZY E:
Nigga runnin' so fast, that shit was crazy.
D.O.C.: Don't let that shit bother you.
EAZY E: Tryin' to get me killed?
FELICIA: Whatever.
EAZY E: Nigga, ain't tryin'
to take no bullet for no bitch,
I guarantee you that.
- ICE CUBE: Bye, Felicia.
- (GASPS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAPPING)
Homies all standin' around just hangin '
Some dope-dealin', some gang-bangin'
We decide to roll and we deep
See a nigga on Dayton's, and we creep
Real slow, and before you know
I had my shotgun pointed in the window
He got scared and hit the gas
Right then I knew I had to smoke his ass
You're flying up
the Billboard 200 albums chart.
R&B and hip-hop charts too.
You have any idea
how many records we're selling?
Ruthless has arrived, Eric.
We're fucking huge.
That is dope, Jerry. That's dope.
(CHUCKLES)
The combined law enforcement
associations of Texas today
called for a halt to sales of the album.
I believe that the rap music
promotes violence against authority
and, consequently, violence
against law enforcement.
- DR. DRE: 15 on that.
- (CHEERING)
ICE CUBE: Man, fuck, man!
MC REN: Hey. Come on, man. Put that shit up.
JERRY: Excuse me. Gentlemen, I'm sorry.
I don't mean to be the bearer of bad news.
EAZY E: What you got?
Oh, shit.
DR. DRE: What's that?
Motherfuckin' FBI.
What the fuck?
I'm supposed to not care about this?
Wait, the FBI? They comin' after us, too?
JERRY: Kind of.
I mean, what the letter say, Jerry?
JERRY: Uh, basically, uh...
"A song recorded by the rap group N.W.A
"on their album Straight Out Of Compton
"encourages violence
against law enforcement.
"Advocating violence and assault is wrong,
"and we in the law enforcement community
take exception to such action."
MC REN: Fuck that.
DR. DRE: Fuck that.
Fuck the law enforcement community.
We got freedom of speech, man.
- What the fuck can they do to us?
- DR. DRE: Right.
You wanna provoke 'em and find out?
Because this is a warning, Cube.
And it's about Fuck Tha Police,
in particular, so...
I think maybe we should not
play that song right now.
Not play what? Fuck that, Jerry.
That's what the song is about.
JERRY: Relax, relax.
We're not giving in to anything.
No. No.
I just say we retire it for now, okay?
It is a reasonably worded threat.
This isn't street bullshit.
This isn't the Crips and Bloods and crap.
This is the federal government.
These guys can come after us
a million different ways.
I don't even want to think about it.
Why provoke them?
The fuck does that mean?
If it was the LAPD,
maybe I'd be a little worried,
but we can't let them censor us, Jerry.
- I'm not advocating for censorship, Cube.
- EAZY E: Wait. Wait.
Maybe none of us should be worried.
Maybe we should be happy.
- What you mean, E?
- ICE CUBE: Dunno about happy.
EAZY E: 'Cause you see,
this right here is a gift.
It's the FBI, E. Whatchu talking about?
EAZY E: This is free publicity for N.W.A.
We take this to the press and we show them
what type of intimidation,
discrimination, and harassment
that we dealing with from our government.
DR. DRE: I like that shit.
ICE CUBE: I'm with that.
- JERRY: That's a different thing.
- My nigga, I feel you.
- If that's what you wanna do, then we can...
- That's what I wanna do.
That's what we wanna do, Jerry. That's it.
That's what we wanna do.
Okay.
DR. DRE: Yeah?
EAZY E: You good?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY) I mean...
- Hate to be the bearer of bad news...
- JERRY: Mmm-hmm.
- But 20!
- 20, man!
Wait a minute, that ain't 20.
- Hey, hey, hey. Shhh.
- DR. DRE: What's up?
Let's not get thrown out
of another fuckin' hotel.
N.W.A: Goodnight, Jerry.
WOMAN PROTESTOR: Compton's crap!
MALE PROTESTOR 1: Go back to Compton!
ICE CUBE: Ain't that some shit.
Speak a little truth
and people lose their minds.
MALE PROTESTOR 2: This is not music!
Shit, the truth is,
they can do whatever they want with 'em.
They bought them motherfuckers.
(LAUGHTER)
(RAPPING) I don't drink brass monkey,
Like to be funky
Nickname Eazy-E yo eight ball junkie
Bass drum kicking to show my shit
Rapping holding my dick, boy, I don't quit
Crowd-rocking motherfucker
from around the way
I got a six-shooter, yo, mean hombre
Rolling through the hood to find the boys
To kick dust and cuss crank up some noise
Police on my balls
I had to pause
40 ounce in my lap,
and it's freezing my balls
For the sake of our children,
I implore each of you
to be unyielding and inflexible
in your opposition to drugs.
JERRY: 'Cause another one called me
and told me she's pregnant by you too.
You just got to slow down.
You can't fuck every broad on the planet.
EAZY E: So now, pussy a problem?
Listen, it's gonna be a problem
if you got 4,000 kids.
- Right?
- EAZY E: Yeah.
You make some money,
you got all these problems.
You're gonna have to take care of 'em.
It's fine.
I'll help you take care of 'em.
- Hey, Cube.
- Sorry to interrupt y'all lobster brunch.
But what's up, E? Where the contracts at,
man? You forgot about me?
Didn't I tell you to... You know what?
Jerry, you want to deal with this?
ICE CUBE: I'm not talking to Jerry,
I'm talking to you.
EAZY E: That's Jerry's job.
JERRY: It's my department.
You're absolutely right to ask, Cube.
The contracts are being
finalized as we speak.
The thing is,
with these attorneys, they'll take forever.
Pouring over it, they'll bleed us dry.
But, they're gonna get done.
I wish I got paid by the hour the way they do.
You know?
Me, too.
I just want to know what's goin' on
since I did write a lot of lyrics on this record.
Everybody knows
how important you are, Cube.
They do?
That's what's goin' on.
We just need some time, that's all.
Everything probably all right.
I must be trippin'.
Shit tastes pretty good.
Someday, right?
Y'all enjoy your meal.
JERRY: Okay.
(JERRY CHUCKLES)
I'm telling you, that guy wants
to be you very frickin' badly.
As if I ain't got enough fucking problems.
Excuse me. Can I get a refill?
At some point,
you just gotta trust somebody.
(CHAMPAGNE POURING)
You know?
You gotta trust somebody.
DR. DRE: Nah, I just think
you overreacting, man.
Eazy one of us, Cube.
What you thinkin' don't even make sense.
No, what don't make sense is
Eazy and Jerry eating steak and lobster
and we eating Fatburger.
Shit don't make no sense.
Look, I hear you,
but I think we need to ride this wave.
For real.
Don't be jumping to conclusions
until you know for sure.
- (PAGER BEEPING)
- You know?
It's my moms, man.
(SOBBING)
DJ YELLA: Yo, Dre,
what's going on?
Moms just called, man.
It's Tyree.
He's dead.
DJ YELLA: What? No.
DR. DRE: He got into a fight,
some motherfucker broke his neck.
It's my little brother, man.
It's my little baby bro.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
I never told y'all this.
But when I was 12, my sister got killed.
Her own husband killed her,
then killed himself.
This dope gang took my cousin too.
Shot him in the trunk of a car.
Fucking Compton, man.
DR. DRE: Come on, man, like...
It's my fault, man.
DJ YELLA: Don't talk like that.
This never would've happened
if I had him out here, man.
D.O.C.: Come on, Dre.
It's my fuckin' fault.
It could've happened in another way.
- You can't blame yourself for that, Dre.
- No.
Tyree gonna always be with you.
No matter what.
ICE CUBE: That's right.
D.O.C.: Yeah, for real, man.
And we always gonna be with you.
MC REN: Hell yeah.
We always gonna be brothers.
(SOBBING) Fuck.
EAZY E: We here, a'ight.
DJ YELLA: I'm sorry, man.
ICE CUBE: You good, Dre.
VERNA: This is not on you, Andre.
If I had just brought him on tour with me.
Like he wanted.
Stop this nonsense now. Stop it.
Your brother looked up to you,
and you took great care of him,
we both did.
It's time to let someone else
take care of him now.
I'm proud of you.
OFFICER: No person shall disturb the peace
by participating or abetting
in any rude, indecent, drunken,
riotous or violent conduct.
Or the use of any vulgar, obscene
or abusive language in a public place.
Note also, the performance of the song
"F the Police", will not be permitted.
Refusal to abide
by all the Detroit City Ordinances
will result in immediate
arrest and forfeiture.
Are we finished here? We got a show to do.
Just watch yourself.
ICE CUBE: Eat a dick.
It's "Fuck tha Police."
EAZY E: (RAPPING) Straight outta Compton
is a brother that'll smother your mother
and make your sister think I love her
Dangerous motherfucker raising hell
and if I ever get caught I make bail
So what about the bitch
who got shot? Fuck her!
You think I give a damn
about a bitch? I ain't a sucker!
This is an autobiography of the E
And if you ever fuck with me
You'll get taken
by a stupid dope brother who will smother
Word to the motherfucker
Straight outta Compton
CROWD: (CHANTING) Eazy! Eazy!
Damn, that shit was dope!
What's up?
DR. DRE: Let's do this shit.
- What's up?
- Let's do this shit.
- Wassup? Let's go.
- What's up?
Hey, hold up, hold up.
ICE CUBE: Y'all know
what the motherfuckin' police
tried to tell us backstage?
CROWD: What?
They tried to tell us
what the fuck we can't play.
(AUDIENCE BOOS)
Motherfuckers tried to tell us
what the fuck we can't say.
This N.W.A.
We do what the fuck we wanna do!
We say what the fuck we wanna say!
So, everybody,
put the middle fingers high in the sky.
And to the punk-ass cop backstage...
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yo, Dre.
- DR. DRE: What up?
- I got something to say.
ICE CUBE: (RAPPING) Fuck the police
Comin' straight from the underground
A young nigga got it bad 'cause I'm brown
And not the other color so police think
they have the authority to kill a minority
Fuck that shit 'cause I ain't the one
For a punk motherfucker
with a badge and a gun
to be beaten on and thrown in jail
We can go toe to toe in
the middle of a cell
Fucking with me 'cause I'm a teenager
With a little bit of gold and a pager
Searching my car looking for the product
Thinking every nigga is selling narcotics
You'd rather see me in the pen
Than me and Lorenzo rolling in a Benz-o
Beat a police out of shape
Then when I'm finished
Bring the yellow tape
To tape off the scene of the slaughter
Still getting swoll off bread and water
I don't know if they fags or what
Search a nigga down and grabbing his nuts
And on the other hand,
without a gun they can't get none
But don't let it be a black and a white one
'Cause they'll slam ya
down to the street top
Black police showing out for the white cop
Ice Cube will swarm
On any motherfucker in a blue uniform
Just 'cause I'm from the CPT
Punk police are afraid of me, huh
A young nigga on the warpath
And when I'm finished,
it's gonna be a bloodbath
Of cops, dyin' in LA
Yo, Dre, I got something to say
CROWD: Fuck tha police!
Fuck, fuck, fuck tha police!
Fuck tha police!
Fuck, fuck...
(GUNSHOTS)
Huh? Fuck!
Come on, nigga.
Hell no! They shootin'! Let's go!
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Go, go! All units, move in.
DR. DRE: Move!
DJ YELLA: Move!
Go, go, go, go, go! Come on, man!
Come on, hurry up! Hurry up!
ICE CUBE: Hold up, hold up.
MC REN: Let's go, let's go.
- Fuck them!
- Come on!
ICE CUBE: Fuck!
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
DR. DRE: Fuck this!
MC REN: What we gonna do?
ICE CUBE: Get off me!
Get the fuck off me!
Man, get off me, man!
OFFICER: Away from the ledge.
(GLASS BREAKING)
OFFICER: Backup!
We need backup in the loading area!
Now!
Man!
Come on. Get the fuck off of me, man!
Fuck y'all.
This is completely fucking illegal!
You realize that?
Let us go! Let me go! Come on, man.
- Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Come on.
Fuck you! Fuck you!
OFFICER: Get in there!
You gotta get in there.
Fuck tha police! Fuck tha police!
CROWD: Fuck tha police! Fuck tha police!
Fuck your mama,
fuck your daddy, fuck your grandma!
Fucking...
These motherfuckers.
D.O.C.: Fuck y'all!
- (SCREAMING)
- (SINGING)
(POLICE SIRENS BLARING)
JOURNALIST: How do you explain
inciting a riot in Detroit?
What do you have to say about that?
I have to say that we
didn't incite that shit.
Right. Like, y'all just got a snapshot
of how Americans really feel.
We gave the people a voice.
We gave the people truth.
Yeah, but your songs, they glamorize
the lifestyle of gangs, guns, drugs.
Our art is a reflection of our reality.
What you see
when you go outside your door?
I know what I see.
And it ain't glamorous.
We get AKs from Russia
and cocaine from Columbia.
And ain't none of us got a passport, so...
(LAUGHS)
- ...might wanna check the source.
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
ICE CUBE: Next question.
Will you be more careful
about what you say, how you say it?
- No!
- Probably not. Nah.
ICE CUBE: Freedom of speech
includes rap music, right?
Well, we exercising our first amendment
as far as I'm concerned.
And the government wrote that.
So, Cube, what's a guy from Compton
do when he starts making
real money like this?
Cube?
- Buy Raider gear.
- (CHUCKLES)
- And curl activator.
- (LAUGHTER)
Next question.
JERRY: Good to see you, Cube.
I can barely see you, Jerry.
What's with all the Godfather shit?
(JERRY CHUCKLES)
Okay.
I know that you've been very eager to sign
a contract with Eric's company,
Ruthless Records.
Eric's company? Ain't it your company, too?
That's incorrect.
It's not my company. I work for you.
- You work for me?
- Uh-huh.
I've made that clear from the beginning.
All right, cool.
So, I could take this to a lawyer
or somebody, right?
Cube, those guys are paid to make trouble.
They're gonna create problems
where no problems exist.
Jerry, you know I don't know
what none of this legal shit mean.
All right? None of us do.
So we're gonna need a lawyer
before we sign anything.
Everybody else has already signed.
I thought you knew this.
You're the only one who hasn't.
There's also this.
$75,000.
Shit!
Sign the contract
and all this money is yours.
That's my money anyway, Jerry.
I earned that money.
- And I wrote a lot of hit songs.
- Mmm-hmm.
We've been performing
on this tour for months.
Sellin' out shows, sellin' records.
- I know there's plenty of money.
- (CHUCKLES)
Really? Jesus Christ.
Give me my money, Jerry.
How the hell do you think this works?
How the hell do you think
all of this gets paid for?
The hotel rooms, the tour buses,
security, the parties, all this shit.
How do you think it gets paid for?
You think it's free?
Why are you doing this now?
If we were so good, why didn't you give us
contracts in the beginning?
Because nothing is a sure thing, Cube.
Even a great talent can crash and burn.
Too much ego, too much excess,
too many expectations.
It tends to ruin things.
You ought to keep that in mind.
This is Eric's company, right?
Bye, Jerry.
I'm out.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
D.O.C.: What up, big Suge?
BUS DRIVER: Here you go.
DJ YELLA: Thank you, sir.
EAZY E: Hey, what up with D.O.C. and Suge?
DJ YELLA: I guess that dude
is gonna be managing him now.
DJ YELLA: One day
you Bobby Brown's bodyguard,
and the next day, you reppin' talent.
MC REN: Come on, man.
I guess everybody
wanna get into the act, huh?
I guess so.
All right, man.
DJ YELLA: I know, right?
JERRY: How you doin'? You good?
BUS DRIVER: Here you go.
I'm helping you out all I can.
You all right?
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I'm good.
- JERRY: What's going on?
- Just happy to be home.
JERRY: You hungry?
JERRY: Yeah?
I'll be there in a minute. All right?
Thanks, man.
- Thanks for everything, bruh.
- You bet!
DR. DRE: So, Cube.
We gonna keep
this momentum going or what?
Nah, man. Not like this.
I'd rather be broke than to get fucked.
I told you not to sign that shit, Dre.
Nigga, I got bills to pay.
And you know that.
And I gotta put some money
in my momma's hand after Tyree passed, man.
- I feel you.
- Right.
We gotta do what we gotta do.
They're gonna take care of you.
You their bread and butter.
Cube, we Ruthless.
We N.W.A. They Ruthless.
Cube, you comin'?
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
I'm about to get out of here.
Take care of yourself, Dre.
Peace.
- Mom.
- I missed you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
- Good.
- Come on. Let's get home.
All right.
So you're leaving the group?
Yeah, I'm through with the bullshit.
Eazy put everything on Jerry,
Jerry put everything on Eazy.
It's a two-man show up there.
There ain't no fuckin' group.
I get that,
but I just want you to understand
that you are walking away
from a winning situation.
Now, how do you feel about this, Kim?
Is he making a big mistake?
- A mistake?
- BRYAN: Yes.
I don't think so, okay.
After hearing all the stuff
that he went through, I would've left too.
Look, I want you to express yourself, Cube.
And I am your biggest fan.
I believe in you.
But I just want you to understand,
there's not a lot of
money in this solo play.
Okay?
But if the first record hits,
I will make it up to you on the second one.
Be ready, Bryan.
These records is comin' in fast.
(RAPPING)
I heard payback's a motherfucking nigga
That's why I'm sick
of getting treated like a goddamn stepchild
Fuck a punk 'cause I ain't him
You gotta deal with the nine-double-M
The damn scum that you all hate
just think if niggas decide to retaliate
They try to keep me from running up
I never tell you to get down,
it's all about coming up
So what they do, go and ban the AK?
My shit wasn't registered any fucking way
So you better duck away, run and hide out
When I'm rolling real
slow and the lights out
'Cause I'm about to fuck up the program
Shooting out the window
of a drop-top Brougham
When I'm shooting let's see who drop
The police, the media,
suckers that went pop
And motherfuckers that say they too black
Put 'em overseas
they'll be begging to come back
They say he promote gangs and drugs
EAZY E: You know Cube's record
is in the Top 20 Billboard, right now?
Our shit never been up there.
He blowin' the fuck up, Jerry.
JERRY: It's gonna be fine, Eric.
It's not just N.W.A anymore,
it's our whole Ruthless roster.
We got D.O.C.,
we got Michel'le, we got Above the Law.
We're moving up to the next level.
You know what? Sit down for two seconds.
Look, we need to keep Dre happy.
Yeah.
Look at him.
You think he needs
any more motivation than that?
EAZY E: I mean, I get it, Jerry.
He drownin' in pussy and shit,
but that don't mean that he...
Now, you worry too much. Stop, okay?
Yeah, ar'ight.
Here, sign some checks.
- Right now, Jerry?
- Yes, right now.
- You're gonna be out of your mind later.
- Come on.
Do it now.
The fact is,
Ren is as good a writer as Cube.
Maybe even better.
We got everything covered.
Just the last one. Okay?
- We finished here, Jerry?
- We're finished.
Good. 'Cause I'm about to go fuck.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
- Ar'ight.
- Yeah.
(INAUDIBLE)
Now I'm only telling you what you told me.
If AmeriKKKa's Most Wanted blew up,
you'd pay me the advance for the follow-up.
Now is that not what the fuck you said?
That is what I said.
But it is more complicated than that, Cube.
Right, there are metrics...
Come on, Bryan!
I got a baby on the way
and a house I just paid for
off the strength of what you told me.
I mean, you gave me your word!
Cube, would you just calm down?
Calm down?
I am just trying to give you what you want.
You not. I been did the work...
I gave you the product.
Give me my money, Bryan!
When a man does the job,
he's supposed to get paid,
and you making it seem like I'm beggin'
for some shit that's technically mine.
Of course you are not begging.
And I am not trying to be difficult, man.
I promise you.
But you can't help me, right?
That's what you telling me?
My hands are tied, man.
BRYAN: Hey!
Shoulda kept your word, Bryan.
Jesus Christ, man!
What the fuck are you doing, Cube?
Goddamn!
I will get you your money, man.
Just... God damn it!
You think I give a fuck
about these fucking records?
I put up these fuckin' records!
This my shit!
I know that, Cube!
I will get you your money!
God damn it! I'm sorry.
Now I'm gonna fuck up your shit.
Look, do not...
God damn it!
(SOBBING) Just, fine.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Take it out what you owe me.
(WHIMPERING) Just...
MC REN: (RAPPING) Prisoner like a hostage
Yo, you shoulda covered
your muthafucking head like an ostrich
Deep in the dirt 'cause you's a sucker
And your ass up high
so I can kick the muthafucker
Don't try to hang your best abroad
'Cause my foot will be so
far up your ass, you'll get hemorrhoids
Before you try to fuck wit Ren
See that shit right there?
That's what I'm talking about.
Fuck that nigga Cube, man.
That nigga ain't shit.
How you figure, man?
His record the hottest shit out right now, E.
Yeah, man, for real. Cube killed that shit.
So we supposed to
just sit there and not say nothin',
and look like bitches and just take it?
Take what?
I don't know what the fuck you talkin' about.
I like that shit.
Clown-ass.
Why you drunk all the goddamn time?
You need to get your shit together.
You's a motherfucking' artist,
if you ain't noticed.
How about you get
your shit together, little nigga.
Come on.
How about you get
your country-ass homeboy.
'Cause the vocals were local in nightclubs
And not getting paid in full
They got the nerve to cuss
Only reason niggaz pick up your record
is cause they thought it was us
(FUNK PLAYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
SUGE: Yo, Dre. D.O.C. was in an accident.
What? An accident?
D.O.C. shouldn't even be alive.
Got thrown out a car, hit a tree.
Is he paralyzed?
No. But his throat got crushed.
He could lose his career over this.
Where your people? Where Eazy and Jerry?
How the fuck should I know?
Come here.
Whatchu know about Jerry?
Whatchu think about him?
He a'ight. I guess.
What about your paperwork?
You cool with that?
I think.
You think?
Look, I just focus on the music, Suge.
That's it.
You see that motherfucker in there?
Gotta make sure it don't
happen to you, man.
Hey, uh...
Maybe some of your people
can look into my paperwork, too.
Most definitely.
I'll arrange.
Go see your boy.
WOMAN: This place is nice.
You're nice.
I figured I'd take you to a nice place,
- Ms. Record Executive.
- Mmm.
Um, record executive assistant.
But, damn.
I didn't realize we was going on
like a "date" date.
I don't even know how to take that.
I got my collared shirt on.
I brought you to this nice restaurant. Really?
Okay. That is not the
kind of collared shirt
- they was talking about.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
It's cute, though.
And you didn't take off
your hat like they asked you to.
And I'm not.
- Oh, really?
- I ain't taking off my hat for nobody.
I think they know that.
So what?
You bring all your little
females here, don't you?
The special ones.
Okay.
(LAUGHS) I'm playing. I'm playing.
There you go getting sensitive.
You don't have to try to impress me.
We could've went to Fatburger.
Go to Fatburger?
(LAUGHS)
BRYAN: Hey! You got a haircut. I love it.
How's that new house treating you?
KIM: It's great. Thanks for asking.
So, how you liking your new decor?
Great.
Yeah, I never did like
the old design anyway, you know?
What you got for me, Bryan?
I know you called me up here for somethin'.
Yeah.
Uh...
It's N.W.A's new record.
I wanted to play it for you first,
before you hear it anywhere else.
DR. DRE: Break me, take me
But watch me pull the trigger
Dre is just a nigga with
heart a nigga that's smart
A nigga that's paid to say
what others are scared to play
We started out with too much cargo
So I'm glad we got rid of Benedict Arnold
Yo, N.W...
Benedict Arnold?
Are they trying to say
that you're like a traitor?
Yeah.
I'm a fuckin' traitor?
I didn't say shit about them
on AmeriKKKa's Most Wanted!
Now they trying to diss?
(RAPPING) Goddamn, I'm glad y'all
set it off Used to be hard
Now you're just wet and soft
First you was down with the AK
And now I see you on a video with Michel'le
Looking like straight bozos
I saw it coming that's why I went solo
And kept on stompin'
While y'all mothafuckers
moved straight outta Compton
Living with the whites one big house
And not another nigga in sight
I started off with too much cargo
Dropped four niggas
Now I'm making all the dough
White man just ruling
The Niggas With Attitudes? Who ya fooling?
Y'all niggas just phony
I put that on my mama and my dead homies
Yella Boy's on your team so you're losing
Hey, yo, Dre, stick to producing
Calling me Arnold but you bent-a-dick
Eazy-E saw your ass and went in it quick
You got jealous when I got my own company
But I'm a man, and ain't nobody humping me
Trying to sound like Amerikkka's Most
You could yell all day
but you don't come close
'Cause you know I'm the one
that flowed ya done run 100 miles
but you still got one to go
With the L-E-N-C-H M-O-B,
and y'all disgrace the C-P-T
'Cause you're getting fucked
out your green by a white boy
With no Vaseline
Now you're getting done without Vaseline
Damn, it feels good to see people, on it
The bigger the cap bigger the peeling
Who gives a fuck about a punk-ass villain
You're getting fucked real quick
and Eazy's dick is smelling like MC Ren's shit
Tried to tell you a year ago
But Willie D told me to let a ho be a ho, so
I couldn't stop you from getting ganked
Now let's play big-bank-take-little-bank
Tried to diss Ice Cube,
it wasn't worth it 'cause
the broomstick fit your ass so perfect
Cut my hair and I'll cut them balls
'cause I heard you like
giving up the drawers
Gang-banged by your manager, fella
Getting money out
your ass like a mothafucking ready teller
Giving up the dollar bills
Now they got the villain with
a purse and high heels
So don't believe what Ren say
'cause he's going out like Kunte Kinte
But I got a whip for ya, Toby
Used to be my homie
and now you act like you don't know me
It's a case of divide-and-conquer
'Cause you let a Jew break up my crew
House nigga gotta run...
That shit's kinda funny.
That motherfucker got us!
Yo, what we about to do?
First thing we're gonna do,
we're gonna sue this ignorant fuck.
That's what we're gonna do.
Defamation of character,
libel, I don't really care.
That anti-Semitic piece of fuckin' shit.
Who the fuck does he think he is?
Un-fucking-believable.
That kind of fucking bullshit!
Jew-bashing bullshit!
You know what?
I'll call my friend at the JDL.
They'll handle him.
We'll see how much he likes that.
Jerry, you gotta relax. Ar'ight?
Niggas don't even know what
anti-Semitic means anyway.
It's just a fucking battle rap.
Come on, Eric, we gotta get organized.
We got to fight this kinda
ignorant fucking bullshit.
You know what? I always knew
that he was a hateful human being.
This is just ignorant shit.
He calls it political?
This is ignorant shit!
I always knew it.
Now the whole world is gonna know.
I'm gonna make sure of that. Okay?
I don't understand why the fuck
you're not more angry about this?
- Did you hear what he said?
- I heard what he said!
- JERRY: Did you hear what he said?
About you? About me? Come on!
You got your way
of dealing with it, I got mine.
We could just go the studio
and just end his fucking career anyway.
I don't know about all that.
Fine, you do that.
You call Dre, and you guys go do that.
Do something!
Damn, E. Who work for who?
What? You questioning that?
My position is fucking solidified!
Don't never question that shit!
Fuckin' Cube, man!
Nigga.
Hey, there go the nigga Cube right there.
What that Ruthless like, nigga?
Fuck Ruthless! This Lench Mob, nigga.
- Fuck Lench Mob.
- MAN: Come here, motherfucker.
WOMAN: Oh, shit!
Shit!
Oh, shit!
(SCREAMS)
Motherfucker!
PETER JENNINGS: We've all seen the pictures
of Los Angeles police officers
beating a man they had just pulled over.
The city's police chief said today
he will support criminal charges
against some of the men.
Here's ABC's Gary Shepard.
At least we got the motherfuckers on video.
LAPD gonna have a real good time
on that level three prison yard.
You know what I'm saying?
JERRY: Dre, maybe we should
try to get back to work.
We are working, Jerry.
I'm having a word with my client.
Man, hold up, man! We got this!
Nah. We got it.
You done? Suge?
Jerry? E? Huh?
REPORTER: Brutality and misconduct
that goes back a quarter of a century
including one incident
that sparked the Watts Riots.
So far this year,
there have been more than 125
complaints of police misconduct
filed with watchdog organizations.
SUGE: Yo, Dre. Hold up.
Look, I did what you asked me to do.
I had my people look at your contracts.
It didn't look good.
But you gotta watch your back.
What you mean by that?
Look, everything you need to know is here.
And you know I can help you with this.
May I help you with something?
This your house?
Who's asking?
It's a nice house.
Who are you? You're with Suge Knight?
Someone else? Ice Cube?
Have yourself a good night.
Jerry.
Shit.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
EAZY E: So, wassup?
When you talked to me on the phone, man,
you sounded pretty worked up.
Yeah, I know you don't
like hearing this shit.
It's about Jerry.
We gotta get rid of that motherfucker, E.
That's really why you came here?
I thought all this shit
was in the past, Dre.
I found some real shit, man. And the shit's
been happening since the beginning.
I had some people look into this.
I ain't been gettin' my fair share.
Do you even know why you rich, though?
Do you know why you got
a big-ass house and you
ain't sleepin' on your
auntie's couch no more?
Because Jerry made that possible for us.
He kicked down the door
for that shit to happen. For us!
And you just gonna turn your back on him?
What, you Cube now?
Cube was right, fool!
E, look at the papers, man,
and you'll see what the fuck I'm talking about.
And forget about Jerry, man!
You keep talking about Jerry this, Jerry that.
We didn't make it because of Jerry,
we made it because our shit is dope!
And we can keep going, E.
We can own the goddamn world,
but we just can't be fucking with him no more.
Man, we started this N.W.A shit.
I just want it to be right.
And this what you think right?
Turnin' your back on somebody
after all he done for us.
You mean all he done for you.
Right?
Look at me.
When Tyree died,
you said we was always gonna be brothers.
I guess you forgot about that.
I'mma start my own company
with Suge Knight, E.
Thought we were brothers, man.
What up, Dre?
This Death Row. We about to do this shit.
This shit sound good.
Yeah. None of it means anything
while I'm under contract with Ruthless.
I told you about that.
I'mma get you outta your contracts,
I promise you.
Yeah, ar'ight.
What up with you, cuz?
Wuddup?
What up, Lo?
Wuddup, Dre?
- Wassup, Warren?
- Chilin' man.
- You good?
- I'm great. You good?
- All right.
- Dr. Dre.
- 'Sup?
- Wuddup with you?
What's goin' on, man?
Yeah, yeah.
So, look, I listened to your demo.
It was tight.
You see that little look he gave me?
Yo, yo, yo, hold up.
Who the fuck is this guy?
My bad, Suge. This the homie, Snoop.
Snoop D-O-double-G, cuz. Who you?
What? What up?
What the fuck you say, Blood?
Hold on! Hold on, hold on.
He with me. He with me.
He ain't with me.
Nah! He here to work, ar'ight?
This is business, Suge. Come on, man.
Anyway, what's this
you workin' on, cuz, I like this.
So look, you know...
It's a new track for this new movie.
It's called Deep Cover.
- Woo-wee.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- For a movie, huh?
- Yeah, a movie.
Dre doing big shit. Okay, okay, okay.
You think you can get down on it?
Oh, most definitely.
Throw me in the booth one time.
All right.
ANCHOR: It's perhaps the most notorious
police brutality case in recent memory.
Those blows from
Officer Powell and Officer Wind's batons
continued and continued for no just reason.
They just let them people do
whatever the hell they want.
(PHONE RINGING)
Rodney King's leg
and facial bones were broken.
Three of the four accused officers took
the stand and admitted that it was brutal,
but said, "Police work is brutal."
And that the video tape only showed that.
- Here.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
You watchin' this shit upstairs?
Hello?
Yo, it's Suge.
We gotta talk about these contracts.
Why you don't talk to
Jerry about that shit?
I don't wanna talk to Jerry.
It's your company. You the man.
Ar'ight. Whatever, man.
I'll be through there.
- Who was that?
- Nobody.
...right across the top of the cheekbone,
splitting his face
from the top of his ear to his chin.
(DOG GROWLING)
Where Dre at?
You said he was gonna be here.
(SOFTLY) I'll get with you outside.
Don't worry about Dre.
Truth be told,
he got nothing to do with this.
This what's gonna happen.
You gonna sign these,
releasing Dre and D.O.C. from Ruthless.
Whatever, homie.
Think I'm signing that?
You crazier than I thought you was.
I'm out.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Get your ass up.
Nah. I think you're gonna
stay here for a while.
Fuck you, Suge!
Y'all niggas don't scare me.
You can talk tough all you want,
but this ain't no record.
Don't make me change you, Eric.
Fuck that's supposed to mean?
Keep talkin',
you're gonna fuck around and get smoked.
SUGE: Nah, nah.
But you better choose right.
You know where the fuck I'm from.
This Bompton, nigga.
Oh, my fucking God.
Eric.
Jesus Christ.
What the hell are you doing here?
You can't sneak in here like that.
I thought you were...
Oh, my God. What's going on, man?
Are you okay?
What happened to your face?
I gotta kill this motherfucker,
Suge Knight.
I just came here to let you know,
'cause shit might get a little thick.
I need to stay protected.
No, you're not gonna do that. No.
I didn't come here to ask for permission.
I came here to let you know.
You wanted to be involved
with this gangster shit?
Here we go.
You do that and you're gonna ruin
everything we've worked for.
(SIGHS)
You really think I got a fucking choice?
Look at my face!
This the streets. Motherfuckers came at me!
Came at us!
If I don't hit back, we finished.
It's over.
I'm not saying that we're
not gonna hit back.
But this is not Compton,
if you haven't looked around.
Drop that shit, okay?
We don't hit back with bullets,
we hit back with lawyers.
We drain these assholes.
That really takes 'em down.
It ain't about the money, Jerry!
(SCOFFS)
I don't care about no money.
Of course it is. And you should
fucking care about the money.
You're so much smarter
than these fuckin' thugs.
You wanna kill somebody?
You're gonna go to jail forever.
No more family,
no more Ruthless, no more anything.
If you kill this man,
his problems will be over
and yours will just be beginning.
Don't be a fuckin' fool.
Hey.
Why the fuck I gotta be the bigger man?
'Cause it's better than
you being a dead man.
I don't want you fuckin' dead.
You okay?
Baby. Let me see.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
- Why you so tense, Dre?
- No, I'm cool.
Man. No, you're not, man.
You've been in that house, what?
A month now?
Nigga, and not one track?
I mean, what's up?
There's too much interference.
Man, you know how they
tryin' to starve me out.
Playin' games with
my motherfuckin' money, man.
That's why the house
was so goddamned empty.
(LAUGHING)
- Hey, come on, man.
- I'm fucking with you, cuz. Hit this.
- All right, man, give me that shit.
- Here.
Fuck I'm taking about.
Have you feeling righteously together.
- Holy shit.
- Oh, hell no. Give me that.
Goddamn, man!
What the fuck is in this shit, Snoops?
- That right there, that's that chronic, cuz.
- Yeah.
- Chronic.
- Yes, sir.
- Let me hit that once.
- Yeah.
- Look it.
- Wow, man.
- All right. Let's head back to the studio.
- Let's go.
I got something for this.
(SMOOTH RAP INTRO)
Damn, Dre.
What the fuck is that? Feeling that shit.
- Yeah. You feelin' it?
- Yeah!
Hey, hey, look,
I'mma spit a little something.
You feel me? You say whatever...
You just jump in, nigga, and just...
Hold on, look, I got something. Here we go.
(RAPPING) One, two, three and to the four
Snoop Doggy Dogg and Dr. Dre is at the door
Ready to make an entrance so back on up
'Cause you know we about to rip shit up
Give me the microphone first
so I could bust like a bubble
Compton and Long Beach together
now you know you in trouble
Ain't nothin' but a G thang, baby
Two loc'ed out niggas so we're crazy
Death Row is the label that pays me
Un-fadable so please
don't try and fade this
But back to the lecture at hand
Perfection is perfected...
JOURNALIST: I want to thank you
for having us here.
- ICE CUBE: Of course.
- Very generous for you to give your time
with everything that's going on right now.
Not a problem.
Now if I may,
are you anti-Semitic?
Now, I thought
this was about the Rodney King trial.
Well, the JDL recently got involved
citing the lyrics about
your former manager Jerry Heller.
I'm not anti-Semitic.
I'm anti-Jerry Heller.
Let me ask you something.
Do the JDL condone Jerry's behavior
when it comes to my situation?
Him trying to get me to sign a contract
without legal representation?
I have no idea.
I didn't think you did.
But when you got that for me,
we can continue on this topic.
Until then, I'm here to talk about the
beating of an unarmed motorist, Rodney King.
And four guilty LAPD officers
who seem to be Daryl Gates' standard issue.
It's also the LAPD and the FBI
who feel that your negative portrayal
of police condones violence.
"Fuck Tha Police" is just a warning,
that's it.
You can't treat people like that
and expect 'em not to rise up.
I'm a journalist just like you.
Reporting what's goin' on in the hood.
The only thing that's different
is that I'm brutally honest.
What's your relationship
with the Nation of Islam?
ICE CUBE: They my brothers.
You know what?
That question right there proves to me
what kind of a unprepared
sandbag reporter you are.
You talkin' to me
like I'm some elected official.
Like I'm running for office.
But I get it, that's your job.
Bigger the story,
the bigger the check in your field of work.
It's not your fault, I shouldn't blame you.
What's your name, man?
Brian.
Eat a dick, Brian.
Get the fuck out my house. Y'all done here.
Can we cut, please?
Excuse me, excuse me,
excuse me, excuse me.
You look like you ready to go.
Yeah. I'm just waiting on my friend.
I should've drove.
You're not havin' a good time?
No! No. I had a really good time,
but now it's starting to get a little wild.
Yeah.
We've been known to get crazy
from time to time.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm Andre.
I'm Nicole.
Come on, man. Lighten up.
We're about to get back in the game.
Big time.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
How do you figure?
Are you trying to piss me off?
Come on. God almighty.
Did you forget about Ren's new album?
Or did you forget about the fact
that you are working on something
I think is gonna be bigger
than anything N.W.A ever did.
All I know... Mmm!
Fucking Cube out here,
- doing it big. Making movies and shit.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Then I keep hearing about
this album Dre about to drop.
Dre is a fucking producer, Eric.
Producers don't rap.
We have him under contract.
He can't do anything.
Cheer up.
Eat, drink and be merry.
- Suge.
- Hey.
- How you doin'?
- All right.
Jimmy Iovine, Interscope Records.
Nice to meet you.
You, too.
JIMMY: So, what do I call you?
Dre? Dr. Dre? Doc?
(CHUCKLES)
Nah, Dre is cool. Go ahead, have a seat.
All right.
- It's good.
- Yeah.
So what do you got today?
DR. DRE: Um...
Well, you know...
I heard John McClain gave you my album.
What'd you think?
I think it was great.
So, you're the artist on the record.
Who produced it?
I did.
Okay. And who mixed it?
(CHUCKLES) Come on, man. I did.
Huh.
Listen, um...
I don't know anything about hip-hop,
but I know that this is special.
Seriously.
Thank you.
SUGE: Hey, look, we'd love
to bring in Interscope,
but there's a little problem.
What's the problem?
SUGE: Ruthless, lawsuits,
and contracts.
How about this?
You give me three weeks
and I don't wanna hear any bullshit
about you shopping this
anywhere around town.
If you do that...
I believe I can solve your problem
with the contract.
SUGE: Lil' nigga, you in my spot.
- Yo.
- DR. DRE: Hey, Suge.
MAN: Suge. Easy, man. Yo.
Hey, Suge, what the...
DR. DRE: Hey. Suge.
You parked in my
motherfuckin' spot or what?
- I didn't know, man.
- It's cool, man.
What the fuck? Suge!
Suge, it's just a parking spot.
Fuck off. Fuck out of my...
SUGE: Move this piece of shit.
And park my car.
And I better not see
one drop of blood on that motherfucker.
Suge, let's go, man.
What?
The jury in the Rodney King case
has delivered its verdict,
and not one of the four police officers
seen on video tape
beating Mr. King a year ago
is guilty of using excessive force.
They've all been found not guilty.
For Christ's sake. Oh, my God.
Judy, the details.
Peter, it was a clean sweep
for the defendants.
Not guilty, the verdict for all of them.
Only on one count against
Lawrence Powell...
I'm sorry.
...on excessive use of force
under color of authority.
OFFICER 1: It's probably the worst case
of police misconduct that I've ever seen.
(CROWD CHANTING)
OFFICER 2: I think it was devastating
to the image of this city
and especially to our police department.
WOMAN: It looks
kind of like we're in a war zone though.
REPORTER: We've got some courageous
shop owners here, who are armed...
MAN: Anarchy is obviously
a statement of political dissatisfaction.
REPORTER 1: Police officers
are still back down,
guarding the area
down there with the Ralph's...
REPORTER 2: The police
are using eerily reminiscent
of military-style assault weapons.
REPORTER 3: You can hear
random gunshots as rioters...
REPORTER 4: The cars
have been left abandoned
because their drivers came under attack...
REPORTER 5: ...our city.
We have fires burning.
Olympic, Pico, Wilshire.
- (CROWD CHANTING)
- REPORTER 6: More than 100 injured,
mostly in the South-Central
section of Los Angeles.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
You know, If we bag all this shit up in ounces,
we should probably be straight.
I think we got enough.
No, turn it down. Turn it down.
Baby. Can you smoke that shit out there?
So, all this weed is for
your Ruthless artists?
Yeah, I mean, shit.
I'm tryin' to take care
of these little money problems, man.
So, they can smoke it, sell it.
Fuck, throw a party on it,
for all I give a fuck.
As long as I just...
(EAZY E COUGHING)
MC REN: Yo, man, you straight?
- E, you straight?
- Yeah, I'm good.
- No, for real, man. You straight?
- Man, I'm good!
I'm just fucking tired, man.
I'm fucking downgrading houses.
How would you feel?
Answer me that!
Dre rolled out. Ruthless money low.
Tomica asking me all kind of questions
about the house.
Answer me this, would you be all right?
Would you be all right
moving out your fucking house?
You all right with it?
E, I'm your boy. I'm in this shit with you.
I'm just trying to make
sure you're good, bro.
I'm good! You good?
- You good?
- DJ YELLA: Yeah, man.
JERRY: Eric.
What, Jerry?
Take it easy.
You know what?
Let's get you outta the house.
I have stuff needs your autograph, okay?
I'll come when I have time, Jerry.
JERRY: Eric, come on.
We still got a business to run.
Don't it look like
I'm running business right now?
JERRY: No. It looks like
you're fucking cutting up weed.
I thought that was a job
for fucking jackasses.
You know what, Jerry?
You right. You absolutely fuckin' right.
We got business to take care of.
I'll see you in a minute.
You all right, E?
E, are you cool?
- Eric.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
"You got knocked the fuck out."
(LAUGHS)
That shit's funny.
- Hey, baby.
How's Friday coming?
This shit is funny. I'm feeling it, though.
What page are you on?
100. I'm not going too much longer, though.
Baby, come here. Look!
(MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
Look how young y'all are.
ICE CUBE: Shit.
Dang!
What?
We left a lot of good records on the table.
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
EAZY E: It's like
I don't even know what I'm doing no more.
I don't know where the money going.
TOMICA: Why you stressin'?
You know I know the business.
Just... Shit.
Lay out all the files,
contracts, whatever it is,
and I'll look into it.
For real. Come here.
Come here.
You just go to New York,
you take care of this
big ol' distribution deal with Sony.
Bring that shit on in.
All right?
And I'll check into everything else.
I love you.
You what?
- You what? I can't hear you.
- (LAUGHS)
So how's your home life, man?
What? That small-ass house
I just moved into in Norwalk?
- (MICROWAVE BEEPS)
- Fuckin' hate it.
No, come on. You know what I mean.
I mean your love life, Eric. Hmm?
You seem pretty serious about this girl.
- I ain't in love.
- Oh? You had me scared there for a minute.
You're too young to settle down.
Well, you don't have to be scared of that.
Oh, man. Wait till you taste this.
Kung Pao chicken.
Fantastic.
And it is better the second day.
There you go.
Dig in.
So, where is this girl from again?
Look, Jerry.
I actually ate right before I came.
So I'm just gonna take this and go.
Hold on. Hold on. Where are you going?
I just came to get this.
These are my bills, my checks.
Look, I'm gonna have a bite of your food.
I'm gonna say farewell.
- I'll talk to you later.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
Your neighbors,
they've been complaining a lot.
The noise.
- Stop.
- (CHUCKLES)
I just think a little
privacy would be better.
(LAUGHS)
So what? You want me to move?
Yeah.
And I...
You know, I happen to know of a place.
There's plenty of room,
and I know the owner.
Are you sure you're ready for that, Andre?
Yeah, I am.
'Cause I'm really feeling you like that.
I'm really feeling you too.
But...
Hey, don't even worry about it.
It was just a thought.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
What's up?
All right. Good night.
Oh, whoa, whoa! Really? Good night?
You okay to drive?
No. Look at you.
Good night, Andre.
Nah. See...
See, I can't help thinking,
maybe you want me to come inside.
Of course I do.
So, what's different now?
I got a lot to think about.
You're asking me to move in with you.
That is a huge step!
I like you, Andre,
but there's a lot going on around you.
Whatchu mean?
I know about the whole Death Row business,
the assault charges,
the shooting.
Just seems dangerous.
My son is my world.
I hear you.
Good night.
(BARKING)
(RAPPING) Hail Mary, run quick see
What do we have here now?
Do you wanna ride or die?
(VOCALIZING)
I ain't a killer but don't push me
Revenge is like
the sweetest joy next to getting pussy
Picture paragraphs unloaded
Wise words being quoted
Peeped the weakness
in the rap game and sewed it
Bow down, pray to God
Hoping that he's listening
Seeing niggas coming for me
and my diamonds...
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- What up, Dre?
What up, Pac?
I'm about to bust niggas in the mouth
with this new album.
(LAUGHS) Okay, I feel that.
- Suge said you got some heat for a nigga.
- Hell yeah!
- Play that for him.
- TUPAC: Okay.
(MUSIC PLAYING) California Love
DR. DRE: Yeah. You feel that?
Yeah. Fuck with me.
California...
- "California Love."
- DR. DRE: Yeah.
(MUSIC PLAYING) ...knows how to party
California...
(GUNSHOTS)
...knows how to party
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- MAN: What the hell was that?
Hold on, Pac.
Stay right there, man.
MAN: Yo. Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
- DOG HANDLER: Come on.
- Come on, man.
DR. DRE: Shut the fuck up
and put your glasses down.
MAN: Stop, man! Stop.
DOG HANDLER: Chop, chop.
Get him. Get hype.
Get hype.
Yo!
What the fuck are y'all doing?
Check this out.
DOG HANDLER:
Get him. Time to eat. Who's hungry?
You hungry, nigga? Yeah!
- Get up.
- DOG HANDLER: Come on!
- Bring your bitch-ass up.
- (WOMEN LAUGHING)
DOG HANDLER: Tight-whitey ass nigga.
You know what to do.
I'd like to make a toast.
To what?
MAN: To Death Row Records...
MAN 2: Death Row!
MAN: ...and Suge
for making all this happen.
And may the West Coast reign forever.
Come on. Come on.
Now toast to Dr. Dre.
Put your glass down.
I said, put the fucking glasses down!
Hey, yo, slow your roll, Dre.
Come on.
This why we got money?
To act like we ain't got no goddamn sense?
We coulda did all this dumb shit
back in Compton!
But this what the fuck y'all turned into.
You sittin' up here eatin' fuckin' crab.
Who the fuck are you? Huh?
This my motherfucking name
on the wall, man!
And y'all in here acting like
y'all on motherfucking vacation.
I got Pac in the next motherfucking room.
Grindin', man! Workin'!
And y'all niggas in here partyin'?
One time?
- You trippin'.
- WOMAN: That's right.
We can do anything we wanna do.
We started this thing. This is us.
Nah, nigga. Death Row, that's us.
I don't know what the fuck this shit is.
Better watch your mouth, Blood.
And who the fuck you talking to, huh?
Nigga, you ain't nothing but a producer.
Get the fuck out my face!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(LAUGHS)
SUGE: Shit!
Dre.
This is bullshit.
SUGE: Dre!
- (ENGINE REVVING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (SIREN BLARING)
- Always fucking with me!
(HORN HONKING)
OFFICER IN HELICOPTER:
Stop the vehicle now.
Driver, hold it right there.
(THROUGH MEGAPHONE)
Turn your vehicle off.
Drop the keys out of the window!
Open the door.
Step out of the vehicle. Hands in the air.
Keep them up! Hold it there.
Turn around.
Turn around. Fingers behind your head.
OFFICER 2: Hold it right there.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: Hey, that's Eazy.
MAN: Wazzup, E! I didn't know that was you.
EAZY E: Hey, wassup? Wassup, homie?
MAN: Hey. Yo, wuddup?
Nah. Hold up.
Hey, hey. Hold up. Relax, homie.
We in a club.
Cube, I just heard you was over here.
Yeah, I'm here. Whatchu need?
Everybody to calm the fuck down
from the looks of it.
I mean, I was just in
the neighborhood, man.
I came here with Bone Thugs.
I was just coming to say wassup.
Wassup?
I saw Boyz in the Hood. It was good.
You ain't called that shit
a after school special?
I like after school specials, Cube.
You know that.
(LAUGHS)
BOTH: What's up, man?
How you feel? You good?
Hell yeah, nigga, I'm good.
It's good to see you.
It's good to see you right now.
Look at you!
Pull your fuckin' homies off me then
if it's good to see me.
ICE CUBE: You had niggas jump us.
EAZY E: God damn!
How you go from selling rocks
in the dope house
to having dinner
in the White House with the President?
They still trying to figure that shit out.
(LAUGHS)
But, hey, all publicity...
BOTH: ...is good publicity.
You know it.
ICE CUBE: You know that's right.
EAZY E: Man.
Look, man, I wish that dumb shit
really would've never
popped off between us.
We shouldn't have
dissed each other in the first place.
Making the fans choose between us?
That wasn't cool.
You right.
You ever think we'd be that big, though?
Hell, no.
I was just talking to my wife about that.
How it was in the beginning.
Shit, we just wanted to do music
for the neighborhood.
Be ghetto stars.
But what if we had the chance
to find out how big we can really be?
Come on, man. You got my mind workin'.
EAZY E: I've been thinking
about that shit all the time.
If we could just take that shit back to '89.
We changed the world!
I hear you.
It was a simpler time, you know?
It was hard then.
But I've had days
where I almost wish
we was gettin' arrested in Detroit again.
- Shit. You know?
- (CHUCKLES)
Shit ain't gotta stop there.
But if we go do this,
we gotta do it right.
And if Dre with it, I'm with it.
But I don't know your
relationship with dude.
But if you want me, Eric,
Jerry can't be there.
All right.
(COUGHING)
Hey, man.
EAZY E: Shit!
ICE CUBE: It's 'cause you
ain't got them damn gloves on.
Man, whatever.
But I hear you.
Yeah?
Shit. Ar'ight.
TOMICA: These invoices haven't been paid.
They're two or three years outdated.
These are cancelled checks.
They all bounced.
And these are past due.
Jerry took advantage of you.
I know it's a lot,
but you had to know the truth sometime.
Now you do.
You know Dre and Cube
tried to warn me about this.
I've been fuckin' up for a long time.
Don't. Don't.
Real long time.
Shit.
JERRY: Hey, man.
Where you been?
I've been calling you all day.
Sit down, Jerry.
(SCOFFS)
What is this all about? The groupie?
The executive assistant?
She even go to college?
Man, you're so much fuckin'
smarter than this.
Sit down, Jerry.
This ain't about Tomica, Jerry.
It's about you.
And you can stop acting
like you ain't never done nothing wrong.
You know what, man?
I know that you're upset. I understand.
But I'm asking you,
I'm advising you, take a breath, okay?
I'm gonna look at the paperwork, Eric.
- You can stop giving me advice as of now.
- It's fucked up.
Here's what's about to happen.
I'mma get N.W.A back together,
and you ain't gonna have
nothing to do with it this time.
How the fuck can you even say
something like that?
What the fuck is going on with you, man?
I know what's good for you,
I know what's good for Ruthless...
And we have worked up a trust
after years of hard work,
and that trust is our foundation, Eric.
- I don't give a shit.
- (COUGHING)
Eric?
You look lousy, man. Are you okay?
Trust?
Trust is a motherfucker.
Is it?
Let me ask you something.
Eric, if what I'm doing is so illegal,
how come I've never been sued?
If I'm such a fuckin' thief,
such a liar, such a motherfucker,
how come nobody's ever come to collect?
Because this is business
and this is how it works.
And it's not always pretty. No.
Do I cover my own ass?
Do I cover my own end? Absolutely.
But don't you dare fuckin' tell me
that I have not taken care of you.
Don't you fuckin' tell me
that I have not had your back from day one!
Day one!
Is this taking care of me?
Are you fucking kidding me?
It's taking care of the
whole fucking thing.
It's business!
And this is how it works.
Have I covered my end?
Do I cover my ass? Absolutely.
But don't you dare fuckin' tell me
that I have not taken care of you.
This business, too?
Yes! This is business.
This is how fucked up it can get.
But I didn't start this.
I didn't fuck it up.
You did!
No.
You did.
(SCOFFS)
You fired, Jerry.
Oh, for Christ...
Eric, this is not how we do things.
This is not you.
Eric!
This is an important company.
Eric, I'm not gonna let you fuck this up.
Eric?
Oh, for Christ's sake!
Eric!
(LINE RINGING)
DR. DRE: Yeah, hello?
Wuddup, Dre?
- Who this?
-Eric.
E?
Just felt like calling.
Yeah. Okay.
What's up?
I mean, you know me, man. Doing my thing.
Killin' all this pussy.
(CHUCKLES)
How about you?
You know, man.
I'm just making tracks. Doing my thing.
Yeah, that Snoop joint you did was crazy.
That was dope.
Yeah? Thanks, E. Good looking out, man.
Look, Dre, I know you be busy,
but I talked to Cube and we were talking
about some possibilities.
Possibilities? Okay.
Yeah, like,
without Jerry Heller
type of fucking possibilities.
Really?
Well, it's about time.
Man, I mean, I know shit kinda went crazy.
You know, the money
kinda had everybody divided, man,
but I really wish it didn't.
To be honest, man,
I'm not proud of all the shit I did either.
So, whatchu think, man?
You think we could get together or what?
Whatchu think?
Yeah, man.
Yeah, that sound good.
Let's do it, E. Let's do it.
I'mma let you know when we can get back
into the studio, you know?
Lay down some tracks like the old days.
Fair enough.
A'ight.
It's good to hear from you, man.
(COUGHING)
Man, y'all niggas
ain't making no music in here.
Hey!
'Sup, E?
What up? What up? What up?
Yo, hey, when are Dre and Cube
gonna roll up in here, man?
- MC REN: Yeah, man.
- I'm ready!
MC REN: 'Cause I'm ready
to get this new shit going.
I'm ready, too.
But long as we stay ready,
we gonna know we go beyond, man.
You already know
this new N.W.A shit about to be crazy.
Here ya go, baby.
E, I got books of new shit.
I got libraries of new shit.
EAZY E: That's what I'm talking about, Ren.
That's what I'm talking about.
I got the tracks. You like that?
Hell yeah.
'Chu think you Dre now? (LAUGHING)
DJ YELLA: I'm trying to murder Dre.
I'm about to murder both of y'all
on the track, though. Check me out.
Check me out.
DJ YELLA: What you doing, E?
You know you don't play no instruments.
You gonna play it?
E, you all right?
TOMICA: Eric.
Baby, you good?
Yeah. I'm all right.
(TOMICA SCREAMS)
TOMICA: Eric! Eric!
MC REN: Call 911.
TOMICA: Eric! Baby?
MC REN: Eric. Get up, man.
TOMICA: Get him up.
MAN: Yo, call 911. Call 911.
MC REN: You all right, E?
TOMICA: Baby? Eric?
- MC REN: Eazy, wake up.
- Eric! Baby.
MC REN: Open your eyes.
DJ YELLA: Yes, we need an ambulance.
Wait... Ain't you gonna say something?
What is it? A respiratory infection?
Pneumonia? What?
Yes, well, um, it is those things,
and more, I'm afraid.
We ran a full blood battery, and, uh...
I'm sorry, Mr. Wright,
but you've tested positive for HIV.
Get the fuck outta here.
What?
A normal T-cell count
is anywhere between 500 and 1,500.
Right now, your T-cell count is 14.
But I ain't no faggot.
DOCTOR: Mr. Wright, actually,
the virus can be transmitted
in quite a few ways,
including unprotected heterosexual sex.
That's wrong.
You got to test that over. Test that again!
We've run the test five times
with five different samples
and the result remains the same.
- Shit!
- Tomica.
EAZY E: Tomica.
But she's pregnant, Doc. What's this mean?
It doesn't necessarily mean
that she's contracted the virus,
but we have to test her to be sure.
What do we do? When we start the treatment?
I mean, what... I gotta get healthy.
I got things to do. I got...
What am I supposed to do?
Mr. Wright, you need to understand
that you are very, very sick.
But I don't even feel that bad, Doc.
Don't tell me that.
DOCTOR: With care and palliative care,
we can probably keep you comfortable
for maybe six months, at the very most.
EAZY E: Comfortable?
What do you mean, comfortable?
It's just a matter of time.
I am truly, truly sorry, Mr. Wright.
I'll leave you time to process this.
Doc. Come on, Doc. No.
Doc.
Come on!
(SOBBING)
And one of the pioneers of gangster rap,
as the leader of the group N.W.A
has revealed he has AIDS...
WOMAN: We were totally unprepared
for the kind of outpouring
of fan calls that we had.
We had over 7,000 calls.
I can't.
- (COUGHING)
- Shh.
Just let me make this right.
Please.
'Cause you healthy, hmm?
- And the baby healthy.
- Yeah. We're healthy.
- So?
- Okay.
But I just...
I love you.
And I don't want none of this.
I just want you to be...
(SNIFFLES) Here.
(SOBBING)
MINISTER: Are we ready?
EAZY E: Yeah.
Tomica Woods, do you take Eric Wright
to be your lawfully wedded husband?
It's Bone Thugs' new LP, man.
Everybody thinks
it's gonna be cool when it drop.
- It's gonna be huge, man.
- That's great.
Do you wanna hear it, man?
You wanna hear it?
EAZY E: Nah, man.
Just leave it here for me.
I'll check it out later. Thanks.
This is bullshit, man.
Hey, Yella, why don't you check on him, man?
See if he ar'ight.
Ar'ight? I'll call you
when I get out of here.
Ar'ight?
WOMAN: What's his condition?
His condition... He's in intensive care.
We're not certain where it's headed.
'Sup, Eric?
It's Dre.
Man, I've been makin' some dope new tracks.
This next N.W.A album,
it's about to be dope.
It's about to be huge, you know?
Hey, you remember that time
when we was making Boyz-N-The Hood?
Your non-rappin' ass.
You was trippin' out, man.
(SOBBING)
I love you, E.
You hear me? I love you, man.
Dre.
Yo, Cube.
How is he doing? Can he talk? Can he...
Nah, man. He in a fuckin' coma.
Got the machines breathing
for him and shit.
He ain't even conscious.
I need to hear his voice, Dre.
I wanna talk to him.
I want him to talk to me.
I feel that.
It's all right, man.
It was good to see you, man.
You too.
Peace.
FEMALE REPORTER:
In Los Angeles this morning,
rapper Eazy-E has died
after a battle with AIDS.
MALE REPORTER: He was among the most
powerful voices of his generation.
NEWS ANCHOR: Towards the end
of his life, the rapper received
more than two and a half thousand calls
a day from well-wishers...
FEMALE ANCHOR:
...Member of the group N.W.A,
which helped popularize
harsh inner-city rap music.
Wright was 31.
DR. DRE: Eazy's gone.
He gone?
(SIGHS)
Shit.
- Okay.
-Okay.
(BEEPS)
Damn, E.
(INAUDIBLE)
RON SWEENEY:
Eazy wrote me a personal letter
to read to each and every one
of his fans and loved ones.
"I just feel that I've got
thousands and thousands of young fans
"that have to learn
about what's real when it comes to AIDS.
"I would like to turn my own problem
into something good
"that will reach out
to all my homeboys and their kin.
"Much love to those
who have been down for me
"and thanks for your support."
SUGE: Pac is in the
studio writing every day.
Snoop is doing his thing.
Whatcha all doing?
Y'all niggas are getting too comfortable.
- Handle this shit.
- Suge.
What's the urgency, Dre?
- (DOG GROWLS)
- Plotz.
I'm out.
I'm outta Death Row.
You ain't done.
Dr. Dre and Death Row are one and the same.
You just can't up and leave.
I'm doing my own thing, Suge.
Starting fresh.
Nobody to answer to but myself.
It's time.
You're one stupid motherfucker.
You gonna walk away from all this money?
If you leave,
everything we created is mine.
We? Okay.
You know what? You can have it.
You ain't taking nobody with you.
Death Row stays Death Row.
And you even think
about touching my money...
Motherfucker, you know how I gets down.
Do what the fuck you gotta do.
You can have the artists, the money,
the masters, all your fuckin' bullshit.
I'm done.
I'm starting my own thing.
You can't put a price on peace of mind.
I'm out.
I got all this nigga's money.
I got everything.
Get the fuck out. Go!
So whatchu gonna call that bullshit?
Aftermath.
DR. DRE: You are now about to witness
the strength of street knowledge.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
It's just, like,
they try to hide what's goin' on
and we tell it like it is, you know?
You know it's gotta be hard,
'cause if it ain't hard, it's weak.
MC Ren in the house.
When you making a record,
you gotta have some hype lyrics.
And you got that, it's gonna sell.
Eazy-E probably was one of the nicest
people you ever would have known.
Not as Eazy, but as Eric Wright.
DR. DRE: We make our records based on
stuff that's happening where we live.
And if people out there
that don't like it, fuck 'em.
Dre and Eazy, they had already
been selling it as cassette tapes.
And they just blew up.
Eazy and Dr. Dre Wild and Wet Pool Party.
This is what it's all about!
We wanted to invite you
to the President's luncheon.
I said if I go down there,
this'll start some shit.
KENDRICK: When I think of N.W.A,
they weren't really music to me.
It was more like a real lifestyle.
Brothers from my neighborhood made it out.
- You got the dopest album out this year.
- Thanks, man.
More than happy to get my career
going like I want it to go.
BOTH: Damn!
You do not know
how long I waited to get in his booth
and to have Dre out there goin',
"You ready?"
I waited all my life for that,
since Straight Outta Compton.
Dre's direction was helping me
become a strong lyricist, which I am now.
EMINEM: Dre has taught me a lot.
Not just rap-wise, but business-wise,
you know what I'm sayin'?
50 CENT: You'd have to even credit
both Eminem's and my success'
to Dr. Dre.
MAN: Apple's purchase of Beats
will be the biggest deal in its history.
ICE CUBE: Our music was like our weapon.
DR. DRE: We let people know that it's okay
to say whatchu wanna say.