After twenty days of continuous bombing,
Nanking finally fell to the Japanese.
It was December the 13th, 1937.
I remember
everyone was running that day,
but no one could escape that heavy fog.
Major Li only had a few men left.
Nanking was no longer
able to put up a fight,
and those left behind, ran for their lives.
Stop counting.
Shu and two others are missing.
Let us in!
There's no room!
Find your own place to hide!
I said there's no more room!
Let's go.
Keep going!
Hey.
There are people inside.
Who is there?
Come out!
Bastards!
Go to hell!
Stop!
Turn around!
Don't move!
American.
From the refuge.
What?
American.
Not soldier.
John Miller.
Raise your hands!
Working at the church.
I said raise your hands!
Separated...
You separated from your families?
You...
families...
separated?
I'm...
going to...
Winchester Cathedral.
You know where it is?
Where?
Mister.
Did you say...
Did you say "mister?"
Who said "mister?"
You speak English?
We are from Winchester Cathedral.
Say that again.
You're kidding?
We are students at the convent.
You going there?
Why do you want to go there?
I'm helping to bury your father.
Well, not your father father...
Father Ingleman.
Father Ingleman, yeah.
I'm helping burying him.
Father Ingleman, I'm sending him off...
to heaven or wherever.
You show me the way?
Peng,
move to the flank,
prepare to engage.
Damn it, are you deaf?
Major Li,
we are the last ones left.
We should leave the city now.
Keep fighting.
Yes sir.
Got you!
Let's go.
Yes sir.
That way!
Up there, on the right!
On the left! Fire!
Cover them!
The Chinese army didn't
have adequate weapons
to destroy the enemy's tanks,
so they employed a tactic
from ancient warfare.
They formed a human shield
to get a bomb close to the tanks.
At the time, the Chinese people
couldn't bear the thought
of their country,
and such selfless acts were not uncommon.
Zhen!
Let me go!
Come on!
Father Ingleman...
fly away.
Fly away?
On here, Japanese, bomb.
- He flew away with the bomb, right.
- Yes.
Why was the deceased out here?
- Gu. All because of Gu.
- Gu?
He said, bad smell.
He moved the body here.
Who's Gu?
Gu is our cook.
He ran away.
He leaves some students here.
Some students took away by parents.
Some students nowhere to go.
So who's inside?
Just you and the girls?
Just you and the girls.
Even without a body,
you gotta pay me.
No.
No... You gotta pay me.
That's the rule.
There's nothing I can do about it.
With what I came through,
I should raise the price.
So is the money inside?
No. No money.
Money? Inside?
No.
Come on.
There's no money inside?
No.
Let's look.
It's a Catholic church.
There's gotta be some cash inside.
No.
No?
You say anything but no?
Can you fix truck?
Help us.
Leave Nanking.
Fix this truck?
For free?
No.
I can take parts, sell parts.
You got tools?
No.
Let's get inside.
Zhen didn't even make a noise.
Even when they stabbed her over and over,
yet she didn't make a noise.
It's all my fault.
It's not your fault.
It is your fault.
Your father promised to take us
on a boat and leave Nanking.
Where is he?
He ran off.
We waited and waited
and now the Japanese are here.
Now the Japanese are everywhere,
and it's too late to go to the refuge.
Zhen died because of your father!
Shut up!
What are you doing?
Stop!
Stop fighting!
Hey.
Hey! Stop!
Stop!
I'm John. Hi.
I'm American.
He's the mortician for Father's funeral.
I know it's hard.
But you've gotta stop fighting everybody.
You know you two... you've seen enough...
seen enough tragedy for a lifetime today.
I can't... um...
I'm not good with kids.
Let's go.
You want some flour?
You like some flour?
- Make some bread for the girls.
- Buns.
Buns.
Buns, whatever.
Let's go find the collection box.
Where?
- Upstairs?
- No.
Oh, nice.
Forget going back to the refuge,
I think I'm bunking here tonight.
He's grim, who's that?
Is that Father Ingleman?
Yes.
These North Europeans they're all like,
you know, tuna, playwrights,
not much fun.
Look at that face,
he's ruining the...
What do you call it? Feng... Fengshui?
I can't have a priest staring at me
- while I'm sleeping.
- No...
My father.
Me...
orphan...
adopted.
I'm sorry.
But I just...
It's not good for me to have a priest
staring at me while I'm sleeping.
I can't.
Please, I gotta just... there, better.
You got any drink around here?
No.
You're a church.
You got wine, something?
Nothing.
Nothing?
- No.
- No, no...
That's a shaving kit.
What a jerk!
I said you are a jerk!
What did you say your name was?
George Chen.
George.
Tomorrow,
you fix truck,
help us.
Fix truck?
No money!
Money, George.
Gu.
Open the door, it's Ling.
Can you hear me
Gu.
Open up.
It's Ling.
Did you really make a deal with him?
Of course.
Otherwise I wouldn't
have brought you here.
Gu.
Open the door, it's Ling.
Gu, have you gone deaf?
Someone's here.
Where's Gu? Ask him to come out.
Go to the refuge on the west side.
Leave now, go to the refuge.
No, we're here for Gu.
Gu's not here.
Bullshit! Get out of my way!
Gu told me,
this church is under Western protection.
The Japanese can't come in.
Bastard! I served Gu all night for free,
he promised to let us stay.
Ask that bastard Gu to come out!
He's really not here.
How come?
He ran off this morning.
You should go to the refuge.
We're not leaving.
Hey! How dare you!
Hurry.
Go to the refuge!
To the refuge!
The refuge doesn't even
have space left for maggots.
Please, have some mercy and let us in.
Don't jump.
They're from the red-light district.
What's that?
It means brothel.
They were the famous
women of the Qin Huai River.
The myths surrounding them
were as ancient as the city of Nanking.
That's a Westerner!
Is he a priest?
No way.
What kind of priest would be such a flirt?
Who cares,
as long as he can protect us.
True.
Come up here.
This was stolen from the bowels of hell.
Long time not make bread.
Long time not make bread? No bread?
Not tonight, tonight we're having bread.
These women quickly took over the cellar.
It was once a filthy, messy place,
but within hours,
they had transformed it
into the Qin Huai River.
The fragrance of rouge and perfume
danced up through the air.
I can smell the bread.
We are coming up!
I couldn't stop them.
Hello.
I remember
when I first saw these women,
they were tramps,
parading around in their lingerie,
not the graceful ladies
that the legends of Qin Huai
had portrayed them to be.
Look, this should be good.
George,
you little shit,
you said there was no wine here.
Excuse me.
What's he saying?
Holy hooch!
How dare you drink the wine!
Now the Westerner Knows about the wine.
We sell the wine to raise
money for orphans.
We're all orphans.
We also need help.
That's right.
What are they saying?
They said they're orphans!
Orphans?
Well, I'd like to adopt all of you,
right now.
Adopt all of us?
You would not be able to cope.
You are not the only
ones who speak English!
That's right!
You speak English?
The Westerner is a playboy.
Of course! Haven't you heard?
Westerners with beards are the horniest!
No wonder she is
the top girl of the Qin Huai River.
Mo, use all of your skills.
Seduce him!
That's right.
Make the big nose go crazy for us!
My name is John.
And you are?
Yu Mo.
I like that.
So what do you and your companions do?
We are kindergarten teachers.
Really? Kindergarten teachers.
Shameless.
And you?
What do you do?
I'm also a kindergarten teacher.
So as,
teacher to teacher,
you wanna...
get together and have a cup of joe, or...
What're those two yapping about?
Tell me.
Nothing. He's asking your price.
I told him.
He thinks you are too cheap.
There's no coffee.
Let's get liquored up.
Cheers.
The kindergarten fee is enough?
You coming?
I want you to take us out of Nanking.
Yeah.
Right.
We do this first?
I'm serious.
Why else you think we
were flirting with you?
Out of Nanking, how?
I don't know how,
but I know your face is
the way out of here.
The Japanese won't touch Westerners.
Did you see it out there?
That's not happening.
No.
Cash enough?
Cause... let's...
Are you kidding?
Wait...
Let's work this out. Let's work it out.
Think about it.
If you help us,
I will thank you in ways
you can never imagine.
All of us will.
Can I get an advance?
The Japanese have posted a notice,
whoever harbors soldiers will be shot.
I'll shoot you first.
Little bastard.
Open up. Carry that guy in.
Get up.
Get some water.
Hurry up!
What a temper.
He thinks he's so tough.
He thinks he's a hero.
Since he's fighting the Japanese,
protecting Nanking and women like us,
he feels he is entitled to have a temper.
Women like us need to hide here.
But if he hides here, he's a coward.
True.
Yeah, what a sissy!
Got scissors?
Thanks.
- You ruined my dress!
- Don't touch him!
Save your attitude for the Japs.
They are searching for
Chinese soldiers like you.
You are endangering us!
There are convent girls here, too.
Understand?
Towel.
What a handsome face.
Dou has good taste in men.
I mean he looks like my brother.
Are you hot for him?
No, he really looks like my brother.
You have a crush on him.
No, I don't.
Dou, cool off.
He doesn't even have hair down there!
He was homeless, so our troop took him in.
He's called Pu Sheng.
He's just a child.
Why are you leaving him with us?
Get some cloth,
tighten the bandage
so he won't bleed too much.
It's the best I can do.
I want him to be in a warm place
before he dies.
Thank you.
Please wait.
What do you want?
We have sharp tongues,
and we were very rude.
I hope you can forgive us.
Don't point a gun at a man of the cloth.
Mo.
Like me as a priest? Do you?
I dressed up for you.
I got a chance now?
Is he the priest?
Does he belong to the church?
You can say that.
What, the bank's closed
for me, but he gets...
He gets a special soldier
discount or something?
Please tell him,
the students can't end up
in the hands of the Japanese.
Otherwise my men would have died
for nothing.
What's wrong with you?
I want to help you.
I've joined the priesthood.
Stop it. It's not the right time.
You don't want cash.
You want me to save you.
I'm gonna save your soul.
I'll absolve you of your sins tonight.
Blessed are thee among women.
Blessed are thy lips,
blessed are thy eyes,
blessed are thy hips...
Don't.
and thy gams, and thy chest...
Stop it!
- Stop it!
- I gotta...
Stop it!
You drunk bastard!
This is a house of love not war,
you get out of here.
Who's he really?
An idiot. Don't mind him.
Fine, I'll leave now.
See,
I'm the only man for you.
You're such a fool!
If it wasn't for your foreign face...
I like it when you're angry.
I wouldn't even look at you!
Harder.
I'll never be into you.
Come here.
Get off me!
I love that!
I love seeing you walk away.
I love seeing that ass.
Mo!
That night,
Major Li didn't go far.
He stayed at the paper
shop across the street.
I know,
he could have changed into
civilian clothing and fled.
I said you can't go in!
Little sister,
we won't shit or piss in there.
We just want to wash up.
We always wash before bed-time.
Bed-time?
Morning for you is night for us.
Little sister...
Don't call me sister!
You want to start a fight?
The bathroom is for people.
You mean we are not people?
You know what you are!
You've got some nerve!
We won't share the bathroom with you!
What a temper!
Sorry, go back to your rat hole.
What the hell?
She's humiliating us.
She thinks we are filthy.
Little bitch!
You're the bitch!
Watch your mouth!
Ling, want to see a good fight?
Really?
I thought you'd only fight for Mo.
Let's pull down your pants
and see what you are made of.
Don't touch me, you filthy whore!
Let's find out if you really
are cleaner than us.
Stop it! It's not fair!
I don't have to hit you,
I can just crush you with my butt!
I don't give a damn, I'm going in.
I won't let you go in!
Stop fighting!
What's going on?
Stop!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
We are just kids!
Hua, that's enough.
No, it's not over!
I won't let you go in!
Japanese!
Go to the cellar, I'll tell the others!
Search the yard!
Split up!
Hurry! Go to the cellar!
Come in, hurry!
Don't shut it, let the girls in.
Let the girls in!
Hurry!
Don't move!
Lieutenant Asakura!
Come over here!
Upstairs!
Hurry!
Let's move the shelves!
There are girls here!
Search everywhere!
Capture them alive!
Lieutenant Asakura!
Come up here!
We've got virgins!
Hurry!
Stop!
Girls! Girls!
This is a house of the Lord!
These are children!
You are breaking the laws
of man and of God!
No soldiers here!
You have no business being here!
I am the priest!
And I command you,
in the name of the Father to leave now!
Girls, you come up here now!
Come up these stairs,
and stand behind me.
You're honorable men,
behave honorably!
I'll eat you up.
Stop! Stop this! Stop! Run!
Stop this! Don't...
Chinese soldiers!
Get them!
Let's go!
Assemble outside! Roll call!
Prepare for combat!
The sniper is across the street!
To your left!
It's a trap! Find the enemy!
Damn it!
He's in the building there!
Use the grenades!
Behind us! Fire!
Keep firing!
Hold your fire!
Wait!
Fire!
First platoon to the back gate!
Second platoon to the front gate!
Colonel,
he used to work for the
traffic department.
Most roads in Nanking are destroyed.
Having him can be useful.
Speak Japanese?
Yes.
Were our soldiers here recently?
Are you the resident priest?
Yes.
Father,
I apologize on behalf of our soldiers.
Please understand.
In the middle of a war,
occasional unfortunate
behavior is inevitable.
Your church
is very beautiful.
How do you do?
Are you students here at the convent?
So sorry to have caused you alarm.
Please...
don't hurt the children anymore.
Naturally.
My name is Hasegawa.
I am responsible for
the safety of this area.
Please do not worry...
about the security of the church
and the students.
I apologize...
but I have no confidence...
in that assurance.
My guarantee is effective.
From now on,
I shall post armed guards
in front of the church
to protect you all.
There is not a lot of food
in Nanking at the moment.
I hope the students will not go hungry.
May I?
Thank you.
Did you like it?
This is a Japanese folk song,
"My Home."
It is about hills and rabbits,
and streams full of fish.
It is the most beautiful song in the world
for those who are homesick.
Do the students sing well?
Very well, yes.
That's good.
I shall come back
in a couple of days to hear them.
Why?
No reason.
I happen to love music.
Father, we shall meet again soon.
I hope you will not be
lonely buried together.
Father John.
You won't leave us, will you?
We shouldn't have taken over your cellar.
Sorry.
If we hadn't fought with that girl,
she would still be alive.
This is all our fault.
Thank you.
Why not answer Shu?
She called me Father John.
We all need you.
I'm a mortician.
You are priest.
No.
- If we have a priest...
- George.
maybe Japanese...
not dare...
You are priest!
George, I'm not.
I'm not a priest.
I'm not!
I stayed here,
because I was looking for your cash.
And because that's the nicest bed that
I've slept in in years. I didn't get there.
But is that like a priest? I'm not a priest!
I'm not.
I took catechism lessons as a kid.
Sometimes I remember that when I'm drunk,
which I am as often as I can be.
You not be priest.
Tell girls yourself.
You little shit!
You are.
We've heard about what happen today.
So you're staying?
Yeah.
Even though you were
a drunk bastard last night,
what you did today makes you a hero.
I'm sorry about last night.
Yeah.
I can't leave them by themselves.
And that little shit
has a way of just... you know.
What do you think the Japanese are up to?
Are they really here to
protect the students?
We were counting on having you
help us leave Nanking.
But I guess now you'll have to
stay here and be a priest.
Yeah, right.
Priest.
Actually, I came to tell you,
our offer is still good.
We still want you to help us escape.
As soon as the Japanese guards are gone.
Just now the ladies were having a bet.
They said that hero or no hero,
you don't stand a chance
when you're up against a beauty like me.
Don't flatter yourself.
We'll see.
Did you like it?
I only have one string.
It sound like a beggar's plea. Even worse.