- What kind is it?
- I dont know. - White?
- And the frame?
- Dark.
- Postmark?
- Same as last time.
- No note.
- No.
Im so sorry, Henrik.
Subtitle by d3xt3r
www.addic7ed.com
THE GIRL WITH
THE DRAGON TATTOO
What is this?
The media event of the year?
Dont try to play it down, Mikael,
it wont work.
Dont try to play it up,
that wont either.
Will you appeal?
Yes, Ill appeal to  you , Viggo.
Up until today,
Mr. Blomkvist was able to play the victim.
"The great journalist
stood up against the lion."
If you call a guy 'Criminal',
and nothing to back it up.
Mr.Blomkvist likes publicity.
Can I get the sandwich.
And a black coffee.
Blomkvist claimed Wennerstrom -
founder and president of The Wennerstrom Group -
used State funds
intended for industrial development
in Poland
in an arms deal
- with the right-wing Ustashe in Croatia.
- Thank you.
I have nothing against Mr.Blomkvist.
Hes a fine journalist.
who I dont believe is guided by malice.
But what he wrote was
inaccurate,
and inaccuracies cant go
unanswered.
All journalists -
have to accept like the rest of us,
actions have consequences.
Blomkvist was ordered to pay 600
thousand SKE in damages
- and all court costs,
which could be significantly more.
And a lighter.
- Where you been?
- Walking.
-   Thinking.
- Smoking?
- Just one.
TV4 called.
I told them no  statement until
weve read the judgment in its entirety.
I have.
Anyone else?
Everyone whos ever wanted
to see you humiliated.
Youve been on the phone all morning.
- Im as much to blame for this as you.
- You are?
-   You wrote it?
- I read it.  I ran it.
Not the same.
- Our credibility isnt dead, yet.
- Mine is.
Im tired.
I'm gonna go home,
crawl under the duvet for a week.
I already called Greger and tell him
I'm not coming home.
Thank you.
Its possible we could wait forever.
You called her and spoke to her.
Didn't you?
Im afraid that doesnt mean much.
No one here particularly likes her.
I find its much better
if she works from home.
But you told her
I wanted to meet her.
But Ive told her many more times I
prefer her not to meet clients.
- But you  like her.
- Very much.
Shes one of the best investigators I have.
-  As you saw from her report -
- But....
Im concerned you  wont like her.
- Shes different.
- In what way?
In every way.
Ms. Salanders here.
Lisbeth,
Mr. Dirch Frode.
How do you do?
- Something wrong with the report?
- No.It was quite thorough.
But Im also interested in
whats not in it.
- Theres nothing not in it.
- Your opinion of him isnt.
Im not paid to give my opinion.
So you dont have one?
Hes clean.
In my opinion.
You mean, he is hygenic?
Hes who he presents
himself to be.
In his business,
thats an asset.
Theres less in his asset column
after his conviction today.
True.  He made a fool of himself.
If it happened that way.
Are you saying he was set up?
That wasnt part of my assignment.
Youre quite right...
he made a fool of himself..
professionally.
How much of a fool can
he make of himself financially?
The judgement will just about
empty his savings.
- May I go?
- A moment.
Your report is light
in another area.
His personal life.
Anything you chose not to disclose?
- Nothing that warranted inclusion.
- Does that means "yes" or  "no"?
I think what Ms. Salander means, and
I agree, is that everyone has a right
to a certain amount of privacy,
- even if theyre being investigated.
- Not in this case.
I need to know if theres anything about him
I might find unsavory -
even if she doesnt.
Hes had a long sexual relationship
with his co-editor of the megazine.
It wrecked his marriage,
but not hers.
Sometimes he performs Cunnilingus.
Not often enough,
In my opinion.
You were right not to include that.
I know.
You needed a better attorney.
You needed your sister.
She offered.
- He declined.
- As she hoped.
Never a good idea mixing
family and business.
And I still would have lost, anyway.
It wasnt even about Mikael.
It   was Wennerstrom sending
a message to the press
- and the FSA saying:
Dont ask questions.
Cheer up.
- Dad.
- Nilla.
You dont have to
worry about me.
- Moms worried.
- About me?
About the money.
Nilla?  What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Is it serious?
I dont want to talk about it since
I know you wont approve.
Of -
Nilla...
- Light of Life.
- Light of- what?
- Hello.
- Mr. Blomkvist?
Forgive me for intruding on your
Christmas.
My name is Dirch Frode.
Im an attorney.
I represent Henrik
Vanger.  Perhaps youve heard of him?
Yes, yes. Of course.
Hed like to speak to you
about a private matter.
This is..uh..
an awkward moment---
Im sorry.  Im about to sit down to
Christmas dinner myself.
No, thats not exactly what I mean.
Youre referring to your recent
legal problems.
That has  provided us with much ammusement.
Herr Vanger has little love
for Wennerstrom either.
Have him call me.
But, hed like to meet in person,
If possible.
Up north.  In Hedestad.
That's not gonna be possible.
Herr Vanger is far too old to make a trip to
Stockholm,
Please.
If youd be so kind as to consider.
Hedestad is lovely in winter.
I'll call you back on this number.
Okay?
Usually when I wake up in a cold
bed, its at home.
- I'm Sorry.
- What are you doing?
Writing the press release.
Saying...
Youre taking over as publisher.
Youre sorry for any nuisance
Wennerstrom was caused.
I cant be
reached for comment.
- Are you giving up?
- Just stepping aside.
This makes me sick.
- FRODE: First time in Hedestad?
- And the last.
Oh, don't say that.
Its lovely in the spring.
You said it was lovely
in winter.
Well, this is unseasonable.
Ill be on the 4:30 train back to
Stockholm.
Unless we get snowed in ...
Im joking.
Youll be home tonight,
if thats what you wish.
Welcome.  Come inside.
Its warm.
How do you do?
So...
What do you know about me?
That you used to run one of the
biggest industrial firms in the country.
- Used to.  Thats correct.
- Right, I didn't mean to...
My grandfather forged the tracks
the 4:30 train will take you home.
We stitched this country together.
We made the steel--
and milled the lumber that built
modern Sweden.
And what our most profitable
product now is?
Fertilizer.
Im not obsessed with the declining
health of the company,
but I am with
the settling of accounts -
and the clock is ticking.
I need your help.
Doing..doing what?
Officially, assisting me with my memoirs.
But what youd really be doing..
is solving a mystery.  And
by doing what you do so well -
Your recent legal mishap of
yours notwithstanding.
Youd be investigating
thieves, misers, bullies,
- the most detestable collection
of people youll ever meet ...
my family.
Would you like to sit?  I could
possibly clear a place if necessary.
- Did you make it?
- Have you something for me?
Im on welfare;
I dont administer it.
This isnt enough.
No thank you?
This is Harriet.  The grandaughter
of my brother Richard.
Richard, was a
Nazi of the first order -
joining the
- Nationalist Socialist Freedom League
when he was 17.
Isnt it interesting how fascists
always steal the word freedom "freedom".
The 4:30.  Yes.
Okay...
Anyway, Richard died a martyr to the Nazi
cause -
in 1940, missed all  the real
excitement -
but not the opportunity
to regularly beat his wife Margareta..
and their son, Gottfried.
Now, Gottfried - Harriets father -
was what people used to call
-  a Good-Time-Charlie.
- Theyre still called that.
Are they?  Okay.
He was a charmer, a ladies man,
a drunk.
In other words, a born salesman -
which is what he did for the company -
traveling around, taking clients
out to dinner and so forth.
- Well, Somebody has to do it.
- Thats right.
Anyway, he died in 1965.
Drowned.  Drunk.
Here on theisland.
His wife Isabella - who was pretty
much useless as a parent before  -
became even more so after his death -
which is when I began looking after
their children -
Martin - who runs Vanger Industries
now that Im retired -
- I've been with him.
- and Harriet.
She was bright and curious,
a  winning combination in any person.
- And beautiful.
- Yeah.
Something happened to her?
Someone in the family
murdered Harriet.
And for the last forty years
has been trying to drive me insane.
It was September 24th, 1966.
A Saturday.
Harriet was 16.
My brothers - along with their
wives, children and grandchildren -
had gathered here
for our loathsome
annual board meeting and dinner.
It was also the day the Yacht Club held
its Autumn parade.
Harriet and a couple of school
friends had gone into town to see it.
She returned a
little after two oclock.
She came to the parlor.
She asked if she could talk to me.
I honestly
dont remember what I was doing
that I thought was more important, but I
told her to give me a few minutes.
It was during those few minutes,
that something else occurred.
The accident had
nothing to do with Harriet -
and yet, everything.
It was chaos as everyone put down
what they were doing.
Police, an ambulance,
fire brigade,
reporter, photographer and onlookers
quickly arrived from town,
just as those of us on the island - the family -
hurried to the bridge from our side.
The driver of the car -
a man named Aronsson -
was pinned and severely injured.
We tried desperately to pry him out
with our hands - since metal tools could spark.
It was an hour after the crash,
Harriet was in the kitchen.
Anna herself saw her.
We finally got poor
Aronsson out of his car
and off to the hospital,
Just us we from our side
slowly drifted back to the house.
The sun was down,
the excitement over,
we sat down to dinner.
It was then, that
I noticed Harriet wasnt there.
And she wasnt there the next
morning.  Or the next.
Or the next forty years.
What was she going to tell me?  Why
didnt I make time for her?
Why didnt I listen?
- And she couldnt have run away?
- Not without being seen.
Firemen stayed
on the bridge all night
pumping out the gasoline.
And no one swam across,
or took a row boat.
All of them were still tied up
on this side Sunday.
Believe me,
I checked.
She couldnt have just
fallen and drowned?
Oh, no. The currents
arent strong here.
Anything that falls into the water
turns up nearby.
Like her father.
His body didnt drift more
than ten meters
when he drowned
the year before.
No. No. Someone killed her,
Someone on the island
that day.
Someone close enough to know
what she used to give me each year
on my birthday.
Those were from her.
The rest...from her killer.
- Who knows about these?
- Just me, the police, the killer...
and now you.
After, the police investigation evaporated,
I kept at it -
studying all the information there was,
Ive spent half my life
examining the events of a single day.
I understand your frustration, But...
what youre asking me to do is
a waste of money
We havent discussed your fee.
We dont need to.
Thank you.
I cant find something you havent
been able to  in forty years.
You dont know that.
You have a
very keen investigative mind.
Heres what I propose:
You come stay on the island. I have a nice little
cottage by the water you can use.
You study the material I give you.
You find something Ive missed- or you dont.
What you're asking me to do
is set aside my life and career....
Think of it as a well
deserved holiday.
A way of avoiding all the
people you want to avoid right now.
As for compensation, Ill pay you double
your salary for as many months as it takes.
Ill quadruple it if
you solve the mystery.
- Herr Vanger.
- Im not done.
Ill throw in one  more thing -
even though youre a
terrible negotiator.
Its something you want more than anything else
and it cant be bought at any price.
So, let me give it to you ...
Hans-Erik Wennerstrom.
He began his career working for me.
And Ive followed it with interest,
shall we say, ever since.
You were right about him.
You just couldnt prove it.
Were in the middle of our worst crisis ever
and youre writing a memoir?
You fired me;
I need something to do.
You fired you;
I need you here,
not the North Pole.
Mikael, You know what this
is going to look like.
Like Ive been gutted.  Like Im
running away.  I am.
Wennerstrm wants to see me waving
a white flag, not a red one.
The more it looks like theres a problem
between you and me, the more itll satisfy him.
There is a problem between us.  He
wont be satisfied until he shuts us down,
Youre leaving me to fight him alone?
Its four hours by train.
Its not the North Pole.
Hey, hey.
The network is busy,
please try again later.
What?
Want some Milk?
The network is busy,
please try again later.
You are Palmgren's daughter?
His ward,
He doesn't have a daughter.
Please.
He's had a severe
cerebral hemorrhaging.
Either from the fall itself,
or a stroke that led to the fall.
His blood pressure is too high.
Im hopeful hell regain consciousness,
but thats not assured.
And its possible, even if he does,
there will be
neurological damage.
Hi, Im Gunner.
The caretaker.
Oh, hey, Gunnar.
Youre an author?
Well, I'm doing a biography
on Herr Vanger.
- I saw you on television.
- Thats unfortunate.
Bit of trouble, I guess.
No jail time, though.
Thats good.
Cost you a lot of money though, yeah?
There.
It's good.
The entire island is
owned by my family.
Your closest neighbor is
my brother
Harald, another Nazi if you can believe.
Two  in the family.
Oh, yes. Hes quite detestable
to put it nicely,
but youll probably never see him.
Hes a recluse.
- He was there that day?
- Indeed, he was.
His daughter, Cecilia,
lives over there.
They dont speak.
Does anyone speak to
anyone on this island?
Isabella, Harriets mother
- who lives there - she speaks to Harald -
which is one of reasons
I dont speak to her
Cecilias brother Birger
lives there.
- Who doesnt he speak to?
- You, probably.
Not that youd want him to.
He can be as unpleasant as Harald.
Im quickly losing
track of whos who, here.
Oh, how youll wish
it were always so.
Soon youll know us all only too
well - with my apologies.
Out there is my nephew Martins
house; Harriets brother.
- Who speaks to him?
- I speak to him.
He runs the company
now, as I think I told you.
Someone shooting their dinner.
Gunner probably.
Oh yes, I met him earlier.
He was 19 when
Harriet disappeared.
He lives over there.
- And you live there?
- Sorry?
Your house.
Oh, yes!
Yes, youre right.
The man who  hires the detective should
always bekept on the suspects list.
DET. MORELL: The fact that
I never found a body  was not surprising.
You cant dig  up an entire island.
But neither could I find the motive.
Was it spontaneous? Was it calculated?
Did she know something someone
wished she didnt?
-  Was it about business?
- Business?  But she was sixteen.
And very bright.
Henrik told me he could easily see her
running the business one day,
She was with some friends that day.
At a parade.
She told them she was  feeling unwell.
She left early
But they also told me
she kept secrets from them, too.
The main thing I learned was that
teenage girls are complicated.
- I have one.
- Then, you know.
I wanted to...
Ask you about this.
She received that from Henrik,
the Christmas before.
I studied it more times
than I can say.
-  I know every page of it.
- The last page Im curious about.
As was I.
List of Names, Numbers and..
Must have some significance.
Theyre local phone numbers.
The first belonged to a woman
called Margot,
whose mother was Magda,
who denied she didnt know Harriet.
The fourth, R.L., belonged to
Rosemarie Larsson,
an elderly woman who died
some years before.
The other three were not connected
in any way that I could find.
Ive reminded you of things youd
rather forget.  Im sorry.
I cant forget it.
Its my "Rebecka Case".
I don't know what that is.
Every policeman has at least
one unsolved case to obsess over.
Back then we had an Officer,
Torstensson.
Year after year he kept
going back to his "Rebecka Case".
taking out the files -
studying them over and over.
We were young, we laughed at him.
That was also a missing girl case?
No, no, no. Thats not why I mention it.
I'm talking about the soul
of a policeman.
Poor old Torstensson never solved it,
and he never let it go.
Hows Mr. Palmgren doing?
I heard he had a stroke of some kind?
That's Terrible.
What exactly do you do at this
security company?
Make coffee and sort mail.
But not full-time.
Not even part-time consistently.
They somehow got
along without coffee or mail
in July and August?
- How much did you made there?
- Enough.
- How much is your rent?
- I pay my rent.
And when was the last time you were late?
Never.
Do you think that ring in your eyelid
makes you attractive?
Heres the problem.
There a discrepancy..
between the obligation of
Mr. Palmgrens guardianship
and the management of your finances.
There's no discrepancy or a problem.
It was clear to him
I could manage myown finances.
- But thats not clear to me.
- Im not a child.
No.  Youre not.
But you were.
And between then and now -
you're committed to a ward at  St. Stephens,
where you continued to display
a violent aggression -
And you failed to adapt to four foster homes
arrested twice for intoxication,
twice for narcotics
again for an assault: smashing
a bottle smashed into a mans face.
And that's not even that long ago.
You may have conned Mr. Palmgren into
thinking youve changed, but
looking at this...
- not to mention how youre looking
at me now -
I don't think you have.
So the Good
-Old-Mr-Palmgren-Days are over.
Starting now, youll be given a monthly allowance.
Youll provide me with receipts for your expenses.
If the numbers dont balance, Ill
have to assume the difference is going to drugs.
Ive been on myself
since I was ten.
The State- has taken care of you.
Ms. Salander?  Please look at me.
Because this is important.
Since, behavior youre displaying
right now is elaborately documented here -
- so it would come as a shock to no
one if I chose an alternative to
very lenient arrangement
I've just outlined.
Would you prefer
institutionalization?
- Mikael?
- Yes.
- I'm Liv.
- Hi.
Were going to the same place.
Hop in.
Okay, thank you.
I found him at deaths door
halfway up the hill.
Im afraid Im a bit out of shape.
No, its a climb for anyone.
I shouldve warned you.
- Come on in.
- Thank you, Martin.
Henrik says great things about you.
What a place,
look at that view!
I used to work in the companys
petrochemical division in Goteborg.
When it was sold, I went with it.
A dark day.
I live in Hong Kong now, but come
back to Stockholm for family events,
and when I do, I drive up to spend a
couple days with Martin.
- She comes for the moose steak.
- You can't blame her, it's wonderful.
Something let's open.
Would you like to try something
else?
No, no, no.
It's fine.
Youre writing a book now,
What is it?
- Henriks biography.
- I love Henrik.
Hes fascinating.
Martin, too.
Together theyre the
Old Sweden and the New.
They are.
You know about Harriet, right?
- You dont?
- Yes, I do.
The family doesnt like
to talk about it,
but it cant just be
swept under the rug.
- What cant.
- Harriet.
- We can talk about that  later.
- No.
We can talk about it now.
Liv knows everything about
my crazyfamily.
-  Which is why shell never marry me.
- Thats one reason...
I don't wanna read about that
in the book.
Everything else is fine,
Harriet certainly.
Everything changed after that.
Not just the family,
but the company as well.
- How so?
- Were not Nordea or Ericsson,
but were still the largest family-owned
company in the country.
At the height, we had 40,000 employees.
We have about half that now,
and that downward slide -
began after my sisters death.
It broke Henriks entrepreneurial spirit,
and his heart.
You were here that day?
I came in a little late, after the accident
on the bridge. The 4:30 train.
I know it well.
It was a terrible day.
And the days after -
searching and not finding her
- were even worse.
This event, Mikael, has to be a
big part of your book.
I got a call from social welfare.
Ive been on to find a new guardian.
- Hi.
- Hello.
I thought Id come over
and say hello.
-   Im Cecilia.
- Oh, yeah. Please, come in.
Some coffee?
No, Thank you.
Were all uncomfortable with the
idea of a chronicle of our family.
Its not about the family.
Its about Henrik and the company.
Like I said...
Its not my intention to present a
malicious portrait of anyone.
Unlike the one
that landed you in court.?
Unlike that one. Yes.
So, what youre saying is, youre not really here
to look into what happened to Harriet?
I cant ignore such
a dramatic event,
but no, thats not
by any means my focus.
All those boxes Gunner carted  down here
- which are where? - in the closet now?
- those werent Henriks
private investigation?
I wonder sometimes whos crazier -
my Nazi father
or my obsessed uncle.
Since were talking about it,
since you brought it up, what was she like?
Im sure Henrik has told you.
He was my age back then, he couldnt know
what was going on
with a teenager,
anymore than I can with my own daughter.
-  You were the same age.
- Actually, my sister Anita was closer to her in age.
She knew Harriet better than anyone -
You should talk to her.
Id love to, where is she?
If I had to guess -
London.
- You dont know where your own sister lives?
- I havent seen her in years.
- We never really got along.
- Im getting used to that comment.
She hates this place
even more than  I do.
She left, moved to London,
That was it.
You couldnt pay her to send a Christmas card,
much less visit.
Ill try to track and help you.
If you do,
and try talking to her about us,
dont be surprised
if she tells you to fuck off.
Subtitle by d3xt3r
You backed up?
- Hard drives at home, yeah.
- Thats good. B'cos this one is gone.
Have you ever had an STD?
Whens the last time
you were tested for HIV?
How many partners have you had
in thelast month?
How many of those were men?
It's regulation,
I have to ask you these things.
- Its a matter of health.
- Write what you want.
Why do you need
such an expensive computer?
- For work.
- Making coffee and sorting mail ?
I shouldnt even have to ask.
I should have control of my money.
And you will.
Once you learn to be sociable.
Get along with people.
Can you do that?
Why don't we start with that?
Why don't we start with me?
You do something for me,
I do something for you.
Thats how normal people do.
I want you to have that computer.
You feel that?
Thats gaberdine.
Unzip it.
And ...
I like the reticence.
Its almost convincing.
- Anita Vanger?
- Through there.
Thank  you.
Excuse me.
I probably should have made an appointment.
No, Its fine.
-   Please.  Have a seat.
- Thank you.
- Mikael.
- Mikael.  How do you do?
How do you do.
So, are you looking
for investment counseling?
Well, I would
if had any money
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Im writing a biography
of your  uncle Henrik.
Thats why Im here.
I haven't seen him in over 20 years.
Actually, it's more than that.
Haven't seen my sister.
Haven't seen anyone...
Most of what I'm writing about
predates that,
so your recollections are valid.
Where to start,
if that was a question.
Well than, let me narrow it down
I've gotten up to 1960
To the event that changed
everything in Henrik's life.
Harriet...
Everything I knew about
that I told to
- - whatever his name was -
- Morell.
My recollections then were a lot
better than they are now.
I'm not speaking of the event itself.
I'm trying to get a clearer sense of
what Harriet was like.
She was messed up.
Like all us Vanger kids.
Crazy mother.
Drunken father.
At least hers wasn't a Nazi.
- Was he abusive?
- Mine?
- No, her's.
- Not that I ever saw.
but you could
tell something was going on.
Somedays, she'd be very withdrawn.
The next minute, she'd be putting on makeup
and wearing the tightest sweater she had to school.
And then, she'd be studying
a Bible like a nun -
no Vanger was ever religious -
can you imagine?
She was obviously,
very unhappy.
What do you think happened to her?
Everyone knows what.
You don't have any thoughts about who?
Why?
All I know is that
I always felt really sorry for her.
I got away when I was 18 and
never went back.
She would have done the same..
but she never made it to 18.
Mr. Bjurman, please.
Its Lisbeth Salander.
Wait for a moment, please.
Im fine.  Im sorry I missed
our appointment.
I had a lot of work.
- Is something the matter?
- ... no, nothing to be concerned about
Actually, I need another
advance on my allowance.
Can I come to your office
tonight?
Why don't you come to my house?
Do you have a pen?
... I dont need a pen,
whats the address??
- Yes?
- It's me.
Lisbeth, come on in.
- You Like it?
- It's nice.
So.
- So, what do you need money for this time?
- Food.
How are you?
I'm so glad that you've decided
to come an visit.
I just want my money.
Well, lets see if I can help
you out with that.
Wait.
- Is there a problem?
- I just want to know...
am I going to have to do this
every time I need money to eat?
You're so cute when are surly.
I fogot to ask you...
Do you like anal sex?
Faith is the assurance of things hoped for,
the evidence of things not seen.
Through faith we understand that
the world was created by the word of God -
- Ill drive you home.
- I can get home on my own.
Are you sure?
- Is it any warmer inside?
- No.
I apologize if youre having
financial problems
at the magazine
during Mikaels absence.
- Well work through them.
- Are you sure?
How long do you think you can hang on?
Six months or so?
- That sounds about right.
- You know, I used to be in
the newspaper business.
We owned six dailies
back in the 50s.
We still own one.
The Courier, here in town.
Which, I let my nephew Birger run it since
he cant run anything else.
So what do you say to
taking on a partner?
Well, Weve never
had to considered it before.
We value our independence very much.
Independence is publishing
is dependant on advertisers -
However much you have, youd retain.
-  We dont care about content.
- Excuse me.  Did I miss something?
Were talking about an
investment in the magazine.
I gather that.
Why would you want to do that?
Well, not out of greed,
thats for sure.
I feel badly that Ive taken Mikael
away from you at the worst possible time.
Now i'm convinced that this is
the right thing to do.  The moral thing..
Thats one reason.
And.
And....
The enemies of my friends
are my enemies.
How long have you
been discussing this with them?
I havent been. They called yesterday
and asked me to come.
Why didnt you tell me?
Why would I.
You live in the wood?
And so, I deserve
to be treated like an idiot?
I just wanted to hear
what they had to say?
You wouldve said 'no'
before they could.
Im saying it now.
Its a bad idea.
You heard me tell them we could
had six months.
I lied. Without their money well be out of
business in three.
You dont know this family.
Like I do. Theyre crazy.
- Were not marrying into it.
- If we do this. Thats exactly what were doing.
You want to say no?
Lets say no.
Instead of 50 percent of something,
lets own 100 percent of nothing.
- Mikael?
- What?
- Im leaving this God-forsaken
island in the morning.
- So?
- So, are you coming to bed or not.
How much do one of those cost?
Around three thousand.
This is really gonna hurt.
Your call.
Petrochemical manufacturer Vanger Industries
has taken a controlling interest in Millennium magazine.
which according to analysts
has been in financial trouble....
Millennium is an excellent magazine.
We also think its undervalued right now,
which is good business for us.
Theres another reason.
I dont like bullies.
Are you referring to Mr. Wennerstrom?
Im referring to anyone who tries
to sue --
their enemies into submission.
If Mr. Wennerstrom would
like to try it again,
hell find himself fighting
a company that can afford to fight back.
Ive always admired Henrik Vanger.
Hes a titan - and a gentleman.
But hes also quite old now -
which may explain..
how he could be taken in
by a convicted liar.
Shit.
PHOTO EDITOR:
The current archive is on CDs,
The older stuff, still negatives.
What general period are you interested in?
September, 1966.
Thank you.
Is this about Harriet Vanger?
Youre too young
to know about that.
Everyone here grows up
knowing about her.
Its how were taught
about strangers.
- Lisbeth?
- I need to pay my rent.
I need some money.
Oh, come in.
I feel..a bit..badly,
how we left it last night.
- Me, too.
Good...
Youre alive.
You recognize this?
I had it with me last time.
I set it here.  Remember?
And the snap,
you see it?
Its not a snap.
Its a wide-angle micro-lens.
I thought it was gonna be
just another blow-job.
Which is disgusting enough.
I misjudged,
just how sick you are.
Okay, this is whats going to happen.
Pay attention.
Look at me.
Once you can sit again,
which could be a while, I admit.
were going to my bank and tell them that
I alone have access to money.
Nod.
After that,
youll never contact me again.
Each month youll prepare a report
of a meeting we will never have.
In it, youll describe
how well Im doing,
how 'sociable' Im becoming.
Then, you will negotiate
with the court--
to have my
declaration of incompetence lifted.
If you fail,
this video will spread
across the Internet like a virus.
Nod.
And, If something happens to me
..if I get hit by a car -
if you run me over with a car -
This will upload automatically.
Nod that you understand.
Oh, Gabardina.
Im taking the keys to this apartment.
Because, Ill  be checking on you.
And If I find a girl in here with you,
whether she came of her own
free will or not -
No.  Not the video.
I will kill you.
Do you doubt anything Ive said?
Do you doubt in the
reports that've followed me all my life?
What do they say?
If you had to sum it up?
They say Im insane.
No, it okay. You can nod
because its true.
I am insane.
Nod!
I know itll be hard for you
to abide by my rules.
The abstinence part,
most of all.
So, Im going to make it
easier for you.
Lie still.  Ive never
done this before.
And, There will be some blood.
- Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- On my way to Skelleftea.
I can only
stay for four hours.
Whats in Skelleftea?
Bible Camp.
Oh, yeah.
- I'm not dangerous.
- Its fine, Nilla.
Whatever you want to do is fine.
-  Everybody needssomething.
- Just so long as its not God.
I didnt say that.
Ive never been around enough to know
everything thats going on with you,
and I apologize for that.
But Id never want
you to not tell me something,
B'cos you think
I might not want to hear it.
Thats what Im doing.
It really should have been me visiting you.
Im sorry.
Its okay.
It was nice seeing you.
Bye bye.
- See you.
- Yeah.
Dont go too hard on the Catholics.
What?
The article youre writing.
I'm not writing an article
about Catholics.
The Bible quotes on your desk...
A woman who is a medium
or a sorcerer; shall be put to death, by stoning.
If a dove is the sinners offering,
the priest shall wring off its head,
cleave its wings, and burn it upon the altar.
Hello.
Detective Morell,
its Mikael Blomkvist.
Yes, Hello.
How are you?
Not still freezing in Hedestad,
I hope for your sake.
You know, The Rebecka Case
that you mentioned.
Would you recall the last name?
Of course I do, but what would it
have to do with anything?
- Nothing probably.
- Jocobsson. Rebecka Jocobsson.
How was she killed?
She was decapitated.
Her arms were cut off and she was burned.
But all this happened in the 1940s -
What have you found?
- Im gonna have to call you back.
- Why?
- Is it Henrik?
- We were talking.
He started rubbing at his arm
an then collapsed.
Is he gonna be okay?
I cant talk, Mikael,
I honestly don't know -
- You gotta go.
- I'm sorry.
I'll talk to you later.
Good evening.
Come on up,
How is he?
Well, The good news is he survived.
How  he does now,
we have to see.
-  Hes in Intensive Care.
- Right.
-  Can I have one of those?
- You want a sandwich?
- A small Scotch.
- Sure thing.
Thank you.
I hate to be indelicate. But...
Henrik promised me something
when I agreed to do this.
- Yeah, Wennerstrm.
- I need to know what he has on him.
- Now.  In case.
- In case he dies?
-  That is indelicate.
- And I apologize.
Well, I dont know what he has on him,
if youre asking me.
And he cant tell you
in the condition hes in.
We also didn't discussed
who Id report
- to if something happened to him.
- Who else, You'd report to me.
We both know nothings going
to come of this, don't we?
No, we don't know that.
What do you mean?
- I may have found something.
- You're joking?
What have you found?
The last time I reported on something
without being absolutely sure,
I lost me my life savings.
I need a research assistant.
Can you authorize that?
Yes.
- Do you have one in mind?
- I can find someone.
I know a excellent one.  She did the
background check on you.
The what?
You don't think we can hire just anyone
without doing background check?
I want to read it.
Herr Frode was kind enough to share
your report with me.
The investigators name...
That is her name, yes?
I can find no record of her, and
Im pretty good at that kind of thing.
Would it really matter?
But It would if I wanted
to speak to her, Yes.
It's against policy.
- You sure?
- Just like your sources. You understand.
Okay.
Here's a name for you.
My sister,
she's also my lawyer.
She'll be contacting you.
Theres information in here that
could only have come from one place.
The reason you can find no record
of her is because
her records have been sealed.
-  Shes a ward of the State.
- What does that have to do with anything?
Shes had a rough life.
Can we please,
not make it rougher on her?
Who is it?
Mikael Blomkvist.
- Actually Im not really up (yet) -
- May I come in? Please.
Hi.
You and I need to talk.
I got us some break...
I'm sorry, I need...
Who do you think you are?
Im the guy you know
better than my closest friends do.
Why don't you put some
clothes  on and get rid of your girlfriend.
We need to talk.
I'm sorry,
You have to go.
Okay.
Do you need me to stay?
No.
- Bye.
Bye.
- Sorry.
- Bye.
I guess I alarmed you
turning up like that.
If you touch me,
Ill more than alarm you.
That wont be necessary.
Your report, very detailed.
but for me,
It wasn't very entertaining.
- It wasnt meant to be.
- When I write about people,
I try to entertain the reader.
Wennerstrm
wasnt entertained much.
Your boss, Armansky...
He tells me, you only work on things
that interest you.
So, I suppose..
I should be flattered.
Are you going to sit down?
He also says that
youre the one he goes to
When the jobs is, sensitive
I'm gonna use,illegal, b'cos that's what it was
when you hacked into my computer.
Im not going to do anything about
that.  I could but I wont.
What Im going to dois tell you a story.
If it entertains  you,
maybe youll
decide to help me research further.
And if not, then I'll do the washing
and you'll never see me again.
What kind of research?
Lisbeth...
Can I call you Lisbeth?
I want you to help me
catch a killer of women.
I've got "R. J.",
Rebecka Jacobsson.
I have absolutely no idea
who the rest of this people are -
or how theyre connected to the death
of a 16 year old girl -
they must be somehow.
So, what we're gonna do is find out who
they are? What happened to them?
and what the Leviticus verses
have to do with anything?
What are you doing?
Getting started.  You can keep
talking if you want.
- Don't you need to look over this?
- I got it.
Cat!
How did you get in?
No ones asked me about Magda
in over 40 years.
Why would a young lady like you want
to know about such an aweful murder?
- It interests me.
- Does it ?
Her husband was our first suspect -
the husband is always the first
suspect, and usually the last -
but not this time.
We moved on to a neighbor.
Then a vagrant -
Once you get to strangers,
its only a matter of time...
before you get to gypsies,
and you know youre never going to solve it.
How exactly was she killed?
- Miss...
- Salander.
I'm sorry..Miss Salander, I hope,
you dont mind my asking,
whens the last time you ate?
I have a high metabolism.
I cant put on weight.
I'm asking because its better to look at
what Im about to show you
on an empty stomach.
If a mans offering is a lamb, it
shall be a female without blemish.
He shall lay his hand upon its head
...slaughter it...
empty its blood
on the base of the altar...
and he shall be forgiven.
- How is he?
- He needs surgery
but theres no DNR in place.
So its up to the family to decide
whether to resuscitate or not,
and theyre not good at decisions.
- Howd it go with Ms. Salander?
- She said yes.
Do you think
I might be able to see him?
He was asleep when I last looked,
- but let me check.
- Thank you.
Don't check.
- Tell him to pack his things and leave.
- Mother, please.
Dont use that tone with me.
Isabella, Mr. Blomkvist
works for Henrik.
- We should put this to a vote.
- Dont be an idiot, Birger.
We all know what Henrik wants,
Can we please just do that?
Henrik is in there fighting for his life in there.
This is the last thing he needs.
Excuse me, Mrs. Vanger,
there's nosmoke in here.
Go back to Stockholm.
When we need a family chronicle
written by a libelist,
we know who to call.
Alright, thanks.
This way, Miss.
If a woman approaches any beast
and dies with it.
He shall kill the woman and the beast,
Their blood shall be upon them.
My family is impossible.
Its why the company is such a mess.
I apologize for my mothers behavior.
I'm use to it.
It has nothing to do with you.
Its between her and Henrik ...
She lost it when my father died.
Her drinking..it got so bad
Henrik took me and my sister away from her,
And left her excommunicated,
in our old house on the other side of the island
She hasn't forgiven him.
You, you must stay.
Youre last chance that  Henrik has
at some kind of resolution.
Put this to rest for him one way of the other,
and Ill try to keep my mother away.
But, please, hurry.
Of course.
Lisbeth?
- I'll get that.
- It's okaya.
- This is Martin Vanger.
- How do you do?
Fine.
- Girlfriend or...
- Assistant.
Thank you, so much.
- Good night.
Any trouble finding the place?
Everyone in town knows
who and where you are.
Thats comforting.  Are you hungry?
Want a sandwich?
No.
- I used to have a motorcycle. A Triumph...
- I know.
The five cases from
Harriets list.
And five more she missed -
three Im sure about.
Rebecka was the first,
jsut as you thought ...
The Second, M.H., is Mari Holmberg
- a prostitute in Kalmar -
murdered in 1954.
Leviticus 20:8.
"If a man lies with a woman,
having a signatia,
made naked as a fountain,
and she has uncovered a fountain of blood."
She was raped and stabbed, but the
cause of death
was suffocation with a
sanitary napkin.
R.L.  Rakel Lunde, 1957 -
Cleaning woman and part-time palm reader,
tied up with a clothesline,
gagged, raped, head
crushed with a rock.
Leviticus 20:27.
A woman who is a medium or sorcerer
shall be put to death by stoning.
I usually like to smoke outside.
Sara Witt, 1964.
Daughter of a pastor.
Tied to her bed, raped,
charred in the fire
that burned down her house.
Leviticus - 21:9.
The daughter of any priest who profanes herself
by playing the harlot, profanes her father
and  shall be burned
with (fire) -
Magda Lovisa Sjoberg, 1960 -
Found in a barn, stabbed and
raped with farm tools.
A cow in the next stall with its throat slit,
its blood splashed on
her, hers on it,
Levtico 20:16,
If a woman lies with any beast,
you shall kill the woman and the beast,
their blood is upon (them) - "
Lea Persson, 1962. Found by her
sister in their pet shop -
raped, beaten.
The killer uncaged the animals,
smashed the aquariums.
There was a parakeet
inside her.
Eva Gustavsson, 1960.
A runaway. Raped,
strangled,
a burnt pigeon
tied around her neck.
Lena Anderson, 1967.
a student.
Raped,
stabbed, decapitated -
- Okay...
- Im not done -
Its all right, were looking for a
serial murderer but...
But what does i have to do
with a teenager on an island?
She was looking for him, too.
Rape.  Torture.  Fire.  Animals.
Religion.
-  Anything Im missing?
- The names.
Theyre all Biblical.
The first woman, the whore,
the Virgin Mary - Sara, Rakel -
all from
the Old Testament.
Which means theyre all Jewish.
If theres one thing the Vangers have
more than their share of, anti-semites.
There is one.
I can sleep on a couch.
Uhm...right.
There's that the...cash on it.
Good night.
- Harriets name isnt.
Isnt what?
Jewish.
- What are you doing here?
- Reading your notes.
- Theyre encrypted.
- Please.
Have some coffee.
Okay..And then well have a talk
about whats yours and whats mine.
Its amazing what you figured out
from the parade photos.
Thank you.
- Too bad you dont have hers.
- Whose?
Her.
Sorry.
There's the one.
Where the fuck is that...?
What does that say there ?
- N, something, R, S, J -
- Norsjo.
Then something, K,
something, R, I, F,
Carpentry.
Where do we go for a carpenter.
Fuck!
The carpentry shop is gone.
I dont know even know if he worked
there or not. But If he did, maybe he used to
use to come in
here to buy hardware.
I dont recognize him.
Sorry.
I had to start somewhere.
Im no detective, but...
...1966, I wouldve started at
the retirement home.
- This is Brannlunds kid.
- Do you know where I might find him, the son?
Next to his father
at the cemetery.
He was killed in an accident on a job
site years ago.
But uh..she might still be alive -
His widow.
Do you know where I might find her?
In 1966, you were in Hedestad
with your husband.
- Who took this?
- A local photographer.
You were taking pictures, too.
That day and ..
I'd love to at them, if by some miracle
you still have them.
It wouldnt be a miracle.  We were on
our honeymoon.
But why?
This, this girl there...I need you
to see it better in an enlargement.
So that's you there.
Just after this was taken...
After, she'd seen something
across the street,
She was murdered.
How awful!
- There you are.
- Thank  you.
Would you mind
if I made a copy of this?
No.
TECH CLERK:I cant give you
any of this stuff without authorization
from Mr. Armansky.
So call him.
Next time,
fill out the proper paperwork.
Which one are you?
Hows your sex life?
I didnt care much
for your last report.
It's so perfunctory,
like your hearwasnt in it.
Lets see a little more enthusiasm
for my recovery in next months.
- But...
- Don't speak!
I dont want to hear your voice.
Just nod.
Start looking for a shrink
you can bribe, this way..
under oath, he can find
absolutely nothing wrong with me.
And stop visiting
tattoo removal websites,
or Ill do it again -
right here.
- Is that  dental floss?
- Yes.
you sterilize that,
Right?
Couldn't we just use tape
or something ?
No.
What ?
- Jesus!
- Drink.
- Just, be careful, its my eye.
- Don't move.
You're not a doctor.
Take off your wet clothes.
Thank you.
I think it stopped bleeding.
That fucking hurts.
Fucking madness.
Jesus, That hurts.
Fuck.
This is insane.
I mean this people...
Somebody was shooting  at me...
It wasnt an accident...
No ones shooting at you now.
You know, Im pretty sure
this is a bad idea.
Why?
Apart from the fact that Im old and
we work together.
You work with whats-her-name.
Thats worked out for you.
I have some standards,
believe it or not.
You need to stop talking.
You want me to open a window?
- I like working with you.
- I like working with you, too.
It could have been a stray shot.
Not that Gunner. If he wanted to
shoot him, It wouldn't have been here.
And then, we have poachers.
They shoot at anything that moves.
Or hes right, Dirch.
What if he is?
- This has to stop.
- Do you want to stop, Mikael?
I have police reports, photos,
Henriks notes, my own notes,
and Lisbeths research.
What I dont have is
Vanger Industries records.
- Thats what I want.
- Why?
Will you authorize it?
The private corporate records?
How far back?
Henrik said I have access to
everything I needed.
- This is what I need.
- Thats not what he meant.
I'll sign a nondisclosure statement,
if that would help..
- You think Henrik would say yes.
- Thats why he has me.
To protect him from himself.
This is insane.
- What do we have to hide?
- After a 120 years of business?
Probably, a lot.
If this is what he needs to finish,
he should have permission.
What am I looking for?
Any connections between
Vanger Industries -
and the towns where
the women were killed...
and everything about Frode.
Your father was taking pictures
that day no one has seen.
I'd like to take a look at that.
- So ask him.
- I was wondering if you could do that?
I dont speak to him,
as you know.
You couldnt make an exception
in my case.
Are you afraid to be in
the same  room with him?
Im not saying you shouldnt be.
You wont help me?
Sorry.
Please.
Are you finished?
I need to know where all the factories,
offices and projects were
from 1949 to 1966.
- You already have everything.
- No, I dont.
Nothing on subsidiary corporations,
- partnerships, or suppliers.
- Then youll have to do without.
Mr. Frode said I have access
to whatever I need, and..
- this is what I need.
- He said you have access to this floor.
Call Him.
Thank you, for seeing me.
Come in.
- Tea?
- Please.
Sven Olof Lindholm.
Me.
Handsome.
Birger Furugard.
Me.
Per Engdahl.
But your interest is in my more
candid photographic work.
Friends,
Relations, that kind of thing.
Please.
- "Blom" ou "Blum"?
- Blomkvist.
Im not a recluse.
I dont close my door to anyone.
They just dont
visit.
Perhaps if you redecorated.
Hide the past like they do.
Under a thin, shiny veneer.
Like an Ikea table..
Im the most honest of all of them.
- The family?
- Sweden.
Landscape?
Some nice landscapes there.
Who is this there?
The blurry one.
I can't tell.
- Thats Gottfrieds boy.
- Martin?
Handsome but useless young man,
Like his father.
Were closing.
Nowhere near finished.
I'm not authorized to stay late.
I am.
And I need access to all the
rooms, including any that are locked.
Call Frode.
Leave the keys with the guard.
CARLN AND VANGER
REBUILD LOCAL PLAN.
GOTTFRIED VANGER ANDd CARLN
SHAKING HANDS.
GRUPO VANGER ACQUIRES
KARLSON'S SHIPPING & FREIGHT.
VANGER INDUSTRIES
INVESTING IN UDDEVALLA
MISS LEA PERSSON
FOUND STRANGLED.
IN MEMORIAM.
Shit!
IN MEMORIAM GOTTFRIED VANGER
1927-1965
Martin?
Mikael?
Hi there.
Your evening stroll?
That's right, I...
- How are you?
- Good.
I stopped at the hospital
on my way home.
Henrik asked me
to ask you something.
What was that?
Come on in,
Ill make you a drink.
Hello, Martin.
Shut the door,
It's quite windy.
- What happened to  you?
- When?
Just now.
- I fell in the dark.
- You don't have a flashlight?
- I'll get you one.
- I just wasn't being careful.
How the investigations going?
- Nothing New.  To report..
- No?
Dirch says, the girl is really clever.
Maybe, she'll turn something up.
Maybe.
Thank you.
- So, What did he say?
- What?
You said Henrik asked
you to ask me something.
- Well, I just did.
- What?
How the investigations going.
That was his question.
Do You hunt?
- We should go hunting together sometime.
- Sure.
Nothing at all?
- New.  To report?
- No. Nothing.
- I can see youre anxious.
- No.
I mean, to get home.
After the walk.
Yeah, Sorry.
I suppose I am.
To have dinner.
With your girlfriend.
Assistant.
Well have better luck
with a gun.
- I'm sorry?
- When we go hunting.
A gun.
Rather than a knife.
I want to show you something.
Bring your drink.
Leave my knife.
To the right.
You know whats harder than
shooting someone?
Just missing them.
That was a very good shot
up at the cabin.
It didnt work.  Im here.
Mikael, it did work.
Youre here.
Inside.
You spilled your drink.
Why didnt you just go home?
May I?
Howd you do it?
What did you find?
We can talk or
we can just get on with it.
I found a picture
no one had seen before.
- Of?
- You.
- In your Uppsala prep school blazer.
- What does that proof?
It shows that you lied about
where you were that day.
- Was I?
-  Or rather when.
So what.
People lie all the time.
It also said that Lena Andersson
was a schoolmate.
Lena...
That was a long time ago.
Wheres this photo now? Is it with all
the other crap on your desk?
There's a cope of that on my laptop,
And there's another on a secure website.
Thats a lie ...
How much does the girl know?
I hope its as much as you.
Thatll make it more fun.
Where is she?
Stockholm.
She went this morning.
And thats a lie.
Shes atour offices
looking at more old crap.
I got a call from our archives manager -
she's very perturbed -
with this girl.  Lisbeth.
I like that name.  Lisbeth.
So, when Lisbeth leaves
Ill get a call from security,
so I can be
at your cottage
to greet her.
I cant thank you enough
for bringing her to me.
Mikael?
So what would you like to know?
Youre the journalist,
ask me questions.
What do I do with my girls?
That's a good question.
Well, before - I do what were doing. Sit down,
Relax, have a drink,
I like that part a lot -
having a chat when you both know
that one of you is going to die.
After - I simply get rid of them.
Far out to the sea -
- unlike my father
leaving them scattered all over
the place like trophies.
Thats not smart if you ask me.
But he was a garish and loud man.
he got what he deserved.
You cant be a sloppy technician like that.
You cant drink to excess
like he did.
This takes discipline.
Its a science of a thousand details.
The planning. The execution.
The cleanup.
Im sure I dont have to tell you
youre going to make quite a mess.
Let me ask you something.
Why dont people trust their instincts?
They sense somethings wrong - someones
walking too close behind them -
You  knew something was wrong -
but you came back into the house.
Did I force you? Did I drag you in? No.
All I had to do was..
offered you a drink.
Youd never think the fear of offending
can be stronger
than the fear of pain -
but you know what?
It is.
They always come willingly.
And then they sit here.
They know its over like..
you do - But somehow..
they still think
they have a chance.
Maybe if I say the right thing -
Maybe if Im polite -
or I cry and beg - "
when I see the hope draining
from their face like it is
from yours right now -
I feel myself...
getting hard.
We are not that different,
You and I.
We both have urges.
Satisfying mine,
requires more towels.
It might amuse you to know that while you
were upstairs having mousse with me and Liv -
who, by the way,
finds me very conventional -
I had Irina was down here
in the cage.
Whos Irina, you might ask?
Just another girl.
Just another immigrant whore.
Who misses them?
- Your sister wasnt.
- What?
Your sister, Harriet,
wasnt just another girl.
You found her?
What happened to her?
You killed her.
You useless fuckin detective.
Is that too tight to talk?
Good.
Im tired of talking to you.
Ive never had a man in
here, before.
In fact, Ive never touched a man.
Except my father.
But it was our duty.
Harriets and Mine.
There's a gun in the television.
May I kill him?
How come a 23 years old
can be a ward of the state?
Im mentally incompetent
and cant manage daily life.
- Since when have they said that?
- Since I was twelve.
Something happened
when you were twelve?
I'm sorry,
That's none of my business.
I tried to kill my father.
I burned him alive.
Got about 80 percent of him.
I'll make some coffee.
- Who is it?
- It's Harriet.
I found it in Martin's basement.
Among his souverneers.
Martin didnt deny killing anyone.
But when I mentioned Harriet,
he was confused.
He was angry - at me - b'cos
I couldn't tell him what happened to her.
He didnt kill her.
And his father didn't do it.
He was dead the year before.
What if she did somehow get away?
And if...
she's still alive?
Theres only one person in this family
who would know where she is.
Fuck me, fuck me.
Your turn.
Right.
Yeah.
Hi.
-  I'm Sorry to bother you.
- What do you want?
- No ones called you?
- About?
Your cousin, Martin.
What about him?
He died in a car accidentlast Thursday.
There's going to be a memorial...
Im not interested in any memorial.
- I understand.
- What do you understand.?
That you dont care
very much of your relatives.
-  I just, thought you should know.
- Now, I know.
Howd it go?
- Okay.  I think.
- Shes on.
And she's shopping.
Shes playing solitaire?
- And she still hasnt called anyone?
- No.
Do we have her cell phone, too?
I was so shed lead us to her.
Put your hand back in my shirt.
Theres only one reason she
hasnt call Harriet.
She cant,
because Harriet is dead.
- I was just thinking.  What if -...
- Just one second.
What were you going to say?
I was just thinking, there could be
one other possibility.
- What is it now?
- Before he died,
your brother hung me
from a hook ...
Harriet.
- So you send the flowers?
- Yes.
We found in the Swedish General Registry,
Annita was married.
But the family never knew,
did they?
So, Im guessing she then came here
on a married name passport
you followed on her
maiden name passport.
No, Actually, it was the other way around.
She thought that it safer for me
to travel with Spencer myself.
What did he think about that?
Nothing.  Only that he loved her.
She said, If you love me, youll do
this and not ask why.
He never did.
And they both died twenty years ago.
A car accident.
You found that, too.
Is that you?
I was 14 the first time he raped me.
- Martin?
- No, my father.
Martin only started,
after he died.
Why didnt you tell someone?
I did.  My mother.
Henrik would have done something.
I almost   told him.  But I was afraid
because of what I've done.
I uh...
You still dont understand, Do you?
A year after the first time -
There were many times
during that year -
my father got drunker
than usual one night
and started bragging...
about women hed killed.
He quoted from the Bible
as he tore off my clothes.
He tiedd a belt around my neck.
He
wanted to kill  me.
I uh...
I made it out of the house and
I went down to the dock.
He came staggering
after me -
I could never fight him off
in a small space,
but out in the open..
I was strong enough to deal
with an old drunk.
When it was over...
I looked up, Martin was standing there -
looking at me.
All Id accomplished was
substitute one for another.
A couple months later, Henrik sent
Martin to school in Uppsala.
And I thought maybe -
just maybe - the nightmare was finally over.
And then I saw him.
across the street -
And I knew..
It would never be over.
Howd you escaped?
Annita...
She insisted that I leave
everything behind.
If I took anything, the police
might've suspected that I was still alive.
While everyone was eating dinner,
I was alone 20 meters away from them.
I spend the night there,
That's when the set-up started.
In the morning,
she came to get me.
I'd grown up with that bridge
as my link to home.
But all I could think is,
If I could just get away for a moment,
Just get passed the police.
I might be safe.
And I was.
Until, you showed up.
You're safe now.
How did you got away?
Someone saved me too.
- How're you feeling?
- I'm fine.
Thank you, Anna.
I made you a promise.
Whether you found anything,
or not.
So, What do you have to tell me?
Hello, Henrik.
I dont even remember Wennerstrom
working here, much less
- being fired.
- How could you?
It was a long time ago.
Which is kind of more to the point than
the money he embezzled to start...
If you're referring to
the statued of limitation...
I had no idea, this was what
Henrik was holding out. If I had,
I never would have let him bring you up here.
He wasnt trying to deceive you.
Oh, Come on, he knows you cant try
somebody after 35 years after the event.
I like Henrik,
but he knows that.
A mans reputation used to mean
something -
he still believes that.
Im sure he thought you could destroy
Wennerstrom with this in the court of public opinion.
The court of public opinion,
now celebrates people's bad behaviour.
He promised me
Wennerstroms carcass on a plate.
This isnt even the plate.
I cant do anything with this.
Of course...
What happened with Wennerstrm?
How did he get you?
I was stupid.
I got something, I got it from
an anonymous source..
Who I'm sure, was one of
Wennerstrm's lakies
Which
he easily proved in court.
You were emphatic that the way I
looked into your life was illegal
and immoral.
Would you feel the same
about Wennerstrm?
Go on.
I did some work on my own on him,
before you hired me.
I havent had a chance to look at it all -
B'cos you and Harriet-fucking-Vanger
have kept me busy ...
-  but I may have something.
- You may have something?
Maybe.
They launder money from arms and drug
sales, and
crime syndicates in Russia.
And that money - accounts for all
but 5-percent of his holdings -
the rest ends up in accounts in the
Cayman Islands.
How do you know this?
This time you dont want to know.
This time I do want to know.
I have access to his computer,
and
his accountants and lawyers.
And how do you have that?
I could have gotten it from a source
inside the company.
- But you didnt.
- But thats what youll say.
But what will you say to me?
That depends on
if you really want to know.
I do. Mikael,
Who gave you access?
Financial Journalist Mikael Blomkvist -
who this time
last year was convicted of libel
in a Stockholm courtroom -
doesnt seem to have learned
from his mistakes.
Or maybe he has -
In the current issue of Millennium
magazine,
he now charges the same
company that successfully sued him -
Before the shit hits the fan.
What happens now?
Hell say i'st a personal vendetta
but it wont work.
The police will investigate,
FI will investigate.
Maybe we'll go to court.
Maybe he'll go to prison.
Do you think?
Probably, not.
This guys never do.
- Whats wrong?
- Its embarrassing.
Tell me.
I need to borrow some money.
50,000.
I have a chance to make an investment.
Its a smart, safe investment.
I really don't think I've got 50,000.
Yes, you do.
You have 65 thousand
in your two accounts.
Im sorry that I know that.
Youll get the money back.
I promise.
- Okay.
You want a coffee?
These allegations - like the last
ones from this so-called journalist -
are as ridiculous as they are untrue -
Ill be seeing Mr. Blomkvist in court again.
Im looking forward to it.
What about his documentation?
Fabricated.  All of it.
The Securities Fraud Office isnt
quite as certain as Mr. Wennerstrom of that.
If even a fraction of what Mr.
Blomkvist is alleging proves to be true,
not only will there be
a securities investigation,
but an organized crime
inquiry as well.
Mr. Blomkvist names no sources.
And we cant force him to.
But we can look for them.
- Beginning where?
- Beginning with...
those closest to Mr. Wennerstrm,
Only someone in the inner circle of a
corporation like this could have access
to this kind of information.
Mr. Wennerstrm isnt available for
comment today,
but Id be happy to answer
your questions.
- Where is he??
- No, he's not.
Has he left the country?
I don't think so.
Thank you.
With his failure to appear before a
Security Exchange Commission panel,
a warrant has been issued for The
Wennerstrm Group CEO.
I can confirm that he left Sweden on
a private jet
that landed in Paris last week,
but whether hes still there,
we dont know.
He could be anywhere by now.
Thank you.
I have a number of accounts at Bank
of Kroenfeld, Cayman Islands.
I'd like to transfer those accounts
and convert them to bonds.
Naturally,
you have the clearingcodes.
Naturally.
How many accounts
will you be transferring?
Thirty.
This will take some time.
For which youll receive
a 4-percent commission.
- I will?
- Then it wont be a waste of it.
A Swedish tourist vacationing here in
Barbados says
he knows where fugitive financier
Hans-Erik Wennerstrm is:
Here in this Caribbean islands
capital, Bridgetown.
Police released this photograph, yesterday-
and say they believe is the disgraced billionaire.
How many of these would you like to
convert for deposit?
All fifty.
Into five accounts.
That looks correct.
The man who is now being called
"Swedens Charles Ponzi ",
may not have
a country to call home,
but does have
enough money to buy one.
According to the International
Banking Commission,
Wennerstrm, a week after the
Millennium article appeared on news stands,
began emptying accounts
at Bank of Kroenfeld in the Cayman Islands.
That money, approximately
two billionEuros,
was then spread over a number of
accounts with the help of
this confederate,
seen here in Zurich -
- Hey.
The money I borrowed.
Already?
- Thank you.
I quit.
Was it a good investment?
It was okay.
What are you doing later?
I'm seeing my daughter.
Okay.
You look nice.
It's Christmas again ...
I'll see you soon.
I miss our meetings.
Im sure you dont.
Why would you?
I was always such a headache for you.
Never showing up with good news.
Only problems.
I have some good news now.
Ive made a friend.
I mean one that youd
approve of.
Im happy.
- shot three times in the head at
close range
in what is being called a
classic gangland execution.
The investigation into Wennerstroms
ties to crime organizations worldwide will
now turn to speculation:
Which of them caught up with him before
Swedish authorities could?
Wennerstrm spent
the last days of..
Its perfect.
- Your father?
- A friend.
Must be a very good friend.