Get out of my way!
Ok, here they are.
Philippe, wake up now,
I bet you 100 euros that I'll lose them.
Philippe?
Deal.
Let's do this!
Gosh, you're on a good night.
Fuck.
You lost them alright.
Get out of the car!
Hands on the hood!
- I double.
- 200 euros that they're escorting us.
You're gonna lose again.
-200 euros!
-Come on! Show me your hands!
Your hands goddammit!
- Wait. I'm gonna explain.
- Shut up. Hands on the hood.
- Wait.
- Get out of the car. Now!
Take it easy!
He can't get out.
He can't even open the door.
Look at him for god's sake!
There's a wheel chair in the trunk.
He's disabled. Go check!
Get off me.
- He's telling the truth.
- SO!
What did you think?
You think i'm driving that fast.
for the fun of it?
I was going to the hospital.
I'm working for him. He's having a stroke!
The more we wait, the worse it gets.
He can't move, he can't do anything.
That's why I'm here.
I think we have a problem here.
Come see this.
-  What the fuck do we do now?
- That's right, think about it. Take your time.
But meanwhile call his 15 years old daughter
and tell her her father is dead because of you!
Because if he's not taken care of within
5 minutes, it's over.
But take your time.
Think. Think fast.
He's dying!
Alright, don't lose any more time.
Go.
- Where are you going?
- ER.
We're gonna escort you, it's safer.
Let's go, we're escorting them!
They're gone. They're leaving.
Good.
Philippe, this is so gross.
I can't deal with that, how do
you produce this... beuargh.
Alright, you'll really have to
get your license eventually.
Yes but meanwhile "we're gonna
escort you, it's safer".
A 200 euros escort.
What? I never bet such amounts
of money.
Let's celebrate a little bit.
"We're gonna escort you, it's safer"
Cool it. I helped you big time.
Philippe, an escort. A safe escort!
Here he comes.
We took care of it.
A stretcher will be here in a second.
- Are you gonna be ok?
- Yeah, it's fine.
- Good luck.
- Whatever.
Now what?
Now you let me decide.
UNTOUCHABLES
Based on a true story
----synch DJSPIDEBOY----
djspideboy@gmail.com
----Translation TOTODUCHNOK----
totoduchnok@hotmail.fr
Do you have references?
Well yes. I validated my CAFAD.
A certificate of aptitude to take care of
disabled persons.
I validated it in a renowned instute
in the Landes country in 2001
I have a high school "Proximity Services" diploma
and a bachelor's in "Social and Familial Economy"
I don't... like... I mean... I have been mostly
studying rather than working.
What is your main motivation?
Money. Duh!
Mankind.
I'm all about mankind.
Good for you.
To help others, I think.
It's good right? It's a good
answer?
I like the neighbourhood.
I love disabled persons. Since I was
a little child actually.
To promotes disabled people's autonomy,
I'd say.
Their social insertion.
Sports too. You gotta move, you know.
For the social life, I mean.
These people can't do anything...
I saw...had my first professionnal experience...
It was Mme Dupont Morathie
A really old lady...
really old...
I assisted her...
until the end, day after day.
In geriatrics there were good times too.
We had King's cake ... er ...
Oh... I'm also an expert in administrative stuff...
Financial aid ...
Welfare ...
I... I don't know...
maybe you qualify?
You'll check, Magalie.
But I don't think so...
- Yvan Laprade?
- Yes.
- No no no, get out!   - I've been waitin for 2 hours.
- It's my turn now.
Hello.
I'm coming to have a paper signed.
Please take a seat.
Do you have references?
References? I do.
So?
We're all ears.
"Kool & the Gang",  "Earth, Wind & Fire".
Those are good references, aren't they?
I don't know them. Take a seat.
If you don't know them, you
don't know anything about music.
I don't think I'm incult when
it comes to music
- Even if I don't know you "Sool" whatever...
- NO.
"Kool & the Gang".
What about you?
You know Chopin, Schubert, Berlioz?
You're asking me if I know Berlioz?
I'd be surprised if YOU knew
anything about Berlioz.
I'm a specialist, though.
Oh really...
Who do you know there?
- Which building?
- What do you mean which building?
But, man...
Berlioz was a famous composer before
your residency was called after him.
Writer, critic of the 19th century.
It's a joke. I know who Berlioz is.
But I see humor is like music for you.
You don't know anything about it.
Tell us about your paper.
I need a signature...
To prove I came to the interview.
It says that unfortunately, despite
my obvious qualities...
whatever usual bullshit you use
you're still not interested.
I need 3 of these to get welfare money again.
I understand, welfare.
- You don't have any other motivation in life?
- Oh I do.
There's one right here.
This here is really motivating...
So, what's happening now?
Signing? Not signing?
I'm sorry I can't sign it right now.
Why is that?
Why?
Oh yeah, that's a bit annoying.
Because I have a deadline, and since
I'm pretty late...
It's "a bit annoying", indeed.
Can't the motivation sign for you?
No, Magalie can't do that.
It's a shame.
She could have dropped in her number as well.
You'll have to come back tomorrow.
9 am. Your paper will be signed.
I wouldn't want to deprive you
from welfare.
- Sorry I can't walk you to the door.
- It's all good.
Don't get up...
I mean stay seated.
See you tomorrow.
- Nina?
- Yeah?
- Is she here?
- No. She'll be back late.
No!  Hey!
Don't use it now, it's using all the water.
Stop the water!
And get out.
- I'm showering, what are you doing here?
- Leave me alone.  - Get out!
Make them leave. Come on.
Bitou, I'm not joking.
Nina!
Nina.  Get out, you and your fat belly!
Let it go!
Give me a towel . Why are you still here...
Get out, all of you!
Bitou, come one
Hey! Bitou!
What do you think you're doing?
Sit down.
What do you want?
Coca-Cola or this one?
I want Coca-Cola.
- Where do you come from?
- School.
Can you wipe the thrash can?
Where are you going now?
Horse-riding.
That's right, act like a smart ass.
It's for you.
Where have you been?
- Holidays.
- Holidays?
You think people don't talk around here?
That I'm incredibly stupid?
You've been gone for 6 months.
Not one phone call. Nothing.
And you come back, as if nothing happened,
giving me a Kinder egg?
Do you think I'm gonna pay the rent with that?
The groceries?
*african language*
Do you think it's a hotel here?
Look at me when I'm talking to you.
Moron.
- It's impossible to talk with you.
- You want to talk?
Alright.
I'm listening.
I'm listening now.
You know Driss...
I prayed a lot for you.
But god forgive me...
I have other children.
I still have hope for them.
I don't want to see you around
here anymore.
You're taking all your stuff.
And you get the fuck out of here.
Got it?
Leave.
Leave!
... and he's gone!
It's a good one, right?
Ok, I'm off.
You don't think it was funny?
Yes?
- I'm here for my paper.
- Yes, I was waiting for you.
- You know... the paper.
- Get in.
Can you tell Philipp the boy is here?
Of course.
- So?
- The beats are not quite done.
- But the radish are good.
- Ok.     - Hello.
Let's go.
Just so you know,
he had a rough night.
Just like you, apparently.
The day starts at 7
with the nurse.
He needs 2 to 3 hours of care every morning.
I'm warning you, most people
give up after a week.
They come and go pretty fast.
Well...
I like the furniture, the music,
it's cool and all...
but I don't think I'll buy it.
And i don't have the whole day.
Listen, I was asked to give you a tour,
believe me I also have better things to do.
It's almost done anyway.
Here, you can communicate
with a babyphone.
It's like a Walkie-Talkie.
You hear him, he hears you.
According to the contract, you
also have your own room.
The toilets.
And a bathroom.
A private bathroom.
Hello...
It's here.
He's waiting for you.
One minute...
So I signed your paper.
It's in an envelope, on the little table.
By the way, how is it to be forced
to rely on others for a living?
What?
You don't have a problem living
from other people's work ?
I'm good, what about you?
Do you think you'd be able to work?
I mean with duties, a schedule...
Responsibilities.
I was wrong.
You're funny.
I'm so funny I'm ready to take you
on a one month trial.
Do you want the day to think about it?
I don't think you'll make it past two weeks.
What?
You can't forget a single bone or
a single muscle.
Everything has to move.
we want to keep the skin and
the joints healthy.
You'll have to be very meticulous.
Rigorous.
Ok? You get it?
Hey, wake up!
Sleep at night.
- I'm not sleeping.
- Come help me.
We're going to bring Philippe to his chair.
And then to the shower.
You know what?
Try yourself.
Show me.
Don't be afraid. Go ahead.
I'm not afraid.
- There. Good enough?
- Wait!
Never let him go until he's all strapped.
It's one of my sins.
None told me.
I'm in training.
Do you want gloves or what?
Rub harder, for god's sake.
It doesn't foam!
It's a weird shampoo.
- How is it going?
- I'm washing his hair...
but it doesn't foam.
What do you mean?
What the hell...
are you kidding me?
You put the cream for his feet
in his hair.
Wait, wait...
Please tell me you can read.
You look really talented, don't you?
They look exactly the same.
Why isn't there only one for everything?
There are 20 of them.
Ok, move on now.
I won't stay here for 2 hours.
- So I'm using this one?
- The one that says "shampoo".
- Are you gonna be ok?
- Of course, he'll be ok.
My feet have never been styled so well.
Go have your lunch, Marcelle.
Everything is fine.
Wow, do these come with a skirt?
Those are contension stockings.
If I don't wear them, my blood won't flow
and I'll pass out.
I'm not putting stocking on you.
We're gonna have a problem here.
Since I won't do it, we'll have to...
at a point... I mean...
we'll have to figure out if... Marcelle!
Maybe she can come back...
and do it herself.
Since she's a girl and everything,
she knows how to.
I don't even know why we're debating,
I'm not gonna do it.
Even for you, at this point you'd
probably better pass out...
You have to say no, to stand up for yourself.
Marcelle! We're not going to do the stockings.
What's the matter, you're dealing with the stockings,
you have a cute little earring, I think it's coherent.
Easy on the sass, alright?
Looks like you have experience...
No? You never thought about...
starting a salon or something?
Ok. Done.
Now what are these gloves for?
Er... we're going to wait a while more for this.
You're not quite ready.
No. He's not quite ready.
What does it mean, Marcelle?
- What is that?
- We'll explain at a point.
Marcelle, we have to talk...
There's a problem with the training.
It's not about being ready.
I do not do that.
I don't empty a stranger's butt.
I don't even empty a friend's butt.
I usually don't empty butts.
It's a matter of principles.
Can we talk about this later?
When I'm done eating, for example?
No.
No use speaking about it later.
I'm done with this.
It's weird, I don't like it.
I didn't say anything about the stockings.
But it cost me.
I'm making compromises, please do
the same for me.
- I'm done with the butt-emptying issue.
- I think I get it.
It's not right.
I'm done.
- Bon appetit.
- Thank you.
- Pretty, huh?
- I love it.
Am I bothering you?
Is it a theater or what?
- I'm trying to eat here.
- Hey, what's up?
- Do you know where I can find a beer?
- Try in your hair.
We had two 6-packs,
did you take them?
I don't know. I don't care.
So take your feather duster with
you and leave.
Come on, let's get out of here.
It's the new guy working for my father
The "guy" has a name you know.
Damn.
- What?
- Sorry.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I'm massaging.
That is nuts.
Are you having fun?
You don't feel anything down there!
What the hell...
- What are you doing again?
- Experiments.
He doesn't give a shit, he feels nothing!
Look!
Stop it, you're gonna burn him.
Lawyer.
No... this is personal.
I'll read it later.
Personal file?
Ok.
Thrash.
She has a little something, though.
Can't we create a hooker file?
- Bon appetit.
- Thanks.
Please.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Fuck, I keep forgetting.
Fuck, sorry.
That's good.
Driss?
Can you come?
Do you hear me, Driss?
Can you please come?
Driss.
What?
It's almost 9.
Philippe is waiting.
It's 9 alreday? I lost track of time,
it took forever for my bath to foam.
- This room's a piggery.
- Make me a coffee, I'm coming.
What about the babyphone?
It's supposed to always be with you.
And I want Nutella! Not jams with weird fruits
that nobody knows of.
I'm not going in there.
Even you!
I'm not gonna load you in the back
like a horse.
What about this one?
This one is not fit for me.
- What do you mean?
- I have to be pragmatic.
Pragmatic?
Oh damn!
Son of a...
Feels good, right?
- It does!
- So good.
It's nervous!
Let's go.
That's the neighbour again.
He always parks here.
He thinks it's his own parking spot.
I see some change coming.
- Hi, how is it going Patrick Swayze?
- What?
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- Can I see that?
- What the...
Come here.
Now read this. Read!
"No Parking"
- Louder. I can't hear you.   - "No Parking"!
- That's the way to do it.
- Read the bottom of it.
- "Reserved spot".
Now you keep that in mind,
and you get the fuck out of here.
Hurry up.
Get lost!
We're opening on tuesday.
It will be sold by tuesday night.
Can we go?
You've been looking at this for an hour.
You're gonna have to move at a point.
This painting expresses an overwhelming serenity.
And some violence as well.
I find it very moving.
Red stains on a white background
are moving?
How much for this thing?
I think it's 30 000 euros.
I can check if you want.
You'd better check indeed.
It sounds exaggerated.
You're not gonna pay 30 000 euros
for this piece of crap!
- Unbelievable.
- You'd better believe it.
This dude nosebled on a white
board and asks 30 000 euros for it?
Tell me Driss, why do you think
people are interested in art?
- I don't know, it's a business.
- No.
That's because it's the only thing
one leaves behind.
That's bullshit. For 50 bucks and a stop at a hardware
store, I can leave something behind as well.
I can even add extra blue
for free if you wan
Stop talking nonsense.
Give me a M&M's.
No.
No feet, No sweets.
Hey, I'm joking.
It's a joke!
- Oh it's a joke!
- Well yeah!
- A joke...
- A good one, right?
Really funny.
It's a classic.
No feet, No sweets.
Give me one.
- It's so good!
- Cool it.
Oh come on!
No legs, Philippe.
I'll say it again for the tight-ass chick.
Too bad there's no audience.
Sorry, I was wrong about the price.
- Sounds right.
- Yes.
It's 41.500 euros.
I'll take it.
Really.
Hi, Philippe.
How are you doing?
You summoned me, I'm here.
I'm listening.
What's so important?
I didn't 'summon' you...
Can't you guess?
Who is this guy?
Everybody's worried.
Yvonne told me he's unstable,
brutal.
He hit a neighbour.
Philippe, you know better than
me you have to be careful.
You can't let anybody come
at your place.
Especially given your condition...
In this case...
I'm not quite sure you know
who you're dealing with.
Go on...
I have contacts in the police.
He's not Al Capone, but...
he's not mother Theresa either.
He's just out of prison.
6 months for robbing a jewelry.
If at least he was qualified...
but I hear he sucks.
Be careful. You know guy from
the suburbs have no mercy.
That's it.
That's what I want.
No mercy. [=No pity in french]
He often hands me the phone,
you know why? He just forgets.
So you're right. He doesn't really
feel any empathy for me.
But he's tall, strong, healthy,
and not as dumb as you think.
So for now, given my 'condition'
like you say...
I don't give a damn about where
he comes from and what he's done.
As you want.
That's all you wanted to say?
Hey, Magalie.
- Do you have a minute?
- No, not really.
I just want to show you
something really fast.
- What is it?
- Don't freak out, you'll see.
- One minute, that's it.
- Deal.
- So?
- So I have a bathtub.
See.
- Really fascinating...
- Yeah.
- So what?
- I was thinking...
we could take a bath.
It's big. There's enough room.
I have bath salts, shower gel...
Alright.
Why not, after all?
Exactly. Why not.
Go ahead.
- Start undressing.
- Oh you're gonna play it naughty.
I like that.
I'm taking off my clothes.
No problem.
What?
Where are you going?
You agreed!
We don't even have to use the salts.
What are you looking at?
I'm always anxious in the morning,
when the mail arrives.
As Apollinaire once said...
Quote...
'I'm desperate when I don't hear from you...
Wait.
I'm lost, you're going too fast.
I was at : "As Apollinaire once said...".
Quote 'I'm desperate when I don't hear from you...
You might not get it, but this
is an intimate time.
- Nope, I don't get it.
- Give it back.
I'll shut it down if you explain.
There's nothing to explain.
He's sending letters.
Letters?
- To whom?
- To women, usually.
Tell me, who is it?
There's one in particular.
Eleonore.
Who is Eleonore?
I've never seen her.
How come?
That's how epistolary relationships work.
It means they write letters
they only communicate by mail.
I'm not stupid, I got it.
Are those the blue letters?
What a seducer.
He's 'epistoling' like a boss
What about you?
Isn't there someone?
Even Albert, the gardener?
- Not at all.
- Come on, I noticed.
He always has a smile for you.
Am I right?
- Am I right or not?
- Stop it now. It's ridiculous.
- So did he get some or what?
- What are you talking about?
- Did he plant his own cucumber?
What?
- I can't believe you...
- Albert, Albert...
- Soon.
- No!
Soon, trust me.
Fuck.
Hello...
Are you ok?
Do you need music?
Stay calm.
Calm down, Philippe.
Philippe.
Hey, Philippe.
Try to relax.
Breathe slowly.
Can you hear me?
Slowly.
You're gonna be ok.
I need air.
Air!
The fresh air feels great.
- What time is it?
- I don't know, around 4 am.
I haven't been out in Paris by
this time of the day in a long time.
What happened?
Medication side effect.
Doctors call these 'Ghost pains'.
I rather say that I'm a frozen steak
thrown in a burning pan.
I don't feel anything, but it's still painful.
It has to stop. There must be
something that will relieve you.
Yup. This could relieve me.
Well, we're all a little sick
when it comes to this...
I might even be sicker than you.
By the way, I meant to ask you.
About the ladies...
Can you...?
How does it work?
I have to adapt.
But concretely...
Can you do it or not?
I don't know if you're aware, but I have
no feelings between my neck and my toes.
So you can't.
It's complicated.
I can, but I'm not always
the one to decide when.
Also, there's pleasure to be
found elsewhere.
Really?
You can't imagine.
I sure can't.
What do you mean?
The ears, for instance.
What about the ears?
It's a very sensitive,
erogenous area.
So you get your ears licked?
I couldn't have thought about that.
Philippe.
- Hit that. It will help.
- What is this bullshit.
Come on, it can't get any worse.
Hit it.
Come on, harder.
Alright, let's share.
More.
- A bit more.
- Enough for tonight.
Sorry to bring this back, but I'm
really curious about the ear thing.
So if you have red ears, it means
you're turned on?
That's it.
Sometimes I even wake up with
hard lobes.
Both of them?
I met my wife Alice when we were
studying political sciences. We were 20.
She was tall and elegant.
Joyful bright eyes.
I saw pictures at your place.
It's the blonde one, right?
Not bad.
We had an incredible story together.
I wish you the same.
God I loved her so much.
Then she got pregnant once, twice...
She had five miscarriages.
Finally the doctors gave a diagnosis.
She didn't have much longer.
We decided to adopt anyway.
Sir.
Please.
Please!
Yes.
I want...
I'm gonna have a tarte tatin.
But cooked all the way.
Because the chocolate cake had a problem.
It was all fluid inside...
flowing everywhere. It was weird.
That's what a 'mi-cuit' is supposed to do, sir.
- That's why?
- Yes.
I'm still gonna have a tarte tatin.
I always liked competition.
Extreme sports, speed...
Going faster, higher...
I had it all with paragliding.
I got high, could see everything.
And breathe.
I was raised with the conviction I was
good enough to pee on the whole world.
I'd like to drink something.
My mouth feels dry.
That's one of the side effects
when you smoke  weed..
- What are the other ones?
- It makes you hungry...
And chatty.
And then a day of bad weather,
a day I shouldn't have gone paragliding.
But you did.
Maybe to to share Alice's pain,
because I knew she wouldn't make it.
In the end, two broken cervicals.
And only my head left to get high.
The pain didn't take my mind away.
My true disability is not having
to be in a wheel chair.
It's having to be without her.
What do the doctors say?
You know, with the recent progress,
they're gonna keep me alive until 70.
With massages and medication.
It's expensive...
but I'm a rich tetraplegic.
I would shoot myself.
Well, you can't even do that
when you're tetraplegic.
Oh shit. That's right.
That's tough, man.
What day are we today?
I don't know, the 8th or the 9th...
So it's official!
- What?
- You did it.
Your trial is over.
- So I'm hired?
- Of course you're hired.
- Can I count on you?
- Yeah.
Good.
Then give me the 'Faberge' egg back.
It's a gift from Alice.
She got me one each year we were
together. I have 25 of them.
They're really important to me.
I don't know, what do you...
I didn't do it.
What kind of egg is that?
Nina.
- What are you doing here?
- Hurry up, get in the car.
Put your seatbelt on.
How are you?
How is school?
Why don't you answer my texts?
I was busy.
So tell me, who did you talk to on the phone?
A cop, he wanted to talk to mom.
I faked her voice and told him
someone was going to pick him up.
Did you find my egg?
Did you find it or not?
I don't care about your stupid egg.
I didn't find it anyway.
What did you tell them?
Nothing. I had nothing to tell them.
I only had 30 grams, you know the law.
They couldn't do anything.
They kept me in custody and
eventually had to let me go.
Do you want to have a sandwich?
- I'm not getting in this car.
- Cool it.
- Let me go!
- Shut up. Who's taking you home?
- Who's taking you home?
- Get lost.
- It's none of your business.
- Get lost!
Her polished eyes are carved in delicate minerals,
And in this strange and symbolic nature...
'And in this strange'
'and symbolic"
- 'nature'
- How boring is that?
'Where the pure angel merges
with the antic sphynx'
I never know if 'sphynx' takes
a 'i' or a 'y'?
I'm so bored by all this.
It's a 'i'.
Do you really have to go through this bullshit?
A sphynx, daisies, angels...
Would you care for a guy telling you this?
Of course, some use a more basic method.
What's next?
What does Eleonore look like?
I don't know, I don't care.
It's intellectual. Emotional.
It comes before the physical
relationship for me.
Intellectual alright, but  what
if she looks like a dog?
You'd be having an intellectual
relationship with a dog.
Very elegant.
Really.
What else.
Bravo.
How long has it been going on?
He's such a pain in the ass.
Six months.
Six months?
And you've never seen her?
She really might be ugly. Or fat.
Or even disabled.
You should add that after the poem:
'by the way, how much do you weigh' ?
Write it.
Thanks a lot for your
useful advice, Driss.
Let's get back to it.
Where was I?
I think a sphynx was eating daisies,
running in the fields, doing weird stuff.
Let's see...
'strange and symbolic nature'
And in this strange and symbolic nature...
You have to call her.
- Where the pure angel merges with
the antic sphynx...
I'm telling you.
Call her.
Spot it, Driss.
I'm better at written communication.
Unbelievable.
Alright, but I'm gonna look for her
phone number, it stresses me out.
Hey!
She's from the north... that's not good.
Leave this envelope.
Never has a 'Miss France' come from the north.
They usually look like crap over there.
Give the envelope back now.
She wrote her phone number, god damn it.
It's a sign. She wants you to call her!
Please. Let it go.
She wrote her phone number, Philippe.
What do you think? It means 'Call Me'.
'I want to lick your ear lobe'.
- Of course, Philippe.
- You're not calling her, are you?
She doesn't give a shit about poetry.
Six fucking months of poetry...
He's bonkers.
['Call Me. I want you.']
- I won't talk to her.
- I'm gonna check if she has a weird accent.
Northern accent sucks..
Put down the phone!
- She wants a piece of Philippe.
- She's gonna have some.
Hello.
Nice voice, for a start.
Hello...
- No.
- Hello...
- Improvise, talk about daisies and shit...
- Eleonore?
- It's Philippe.
Well I...
I'm calling you because I really
wanted to hear your voice.
And so far, your 'Hello' already
fills me with joy.
Hold on. I'm gonna get her.
Stop with you complicated sentences.
- Hello.
- Eleonore. It's Philippe.
Philippe?
Igen.Szerettem volna rni
egy levelet, aztn...
I was writing you a letter.
And I thought, why not simply call her.
Don't forget to ask about her weight.
- Pardon me?
- Nothing.
I'm grieving.
I want to cry.
I'm afraid.
Lord give me peace...
Exactly, that's it!
I can't corner you.
- How great that you love 'Rimbaud'.
- Sorry.
- I was first in line.
- Eleonore.
I'm glad.
Yes, I am.
- What a big mouth... he can't be stopped.
- I'm sending you kisses.
Everyone kisses, licking ears and all.
Good.  So what's up?
There's good news and less good news.
- What about the good part?
- 116 lbs.
- 116 lbs?  That's really good.
Unless she's three feet tall.
On the other hand...
she wants a picture.
- So?
- Come on.
Good evening.
Can I see your tickets?
- Good evening.
- It's over here.
- Perfect.
- Have a good night.
- Good night to you.
- We'll be just here if you're looking for us...
We're not going to move.
Especially him.
Wait...
What do you think women want?
I don't know.
A cute, charming, elegant man...
No kidding.
They want money. Security.
Ask this dude.
And you have all that.
I might be naive, but I still hope
I have something more than my bank account..
She spent 6 months reading your goddamn
poems. And she likes it.
She's weird, don't worry.
I'm sure she doesn't give a damn
about the chair.
That's true.
Plus guys from the north drink so much
they're all beating their ladies.
She'll see there's no risk with you.
Jerk.
That's good thinking though, right?
Yeah, whatever.
The photo is a good test.
If she sends hers back it's a good sign.
You can send a picture of you
with the chair, but not too obvious.
You don't have to send a Telethon-like picture...
Drooling and all...
Looking like shit.
Alright, alright.
He has a problem.
A big one.
Shush yourself.
He's a tree...
A singing tree.
In german?
Stop shushing me!
It's in german anyway.
As if it wasn't enough.
You're crazy.
Oh man.
- How long does it last?
- Four hours.
Fuck.
You looked damn fine in the old times.
Which one?
This one.
There's also this one...
I like it a lot.
The chair is not obvious.
But you can see something is going on,
and you look really good.
- Are we doing this?
- I don't know.
Didn't you have a blast on the phone?
I did.
Is that all?
- I had a fucking blast.
- So?
So we're sending this goddamn picture.
That's what I'm talking about.
Let's do it!
Give me a cigarette.
Don't you ever knock?
Are you painting?
- Yes, get out!
- You're kidding me.
Ha ha, painting. Did you learn how to
read as well?
I told you to get out of here!
Or what? You'll beat me? Is that
how women are treated in your country?
You're out of your mind.
Fuck off!
- I'll leave when I want.
- Right!
- See, I'm deciding to leave now.
- Leave!
God damn it.
Replace this picture with
the other one.
Please post it yourself,
and be discreet.
As you want.
Now throw the other picture in the thrash.
I'm loosing it.
She's driving me crazy.
- What's wrong?
- Your daughter is.
- I was painting...
- You were... what?
Yes, whatever. I wanted to tell you...
She needs to cool it...
otherwise I will slap her.
- Alright, cool it a little.
- No, I'm not cooling anything!
Am I not your arms and your legs?
Yes.
Well I want to be your hands too.
So she can get what she deserves.
Since you can't really do anything
besides driving your chair over her.
Driss, don't you think you're exaggerating.
Yvonne.
Yvonne...
Well...
She might need a light admonition.
A light one?
She's 16, dressing and painting
her face outrageously.
She's also making out with the
annoying dude all over the house.
But that's none of my business.
It's her education.
What I have a problem with is
how she despises everyone.
How she talks to me. To you!
What are we? Slaves?
So if you let me, I'll give her
a lesson right now.
Alright, I get it. Let me take care of it.
Then take care of it.
Fast.
I'm gonna break something...
He's painting?  What is he painting?
I have no idea.
Get up, Philippe.
Fits you like a charm.
Right.
You need to respect the people working for me.
It's unacceptable. Do you understand?
I think she doesn't. Toughen up.
By the way I don't want to see this
dude here anymore.
- God I get it! Leave me alone.
- I won't leave you alone.
Do I need to drive my chair
over you to make you obey me?
That's it. We're getting there.
- You did that?
- Yeah.
I love it.
I'm not saying I would hang it
at my place...
but it's...
How much do you think we'll get from it?
We'll see.
We'll see more or less?
It's...
- What the hell?
- What?
- I wasn't gonna use the tongue.
- You're retarded.
Can't you go faster?
I can't run in these conditions.
- I'm at the maximum.
- The maximum... it's way too slow.
I can do 9 miles per hour.
Is 9 miles/hour ok?
Is it the best he can do?
Can't we get more?
- It's the maximum.
- It'll do.
Oh yeah...
No, no.
Stick to the ear.
There.
- Bye.
Hi Yvonne.
No he can't hear me.
Yvonne, trust me.
Ok.
We'll be home at 8:30.
Yes, we'll be on time Yvonne.
- What's up? She's freaking out?
- Yeah.
It's your surprise birthday again.
It's half an hour earlier.
She's all stressed out every year.
She's inviting all my family, every
year it's exactly the same deal.
They're mostly coming to see if
I'm still alive.
Just checking.
And I pretend to be surprised.
Everyone's doing their best.
But in the end we're all really bored.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Would you mind changing seats?
I called this one.
I would mind indeed.
- Oh believe me you'll do it
Come on! Just shift to the left.
There.
Very nice of you.
The suit makes you look like another man.
It looks good.
You look like Barack Obama.
Really?
She has the hots for me.
Barack Obama.
How cool is that.
It's a bit like someone called you...
Mitt Romney for instance.
Raffarin.
Or George Bush.
What are you doing?
You're gonna miss the concert.
Leave me alone.
- Are you menstruating or what?
- Get out.
- What's up?
Elisa.
- Leave me alone, goddammit.
- What did you take?
What did you do?
- Where did you find this?
- In Yvonne's purse.
Imodium?
What was your plan?
Suicide?
- You're just gonna stop pooping for 3 months.
- Leave me alone!
Wait... you took Ibuprofen too?
You're gonna die!
It's dangerous!
What should we do?
Call 911?
Why would you do that?
It's Bastien.
- What about him?
- He dumped me.
He doesn't care about me.
He called me a slut.
That's not ok at all.
Nobody would care if I died anyway.
Bullshit! Stop saying that.
Let's join the party.
Can't you go see him?
Talk to him?
- To who?
- Bastien. I'll pay you.
What do you mean you'll pay me?
You've really lost it!
Do you think I have time to deal
with childrens' heartaches?
- Please.
- Talk to Bastien?
Paying me?
Who do you think you're talking to?
Please, Driss.
How much?
You're silly.
Well, there's something.
There's a particular touch to it.
But I mean... 11 000 euros for an
unknown artist seems like a lot.
Hmm...
On the other hand, if I don't buy it
it's going to be worth the triple in a year...
And you'll tell me:
'I told you'.
Am I right?
Hmm.
- You told me he has a gallery in London?
- Berlin.
Berlin?
Well that's...
I don't know...
11 000 euros is a lot.
Come on, give me something.
Does she have someone?
Yes. Fred.
What about Fred?
They've been together for two years.
But it's an on and off thing...
There's a lot of tension.
Right now...
I know it's not going that well.
- Maybe because of me.
- Yup.
- Did she say something about me?
- No.
Alright, of course she did.
A little bit.
Yes! I knew it! She's got the hots for me.
What, you're spoofing me?
- No.
- Laugh as much as you want.
One day Magalie will be in my bed.
Hope well and have well.
Careful with the appetizers,
given your stomach issues...
I'm not a doctor, but I know if
you take Imodium, something's wrong.
Pardon me.  Please...
Can I ask you a favor?
A little piece for me?
No, Philippe!  We were chilling.
Yes.
Vivaldi, the Fours Seasons
You'll see, you'll like it.
What about that? Don't tell me
you don't feel anything.
Nope. Nothing.
Not at all.
For me, it's not music if you
can't dance to it.
Let's try something else.
Yeah. I know this one.
It's a commercial!
For coffee, right?
I shall leave thee now.
I am expected by the king at the castle.
I'm taking the minstrels there.
Let's go.
I'm a brave and good knight.
Wow, that's creepy...
It's about naked dudes...
They're running naked in the fields.
And giggling...
Alright, alright...
Bach was badass.
I'm sure he got all the chicks with his music.
It's the 18th century's Barry White.
Oh I know this one.
Everyone know it.
Of course.
"You have reached the Paris unemployment agency"
"All our lines are currently busy"
"The estimated waiting time is : two years"
Isn't it Tom and Jerry?
Tom and Jerry...
What a jerk.
Help!
Now it's my turn. We listened to your classics,
let's listen to mine.
'Earth, Wind & Fire'.
I told you about them. So good!
It's something else.
That's something else for sure.
Am I right?
Driss.
- Driss.
- I can't hear you.
Come on, dance for Philippe's birthday.
Come on. for Philippe.
There.
So...
With all that I didn't give you my present,
it arrived this morning.
I didn't want to ruin the party,
if she was ugly or something.
You never know.
But at least she responded.
Well...  Good night!
Alright, I'll open it...
So?
She does not look like a dog.
Not at all.
Oh damn...
It must be the only northern girl
with all her teeth.
There's a note with it.
'I'm coming to Paris next week. I'm waiting for your call.'
'Dot dot dot.'
You know what 'Dot dot dot' means, right?
What does it mean?
- That's good?
- Of course it's good, she wants you.
One dot, two dots, three dots,
she wants you, end of the story.
- She wants me...
Feels good, doesn't it?
- I'm too excited to sleep.
- But you will.
I'm putting the picture here.
She's watching you sleep.
There.
Good night, Philippe.
Sweet dreams.
Let's try the hat again.
- Not bad.
- No.
No. He looks like a chimney sweeper.
He can't be dressed too classic.
- What did I just say?
- Ok, so it's too classic.
- Forget the hat.
Regular or fancy?
There's something.
It works.
- What about this?
- Stop laughing.
- Let's go horse-riding...
- Come on.
Yvonne will take me there.
I'll go alone.
- Really?
- It's ok.
Yes. I'll manage.
Alright.
I think I'm freaking out a little.
Don't worry, noone can tell.
4 a x c minus b square
- b square?
I found 20, not b squ...
Hey.
Go take a walk, funny hair.
- So Bastien... You remember me?
- Yeah.
- Oh yeah?
- What's wrong?
I heard what you told Elisa.
It's not very nice.
- I didn't say anything...
- Shut up.
Now you'll act like a man and apologize.
- I'm sorry, man.
- Hands off me.
- Not to me, to her!
- Ok, to her.
And you'll bring her croissants every morning.
- Plain or with butter?
- What?
- Whatever. I don't care.
Do as you want, but do it right.
- You be nice.
- Yes. I'll be very nice.
Now move. Move!
And take care of your hair.
Put a hair clip or something.
What time is it?
4:45
Should I loose the hat?
Yeah. That's better.
What time is it?
46 - 47.
It's not changing that fast.
I'd like a whisky.
Yeah.
Please.
One more.
I don't if it's a good idea...
Make it a double.
Sir, a double whisky please.
- Hello.
- Hello, Driss.
What are you doing now?
Are you busy?
I'm working out.
How's it going?
Don't you want to get away?
No questions?
No. No questions.
- You want to leave?
- Yes.
Where are we going?
Get some fresh air.
I'll be there after a shower.
We're going. Take the hat.
- But ti's barely 6.
- We're going.
- Good evening.
Give him so champagne too.
It'll help him relax.
- I'm not stressed out.
- Really?    - No.
It's only us?
The other people didn't come?
It's just us.
Ok, I'm a little nervous.
Why?
I don't know.
We both know you're not the luckiest person.
The accident...
The chair...
Your wife.
It's Kennedy-like scary.
- Miss.
- Yes?
Can you give him the package?
Thank you.
Why?
What's that?
That's what you're worth in the art business.
I got 11 000 euros for your painting.
You shouldn't stop, you have
a hell of a talent.    - Yup.
That's a good deal.
I knew it.
I felt it.
It was instinct.
With the music and all...
It all blended...
And then, an epiphany!
I saw a light.
Ok, stay humble will you?
11 000 euros, though, can you believe it?
What was that?
Nothing. Just a hole in the cabin.
Philippe, tell me if something's wrong.
It was very nice knowing you.
No Philippe, I don't like these jokes.
Really
You're used to drama, but I'm not.
You have to be really insane to do that.
A little bit.
I'll tell you something, Philippe.
- You're a maniac.
- Really?  I didn't know that.
- Now you get Driss ready.
- Sure.
Right. In your dreams.
I'm not doing any of this.
I'll be waiting for you over there.
I'll take pictures...
'Get Driss ready...'
How are you gonna take pictures?
Laugh all you want. I'm not doing this.
- I don't want to anymore.
- Wait.
- Take it off.
- Wait, wait.
I don't have to anyway, right?
Wait, what's going on?
Is something wrong?
Oh man.
Fuck.
Why is it going higher?
What's going on?
Oh my god.
Hey, Driss!
Relax, for god's sake.
I'm relaxed, can't we get down now?
I've seen it ,it's cool. I'm done.
What the hell!
What is happening now?
Come on, Driss.
Listen to this.
Where can you find a tetraplegic?
Where can you... I don't know.
Where you left him.
Awful.
You're awful.
Driss, someone's here for you.
What are you doing here?
Why did you hide this?
- You answer the question.
- How did you find me?
The unemployment agency sent this.
It mentions the address.
- And what's that?
- Nothing. Let it go.
- What did you do?
- I fell from my scooter.
- From your scooter?
- Yeah.
Bullshit. Get up.
This way.
Damn.
That's your room?
- Tell me what happened.
- Nothing.
- Tell me.
- It's none of your business.
How is it not my business?
You're hiding here but it's none of my business?
We were only four and they screwed us.
But don't worry, they're gonna pay.
You're not gonna make anyone 'pay'.
Does mom know?
No.
- Don't worry, I have it covered.
- You have nothing covered.
- You're a pain in the ass.
- Right.
Now you stay here and you don't
touch anything.
- Can I lie down?
- You don't touch anything!
Alright, I got it.
Moron...
I'm telling you, he's with me.
Stop crying Nina.
He's not wounded, it's just a scratch.
He's fine.
Calm down, Nina.
Nobody's killing anybody.
It's only words.
Meanwhile I can't take care of him.
I'm working.
No, don't tell her.
You go crying in your room if you want,
but you don't tell her anything.
I think it's time for bed.
I'm gonna stay up for a bit.
Sit down.
Sit down here.
What do you think of that woman?
- She looks hot.
- What else?
Can we go upstairs now...
I have something to deal with...
I imagine her getting up...
and turning around...
so that I can finally see her face.
The boy looks like you.
- Adama?
- Yes.
I saw him earlier.
I think if I had crossed him in the street,
I could have told he was your brother.
That's weird.
Why?
Because he's not my brother.
Really?
It's complicated.
Is he your brother or not?
Ok. I get it.
Let's go.
My parents...
they're not really my parents.
They're my uncle and my aunt.
They came to get me in Senegal
when I was 8.
They couldn't have children, so they
went to see a brother who had a load of them.
They took the elder.
Me.
I was called Bakary.
That's my real name.
But there were several Bakarys in the
neighbourhood so they called me Idriss....
somehow it turned into Driss.
Then what?
Then out of nowhere my mother...
I mean my aunt...
she got pregnant twice.
Then my uncle died.
And then there were other guys,
other children.
I told you it's complicated.
About Adama. Don't you think he
needs a light admonition?
He came to get you, didn't he?
Driss.
I think it's the end of the road.
You weren't going to push a disabled's
chair your whole life anyway.
And since you worked well, you'll
get unemployment again.
Enough.
Let's go.
Come on.
Yeah.
Vassary Bakary. Bakary Vassary.
It's beautiful.
Very poetic.
It has an alliteration.
- Do you know what an alliteration is?
- No.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Bastien. Thank you.
Oh we're having a brunch tomorrow.
Could you bring something more...
Of course.
- Goodbye Yvonne.
- You didn't forget my little treats, did you?
No.
- Good, thanks.
- Say hello to Elisa.
See you tomorrow.
Bastien, my friend.
What's up?
So it's true.
- You're leaving.
- Yeah.
Don't worry, I have your number.
I'll call you very soon.
- I know it's gonna be tough for you. Be strong.
- It's a shame.
You know I'm getting your room?
There's a water issue in mine.
I might stay, in the end.
We'd have to get warm in the bed together.
It would be a little too small.
I'm not alone.
Here she is.
- This is Frederique.
- Hello.
Hi.
I get it...
- What?
- I understand, it's your...
So that's why...
Yes.
Well.
I'm not giving you a kiss, then.
I would be up for a threesome you know.
Well... I'm down.
Not now though, I have to leave.
But I can come back.
- I have stuff to do, but I'll be back.
- I'm joking.
Alright...
See you, dudes.
Mr Michel Saloudy.
Keep it on all the time!
Are you mad about Magalie?
No. Nice one.
Nice one, but...
it did seem weird that she would resist.
It never happened to me.
Kiss?
Yes. Sure.
Yvonne.
You're good...
See you.
Yvonne.
Wait.
We won't need that anymore.
Bye.
Watch your foot.
Let's go.
Wait.
What is your bank?
Ok.
Excuse me.
Could you please move your car?
You can't park here.
It's written over there.
- I'm moving.
- Thanks.
I'll call you back.
Why do you mind?
We're not even driving.
It's a matter of principles.
Go on.
Wait for me over there.
What are you doing?
I'm coming.
I can cancel my date you know.
Of course not.
Why would you do that?
Have a good tim.
Everything's fine.
Yvonne?  I'm ready.
Good. I'll be here in a minute.
Well, everything's ready.
You just have to serve.
Call me if anything's wrong.
- Call me, ok?
- Yeah.
So if you're ready, I'm gonna serve your meal.
Take these scrubs off.
I feel like in an asylum.
- Alright.
- Do you have a cigarette?
No. I don't smoke.
Not anymore.
To be honest I gave up recently...
and you should do the same.
Even if you're not exercising or something...
it's better for your lungs, your breath.
You're not going to eat.
What the hell!
Come on. Be careful.
I'm sorry.
- Good morning, sir.
- What?
It's the person you asked for ...
For the head massage.
It's Mr Jacquet.
Good morning.
Get out!
Leave me alone.
Leave!
- Is it my fault?
- No, non.
He got up on the wrong side of the bed.
'got up on...'.
Idiot.
Moron.
Driss Vassary?
- Yes
- It's your turn.
You've only had your driving license for a month.
Yes, but I've been driving for longer.
I mean I drove in private ways,
out of the roads.
Parking lots ...
I'm a good driver.
I read your file.
In your personal evaluation you only
wrote one word : pragmatic.
Yes.
It is important.
You forgot to mention another important
aspect in our company.
Did I?
You could just take the time
to read the poster line.
- Hey, that's a twelve feet rhyme.
Sorry?
You-could-just-take-the-time
To-read-the-pos-ter-line
12 feet.
- That wasn't on purpose.
- Your catchphrase is 'Just in time'.
Oh that's why you put Dali's watches..
A little artistic touch.
Maybe...
- You like paintings?
- I do.
- I like Goya.
- She's alright...
...didn't sing much since Pandi-Panda.
[Chantal Goya is a french children's singer]
Yes.
I'm coming.
I'm on my way.
- Are you ok?
- Yes.
Leave me alone.
Do you need water?
A wet towel?
Get out.
- I mean I can...
- Leave me alone.
There.
- Thanks, dude.
- You're welcome.
- Have a nice week-end.
- You too.
- What's going on?
- He's not doing well.
- Where is he now?
- He was in the garden earlier.
Ok.
So...
What's going on?
What's the deal with the beard?
Freud?
Abraham Lincoln?
An old dude, anyway.
Victor Hugo.
You need a good shaving.
Take care of yourself.
It was time I came back.
I'll be here in a minute.
Now what?
Now you let me decide.
Don't you like that?
A sharp fast cut would relieve me.
It's good to see you're doing better.
I did my best.
Open your eyes.
Oh my god.
It's terrible.
- It's really bad.
- No! It looks good.
No.
Look...
leather jacket, without sleeves.
A Village People-like cap.
I know!
Jose Bove.
You look exactly like him.
Really weird. An orthodox priest or something.
- The pope.
- Exactly, the pope.
Come on.
He's crazy.
What are you up to?
- I'm scared.
- No you'll see, it's awesome.
I look like my grandfather.
Really?
Oh Philippe, the moustache is turning me on.
What is happening to me?
- Ok, I'll shave the rest.
- Thank you.
Alright.
No. Please. No.
No.
No
Nein!
- Nein is what you mean.
- I'm not ok with that.
Philippe, ach.
So I'm your toy now.
You know you're mental right?
You have to get help.
Don't you feel like invading countries right now?
Ok, we're getting there...
just shave the rest.
You think it's funny?
Yes, I'm thinking about tetraplegic nazis.
How could they do the sign?
Ok, now you had fun. Shave it.
Heil.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
Vassary. I have a reservation at 1.
- Yes. Vassary.
- Follow me.
- Over here.
- Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
So, Philippe.
I'm not staying for lunch.
- Why?
- I'm not leaving you alone.
You just happen to have a date.
A date?
What do you mean?
Don't freak out. It'll be fine.
What the...
Only this time you can't flee.
By the way...
I took my time, but I found it.
Give her my respects.
Driss.
What's going on?
Hello, Philippe.
Philippe Pozzo Di Borgo now lives in Marocco.
He's married again, and had two daughters.
Abdel Sellou now owns a company.
He's married and has three children.
Philippe and Abdel remained close friends.
----Thanks for watching----
totoduchnok@hotmail.fr
djspideboy@gmail.com