Subtitle by : Harout Timing by : TaMaBin
(LatinoSubs) and
WWW.DIMENSIONPELICULAS.COM
On December 26th, 2004,
the deadliest tsunami
on record hit the South
East Coast of Asia.
The lives of countless families all
over the world changed forever.
This is the true story of
one of those families.
Oh God!
- ...Did you set the alarm before we left?
- Yes, that was the last thing I did.
No, I was the last one to leave.
I was the last one to leave
and I'm sure I didn't set it.
No darling, I was the last one out.
and I did, I promise.
Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
No no, I was the last one
'cause I went back in.
And that means the alarm is not set.
Cause I didn't set it.
Well, I guess that means
that we be coming home
to a large bunch of hippies...
...sleeping in our bed.
Well, just like your old college days.
It's alright, it's fine.
It's just turbulence Maria.
Please Turn Off Electronic Devices.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are about
to begin our descent to the airport.
The local time is 1:30 in the afternoon...
What are you doing? It's time to set down,
we are about to lend darling.
Lucas won't talk to me.
Please fasten your seatbelts...
...and return your seat to
the upright position.
Take my seat.
What did I do? I didn't do anything.
It's all right, just sit down
and stop worrying.
Buckle up!
Sit down please ma'am.
Lucas.
- Lucas.
- What?!
You know you could try being a bit nicer
to your brother, he's just scared.
What else is new, everything scares him.
I wonder who it takes off that.
KHAOLAK, THAILAND CHRISTMAS EVE
Take your stuff, don't forget any bags.
Have you been to Khaolak before?
No, it's our first time.
This is the best holiday season ever.
From dawn to dusk (?),
this area is very quiet.
Great for families.
The archipel (?) is brand new,
which just opened a week ago.
- You'll love it here.
- All right.
I'm sorry, but we made a booking
on the third floor, the sea view (?).
I know. We are sorry, that was a mistake.
But we feel that you
might love this better.
- Where do you come?
- Japan.
You don't look Japanese.
I work for a big company there,
and we moved around a lot, you know.
And you, you don't work?
I'm a doctor.
Not practising right now.
Just taking care of the kids.
I see, you got promoted.
That's nice!
- Mom!
- Yes.
Can I have one of these, please?
Lucas, if you are
thirsty, would you just...
- Drink water.
- Exactly.
- Boys, come and see this.
- Come on.
Look.
Isn't it great?
- Dad, can we swim there?
- Yeah, we could go swimming, yeah.
Ten, nine...
...eight, seven, six...
...five, four, three...
...two, one!
Look, mine is coming up.
- Is it?
- Is it? It is going up.
It's going a different
way than the others.
- It's catching up.
- Yeah, it's catching up.
Good morning. Good morning.
- Wake up!
- What are you doing?
It's Christmas!
It's Christmas morning.
- I want to go outside!
- No, no, no.
- Here I go!
- Wait, one at a time!
What is it?
Wow, a telescope. It's a
complete novastar that you
can stick on the ceiling,
the all moving way. (?)
Oh look, a scarf! I love it!
Thank you darling.
I mean Santa Claus.
What about you man? A ball?
Goal, yes!
I can't get sleep.
- ???
- Yeah. Sure.
Can we go outside and watch the stars?
Maybe tomorrow.
Close your eyes and
think of something nice.
Mom, come play ball with me!
In a minute, dear, play with Lucas.
- I can't believe you. (?)
- What?
I hide that thing and I forget
where I put it.
I was just checking to see, uh,
the home (???) over in Japan.
Liar.
I got a text saying that O'Neil
she's been given an two-year extension
on this contract.
Which means that the two of us are
doing the same job.
- That can only mean one thing.
- They can't fire you.
That would be too expensive. Don't worry.
Well I do worry. Because we can't
afford to lose this job, can we?
I can go back to work.
- Maybe it's time.
- In Japan?
No.
Oh, you want to go home?
It's not the worst idea, is it?
Well, you should think about it. But I'm
going to play with the boys now so...
- This is awful!
- Awful, I'll give you awful.
Catch it!
Oh no, go get it Lucas!
Henry, the boys!
- Lucas!
- Dad!
Lucas!
Mom!
- Lucas!
- Mom, help me!
Get me out of here!
Mom!
Lucas, stay there.
Stop!
Give me your hand!
Hold on to that!
Lucas!
Mom!
- I wanted to help!
- Get my hand!
Come on.
Lucas!
Mom! Dad!
Mom, Mom.
Mom!
Please.
Never do that to me again mom.
- Never do that to me again mom.
- I'm here.
All right. I'm here.
- Hung up that tree, that tree over there.
- Yes, yes.
That is perfect. That is perfect.
Be careful, Lucas.
No, don't move.
Stay very still.
I was a brave kid mom but I was scared.
I'm scared too.
Where is everybody?
I don't know.
Mom.
What?
- You're bleeding mom.
- Oh my God!
It's okay.
- I can't see you like this.
- It's okay. - I'm sorry.
You go first.
The tree there, the big one.
Do you think we can climb it?
Okay, let's go.
Dad
Wait. Did you hear that?
- Mom, there's nothing we can do.
- Wait.
We are almost there.
We have to get to safety.
No, we have to help the child.
Mom, if another wave catches us
down here, we will die.
We have to climb that tree right now.
Come on.
- Where are you?
- Mom, look at you, we need help!
We cannot risk it.
We can't risk it mom. Come on.
Listen.
What if that boy was Simon or Thomas?
What if they needed help?
You'll want someone to
help them, wouldn't we?
Simon and Thomas are dead!
Even if it's the last thing we do.
Where are you?
Dad
Look there, Mom, I see.
Are you okay?
Okay, okay.
What's your name?
I'm Lucas, what's your name?
- Daniel.
- Okay, Daniel.
You'll be okay, we gonna
get you out, okay?
Lift him.
It's all right. It's all right.
Are you okay?
All right.
Its okay. Don't worry.
Okay, okay.
Don't move. I'll be back.
Mom, I'm coming down,
just give me a second.
No, I can do it.
- Mom, I'm coming down.
- I can do it, Lucas!
Just stay there, please.
Mom. Mom.
Thank you.
Did you hear that?
Moma, look. They are coming for us.
Hey, over here!
Hey!
Climb down, Lucas.
No, no, no!
- Lucas?
- Mom, I'm here.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
My boys. I can no longer see them.
My boys.
Do not let them take me
anywhere without you.
Don't worry Mom.
I will not leave you alone. I promise.
All right, come on.
Where is Daniel? What about Daniel?
Daniel?
Lucas, where is Daniel?
I don't know.
Thank you.
- It's very cold in here.
- It's not cold, Mom.
Mom.
Mom, what's wrong?
I need some antibiotics.
Look in the cupboard.
I can't read the labels.
They are in Thai.
It got to be in English
and look at the side.
Look carefully.
Oh, thank God.
See that boy?
I'm all he's got in the world.
Do you understand?
I'm a doctor too.
I'm bleeding. You've got to stop it.
Please, I need some antibiotics.
Please help.
- Are you okay?
- I lost my husband and two children.
If something happens to me...
What color is it?
- What?
- My leg?
- Is it still red?
- Yes, it's still red.
- What does it mean?
- It's good.
As long as it doesn't turn black.
You need to eat something. Eat it.
- So bossy.
- I wonder who I take after.
Hello.
What's your name?
My name is Maria. And this is my
son Lucas. What's your name?
Hey, give her some tangerine.
She must be starving.
Be careful.
Turn your head to the side please.
You'll choke if you don't.
Please, please she needs help.
- Turn her head.
- Help her, Lucas, help her.
Mom, are you okay?
Mom, Mom are you okay?
What are you doing?
Mom, are you okay?
Stop it, Mom, that's enough!
Mom, stop it! Mom!
Mom, Stop it!
Francesca! Francesca!
Lucas, look at this place.
They're so busy in here.
You got to go and do something.
Go help people.
You're good at it.
- What do you want me to do?
- Just one thing. Anything.
Will you be alright?
Come on, Lucas!
I'm not going anywhere.
- I promise.
- Okay.
It's your family?
- Are you looking for your family?
- Have you seen them?
Okay, calm down!
I will help you. Okay?
I'll try to help you. Okay.
Okay.
Morten Benstrom?
Excuse me are you Joseph Benstrom
or Morten Benstrom?
Morten Benstrom?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I'm looking for my, my son.
- Your child?
- Peter Barry.
Yes. He'll be wondering where I am.
Peter Barry? Morten Benstrom?
Morten Benstrom?
Peter Barry? Joseph?...
Anne-Marie.
Sorry, what's your name again?
Anne-Marie! Anyone?
Radha Castorini.
Tatiana... Tatiana Jenochova.
Joseph Benstrom, anyone?
Morten Benstrom?
Radha Castorini?
Iris...
Anne-Marie De Brown?
- Morten Benstrom?
- Yes.
- Morten Benstrom from Sweden?
- I know your dad.
- Papa.
Yes, your papa is here.
- I'll bring him here. Okay?
- Yes.
No, no, no, you need to stay here.
I will bring your papa here. Okay?
Wow, no, you have to stay here,
you have to stay here.
Because it's a very long way, and you
you have to rest. Okay?
Okay?
Okay.
Benstrom!
Where is my mom?
Mom?
Mom! Mom!
No, no, what are you doing?
This is my mom's bed! Get off!
- It's okay, take it easy boy.
- No! My mom was here!
And she took her file.
Look, you have to come with me.
I will help you.
Okay?
Okay.
What's your name?
- What's your name?
- Lucas Bennett.
Where were you staying?
In uh, the beach resort in Khaolak.
Was somebody else traveling with you?
Lucas?
My dad and my two little brothers.
You know what happened to them?
Is there somebody we could call?
My granddad.
What's his name?
Bryan but I don't remember his number.
Lucas?
Maria?
Maria!
Fuck.
Lucas!
Maria!
Hey man! Are you all right?
I just need a minute.
I'll be up in a second.
Don't even bother, they are sending
trucks to the mountains.
Just hold on tight, okay?
They'll be here soon.
Yes, I know.
- Can you tell them I'm back?
- Yeah, sure. Hold on.
Hey boys, your dad is back!
- Dad! Dad!
- Dad!
Hey!
A lot of (?)
helicopters just flew by.
- Did they?
- Yeah!
Mom and Lucas...
Why don't you come
down a minute, Thomas?
What about me?
You stay and see if you can see
any more helicopters, that's okay?
- Okay.
- Good boy.
You're almost there, buddy.
Got it?
Oh, my God!
I still haven't find them.
Did you see a lot of dead people?
I'm just very serious, Thomas.
- Not mom and Lucas, right?
- No, I didn't see them.
I bumped my feet on the
reef, that was really hot.
Everyone was leaving.
Can we leave yet?
I need you to...
I need you to do me a favor, Thomas.
Everyone going to the mountains,
shelter, to be safe.
but I can't go with you.
You can't leave us alone again, Dad.
I have to keep looking for them, you see?
- You have to look after Simon.
- No!
No, stay with us, I can't look...
I have never looked after someone before.
- I'm scared.
- I know, I know.
I'm scared too.
But you know, you know, the most
scary bit for me...
- When the water hit.
- No.
After that, when I
came up, I was on my own.
That was the scariest part.
And then I saw the two of
you climbing to the tree.
I didn't feel so scared anymore.
I knew I wasn't on my own. You see?
What if Mommy and Lucas
are on their own right now...
Imagine how scared they'll be.
- We'll look for them-
- No!
Thomas, you have to look after Simon.
And I'm going to keep looking for them.
Okay?
Now (do ?) you understand?
Hello.
Yeah, I hear you.
Are you alright? Have you lost someone?
We're fine. We just want
to get out of here.
Excuse me. I've been trying
to place a call back home.
I wonder if I could use
your phone? It will be very quick.
Look around you man, everybody's
needing something right now.
Our battery is almost dead,
and we need the phone.
I'll see you in the morning. Okay?
- You're not you coming?
- No, I'm not coming.
Thomas will take care of you, all right?
Listen to me, you can
behave yourselves, okay?
You need to stay with this group.
And I'm going to be with you just
as soon as I can. Okay?
You gonna behave yourselves. Okay?
I love you.
Will you look out for my
boys for me? Please.
Come with us.
You know it's useless.
I can't stop looking.
I love you. I'll see you
tomorrow, I promise.
I love you.
Maria
Lucas
Oh no!
Hey man, are you okay?
Get in the car. We will drive
you somewhere safer.
My wife didn't want to come
to Thailand for Christmas holidays.
Because of my leg.
I insisted, my little girl Gina.
She's just two.
The noise woke me up.
I was alone in the room.
I went out to the terrace and saw the
sea coming in land.
It took me five seconds to reach the
stairs, but the water was already there.
It was not more than five seconds.
On the bed, I found a note from my
wife saying they were at the beach.
- You were at the hotel, right?
- Yeah.
My whole family was around the
swimming-pool when the water hit.
I found my middle son first, Thomas, he
was on top of this really tall tree.
It took me forever to
convince him to come down.
Because he was so scared, you know.
And I found my little one, Simon,
he was holding on top of a palmtree.
He's only five.
I sent them to the mountains.
You know. So I can keep looking
for my wife and my oldest son.
Toughest decision I ever made.
- Have you called home yet?
- I can't find a phone.
I'm saving my battery,
just in case, my family calls.
Please.
Thank you. It will be
very quick, I promise.
- Yes?
- Bry?
Yes Henry, thank God, how are you?
- Did you hear from anyone yet?
- No Henry, you're the first call.
Is everyone all right?...
Henry?
Maria and Lucas are not here.
What do you mean, not there?
The wave came and swept everyone away.
I found Thomas and Simon,
but not Maria and Lucas! ...
I don't know what to do or where to look!
Henry. Calm down!
I have to go. Many people
need this phone, okay?
- I'll call you later.
- Henry?
Sorry, sorry.
Thank you.
- What do you want me to do?
- You can't leave it like that.
- Go on, come on.
- Go on!
Come on man, come on.
I should call him back.
- Yes, Henry?
- Bry, it's me again. Look...
I promise I won't stop
looking until I find them.
- Okay?
- Okay.
I don't know what to do,
because it's nighttime.
I'll look in all hospitals,
I'll look in all shelters.
I will find them, I promise you that.
- I'll call you when I do.
- Okay.
- Okay. All right.
Thanks.
Can I go with you?
I'm afraid.
Close of you eyes,
think of something nice.
May I sit with you?
How old are you?
Almost seventy-four. And you?
Seven and a half.
Can you cover me?
- Is he alright?
- Yeah, he just have trouble sleeping.
With a blanket on him, he's alright.
You like looking at stars, don't you?
I do, (?)
constellations.
Here, the sky is different.
Some of those stars have been
burned out for a long, long time.
Did you know that?
They're dead, aren't they?
They're dead, but once
they were so bright...
That their light is still
travelling through space.
And we can still see them.
How can you know which one
is dead and which is not?
You can't, it's impossible.
It's a beautiful mystery, isn't it?
Lucas Bennett, can you come with me?
Sit here.
Your name is Lucas Bennett, is that right?
- Yeah.
- And your mother's name is Maria Bennett?
Is that correct?
We would like you to look
look at those things
please and see if you
recognize any of them?
Have a good look.
Take your time.
- Anything look familiar?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
- Do you recognize anything?
- I don't think so.
You don't think so?
Lucas?
Could you please come with us?
Mom.
- Where have you been you?
- Where the hell I have been?
Where the hell were you? You promised
me you weren't going anywhere.
I thought you were dead, Mom.
- Sorry.
- I thought you were dead.
We're so sorry.
Someone must have changed
her (?) during surgery.
How is she?
He had surgery in her
chest, but she lost a lot of blood.
He was too weak
to have her leg operated on.
She has to go back to
surgery when she recovers.
But she'll be okay, right?
Nothing. What next?
We should try to get a ride
and go to this hospital.
- Where are my kids?
- They took them away.
- They didn't let me go with them. Sorry.
- Where?
I don't know.
- I need to pee.
- You have to wait, Simon.
Mom... Mom. Wake up.
Mom, guess who I saw out there outside.
My leg. How is my leg?
Still red.
Please, my mom.
Her wound are looking very bad.
We're doing the best we can.
We are taking your mom to
surgery right away.
No, no, five minutes.
Give me five minutes, please.
I don't want you to slow down.
These are the names of my little
girl Ginna and Katie, my wife.
She's American. Will you
check the list for me?
Of course.
Please, they told us her
daughter could still be at ???
We already been to this hospital.
We have checked all
hospitals. But this one, please.
Five minutes. Please
just wait five minutes.
I won't be long, I'll be right back.
Lucas... Lucas... Is there
anything left in the can?
Don't worry, I'll get you something.
- I need to pee.
- Can you hold it?
No.
Simon, what are you doing?
Hurry up, they're going to leave us here.
What are you doing?
- No luck.
- Sorry.
Sorry, and thanks for waiting.
We go now.
Dad!
It's Lucas!
- Lucas! Lucas!
- Lucas!
- Simon! Thomas!
- Lucas! Lucas!
Are you okay?
Lucas!
- Dad!
- Lucas!
Let's go, no need to wait.
- Mom is here.
- What?
She's very weak. She says
some weird stuff sometimes.
The nurse is going to operate
her as soon as they can.
Mom, look who's here.
Hey. Hey, my darling.
Mom.
- Is everyone okay?
- We are all okay.
- I'm gonna die.
- No, no.
Is it okay to take this off?
- You're back?
- Yeah.
I can rest now.
Maria, what?
What, what darling?
- I'm dying.
- No. No.
- You're gonna be fine.
- Take care of my babies.
Hey, that's not why I came here for.
You're gonna be fine. They're
going to take good care of you. Okay?
I promise you we are going to be fine.
- Henry. I'm scared.
- We're gonna fine.
I promise we're going to be okay.
We're taking her for surgery.
We need to take her now.
Okay.
I love you. You're gonna be okay.
I love you so much.
I love you.
I'm sorry, I'm going to let
go of your hand... (???)
Lucas, thanks for taking care of mom.
We took care of each other.
- Dad?
- Yeah.
There is something I didn't tell Mom,
and really need her to know.
I have a family too.
I've been saving my strength...
Because I want to see them...
One more time.
No, no.
Oh do you have to?
- We don't want you to feel any pain.
- I'm afraid to go to sleep.
You're in good hands.
Close your eyes and think
of something nice.
Think of somehing nice.
Mom is okay, Lucas.
We're going home.
Mr. Bennett, I'm one of the.. (???)
... U.S. health insurance (???)
We are here to care of your family.
They have nothing to worry about now.
In a few hours, we will be
at Singapore General Hospital.
Where your wife will receive
the best treatment in your living.
They will take you to the
plane. See you there.
Have a safe flight.
Where are we going?
They take us to Singapore.
We'll be safe. Okay?
Please take your seat.
We will be taking off shortly.
Okay.
- Can I just...
- Yeah, okay. One minute.
How are you?
Here, with you.
Mom, this morning...
I saw Daniel again...
He was so happy.
He was in somebody's arms.
I bet it was his dad, Mom.
I'm proud of you.
I love you so much.
Thank you. Thank you.
Sorry, but you have to get back
to your seat now.
Fasten your seatbelts, please.
I don't want to.
No? You have to fasten
your seatbelts in the plane.
WE ARE AT THE BEACH
Its all right.
THE IMPOSSIBLE
This film is based upon the true story of
Maria, Quique, Lucas, Thomas, and Simon.
Subtitle by : Harout Timing by : TaMaBin
(LatinoSubs) and
WWW.DIMENSIONPELICULAS.COM