sub by maXeer
My name's Ralph and I'm a bad guy
Ah.. Let's see
I'm 9 feet tall
I weigh 643 pounds
Got a little bit of a temper on me
Hey, you moved my stump!
My passion bubbles very
near the surface, I guess..
I'm not gonna lie
Anywho.. what else?
Aaah...
I'm a wrecker I wreck things
Professionally I'm gonna wreck it!
I mean, I'm very good at what I do
Probably the best I know
The thing is, Fixing is the name of
the game Literally, Fix-It Felix, Jr.
I can fix it!
So, ya.. naturally the guy with the name
Fix-it Felix is the good guy
He's nice enough as good guys go
Definitely fixes stuff really well..
but,.. aah.. if you got a magic hammer
from your father, how hard can it be?
If he was a regular contractor..
carpenter guy
I guarantee you, you would not be able
to fix the damage that I do.. as quickly
And when Felix does a good job
He gets a medal
But are there medals for wrecking stuff
really well? To that I say HAAH!!
And no... there aren't
- So cool..
- This animation is so real
30 years I've been doing this
And I've seen a lot other games
come and go.. kinda sad
Think about all those guys from Asteroids?
...Boom!! ..gone..
Centipede??
Who knows where that guy is.. you know
Look a steady arcade game is nothing
to sneeze at I'm very lucky
It's just.. I got to say:
It becomes kinda hard to love your job
when no one seems to like you for doing it
All clear..
The Arcade's closed!
Woo.. what a day.
So, you wanna head to Tappers, Ken?
If you're buyin' buddy
Quittin' time!
I donno.. Maybe I won't be feeling this
way if things were different after work
But.. it is what it is.
- Good job, everyone!
Felix and the Nicelanders
go hang out in their homes..
which he just fixed and very..you know
They go to their homes, I go to mine..
which happens to be.. a dump
And when I say a dump I don't mean like
a shabby palce, I mean an actual dump
Where the garbage goes
and a bunch of bricks
and smashed building parts.. that's..
That's what I call home.
I guess I can't bellyache too much
without my bricks, without my stump.
It looks uncomfortable
it's actually fine
I'm good
But..
if I'm really honest with myself
I see Felix up there..
getting patted on the back..
people are giving him pie..
thanking him and..
so happy to see him all the time..
Sometime to think..
Man!.. Sure must be nice
being the good guy
Nice share, Ralph. As fellow
bad guys we've all felt
what you're feeling and
we've come to terms with it
Really?
- Right here, I'm Zangief, I'm bad guy!
I relate to you Ralph When I hit bottom
I was crushing man skull
like sparrow egg between my thighs
And I think, why you
have to be so bad Zangief?
Why can't you be more like good guy?
Then I have moment of clarity
If Zangief is good guy.. who'll crush man
skull like sparrow's egg between thighs?
And I say, Zangief, you are bad guy,
but this does not mean you are bad guy.
Right, I'm sorry. I
just..You lost me there.
- Zombie, bad guy.
Zangief saying:
Labels not make you happy
Good...
Bad....
You must love you
Yea.. inside here!
Whoa, whoa ..ok oh!
alright ..I get you..
Watch out, it's dripping
- Question, Ralph
We've been asking you
to BAD-ANON for years
now and tonight you..
you finally show up
Why is that?
- I donno, I just felt like coming
I mean, I suppose it has something
to do with the fact that.. uh..
Well.. today is the 30th Anniversary
of my game
Happy Anniversary, Ralph
- Thanks, Satan.
Err,. it's Satine, actually
- Got it!
But here's the thing..
I don't wanna be the bad guy anymore
You can't mess with the program Ralph.
- You're not going Turbo, are you?
Turbo? No, I'm not going Turbo
C'mon guys!!
Is it Turbo who don't want a friend?
Or a medal?
or a piece of pie every once in a while?
Is it Turbo who want more out of life?
- Yess...
Ralph, Ralph.. we get it!
But we can't change who we are
And the sooner you accept that...
..the better off your game
and your life will be.
Hey, one game at a time, Ralph
Now let's close out with the
Bad Guy Affirmation
I am bad, and that's good
I will never be good
And that's not bad
There's no one I'd rather be than me
Ok guys, see you next week
Hang in therel, Ralph.
- Hey Zombie, don't forget your hatchet
There you go
Welcome to Game Central Station.
Sub by: maXeer
MC
Step aside sir, random security check
Random my behind, you always stop me!
- I'm just a sarge for tech
and doing my job, sir.
Name?
- Lara Croft.
- Wreck-It Ralph.
And, where you're coming from?
- Uh... Pacman.
You bringing any fruit with you?
- No.
No, no fruit.
- Ok then, where you headin?
Uh.. Fix-it Felix Jr.
- Anything to declare?
I hate you
- I get that a lot.
Proceed.
Bad guy coming..
If you leave your game
stay safe, stay alert..
and whatever you do..
don't die..
Because if you die outside your own game
you don't regenerate ever
Game over.
Here you go, buddy
It's fresh.
It's straight from Pacman's
Hang in there, guys
Name?
- Argggghhhh!!!
Happy 30th Anniversary
They're having a party without me
Pacman? They invited Pacman?!!
That cherry
chasing dot muncher
isin't even on this game
Great party, Felix
- Why.. thank you, friend
Felix... you're needed
on the dance floor
Oh! I bet that's Mario
Fashionaby late, for the norm
I'll get it, Felix.
It's Ralph.
He'll wreck the party.
- Get rid of him, Felix.
Oh right! I'll go talk to him
Carry on everyone
Ralph, can I help you?
Hey Felix. Just wanted to check
on you I saw a big, uh..
explosion or something
over the building there
Oh.. That was our.. just fireworks
- Fireworks, okay
Somebody's birthday.. or?
- Well... it's.. more of an anniversary
The 30th Anniversary of our game, actually
- What? is that today?
I know
- Oh, I'm such a dummy with dates
Anyway.. uh..Congratulations!
- Thank you, Ralph.. and to you too.
Uh, just the heads up Felix They're
bringing out the cake in just a few shakes
Hey, Glenn!
- Ralph!
Cake..Heard about this cake stuff
Never had it. No one ever
seem to throw it out so I..
it never, never ends up in the dump,
I never actually tasted it
I always wanted to try cake
I don't suppose you'd like to
come in have a slice? would you?
Hello, everybody
I'm okay, I'm okay Fit as a fiddle
Now... You all know Ralph.
- Evening
Evening Nel..
Lucy..
Don. Dana.
- Diana.
Big Gene!
- Why is he here?
He's just here for a slice of cake
- And, am a big part of the
game technically speaking
Uh. Why are you here, Gene?
Oh look!!
The cake
Well I'll be dit
You really outdone yourself, Mary.
Oh and look, there's
all of us at the top
- Each appartment is
everyone's favourite flavor
Your Woods, is red velvet
- Guilty!
And lemon for Lucy Brum cake for Gene.
And for Felix..
- Hey, Mary...
Umm.. what.. what's the flavor of
that mud that I'm stuck in there
Hm? Oh.. Chocolate
- Never been real fond of chocolate
Well, I did not know that
- One other little thing,
I hate to be picky but..
you know this angry little
guy here would might be a
lot happier if you put him
up here with everyone else
See that? Look at that smile
- No, no no.. You see Ralph,
there is no room for you up here
Well what about this we can make room
Here, we can take turn..
Easy!
How about.. we just eat the cake?
- Hang on!
Felix needs to be on the roof because
he's about to get his medal
Well, how about we just take that medal
and give it to Ralph for once.
Would that be the end of the world Gene?
- Now you're just being ridiculous
Only good guys win medals
and you, sir .. are no good guy
I could be a good guy if I wanted to
And I could win a medal
Uh huh? and when you do
come and talk to us
- And then would you finally let me
be on top of the cake with you guys?
If you win a medal We'll let you
live up here in the Penthouse
But it will never happen because you're
just the bad guy who wrecks the building
No, I'm not
- Yes, you are.
No, I'm not!!!
Yes, you are
Alright, Gene, you know what?
I'm gonna win a medal
Oh I am gonna win a medal The shiniest
medal this place has ever seen
A medal that will be so good that it
will make Felix's medals wet their pants
And goodnight Thank you for the party
Is he serious?
- Oh please..where is a bad
guy gonna win a medal?
Of course he's not serious
I've never been more serious
about anything in my life
That's why I came straight here Tapper
You never give me a bum steer now..
C'mon.. where can a guy like me
go and win a medal
I don't think such a game exist, Ralph
Oh c'mon.. You know people,
there's gotta be..
- Hey, Tapper, need a root beer
Coming..
Hold that thought
Okay! As you were saying?
- I was saying...
I can't spent another 30
years living alone in
the garbage I'm not going
back without a medal
Well, I don't know what to tell you
Maybe somebody left a medal here
You're welcome to take tour
to lost and found
Okay.. let's see what we got here
Oh!! Shoo, shoo
C'mon, get down
Mushroom?
No
Wat is this?!
Oh c'mon, Zangief Gross
What am I doing?
Hey, excuse you!
Our mission: Destroy all Cy-Bugs
We are humanity's last hope
- You ok there, space killer?
We've only been plugged
in a week and everyday
it's climb the building and fight bugs
Climb the building fight more bugs
Ya ya ya ya, right, look
Easy on the overall spaceman!
The toughs all over alright?
- And offer what.. a lousy medal??
Medal? You win a medal?
- Yea, Medal of Heroes
Is it shiny?
- Pretty shiny
It says Hero on it?
And you say, you win it
by climbing a building?
And fighting bugs
- Right, bugs. Listen, is there
any chance I could go
with you to your game
you know, maybe get one of those medals?
- Negatory.
Wha.. is that mean maybe?
- No. Look, only the
bravest and the best..
serve in our corps..
Bug!!!
We are humanity's last hope
Attention! The Arcade will open
in five minutes
Please report to your game
I can't feel my legs
What is all this stuff
Huh.. smells like Ralph in here
Alright, what is.. what was it called?
Hero.. hero's something...
Hero's.. uh.. duty .duty
Hero's duty
Sorry, Q*bert.
It's me, Ralph
The wall
Morning kids, c'mon in. Good to see you,
Good to see you. You too, little fella
Quarter Alarm.
This is not a drill
Sweet golden medal
On a planet with no name a top secret
experiment has gone horribly wrong
You are humanity's last hope
Rootin tootin, ready for shooting
Now listen up, cause I'm
only gonna say this once
Fear is the four letter word, ladies
You wanna go pee-pee in your big boy
slacks, keep it to yourself
It's make your mamma proud time
- I love my mamma
Heads up
First Person Shooter coming through
Oooh Robot
Gameplay in three, two, one
We are humanity's last hope
Our mission..
Destroy all Cy-bugs
You ready rookie? Let's find out
Sweet engemawni
Wait a minute
Cy-Bug 12 o'clock
take it, rookie
Watch it, rookie
These monsters become what they eat
My gun Give me that thing
Shoot the eggs before they hatch
Oh no no, something
coming out of their bottom
Oh gross
- Markowski, get back in formation
Alright ladies, The kid and
whispers and ticle fights stop now
The entrance to the lab is straight ahead
- I'll meet you guys inside
No..
- Thank you, hurry
When did videogames become
so violent and scary
Take me out of here
Get him..
GAME OVER
What a????
Hey, get..get of me
It's game over. Stop it
Reaching up, reaching up
Cease fire, cease fire
Attention! Return to start positions
Here, here let me help you there
Sorry about that, I just
Ah yea, well you must be upset
- Markowski.
Who? Wow oh. ye.. me, I'm
Ya, I'm Markowski.
What's the first rule of Hero's Duty?
- No cuts, no buts, no coconuts?
Never interfere with the
first person shooter.
Our job is to get the gamers
to the top of that building
So they can get a medal and that's it
So, stick to the program, soldier
- Right, right.. aye aye!
Quarter Alarm.
- Alright pussywillows.
Back to start positions
Yea, right
No way I'm going through that again
The last really gives the medal, huh?
New racers daily Sweet
I got next game
- Go away kid, we're gonna
play all 9 of today's racers
Oh..Sorry.
Hmm.. Where is the
wrecking guy?
Where is Ralph?
He should be wrecking the building
Shhh.. stick with the program
Fix it Felix.
I can fix it
Ralph, quarter alert Game on
Do something, Felix.
- Just act natural
I'll fix it
Oh my reend! where is he?
Mister Litwak.
- What's the trouble sweetheart
The game's busted
I can fix it I can fix it
Oh boy, looks like the game's
gone cuckoo like my nana
Sorry sweetie, here's your quarter back
But what about the game?
- I'll have someone look at it tomorrow
But if he can't fix it,
it might be time to
put old Ralph and Felix out the pastures
..like my nana
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are Out of Order
- Sweet mercy, without
Ralph, we are doomed
They're gonna pull our plug
Okay, everybody calm down..
Ralph probably fell asleep in
the washroom of Tappers again
See?
There he is now
Why.. it's Q*Bert.
What brings you here, neighbour?
What's he saying, Felix?
- Standby, my Q*Bertee is a little rusty
Ralph's gone Turbo!!
Shining..
Attention! The Arcade is now closed
You get a load of Markowski
Shut your chew-holes!
Cy-Bug.
Taes
Slick tidly weeky pie size
- I'm Fix-it-Felix Jr ma'am,
from the game Fix-it-Felix Jr.
Yumani, jemani look at that
high-definition your face...
It's amazing
Flattery, don't charge
these batteries civilian
Now state your business
Oh.. I'm looking for my colleague.
Reck-it Ralph.
- Never heard of him.
Well..Q*Bert saw him come in here
- Impossible, nothing gets past me
That came from the tower
Nice shells be sH♪!&!
Okay..
that was easy
Congratulations soldier
It is my honour to bestow upon you..
..the medal of heroes
No way..
- Attention.
History will long revere
your courage and sacrifice
Well..Thank you
- You have edged in the rock of
virtue, a legacy beyond compare
Thanks guys At ease...
You are the universe's greatest hero
The living embodyment of
all these core represents
Bravery, integrity,
grace under pressure...
and above all... dignity
- Escape mode activated
Incoming
Ralph.
- Cy-Bug.
So long, sucker
Sugar Rush?
Oh.. No!!
This is a candy go-cart game
over by the Wack-a Mole
I gotta get out of here
Oh no..My medal?? Whe..
whe.. wait.. where...???
No no no no no my medal
Hi, mister
Hello
Man.. you scared me kid
Uh!!..Nearly soiled myself
- What's your name?
Uh... Ralph..Wreck-It Ralph.
- You're not from here, are you?
No well, yeah. I mean not from right in
this area I'm just doing some work here
What kind of work?
- Just some routine candy tree trimming.
You probably wanna stand back..
in fact This whole
area is technically closed
while we're trimming
Who's we?
- Candy tree department
Oh, where's everybody else?
- Ah, it's just me today
So you just meant like the royal 'we'?
Yup.. that's right
Hey, are you a hobo?
- No
I am not a hobo But I am busy, okay...
so, will you go.. go home
- What's that?
Didn't hear you, your breath is
so bad it made my ears numb
Listen, I try to be nice
- I try to be nice
Your mimicking me
- Your mimicking me
Okay, that is rude...
- Okay, that is rude...
and this conversation is over
- and this conversation is over
I won't grab that branch if I were you
I'm from the candy tree
department so I know what..
- It's a double stripe
Double stripes are prank... Kadoing!!
Hey, why are your hand
so freakishly big?
Uh.. I donno
Why are you so freakishly annoying?
Why are you so freakishly..
Sweet mother of monkey milk, a gold coin
Don't even think about it, that is mine
- Race you for it!
Hey hey hey hey
I don't have to race for it
cause that's mine
The winner
- Give it back, give it
Double stripe...
Thank you
Wait, let me talk to you for one second
Ok, here's the thing, I'm not
from the candy tree department
- Lying to a child
Shame on you Ralph
- But, I wasn't lying about
the medal, that is my medal
That's why I was climbing the tree..
It's mine, it's my
It's precious to me, that thing is this..
my ..it's my ticket to a better life
Yea, well, now it's my tic-ket
What the..
- See you champ!
Come back..
I'll find you
I will find you
- Double stripe
Nowhere to hide
Yea, banged around in here
like some kind of hot
shot Then he went barreling
down into that..
sweet little game like a crazy person
- Sugar Rush.
Cy-Bugs would chew up
that game faster than a
chicken hawk can a coop
of crippled roosters
What was that now?
- What are you, a fig?
There was a Cy-Bug on that shuttle
Do you even khow what a Cy-Bug is?
I can't say that I do, ma'am
- Cy-Bugs are like a virus
They don't know they're in a game
All they know is...
eat, kill, multiply
Without a beacon to stop them
..they'll consume Sugar Rush
- But you think they'll stop there?
Yes!
- Wrong!
Viruses do not stop
Once those Cy-Bugs finish
off Sugar Rush..
..they'll invade every other game
until this Arcade is..
nothing but a smoking husk
of forgotten dreams
Kohut, my cruiser.
Sheepers, is she always this intense?
- It's not her fault
She's programmed with
the most tragic backstory ever
One day she didn't do a perimeter check
Her wedding day
Wait, ma'am.
I'm going with you
Like fun you are short stack You die
outside your game, you don't regenerate
Well, neither do you, ma'am
And it is my job to fix
what Ralph wrecks
And I cannot ask you
to risk your life cleaning up his mess
No flex on this one ma'am
I am coming along with you
Citizens of Sugar Rush.
Just in time
All hail, our rightful ruler
King Candy.
Hallo, my loyal subjects
Have some candy
Thank you for that stering
introduction, Sour Bill.
And thank you to today's avatars
It was a wonderful day of racing
It was.. but now the Arcade
is closed so it's time to
wipe the slate clean and race
to decide our new avatars
The first 9 racers to
cross that finish line
will represent Sugar Rush
as tomorrow's avatar
Race, race, race, race
- Calm down
Listen, this event is pay to play
we all know this
The fee to compete is one gold coin from
your previous winnings, if you have won
Which I.. I have
Let me go first
King Candy.
Taffyta Muttonfudge.
Say sweet
Adorabeezle Winterpop.
Gloyd Orangeboar.
Coin stealer
Wait till I catch that brat
- Minty Zaki.
Snowanna Rainbeau
Rancis Fluggerbutter.
Jubileena Bing-Bing.
Swizzle Malarkey.
Candlehead.
Sour Bill, who is that last one?
Vanellope von Schweetz.
- Yippie
I'm in the race
- Venellope?
The glitch.
No, no
Everything is alright Security!!
Come here, kid
- We're not gonna hurt
you, you little freak
Get back here
You....
Give me back my medal right now
No, no...
- What is that?
What are you doing?
Come back here
Can't move
- Now, we got him
Oh good, the cops
She went that way
Oww... what are you doing?
Okay folks Calm down
Everything's alright
The monster's been caught.
We'll repair all the damage Don't worry we
will have our race before the Arcade opens
And I'm in it
There is no way that
I am racing with a glitch
Francis, Candlehead, come on.
Sour Bill, that glitch
cannot be allowed to race
And bring that thing to my castle
Sour Bill, detafify this monster
so we can see what we're up against here
Mmmkay..
Milk my duds, it's Wreck-It Ralph?
Ya, who are you?
The guy that make the donuts?
Please,... No!
I'm King Candy.
I see you're a fan of pink
- Salmon, salmon.. that
is obviously salm..
What are you doing here?
Look! Your candiness
This is just a big misunderstanding
Just get me out of this cupcake I'll get
my medal, and I'll be out of your way
Your medal?
Bad guys don't win medals
Well, this one did!
I earned it over in.. Hero's Duty.
You game jumped? Ralph!
You're not going Turbo, are you?
What? No no no no..
- Because if you think
you can come in here...
to my kingdom and take over my game..
you've got another thing coming...
Easy! Your Puffyness
It's not my fault one of your children
of the candy corn stole my medal
Children of the candy corn?
Who...?
The glitch... the coin she used to buy her
way into the race, that was your medal?
She did what?
I need that back
Well, I'm afraid I can't help you,.
it's gone
you know, it's.. it's
nothing but code now
and it will stay that way until someone
wins the cup at the end of the race
Well, maybe I'll just have to have
a little talk with the winner then
Is that a threat I smell?
Bwlaaah..beyond..halitosis is so
obviously you're suffering from
Listen, nelly wafer, I'm not
leaving without my medal
Yes, you are!
Wynnchel, Duncan,
carry him out of that cupcake
And on the first train back home And if I
ever see you here again Wreck-It Ralph...
..I'll lock you in my Fungeon
Fungeon?
- Fun-dungeon? You know,
it's a play-on words?
It's a Fu..
Never mind
Now, I got a glitch to deal with
thanks to you
Goodbye, Wreck-It Ralph.
It hasn't been a pleasure.
It's hard as a rock
- I can see that
Get the tools
- What tools?
Quiet you!
What?? No!
- Take it easy big boy
Stay away from me
- He's getting away
Quick, call out the Devil-dogs
Chocolate I hate chocolate
I gotta get my medal back
The pot goes to the winning racer
Hey kids, can I talk to you for a second?
Hello, fellow racers
It's that little crumb snatcher
Candlehead, Taffyta, Rancis
you're looking well
Came by to check out
the competition, huh?
Well, here it is the Lickety Split
- Jeez, looks like she built it herself
Built it myself
Fastest pedal power west to
the Wack-a-Mole Check her out
Oh..Vanellope
It's so.. you
But.. you have to back out of the race
Oh no, I.. I don't, you know
cause I..i paid my fee...
and I'm on the board
So, ya.. I'm definitely racing
Ya, well.. King Candy says
glitches can't race
I'm not a glitch, Taffyta
Just got pixlexie, okay
The rules are there for
a reason, Vanellope
To protect us
Say, I'm you..
I'm in my weird little car..
and I'm driving and..
actually feel kinda cool for once..
and then all of a sudden.. oh no..
I'm gli..gli..gli..gli... glitching
See, you're an accident
just waiting to happen
- Oh no, I gli..
gli..gli..gli..glitch too
Oh hey hey, what are you doing?
- Uncool
Stop. You're breaking it
Please, I just wanna race like you guys
You will never be a racer
because you're a glitch
And that's all you'll ever be
Hey.. leave her alone
Let's get out of here
Scram, you rotten little cavities
before I throw you in a mud
What are you looking at?
You're welcome, you rotten little thief
- I'm not a thief
I just borrowed your
stupid coin I was gonna
give it back to you as
soon as I won the race
It's not a coin It is a medal
Coin, medal.. whatever... just go back to
your own dumb game and win another one
I can't, I didn't win it in my game
I won it in Hero's Duty.
Hero's Duty?
It's not that kind of duty
I bet you really get a 'watch where you
step' in a game called Hero's Duty?
What'd you won the medal for, wiping??
I hope you wash your hands
after you handle that medal..
Listen..
- One more, one more
Why did the Hero flush the toilet?
Say 'why?'
- Why?
Because it was his 'duty'!
- How dare you insult Hero's
Duty, you little girlsnipe!
I earned that medal You better get
it back for me, too schweetz sister
Well unless you've got
a go-cart hidden in
the back-folds of your
neck, I can't help it
What a moron...
Hey, genius..that's a jaw-breaker
You're never gonna...
Enjoy your little tantrum day, poor baby?
- Leave me alone
Look, you want that medal, right?
And I want a race
So, here's what I'm thinking
You help me get a new cart a real cart
and I'll win the race and get
you back your medal
You want me..
to help you???
All you gotta do is break
something for me...
C'mon, what do you say, friend?
We are not friends
Oh. C'mon... pal
You son of a gun
C'mon buddy Just shake on it
Ah.. c'mon jumbo
Ralph my man.. my main man...
Hey, my arms getting tired
We have a deal or not?
You better win
Well, I'll say this much... they don't
call your friend 'Wreck-it' for nothing
There's the shuttle
Is he in there?
Nope. Lucky for him
Otherwise, I would have slap his corpse
No Cy-Bug either
Gotta find it before it
lays it's filthy eggs
He came this way but the Sugar particles
in the atmosphere are jamming my sensor
Can't get a read on it
So, what is it with this
Wreck-it joker, huh?
Why'd he go AWOL?
I wish I knew, ma'am
he was acting all squirely last night
Going on about cake and medals
But, I never thought he'd go Turbo!
Go Turbo??
That's right,
you guys just got plugged in
Well, back when the Arcade first open
TurboTime was by far the
most popular game...
..and Turbo...
- Turbotastic.
Well, he loved the attention..
- Turbotastic
So, when Rogue Blaster got plugged in and
stole Turbo's thunder
- New game
- alright
...boy.. was he jealous.
..so jealous that he abandoned..
..his game
..and try to take over the new one
- These are the greatest
graphics I've ever seen
Turbotastic
- Hey, is that..??
That looks like Turbo.
- What's Turbo doing in this game?
Oh, c'mon Mister Litwak
Turbo ended up putting both games
and himself out of order
...for good
Yes, The selfish man is like a mangy dog
chasing its own cautionary tail
I know..right?
That's why I have to get Ralph home or
the same thing's gonna happen to my game
Ungh... Oh
- What is this?
Nesquicksand?
Quicksand
Oh, I'll hop out and
grab you one of those vines
I can't hop
I'm hop-less
This is hopeless We're gonna drown here
Stop draking, stop..stop moving
You're making us sink faster
- We're gonna die..
Get a hold of yourself
Ah, the vines They are Laffy Taffy.
They're attracted to whatever
makes them laugh
Here, hit me again
That's not funny enough Harder.
Look, you're a nice guy I can't...
- No, ma'am.. the Arcade
is depending on us
Now do your duty That's an or..
It's working..
Hit me again
Oooh.. your eye..
I can fix it
Now go....
Fra..fantastic
Again
You mean business..
Killing
s u b by:
m a X e e r ( M C )
Alright, enought with the goo-goo eyes
We've got work to do, let's go
Ungh!.. lost the Cy-Bug
C'mon, we'll get a better
view from the air
You think you can fix that shuttle?
Can do
Alright, do your thing
knuckles, bust it open
- What's this?
You're a full-on criminal, aren't you?
hey, we shook on it
Thank you, jeeps
What is this place?
Where are the carts?
We gotta make one
- What? No no no no.
Look kid, bad idea
Trust me, I don't make things
I break things
Well, looks like you're gonna be stepping
outside your comfort zone then, gladius
Ooh, this is a good one
Welcome to the Bakery.
Let's bake a cart
What is this? Another game?
- Ya, well.. it's a mini game
You have one minute to win it
- What?
C'mon, Ralph.
- Now..Mixing.
Put the ingredients in the bowl
and throw away the trash
Hairbrush..
- No
Underpants..
- No, no
You're getting all the wrong stuff, kid.
- I'm trying
Afterall, I'll do it
No, yes
Urgh!..Gross
Milk... yes yes..
Bever up!
C'mon, no sleeping on the job
Baking
Pump up the head and hold
the perfect temperature
A little help here
- I'm on it
Ralph!??
- Yup, no bother.. I just...
- Give me this thing.
Ok, good.. little more
Hold it, hold it
C'mon get up Ralph.. 15 seconds
- Decorating
Wheels first
- How many?
Four, doink
Now frosting, a butt load of frosting
- No problem
Time's up!
Congratulation you did it
and here's your cart
Look, kid...
I tried to warn you
I..i can't make things, I just... break
- I love it!
You do?
I love it!
I love it, I love it, I love it
Look, it's got a real engine
and look at these wheels
I love it I finally have a real cart
C'mon, a work of art like this
must be signed
This is Beard Papa.
The glitch is in the Bakery.
Get me King Candy.
Well, what?? you have teeth? I don't
think I've ever seen you smile before
I'm not smiling it was...
I'm gassy.. okay
Hold it right there, glitch
And Wreck-It Ralph?
Start the cart start the cart...
- I.....
What are you waiting for? c'mon let's go
I..uh.. I ..don't know how
to drive a real cart
You don't...
What!?
Are you hurt, sire?
- No, he just glazed me
Get them
- Gain way
Stop in the name of the king
..that's me
Get off the road
Head for Diet Cola Mountain.
Drive into the wall..
- What?
Right there between the
two sugar-free lollipops
- Are you crazy?
Just do it
Where'd they go?
Maybe.. they've just turned..
Find that glitch destroy that cart
She can't be allowed to race
So let me get this straight
You don't know how to drive
Well no, not technically
But I just thought that...
What did you think? Oh.. I
just I'll just magically
win the race just because
I really want to
Look wise guy, I know I'm a
racer, I can feel it in my cone
That's it..!
I'm never getting my medal back
What is the big whoop about
that crummy medal, anyway?
- The big whoop, well this
may come as a shock to you..
but in my game, I'm the bad guy
and I live in the garbage
Cool... - No, not cool
Unhygenic and lonely and boring
And that crummy medal
was gonna change all that
I go home with that
baby around my neck then I'll get a
penthouse, pies,
ice sculptures, fireworks
It's grown up stuffs,
you wouldn't understand
- No, I get it
That's exactly what racing
would do for me
Well, guess what?
- What?
News flash..neither one of us
is getting what we want
What was that?
Diet Cola Hot Springs
Watch out for falling Mentos
- Ya, check it out, look
Oh, you gotta watch out for the splash
That stuff is boiling hot
Ya, I got that thank you
What is this dump?
I think it's some sort of
unfinished bonus level
Ya, it's pretty cool, huh?
I found that secret opening
and now I live here
See, oh look look look look
Welcome to my home
I sleep in these candy wrappers I like
bundling myself up like
a little homeless lady
By yourself?
With all these garbage around here?
Well, ya
I mean, everyone here
says I'm just the mistake
and that I wasn't even suppose to exist
What do you expect?
Listen kid..
I know it's none of my business
but why do you even stick
around this game
You really don't know anything, do you?
Glitches can't leave their games
It's one of the joyous of being me
Hey, what are you doing?
C'mon..
I know it's a dump but it's all I got
If you're gonna be a racer,
then, you'll have to learn how to drive
You can't do that...
without a track
Alright now..
Let's hustle up, we got
some driving to do
- No wonder I'm driving..I'm gonna
learn to drive.. I'm gonna..
Oh wait, do you know how to drive?
- Ya, I mean, I haven't done it but...
look, I flew a spaceship today okay
You crashed it
- Just get in, how hard can it be? okay
Uh.. start it up
There you go
So there's some buttons on the floor
- Pedals
Pedals, right!
Now.. uh..
Thats the 'go' pedal
That, I believe is the stopper
And this... wait
What is this?
It doesn't do anything
Woo, what's this joystick do?
Okay, good.
Let's try that again
That's good, keep going Shift it again
I told you Racing's in my cone
Is that little not the best?
- Hey you Ralphy, watch this
Look out!
So, how did I do?
Well, you almost blew
up the whole mountain
Righ right, that's a good note
You gotta get that
glitch under control kid
Ok, I will I will and..
And then, you think I get a chance?
Tiny
Yes, I'm gonna win, I'm gonna win I'm
gonna win, I'm gonna win, I'm gonna win
Top shelf
- Top shelf
Did you find the..?
Tell me you found her..
You didn't?
Go, leave me.
Up up down dwon..
hmm hmm.. hih ..hih
Start.
Oh.. Code
That's the sweet lifeblood of the game
Where are you?
The Stadium, no.
Jumbotrons
Ahah!
There it is
The winner's cup
One of these things is not like
the others... it's you
We're gonna give you a nice new home
Success
Sour Bill, I'm going out, you're in charge
of the castle until I get back
Your face is still red, you might
wanna hit it again with your hammer
Oh, that's not blood force trauma ma'am
That's just the honey glow in my cheeks
Okay..
- Ma'am, I just gotta tell ya
You are one dynamite gal..
Wow..
One dynamite gal
Dynamite gal
Dynamite....
Get out
All I said is you're a dynamite gal?
- I said get out
Oh.. jimanny jamanny
Yes
I'm Fix-It Felix Jr, sir
from the game Fix-It Felix Jr.
Have you seen my friend Ralph?
- Wreck-It Ralph?
Yes, yes that's him
Should've lock him up
when we had the chance
Lock him up?
- Not making the same mistake with you
Hurry hurry, let's go
time's a wastin' ..c'mon Ralph
This is it, this is really happening
I almost don't believe it
I mean, I have dreamt about it
for so long and now..
and now.. now I think I'm gonna
puke actually, I think I might puke
You know, like a 'vurp'
A what?
- Vomit and a burp together
and you can taste it, and it's just
like rising up Oh this is so exciting
Yes, it is, it's exciting
I mean am I ready to be a real racer?
Ralph, what if the gamers don't like me?
Who doesn't love a brat with dirty hair?
C'mon Those people are gonna love you
You know why?
Cause you're a winner
A winner
- And you're adorable
I'm adorable
- And everyone loves an adorable winner
Okay, c'mon
Listen to me, if you get nervous
just keep telling yourslef 'I must win
Ralph's medal or his life will be ruined'
And have fun, got it?
- Got it!
Oh wait!
Hold on..
Where you going?
- I forgot something, I'll be right back
Kids
Ralph, there you are, hello
- Huh??
You!!
- No no, I come alone, unarmed
I've had enough of you, pillow pants
- Calm down, please
I'm gonna beat the hella out of you
You wouldn't hit a guy with
glasses, would you?
You hit a guy with glasses, that's..
well played
- What do you want Candy?
Listen, I just wanna talk to you
I'm not intrested in anything
you have to say
But how about this?
Are you interested... in this?
My medal..how did you..??
- It doesn't matter
here, it's yours Go ahead and take it
All I ask is that you hear me out
About what?
Ralph, do you know what the hardest
part about being a king is?
Doing what's right
No matter what
- Get to the point
Point being I need your help
Sad as it is,
Vanellope cannot be allowed to race
Why are you people so against her?
- I'm not against her..
I'm trying to protect her.
If Vanellope wins that race..
she'll be added to the race roster
Then gamers can choose
the racer's avatar
And when they see her glitching and then
get glitching in just being herself
They'll think our game is broken
We'll be put ourt of order for good
All my subjects will be homeless
But there is one who cannot escape
because she's a glitch
Help.
Somebody help me..
When the game's plug is pulled
she'll die with it
You don't know that will happen
The gamers could love her
- And if they don't?
I know it's tough, but heroes have
to make the tough choices, don't they?
She can't race Ralph but...
She won't listen to me
So, can I count on you to
talk a little sense into her?
Very good
Uh.. I'll give you two some time alone
I'm back..
Did you miss me?
- Yea..Uh..
Hey, can we talk for a second?
- Wait, first kneel down
What? no no. w.we really..
- You just do it!
Okay
Now, close your eyes
Vanellope..
- Shut.. close them
Okay, open them up
To Stinkbrain Jee, thanks
Turn it over "YOURE MY HERO"
I made it for you
Just in case we don't win
Not that I think there's even a
remote chance we're not gonna win
Thanks kid..Uhmm, listen
- Now.. rise, my royal champ
I've got a date with destiny
Ralph, c'mon move your molases
Uh, I've been thinking
- That's dangerous
Who cares about this
stupid race anyway? Right?
That's not very funny, Ralph
- No, I'm serious and..uh..
It was really fun to build the cart
and everything but.. maybe..
maybe, you shouldn't do it
- Uh.. Hello? Is Ralph in there?
I'd like to speak to him please
- Look what I'm saying
is, you can't be a racer
What?
why would you..
Wait a minute..
No.
- Where did you get this?
Look, I'm gonna be straight with you kid,
I've been talking to King Candy..
King Candy? You sold me out?
- Yea
No, I didn't..
Listen, you don't understand
No I understand, plunny traitor!
I'm not a traitor, listen..
- You're a rat
and I don't need you
and I can win the race on my own
But I'm trying to save your skin, kid
- Put me down, let me go..
No, you listen to me, you know whats gonna
happen when the players see you glitching
They're gonna think the game's broken
- I don't care, you're a liar
Yo, you better care because if your game
goes out of order
you go down with the
ship later, thats true
- I'm not listening to
you, get out of my way
I'm going to that race
- No, you're not
Take me down from here, Ralph... right now
- No
I'm doing this for your own good
Wait, wait wait
No.. no.. no no no no
Please Ralph...
No....
Stop it! ..Stop it...
No...
You really are a bad guy
Hello, anybody home?
Felix..
Mary..
Well, you actually went and did it
- Gene, where is everybody?
They're gone, after Felix went to find you
and then didn't come back
Everyone panicked and abandon ship
But.. but, I'm here now?
- It's too late, Ralph
Litwak's pulling our plug in the morning
But, never let it be said that
I'm not a man of my word
The place is yours, Ralph.
Enjoy.
Gene, wait, wait
Listen, this is not what I wanted
Well, what did you want, Ralph?
- I don't know.. I.. I just
I was just tired of living alone
in the garbage
Well now, you can live alone
in the Penthouse
Hey cough-drop,
explain something to me
If Vanellope was never meant to exist...
then why is her picture on
the side of the game console?
What's going on in this candy coated
hearted darkness? -Nothing...
Talk.. - No
I'll lick you..
You wouldn't
- Oh yea?
That's like sand-paper
Wonder how many licks it will take
to get to your centre?
Well, say that to my grave..
- Fair enough!
They call you Sour Bill for a reason
Had it enough yet?
- Okay okay, I'll talk, I'll talk.
Vanellope was a racer until
King Candy try to delete her code
Try to delete her code?
So, that's why she's a glitch
Why is he doing this to her?
- I don't know.
Suit yourself
- No no no, I swear I don't know
He literally locked up our memory
and I cannot remember
Nobody can But, I do know this..
He'll do anything to keep her from racing
because if she crosses the finish line...
the game will reset
and she won't be a glitch anymore
Where is she now?
- In the Fungeon with Fix-It Felix.
- Felix??
I'm sorry, that's all I know
that's all I know, I swear
No please don't put me back
in your filthy mouth again
Stick around
- Yes, okay I will, I will.. thank you
C'mon I know you're out there
Saccharin saturated nightmare
Where?
Doomsday and Armageddon just had
a baby, and it is ugly
Hello, hello... somebody?
Anybody?
Please let me out
What is that.. what he says...?
I'm gonna wreck it
Why do I fix everything I touch?
Felix
- Ralph, I'm so glad to see you
No, wait.. I'm not
What do you have to say for yourself?
Wait, I don't want to hear
I'm not talking to you
Okay, don't talk That's fine
But you have to fix this go-cart
for me pronto
I don't have to do boo
Forgive my potty mouth
I'm just so..
so crossed with you
Do you have any idea
what you put me through?
I were in Hickelty pickelty
all over creation looking
for you, I almost drowned
in chocolate milk mix
And then, I met the most dynamite gal
Oh.. she gives me the
honey glow, something aweful
But, she rebuff my affections
And then, I got thrown in jail
Felix, pull yourself together
No, Ralph you don't know what it's like to
be rejected and treated like a criminal
Yes, I do That's everyday in my life
It is?
- Which is why I ran off
I try to be a good guy but I'm not
Just a bad guy and I need your help
There's a little girl
whose only hope is this cart
Please, Felix fix it
And I promise I will never try
to be good again
I know, I know, I know I'm an idiot
And?
- and a real Numbskull
- a selfish diaper baby.
And?
- and.. a Stinkbrain.
The stinkiest brain ever
My sweet subjects, I came without a
flinch of hesitation to show you
that I have never been
so happy in all my life
to say the following words
Let the Random Roster Race commence
Okay, remember.. you don't
have to win Just cross
that finish line and
you'll be a real racer
I'm already a real racer
And I'm gonna win
Power Up.
Oh..
A La Mode.
Sweet Seekers.
Have some candy
Behind you..
Infront of you..
It's the glitch
- The glitch
Light 'em up Candlehead
What's this?
Cherry Bomb.
I told you
You're just an accident waiting to happen
My candle...
Alright, gotta keep it under control
No more glitching
Okay kid, let's finish this thing
without any more surprises
Hope you're happy jump-pile
This game is going down and
it's all your fault
My lady, you came back
- Canned it, Fix-It.
That Cy-Bug you brought with you
multiplied
No, it died in the taffy swamp
believe me
You're wrong!
Listen up people,
head to Game Central Station, now..
Move it let's go let's go
No
Get off of my track
- hey, what are you crazy?
I forbid you to cross that finish line
Knock it out
Ralph, look
- Kid...
No, Stop it. - Let me.. urgh!!
- Not letting you undo all my hard work
Is that....
No way....
What the... Who are you??
- I'm Turbo
The greatest racer ever
And I did not reprogram
this world to let you
and that holocust riddled warhock
take it away from me
Turbotastic
End of the line, glitch
Glitch. That's it
C'mon, Vanellope. I know you said
you wouldn't do it again...
But you're gonna do it one more time
Just focus and concentrate
And..
Glitch.
No
Sweet mother of monkey milk I did it
Bring it home kid
The finish line's wide open
No
Kid, kid are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine
Let's finish this race
Oh my randd!!
- Alright C'mon we gotta get out of here
But I didn't cross the finish line
- There is no finish line
Move it or lose it people
c'mon everybody out now
Ralph, it's not gonna work
- We gotta try
Kid
- Ralph I told you I can't leave the game
C'mon
- Ralph, just stop
It's gotta work
- Stop, it's no use
It's okay, Ralph.
Alright Fix-It, that's everyone
now we gotta blow up this exit
Just go, go without me
What about this game?
- Nothing we can do about it
Without a beacon, there's no way
to stop these monsters
Beacon..
stay with Felix
Let me borrow that thing lady
- Ralph, where are you going?
I got some wrecking to do
I'll meet you at the finish line
- No, wait
Fix-It, get behind me
One more..
Welcome to the Boss Level
- Turbo.
Because of you, Ralph, I'm now
the most powerful virus in the Arcade
I can take over any game I want
I should thank you
but.. it'd be more fun to kill you
Get back here little guy
Where do you think you're going?
I'm not through with you yet
Up we go
- No
Fall back
Kid
Look at that, it's your little friend
Let's watch her die together, shall we
No
It's game over for both of you
- No
Just for me
I'm bad, and that's good
I will never be good and that's not bad
There's no one I'd rather be..
..than me
Kid
- Don't worry, I got it under control
Why are you going into the light...
No, no..
Yea.
Go into the light
Chocolate, it's chocolate
I love chocolate
Beautiful chocolate
You did it, Ralph.
Oh..Way to go brother
I'm... es..
All fixed
- You ready for this?
Ready as I'll ever be
Look at all the magic sparkles
Now, I remember
All hail, the rightful ruler
of Sugar Rush.
Princess Vanellope.
I remember She's a princess
That's right
- We are so sorry about
the way we treated you
Ya, those were jokes..
See, I was just doing
what Taffyta told me to
Tat tat! as your merciful princess
I hereby decree that
everyone who has ever
mean to be shall be...
..executed
- What?
No no no, please please
- Oh my lamnd
Oh this place just got interesting
I don't wanna die
- I'm just kidding
You are?
- Stop crying, Taffyta.
I'm trying but..
it won't stop
Wow.. so this is
the real you?
Princess..
- Oh, Ralph, what are you nuts?
C'mon, this isn't me This is me
Look, the code may say I'm a princess but,
I know who I really am Ralph
I'm a racer with the greatest
superpower ever
I was here I was there.
I was glitching through the wall
I'm not giving that up
Pardon me for asking but, without a
princess, who's gonna lead us? - Yea who?
Uh.. me. I'm thinking more along
the lines of a constitutional democracy
President Vanellope von Schweetz.
Has a nice ring to it don't you think?
Fix-It, Wreck-It, the
Arcade's about to open.
Let's move 'em out
You know you could just stay here
and live in the castle
You'd have your own wing
where no one would
ever complain about you or
treat you bad ever again
You could be happy
I'm already happy
Got the coolest friend in the world
And besides, I've got a job to do too
May not be as fancy as
being president...
but it's my duty And it's a big duty
Ralph, you coming brother?
See you later, president Fartfeathers.
Au revoir, admiral Underpants.
And farewell, bareness Boogerface.
Goodbye, major Bodyodour.
Hasta la vista.
Ralph..
- Alright, to be continued
I'm gonna wreck it
Hey, Ralph's back Isn't it great?
The game's all here
- So, I'm happy to report...
and you'll be happy to hear
I'm taking life one game at a time
First, the job hasn't change
But, news flash..
The Nicelanders are being nice to me
And you know that got me thinking about
those poor guys left without a game
So here's what we did
- We're going to wreck it!
We ask them to help us out
in the bonus level
We can fix it!
I'm tellin' you guys, we haven't been
this popular in years
It's crazy The gamers say we're Retro
which... It means...
Old.. but Cool
How come I never noticed this game
Oh and I decided that living in
a dump wasn't making me feel very good
So, I cleaned it up, built myself a little
shack and a couple for the new guys too
Well, with a little help from Felix
Oh and guess who is the best man
at his and Calhoun's wedding?
That's right my friend
Old ham hands himself
Very elegant affair,
should've seen her, lot of grandeur.
And not a single bug
And let's just say
some tears were shed.
But I gotta say,
the best part of my day...
is when I get thrown off the roof...
because when the Nicelanders lift me up..
I get a perfect view of Sugar Rush
And I can see Vanellope racing
The kid's a natural..
And the players love her glitch and all
Just like I knew they would
Turns out I don't need a medal
to tell me I'm a good guy
Cause, if that little kid likes me...
How bad can I be?
Sub by: maXeer
~~ MC ~~