Once, when I was six years old,
I read a book about the primeval forest.
The book said,
"Boa constrictors swallow
their prey whole, without chewing it."
I pondered this deeply.
And then, I did my first drawing.
I showed my masterpiece to grown-ups
and asked if the drawing
frightened them.
Frightened?
Why should anyone
be frightened of a hat?
Grown-ups.
They never understand
anything by themselves.
So, I did another drawing.
Well. My advice is stick to arithmetic.
- History.
- And grammar.
I took their advice and I grew up.
I forgot all about being a child.
Until something miraculous happened.
The Little Prince
I have always wanted to find someone
to share my story with, but...
I don't know...
I guess this world just got too grown-up.
Tonight, let's recap today's recap
of today's market activity.
Record-breaking numbers
were written down on pieces of paper,
taken to the bank,
placed in drawers and locked with keys.
Backs straight.
Listening attentively.
Listening.
No excessive blinking.
Unexpected praise.
Acknowledge and thank you.
A real smile, sweetie. Show your teeth.
Not too much.
Good. Okay.
Now remember,
statistics tell us that if the panel
is leaning toward acceptance,
they will ask only one question.
The big question.
Are you Werth Academy material?
One, two, three.
Three things make me Werth...
Zero-one-seven?
Go on.
We've reviewed your application.
Thank you!
We've reviewed your file...
Thank... You.
We've read your essay,
"The transformative power of zero
on the bottom line"
and the follow-up, "Zero, still my hero."
Everything looks to be perfect.
We will ask you just one question today.
The big question!
"Are you Werth Academy material?"
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
One, two, three.
Three things make me
Werth Academy material.
No. No.
One, like Werth, I am intelligent.
Two, like Werth, I am serious.
- Stop.
- Three...
Like Werth...
My unwavering...
Abort... Abort.
...will to
learn...
Thank you.
Sweetie!
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO BE
WHEN YOU GROW UP?
ESSENTIAL.
Apparently,
they changed the big question.
I'm sorry, Mum.
Don't be.
We'll just have to go to Plan B.
"B"?
You said Plan B was impossible!
That's why we went with Plan A.
Plan B is the new Plan A.
We're moving forward!
Neighbourhood identified. Check.
If by some miracle we find
an affordable house here,
they will have to take you.
REDUCED PRICE
HOUSE FOR SALE
Check. Check.
Moving truck, check.
FIRST DAY OF SUMMER HOLIDAYS
Matters of consequence today for
the serious and sensible man...
We did it!
You're going to Werth Academy
whether they like it or not.
Whether volcanoes are extinct or alive,
it comes to the same thing for us.
No one is ever satisfied
where he is, pursuing nothing...
Our new home. Check.
Is it too late for a Plan C?
Just keep reminding yourself that
that house made this house available,
and made your future possible.
Mum?
Do you really think
I'm Werth Academy material?
You will be by the end of the summer.
I have a plan.
Right on time.
I present to you your life plan.
My life plan?
Your life plan.
We're not leaving anything to chance.
Everything's here.
From top to bottom. Left to right.
Let's take a look.
The minute of the hour,
hour of the day, day of the week,
week of the month, month of the year,
the year of your life.
Everything! Got it?
It's even got a chart
for all your birthday gifts.
Like your ninth birthday,
coming up. Microscope.
Perfect for
the Werth Academy biology curriculum.
It's already wrapped.
- Wow.
- Yes.
But for now, this is your priority.
The first day of your new school.
We've got 53 days to go,
which doesn't sound like much,
until you break it into hours, 1,272.
Or minutes, 76,320.
Only then do you realise
how much can be accomplished.
You will use every minute,
hour and day according to this.
Because, let's face it,
you're going to be all alone out there.
All alone.
So...
We can't afford any more mistakes,
like the interview.
Right.
You're going to make
a wonderful grown-up.
Thank you, Mum.
I wish I could stay, sweetie,
but it's the Davis audit, again.
Kelly's numbers on
the Miller account are problematic.
Fines found out
and now Logan's in a panic.
Fisher wants nothing to do with it...
Logan.
- So I've got to go...
- And put it right.
Yes, but I'm not even sure
that's possible.
If anyone can do it, it's you. Go on.
I've got my life plan!
You're my senior VP.
Let's do it.
Gas.
Anybody home?
Bolts...
I didn't actually believe
he had a plane back there.
I think the old guy flew away years ago.
I'm just thankful
we don't live next door to him.
Roger that.
What a surprise!
A very good afternoon to you, Officer.
Hello, friends!
I was just...
I was immersed in a game of bridge.
Do you play?
Sir, did you try to start your plane again?
Yes, I did.
I'm terribly sorry.
I fear I have caused extensive damage
to the house next door.
Handcuffs?
I'd rather not.
Hold on.
It's here, somewhere.
Sir?
Found it.
Found it!
Sir...
Sweetie, I'm home. I brought Chinese.
Mum?
Hello.
Hi.
Where did you get the pennies?
The old man next door.
Actually, it was the police officer
who "gave" them to me.
What?
What kind of a nut keeps an aeroplane,
and actually starts it, in his backyard?
Are you sure you're okay?
- I have to call the insurance.
- Done.
- And file a police report.
- Done. In duplicate.
- Photo documentation?
- Inside and outside.
The lighting could have been better.
It's not so bad.
I'll call a contractor in the morning
and we'll forget the old man even exists.
I've already forgotten him.
Matters of consequence,
let's recap today's recap,
of today's market activity,
with a detailed account...
Numbers of the day.
There are also hundreds of others...
"Once upon a time there was
a little prince who lived on a planet
"that was scarcely bigger than himself,
and who had need of..."
A friend?
I thought you could use a friend!
No, here I am, up here.
Here! Hi.
I'm sorry.
That's just the beginning of the story.
It's okay. Nobody understands it anyway.
All right, bye-bye.
See you later, maybe.
She made the most frightful noise.
It resounded all over the place.
- Maybe during lunch...
- I can count the pennies.
Once upon a time
there was a little prince
who lived on a planet
that was scarcely bigger than himself,
and who had need of a friend.
"And I lived my life alone
without anyone I could really talk to.
"So I learned to pilot aeroplanes."
I flew more or less all over the world,
until I had an accident
in the Sahara desert.
If you please, draw me a sheep!
If you please, draw me a sheep.
Draw me a sheep!
When a mystery is too over-powering,
one dare not disobey.
Draw? I don't know how to draw.
That doesn't matter.
The first sheep I drew was too sickly.
And the second one,
not to his liking either.
You see yourself
that this is not a sheep.
This is a ram, it has horns.
- And this one was...
- Too old!
I want a sheep
that will live for a long time.
So, I drew this.
The sheep you ask for is inside.
That is exactly the way I wanted it!
Do you think this sheep
will eat a great deal of grass?
Because where I live,
everything is very small.
I'm sure there will be
enough grass for him.
He's a very small sheep.
Not that small. Look!
He's gone to sleep.
Wow.
Hello?
Hello!
Hold on. Don't move.
Good.
Here we go.
Wow.
I... I just wanted to give
your drawing back.
You don't like it?
It's not that.
It's not very good.
I think it's nice.
I read the story, too. Attentively.
And I found it quite odd.
Odd?
I mean curious... Or interesting...
I have some issues
with some of the facts.
You have questions?
I don't mean to be rude. Can I?
What? Be rude?
Sure, go ahead. I'm listening.
First of all, what was the kid
doing there in the desert?
It's very strange.
No one can last very long
in a desert without food and water.
Where are his parents?
Does he even go to school?
Does he really live up there?
I took basic astronomy
and there was no mention of life,
or children, on any other planets.
Unless it's true
that he came from a star.
But that's unlikely.
Not a star. An asteroid.
Asteroid B-612.
We didn't cover asteroids.
But the fact that he wanted a sheep,
that pretty much proves that he exists.
Don't you think?
Hold on, I'll show you another drawing.
Wow.
This is a pretty serious fire hazard.
I never looked at it that way.
Where did you get all this stuff?
As time goes by
some things just kind of stick to you.
There's a name for it...
- Collecting?
- Hoarding!
That's it, hoarding.
I'm a hoarder. A bit of a hoarder.
What's your name, little fox?
He can't answer you.
I keep meaning to sew him a mouth.
Are you okay? You're okay?
I'm fine, this happens sometimes.
Give me a minute.
The last time this happened,
I was down here for three days.
- Three days?
- That's okay.
That's why I always keep
a baloney sandwich in my pocket.
Want a bite?
I think I'm baloney intolerant.
You don't know what you're missing.
It's going to be a clear night.
The stars will be out soon.
Wow.
The Little Prince,
he was very fond of sunsets.
One day he saw 44 of them.
What?
His planet, it was so small,
all he had to do was move his chair
a few steps to see another one.
But a small planet also had drawbacks.
He needed
a sheep to eat the baobab sprouts.
- Baobab?
- Yeah.
It's a very greedy tree.
And every day, he toiled
to stop them from turning up.
For if you intervene too late...
Catastrophe.
Now, luckily, there are good seeds, too.
And one day, from a seed blown
from no one knew where,
a new kind of sprout came up.
I know you'll be miraculous.
I know you will.
How beautiful you are!
I'm only half awake.
Forgive me, I'm still quite dishevelled.
You're perfect.
Am I not?
I was born
at the same moment as the sun.
It was there they shared
their first sunrise
and their first sunset.
It's very cold where you live.
Could you be kind enough
to think of my needs?
So the Rose began very quickly
to torment him with her vanity.
I suppose you wouldn't have a screen?
And at night I want you
to put me under a glass.
A glass globe, now. My needs...
My beauty... My screen...
Now, the shame of it was
that they loved each other.
But they were both too young
to know how to love.
Full of doubt, he ran away.
Of course I love you.
If you're not aware of that, it's my fault.
Please forgive me.
He left her? All alone?
But where did he go?
He didn't know it at the time,
but his leaving was just the first step
on a journey back to her.
- Really?
- Yes.
Look at that, the stars are out.
Wow.
They're so bright.
There are so many to look at.
And on a good day, if I listen carefully,
I can hear him laughing up there.
No! I have to go!
Sweetie? Where are you?
Hi.
Your desk is a mess.
Did you finish your study work for today?
No, not exactly.
What have you been doing?
I read a lot...
And I made a friend.
A friend?
No. No, no, no.
No.
Maybe...
Yes.
Okay.
FRIEND
If you study hard and you stay
completely on track with the plan,
you can spend some time
with your new friend.
Next summer,
on Thursdays, from 1:00 to 1:30.
Okay? Can't wait to meet her.
"He found himself
in the neighbourhood of asteroids
325, 326, 327,
"328, 329, 330..."
What?
Here's a subject.
Approach.
Sire, over what do you rule?
Over everything.
And the stars obey you?
They certainly do.
I do not tolerate indiscipline.
I would very much like to see a sunset.
It would remind me of my rose.
Order the sun to set.
You shall have your sunset.
I shall command it.
But I shall wait
until conditions are favourable.
When will that be?
Well, that will be about...
That will be this evening,
about 20 minutes to 9:00.
Good morning.
You're wearing a funny kind of hat.
What... It is a hat for salutes, actually.
To raise when people acclaim me.
Clap your hands, yeah.
Thank you. Thank you.
You see?
Do you really admire me very much?
Am I not the handsomest,
the best-dressed, the richest...
The most intelligent man on this planet?
But you're the only man on this planet.
Do me this kindness and...
Admire me just the same, please.
I own the stars...
I handle them.
I count them, then I recount them.
But what good does that do you?
Well, it makes me rich. How's that?
And what good does it
do you to be rich?
It makes it possible for me
to buy more stars.
Plus anything else you can think of.
Grown-ups are certainly very odd.
And check. Check. Check.
Check.
And check. And check.
Check...
Grown-ups are certainly very, very odd.
I've lived a great deal among grown-ups.
I have seen them up close.
And that hasn't much changed
my opinion of them.
Yes. I'm not so sure
I want to grow up any more.
Growing up is not the problem.
Forgetting is.
I definitely don't want to forget.
I managed to grow up
and I never forgot the Little Prince.
Yeah...
Good evening.
What planet is this?
This is Earth.
This is Africa.
Where are all the men?
It is a little lonely in the desert.
It is also lonely among men.
You are a funny animal.
You are no thicker than a finger.
But I am more powerful
than the finger of a king.
You haven't any feet.
You cannot even travel.
I can carry you further
than any ship could take you.
I can help you someday,
if you miss your own planet.
I think I understand you.
There you go,
try that one on the left there.
I'm scared.
That's normal. It is scary.
Why do you think I sent you?
Almost there. You got it now.
Just reach! Reach for it!
- I got it!
- There you go! You got it!
Well, that was...
That was double scary, right?
Triple and quadruple.
We're going to have to amputate them.
What?
- Feels better, right?
- Yes.
But it happened that after
walking a long time through sand,
and rocks, and snow,
the Fox appeared.
Hey! Come play with me.
I cannot play with you.
I am not tamed.
What does that mean?
Tame means, "To establish ties."
To me, you are just a little boy
who is just like 100,000 other little boys.
And I have no need of you.
And you have no need of me.
To you, I am just a fox
like 100,000 foxes.
But if you tame me,
then we shall need each other.
Hey, there.
To me,
you will be unique in all the world.
And to you,
I shall be unique in all the world.
Who are you?
We are roses.
My rose is just a common rose?
But she told me she was the only one of
her kind in the whole universe.
But she is not a common rose.
She is your rose.
The time that you have devoted to her
makes your rose so important.
She is my rose.
You must return to her.
Are you going to cry?
My taming you
has done you no good at all.
Let me make you a present of a secret.
It's very simple.
It is only with the heart
that one can see rightly.
What is essential is invisible to the eye.
They won't be together any more?
But they will.
The Fox, he sees the Little Prince
when he looks with his heart.
If you can do that,
you'll never be lonely again.
Right. But I'm not lonely.
I've got you now.
I am so lucky.
I thought I'd never find anyone
who wanted to hear my story.
Then you came along. Just in time.
Wait...
What do you mean, "Just in time"?
Well, everyone has
to say goodbye sooner or later.
You're leaving?
Well...
What if I get that old plane running?
What if it's time for me
to go be with the Little Prince?
But...
He already has his rose...
And I need you here.
Hey. Hey.
You hungry?
I know a great place
where we can get
free pancakes on your birthday.
But my birthday's not for two weeks.
They don't know that.
It's like flying a plane.
Like the one you crashed?
Exactly!
You're joking?
Pull over.
Do you have a driver's licence?
No.
- A learner's permit?
- No.
How old are you?
- Hi, Officer.
- Your car is out of the garage, again.
Yeah...
Good afternoon, Officer.
If I may say something...
It's my birthday today.
- Mum, I can...
- Wait for me inside.
- But...
- Now.
I'm very sorry to call you at work.
Apparently, they were going
to get pancakes...
- Would you like to speak to him?
- Yes...
No! No, no!
Mr Fox!
According to this, you're still in bed.
Asleep. Yesterday.
Your "friend" doesn't even
have a driver's licence.
No. They took it away
after the fourth time
he drove away
with the gas pump attached.
You could have been killed!
- Mum, I can explain...
- No, you mean you can lie.
- But...
- You lied to me,
to the police officer.
And before I forget, happy birthday.
You even managed
to lie to your life plan!
That? It's just a board full of magnets!
You care more
about that than about me.
You're wrong.
I care about it
as much as I care about you.
It is you.
This is your life and I'm the only one
taking any responsibility for it!
That's your version of my life, not mine!
If you were ever around, you'd see that!
You know full well
why I have to work so hard.
You're just like him now.
Too busy, always working.
How long until you
completely disappear?
"I believe
that for his escape he took advantage
"of the migration
of a flock of wild birds?"
No, no!
Okay, enough of this nonsense.
You have two weeks to focus.
But, Mum!
LOVE,
DAD
Let's look for a well.
The stars are beautiful because
of a flower that cannot be seen.
What makes the desert beautiful
is that somewhere it hides a well.
In the moonlight, I looked
at his pale forehead, his closed eyes,
his locks of hair
that trembled in the wind,
and I said to myself,
"What I see here is nothing but a shell.
"What is most important
is what is invisible."
We found a well at daybreak.
The men where you live
grow thousands of roses
and they do not find
what they are looking for.
What they are looking for
could be found in a single rose,
or a little water.
Hold your horses.
Let's go look for a well.
No. Listen.
I made a big mistake the other day.
You can't come over here any more.
- This will be the last time.
- What?
Let's get that plane running!
If you managed to find a well
in the middle of the desert,
then we can go
and find the Little Prince.
He'll be able to help us.
Wait, little one. We can't just take off.
You're right.
We must fix that wing first.
No, no.
I'm sorry, but when
the moment does come for me to leave,
I have to go alone.
But I won't be any trouble,
and I won't take up much room
in the plane. I promise.
Don't go without me.
I think it's time I told you
the end of the story.
That evening, I finished fixing my plane
and I went to find the Little Prince.
I shall be there tonight. Wait for me.
You're sure I won't suffer too long?
Did you shoot it?
No, it disappeared among the stones.
What happened?
Somehow,
he knew that I had fixed my plane.
I, too, am going back home today.
It is much farther.
It is much more difficult.
I am afraid.
I can't believe
I'll never hear you laugh again.
I'm going to give you a present.
In one of those stars, I shall be living.
In one of them, I shall be laughing.
And so, when you look up
at the sky at night,
it will be as if all the
stars are laughing.
Tonight, do not come.
You let him go? Not to the Snake!
It wasn't my choice.
It was time to say goodbye.
You understand that it is too far?
I cannot carry this body with me.
It will be like an old abandoned shell.
There is nothing sad about old shells.
- Here's the place.
- I shall not leave you.
But...
You...
You said he's up there, didn't you?
Back with his rose?
Well...
It is as he said.
I look at the stars
and I hear him laughing.
But you don't know for sure?
It would comfort me
very much to know for sure,
but instead,
I choose to believe he is up there.
Is that what you want me to do
when you go?
Just look up to the stars
and make-believe that you're not gone?
But...
If you look with your heart,
I'll always be with you.
Yes. Just like I know the Little Prince
will always be with his rose.
But you can't know for sure.
What if he's not back with his rose?
- What if he's all grown up and alone?
- But...
What if he's lost
and he's forgotten everything?
Wait. Hold on, My little girl. Hold on.
The Little Prince will never forget.
He'll always be up there for us,
to help us.
I don't want his help.
I hate the Little Prince!
I wasted my whole summer on
the Little Prince!
I wish you had never told me
this stupid story.
LAST DAY OF SUMMER HOLIDAYS
The weather caused
32 people to be late for work.
Productivity decreased by 0.4%.
What...
Dear!
No...
Sweetie...
No!
Sweetie!
Hey!
Sweetie, stop!
What are you doing? Stop!
Stop! You can't go!
Please, I need you here!
No!
Please! You have to let me see him!
What happened? Will he be okay?
So...
Let's not forget,
tomorrow's an important day.
The Aviator needs you.
I'm going to find you.
Wow.
Do you know how to fly a plane?
Yeah, I didn't think so.
Okay, well...
Yes! I can do this.
Here, hold these.
I think I've got the hang of it now.
I've got you!
Where are the stars?
What is that?
A star?
Wait a minute. That's no star.
The Aviator never mentioned this place.
Could it be?
It's him! It's him!
What is he doing here?
Buckle up.
We need a gap.
I think I see one up ahead.
Prepare for landing.
We did it!
That wasn't too bad.
Look! Up there.
Step out of the vehicle.
I said step out of the vehicle.
I'm very sorry, Officer.
If I could just explain...
Keep your hands where I can see them.
Unsafe speeding. Unsafe lane changes.
- Unsafe everything.
- What?
Running multiple red lights.
- I'm trying to find my friend...
- Destruction of city property.
A friend of a friend.
We've never officially met.
No use of turn signals. No signals at all.
I just wanted to grab him
and take him home.
Attempted kidnapping!
Add that to the list.
Attempted kidnapping.
Hey, are you...
Thank you.
The Conceited Man.
Disobeying a uniformed officer,
of the law, no less.
Me!
Wait.
Why are you not on your planet?
- Why are you so small?
- Because I'm a child.
That is absolutely not allowed here.
- Let's go!
- Hey! Hey!
Not so fast!
Thank you. Thank you.
That's right. Go on.
We need a disguise.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Sorry. Could I... Sir?
Here are my subjects.
Approach.
Is that the King?
- 67th floor.
- As you wish.
- 27th floor.
- Granted.
- 14th floor.
- Certainly.
- 142nd floor.
- Of course.
- 34th floor.
- Happily.
No.
Top floor, please.
What? Top floor?
When conditions are favourable?
Your Majesty?
Well...
Conditions are favourable.
It is done.
There he is!
Little Prince! Little Prince!
What?
- I'm so sorry.
- I'm okay.
My chin.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
I was just...
I was just taking a little break, that's all.
I thought you were someone else.
You did?
That's great! That's great.
Please don't report me.
Break's over. See? I'm working.
Work, work, work.
No need to report me.
I don't think it was him.
What are we going to do now?
Mr Prince?
Can it be?
Excuse me?
Darn it!
I think you dropped this.
My badge!
- Catastrophe.
- It is him.
- Can I...
- What happened to you?
Give me that. Please.
The Aviator's not going to like this.
- Give it!
- You're not supposed to be like this.
Come on, give me that!
Thank you.
How does this work?
I'm working. See? I'm being essential.
- Wait, stop!
- No, don't talk to me.
I know who you are!
You're the Little Prince,
and you're afraid of baobabs!
No... I'm Mr Prince,
the maintenance man.
I'm afraid of the Businessman.
An aviator drew you a sheep!
You ask too many questions!
You travel
with a flock of migrating birds.
Go away. Excuse me! I am very busy.
You tamed a fox. A fox like him!
Never had a pet.
He wasn't your pet, he was your friend.
Does it look like I have time for friends?
I'm working!
No!
That was my last brush!
I'm going to get fired.
This was my last chance.
This is so unfair!
I was just doing my job.
- Actually, there's one more...
- Thank you.
- Now I have to get back to work.
- Wait!
You know what?
You're slowing down my productivity!
You had a rose!
A what?
A rose.
A really beautiful one. Miraculous even.
One that was unique in all the world.
You know, I've heard
quite enough of this nonsense.
I have to work. Thank you.
You've forgotten everything!
I'm very busy. I have responsibilities.
You've become just another grown-up!
Give me that.
No!
Why did you do that?
Why did you do...
It's all right, I won't cry.
I won't cry.
I'm a grown-up. Men don't cry.
My brushes got knocked over.
It's not a reason to cry.
Crying is useless.
Blow.
Wait a minute, why are you so short?
- Are you really old?
- What?
No! I'm a child.
Just like you're supposed to be.
You're a child?
Children are certainly very odd.
This is not good.
I think I know someone who can help.
Are you sure about this?
Mr Prince,
what a pleasant surprise.
This child needs your help.
Does she?
Here, we don't
normally allow little dogs.
But for you,
we will make an exception, won't we?
Delightful.
Come in, come in!
So how have you been? Things good?
I love my job cleaning the roof.
Wonderful, wonderful.
- Anything inessential...
- Must be made essential.
Well done, Mr Prince.
You see, it's really a magnificent thing
the Businessman has created here.
You might even call it a work of art.
But of course, you'd be wrong.
Very wrong.
Nothing so trivial as that.
My plane!
It's much more important.
Much more essential.
No! Wait!
How could you?
You said you would help.
GRADUATES
I am. That's how they helped me!
Mr Prince!
It seems that
you've finally done something...
Let go.
You'll tell the Businessman?
How essential I've been?
Yes, I most certainly will.
The Businessman told me about
this evidence of childhood
you brought with you.
- Please! Those are important!
- No!
There is nothing essential in here at all.
It is time
to grow up.
THE ESSENTIAL GUIDE
TO EVERYTHING ESSENTIAL
How could everything essential
fit into just one book?
It is incredibly succinct.
And single-spaced.
I'm supposed to read this
over and over and over, until I'm old?
Not at all.
Here, we take a more
accelerated approach to growing up.
Isn't that right, Mr Prince?
No, never mind.
Those blank eyes,
you've forgotten everything, haven't you?
Now, you're going to feel a slight pinch.
Just relax.
Yes! Please sign there.
A consent form releasing myself,
the Businessman,
- and the corporation from all liability...
- Help!
...in case of accidental death
or dismemberment during
the centralising process.
I'm trying to help you!
You're going to make
a wonderful grown-up.
Leave them!
I said, leave them!
Act your age, Mr Prince!
Remember, you are
a graduate of my class.
Stop! What do you think you're doing?
Return to your desk, please.
I didn't think that through.
The Businessman
is going to be very disappointed in me.
Thank you. But why?
I never knew what this was,
or where I even got it,
but I thought maybe it was important...
Your sheep!
My sheep?
I don't get it.
The Aviator gave it to you
in the desert on Earth,
to eat the baobabs.
- Catastrophe.
That's right.
The Aviator drew all of these for you.
- He really needs you right now.
- Me? He needs me?
Growing up is not the problem.
Forgetting is.
I have an idea.
We just need... My plane!
There it is!
It's okay.
Hurry!
We did it!
No!
Which button?
No, no, no...
Yes!
We can catch it on top of the next pile!
Wait, where's Mr Prince?
I remember these.
The stars.
What are they all doing here?
Look at the stars.
The stars are beautiful...
The stars are beautiful
because of a flower
that cannot be seen.
Because of a flower
that cannot be seen?
Your rose!
I have a rose...
I see you've found my collection,
501,622,731 stars.
You? You did this?
But you're supposed
to just count the stars.
Own! Say it with me.
Own. I own the stars.
Thank you. Thank you.
They used to be merely
little golden objects in the sky
that set lazy men to idle dreaming.
But now, the stars
have finally been made essential.
Where did you get that?
She's curious.
Isn't that just like a child?
No!
Thank you.
All right! Enough.
- Thank you.
- All right!
Enough!
What are you going to do
with all the stars?
Don't worry, my little girl.
I put the stars to good use.
There. You see? The inessential has
become perfectly essential.
How it should be for all things.
Take her back to the classroom.
Make sure no one interferes.
- No! Put me down. I can't...
- Stop!
- Don't let them do this to me.
- I said stop.
- Wait.
- Wait?
I've given you 371 jobs,
and you have been fired
from 370 of them.
I think it's time you get back to work,
my little failure.
No! Leave him!
Stop wriggling.
Stop!
- Take your hands off her.
- What? Stop?
I'm not a failure. I'm...
I'm the Little Prince.
What?
He thinks he's little, and a prince!
Wonderful.
Look at me! I'm a bumble bee.
What are you? A duck?
He's hopeless.
I'm not hopeless, I'm hopeful!
That's right! I'm full of hope!
And I love a rose!
And she loves me,
and she is waiting for me!
So...
I don't think I want to work
for you any more.
So...
I quit!
That pile!
When are you going to forget about
being a child?
Never!
Sorry, Mr Prince!
No, it's my fault.
My face shouldn't have been there.
Good.
No.
I'm scared.
Hang on!
- I'll be right back!
- Where are you going?
Wait! Where are you going?
That's not good.
I will grow up, but I'll never
be a grown-up like you!
Wow!
No!
Got you!
I got you, too.
Wonderful.
This is very, very bad for business.
That was amazing!
The stars are back.
I forgot how beautiful they are.
- Look! Asteroid 325!
- You remember!
And 326!
And 327!
And 328!
It's working!
Look! B-612!
The baobabs.
Your rose! She's there!
Hold on!
You're not going to try and land,
are you?
No, stop! Turn around! Stop!
What's happening?
I think we're falling.
- Where are you going now?
- Sit still.
Let's go.
Over here! I found her!
Look.
My rose.
It's her.
No...
No, how can this be?
I'm so sorry.
You're supposed to be with her.
I'm going to lose him, too.
And grow up.
And forget all about him.
Forget everything
forever.
I don't want to lose him.
Don't cry.
How can you not be crying?
I can see her.
She was not a common rose.
She was the only one of her kind
in the whole universe.
I remember her.
I remember all of it.
She's not gone.
She's still here?
It is only with the heart
that one can see rightly.
What is essential is invisible to the eye.
He'll always be with me.
I understand now.
- Please tell the Aviator I remember him!
- I will!
Don't forget.
I won't!
I won't forget any of it! I promise.
Sweetie?
Yes?
- We're late.
- What?
No, we're not.
We need to stop by the hospital
before school.
122, 123, 124...
Okay.
You're here.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry for what I said.
I don't even remember.
That's sweet.
No, I don't even remember who you are.
I got you, didn't I?
I've got something to show you.
You did this?
All my drawings, all in order?
This is so wonderful.
Sweetheart.
"You run the risk of weeping a little,
if you let yourself get tamed."
You're going to make
a wonderful grown-up.
Thank you.
Did you see this?
It's wonderful.
Look. You see? That's the fox.
My fox.
The End
You probably think
this is a hat, but it's not.