- What time is it, hon?
- It's early, you should be asleep.
I told you to wake me.
You have to rest, for both of you.
I love you.
I love you too.
Wait till Daddy comes home, okay?
I'll bring him back.
Okay, listen up.
Our target is Tama Riyadi.
I'm sure most of you know
who I'm talking about.
This man has become something
of a legend in the unerworld.
Pushers, gangs, killers,
they all respect him like a god.
For the past 10 years his building
has been a no-go zone for police.
I don't care how big he is or who
is behind him, he must be stopped.
That enterprising fuck's been renting
out rooms like it's an apartment.
To any low-life piece of shit
looking to keep his head down.
Our mission is simple.
We go in, and we take him out!
Yes, sir!
Now, Tama isn't alone in this.
Intelligence reports
of an in-house narcotics lab.
This means he has more than enough
muscle to protect his investment.
He also has two trusted guards.
One, a fucking mad dog.
A maniac of feet and fists that
would tear down walls for his boss.
The other, Andi.
The brains of Tama's business.
He keeps Mad Dog in check,
but don't be fooled.
Given the opportunity,
he will put bullets in you.
Watch this for me, I'll be right back.
Now, where were we?
Focus at all times.
We take the place floor by floor.
Silence every spotter,
secure every corner.
Why us? Why today?
Why the fuck not?
It's a valid question.
And ifs a valid answer, boy.
Are you done?
Can I continue?
This won't be the first time
the place has come under fire.
For years rival gangs
have tried to take over his patch.
But each and every one of them
has failed.
Be alert.
We are dealing with a force
ready and willing to fight.
Thirty seconds!
Gear up.
I don't want to see any empty seats
on this truck when we're done.
Now let's clean up this fucking city.
- Morning, lieutenant.
- Good morning.
Who are they?
Newly assigned to my unit,
don't worry, they won't get in our way.
You do realize why we're here.
Lieutenant, we have a lot
of space to secure.
We need the extra numbers.
And a lot of potential fuck ups
by kids who aren't ready.
This isn't the most ideal
training ground, Jaka.
I'll keep them back.
Further, much fucking further back.
Split teams.
I lead my unit to section B-3.
Your unit flanks
and clears the target.
Lieutenant Wahyu, you're on me.
Take him out.
B-3 clear.
Okay, let's move.
Shut your mouth and move.
What the fuck is going on?
I have to get upstairs.
I don't give a shit
where you need to go.
I have a sick wife alone up there.
She needs her medication.
- I'm sorry but I have to go.
- Are you deaf?
One more step and
I'll fucking end you.
What the fuck?
That's enough.
Bows, drop it.
You wanna play hero?!
Go ahead, just stay
the fuck away from me.
- What room are you staying at?
-726.
Relax.
We'll get you to your room soon.
For now I need you to stay back
with me, until this area is safe.
And who's going to keep
it safe for my wife?
Sir, I understand your concern.
But you have to remain calm.
- This is bullshit.
- Listen.
You don't have much of a choice.
You're either with me...
...or with him.
Okay, everyone.
We're going in.
You keep on him like fucking glue.
Clear!
Tie him!
Motherfucker!
Don't move!
Don't do anything stupid.
Don't move an inch.
Good.
Now...
Wait!
Police!
- What the fuck was that?
- Necessity.
Sergeant!
We've got another spotter!
Motherfucker!
Police!
We have company.
They're here.
Cut all communications
and lock it down.
I'll call the neighbors.
We have visitors.
You know what to do.
I'll take the one on the left,
you take the one on the right.
Now.
Stop! Let him scream.
Exterior secured.
Last night was the worst fucking
game I've ever seen.
You didn't miss much,
I saw the whole thing.
I don't know
what they were thinking--
Help me, please!
They're coming to kill me!
- Don't move!
- You gotta help me, please!
Stop!
Fifth ﬂoor secure.
Hold the line!
Find out what is going on
down there.
Lieutenant, stay on me.
Rama, leave him.
Return to your position.
Vehicle 1, Vehicle 1.
This is Jake. Come in.
All units, this is Jaka.
Come in.
They're all dead.
Good morning, everyone!
You may have noticed we have
some guests trawling the halls today.
Now I certainly did not invite them, and
they most certainly are not welcome.
So in the interests of public health...
...should you help rid this building
of its recent infestation...
...well, then you can consider
yourself a permanent resident.
Free of charge.
You'll find these fucking
cockroaches on the sixth ﬂoor.
Now go to work.
And please, enjoy yourself.
Lieutenant, put a call in,
we need backup.
We can handle this.
With all due respect, sir, they'll burn
us along with the truck if we stay here.
Now make the call.
- I just can't.
- What do you mean, you can't?
We're not, this isn't...
Who else knows we're here?
What the fuck have you
brought us into, lieutenant?
We're alone here.
Sergeant!
Stay put.
Wait!
Everyone fall back!
Move!
- What the fuck have you done now?
- Come here.
See for yourself.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
Watch your mouth, boy.
It's all under control. I got this.
Then tell me, genius...
...what happens when
they send in reinforcements.
You don't shoot cops.
You buy them!
Yeah, because they look like all
they want is a fucking check.
There won't be any reinforcements,
there won't be any repercussions.
This is no different from one
of our rivals getting torn to pieces.
Once we're done, there won't
be any evidence left behind.
What makes you so sure?
Because I know who's behind this.
That quaking old fuck.
And I got him right where I want him.
- Fall back. Hanggi, open the door.
- Yes sir!
- Clear!
Keep the door shut.
No, wait!
Fuck!
We have to get out of this place.
Alee, the axe!
Sergeant!
Follow me.
Jaka!
Wait!
They're coming!
Bows, the axe!
Get me the fuck out of here!
Alee, help!
Dag“!
Once I pop this, turn it around.
One, two, three!
What the fuck was that?
Looks like we just learned
what we're dealing with.
What's the damage?
It's pretty contained, I'd guess
we've lost no more than two rooms.
That's not bad.
Around 30 tenants
who once paid us rent...
...are now spread
across the fucking walls.
Check which rooms they stayed in.
Clean out their stashes.
They can cover the damage.
Both of you get down there.
I want this situation under control.
Yes, boss.
You take the stairs and I'll take the lift.
We'll meet at the seventh ﬂoor.
Tomy, Angga, go with him.
I'm fine alone.
Go with him.
They're going-
Fine.
- Where are we going?
- Room 726, he lives here.
- No.
- Trust me, I know what I'm doing.
- Don't fucking leave me with that guy.
- He's not one of them.
If that bastard cuts me,
I swear to God I'll fucking haunt you.
I can live with that.
Leave it.
Up. Two ﬂoors.
Open the door!
I have an injured man here.
If you don't open up, we're dead.
Don't do it, don't get involved.
Please, they're close.
I'm begging you, look at me.
Open the door.
Please.
You can't turn your back on us.
Now open the door.
Start from there.
This way.
Wait.
What the fuck is going on?
Shut the fuck up or I'll bleed you.
Check everything and every corner.
Don't leave anything to chance.
- You hiding anyone here, friend?
- No, I swear it.
You wouldn't be lying
to me now, would you'?
I got no time for liars.
Puts me in a bad mood.
When I'm in a bad mood,
I tend to lash out.
- I promise, I'm telling you the truth.
- We'll see.
What's this?
- No, please don't.
- Hey, stop, goddamn it!
This is all I got, you fucking punks!
Fuck you! Leave us alone!
I'm getting real tired of your shit.
Look around you, there's no one
here, you've ruined my home.
- Don't fucking question me, friend.
- I told you the truth. Leave us alone.
You want me to slice that bitch up?
Well, do you?
Then sit down!
Okay, let's go.
Quick, I need a knife
or something sharp.
You're gonna be okay.
But you have to stay calm.
I just gotta patch you up
Hold on, focus-.
All I have is this.
Fuck you, look again.
I swear it's all I got.
What about a spoon?
Or some chopsticks?
Fuck it, just do it.
Why?
What the fuck are you doing?
You have to tell me all
I need to know about this place.
Anything I can use to help
get him out of here.
I wish I could, but the truth is Tama
has this place completely in control.
Even if you find a spot
away from his cameras...
...you'll be trapped in the corridors.
There's no escape route.
No passage you can take.
If you make it, it will be
the same way you came.
You have to break your way out.
You should be careful.
You're not here to do good.
Don't be blind.
I've seen that old man here before.
He knows this building
as well as I do.
Not every cop
is swayed by money, sir.
If I believed that, I would
never have opened the door.
He's boneheaded and stubborn.
But he's a good man.
Take care of him,
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Man, that's too much!
He's here!
Up]
Take the leg!
Where'd he come from?
Stop it! Calm down!
What the fuck are you doing here?
Keep watch.
They're gone.
We don't know that yet.
Think about it, Jake,
one's a cripple, the other a rookie.
They didn't stand a chance.
Now, I'm sorry, but we're not going
up there just to find their dead bodies.
Listen to me, you prick.
When it comes to the lives of my men,
it'd be wise for you to shut the fuck up.
You wanna talk about risking lives?
Well, you already risked theirs.
And now I own yours.
Who ordered this?
What?
Well, it sure as shit wasn't you.
No one leads the charge when
it comes to their own dirty work.
Careful, Jaka.
Remember your rank.
Rank?
Rank counts for shit now.
Once we make it out of here...
...you'll be mopping up puddles of piss
in a prison cell for the rest of your life.
We're not hereto do good.
We're here to make someone rich.
I'm asking you one last time,
who ordered this hit?
Another time maybe.
I'll take my chances here first.
Suit yourself.
We're going back up there.
We're going to find them.
And only then do we leave.
Any objections?
Thought not.
Everyone ready.
Move.
Protect him!
Now!
I've never really liked using these.
Takes away the rush.
Squeezing a trigger...
...it's like ordering takeout.
Now this.
This is the thing.
This is the pulse.
This is what I do.
You shouldn't be here.
Nor should you.
Who are they?
They're no one.
Don't they check for links
before they send you?
They got nothing on record
about you, just your first name.
No one knows shit about us.
I almost fucking choked when they
pinned your photo on the board.
Six years with no contact,
and this is how I find you.
You have to leave this place.
Now.
I can't.
Not without my team.
- What?
- You heard me.
I don't think you realize
the situation you're in.
Oh, I understand fine.
I'm not the one living here.
Don't worry about me. I'm fine.
Next time you want to talk,
just pick up the phone.
I spent the last 24 hours listening to
my best friends talk about killing you.
I'm the only one who can get
you out of here safely.
Without handcuffs
around your wrists.
Wait, what's that?
You're getting me out?
You need saving. Last I checked my
guys are almost done collecting these.
- Fuck you, just do what I say.
- And go where? Home?
If I was such a disappointment
to him then...
...think how proud he's gonna be
now that I am who I am.
He just wants you home,
we all do.
You don't get it.
That ain't me anymore. This is.
Just because you see what I do as
wrong doesn't mean I can't be good at it.
This is the one thing
I know how to do.
I fucking own it.
No, Rama.
I won't go back to who I was.
You're going to be an uncle.
What?
Yeah, a boy, due in two months.
You tell me this now,
because you expect me to leave.
I told you because
you're my fucking brother.
Think about what you're doing!
If you stay here you'll be fucking
dead before that boy is born.
Haven't you thought about that?
I've thought about it every day
since I was given this assignment.
And it fucking terrifies me.
This is fucking ridiculous.
You should leave,
I don't have much time.
At least change your clothing
before you go back out there.
No, this fits me just fine.
Hang back, till the area is clear.
Wait! Hold the lift.
- Where are your men?
- Still hunting. And yours?
Same.
- Where are you taking him?
- The boss.
That's not the guy.
- It is.
- No, it definitely isn't.
Plus this guy is dead already.
Yeah, well, I'm taking him anyway.
What have you got?
Rama.
Get in.
'%'here's Bows?
He's safe.
- We lost the sergeant.
- They got him, he's dead.
Motherfucker dragged him
across the floor like an animal.
What happened?
Why did you split up?
We were ambushed, outnumbered.
And he ran.
Sergeant ordered me to protect him.
Right now all we can do
is try to survive this.
We have to move soon and fast.
You've been the cause of every
drop of blood spilt in this place.
But not now. Now you're gonna
be with us step by step.
Blow for blow.
Until this nightmare is over.
Then what?
We go up. We attack.
We get who we came here for
and we use him to get out.
Finding him won't be easy.
The fifteenth ﬂoor.
It's where he runs everything.
But reaching him
is another thing entirely.
And assuming we do get him...
...what then? What's your plan?
We'll convince him.
How?
Men change with a gun to the head.
We don't have a gun.
A knife, a chair leg,
your bare hands, anything.
Just do whatever it takes
to make him ours.
We still have time,
we can still get out.
Who the fuck is that?
I told him it's the wrong guy.
He's wearing a vest, he counts. I'm not
the one who came back empty-handed.
That's not true, is it, Andi?
Excuse me.
Surely you've got something to show.
You of all people wouldn't waste
my fucking time for nothing.
I'm sorry, I don't.
Show me your hands.
Bring them here.
- What?
- Here.
Empty'
But I'm sure you have something.
Turn them.
I was wrong.
You did waste my fucking time.
I found dead bodies,
there's a lot of them.
Oh, yeah? What else?
If I had to guess, I'd say there
are two more cops out there.
What if I said there are three cops left,
would you agree?
As I said, there's a lot of floors.
You could give or take.
Give or take...
You little prick.
I'll admit it, I was impressed,
I really was.
But never underestimate
the persistence of paranoia.
After seeing that, I'd have
sat still with shit in my pants.
Seems these monitors
are the only truth I got left.
They never lie, they tell me
everything I need to know.
But there's one thing
I wanted to ask.
Why?
Ballsy move like that...
...ain't from no clash of conscience.
No, there's more to this.
Then I think, it doesn't matter because
you're going to die soon anyway.
I don't really give a shit
about "why" anymore.
No, what I want to know is...
...who is this little cunt
that's been tearing my place up?
And what would it mean for you...
...if you were to die in front of him?
Or better yet, for him to be
cut open in front of you!
Fuck you.
Hurry!
Don't move!
Drop the gun.
Are we gonna play this game now?
Get over here.
Faster!
Did I do something wrong, officer?
Shut the fuck up!
Put your hands in the air!
Dagu, tie him.
Now you're going to get me
the fuck out of here.
Amazing.
Wahyu, what the hell are you doing?
Dagu?
He didn't make it.
Fuck, you motherfucker! Why?
Save it. We're almost done here.
Just one last thing to clean up.
- You'll never get out of here.
- Shut up!
Did you honestly think
it would be that easy to get in'?
Did you think we were
that fucking stupid?
I was waiting for you,
we all were.
Ready to pick you off one by one.
Didn't work too well, did it?
Oh, I don't know,
you got at least 18 dead.
No transportation.
You're stuck here.
You got no one left.
And if we're talking strength
in numbers...
'We're talking a bullet, and I
only need one for your fucking head.
You don't get it,
you're already dead.
You've been dead since
I got the call from Reza.
Now I've got your attention.
It was the name, right'?
Reza and the rest of the suits have
been happy with me since day one.
Because I know who to pay
and more importantly, how much.
But you?
All you are is a collector.
It was never about replacing me.
They sent you here to die.
Fuck you!
No, fuck you, big fucking man!
You listen to me, you think
they'll let you join them at the top?
Never! You'll always be looking up.
You think when all this is over they'll
welcome you back and promote you.
Make you a hero?
Never! You fuck!
You'll be met by someone
emptying a gun into you.
A fucking pillow over your face
when you sleep.
You're done, you're out.
Asshole.
Be quiet.
All residents, please return
to your rooms.
It's all over.
He always knew that someday
someone would try to fuck him over.
This was his insurance.
It's evidence of every
dirty cop he ever dealt with.
Not everyone you salute is rotten.
Find Bunawar.
He's a good man.
Open the gate!
Just keep walking.
Follow me.
If there's one thing I know for sure,
it's that in this world...
...I can protect you.
But can you do the same
for me in yours?
They'll come here.
They'll tear this place to the ground.
We'll be long gone
before they get here.
Then why stay?
For the same reason
you stayed in that uniform.
It just fits.