Yes!
I am in train
speak louder
you cried a lot
she is hungry!
So feed her
i have forgot her feeder at home
i have got a new game "Call of duty"
what a game dude?
I will go back to home
let's go back to home
who are you people?
Ma'am! You shouldn't pick up
heavy stuff in this condition
i am driving this cab from 15 years
every person goes to house or hotel
straight from the airport
you are the first customer who is going
to police station
here it comes!
Now what?
His wife must have said the same
thing every night
how much?
Here's your bag
that's my number
if you ever need a cab so call me
just go straight
shall i take it
you came from abroad?
Yes! From London...
right now?
You will have to provide me the details
one month back...
want some tea?
So tell me one month back...
he came from London to Calcutta
he has an assignment for 2 weeks
he called me everyday first 2 weeks
but suddenly he stopped calling me
no messages, nothing
now i didn't understand what
should i do?
So i came here
your name?
Vidya bagchi
it's bidya!
Ma'am! In Calcutta we pronounce
it like this
your husband's name?
Anav
his age?
complexion!
Fair!
Height!
Taller than that...
do you have any photo?
It's one year older
no! 2 years older
don't you have his current photo
he is not fond of photos
it's not enough that we elope and get
married now you also need my photo
what's the proof that you got
married with me
that was our wedding day so i forced
him for a photo
what your husband did?
We both are software engineers
we make programmes
to save computers from virus attacks
like we police officers protect
the citizens
anabh about to came back to London
after finishing his assignment
but he didn't come,
he suddenly disappeared
no message!
No phone calls
and anabh is not like that
they told me that anabh didn't came
there for assignment
he came there, i knew it
we used to talk everyday
he called me thousand times a day
and i scolded him that don't waste your
money in phone bills
i don't know why they are lying
to me
Case is complicated,
but i will try my best
it will take some time
but it will be done
you will have to sign here
may i help you?
You have to clear the memory
what happen?
Sit!
Have some water
get me a cab
why cab?
Rana will drop you
how far away from here?
It's just nearby
how do you feeling now?
You came first time in Calcutta
entire Calcutta is preparing
for festival
so you know about durga festival
my husband is bengali so i must
know that
your name is common bengali name
why they call you rana?
In calcutta everyone have 2 names
two different names for a
single person
different identities
hotel has come?
It doesn't looks like the hotel
are you sure it's the same place?
Address is same
why your husband would stay here
are you the manager?
Yes!
I have called you from london
regarding my husband
look! I am not a queen
when you called up from london
so i told you that your husband
was not here
you are saying the same thing
that's why i came here and i know
because he called me everyday
from here
there must be some confusion
anabh stood here
this man is lying
show me your records...
that's your records
you don't have computer
ma'am! Computers are only available
in five star hotels
this is guest house
if you will go to lift then there
is a peacock statue
abnav told me that tamil's peacock
is still behind me here
where is the lift?
But your husband is not here
i mean he was...
are you joking?
Peacock is really there
but how do you know that?
If abhnav didn't tell me then
how do i know
i don't know why everyone is
lying to me
abhnav didn't stay here but
i will stay here
i will stay in room no. 15.
Are you sure?
Give me the keys
why are you standing at the door
you took so long
i am waiting for you here since long
and your phone was also not reachable
if it would not reachable
then i will wait for here
rain has started
now business is over
no hot water in my room i knew it
you knew it then why did you write
down on board running hot water
you need hot water then call vishnu
don't ask him that's radio
his life...
he will never give you that
you called me sister so
you are my brother
call mrs. Vidya bagchi
do you have an appointment?
Yeah!
Your husband didn't came to my company
for any assignment
i am h. r. Manager
i approve every assignment
and i didn't sanctioned any assignment
for abhnav bakhsi...
employee records are in old office
perhaps his photo is there
just look milind's photo once
then decide
you can't do a single job
you can't bring a single client
for life insurance
if it will keep running like that
then sooner you will be fired
from this job
switch off your phone and pay
attention on your targets
you will have to go Calcutta
right now
someone has shot n. d. O's h. R manager
that's local police station case
why you must have to go Calcutta
they want to open milind's record
any more information?
Some pregnant woman came from london
i want this room vaccant for
few moments
all of you go outside
Can't you hear me?
I want this room vaccant
anything else?
Tell me
you shouldn't smoke in
front of me
we don't know about each other
so what i have to do
you leave it to me
my husband is missing
what happen?
Why are you outside?
That lady is a problem, really?
What's going on here?
Look! I am talking to her...
out!
But who are you?
Close the door
so what were you saying?
Who is he?
Abnav's face is familiar to their
ex-employee
but there was no employee milind there
i think agnus doesn't know anything
because i remember she told
me his name milind
i know about n. d. O better than you
and agnus
2000 people worked there
actually she also told me that...
when she was trying to access
milind's records
then it was...
you are not listening to me
there was no file of milind
milind exists and who is milind
where did you find this paper
who cares?
Who is milind?
Is he your husband?
Look at to him carefully
is he your husband
no!
Then who cares that who is he?
Forget milind and i will also forget
that where did you find this paper
milind is not abhnav
but he looks like abhnav
and for this reason something
happened to my husband
that's important for me to know that
who is milind
rather you tell me
or leave it to me
i will find the answer and come
back to you
how would you find out?
I will go outside and ask everyone
rather he is the common man
police...
or media...
somebody will must have the answer
of this question
sit!
Two years back that
Calcutta metro attack
do you know something about that
milind was involved in that attack
he is the prime suspect in this case
then why nobody knows about milind
milind doesn't exist for the people
when i have been told to arrest him
but till then it was too late
milind was disappeared along
with his records
but how somebody could disappeared
milind was a federal agent
he met with the enemies
we have been hiding this issue
from the public
there is someone inside our system
who is helping milind
this is really a dangerous game
milind's protectors are very powerful
they can do anything
are you alright?
Thank god i saved you today
but if i wouldn't save you tomorrow
i will pray to god that you and your
baby should be fine
anything could happen here
go back!
I don't wanna come back
keep your bureau and your system
only one project was failed
it means we should close the bureau
we should shut down the system
only one project?
You can say very easily
you gave me this assignment
ohoose 3 people train them and make
them best bureau agent
and what have i done?
I have got 2 nice people
but i have trained mutant like milind
and he sold him up to those people from
whom he have to save us
for those civilians i trained him
he killed those civilians
we will find milind
you come back
you can't find milind
i have trained him
they can find only stupid people
like us
who is shouting for nothing
that our system is perfect
there is no corruption in our system
one person helped milind to escape
that person is still working
in your bureau
the day you will find him
i will come back that day
three things could be happen
anbhav left me
anbhav and milind are same person
anbhav's face is familiar to milind and
that's why he is in trouble
so you are saying that...
anbhav's face is familiar to milind...
i am sure
we will have to find milind to
get anbhav
and the day we will find milind
that day we will anbhav too
how is that possible
how we will find that person
from his house
i have seen milind's address in
agnus file
oan you climb up?
Yes
here it is but it's closed
officer is breaking the lock
you have said it
i don't know what was the need
to lock this place
nothing is here
and if there was something then
that company would have got it
let's go back from here
i will see once
don't do it over and over again
we will must f'ind something
did you see only flat no.3 letter
box was not there
do you have any letter for flat no.3
i have one
milind used to order tea from here
they might have told us something
how do you know?
You gave me the tea in same glass
remember same glasses were
in milind's house
and there was no kitchen in
milind's house
are you scared?
He is my friend
what's your name?
Tell me do you know something
about flat no.3
what kind of man he was?
When you went to give him tea
so did he smile on you
did he talk to you?
He didn't talk anything but...
he always order one cup of tea
sometimes another person had come
so he ordered two cup of tea
who is another man?
He always brought a suit case
when you smile you look
so handsome
you can win any kid's heart
i am sure...
what?
That you will be a good mother
agnus told me that milind's blood
group was very rare
if somebody have rare blood group so
he store his blood in our department
so if there is any emergency so he
could use his blood
in this case when did you need this
blood last time
oan you check?
In 25th may 2008 we needed this
blood group
not a single paper
no record, nothing
there will be but it's disappeared like
every milind's link
shop is closed here
there must be something
i am not gonna give up
you have always supported me
i can't go further without your help
there is a man who could help us
in old times he was a police informer
bob biswas was a contract killer
it's his phone and we have found
these photos from his phone
and you are the next
this time you survived but that person
who hired bob
who doesn't want that anyone could
lead to milind
i gave this photo to agnus...
iook at this!
I gave this photo copy to agnus
it means who gave contract to bob he
is working in n. d. O
it means whatever i said you did
not listen
and you are not trying to understand
your life is in danger
and i will have to inform khan...
did you f'ind mr. Briefcase name?
He is in i. T department and tyagi
reports him
we were thinking that tyagi is
doing everything
but tyagi was just giving information
we have no proof of that
let's go to police
that phone is my evidence
look at this
bob got this message from
some web site
once i will hack this website
then we will know from whose computer
this message was sent
are you hacker?
Only for spare time
do you know i am police
it's the i. p. Address of that computer
where these photos has been uploaded
and i am sure this is
mr. Briefase computer
and once it wil be confirm then we
will find milind
that matter is really serious
and i am still telling you that we
should go to police
we don't have much time
mr. Briefcase will know soon that
bob is dead
and he will try to remove all
the records
i have to access shiver's computer once
then we will go to police
do you think death is a joke
i have told you many times
your life is in danger
you have seen it from your eyes
after that you are joking
with your death
because after abhnav
life has become a joke for me
you didn't go yet
sir office is getting closed for
veneration
so i was finishing my jobs
one day if i will get some time
then i will take you outside
for coffee
why did you put visitor's book
give me employees book
do it fast whatever you want
did somebody came with sapna
one man and woman came with her
close all the door
don't let anyone out
is somebody downstairs?
No!
That back door is open where
people smokes
we are leaving from back door but
somebody is following us
please come fast.
What happen?
I have to call mr. Khan
this man can't die
we needed this man alive...
we will have to stop this operation
if milind will meet bagchi then her
life is in danger
you didn't understand
milind doesn't spare any eye witness
and this time he won't spare her
so we will try to protect your bagchi
you know and you...
we are scarifying her
this is very wrong
you will teach me what is right
and wrong
my job is to protect this country
and everything is right whatever
i have to do for that
if i will have to sacrify bagchi to
arrest milind
then what's the difference between
milind and us? Nothing...
we are working for law and he
is against the law
that's why we are right
and he is wrong
love is good thing
but learn it to use on right place
that love is telling you to tell
vidya about khan
it's wrong
you can save only one life with that
and what about those thousand lives
what milind will destroy
i was not going to tell her
take his mobile
don't let him go anywhere not
even bathroom
are you sherma?
Khan is calling you
he told me to stay here
sir!
Where is rana?
Where is bagchi?
She just check out...
she is just a story,
i don't have much time
if you want your husband back
if i will return the papers so
you will return me my husband
Can you return it?
Think about it...
who cares?
Who was this bagchi?
She was a mystery
where did you find this shirt?
That's my school uniform
check her hotel room and her
finger print,
and her husband?
So you didn't understand yet...
you narrated her a story in
the beginning
and she narrated you a story
in the beginning
milind was existed
but there is not vidya...
and nor any abhnav
whose face is familiar to milind
she was using us
i think vidya has been hired to
find and kill milnd
and she used us to get milind
she wanted us to sacrify her
to get milind
before we could arrest sheetal
vidya also killed her
you have put bhaskar and milind
in her custody
she knew that...
nobody is scared from pregnant woman
you needed proof against bhaskar
but who sent her?
He must be proud on you
because what you have done today non
of us could do that
may i tell you one strange thing
since last few days...
i have forgotten that
i am not pregnant
i felt that...
my kid is alive inside me...
i will find aroop somewhere...
i can't live without them
i want my aroop back
i want my kid back...