Close it!
Move!
Take out the ammunition
take it out!
Yes Qasim!
I have found the back door
Give me the order!
Don't spare anyone alive
Understood!
Kill everyone
Give me the bomb!
Fazal Khan is dead!
Now we will know who died and
who survived
Qasim!
Move!
I was about to shoot Vinod on his ass
but he came to my front
Anchor asked to Minister on TV
Tell me our national anthem
So he start singing
That's our minister
Fazal Khan is dead
I have demolished his entire castle
Stop the car!
It's police check post
Why this police check post is here?
What we do now?
Shall we go?
Leave it!
This check post is for us
Don't shoot here!
There are two kinds of human
One form is Clever and
second form is stupid
And this game is based upon these
two kind of humans
Now when some clever human started
foolish things
and when some fool has become a
part of cleverness
You never find out
This Wasseypur's story is strange
If you will see from outside
then Wasseypur is the village of
decent men
but when you enter inside...
then there are lot of bastards are
hidden inside...
Now what they have been proved
in the end that's another thing
at least they all think themselves
Clever in their lives...
We muslim's battle is not today's war
it has been running since centuries...
And in Wasseypur this fight was not
between Shia and Sunni
All of them were Sunni
This fight was between Qureshis and
other muslims...
It has announced war later
earlier it was one sided attacks...
Qureshi were butchers...
and Everyone was scared from Butchers
They scared the people...
Now Qureshis were ruling
in Wasseypur
When this village was outside
the Dhanbad
and then Dhanbad become
a part of Bengal
After freedom Dhanbad went to Bihar
and Wasseypur has become a part
of Dhanbad
Now Dhanbad is in Jharkandh
And Wasseypur is in the centre
of Dhanbad
Anyway!
Story is still running
But it was started
when around Dhanbad...
British has occupied all the harvests
and started coal business
when trains runs with coal...
and all factories and machines
runs with coal
When Sultana dacoit used to live here...
and he robbed their trains
That man attacked on british trains
and robbed their treasures
One day force were travelling in train
instead of treasure
when Sultana attacked on the train
British has arrested him and sent
him to Black Water
Mulla Jee told me that British gave
him death sentence
Your Moulvi is a stupid man
Actually Sultana was Qureshi
He is in Wasseypur
and british is still looking for him
and he's still robbing their trains
We have removed the tracks
if you will drive it then you will
be stuck
There is nothing in train but food bags
We are also businessmen
We are not dacoits who came to
rob the money
We have quit rob the treasure...
Now Sultana robs the food bags
May I go?
You have train
and I have bull cart
So until I don't return and ask
you to leave
till then sit here...
Where is the car?
I don't know
Open the box
I will check...
Why did you stop the train?
Train is empty
Why all boxes are empty?
Sultana dacoit came...
he robbed all the food...
There is someone who is robbing the
train with my name
Who could he be?
Shahid Khan!
He is only person who have horse
But his horse used for
commercial purpose
It was...
but now he sell food...
How is your business?
Entire market is finished...
He is selling the food in cheap prices
If we will try to fight so we will
be finish...
When your younger brother will come?
He should have come in 2 months
Train track passes from the
Qureshi neighbourhood
only qureshi lives both side
of the track
So Qureshi have right on every train
nor any pathan...
Look!
I just want to tell you one thing
Whatever you do
but don't do blood bath
Shahid is also belongs to
this Wasseypur
But he doesn't belongs to our caste...
If we will be caught so we appologize
to Mukhtar Sahab
He won't kill us
If he will kill us then...
He won't do it
I know him
Dog never change it's breed
If you don't beat the horse so
he never run
Shahid was stubborn like that
His life was in danger
Everyone knew that who is
robbing the trains...
but how do he listen to anyone
Are you scared?
Do you know who is Shareef Qureshi?
You are using his name
Sultana dacoit died in black water
and the rest are stories...
He is butcher
So what will he do?
We pathans keep thousand butchers
in our houses
They are weak like their goats
And tomorrow I will remove the train
from the tracks
Here they come!
Run for your lives
Don't spare anyone alive
Where is everyone?
Only I am alive
They have killed all of them
You said that they won't
do anything
tell him to leave Wasseypur with
his family
We will go...
but ask him how I will feed them
and by the way what have
I done with him
One food bag
will reach to your him from
every train
Fine!
Don't give him any food bag
Shahid khan must escaped for
his life
but he was not coward
He knew that Qureshi won't
spare him
We all lived in Darbar
Shahid's wife gave him his
kid's swear
that he will quit his bad habits
and he will find a job
Please stop the work
Water is pouring inside...
Everyone will sink down
Do your work!
Even 9 hours are not completed
from 12 hours job
Everyone will sink down...
Nobody else is asking for me
Then why you have a problem
What?
Shahid Khan!
His baby is stuck in his wife's womb
So?
Please give him news,
No need of it,
Get lost from here
Nobody will stop the work before
12 hours
If anyone will stop the work
then I will remove his skin and hang
him to butcher market
Do something!
Do your work!
Don't talk
What are looking at me?
I have to go
Kid is stuck in wife's womb
It doesn't stuck in your womb
Do your work
I insist let me go!
Don't you understand?
Open it!
Why?
Are you a Governer?
I am not from those people who will
endure your abuses
I have done my work with honesty
If I will be late today
then I will kill you...
How she is?
She is in pain!
So why you didn't come earlier?
I wanted to come
but he didn't let me come
It's been 6 hours but kid is
not coming out
what were you doing from 6 hours?
I was coming but...
he pushed me away
We can't blame to God for
life and death
We gave life with our wish and
sometimes by mistake
but people died from our mistake
It wasn't that Pehelwan's mistake
who didn't let me come
It was my mistake
that I defeated from that Pehelwan
And I have to suffer the punishment
of my weakness
Shahid Khan will kill our man
Who Shahid Khan?
Do you accept this marriage?
Yes! I do...
Coming!
He killed my father
My father sat in his car and gone
with him
he never came back
I have only object in my life
Revenge!
I can't see Ramdheer Singh's progress
I have to finish that bastard
I won't shoot him
I will make fun of him
I will show him his value
Slowly slowly I will snatch everything
from him so he will die...
I am standing on this stage and
promise you
In 1952 when Jeewan Raam was
announced Minister
so he announced Coal Welfare
Association to see labour's condition
as per that National Trade Union
has been established
As per that Supervisors pressurized
Coal Mines Oweners
and Ramadheer Singh was the
Leader of that movement
This trade union has become a
face of Mafia
Union Leader has become contractors
and they were raising funds to make
other labours to their workers
They gave money on interest
and they keep their salaries
for interest
New contractors came one by one
He has become politican and
won the election
My dad run coal mines for
many years
I know how contractors and labours
stealing coal and sell in black markets
I won't let this black
marketting happen
My profit should be great
Coal is a great thing
It looks like stone
but it's not think like stone
it's light weighted
if you will put it into water
now it will be dry
and it will become
heavy
16 Tons...
you are facing many injustices
Our union...
And how it's happening
It's all happening under Chief...
I have told you
that my share should be same
like other contractors
I am sending the stuff as per
your demand
It's going...
but it's not reaching there.
Until S.P. Sinha will alive
till then nor we will eat something
neither we will have house
What do you think?
S.P. Sinha is just educated
he is writing in his office
How do he know how people
are stealing
We don't have food to eat
and he is gardening outside
his house
You shouldn't break the flower
just play with it
What was under S.P. Sinha
Ramadher Singh has become contractor
from Owner
And after killing S.P. Sinha
Ramadheer's terror has increased
Your father was a big man
Where is Sardar Khan?
Sardar khan came here
She says that she is Nagma
She said I am Nagma
and you think she is Nagma
I didn't found out
I was drunk
She took advantage of me
What are you doing?
She will die
Let her die
I won't spare you alive
I will see you later
Where are you running?
Some day you will come home
Please forgive me
What is it?
I don't know
Nothing could happen right now
Somebody is inside my womb
So I am not taking him out
Don't you ashame?
You will make your kid dirty
This is not right...
When somebody is already inside
So you should control your self
Rama Heer Singh recognized Sardar
Perhaps not me,
Besides he saw me with Shahid
It was a time...
when big people forget their names
but they never forget their land...
Where it's written that this
land is yours...
If it's your land then show me
the papers
Land is mine
I have already made a deal
And what you are trying to occupied
It won't be good for you
Think and speak!
Don't tell me the differences
Here's the land papers
I have bought it for Rs. 10
Do you know what's your value?
If you will keep sitting on your chair
then it will be good for everyone
You don't know who am I?
When you go back to home and
itching your father's ass...
then ask him who am I?
How many days I will be imprisoned
to slap a minister in police station
Start the car!
You will appoint anyone without
any information
I didn't know...
Look! Everyone look your minister
has been beaten up
What are you doing?
Why are you beating him?
If you will interfere then I will
slit your throat
I have beaten up Minister
in S. P's office
In front of his father
My name is Sardar Khan
Tell everyone
Last night I saw a nightmare
Do you remember Shahid Khan?
He came to your dreams
his son
His son's ghost came to my dream
Whom you have killed and buried
Where did you buried him?
Do you remember?
Go there!
And dig that place and bring
his bones
Priest was saying that...
His body is still alive
And he is scaring me
Now tell me the truth
Otherwise I will kill you
and bury there
I made a mistake
Your mistake will create a scene
He is Pappu
from Punjab
He is expert to make bombs
Will you make bomb?
I will...
What do you need?
I will need Sulpher
And...
Coal powder,
Will you make it?
Where?
To give food
Who?
To my dad
What did I told you?
Why are you beating me?
Do it properly
Why?
I'm going to give food to my dad
Are you my son or your dad's son
where your father used to go
I am Sardar Khan's son
What?
Food!
Open it!
How much time it will take
I am making bomb not tea
It will take time
Celebrate your next eid here
Tie it fast
I will have to tie it tight
Make it fast
He is coming
Give me the gun
Come fast Pappu!
Throw the bomb on the wall
It didn't blown up
Few people doesn't teach anything
to their women
Some day butchers will see her then
they will rape her
But what she is doing here?
Sultan brought her up here
She stood in mosque last night
She came here
Wait!
Until I am alive
You will have never pay for ice cream
Who is that?
Uncle!
Show me the picture
Qureshi were ruled in Wasseypur
from Sultana dacoit's time
It was sultana that time
Now it is Sultan
And Sultan's Butcher Goon can
do anything here
They kidnapped any woman
They does anything
with whom other muslims were scared
Qamar Makhdoom has decided to
get them their rights
But Qureshis made fun of him
What's the matter?
Nowadays you came to get by yourself
You don't order at your home
I want to meet Sultan
Sultan is the son of Sultana dacoit's
daughter's son
whom Ehsan Qureshi has grown up
at his home
He chopped the buffalo when he
was 12
And still today he chopped 60 buffalos
that's why others are scared from him
What we do about these Qureshis?
We tried to explain them
We requested them
But they don't care
Everyone knew about your
dad's legendary
Now you just come back
That house was empty in neighbourhood
We all have bought it
now Sultan has occupied that house
His goons gamble all day long there
They drink beer
They kidnapped a woman
in night
What we do now?
Let's go!
How do I go college?
He stood there everyday
If I change the lane so he
came from anywhere
He looks at me like no man has
seen a woman
It seems that he will eat me
He is a Pehelwan of Dhanbad
If you will kill him in Wasseypur
then there is no problem
He must J. P Singh's man
Now if we will do something...
then it will are will know
How are you?
Is he dead?
Not dead?
Sardar lived in Wassepur for 1 year
after the jailbreak
He killed Pehelwan there
J.P. Singh's Pehelwan
whom nobody has touched yet
Wasseypur was muslim's area
He chopped his body and threw
it to every Slaughter house
Qureshi's had contract of
Bhau Jee Street
and Qamar Makhdoom was not favourite
of Qureshis...
That girl was not belong to Qureshi
besides that Qureshi did't said
anything
And their Sardar Sultan remains quite
Emergency was over
It was 80's...
and Wassepur has become Dhanbad
where Sardar was living two lives
One house in Wasseypur where
Qureshis were his enemies
Seond house is in Dhanbad where
Ramadheer Singh was his enemy
There was only one advantage to
live in Wasseypur
that police never came to this area
Why did you came here?
This is Wasseypur
Sardar Khan killed Pehelwan
in Dhanbad
I thought he is here
When Sardar will come in markets
then you shall catch him
This is Wasseypur
Here pigeon fly with one wing
and save his respect from
another wing
I have proof!
I have brought cycle material
Cycle's pipe is weak and it will
not explode properly
So what should I bring?
Truck's steering pipe
How much pipe I will have to bring
What is the range?
How much?
From which distance I will shoot and
man will be hurted
It will shoot till 20 feets
What did you made?
It shakes my hand
I shot in Qasai Market and it
goes to Calcutta
Do you think I am a fool?
Who was that?
What was that?
Sardar Khan!
Everyone was gone to mourne
I was sleeping upstairs
I am not feeling well today
I heard a blast...
When I came out
I have seen everywhere...
We should kill him
And Sardar has become so famous
that he has forgotten
that his wife and sons are
still alive...
Shall I turn off the light
Let it be...
I will turn it off
They are not scared
They are waiting
They watch and attack
What happen?
Doctor has stopped me,
Doctor doesn't know anything
So what should I do?
Good excuse!
Like I wanted to do it
God left your child in my womb
My mom didn't had 4 kids,
You are taking revenge of that
I am not taking revenge
You really enjoy to born the kid
When you stay at home?
You have no time,
If I will bring another wife?
What do you mean?
Like I don't know about your affair
Did you make her pregnant?
Why are you staring at me?
I am leaving
Give me the keys
Where are you going?
It's me Sardar!
Where you have been?
You stay here!
I am coming
What happen?
You are feeling pain
Leave me!
Enough!
Will you kill me?
What happen?
What you have done with me?
You have tied me here
Why are you cursing me?
I don't want to be child making machine
So who is making?
So what is this?
This is love
Where is your mom?
She is conscious...
Is it boy or girl?
Boy!
So smile!
Do you need money?
You don't want to meet mom
Now she is conscious so what
it worths...
Tell her that I came in new shirt
Your dad has stopped sending money
Find a job and earn some money
Tell me where are you going?
Who you are going to kill?
What?
How much you got?
20 rupees
That's it
You will give 10 rupees to mom
I will give whole money to mom
Did you recognize me?
What?
Ramadheer!
Come I will drop you home
Since when your dad didn't come home
A year!
Or more than a year
He earns millions
and he spend his money to that
woman and his sons
You both are cleaning train toilets
instead of going school
Don't you feel angry?
It's 1000 rupees.
Keep it
Tell your mom
Ramadheer is with her
Who gave you?
Ramadheer Singh gave me
He said if you need more money then
come and get it
He gave you and you keep it
Are you a beggar?
Is your dad died?
Why dad doesn't come home?
Why he doesn't send money
Now you want to kill him
Why did you get the money?
So what if your dad doesn't
come home
You are roaming with his respect
You take money from Ramadheer Singh?
Don't rub it!
I am not injured
Get some automatic guns,
You will get everything
Learn something from him
He doesn't have anything to do
Go and help your mom
Time has come that steeling coal
was a small business
Coal Labour has started their small
business
Big business was Contractorship
Rather it's a wood contract
It has written 32 trucks rate
So 32 truck is parked there
Where it is?
Look over there
that's only one,
That's the 32nd truck...
I have to fill entire mine
Otherwise land will be collapse
We have started sand near lake
Sardar got the contract to fill the
mine with land
And Sardar has become a king
of Wasseypur
After killing Qureshis and blown up
their houses...
Sardar has removed them
from Wasseypur
and he started iron business with
Asghar
Coal chapter has become history
for Dhanwaad Mafia
Old Machines tendor is coming
for factories
He grown up!
Will you work with us?
Put him on some job
Make a line and everyone will
get money
if someone is not in the line so
don't give him the money
How is your mom?
Where is your brother?
I want to tell you something
Come home!
I would...
but I am scared from your mom
Ramadheer couldn't harm me
but if his mom wants...
So she can fry my liver
Bring the gun
Why you didn't keep the gun here?
He is been shot
I am fine!
Bring the jeep
I am fine
You are not fine
Get him up!
Nothing happened to me
Where is the key?
You have put the keys in your ass
You had the keys
My son has been shot
Check him!
He is standing here
you are not doing right
He won't lay down from himself,
If he will die...
What is this?
Remove your shirt!
I think electicity is gone
Now nothing can happen in dark
So what if electricity is gone,
There is no tube light in my ass
Nothing will happen in dark,
Everything will gone wrong
Operate him!
Where is Danish?
He is in operation theatre...
how he is?
Go and seee...
What happen?
Now I will have to give you invitation
card to get down
That car is parked over there...
Yes!
Open it's every part
We are just making your car in pieces
If something would happen to my son
then I would fire so many bullets
that your driver...
would become rich to sell
bullet holes
Are you enjoying?
Smell him and tell what he
got in breakfast?
Wife's thrash
What?
This is not good
What's the problem?
You live on one floor and she
will live on another floor
If you want you can make
seperate kitchen
Do you want your daddy?
Yes!
Let's do one thing
I will make you in two pieces
I will have one leg
and she will have another leg
Get lost from here
You won't come.
Never!
Fine!
I will come later
Where is daddy?
In hell...
Give your right to someone else...
I am getting married next month
We are waiting for your releasing order
Do you know?
We have quit all bad business
I have started new business of
selling fishes
It's a good business
What are you looking over there?
I will come to pick you up
before marriage
I will come
I met your old friends in jail
Last time when dad send
me with money
so I didn't understand...
that why a gun of 150,000
would be sold so cheap
it should be expensive
Money is there!
Total 250,000
Now I know...
that your dad have gun factory
I also want to pee,
Come out!
So pee in another washroom
I will stop the train for your pee
You came again
What's the matter?
You ran in hurry
where are you going?
Home!
Everyone is going home but where
are you going?
What's your name?
Fazal Khan
It's your bag
Open it!
New clothes
Jail staff didn't return my old stuff
Whose bag is that?
Mine!
Put it down!
Have I done some mistake?
You are telling me politics getting
engage with enemy
you are getting married with
Sardar Khan's family
That's why he is alive
Wait!
What are you doing?
What happen?
It hurts...
Any reason to join the police force?
Amitach Bachchan joined police force
in Zanjeer
because he wanted to take revenge
Later he learn something
In Deewar he has become goon
to take revenge
I still don't get thrown money
Do you understand?
Where are you going?
Dad is about to leave!
Brother is gone to his room
So I will have to go
Sit!
Let me go!
I will drop you
Danish!
He slept late
Fazlu made a phone call he slept there
Nasir!
He is also sleeping
Asghar!
He is gone out
You know about everyone
You woke up earlier and now you
are shouting
What's my name?
Sardar Khan!
Thank God you remember my name
I will come till evening
It's me...
Tell your mom that I came here
It's 10,000
If you need more then tell me
I will send it
May I leave?
He is gone!
Full the tank!
There is only one object in my life
Revenge!