Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
Sometimes,
I think I'm cursed.
Because of something that
happened before I was even born.
See, a long time ago,
there was this family.
The papa, he was a musician.
He and his family would sing and
dance and count their blessings.
But he also had a dream.
To play for the world.
And one day,
he left with his guitar
and never returned.
And the mama...
She didn't have time to cry
over that walk-away musician.
After banishing all music from
her life she found a way...
to provide for her daughter.
She rolled up her sleeves
and she learned to make shoes.
She could have made candy,
or fireworks,
or sparkly underwear...
for wrestlers,
but no, she chose shoes.
Then she taught her daughter
to make shoes.
And later,
she taught her son-in-law.
Then her grandkids
got roped in.
As her family grew,
so did the business.
Music had torn
her family apart.
But shoes held
them all together.
You see, that woman was
my great-great-grandmother,
Mama Imelda.
She died
way before I was born.
But my family
still tells her story
every year
on Dia de los Muertos...
the Day of the Dead.
And her little girl,
she's my great-grandmother,
Mama Coco.
Hola, Mama Coco.
How are you, Julio?
Actually, my name is Miguel.
Mama Coco has trouble
remembering things.
But it's good
to talk to her anyway.
So, I tell her
pretty much everything.
I used to run like this.
But now I run like this
which is way faster.
And the winner
is Luchadora Coco!
I have a dimple on this side,
but not on this side.
Dimple, no dimple.
Miguel, eat your food.
My abuelita,
she's Mama Coco's daughter.
Oh, you're a twig, mijo.
Have some more.
No, gracias.
I asked if you would
like more tamales!
Si?
That's what
I thought you said!
Abuelita runs our house
just like Mama Imelda did.
No music!
♪ Y aunque la vida ♪
I think we're
the only family in Mexico
who hates music.
And my family's fine
with that. But me...
- Be back by lunch, mijo.
- Love you, Mama.
I am not like
the rest of my family!
- Hola, Miguel!
- Hola!
- Muchas gracias.
- De nada, Miguel.
Hey! Dante!
Sit. Down.
Roll over. Shake.
Fist bump!
Good boy, Dante!
I know I'm not
supposed to love music.
But it's not my fault!
It's his!
Ernesto de la Cruz.
The greatest musician
of all time.
Right here
in this very plaza,
Ernesto de la Cruz
took his first steps...
toward becoming the most beloved
singer in Mexican history.
He started out a total
nobody from Santa Cecilia, like me.
But when he played music, he made
people fall in love with him.
He starred in movies.
He had the coolest guitar!
He could fly!
And he wrote the best songs.
But my all-time favorite,
it's...
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have
to say goodbye
- ♪ Remember me
♪ Don't let it make you cry
For even if I'm far away
♪ I hold you in my heart
I sing a secret song to you
♪ Each night we are apart
Remember me
♪ Though I have
to travel far
- ♪ Remember me
♪ Each time you hear
a sad guitar
♪ Know that I'm with you
the only way that I can be
♪ Until you're
in my arms again ♪
He lived the kind
of life you dream about.
Until 1942.
When he was crushed
by a giant bell.
I want to be just like him.
Sometimes,
I look at de la Cruz
and I get this feeling
like we're connected.
Like if he could play music,
maybe someday, I could too.
If it wasn't for my family.
- Ay-ay-ay, muchacho.
- Huh?
I asked for a shoe shine
not your life story.
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
I just can't really talk about
any of this at home. So...
If I were you,
I'd march right up
to my family and say...
"Hey, I'm a musician.
Deal with it."
I could never say that.
You are a musician, no?
I don't know.
I mean, I only
really play for myself.
Ah! Did de la Cruz become
the world's best musician
by hiding his skills?
No! He walked out
onto that plaza
and he played out loud.
Mira, mira, they're
setting up for tonight!
The music competition
for Dia de Muertos.
You want to be like your hero?
You should sign up!
Uh-uh.
My family would freak!
Look, if you're too scared then,
well, have fun making shoes.
Come on, what did
de la Cruz always say?
Seize your moment?
Show me what
you got, muchacho.
I'll be your first audience.
Miguel!
- Abuelita!
- What are you doing here?
You leave my grandson alone.
Dona, please!
I was just getting
a shine.
I know your tricks, mariachi.
What did he say to you?
He was just
showing me his guitar.
Shame on you.
My grandson is a sweet little
angelito querido cielito.
He wants no part
of your music, mariachi.
You keep away from him.
Ay, pobrecito.
Oh, estas bien, mijo.
You know better than to
be here in this place!
You will come home. Now.
How many times
have we told you?
That plaza is
crawling with mariachis.
Yes, Tio Berto.
- No, no, no, no, no!
- Ah! Go away, you. Go!
It's just Dante.
Never name a street dog.
They'll follow you forever.
Now, go get my shoe.
I found your son
in Mariachi Plaza.
Ay, Miguel!
You know how Abuelita
feels about the plaza.
I was just shining shoes.
A musician's shoes!
But the plaza's where
all the foot traffic is.
If Abuelita says no more
plaza, then no more plaza.
- But what about tonight?
- What's tonight?
Well, they're having
this talent show.
And I
thought I might...
- Sign up?
- Well, maybe?
You have to have
talent to be in a talent show.
What are you gonna do?
Shine shoes?
It's Dia de los Muertos.
No one's going anywhere.
Tonight is about family.
Ofrenda room. Vamonos.
Don't give me that look.
Dia de los Muertos
is the one night of the year
our ancestors
can come visit us.
We've put their photos
on the ofrenda
so their spirits
can cross over.
That is very important.
If we don't put them up,
they can't come.
We made all this food,
set out the things
they loved in life, mijo.
All this work
to bring the family together.
I don't want you sneaking
off to who knows where.
Where are you going?
I thought
we were done.
Ay, Dios mio. Being part
of this family means
being here for this family.
I don't want
to see you end up like...
Like Mama Coco's papa?
Never mention that man!
He's better off forgotten.
But you're the one who...
I was just...
But... I...
Papa? Papa is home?
Mama, calmese, calmese.
Papa is coming home?
No, Mama.
It's okay. I'm here.
Who are you?
Rest, Mama.
I'm hard on you
because I care, Miguel.
Miguel? Miguel?
What are we going
to do with that boy?
You're right.
That's just what he needs.
It's you. Get in here.
Come on, Dante. Hurry up!
You're gonna
get me in trouble, boy.
Someone could hear me.
I wish someone
wanted to hear me.
Other than you. Ew. Okay.
Perfecto!
I have to sing.
I have to play!
The music, it's not
just in me, it is me.
When life gets me down,
I play my guitar.
The rest of the world
may follow the rules,
but I must follow my heart.
Ugh!
You know that feeling like
there's a song in the air and...
it's playing just for you?
♪ A feeling so close...
♪ You could
reach out and touch it
♪ I never knew
♪ I could want something
so much, but it's true ♪
You must have faith, sister.
Oh, but, Padre,
he will never listen.
He will listen. To music.
♪ Only a song,
only a song
♪ Has the power
to change a heart ♪
Never underestimate
the power of music.
But my father, he will
never give his permission.
I am done
asking permission.
When you see your moment, you
mustn't let it pass you by.
You must seize it!
Senor de la Cruz,
what did it take for you
to seize your moment?
I had to have
faith in my dream.
No one was going
to hand it to me.
It was up to me
to reach for that dream.
Grab it tight
and make it come true.
...and make it come true.
No more hiding, Dante.
I got to seize my moment!
I'm gonna play in Mariachi
Plaza if it kills me.
Dia de los Muertos has begun!
No, no. We have to make
a clear path.
The petals guide
our ancestors home.
We don't want
their spirits to get lost.
We want them to come
and enjoy all the food
and drinks on the ofrenda.
Mama!
Where should we
put this table?
In the courtyard, mijos.
You want it
down by the kitchen?
Si. Next to the other one.
- Get under! Get under!
- Miguel?
Nothing! Mama, Papa. I...
Miguel, your abuelita had
the most wonderful idea.
We've all decided. It's time
you joined us in the workshop!
- What?
- No more shining shoes.
You'll be making them
every day after school.
Oh! Our Migueli-ti-ti-ti-to
carrying on
the family tradition.
And on Dia de los Muertos!
Your ancestors
will be so proud.
You'll craft huaraches
just like your Tia Victoria.
And wingtips
like your Papa Julio.
But what if
I'm no good at making shoes?
Ah, Miguel. You have your
family here to guide you.
You are a Rivera.
And a Rivera is...
A shoemaker.
Through and through.
That's my boy!
Berto!
Break out the good stuff.
I want to make a toast.
Dante! No, Dante. Stop!
No, no, no, no, no! No.
De la Cruz's guitar?
Papa? Papa?
Mama Coco, is your papa
Ernesto de la Cruz?
Papa! Papa!
Papa! Papa! It's him!
I know who my
great-great-grandfather was.
Miguel, get down
from there.
Mama Coco's father
was Ernesto de la Cruz!
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna be a musician!
What is all this?
You keep secrets
from your own family?
It's all that time
he spends in the plaza.
Fills his head
with crazy fantasies.
It's not a fantasy.
That man was
Ernesto de la Cruz!
The greatest musician
of all time!
We've never known anything
about this man!
But whoever he was, he still
abandoned his family.
This is no future
for my son.
But, Papa, you said
my family would guide me.
Well, de la Cruz
is my family.
I'm supposed to play music.
Never! That man's music
was a curse.
I will not allow it.
- If you would just let...
- Miguel...
You will listen
to your family.
No more music.
- Just listen to me play!
- End of argument.
You want to end up
like that man? Forgotten?
Left off
your family's ofrenda?
I don't care if I'm on
some stupid ofrenda.
- No!
- Mama!
There. No guitar.
No music.
Oh, come. You'll feel better
after you eat with your family.
I don't want
to be in this family!
Miguel! Miguel!
I want to play in the plaza,
like de la Cruz.
Can I still sign up?
You got an instrument?
No. But if I
can borrow a guitar...
Musicians got to bring
their own instruments.
You find a guitar, kid,
I'll put you on the list.
- Can I borrow your guitar?
- Sorry, muchacho.
- You guys have a spare guitar?
- No.
I need a guitar
just for a little bit.
Get out of here, kid.
Great-great-grandfather,
what am I supposed to do?
No, no, no, no.
Dante, stop! Callate! Shh!
I'm sorry.
Senor de la Cruz,
please don't be mad.
I'm Miguel.
Your great-great grandson.
I need to borrow this.
Our family thinks
music is a curse.
None of them understand
but I know you would have.
You would have told me
to follow my heart.
To seize my moment!
So, if it's
all right with you,
I'm gonna play in the plaza.
Just like you did!
The guitar! It's gone!
Somebody stole
de la Cruz's guitar!
The window's broken.
Look!
All right, who's in there?
I'm sorry.
It's not what it looks like.
De la Cruz is my...
There's nobody here.
- Miguel!
- Mama!
Miguel, come home.
Where are you, Miguel?
Dios mio!
Little boy. Are you okay?
Here. Let me help you.
Thanks. I...
Do you mind? Whoa!
Look how big she's getting.
Dante!
You can see me? Wait!
What's going on? Dante!
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Miguel?
You're here? Here, here.
And you can see us?
Our Migueli-ti-ti-ti-to!
Remind me how I know you.
We're your family, mijo.
- Tia Rosita?
- Si.
- Papa Julio?
- Hola.
Tia Victoria?
He doesn't
seem entirely dead.
He's not quite alive either.
We need Mama Imelda.
She'll know how to fix this.
Oye! It's Mama Imelda.
She couldn't cross over.
- She's stuck!
- On the other side!
Tio Oscar? Tio Felipe?
Oh. Hey, Miguel.
I have a feeling this has
something to do with you.
But if Mama Imelda
can't come to us...
Then we are going to her.
Vamonos!
Whoa.
Come on, Miguel.
It's okay.
Dante? Dante!
Dante, wait up!
You got to stay with me, boy.
We don't know... where...
This isn't a dream then.
You're all really out there.
- You thought we weren't?
- Well, I don't know.
I thought it might've been
one of those
made up things
that adults tell kids.
Like vitamins.
Miguel,
vitamins are a real thing.
Well, now I'm thinking
maybe they could be.
Mija, it's not nice to stare at...
Ay! Santa Maria!
Are those...
Alebrijes! But those are...
Real alebrijes.
Spirit creatures.
They guide souls
on their journey.
Watch your step. They
make caquitas everywhere.
Welcome back
to the Land of the Dead.
Please have all offerings
ready for re-entry.
Welcome back.
Anything to declare?
Some churros.
From my family.
How wonderful. Next.
If you are
experiencing travel issues,
agents at
the Department of Family...
Reunions are
available to assist you.
Next family, please.
Oh! Your photos
are on your son's ofrenda.
Have a great visit.
Gracias.
And remember
to return before sunrise.
Enjoy your visit.
Next.
Your photo's on your dentist's ofrenda.
Enjoy your visit.
- Gracias.
- Next?
Yes! It is I.
Frida Kahlo.
Shall we skip
the scanner?
I'm on so many ofrendas it'll just
overwhelm your blinky thingy.
Well, shoot, looks like no one
put up your photo, Frida.
Okay, when I said I was Frida,
just now, that was a lie.
And I apologize
for doing that.
No photo on an ofrenda,
no crossing the bridge.
I'm just gonna zip right over.
You won't even know I'm gone.
Hey!
Almost... there.
Just a little further.
Upsy-daisy...
Fine. Okay. Fine, who cares?
Dumb flower bridge!
Aw. I don't know what I'd do
if no one put up my photo.
- Next?
- Oh! Come, mijo. It's our turn.
Welcome back, amigos.
Anything to declare?
As a matter of fact, yes.
Hola.
Paging Marta Gonzales-Ramos.
Please report to Level Seven.
Whoa!
I miss my nose.
Come on, help us out, amigo.
We got to get to
a dozen ofrendas tonight.
We are not visiting your ex-wife's
family for Dia de Muertos!
I demand to speak
to the person in charge!
I'm sorry, senora, it says
here no one put up your photo.
My family always puts my
photo on the ofrenda.
That devil box tells
you nothing but lies!
- Mama Imelda?
- Oh, mi familia!
They wouldn't let me
cross the bridge.
Tell this woman
and her devil box
that my photo
is on the ofrenda.
Well, we never
made it to the ofrenda.
- What?
- We ran into...
- Miguel?
- Mama Imelda.
What is going on?
You the Rivera family?
Well, you're cursed.
What?
Dia de los Muertos is the
night to give to the dead.
You stole from the dead!
But I wasn't
stealing the guitar.
Guitar?
It was my
great-great-grandfather's.
He would have
wanted me to have it.
Ah, ah, ah. We do not speak
of that musician.
He is dead to this family.
Uh,
you're all dead.
I am sorry.
Whose alebrije is that?
That's just Dante.
He sure doesn't
look like an alebrije.
He just looks
like a plain old dog.
Or a sausage someone dropped
in a barbershop.
Whatever he is, I am
terribly allergic.
But Dante
doesn't have any hair.
And I don't have a nose,
and yet, here we are.
But none of this explains
why I couldn't cross over.
Oh!
You took my photo
off the ofrenda?
- It was an accident!
- How do we send him back?
Well,
since it's a family matter...
the way to undo
a family curse
- is to get your family's blessing.
- That's it?
Get your family's blessing
and everything should
go back to normal.
But you got
to do it by sunrise.
What happens at sunrise?
Hijole! Your hand!
Whoa, Miguel, can't have
you fainting on us.
But not to worry.
Your family's here.
You can get
your blessing right now.
Cempasuchil, cempasuchil.
Aha! Perdon, senora.
Oh.
Now, you look at the living
and say his name.
Miguel.
Nailed it. Now say,
"I give you my blessing."
I give you my blessing.
I give you my blessing
to go home...
to put my photo
back on the ofrenda,
and to never
play music again.
What? She can't do that!
Well, technically, she can
add any condition she wants.
Fine.
Then you hand
the petal to Miguel.
No skeletons!
Mariachi Plaza,
here I come.
Two seconds and you already
break your promise.
This isn't fair. It's my life.
You already had yours.
Papa Julio,
I ask for your blessing.
Tia Rosita? Oscar?
Felipe? Tia Victoria?
Don't make this hard, mijo.
You go home my way or no way.
You really hate
music that much?
I will not let you go down
the same path he did.
The same path he did.
He's family.
Listen to your Mama Imelda.
She's just
looking out for you.
Be reasonable.
Con permiso,
I need to visit the restroom.
Be right back.
Uh, should we tell him
there are no restrooms
in the Land of the Dead?
Vamonos.
We got a family
looking for a living boy.
If I want to be a musician,
I need a musician's blessing.
We got to find
my great-great-grandpa.
Hold it, muchacho.
I found that living boy!
Oh, whoa, excuse me.
Excuse me, folks.
Excuse me.
Oh.
No, no. Dante!
Disturbing the peace.
Fleeing an officer.
Falsifying a unibrow.
- That's illegal?
- Very illegal.
You need to clean up
your act, amigo.
Amigo? Oh, that's so nice
to hear you say that
because I have just had a...
really hard Dia de Muertos
and I could really use
an amigo right now.
And amigos,
they help their amigos.
You get me across
that bridge tonight,
and I'll make it
worth your while.
Oh! You like de la Cruz?
He and I go way back.
I can get you front row seats to
his Sunrise Spectacular show.
I'll get you backstage.
You can meet him.
You just got to let me
cross that bridge!
I should lock you up
for the rest of the holiday.
But my shift's almost up and I
want to visit my living family.
So I'm letting you off
with a warning.
Can I at least
get my costume back?
Uh... No.
Some amigo.
Hey! Hey!
You really know de la Cruz?
Who wants to... Ahh!
Ay! You're alive!
Shh! Yeah, I'm alive.
And if I want to get back
to the Land of the Living...
I need de la Cruz's blessing.
That's weirdly specific.
He's my
great-great-grandfather.
He's your Gr... What?
Ugh.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait.
Wait. No, wait, wait, wait.
Wait! Yes! You're going back
to the Land of the Living!
You know what? Maybe this
isn't such a good...
No, no, nino! Nino, nino, I can help you.
You can help me.
We can help each other.
But most importantly,
you can help me.
- Miguel!
- I'm Hector.
That's nice.
Esperame, chamaco!
Ay, he is going
to get himself killed.
I need my spirit guide...
Pepita.
Who has that petal
Miguel touched?
Here. Nice alebrije.
Ay, ay, hold still. Look up. A ver, a ver.
Look up, up, up.
Aqui arriba, eso...
Eh, la rayita.
Okay. Hey! Ta-da!
Dead as a doorknob.
So listen, Miguel,
this place runs on memories.
When you're well remembered,
people put up your photo
and you get to...
cross the bridge
and visit the living
on Dia de Muertos.
Unless you're me.
You don't get
to cross over?
No one's ever
put up my picture.
But you can change that!
This is you?
Eh, muy guapo, eh?
So, you get me
to my great-great-grandpa...
then I put up your photo
when I get home?
Such a smart boy! Yes!
Great idea, yes! One hiccup.
De la Cruz is
a tough guy to get to
and I need to
cross the bridge soon.
Like, tonight.
So, you got any other
family here, you know?
Someone a bit more,
eh, accessible?
Mmm... Nope.
Don't yank my chain,
chamaco.
You got to have
some other family.
Only de la Cruz.
If you can't help me,
I'll find him myself.
Oh! Okay. Okay, kid.
Fine! Fine!
I'll get you to your
great-great-grandpa.
It's not gonna
be easy, you know?
He's a busy man.
What are you doing?
I'm walking like a skeleton.
Blending in.
No. Skeletons
don't walk like that.
- It's how you walk.
- No, I don't! Stop it!
Whoa! Ernesto de la Cruz's
Sunrise Spectacular?
Que padre!
Every year your great-great-grandpa
puts on that dumb show...
to mark the end
of Dia de Muertos.
- And you can get us in!
- Um...
Hey, you said you have
front row tickets!
That... was a lie.
I apologize for that.
Cool off, chamaco.
Come on. I'll get you to him.
How?
Because I happen to know
where he's rehearsing.
♪ Remember me
Don't let it make you cry ♪
You better have
my dress, Hector.
Hola, Ceci.
- Hola.
- Ceci, I lost the dress.
Ya lo sabia!
I got to dress
forty dancers by sunrise.
Thanks to you, I'm one Frida
short of an opening number!
Dante!
We shouldn't be in here.
No, no, Dante! Ven aca!
You! How did you
get in here?
- I just followed my...
- Oh! The mighty Xolo dog!
Guider of wandering spirits.
And whose spirit
have you guided to me?
I don't think
he's a spirit guide.
Ah, ah, ah.
The alebrijes of this world
can take many forms.
They are as mysterious
as they are powerful.
Or maybe he's just a dog.
Come, I need your eyes.
You are the audience.
Darkness.
And from the darkness,
a giant papaya.
Dancers emerge
from the papaya,
and the dancers are all me.
And they go to drink from
the milk of their mother,
who is a cactus.
But who is also me.
And her milk is
not milk but tears.
Is it too obvious?
I think it's just
the right amount of obvious?
It could use some music.
Oh, what if you did like...
Oh! And then it could go...
And what if
everything was on fire?
Yes! Fire! Everywhere!
Inspired! You have
the spirit of an artist.
The dancers exit. The music
fades, the lights go out.
And Ernesto de la Cruz
rises to the stage!
Huh?
He does a couple of songs, the
sun rises, everyone cheers...
Excuse me,
where's the real de la Cruz?
Ernesto doesn't do
rehearsals!
He's too busy hosting that fancy
party at the top of his tower.
Chamaco, you can't run off
on me like that.
Stop pestering
the celebrities.
You said my great-great-grandpa
would be here!
He's halfway across town
throwing some big party.
That bum. Who doesn't show up
to his own rehearsal?
If you're such good friends,
how come he didn't invite you?
He's your great-great-grandpa,
Hey, Gustavo! You know
anything about this party?
It's the hot ticket!
But if you're not
on the guest list,
you're never
getting in, Chorizo.
Hey! It's Chorizo! Choricito!
A-ha. Very funny, guys.
Very funny.
Chorizo?
Oh, this guy's famous!
Go on, go on.
Ask him how he died.
I don't want
to talk about it.
He choked on some chorizo!
I didn't choke, okay?
I got food poisoning
which is a big difference.
This is why
I don't like musicians.
Bunch of
self-important jerks.
- Hey! I'm a musician!
- You are?
If you really want
to get to Ernesto,
there is that
music competition...
at the Plaza de la Cruz.
Winner gets
to play at his party.
No, no. Chamaco,
you're loco if you think...
I need to get my
great-great-grandfather's blessing!
You know where
I can get a guitar?
I know a guy.
Have you found him, Pepita?
Have you found our boy?
- A footprint!
- It's a Rivera boot.
- Size seven!
- And a half.
- Pronated.
- Miguel.
Why the heck would
you want to be a musician?
My great-great-grandpa
was a musician!
Who spent his life
performing like a monkey
for complete strangers.
No thank you.
No! Guacala!
What do you know?
So, how far is
this guitar anyway?
We're almost there.
Keep up, chamaco. Come on.
- Cousin Hector!
- Hey! These guys! Hey, Tio!
¿Que onda?
These people are
all your family?
Uh...
In a way. We're all the ones
with no photos or ofrendas.
No family to go home to.
Nearly forgotten, you know?
So, we all call each other
cousin, or tio, or whatever.
- Hector!
- Tia Chelo!
Muchas gracias!
Hey! Save some for me!
Is Chicharron around?
Eh, in the bungalow.
I don't know if he's in
the mood for visitors.
Who doesn't like
a visit from Cousin Hector?
Buenas noches, Chicharron!
I don't want to see
your stupid face, Hector.
Come on.
It's Dia de Muertos.
I brought you
a little offering.
- Get out of here.
- I would, Cheech.
But the thing is,
me and my friend, Miguel...
We really need
to borrow your guitar.
- My guitar?
- Yes.
My prized beloved guitar?
I promise
we'll bring it right back.
Like the time you promised
to bring back my van?
- Uh...
- Or my mini-fridge?
- Ah, you see...
- Or my good napkins?
My lasso? My femur?
Well, no,
not like those times.
Where is my femur?
You...
Whoa, whoa.
- You okay, amigo?
- I'm fading, Hector.
I can feel it.
I couldn't even play
that thing if I wanted to.
You play me something.
No. You know
I don't play anymore, Cheech.
The guitar is for the kid.
You want it,
you got to earn it.
Ay, only for you, amigo.
Any requests?
You know my favorite, Hector.
♪ Well,
everyone knows Juanita
♪ Her eyes
each a different color
♪ Her teeth stick out
And her chin goes in
♪ And her...
♪ Knuckles they
drag on the floor
- Those aren't the words.
- There are children present.
♪ Her hair is like a briar
♪ She stands in
a bow-legged stance
♪ And if I weren't so ugly
♪ She'd possibly
give me a chance ♪
Brings back memories.
Gracias.
Wait. What happened?
He's been forgotten.
When there's no one left
in the living world
who remembers you...
you disappear
from this world.
We call it
the final death.
Where did he go?
No one knows.
But I've met him. I could
remember him when I go back!
No, it doesn't work
like that, chamaco.
Our memories,
they have to be passed down
by those
who knew us in life...
in the stories
they tell about us.
But there's no one left alive
to pass down Cheech's stories.
Hey, it happens
to everyone eventually.
Come on, de la Cruzcito,
you've got a contest to win.
You told me
you hated musicians.
You never said you were one.
How do you think I
knew your great-great-grandpa?
We used to play
music together.
Taught him
everything he knows.
No manches! You played
with Ernesto de la Cruz...
the greatest musician
of all time?
Ah, you're funny.
Greatest eyebrows
of all time maybe.
But his music?
Eh, not so much.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Welcome
to the Plaza de la Cruz!
Showtime, chamaco!
Llevelo!
T-shirts! Bobbleheads!
Bienvenidos a todos!
Oh!
Who's ready for some musica?
It's a battle
of the bands, amigos.
The winner gets to play
for the maestro himself,
Ernesto de la Cruz...
at his fiesta tonight!
That's our ticket, muchacho.
Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
Let the competition begin!
So, what's the plan?
What are you gonna play?
Definitely Remember Me.
No! Not that one. No.
Come on.
It's his most popular song!
Ah, it's too popular.
♪ Remember me
Though I have to travel far ♪
♪ Remember me... ♪
♪ Don't let it
make you cry... ♪
- What about Poco Loco?
- Epa! Now that's a song!
De la Cruzcito?
You're on standby.
Los Chachalacos,
you're up next.
Los Chachalacos!
You always this nervous
before a performance?
I don't know.
I've never performed before.
What? You said
you were a musician!
I am!
I mean, I will be.
- Ay!
- Once I win.
That's your plan?
No. You have to win.
Your life
literally depends on...
you winning. And you've
never done this before!
I'll go up there.
- No! I need to do this.
- Why?
If I can't go out
and play one song,
how can I call
myself a musician?
What does that matter?
Because I don't just want to
get de la Cruz's blessing...
I need to prove
that I'm worthy of it.
Oh, that's such
a sweet sentiment
at such a bad time!
Okay! Okay.
You want to perform?
Then you got to perform!
First, you have to loosen up.
Shake off those nerves.
Now give me
your best grito.
- My best grito?
- Come on, yell! Belt it out.
Ah, it feels good.
Okay, now you.
Oh, come on, kid.
De la Cruzcito,
you're on now!
Miguel, look at me.
Hey, look at me.
You can do this.
Grab their attention
and don't let it go.
Make them listen, chamaco.
You've got this.
De la Cruzcito
What's he doing?
Why isn't he playing?
Bring back
the singing dogs!
Que bien!
Vamonos! Whoo!
♪ What color is the sky?
Ay mi amor, ay mi amor
♪ You tell me that it's red
♪ Where should I put my shoes?
Ay mi amor, ay mi amor
♪ You say
put them on your head
♪ Ay mi amor, ay mi amor
♪ You make me un poco loco
Un poqui-ti-ti-to loco
♪ The way you keep me guessing
I'm nodding and I'm yes-ing
♪ I'll count
it as a blessing
♪ That I'm only
un poco loco
No! No! No!
Not bad for a dead guy!
Not so bad yourself,
gordito! Eso!
He's close! Find him!
♪ The loco that you make me
It is just un poco crazy
♪ The sense
that you're not making
♪ The liberties you're taking
♪ Leaves my cabeza shaking
You're just un poco loco
We're looking
for a living kid.
About twelve?
Have you seen a living boy?
♪ Un poqui-ti-ti-ti-ti-ti-ti-
ti-ti-ti-to loco ♪
Hey! You did good!
I'm proud of you. Eso!
Otra! Otra! Otra!
- Hey! Where are you going?
- We got to get out of here!
What? Are you crazy? We're
about to win this thing.
Damas y caballeros,
I have an emergency
announcement.
Please be on the lookout
for a living boy.
Answers to the name
of Miguel.
Earlier tonight
he ran away from his family.
They just want to send him back
to the Land of the Living.
Wait, wait.
You said de la Cruz
was your only family.
The only person
who could send you home.
I do have other family,
but...
You could have taken my
photo back this whole time?
But they hate music!
I need a musician's blessing.
- You lied to me!
- Oh, you're one to talk.
Look at me.
I'm being forgotten, Miguel.
I don't even know
if I'm gonna last the night.
I'm not gonna
miss my one chance
to cross that
bridge because...
you want to live out
some stupid musical fantasy.
It's not stupid!
I'm taking you
to your family.
- Let go of me!
- You'll thank me later.
You don't want to help me.
You only care about yourself!
Keep your dumb photo.
Stay away from me!
No!
Hey, chamaco!
Where did you go?
Chamaco! I'm sorry!
Come back!
Dante, callate! No!
Dante, stop it.
He can't help me.
Dante! Stop!
Stop it! Leave me alone!
You're not a spirit guide.
You're just a dumb dog!
Now get out of here!
- It's him!
- It's that living boy!
- I heard about him. Look!
- He's alive!
- He's alive.
- The boy is alive!
This nonsense
ends now, Miguel!
I am giving you my blessing
and you are going home.
I don't want your blessing!
Miguel, stop!
Come back! Miguel!
I am trying
to save your life!
- You're ruining my life!
- What?
Music's the only thing
that makes me happy.
And you want to
take it away.
You'll never understand.
♪ Y aunque la vida
me cueste, Llorona
♪ No dejare de quererte... ♪
I thought you hated music.
Oh, I loved it!
I remember that feeling...
when my husband would play,
and I would sing
and nothing else mattered.
But when we had Coco,
suddenly there was something
in my life that...
mattered more than music.
I wanted to put down roots.
He wanted
to play for the world.
We each made a sacrifice
to get what we wanted.
Now you must make a choice.
But I don't
want to pick sides!
Why can't you be
on my side?
That's what
family's supposed to do.
Support you.
But you never will.
- Have a good time.
- Oh, how exciting!
Oh, El Santo. I'm a big fan!
You mind if I...
Gracias, Senor.
- Invitation?
- It's okay.
I'm Ernesto's
great-great-grandson.
- Disculpen, senores...
- Hey, guys! It's poco loco!
- You were on fire tonight!
- You too!
Hey, musician to musician...
I need a favor.
Oh, the competition winners.
Congratulations, chicos.
Thanks, guys!
Whoa!
Hey! Enjoy the party,
little musico!
Gracias!
Oh!
Look! It's Ernesto!
De la Cruz!
Senor de la Cruz!
Pardon me! Senor de la Cruz!
Senor de la...
When you see
your moment,
you mustn't let it
pass you by.
You must seize it.
This one has a wise spirit.
♪ ♪
We're almost there, Dante.
Senor de la Cruz!
Senor de la...
But what can we do?
It is hopeless...
You must have faith, sister.
But Padre,
he will never listen.
He will listen... to music.
♪ Senoras y senores,
buenas tardes, buenas noches
♪ Buenas tardes, buenas
noches Senoritas y senores
♪ To be here with you tonight
Brings me joy! Que alegria
♪ For this music
is my language
♪ And the world
es mi familia
♪ For this music
is my language
♪ And the world
es mi familia
♪ For this music
is my language
♪ And the world
es mi familia
♪ For this music
is my lang... ♪
Are you all right, nino?
It's you!
You are that boy!
The one who came
from the Land of the Living.
You... know about me?
You are all anyone
has been talking about.
Why have you come here?
I'm Miguel.
Your great-great-grandson.
I... have
a great-great-grandson?
I need your blessing
so I can go back home
and be a musician.
Just like you.
The rest of our family,
they wouldn't listen.
But I hoped you would.
My boy, with a talent like
yours, how could I not listen?
Aww!
I have a great-great-grandson!
- Look! It's Frida!
- Yes, it is I. Frida Kahlo.
- It is an honor, Senora.
- Gracias.
Hey, Negrete! Infante!
Have you met
my great-great-grandson?
My great-great-grandson.
He's alive!
And a musician to boot!
Dimple. No dimple.
No dimple!
To our friendship.
I would move Heaven and
Earth for you, mi amigo. Salud!
Poison!
You know,
I did all my own stunts.
♪ Though I have to say
goodbye Remember me... ♪
All of this
came from my amazing fans
in the Land of the Living.
They leave me more offerings
than I know what to do with!
Hey, what's wrong? Is it too much?
You look overwhelmed.
- No! It's all great!
- But?
It's just...
I have been looking up to you
my whole life.
You're the guy
who actually did it!
But did you ever regret it?
Choosing music
over everything else?
It was hard.
Saying goodbye to my hometown.
Heading off on my own...
Leaving your family?
Si. But I could not have
done it differently.
One cannot deny
who one is meant to be.
And you, my great-great-grandson,
are meant to be a musician!
You and I,
we are artists, Miguel.
We cannot
belong to one family.
The world is our family.
Ooh! Ooh!
The fireworks have begun!
Soon the party will move across
town for my Sunrise Spectacular.
Miguel,
you must come to the show!
You will be
my guest of honor!
- You mean it?
- Of course, my boy.
I can't.
I have to get home
before sunrise.
Oh! I really do
need to get you home.
It has been an honor.
I am sorry
to see you go, Miguel.
I hope you die very soon.
You know what I mean.
Miguel, I give you my bless...
We had a deal, chamaco.
Who are you?
What is the meaning of this?
Oh, Frida! I thought
you couldn't make it.
You said
you'd take back my photo.
You promised, Miguel.
You know this, uh, man?
Uh, I just met him tonight.
He told me he knew you.
Hector?
Please, Miguel.
Put my photo up.
My friend,
you're being forgotten.
- And whose fault is that?
- Hector, please...
Those were my songs you took.
My songs that made you famous.
What?
If I'm being forgotten,
it's because you never
told anyone
that I wrote them!
That's crazy! De la Cruz
wrote all his own songs.
You want to tell him
or should I?
Hector, I never meant
to take credit.
We made a great team,
but you died...
and I only sang your songs
because I wanted to keep
a part of you alive.
Oh, how generous!
You really did
play together.
I don't want
to fight about it.
I just want you
to make it right.
Miguel can put my photo up, and
I can cross over the bridge.
I can see my girl.
Ernesto,
remember the night I left?
That was a long time ago.
We drank together
and you told me
you would move
Heaven and Earth...
for your amigo.
Well, I'm asking you to now.
Heaven and Earth?
Like in the movie?
- What?
- That's Don Hidalgo's toast.
In the de la Cruz movie,
El Camino a Casa.
I'm talking about
my real life, Miguel.
No! It's in there. Look!
Never were
truer words spoken.
This calls for a toast.
To our friendship!
I would move Heaven and Earth
for you, mi amigo.
But in the movie, Don
Hidalgo poisons the drink.
- Salud!
- Poison!
That night, Ernesto.
The night I left...
We'd been performing
on the road for months.
I got homesick...
and I packed up my songs.
You want to give up now
when we're this close
to reaching our dream?
This was your dream.
You'll manage.
I can't do this
without your songs, Hector.
I'm going home, Ernesto.
Hate me if you want,
but my mind is made up.
Oh, I could never hate you.
If you must go,
then I'm sending you off
with a toast.
To our friendship.
I would move Heaven and Earth
for you, mi amigo. Salud!
You walked me
to the train station.
But I felt
a pain in my stomach.
I thought it must have been
something I ate.
Perhaps it was
that chorizo, my friend.
Or something I drank.
I woke up dead.
You poisoned me.
You're confusing movies
with reality, Hector.
All this time, I thought
it was just bad luck.
I never thought that
you might have... That you...
- How could you?
- Hector!
Security! Security!
You took everything
away from me! You rat!
Have him taken care of.
He's not well.
I just wanted to go back home.
No! No!
I apologize.
Where were we?
You were going to give me
your blessing.
Yes. Uh, si.
Miguel, uh,
my reputation...
It is
very important to me.
I would hate
to have you think...
That you murdered Hector
for his songs?
You don't think that.
Do you?
I... No. Everyone
knows you're the good guy.
Papa Ernesto, my blessing?
Security? Take care of Miguel.
He'll be extending his stay.
What? But I'm your family!
And Hector
was my best friend.
Success doesn't
come for free, Miguel.
You have to be willing to do
whatever it takes
to seize your moment.
I know you understand.
No! No!
Let go! No!
Help!
Can anyone hear me?
I want to go home.
- Hector?
- Kid?
Oh, Hector!
You were right.
I should have gone
back to my family.
They told me not
to be like de la Cruz,
but I didn't listen.
I told them I didn't care
if they remembered me.
I didn't care if I was
on their stupid ofrenda.
Hey, chamaco.
It's okay. It's okay.
I told them I didn't care.
Hector! Hector?
She's forgetting me.
- Who?
- My daughter.
She's the reason you wanted
to cross the bridge.
I just wanted
to see her again.
I never should have
left Santa Cecilia.
I wish I could apologize.
I wish I could tell her that her
papa was trying to come home.
That he loved her so much.
My Coco...
Coco?
Where did you get this?
That's my Mama Coco.
That's my Mama Imelda.
Is that you?
- We're...
- Family?
I always hoped
I'd see her again.
That she'd miss me.
Maybe put up my photo.
But it never happened.
You know the worst part?
Even if I never got to see
Coco in the living world...
I thought at least
one day I'd see her here.
Give her the biggest hug.
But she's the last person
who remembers me.
The moment she's gone
from the living world...
You disappear...
from this one.
You'll never get to see her.
Ever again.
You know,
I wrote her a song once.
We used to sing it every
night at the same time.
No matter
how far apart we were.
What I wouldn't give
to sing it to her
one... last... time.
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have to say
goodbye Remember me
♪ Don't let it make you cry
♪ For even if I'm far away
I hold you in my heart
♪ I sing a secret song to
you Each night we are apart
♪ Remember me
Papa!
♪ Though I have to
travel far Remember me
♪ Each time
you hear a sad guitar
♪ Know that I'm with you
The only way that I can be
♪ Until you're in
my arms again
♪ Remember me ♪
He stole your guitar.
He stole your songs.
You should be the one the world
remembers, not de la Cruz!
I didn't write Remember Me
for the world.
I wrote it for Coco.
I'm a pretty sorry excuse
for a great-great-grandpa.
Are you kidding? A minute ago I
thought I was related to a murderer.
You're a total upgrade.
My whole life,
there's been something...
that made me different.
And I never knew
where it came from.
But now I know.
It comes from you.
I'm proud we're family!
I'm proud to be his family!
I'm proud to be
his family!
Dante?
Dante!
It's Dante!
- Imelda!
- Hector.
You look good.
Dante! You knew he was my
Papa Hector the whole time!
You are a real spirit guide.
Who's the good spirit guide?
You are!
Whoa!
Dante!
There they are!
Miguel! Miguelito! Look, it's Miguel!
He's all right.
Gracias, Dios mio.
Que bueno.
Mijo, I was so worried!
Thank goodness
we found you in time.
And you... How many times
must I turn you away?
Imelda.
I want nothing to do with you!
Not in life, not in death!
I spent decades protecting
my family from your mistakes.
He spends
five minutes with you
and I have to fish him
out of a sinkhole!
I wasn't in there
because of Hector.
He was in there
because of me.
He was just
trying to get me home!
I didn't want to listen,
but he was right.
Nothing's more
important than family.
I'm ready
to accept your blessing.
And your conditions.
But first,
I need to find de la Cruz.
To get Hector's photo.
- What?
- So he can see Coco again.
Hector should be
on our ofrenda.
He's part of our family.
He left this family!
He tried to go home
to you and Coco.
But de la Cruz
murdered him!
It's true, Imelda.
And so what if it's true?
You leave me alone
with a child to raise...
and I'm just
supposed to forgive you?
Imelda, I...
Hector!
I'm running out of time.
It's Coco.
She's forgetting you.
You don't have
to forgive him.
But we shouldn't
forget him.
I wanted to forget you.
I wanted Coco
to forget you too, but...
This is my fault.
Not yours.
I'm sorry, Imelda.
Miguel, if we help you
get his photo,
you will return home?
No more music?
Family comes first.
I can't forgive you.
But I will help you.
So, how do we get
to de la Cruz?
I might know a way.
- Good luck, muchacho.
- Gracias, Frida.
- Here, let me help you with...
- Don't touch me!
- Everyone clear on the plan?
- Find Hector's photo.
- Give it to Miguel.
- Send Miguel home.
Got your petals?
Now, we just
have to find de la Cruz.
Yes?
Don't I know you?
That's for murdering
the love of my life!
- Who... Who the...
- She's talking about me!
I'm the love of your life?
I don't know.
I'm still angry at you.
Hector!
How did you...
And that's for trying
to murder my grandson.
- Grandson?
- She's talking about me!
You! Wait.
You're related to Hector?
The photo!
Uh...
After him!
Security! Ayudenme!
- You said love of your life.
- I don't know what I said.
That's what I heard.
Places, Senor.
You're on in thirty seconds.
Ay! Miguel! I have it!
Oh!
Hurry! Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen...
the one... the only...
Ernesto de la Cruz!
Get her off the stage.
Sing! Sing!
♪ Ay, de mi Llorona
♪ Llorona de azul celeste
♪ Y aunque la vida
me cueste, Llorona
♪ No dejare de quererte
♪ Me subi al pino mas alto,
Llorona
♪ A ver si te divisaba
♪ Como el pino era tierno,
Llorona
♪ Al verme llorar, lloraba
♪ Ay de mi Llorona, Llorona
Llorona de azul celeste
♪ Y aunque la vida
me cueste, Llorona
♪ No dejare de quererte
Let go of me!
♪ Y aunque la vida
me cueste, Llorona
♪ No dejare de quererte
♪ Ay, ay, ay ♪
I forgot
what that felt like.
You still got it.
Oh.
Miguel,
I give you my blessing.
To go home,
to put up our photos
and to never...
Never play music again.
To never forget how much
your family loves you.
You're going home.
You're not going anywhere.
Imelda!
Stay back!
All of you, stay back.
Not one more step.
Dante!
Ernesto, stop!
Leave the boy alone.
I've worked too hard, Hector.
Too hard to let him
destroy everything.
He's a living child, Ernesto.
He's a threat!
You think
I'd let him go back
to the Land of the Living
with your photo?
To keep
your memory alive? No.
- You're a coward!
- I am Ernesto de la Cruz.
The greatest musician
of all time!
Hector's the real musician.
You're just the guy
who murdered him
and stole his songs!
Murdered?
I am the one
who's willing to do
what it takes
to seize my moment.
Whatever it takes.
No!
Miguel!
Apologies, old friend.
But the show must go on.
Please,
please, mi familia.
Murderer!
Orchestra.
A-one, a-two, a-one...
♪ Remember me
Though I have to s... ♪
Hey!
Look!
Nice kitty.
Put me down! No, please! I beg of you!
Stop! Stop! No!
No! No!
What did I miss?
Good boy, Dante!
Miguel!
Hector!
The photo... I lost it!
It's okay, mijo.
It's o...
Hector! Hector?
Coco.
No! We can still
find the photo.
Miguel, it's almost sunrise.
No, no. I can't leave you.
I promised
I'd put your photo up.
I promised you'd see Coco.
We're both
out of time, mijo.
Oh no! No!
She can't forget you!
I just wanted her to know
that I loved her.
Hector!
You have our blessing,
Miguel.
No conditions.
No! Papa Hector, please!
No!
Go home.
I promise I won't let Coco forget you!
There he is!
Miguel! Stop!
Where have you been?
I need to see
Mama Coco, please.
What are you doing with that...
Give it to me!
Miguel, stop!
Miguel! Miguel!
Mama Coco? Can you hear me?
It's Miguel.
I saw your papa.
Remember? Papa?
Please! If you forget him,
he'll be gone. Forever.
Miguel,
open this door!
Here. This was
his guitar, right?
He used to play it to you?
See? There he is! Papa!
Remember? Papa?
Miguel!
Mama Coco, please!
Don't forget him.
What are you doing
to that poor woman?
It's okay, Mamita.
It's okay.
What's gotten into you?
I thought
I'd lost you, Miguel.
I'm sorry, Papa.
We're all together now.
That's what matters.
Not all of us.
It's okay, Mamita.
Miguel, you apologize
to your Mama Coco.
Mama Coco?
Well? Apologize!
Your papa,
he wanted you to have this.
Mama, wait!
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have
to say goodbye
♪ Remember me
♪ Don't let it make you cry
♪ For even if I'm far away
♪ I hold you in my heart
I sing a secret song to you
♪ Each night we are apart
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have
to travel far
♪ Remember me
♪ Each time
you hear a sad guitar
♪ Know that I'm with you
The only way that I can be
♪ Until you're in
my arms again
♪ Remember me ♪
Elena? What's wrong, mija?
Nothing, Mama.
Nothing at all.
My papa used
to sing me that song.
He loved you, Mama Coco.
Your papa loved you so much.
I kept his letters.
Poems he wrote me. And...
Papa was a musician.
When I was a little girl...
he and Mama would sing
such beautiful songs.
And right over here,
one of Santa Cecilia's
greatest treasures.
The home of the esteemed
song writer, Hector Rivera.
The letters Hector wrote home
for his daughter, Coco,
contain the lyrics...
for all of your
favorite songs.
Not just Remember Me.
And that man
is your Papa Julio.
And there's Tia Rosita
and your Tia Victoria.
And those two
are Oscar and Felipe.
These aren't just old pictures,
they're our family...
and they're counting on us
to remember them.
♪ Say that I'm
crazy or call me a fool
Enjoy your visit, Hector.
♪ But last night it seemed
that I dreamed about you
- Papa!
- Coco!
♪ When I opened my mouth
what came out was a song
♪ And you know every word
and we all sang along
♪ To a melody played
on the strings of our souls
♪ And a rhythm that rattled
us down to the bone
♪ Our love for each other
will live on forever
♪ In every beat
of my proud corazon
♪ Our love for each other
will live on forever
♪ In every beat
of my proud corazon
♪ Ay mi familia
Oiga mi gente
♪ Canten a coro
Let it be known
♪ Our love for each other
will live on forever
♪ In every beat
of my proud corazon
♪ Ay mi familia
Oiga mi gente
♪ Canten a coro
Let it be known
♪ Our love for each other
will live on forever
♪ In every beat
of my proud corazon ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have to say
goodbye Remember me
♪ Don't let it make you cry
♪ For even if I'm far away
I hold you in my heart
♪ I sing a secret song to
you Each night we are apart
♪ Remember me
♪ Though I have to
travel far Remember me
♪ Each time
you hear a sad guitar
♪ Know that I'm with you
The only way that I can be
♪ Until you're in
my arms again
♪ Remember me
♪ If you close your eyes
and let the music play
♪ Keep our love alive
I'll never fade away
♪ If you close your eyes
and let the music play
♪ Keep our love alive
I'll never fade away
♪ If you close your eyes
and let the music play
♪ Keep our love alive
I'll never fade away
♪ Remember me
♪ For I will soon be gone
Remember me
♪ And let the love
we have live on
♪ And know that I'm with you
the only way that I can be
♪ So, until you're
on my arms again
♪ Remember me
♪ Remember me ♪