How did we end up here?
This place is horrible.
Smells like balls.
We don't belong
in this shithole.
Shit.
Hey, Sam.
Dad, what kind of...
Shut up!
What kind of flowers
did you want?
Alchemillas. Or something
that smells nice.
Something soothing. It all
smells like fucking kimchi!
That looks nice.
Anything but roses.
I hate this job.
Riggan,
everyone's set for 1-4.
They're ready for you.
Riggan,
they're ready for you.
Mr. Thomson.
Steve.
It's Daniel.
Okay.
Oh, hey, buddy.
How you doing?
Pretty good. Yeah, I'd be a lot
better if I could get, uh...
...Ralph to stop,
you know, acting.
He'll be fine.
And he was yelling,
"I love you,
I love you, bitch!"
What do you do
with a love like that?
That's not love
and you know it.
Why do you insist
on calling it love?
Say what you want,
but I know what it was.
What about you, Nick?
Does that sound like love?
Sorry I'm late.
Sound like love...
Look, I'm the wrong
person to ask.
I only heard the man's
name mentioned in passing.
I wouldn't know. You'd have
to know the particulars.
I think you're saying
love is absolute.
Yeah. The kind of love
I'm talking about is...
The kind of love
I'm talking about,
you don't try
and kill people.
It was love, Mel.
To Eddie, it was.
I don't care
what anyone says.
He was ready
to die for it.
Ask her what he did after
she left him.
He shot himself in the mouth,
but he screwed that up, too.
Poor Ed.
Poor Ed, my ass!
The guy was dangerous!
How did he screw up
shooting himself in the mouth?
He used to carry this .22.
We lived like fugitives then.
Ralph, Ralph, Ralph.
Fugitives are scared,
you know?
Fugitives are on the run.
Can you give me more of that?
You know, fear?
Great idea.
We lived like
fugitives then.
I never knew if he was going to
come out from behind a bush,
or a car,
and just start shooting.
The man was crazy!
He was capable of anything!
Christ,
what a nightmare.
He'd call me at
the hospital and say:
"Son of a bitch,
your clays are numbered!"
Too much?
It's a little bit too much.
I can tell, because you...
I just want to
give you a range.
Call 911!
Is he breathing?
Is blood coming
out of his ear?
Where are you going?
Did someone call 911?
Do not move him!
Wait for an ambulance!
Well, that's
a fucking lawsuit.
Where are you going?
The understudy'll be here.
Forget the understudy.
Cancel the first preview.
But it's a full house!
We'd have to refund...
Just do it.
How's Ralph?
He'll be fine.
Wait. Will you fucking wait?
Jake, it would
have been a disaster.
That guy's the worst actor
I've ever seen.
Bleeding's the most honest
thing he's done so far.
He's not that bad!
Okay, he's fucking terrible.
You have the press in your
dressing room in a few hours.
I'll make something up.
I'll think of something, riff.
Hold on.
That wasn't an accident.
What do you mean?
I made it happen.
Oh, okay.
Are you drunk?
Just find me an actor... a good actor.
Woody Harrelson!
He's doing
the next Hunger Games.
Um, Michael Fassbender.
He's doing the prequel
to the X-Men prequel.
How about, uh, Jeremy Renner?
Who?
Jeremy Renner!
He was nominated.
The Hurt Locker guy.
He's an Avenger.
Fuck! They put him in a cape, too?
I don't care.
Just find me someone.
Ralph will sue us. He will
sue us and he has a case.
Just make it go away.
Look, you're my attorney. You're my
producer. You're my best friend.
Now go out there and do
what you were born to do.
How do you suppose I do that?
How...
Next, an exclusive
interview with Robert Downey, Jr...
who's busy following up his
billion-dollar Iron Man franchise...
...with the equally successful
Avengers series.
That clown doesn't
have half your talent...
...and he's making a fortune
in that Tin Man get-up.
We were
the real thing, Riggan.
We had it all.
We gave it away.
Breathing in.
We handed these poseurs
the keys to the kingdom.
Breathing out.
You listening to me?
Breathing in,
I embrace my anger.
Yeah, embrace it.
But I'm not going away.
You know I'm right.
Look at that.
These people don't know
what you're capable of.
Why would
somebody go from playing
the lead in
a comic book franchise...
...to adapting Raymond Carver
for the stage?
As you're probably aware,
Barthes said:
"The cultural work done in the
past by gods and epic sagas...
"...is now being done by laundry
detergent commercials...
"...and comic
strip characters."
This is a big leap
you've taken.
Yeah, it is.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
Like you said...
...that, uh,
Barthes said, uh...
Birdman, like lcarus...
Okay, hang on.
Who is this Barthes guy?
Which Birdman was he in?
Uh, Roland Barthes
was a French philosopher,
and if you knew anything
about the history of...
Now is it true you've been injecting
yourself with semen from baby pigs?
I'm sorry, what? As a method
of facial rejuvenation?
Where did you read that?
It was tweeted by
@prostatewhispers.
That's not true.
I know,
but did you do it?
No, I didn't do it.
Okay, I'll write
you're denying it.
Don't write anything.
Why would you write anything?
Don't write what she said.
I didn't put any baby pig...
Are you at all afraid that
people will say you're doing this play...
...to battle the impression
you're a washed-up superhero?
No, absolutely not.
That's why...
...twenty years ago,
I said no to Birdman 4.
Birdman 4?
You do Birdman 4?!
Thank you for coming out.
Thank you.
We're expecting
some great pieces.
The guys in publicity...
...want a Times feature,
which is the worst
idea right now.
What are you doing?
I don't want to look
at this anymore.
That was a present
from the crew.
Don't fuck with them...
they're union.
I don't care.
How'd it go?
Good.
They talk about Ralph?
He did it.
The motherfucker did it.
Threatened to sue us.
What'd you say?
Me?
I said, "Motherfucker,
are you threatening me?
"If I so much as get
a letter from a lawyer...
"...the press is getting
pictures off your computer."
What pictures?
He has a thing
for nuns in diapers.
Why do you care? Point
is, I made it go away.
That's great.
Yeah, it's fantastic,
except for one thing.
We have no actor.
Uh-huh.
And if we cancel the preview,
the press will smell blood.
We can't afford to
lose any more money.
What do you think
I should do?
We hired an understudy.
Use him.
No.
Riggan, listen to me. Please,
for the love of God, listen.
Our perfect dream actor is not going
to knock on that door and go,
"Hey, fellas,
when do I start?"
Can I talk to you?
What's up?
You find another actor?
No.
Mike's available.
Mike who?
I thought he was
doing the thing...
He quit. Or got fired.
Mike who?
Which is it, quit or fired?
With Mike, it's usually both.
Mike fucking who?
Shiner.
Yes!
Jake.
How do you know
Mike Shiner?
We share a vagina.
You think he'd do it?
Mmm-hmm.
How do you know?
He told me.
Jake.
Yes.
Ask me if he sells tickets.
Does he sell tickets?
A shitload. Ask me if the
theater critics love him.
Do theater critics
love him?
They want to spooge on him.
Right on his face.
Everything for a reason.
You think he'd come in
this evening?
I'll call and find out.
I'll call his agent.
Amazing, amazing.
Annie? Clear the theater,
send everyone to dinner
and give me some lights!
We've got
a put-in tonight.
Who?
You'll find out.
Intimidating, isn't it?
You have any idea
the people who have
walked on these boards
before you?
Geraldine Page.
Helen Hayes.
Jason Robards. Marlon Brando.
And now Riggan Thomson.
Thanks for coming
in on such short notice, Mike.
This is what I do.
You wrote this adaptation?
I did, yeah.
Ah.
And you're directing and starring.
That's ambitious.
Well, thanks.
Well, it's a good theater.
I can't speak for your play, but...
let's do a little bit of it.
Oh, I didn't expect
you to just jump right in.
It's first preview tomorrow night.
Let's get to work.
Well, feel free to take the script
up until you feel comfortable.
No, let's just do some of it.
Uh...
Take a look at page 20.
I'm good. I don't need it.
I don't need the script.
Give me a cue.
What?
Feed me a line.
Okay.
Okay, uh, let me think.
I'm the wrong person to ask.
I didn't actually know him.
I only heard his name mentioned
in passing. Mmm-hmm.
You'd have to know
the particulars.
But I think what you're
saying is love is absolute.
- Is that what I'm saying?
- Am I saying love is absolute?
Yes. Okay, yeah!
The kind of love
I'm talking about is absolute.
The kind of love I'm talking about,
you don't try to kill people!
How do you know the lines?
It's a thing I have. I don't
know, it's a gift. Wow.
Come on. I've been helping
Lesley get off book for a month.
These lines are right here.
That makes sense.
That's good.
Give me my cue again.
I'm the wrong person to ask.
I didn't actually know him.
I only heard his name
mentioned in passing.
You never know the particulars.
I think what...
Can I make a suggestion?
Do you mind?
No, not at all.
No, no, forget that.
Just stay with me.
"I'm the wrong person to ask," he
says, but what's the intention?
Is he fed up
with the subject?
Deflecting guilt
over the marriage?
And here's the thing... you
have four lines after that
that all say the same thing.
"I didn't know him."
"I only heard his name
mentioned in passing."
"I wouldn't know."
"You'd have to know
the particulars."
"Particulars" sounds
like my grandmother.
The point is, you don't know the guy.
We fucking get it.
Make it work with one line.
"I didn't even know
the man." Right?
Wait... You know
my lines, too, huh?
Can we not get hung up
on knowing lines?
Can we just work on this?
Tear it apart?
So why don't you just give
me that same thing again,
but cut it down. Try it.
Uh...
I'm the wrong person to ask...
Oh, no! That's the thing...
"I'm the wrong person to ask."
I think it's, "Fuck you."
"Fuck you.
Don't put me on the spot."
"Don't make me feel
self-conscious about my marriage
"while my wife is sitting..."
Right there.
"...right there."
Can I sit down for this?
Yeah, sit. Good idea.
So just give it to me as a
"Fuck you." Lay it on me.
Just do it. Give it to me.
Well, I'm thinking. Fuck me hard.
Just give it.
Come on!
Just do it!
Hey, I'm the wrong
person to ask!
I don't even know him.
What's your point?!
What's my point?
Yeah, what are you saying?
Spit it out!
on! on!
You're saying what? You're
saying love is absolute.
Yes! Yes!
The kind of love that I'm
talking about, it is absolute!
The kind of
love that I'm talking about,
you don't...
...you don't try
to kill people.
Yeah. Good.
I don't know...
what do you think, boss?
You want to do
this with me?
What do you think?
Everybody's back. Larry needs
to see him for a fitting.
I'll take that as a yes.
So, who are you?
That's Sam, my daughter. Oh.
Wow! That's amazing. You don't
look anything like each other.
What do you do?
Um... She's my assistant.
Works with me.
And does she talk
and speak?
She does. Yeah.
She can even sit or stay or roll
over, if you have any treats.
Welcome aboard, Mike!
Thank you, Captain.
Um, I'm Mike... Shiner.
Oh, I know who you are.
I, uh, saw you in Hothouse
at the Geffen.
You were great.
Oh, thank you.
Your ass is great.
Dude. Seriously?
That was just me...
Larry? Larry?
This is the theater,
sweetheart.
Don't be so self-conscious.
He's here.
Thank the Lord
and pass the biscuits.
I finally have
an actor to dress.
How are you, Larry?
Better now you're here.
Take off your clothes.
You're just going
to stand there?
This is the theater, honey.
Don't be so self-conscious.
We have to start from scratch
with less than 24 hours.
Here. Try these...
Holy shi...!
Where are your underpants?
Under the bed
at home, I think.
Uh...
No. Okay, okay.
Everything's too small.
You're not kidding.
Oh.
Whoa. That's nice.
Forgive him, Larry. Mike's
like my 5-year-old son.
Neither of them
has clean underwear.
Or pubic hair, I imagine.
I can alter the suit,
but we're going to have to
make new trousers and shirts.
And underwear.
What are you doing?
Waiting on Larry.
I'm finished!
Then I'm just standing here
with my cock out.
Well, get dressed.
Riggan's daughter
is hanging around...
she might walk in here.
You haven't seen her.
She's always around,
watching everyone,
like Little Miss Creepy.
I don't know if drugs
fried her brain or what...
...but I don't want
her running to her father
saying you
showed her your junk.
Then we should
ask her to leave.
Oh, God. Really?
Mmm-hmm.
- Sammy?
- It's Sam.
Sam... Lesley.
Listen, um, what I said...
Oh, don't worry about it.
He's a handful, huh?
How do you always manage to
find a new way to humiliate me?
Oh, to be fair,
you make it really easy.
What was she doing here?
She brought me down.
And stayed?
Well, she is a little...
something.
This is Broadway.
And I'm here, finally.
Now, please, do me a favor,
I'm begging you...
don't fuck it up!
Lesley.
Come here.
Play with my balls.
Don't do it. Ow!
Just sign it.
Listen...
No, you listen to me!
I can't afford
to listen to you.
I have to go
shopping again.
Just sew something,
you old fuck!
Give him
whatever he wants!
It's four times what
we paid what's-his-name!
Go into the reserve.
It's gone! We spent it
on fog and fake trees...
It's a dream sequence.
...and dancing midgets!
You can't say
"midget" anymore.
The reserve is gone!
You didn't see
what I just saw.
I'm telling you,
this guy's the real deal.
I can feel it.
He's the actor
we've been waiting for.
Come on. Just get
the contract done.
Please, Jake.
I'll get the money.
Okay, I'll do it.
Stop smiling.
You're freaking me out.
Sorry. You're right.
Is it true? Shiner?
Holy shit.
When can I meet him?
He's with Larry now.
I'm going to Starbucks.
Want anything?
I'm good.
She has a great ass.
I have news for you, too.
Is it good or bad?
'Cause I really...
I missed my last two periods.
I think
it's really happening.
Wow.
Is that good or bad?
Riggan!
It's good. It's great.
Say something else.
Um...
Uh...
You sure it's mine?
Well, you know,
there's you,
there's Jake, the masseur
wore a condom...
...yeah, I'm pretty sure
it's yours.
Idiot.
Are you excited?
Yeah.
Me, too.
You're not funny!
What? Hey, what?
First preview tomorrow.
Here we go.
I rode with him in the
ambulance to the hospital.
I will never get
that image out of my head.
Right before he did it, his
eyes were so sad and lonely.
Did you have
to treat him?
I didn't have to,
but I did.
Music out.
Cue 34, 35 ready.
He was
in terrible shape.
His head swelled to twice
the size of a normal head.
He's good, huh?
He's incredible.
I think
he's drinking real gin.
What?
Ask Nick. I want you to ask
Nick if he thinks that's love.
Oh, honey,
can't we just go to dinner?
Mel,
don't get him started.
You don't know
how he's been lately.
He's been depressed.
I've been worried.
You've been what?
Let me tell you guys something about
real love. I'll tell you something.
We all should be ashamed
when we talk like we know
what we're talking about...
...when we talk about love.
Oh, for God's sake,
are you getting drunk?
I don't have to be drunk
to say what I think.
We're not drunk. We're having
a few drinks. Exactly.
You've had more than a few.
What, are you counting?
Leave her alone. If you're not
drunk, don't talk like you are.
Shut up!
Do me a favor.
For once in your life,
honest to God,
shut up for a minute.
Anyway, like I was saying...
...you want to know about real
love, there's this old couple...
...had a car wreck,
out on the interstate.
Some drunk kid plowed
his old man's pickup...
...right into their camper.
By the time I got down
to the hospital, this kid,
this fucking teenager,
was dead.
So we took the old couple
up to the O.R.
We worked like hell on them
through most of the night.
By the time we were done with
them, we just, you know...
...wrapped them
in full body casts.
The husband,
the old man...
...was depressed
for the longest time.
Even after I said to him,
"Your wife's going to pull
through", he was still depressed.
So, I went up to the mouth
hole and I asked him.
And he told me it was because
he couldn't see her...
...through the eyes.
Couldn't see his wife.
Can you imagine?
I'm telling you, this guy's
heart was breaking because...
Ugh...
...he couldn't turn
his goddamn head
and just look at
his goddamn wife.
Shit.
I mean,
it was killing this guy.
I am so tired of this.
Is this water?
It was killing him.
Did you replace
my gin with water, man?
Oh!
Mike, come on.
"Come on," what?
You're drunk.
Yes, I'm drunk. I'm supposed to be drunk!
Why aren't you drunk?
This is Carver!
He left a piece of his liver on the
table each time he wrote a page!
If I need to be drinking gin, who
the fuck are you to touch my gin?
You fucked with the period,
you fucked with the plot
so you'd get the best lines.
Leave me the fucking tools that I need!
Oh, come on, people,
don't be so pathetic.
Stop viewing the world through
your cell phone screen!
Have a real experience!
Does anybody give a shit about
the truth other than me?
This set is fake,
the bananas are fake.
There's nothing in
this milk carton!
Your performance is fake.
The only thing that's real on
this stage is this chicken.
So I'm going to work
with the chicken.
That was interesting.
Bring the curtain down.
That's good bird, man!
Get him out of here!
How do you
want me to do that?
Hey, wait.
I want him gone.
No!
We cannot do that!
Of course we can!
It's our show!
Listen to me.
No, you listen to me.
Get him the fuck
out of my play.
It was a preview!
Nobody gives a shit!
Nothing matters until
that old bat from
the New York Times
comes opening night!
We're getting rid of him.
Shut up! Shut up and
listen to me for once!
As soon as we announced he was
taking over, the advance doubled.
We can't afford to
lose any more money
and we can't
afford to lose Mike.
This is about being respected
and validated, remember?
That's what you told me!
That's how you got
me into this shit!
Now, you're the director.
Get him under control.
Fuck.
This isn't the '90s anymore.
Your zipper's down.
Fuck.
You were
really good, cabrón.
Mmm-hmm.
Out in front of the theater
in ten minutes!
Don't overthink it.
What the hell
was going on up there?
I didn't know you
were here tonight.
That guy's an asshole, huh?
What are you doing here?
Sam and I are going to grab a
bite after she's finished.
No, I mean here. Now.
Well, I know how much
this means to you.
Oh.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
So what's happening?
With the play?
You saw what.
No. You and Sam.
Oh, you know, it's great.
It's the same.
Do you talk to her?
Yeah, we talk.
It's just been so crazy
around here, you know?
You understand
where her head is at.
Of course.
She's trying to stay away
from everything and everyone
that got her into rehab
in the first place.
I know. I really do.
I get it.
That's all she's had,
so she's confused.
Yeah, I get it.
I know you're caught up
in all this stuff, but...
"Stuff"?
Uh...
You know what I mean.
Riggan, you don't have to be
a great father right now.
You just have to be one.
Oh, sorry.
How's that going?
I'd rather not talk about it.
You're drinking?
Yeah, I'm having a beer.
So...
...what's going on with you?
Me? Oh...
Nothing.
Everything's the same,
I guess.
I'm going back
to teaching.
Oh, yeah?
I'm thinking of refinancing
the Malibu house.
What? I'm sorry.
I'm thinking of refinancing...
No, I heard you.
I just need a second.
That's going to
be Sam's house.
Why Would you...?
For this play?
I need the money.
Do you have any idea
how crazy that sounds?
What do you want me to say? My
health lasted longer than the money.
Go figure that out.
What's going on?
Riggan, look at me.
Uh...
I got a chance to
do something right.
I got to take it.
I got to.
It's funny. I was sitting
here, waiting for you...
...and all of a sudden, I couldn't
remember why we broke up.
You know, the last time
I flew here from L.A...
...George Clooney was sitting
two seats in front of me...
...with a nice pair of cufflinks
and that fucking chin.
We ended up flying through
this really, really horrible storm.
I mean, the plane was
rattling and shaking.
And all the people
on board are, you know, crying.
I mean, crying.
Praying, right?
I just sat there.
They're crying,
I sit there.
And I'm thinking,
"Oh, boy...
"...the next morning, when
Sam looks at the paper...
"...it's going to be Clooney's
face on the front page, not mine."
You know? Boom.
Did you know
Farrah Fawcett died
the exact same day
as Michael Jackson?
Is that crazy?
Why did we break up?
Because you threw
a kitchen knife at me...
...and an hour later, were telling
me how much you loved me.
Just because I didn't like that ridiculous
comedy you did with Goldie Hawn...
...did not mean
I did not love you.
That's what you always do...
you confuse love
for admiration.
It's your house...
do what you want with it.
Just be there
for our daughter.
I will.
You're not Farrah Fawcett,
Riggan.
We should have done that
reality show... The Thomsons.
Shut up.
That would've been good.
Shut up!
Crazy, druggy, wise-ass daughter,
MILF-y wife with perky tits.
People would've
wanted to see that.
Shut up.
More than this piece of shit.
Shut up!
The sun bed is here.
What does that mean?
It means there's a sun bed out
there being delivered to in here.
Who ordered a sun bed?
Mike. He said it's
for his character...
part of his process
and that shit.
He said he has
to be a redneck.
Son of a bitch.
Let's go. Walk.
Where are we going?
To get you coffee.
Did I do something to disrespect you?
Not yet.
I have a lot riding on this play.
Oh, is that right?
Yeah. People know
who I am, and...
Bullshit. They don't
know you, your work.
They know the guy
from the bird suit
who tells coy, slightly
vomitous stories on Letterman.
Well, I'm sorry
if I'm popular.
Popular?
I don't give a shit.
Popularity is the slutty little
cousin of prestige, my friend.
Okay, I don't even know what
the fuck that means. Mmm.
It means, my reputation is riding
on this, and that's worth a, a...
A lot. A lot, exactly!
Fuck you. Yes!
If this doesn't
work out for you,
you fuck off back to
your studio pals...
...and dive back into that cultural
genocide you guys perpetrate.
A douchebag's
born every minute!
That was P.T. Barnum's premise
when he invented the circus...
...and nothing has changed. You guys
know if you crank out toxic crap...
...people will line up
and pay to see it!
But long after you're gone,
I'll be on that stage...
...earning my living,
baring my soul,
wrestling with complex emotions,
'cause that's what we do.
Oh, so that's what
tonight was about?
You wrestling
with complex emotion?
Tonight was about seeing if it's
even alive, if it can bleed.
This isn't a backlot, Riggan, this is New
York City. This is how we do things.
Where are you going?
They have coffee here.
Thanks, Tommy.
They were laughing at us.
Tonight they were laughing,
tomorrow they'll be tweeting.
Who cares?
These are people
who pay half price
to watch us rehearse.
Stop caring.
This play's a drama.
It's about...
You don't know what the play's about.
I do know.
No, you don't. That's
what previews are for.
That's why they
call them previews.
That's where you figure out
what the play is.
Okay, look, look.
Listen to me.
You see the woman at
the end of the bar?
The one who looks like she
licked a homeless man's ass?
Yeah.
All that matters is what she writes
about us in 500 words in the Times.
That's, uh...
Tabitha Dickinson, yes.
The only opinion that matters
in New York theater is hers.
If she likes us, we run.
If she doesn't, we're fucked.
She does look like she
licked a homeless guy's ass.
Do me a favor.
Don't get your panties in a twist
over a preview, like some rookie...
...and don't tell me
how to do my job.
This is my town
and to be honest,
people don't give
a shit about you here.
- You're Riggan Thomson, right?
- Sorry to interrupt.
Would you mind having a
picture with us here?
Would you mind?
The button's on the bottom.
Who is this guy?
He used to be Birdman.
Oh, you're such a doll. Thank you.
You're so sweet.
Handsome.
Oh.
Okay, sweetheart,
come on.
Are we good here?
I'm going to go home.
All right.
See you tomorrow.
Oh...
I want to know something.
Why Raymond Carver?
I was a kid,
in high school...
...doing a play in Syracuse,
and he was in the audience.
And he
sent this back afterwards.
A little note.
"Thank you for an honest performance.
Ray Carver."
That's when I knew
I was going to be an actor.
Right there.
Oh.
What's so funny?
It's just on
a cocktail napkin.
So?
He was
fucking drunk, man.
You headed
to Hollywood, Mike?
No.
Hollywood's
heading here, Tabby.
Good luck with that.
"A man becomes a critic
"when he cannot
be an artist...
"...the same way a man becomes an
informer when he cannot be a soldier."
That's Flaubert, right?
He's a Hollywood clown
in a Lycra bird suit.
Yes, he is.
But tomorrow night
at 8:00...
...he's going out on that
stage and risking everything.
What will you be doing?
Don't you ever worry that
I'll give you a bad review?
I'm sure you will...
...if I ever give you
a bad performance.
Miss Dickinson.
Mr. Shiner.
What are you
still doing here?
Nothing.
Um, your costumes are hanging
in your dressing room.
Oh, great. Great.
Oh, I got that coconut water
you wanted.
If you want the face stuff,
it's not open till tomorrow.
What?
Uh...
I'm not sure that
I said thank you.
For what?
Everything. You've been doing
a really good job, honestly.
I've been so preoccupied
with all the...
Okay, well,
I just wanted to say that.
What is that?
That smell.
What is it?
Look at me. Look at me!
What?
You've got to be shitting me.
Where is it?
Can we not
do this, please?
Dad?
Where is it?
I can't believe this.
Ugh.
What is this?
Chunky peanut butter.
This. This. What is that? Ah.
That's pot. Relax.
"Relax." You can't do this to me.
To you?
You know what
I'm talking about.
Oh, yeah, you!
What else is new?
Don't do that thing where you...
Make it about me? Never!
I'm trying to do
something important!
This is not important!
It's important to me!
Maybe not to you
or your cynical friends
whose only ambition
is to "go viral"...
...but to me...
God, this is my career!
It's my chance to finally do
work that means something.
That means
something to who?
You had a career, Dad, before
the third comic book movie.
Before people started to forget
who was inside that bird costume.
You are doing a play based on a
book written 60 years ago...
...for a thousand
rich old white people...
...whose only concern is where to
have cake and coffee afterwards!
Nobody gives
a shit but you!
And, let's face it, Dad...
...you are not doing this
for the sake of art,
you're doing it to
feel relevant again.
Well, guess what? There's
an entire world of people
who fight to be relevant
every single day!
And you act like
it doesn't exist.
Things that are happening
in a place you ignore...
...that has already
forgotten about you!
I mean,
who the fuck are you?!
You hate bloggers,
you mock Twitter.
You don't even
have a Facebook page!
It's you who doesn't exist!
You're doing this
because you're terrified,
like the rest of us,
that you don't matter.
And you know what?
You're right! You don't!
It's not important, okay?
You're not important...
get used to it!
Dad.
In the clays before Nick's
depression started to eat away at him...
...he never knew
I was pregnant,
and I never
intended to tell him.
I guess we make
choices in life,
and we choose to
live with them.
Or not.
I didn't want that baby.
Not because
I didn't love Nick,
and not because I didn't
love the idea of it...
...but just because I wasn't
ready to love myself.
There's a distance
to it all now.
A wistful distance, underscored
by a gentle breeze...
Actors in position.
...and the sound
of birds...
Music out.
...laughing at
the whimsy of it all.
Lesley?
What?
I think I'm hard.
No, it's just sometimes you don't
consider other people's feelings.
No, no. I'm getting
hard... feel that.
What?!
You've got to be kidding.
Let's really do it.
Let's fuck.
No, are you crazy?!
It'll be incredible!
It'll be real.
Cut it out!
I'm serious, Mike.
Don't call me Mike.
Call me Mel.
Get off!
Terri! Terri!
Terri, I know
you're in there!
Get off me! Get off!
- Ed?
- Why?
What are you doing here?
Just tell me why.
Take it easy, okay? I know this is hard.
Shut up! Shut...
Shut up! Just don't
do anything stupid.
Eddie, please!
What's the matter with me? Why do I
always have to beg people to love me?
Eddie, please,
give me the gun.
Look at me.
I was drowning.
I'm just not capable of...
You deserve to be loved,
Eddie. You do.
I just wanted to
be what you wanted.
Now I spend every
fucking minute praying
to be somebody else.
Somebody I'm not!
Anybody-
Just put the gun down, Ed.
She doesn't love you anymore.
You don't, do you?
No.
And you never will.
I'm sorry.
I don't exist.
I'm not even here.
None of this even matters.
I don't exist. I don't exist.
Ed...
I don't exist.
Ed! Eddie, Eddie, don't do that!
You're such an asshole!
What?
That's the best you've been.
Why would you do that?!
We were onstage!
What the fuck?! It's like
my head was a jar of Bolognese!
I'll fix the blood rig.
...They're fucking
in a motel room.
You can't get it up
in six months
and now you want to fuck me
in front of 800 strangers?!
I need it to feel real, okay?
I need that intensity.
Oh, fuck you!
Oh.
I was in the moment.
I thought you were, too.
I'm sorry.
I told you to stop,
you fucking animal.
You were brilliant.
What is wrong with you?!
I want your shit
out of the apartment.
What? Hey, no, wait.
Look, look, I'm sorry.
Can we just...
No, we can't, Mike!
Maybe up here,
you're Mr. Truth...
...but in the real world,
where it counts,
you're a fucking fraud!
How's that for truth,
you dick?!
What's wrong?
He's an asshole.
What'd he do now?
Oh, nothing, just try to fuck
me in front of the audience!
Oh, my God!
Right?
That's kind of hot!
Why don't I have
any self-respect?!
You're an actress, honey.
I'm pathetic!
Look at me.
You know, I've always dreamed
of being a Broadway actress...
...since I was a little kid.
And now I'm here, and I'm...
...I'm not
a Broadway actress,
I'm still
just a little kid.
And I keep waiting for someone
to tell me I made it.
You made it.
I did?
Sadly, it was with Mike Shiner on a
fake motel bed in front of 800 people.
Shut up.
Oh.
Hey, is she okay?
She'll be fine.
Look, none of this
is your fault, okay?
You're beautiful
and you're talented...
...and I'm lucky
to have you.
Okay?
Okay.
That was kind of sweet.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Two years, and he's never
said anything like that to me.
You're beautiful
and you're talented...
...and I'm lucky
to have you. Okay?
We're gross.
We are.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Do it again.
Can we discuss this
like two mature artists?
What is the big deal about...
Fuck you!
You're not ready yet.
That's fine.
Hmm.
Fuck. Actresses.
They drive me
fucking crazy.
Riggan?
Your gun is ridiculous. I can see
the red plug in the barrel...
...so you look like a kid with a
plastic toy when you point it at me.
I don't feel
threatened at all.
Get a better one.
Have some self-respect.
Please.
Hey, apart from that, uh...
...I thought it was
a pretty fun crowd, huh?
I don't think
it's high enough.
Me, neither.
What are you
doing up here?
Uh, adrenaline.
I just got out of rehab.
It's the closest thing
I get to a drug.
You went to rehab?
Cool.
It wasn't all
Dr. Drew or anything,
but that dude from
American Pie was there.
Jump!
Eat me!
Okay, then jump on my face!
I love this city.
Yeah?
Why do you act like
a click all the time?
Do you just do it
to antagonize people?
Maybe.
You really don't give a shit
if people like you or not.
Not really.
That's cool.
Is it? I don't know.
What?
Let's play a game.
A game? What are you, eight?
Mmm-hmm.
What are you, 78?
Truth or dare.
Oh, come on.
Truth or dare?
Oh.
Truth.
When we first met, you made
a comment about my ass.
Why did you do that?
You have a terrific ass,
and I noticed that.
And I just commented on it.
Truth or dare?
Dare.
Really?
Yeah.
There's a bald guy and he's
going to walk right under you.
Spit on his head.
No.
You said dare.
Truth.
No, it's too late.
Happy?
Yeah.
Ew!
Truth or dare?
Truth.
You're boring.
The truth is
always interesting.
Uh...
You want to fool
around with me?
No.
Really?
Why not?
That's a second question.
It's a second part.
I'd be afraid
I couldn't get it up.
That didn't seem to be a
problem for you onstage.
Nothing is a problem
for me onstage.
I want to ask
another question.
You already did.
One more.
Go ahead.
If you weren't afraid, what
would you want to do to me?
I'd pull your eyes
out of your head...
That's sweet.
...and put them
in my own skull...
...and look around,
so I could see the street
the way I used to
when I was your age.
Good night.
Don't kill
the messenger.
He's an asshole.
I told you.
You fucking prick.
He's playing you-
This is it?
Page 12. Page 12.
"Riggan Thomson, best known
as the face of Birdman,
"tries not to lay
an egg on Broadway."
Where's the rest of it?
There is no rest of it.
Don't worry... it'll be used to
scoop up dog shit tomorrow.
How can you be so calm?
What are my other choices?
Aren't you scared at all?
About what?
About being
humiliated out there!
It won't be the first
time I've been humiliated.
Well, of course it won't.
You're an asshole.
And by the way,
I'm not pregnant,
so there's one thing
not to worry about.
Forget about her.
He stole your front page.
He's stealing your show.
He thinks you're a joke.
Now two million people
agree with him.
Maybe you are, Riggan. Maybe
that's what you are-a joke.
Whoa! What the hell
is going on?
Get up!
Ow! That hurts!
Back away!
So Carver's the reason
you became an actor, huh?
Listen, this is
my fucking show.
I did the work, I raised the
money and I arrange the press!
Oh, Jesus. They called
me for an interview.
I told them the first thing
that came into my head.
We got the cover
of the Arts section!
Fuck the Arts section!
You told them the first thing
that came into your head?
Right.
You're Mr. Natural.
Mr. Fuck-the-scene-
just-stare-
at-my-massive-hard-on.
That's truth.
You think
it looked massive?
Shut the fuck up.
You don't get hard on my
stage unless I tell you to.
Your stage? Oh, let me
tell you something.
This stage has belonged
to a lot of great actors,
but you are not one of them.
So you wrote
your own lines, huh?
Ow!
I did, actually.
You wrote a few
changes and mumbled,
you self-absorbed prick.
I'm self-absorbed'?
Look at you.
You nobody piece of shit!
Nobody? My massive hard-on
got 50,000 views on YouTube.
A cat playing with a dildo
gets more than that.
I don't care.
Yes, you do! You care.
I'm a theater actor. I don't
give a shit. You care.
Everybody says,
"Oh, Mike is so honest.
"Mike is so motherfucking
truthful!"
Ow!
You said in the interview your
father was a drunk like Carver.
Is that true?
No. No.
'Cause my father was.
My father was a mean fucking drunk.
You understand?
He beat the shit out of us.
But at least when
he was beating us...
...he wasn't thinking about
taking us out to his toolshed.
Because when
he got us out there...
...that bastard
would smile and say:
"You want to get on your
knees and unbuckle my belt,
"or do I take it off
and use it on you?"
After a while, I made myself numb, so...
But my...
My little sister...
- Okay. Okay.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, God.
Uh, I didn't know.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
That's fucking horrible, man.
I'm sorry.
It's also not true. See,
I can pretend, too. Oh!
Don't fuck with me, Mike.
You're a little bit crazy. You
should start using that onstage.
"Working with
Riggan Thomson's
"like Waltzing
with a monkey? Huh"
I might have said that.
You might?
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Yeah.
Why don't you get your
wings and your bird suit?
Ow!
I'm gonna crab up on your ass
and fucking choke you out!
Get off me.
What are you looking at?
What are you going
to do, replace me?!
Get fucking Ryan
Gosling or some shit?!
What do you think my friend Tabitha
will do to you in the Times,
you fucking dilettante!
You are lame, Riggan...
...rolling around with
that poncy theater fuck...
...in an 800-seat
shithole like this.
Oh, you really
fucked up this time.
You destroy a genius book with
that infantile adaptation.
Now you're about to destroy
what's left of your career.
It's pathetic.
Breathing in, I am calm.
Let's get the hell out
of here while we can.
I ignore this
mental formation.
This is a mental formation.
Stop that shit!
I'm not a mental formation. I'm
you, asshole.
Leave me alone.
You were a movie star,
remember?
Pretentious, but happy.
I wasn't happy.
Ignorant, but charming. Now, you're
just a tiny, bitter cocksucker.
I was fucking miserable.
Yeah, but fake miserable.
Hollywood miserable.
What are you
trying to prove?
You're an artist?
You're not.
Fuck you!
No, fuck you, you coward.
We grossed billions!
You're ashamed of that?
Billions!
And billions of flies
eat shit every day!
So what?
Does that make it good?
I don't know if you noticed,
but that was 1992!
You could jump
right back into that suit,
if you wanted to.
Oh, look at me!
Look at this!
Look, look, look!
I look like a turkey
with leukemia!
I'm fucking disappearing.
This is what's left!
I'm the answer to a fucking
Trivial Pursuit question!
You're an imposter here.
Eventually they will
figure you out.
What part of this don't you get?
You're dead.
We are not dead.
Oh, please,
just stay dead.
We are not dead.
Stop saying "well"
There is no "we!"
I'm not fucking you! I'm
Riggan fucking Thomson!
No, you're Birdman.
Because without me,
all that's left is you...
...a sad, selfish,
mediocre actor...
...grasping at the last
vestiges of his career.
What the hell did you do that for?
I liked that poster.
It's always "we," brother.
Fuck you!!!
Shut the fuck up!
Leave me alone!!
You're fucking, so fucking annoying!
Shut up!!
Hey. What's up?
Um, well...
...one hour till curtain.
Why don't you rest a bit?
Yeah, I'm going to lay down.
Almost there, buddy. Last preview.
Okay. Cool.
How you doing?
Good. Great.
The money came through. I just need
to transfer it into the account.
Good. That's terrific.
So... I'll go, uh, do that.
Thanks for stopping by.
You know I'm proud
of you, don't you?
This took balls.
And you did it, okay?
I know.
I think we should
cancel the preview.
I'm tired, dude. I can't
do this anymore, Jake.
I can't.
That's a joke, right?
You know, I don't think this is for me.
The whole...
They're laughing at me.
There is a three-block line
of people waiting for you.
It's a full house.
We're sold out!
Really?
Yes!
And the French
ambassador's coming.
The Prince of Saudi Arabia's
bringing one of his wives.
And I didn't want to tell you
this, but Martin Scorsees...
...is casting his new film, and...
Don't tell anybody.
No, I won't.
Okay?
Okay. Yeah, yeah,
I can be ready.
Good.
Thank you.
How is he?
He'll be fine.
Poor creature.
Is it true? Scorsese?
Yeah.
And the new Pope, too.
You're an asshole, Jake!
I'm the one
keeping this afloat!
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
I think I cut
my hand shaving.
Well, I just
wanted to say... I'm sorry.
What for?
I knew what
Mike was capable of
and I brought him
in anyway.
No, no, no.
You did good.
Are you kidding?
You did great.
Tomorrow's my first opening
night on Broadway.
Mine, too.
And I just want to let you know
that, no matter what happens...
...I'm really
grateful to you.
Oh, no, no, no.
Me, too.
This is exciting.
We have a full house.
Jake just told me.
Yeah, it's great.
Oh, God.
For fuck's sake,
just jump already.
How'd you know
I'd be up here?
Well, I didn't know,
but I kind of hoped maybe.
Where is Lesley?
Lesley?
Uh, Lesley's moving on.
Smart girl.
Oh, thank you. I appreciate that support.
You ready for
your last preview?
Sure, yeah.
Who did that to you?
Could have been
anybody, I guess.
Yes.
I'm sort of hoping
it was Lesley.
It wasn't Lesley.
Oh, my God.
Are you fucking kidding me? No.
Jesus Christ!
I think maybe
I deserved it.
Fuck.
Tell me something.
What is the worst thing
that he did to you?
Seriously.
He was never around.
Yeah? I mean, so what?
That was it?
No. It was how he tried
to make up for it...
...by constantly trying to
convince me that I was special.
Okay. Look.
Look at me.
He was right, though.
About what?
About your being special.
You've been hanging
around here...
...trying to make
yourself invisible
behind this fragile
little fuck-up routine...
...but you can't.
You're anything but invisible.
You're big.
You're kind of
a great mess.
It's like a candle burning at
both ends, but it's beautiful.
No amount of booze or weed or
attitude is going to hide that.
I'm glad you're an actor and not a
writer, 'cause that was, like...
...Oprah...
...Hallmark...
...R. Kelly bad.
Yeah, well, I wasn't...
Mmm...
Truth or dare?
Truth.
No.
Truth or dare?
Do you have any idea
where you're going?
Absolutely not.
How do you do it?
Do what?
Go out there
every single night
and pretend to be somebody else
in front of all those people?
I don't pretend out there.
I told you.
I pretend just about every
place else, but not out there.
That's a shame.
What are we doing here?
What do you mean?
I mean, what are
we doing here?
By the time we got to
the hospital, the kid was dead.
So we took the old couple
up to the O.R.
We worked like
hell on them...
...through most of the night.
The husband, the old man, was
depressed for the longest time.
Even after I told him
the wife would pull through,
he was still depressed.
So I went up to the mouth
hole and I asked him.
And he told me it was because
he couldn't see her...
...the wife,
through the eye holes.
Can you imagine?
I'm telling you, this guy's
heart was breaking...
...because he couldn't turn his
goddamn head to see his goddamn wife.
So...
...I guess the question
we should ask ourselves is...
...what do we talk about
when we talk about love?
Mel and I had been
together five years...
...and I don't know how many
times I've heard "I love you,"
but it wasn't
until that night...
The blood rig
should be good now.
Be ready to go
in two minutes.
That was amazing!
Yeah, good, right?
It's actually going well.
Yeah.
I think we need to talk.
No, no.
Yeah, I guess
you're right...
...but we will eventually,
because that's the only way
I'll get a chance
to say I'm sorry.
I really am sorry.
We'd have made great parents.
Horrible.
We'd have been...
...awful.
We'd have raised...
...a serial killer. Or Justin Bieber.
I really wanted
to be a mom.
But my body doesn't
seem to agree.
When I imagined
myself on Broadway,
I never saw
the dancing reindeer.
Nice touch.
In the clays before Nick's
depression started to eat away at him...
...he had no idea
I was pregnant...
...and I never intended
to tell him.
I guess we make
choices in life,
and we choose
to live with them.
Or not.
I didn't want that baby.
Not because I didn't love
Nick, and not because
I didn't love the idea
of it, but because...
...I just wasn't ready
to love myself.
There's a distance
to it all now.
Hey, Jimmy,
you got a smoke?
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Jimmy!!
Shit!
Fuck!
Fuck.
Hey, aren't you
Riggan Thomson?
Holy shit,
let me get an autograph.
Don't be a click.
Give me an autograph.
Dude, you rock!
Birdman!
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God!
You know who that is?
Oh,
can we take one picture!
Just one picture!
Kids, get next to him!
You suck!
You suuuuck!!
Hey, Birdman!
Riggan, I'm missing him.
It's the Bird-fucking-man!
Hey, come look at this guy!
Birdman! Hey, Birdman,
whooo, look at that!
Where you going, man?
You look so old
in person.
Fuck you!
Sir! Sir!
Where are you going?
Sir! Where are you...? Sir!
What are you doing?
Waiting for Jake. This is
my attorney, Mr. Roth.
We're pursuing financial
remunerations for the injuries...
I got a play to do!
Sir, you can't go in there!
Actors Equity is
a very strong union, sir!
Knock, knock, knock!
Terri! Terri!
Ed?
What are you doing here?
Why?! I just need
you to tell me why?
Take it easy, Ed.
I know this is hard.
Shut up! Fuck you!
Shut up!
Eddie, please!
What's wrong with me?!
Why do I always... beg
people to love me?
Eddie, please,
just... just give me the gun.
I just wanted to
be what you wanted.
Now I spend
every fucking clay...
...trying to be
somebody I'm not!
Put the gun down. She doesn't love you!
Eddie.
Look at me.
I was drowning.
I'm just not capable of that
kind of...
You deserve to be loved,
Eddie. You do.
I just wanted
to be what you wanted.
Mr. Roth?
Okay, don't leave, please.
Is that a threat?
What wheelchair?
Okay, Mr. Roth, please hear me out.
Will you?
Don't hang up.
Give me 10 minutes
to grab my things,
give me 10 minutes and
we can... Don't hang up.
Goddamn it!
The motherfucker hung up!
Dad.
Dad!
Are you... okay?
Why?
You seem sort of...
No, I'm good, I'm good.
This is good. You want some?
No.
Do you really think you'll be
ready for opening tomorrow?
Yeah. Yep.
Yeah, well, I mean...
...previews were
pretty much a train wreck.
We can't seem to get
through a performance...
...without a raging fire or a
raging hard-on. I'm broke.
I'm not sleeping,
like, you know... at all.
And, uh, this play is kind
of starting to feel like...
...a miniature, deformed version
of myself that just keeps...
...following me
around and, like...
...hitting me in the balls with,
like, a tiny little hammer.
I'm sorry,
what was the question?
Never mind.
Tonight wasn't bad.
I know.
It was weird,
but it was kind of cool.
Yeah, really?
Yeah, I think
people liked it.
What are you doing?
Homework?
No, I don't...
No, um...
When I was in rehab,
they made us do this.
Really? What is it'?
Um... These dashes represent
the six billion years
that the Earth
has been around.
So, each dash represents
a thousand years.
And, um, this... is how long
humans have been here.
150,000 years.
I think they're
trying to remind us that
that's all our ego and
self-obsession are worth.
I was a shitty father,
wasn't I?
No, you were...
You were fine.
That's right,
I was... l was just fine.
I can't...
Dad?
Oh, shoot. I'm sorry.
You just wiped out the
entire human race.
There it goes. I'm sorry.
Um...
You're becoming
a trending topic.
Really?
I should probably tell you about
this before anybody else does.
350,000 views in
less than an hour.
Fuck.
Believe or not,
this is power.
Hey, look,
it's Riggan Thomson!
Look at that!
One million, three hundred
thousand hits in the last 2 hours.
That's Birdman
actor Riggan Thomson.
Give me another one.
You got it.
That takes a lot of balls.
- Or not.
- Ouch!
What do you have
to do to get a job these days?
Why must actors
have to resort to this?
That's going over
to Ms. Dickinson.
Give me a minute.
Hey, um, that's on me.
She's a friend of mine.
Okay. No problem.
Thank you.
That was...
...twenty years before I put
on that goddamn outfit.
I don't care.
Okay. I was just...
You know, before
you come tomorrow night.
It doesn't matter.
I'm going to
destroy your play.
But you didn't even see it.
Um, you know, did I do
something to offend you?
Actually, you did.
You occupied
a theater which
might have been used on
something worthwhile.
Okay. But you don't even know
if it's any good or not.
That's true. I haven't read a word
of it, or even seen a preview...
...but after
the opening tomorrow,
I'm going to turn in the worst
review anybody has ever read.
And I'm going to
close your play.
Would you like to know why?
Because I hate you,
and everyone you represent.
Entitled, selfish,
spoiled children.
Blissfully untrained,
unversed and unprepared...
...to even attempt real art.
Handing each other awards
for cartoons and pornography.
Measuring your
worth in weekends?
Well, this is the theater.
You don't get to
come here and pretend
you can write,
direct and act...
...in your own
propaganda piece
without coming
through me first.
Ah.
So break a leg.
Wow. So what has to
happen in a person's life
for them to become
a critic, anyway?
What are you writing,
a review?
Huh? Is it any good?
Is it bad?
Did you even see it?
Let me read it.
I will call the police.
No, you won't. Let's read
your fucking review.
"Callow." Callow is a label.
"Lackluster."
That's just a label.
"Marginalia"? Are you kidding me?
It sounds like you need
penicillin to clear that up.
That's a label, too. These are all labels.
You just label everything.
That's so fucking lazy.
You're a lazy fucker.
You're a lazy...
Do you know what this is?
Do you even know what it is?
You don't. You know why?
Because you can't
see this thing
if you don't know
how to label it.
You mistake those noises in
your head for true knowledge.
Are you finished?
No.
There's nothing in here about
technique, about structure...
...about intention. It's just
a bunch of crappy opinions...
...backed up by even
crappier comparisons.
You write a couple paragraphs,
and you know what?
None of this costs
you fucking anything.
You risk nothing.
Nothing, nothing, nothing!
Well, I'm a fucking actor.
This play cost me everything.
So I'll tell you what.
You take this fucking...
...malicious, cowardly...
...shittily written review and you
shove it right the fuck up...
...your wrinkly... tight ass.
You're no actor,
you're a celebrity.
Let's be clear on that.
I'm going to
kill your play.
Tomorrow...
...and tomorrow...
...and tomorrow,
Creeps in this...
...petty pace...
...from day to day...
...to the last... syllable...
...of recorded time;
And...
...all of our yesterdays...
...have lighted...
...fools...
A pint of whiskey,
please.
...the way
to dusty death.
Out... out...
$6.50, my friend.
$6.59 Uh?
Here... l don't know what
that is, just take it.
But your...
Life is but
a walking shadow,
A poor...
...player...
...that struts and frets
his hour upon the stage...
...and then is heard...
...no more!
It is a tale...
...told by an idiot...
...full of sound and fury...
...signifying nothing!
Where you going, man?
Was that too much?
I was just trying
to give you a range.
It's a little bit too much.
I can tell, because you...
I just want to
give you a range.
That was a little too much.
It was a little too much.
God, you look
like shit, brother.
You get that mongoloid look
when you're hung over.
Yeah.
Let's go. Come on. Get up.
It's a beautiful day.
Forget about
the Times... everyone else has.
Come on. Stand up!
So you're not a great actor.
Who cares?
You're much more than that.
You tower over these
other theater douchebags.
You're a movie star, man!
You're a global force!
Don't you get it?
You spent your life
building a bank account
and a reputation...
and you blew 'em both.
Good for you.
Fuck it.
We'll make a comeback.
They're waiting for something huge.
Well, give it to them.
Shave off that pathetic goatee.
Get some surgery!
Sixty's the new thirty,
motherfucker.
You're the original. You paved
the way for these other clowns.
Give the people
what they want...
old-fashioned
apocalyptic porn.
Birdman: The Phoenix Rises.
Pimple-faced gamers
creaming in their pants.
A billion worldwide,
guaranteed!
You are larger
than life, man.
You save people from their
boring, miserable lives.
You make them jump, laugh,
shit their pants.
All you have to do is...
That's what
I'm talking about.
Bones rattling!
Big, loud, fast!
Look at these people, at their
eyes... they're sparkling.
They love this shit.
They love blood.
They love action.
Not this talky, depressing,
philosophical bullshit.
Yes.
And the next
time you screech...
...it'll explode into
millions of eardrums.
You'll glimmer on thousands
of screens around the globe.
Another blockbuster.
You are a god.
See? There you go,
you motherfucker.
Gravity doesn't
even apply to you.
Wait till you see
the faces of those
who thought we were finished.
Listen to me.
Let's go back one more time
and show them what
we're capable of.
We have to end it
on our own terms...
with a grand gesture.
Flames. Sacrifice.
lcarus.
You can do it.
You hear me?
You are...
Birdman!
Hey! Is this for real,
or are you shooting a film?
A film!
You people are full of shit!
Hey, man,
can I help you?
Be careful.
Sorry, I can't talk.
I'm late.
Music.
You okay, man?
You want me to call
somebody for you?
Do you know where to go?
Yeah.
I know where to go.
Oh! Hey!
Oh! on!
Whoa!
You see?
This is where you belong.
Above them all.
Stop the music.
I beg your pardon?
Sir, you did not pay me!
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
This guy didn't
pay me. He's fucking crazy!
Not a bad
first act, huh?
Not bad at all.
It's going really well.
I didn't think
he could do Broadway.
I never would
have expected it.
If the 2nd act
is half as good...
It's pretty glorious.
What do we talk about when
we talk about Riggan Thomson?
How long
is the intermission?
Birdman can act.
Whoa.
I just came to say hello.
It's going great out there.
You're so good.
I mean it. I really mean it.
Places
for the final scene, Riggan.
Do you need to...?
No, it's fine.
Just sit here for a second.
Look at all these roses.
I hate roses.
And you hate roses.
Are you okay? You seem...
I don't know,
you seem abnormally calm.
I am calm.
I'm great, actually.
You know...
I got this little voice...
talks to me sometimes.
Tells me the truth.
It's comforting.
Kind of scary,
but it is comforting.
I'm going to pretend I
didn't hear you say that.
Okay.
You wouldn't believe
the crowd outside.
They said some people
paid up to $500 a ticket.
Really?
Hey-
Can I tell you
something funny?
Remember our last
anniversary party?
Seriously? You want
to ruin a nice moment?
Do you remember?
You fucked Janet
Rossbach in our bed.
Skip over that part.
Oh, gladly.
You threw all the guests
out of the house...
...and you threw all
the furniture out the window.
I remember. Locked
yourself in the bathroom.
Why are we
talking about...?
I drove out to...
...Malibu.
I just sat on the beach for a
while, looking out at the ocean.
Riggan.
And I walked...
...straight into the water.
And then I tried
to drown myself.
I was up to my chest
when I felt the first one.
On my back,
it was like somebody was
holding a frying pan to
me and really burning.
And then they were on my
chest and all over my legs.
The water was full
of jellyfish.
They were all over me.
I had to fight my way
out of the water
and went up to the beach.
I was rolling around
like a maniac in the sand...
...crying.
You said it was a sunburn.
I know.
And you believed me.
To be honest,
I didn't give a shit.
I love you.
And I love Sam.
I know.
I really wish I hadn't
videotaped her birth.
Why?
'Cause...
...I missed
the moment, really.
I don't have it.
I should have just been
there with the two of you.
You know... just
the three of us.
But I wasn't.
I wasn't even
present in my own life,
and now I don't have it...
...and I'm never
going to have it.
You have Sam.
Not really, I don't.
I mean, she's...
No, she's just
going through...
No, I get it,
I understand.
She needed to have a dad...
...and instead she got
this guy who was a...
...three-day
viral sensation.
It is so pathetic,
I can't...
There are things
more pathetic than that.
Yeah, like?
That moustache.
Riggan, we are in the motel.
Last scene has started.
You're not here.
Last chance for "places."
You better get
back to your seat.
Twenty little leopards
laughed at two lofty lions.
Break a leg, Mr. Thomson.
Let me put the blood rig on.
Riggan!
Terri!
Eddie! What are you
doing here?
Why? I just want
you to tell me why.
- Shut up!
- Eddie, please!
What's the matter with me?
Tell me. Why do I always have
to beg people to love me?
Eddie, please,
give me the gun.
It was me. I was drowning.
I'm just not capable of...
You deserve to be loved,
Eddie. You do.
I just wanted to
be what you wanted.
What you wanted.
Now I spend every
fucking minute trying
to be something else,
something I'm not.
Just put
the gun down, Ed.
She doesn't
love you anymore.
You don't, do you?
No.
And you never will.
I'm sorry.
Ah.
I don't exist.
I'm not even here.
Bang!
Is he up?
He just woke up.
I thought I lost you, buddy.
What the hell happened?
I was watching you onstage
and all of a sudden...
...you had that goofy look in your
eye and you just...
What is wrong with you?
He tried to...
I'm happy! He's alive! My
best friend is alive! And...
...he's the fucking
man of the hour.
What is that?
You have to be shitting me.
Read it.
I don't believe this.
"The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance"?
Read it.
"By Tabitha Dickinson."
Read it out loud!
"Thomson has
unwittingly given birth
"to a new form, which can
only be described as...
"...super-realism.
"Blood was spilled both
literally and metaphorically
"by artist
and audience alike.
"Real blood.
"The blood that has
been sorely missing
"from the veins
of American theater..."
You're happy about this?
Happy?
I'm fucking euphoric!
This is the kind of review that
turns people into living legends!
He shot the nose
off his face!
He got a new nose!
And if doesn't like that one,
we'll get him a new one!
We'll use Meg Ryan's guy.
Who cares?
They're lighting candles
for him in Central Park.
Turn on the TV.
...a vigil for
actor Riggan Thomson.
They're praying for him all over the
country. He did it. You did it!
I've been reborn, brother.
And I can see the future.
This play is going to
last forever.
It's going to open
in London, Paris.
The studio will call,
we're going to get
book deals... you'll see.
So you can see the future?
Yeah, I can!
How about that, huh? Did
you see that coming?
Oh.
Why aren't you
saying anything?
This is what you wanted,
wasn't it?
Riggan, this is
what you wanted.
Yeah.
Yeah, this is what I wanted.
Okay, listen.
You're going to get hit
with a "brandishing
a weapon" charge.
If anybody talks to you about
it, it was an accident.
Is that what this was?
An accident?
An accident.
Did you intend
to shoot yourself!
You motherfuckers, this is a hospital!
Get the fuck out of here!
This is a hospital!
Get the fuck out,
you assholes!
Out! This is
a personal matter!
A personal matter!
Hey, Sam!
What did you feel like
the night your father
tried to kill himself?
Lilacs.
Are you laughing?
What's so funny?
I can't smell them.
What are you doing?
Posting a photo of you
on your Twitter page.
I have a Twitter page?
Yeah, I set it up today.
- Let me see.
- No way.
You look hideous.
Oh, wow, thank you.
I appreciate it.
I'm just kidding.
No, I'm actually not.
You do look hideous.
You got 80,000 followers
in less than a day.
Really?
I'm going to scare
the shit out of them.
Let me look at it.
Mmm-mmm. It's done.
Uh, I'm going to get
a vase for the flowers.
Oh.
Ah.
Bye-bye... and fuck you.
Dad?