Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
(WOMAN 1 TALKING INDISTINCTLY
ON RADIO)
WOMAN 2: (ON RADIO)
Stardust, go ahead.
WOMAN 1:
Activate the V-10 recorder.
WOMAN 2: Copy.
(MAN 1 TALKING INDISTINCTLY
ON RADIO)
Quarter activation complete.
MAN 2: Copy. Thank you.
AUGGIE: I know I'm not
an ordinary 10-year-old kid.
I mean, I do ordinary things.
Eat ice cream. Ride my bike.
I'm really good
at playing sports.
Well, on my Xbox.
I love Minecraft, science
and dressing up for Halloween.
I love to lightsaber fight
with my dad.
And watch Star Wars movies
with him.
And drive my big sister crazy.
And dream about being in outer
space, just like any ordinary kid.
I just don't look ordinary
when I'm doing these things.
Not even my birth
was ordinary.
It was hilarious.
Now, how can a birth
be hilarious, you ask?
A teenage doctor helps.
This is my first day.
Nate!
AUGGIE: A massive video camera
also aids the situation.
But to really be funny, you need
what all the best jokes have.
A punch line.
DOCTOR: He's coming!
(BABY CRYING)
(BABY CRYING FADES)
(INAUDIBLE)
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
Where's the baby going?
Go with the baby!
You need to go, sir.
AUGGIE: I've had 27 surgeries
since then.
They've helped me to breathe, to
see, to hear without a hearing aid,
and some even helped me
look a bit better.
But none of them
have made me look ordinary.
NATE: He said
he doesn't want to go.
But he's ready.
NATE: No, he's not ready.
I cannot
home school him forever.
Every year that we wait,
it'll just be harder to start.
This is the first year
of middle school for everyone.
He will not be
the only new kid.
NATE: Okay, well, he's gonna be the
only new kid that looks like him.
Look, will you stop
folding towels
for just one second
and please listen?
It's like leading
a lamb to the slaughter.
And you know it.
AUGGIE: I know I'll never
just be an ordinary kid.
Ordinary kids don't make other
kids run away from playgrounds.
Ordinary kids don't get stared
at wherever they go.
But it's okay
if you wanna stare, too.
My name is Auggie Pullman.
Next week,
I start fifth grade.
And since I've never been
to real school before,
I'm pretty much totally
and completely petrified.
(SIGHS)
Mrs. Pullman,
so good to see you again.
And you must be Auggie.
What a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Mr. Tushman.
You can laugh about that.
Tushman.
I've heard 'em all.
- Tushy. Butt man. Butt face.
- (CHUCKLES) Oh.
Mr. Tuchus.
- (AUGGIE SNORTS)
- (LAUGHS)
MR. TUSHMAN: And then in the
spring, we have a science fair.
And from what your home school teacher
tells me, you'll get first prize.
You hear that, Auggie?
Then right before graduation,
whole class takes a trip
to a nature reserve
in Pennsylvania.
It is the highlight
of the year.
- I promise you.
- (KIDS CHATTERING)
Oh good, they're here.
Who are they?
Well, I thought it would be
helpful for you
to meet some of our students
'fore you start school, Auggie.
What do you think?
Other kids now?
MR. TUSHMAN: They were
in the elementary school
so they know their way around and
they'll give you a nice tour.
It will be fine.
MR. TUSHMAN: Auggie, this is Jack
Will, Julian, and Charlotte.
Guys, this is Auggie Pullman.
Hi.
Hey.
AUGGIE: Meeting kids is harder
than meeting adults.
Everyone makes
the same face at first.
But kids aren't as good
at hiding it.
So I usually look down.
You can learn a lot
about people from their shoes.
I think these three are
trust fund kid,
hand-me-down kid...
Uh-oh, crazy kid.
I act in TV commercials.
Really?
Yeah. Tide.
MR. TUSHMAN:
Why don't you guys
take Auggie 'round
the school a bit, huh?
Just be back here in, uh,
a half hour?
CHARLOTTE: I started
when I was two.
Local spots mostly.
Then when I was three I booked
my first national. Nestlé Quik.
It was hard, because
I'm lactose intolerant.
Anyway, have you ever heard
of a spit bucket?
So this is our homeroom.
We have Mr. Browne.
My mom says
he's a little weird.
CHARLOTTE:
Then I was in the chorus of
the Radio City Music Hall
Christmas Spectacular.
I auditioned
for Annie on Broadway.
I got two callbacks for Molly, but I guess
they went in a different direction.
Hey, Charlotte!
Don't you ever stop talking?
So this is the cafeteria.
The food here is okay
for school food.
Or do you eat special food?
Wow! This reminds me of my
guess spot on Law & Order.
So the science elective
is supposably really hard.
So you probably won't be
spending much time here.
No offense, but if you've never
been in a real school before...
Dude, he's been home schooled.
Okay, I'm just saying.
Science is supposably
really hard.
But you're taking it,
too, right?
(CHUCKLES) Hey,
maybe you could fail together.
Why don't you get out of the
way, so he can check it out?
Okay.
I mean, there's nothing much
to see. Desks. Chairs.
The incubator. Bunsen burners.
Those are some
really gross science posters.
Oh! And this is an eraser.
CHARLOTTE: He knows
what an eraser is.
How am I supposed to know
what he knows?
He doesn't say anything.
You know
what an eraser is, right?
(WHISPERS) Dude,
you have to say something.
Yeah, I know
what an eraser is.
Is... Is your name Jack
or Jackwill?
(GIGGLES) You thought his name
was Jackwill?
Yeah, a lotta people call me
by my first and last name.
I don't know why.
Got any other questions?
Actually, I've got
a question for Auggie.
What's the deal
with your face?
Dude!
I mean were you
in a car crash or something?
Julian!
What? Tushman said we could
ask questions if we wanted to.
Not rude questions.
Besides, he was born
like that, Mr. Tushman said.
Yeah, I know. I just thought maybe
he was, like, in a fire, too.
Hey, Julian, shut up.
You shut up!
Why don't we all shut up?
No, I wasn't in a fire.
And the word's "supposedly."
What?
You said that science
is supposably really hard.
Twice.
The word's "supposedly."
With a "D."
Maybe my mom
can home school you, too.
Do you wanna tell us yet
how you felt about the tour?
Today?
Mr. Tushman
went out of his way
to tell me how sweet
those kids were
and that Julian
is apparently quite the dream.
(SIGHS) No.
ISABEL: Not a dream?
Is he one of those kids that acts
one way in front of grownups
and then another way
in front of kids?
Yeah, I guess.
Well I know it's hard, but
you have to understand that
he probably feels badly
about himself.
And when someone acts small, you just
have to be the bigger person, all right?
Right.
Via, I'll get the pizza.
(WHISPERS) Look at me, Auggie.
That kid sounds like
a real jerk.
If someone pushes you,
push back.
Don't be afraid of anyone.
(WHISPERS)
Why are we whispering?
Because I'm afraid of Mom.
You just gotta be
a bigger person
and rise above it.
It's that easy.
Auggie, I do believe that this is the
best year for you to start school
because everybody
is going to be new.
But if you really
don't wanna go...
No. It's okay. I wanna go.
You do?
AUGGIE: Mmm-hmm.
ISABEL:
What changed your mind?
Well they have a really good
science elective.
And I need
a better science teacher.
NATE: Oh! (CHUCKLES)
- Oh, wow. There's that.
- NATE: Whoa! Whoa!
Are you gonna take that, Mom?
Can I get some backup here?
You gonna let him talk
to your wife like this?
NATE: I'm not gonna let him
talk to my wife like that.
- AUGGIE: Please!
- NATE: Get him! Come on, Via.
- Get in there.
- (INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
I'll meet you right here
after school.
Okay? Right here.
(WHISPERS) I love you.
AUGGIE: Love you, too.
I'll see you later.
Can you hear me?
We're gonna have
a little man-to-man.
Now, I gotta stop here, because
past this point is a No Dad Zone
and you don't wanna walk up with
your parents because it's not cool.
AUGGIE: But you're cool.
(SIGHS)
I know I am, but technically
most dads aren't, so...
And neither are these helmets.
Hey.
Two rules. First, only raise
your hand once a class,
no matter how many answers
you know.
Except for science.
Crush that one.
Check.
Second, you're gonna feel like
you're all alone, Auggie.
But you're not.
Check.
Should we lose this? Come on,
costumes are for Halloween.
Prepare for blastoff.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
I love you.
Love you, too.
Have fun.
AUGGIE: Bye.
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) Have an
excellent mission and Godspeed.
MAN: We are ready
to proceed at this time.
WOMAN: 10. 9. 8. 7.
Dear God, please,
make them be nice to him.
WOMAN: 4. 3. 2. 1.
(ROCKET BLASTING OFF)
AUGGIE: My mom always said...
"If you don't like
where you are...
"just picture
where you wanna be."
ALL: (CHANTING)
Auggie! Auggie! Auggie!
Auggie! Auggie!
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(LOCKER SLAMS SHUT)
AUGGIE: I can't wait
till Halloween.
(ALL CHATTERING)
All right, let's settle down.
Everybody settle down.
Uh... Saved.
Sorry.
MR. BROWNE: Everybody find
your seats? Yes?
Finding our seats. Great.
(BELL RINGS)
All right, now some of us are lucky
enough to know each other. Yeah?
And, and others are new.
Hi there.
Okay, my name is Mr. Browne
and you're late.
Yeah. I'm so sorry.
I was just helping set up
chairs for the assembly.
MR. BROWNE:
Don't worry about it.
Can anybody tell me
what this word means?
Anybody? No?
Precepts are rules
for really important things.
Like mottos.
Or like famous quotes.
Or like, um, lines
from a fortune cookie. Right?
Precepts can help motivate us.
They can help guide us when
we have to make decisions
about really important things.
Okay?
"So why are you talkin' to me
about precepts
"this early in the morning,
Mr. Browne?"
Well, let me tell you.
Because precepts can also
tell us a lot about ourselves.
Who is it that I aspire to be?
That is the question that we should
be asking ourselves all the time.
What kind of person am I?
So this is what
we're gonna do.
Um, everyone's gonna come up
with two things
that they think everybody else
should know about them.
All right? I'll go first.
Number one, I used to work on
Wall Street. For a long time.
And two, I left Wall Street
to pursue my dream and teach.
Boom, who's next?
Yes.
Julian Albans.
And I think it's cool how
you're pursuing your dream.
Thank you very much, Julian.
Let's hear your two things.
Okay.
One, I just got Battleground Mystic
on my Wii and it's totally awesome.
And number 2, we got
a ping pong table this summer.
Amazing.
Any questions for Julian?
Yes?
Is Battleground Mystic
multiplayer or single player?
Let's not
those kinda questions.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- Okay, uh...
(SIGHS)
Hi.
My name's August Pullman.
Auggie.
And, um...
I have a sister named Via
and a dog named Daisy.
I love Star Wars.
And I just said three things.
Yeah. Sorry.
That sounds like a bonus
to me. Three things.
Thank you very much, Auggie,
that was perfect. Who's next?
Oh! I actually have
a question for Auggie.
What's the deal with the braid
in the back of your hair?
Is it like a Padawan thing?
What's a Padawan thing?
Oh. It's from Star Wars.
Padawan is a Jedi apprentice.
Who's your favorite character,
Auggie?
Boba Fett.
What about Darth Sidious?
Do you like him?
Ouch.
Okay, can we talk about
Star Wars at recess? Yes?
All right. Who wants to read
this month's precept?
ALL: Me! Me! Me!
Me! Me! Me!
What about you?
What's your name?
Summer.
Want to give it a shot?
"When given the choice between
being right or being kind,
"choose kind."
(BELL RINGS)
JULIAN: Hey, can I sit there?
Sure!
You eat like the Sarlacc
monster, my young Padawan.
(CHUCKLING)
Newton's first law of motion.
An object in motion
will stay in motion unless...
It's okay, I didn't expect you
to know that on the first day.
Acted on by another force.
Very good.
Here's how it works.
A moving object will only
change its speed or direction
if something else
causes it to do that.
Hey Darth Hideous,
did you hear?
Padawan braids were lame
15 years ago.
Supposedly. With a "D."
Dude!
More like
they were always lame.
JULIAN: See you tomorrow.
MILES: Later, Barf Hideous!
Hey.
Hey, Mom.
Auggie, you're supposed
to knock.
I'm serious this time.
Wait, did someone
make fun of it?
I, for one, had a great day.
Just trying
to lighten the mood.
Right, Daisy?
Right. Good girl.
Well I went to, um,
Kinko's today
to see if they could
get my thesis off this.
You're gonna finish
your dissertation?
VIA: What is that?
It's a floppy disk.
A what?
Come on! You, it, a floppy...
These kids today.
It's basically an iPhone.
You know, it doesn't play music
or, you can't call, but...
They couldn't get the file.
That's okay.
You'll find a place.
Well I think it's great, Mom.
Maybe. Thank you.
So Auggie...
AUGGIE: Yeah?
Hi.
How was your first day
of school?
Earth to Auggie.
We asked you a question.
Come on, how was your day?
Good.
Good how?
Good like it was good?
Or good like it was bad and
you just don't wanna tell us?
It was good, okay?
I just don't know
what you want me to say?
It was good!
Okay, okay, hey!
If you're mad at Mom
about going to school,
it was my idea, too.
Why can't I just say "good"
like anybody else?
Battin' a thousand today.
Are they gonna ask
about my day?
That is not the way
we leave the table.
Hey, come on. Talk to me.
Sit down.
Take that off, please.
(VOICE BREAKING) I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It'll be okay.
Why do I have to be so ugly?
You are not ugly, Auggie.
You just have to say that
because you're my mom.
Oh, because I'm your mom,
it doesn't count?
Yeah.
Because I'm your mom, it counts the
most because I know you the most.
You are not ugly and anyone who
cares to know you will see that.
They won't even talk to me.
It matters
that I look different.
I try to pretend
that it doesn't, but it does.
I know.
Is it always gonna matter?
I don't know.
Honey, listen...
Look at me.
We all have marks on our face.
I have this wrinkle here
from your first surgery.
I have these wrinkles here
from your last surgery.
This is the map that shows us
where we're going.
And this is the map that
shows us where we've been.
And it's never ever ugly.
But what about your gray hair?
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
That's compliments
of your dad, I think.
(CHUCKLES)
And as though we summoned him.
- (CHUCKLES)
- AUGGIE: How was your day?
My day is really good
right now.
So they went to Florida, where
Gollum was living in Miami. And...
Oh, you know what it is?
Daddy doesn't have
his glasses on.
You're making this up.
(ALL LAUGHING)
VIA: August is the sun.
My mom and dad and me
are planets orbiting the sun.
But I love my brother and I'm used
to the way this universe works.
My mom says that on my fourth birthday
I wished for a little brother.
And when he was born, it only took me
a few seconds and I was all over him.
Can you hear me?
If they stare, let them stare.
You can't blend in when you
were born to stand out.
I've never asked my mom
for help with my homework.
I never needed my dad to
remind me to study for a test.
I just did most of my studying
in waiting rooms and hospitals.
Mom and Dad would always say I was the
most understanding girl in the world.
I don't know about that.
I just knew my family
couldn't take one more thing.
I know my family loves me, but
ever since my grandma died,
my best friend Miranda is the
only person who knows me.
Miranda!
Wow. Look at you.
Hey, Via.
I've texted you,
like, 1,000 times.
When'd you get back from camp?
Two weeks ago.
Two weeks?
Sorry, it's been crazy.
You know?
Yeah, no, that's okay.
What'd you do to your hair?
Do you like it?
Yeah. Yeah. It looks wild.
Just trying something
different, you know.
I'll catch you later.
- Hey, Ella.
- Hey.
(SIGHS)
Thinking about signing up?
- For what?
- The drama club.
They study theatre in the fall
and do a play in the spring.
Um...
No, not really.
I'm not a theatre nerd.
(CHUCKLES) Well,
that's too bad. I am.
I'm Justin by the way.
Sorry, that was...
That was rude. Um...
I'm Via. Olivia.
First days suck, don't they?
(SIGHS) Yeah. Yeah, they do.
My mom tried to walk me here
from the subway.
I literally had to ditch her
at the traffic light.
My mom still doesn't think
I can use a MetroCard.
You an only child, too?
Yeah. Yeah.
They never listen.
This one time I told my mom
I wanted to take guitar lessons
and play like Jimi Hendrix.
What happened?
(CHUCKLES)
Well it was nice to meet you,
Via. Olivia.
Yeah. It was nice to meet you,
too, Justin.
Maybe, I'll see you around.
Though not onstage, clearly.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
Good night, honey.
Where's Mom?
She fell asleep.
Oh. Okay.
How's Auggie?
(SIGHS)
There's some bully, you know.
How was your first day?
It was... It was really good.
It was good?
Yeah.
Say hi to Miranda for us.
I will.
Sweet dreams.
Good night.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
VIA: My mom put her life
on hold for my brother.
She always wanted to be a children's
book illustrator and teach art.
She was one thesis shy of getting
her master's when Auggie was born.
Then she stopped writing it.
She stopped a lot of things
when Auggie was born.
But she is still great
at drawing.
I don't know
if she even realizes that
she makes Auggie the center
of every universe she draws.
Miranda used to joke that
my house was like the Earth.
It revolved around the son.
Not the daughter.
That doesn't change the fact
that my mother has a great eye.
I just wish that one time, she
would use it to look at me.
MR. DAVENPORT:
Yeah, good job, good job.
Miranda?
Via? What are you doing here?
Just trying something new.
You?
Uh, same.
MR. DAVENPORT: All right,
everybody, let's go!
Time for vocal warm up.
Bring it in! Bring it in,
people, let's go!
Everybody, hands up!
Reach high! And...
(FLAPPING LIPS)
(ALL FLAPPING LIPS)
Guys, can you please...
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Okay. You... You guys, skooch.
Sit. Just be closer.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Stay. Stay, good.
Hey, hey. What's your name?
Auggie.
Nice boots.
Great. Thanks.
Okay, everybody, here we go. We're
skooching and say "Cheese."
ALL: Cheese!
AUGGIE: School became...
Well, I got used to it.
Except for dodgeball.
What evil man
invented dodgeball?
But my least favorite zone
at school is courtyard.
Because
the whole school's there.
No one does anything mean.
Or says anything. Or laughs.
They all just look, then
look away, then look back.
They're just being
normal kids.
I kinda wanna tell them, "Hey, I
know I look weird, but it's okay."
I mean, if Chewbacca started
going to school here one day,
I'd probably stare at him
a bit, too.
(CHEWBACCA GRUNTING)
I'm sorry if my staring
made you feel weird.
(GRUNTING)
In order for any of us to see,
we need light.
So right now light is bouncing off
this card traveling through the air,
through the glass,
to your eye.
But what if we added water?
- ALL: Whoa!
- (CHUCKLES)
Whoa, indeed.
Any time light passes from one material
or medium to another, it bends.
This bending of light
is also known as...
Refraction.
Very good, Auggie.
Jack, you okay?
Yeah, yeah, refraction.
Good. Clear your desks.
Pop quiz.
(ALL GROANING)
(WHISPERS) Hurry.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
Hey, Jack, come sit here.
In a sec.
Where's he goin'?
Hey.
Thanks for your help today.
No problem.
And don't worry, I got a couple
wrong so Ms. Petosa wouldn't know.
I'm not worried. The worst
they can do is kick me out.
Not loving school either, huh?
Oh, it's great.
(CHUCKLES) I wanted to go
to Wayne Middle.
The one
with the great sports teams.
Then why'd you come here?
They gave me the scholarship.
Well, if you need help
in science,
you can come to my house
after school.
You know, if you want.
Great. Thanks!
What's wrong?
I just don't like eating
in front of people.
What do you mean?
It's a long story,
but when I eat,
I think I chew like
some prehistoric swamp turtle.
No joke? Me too!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
AUGGIE: Now there's tuna
on your face.
Yeah! Tuna, man!
No, no, no, let me show you
how it's done.
- (CHUCKLES)
- (MIMICS CHOMPING)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Dude, that's even more gross.
I'm going as Boba Fett
this year.
I like Halloween, but Christmas
is still the best holiday.
AUGGIE: No way.
Halloween is the best.
A pillowcase of candy versus
two weeks off school.
You're nuts.
- (BARKS)
- You see?
Even your dog agrees.
Hey, Mom, is it okay
if Jack comes over?
Yes!
Thanks, Mrs. P.
I mean, you get snow
on Christmas.
But you can get snow
on Halloween.
- JACK: How?
- If you live in Alaska
or there's a blizzard.
(EXHALES) I've got to be cool.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You ever thought about
having plastic surgery?
No, I've never
thought about it. Why?
(CHUCKLES)
Dude, this is after
plastic surgery!
It takes a lotta work
to look this good.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- Oh my God! Oh my God.
BOTH: 1, 2, 3, 4,
I declare a thumb war.
Bow, kiss, begin.
Nate.
Fire.
(INAUDIBLE)
Okay, everybody, if you can't see the
camera, the camera can't see you.
Now let's improv like
we know what we're doing.
Okay, everybody say, "Stella!"
- ALL: Stella!
- (CAMERA CLICKS)
So I can't figure you out.
What?
Um, I can't figure you out.
Oh?
Most theatre people won't
stop talking about themselves.
But you don't talk.
I... I listen.
Me, too.
I know.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
So you do pay attention.
Okay, that's a start. Uh...
I'm a good listener
so tell me something.
Who are you gonna
audition for?
Um, I'm not really
the Our Town type.
Oh come on. Don't be
the "run lights girl."
Should be Emily.
The lead?
Look, your family can't cheer
for you in a booth.
Oh, they're pretty busy.
I don't think they would
cheer for me anyway.
Come on,
there's not one person
in your family
who would applaud you?
My grandmother.
There you go. Bring her.
I can't.
Well, then I'll applaud you.
Why are you being
so nice to me?
Because you're an only child.
We have to stick together.
Think about it. Okay?
And your grandmother's
still cheerin' you on.
GRANDMOTHER: I know you.
And I love you more than
anything in the world.
What about Auggie?
I love your brother.
But he has a lot of angels
looking out for him.
And you have me.
Yeah.
You are everywhere.
And...
...you are my favorite.
You're my favorite,
too, Grams.
Mom, Daisy ruined
my Boba Fett costume!
What? Where have you been?
It's very late.
- I'm sorry.
- She threw up all over it.
Okay, well,
you'll just have to wear
- your costume from last year.
- But I told Jack
I was going as Boba Fett,
not Ghostface.
Well, tomorrow is Halloween.
And all the shops are closed.
And my artistic hands are busy
making meatloaf.
So you do the math.
Fine!
Do you need some help, Mom?
What?
Some help.
Oh, uh, yes, thank you.
Er, mince that rosemary,
please.
Where did you say you were?
I, uh...
I went to Coney Island.
How about you stay home
from school tomorrow? Hmm?
It's Halloween. We can
make it a 3-day weekend.
Spend some time together.
Yeah. Yeah,
that would be really nice.
Yeah?
Okay, good.
Peppers? I don't want peppers.
- Peppers give Daddy gas.
- (CHUCKLES)
AUGGIE: I don't care what Jack
Will says about Christmas.
NATE: Hey, Auggie!
AUGGIE: For me, Halloween is
the best holiday in the world.
It's so awesome,
when I'm wearing the costume!
I usually walk with my head
down to avoid being seen.
But on Halloween,
I walk with my head up high.
I don't even know
who that was.
He didn't even know
who I was. It's so cool.
Especially because people
don't like to touch me
because they think
I'm contagious.
Oh, yeah, Chewie! Up high!
Boom goes the dynamite!
(KIDS LAUGHING)
It really does look like him.
- This part right?
- AMOS: Yeah.
JULIAN: I mean, he's always reminded me
of, like, the shrunken head, you know?
- AMOS: Or an orc.
- JULIAN: Yeah.
If I looked like him,
I'd swear
I'd put a hood over my face
every day.
JACK: If I looked like him,
I think I'd kill myself.
Why do you hang out with him
so much, Jack?
MILES: Yeah.
JACK: I dunno.
Tushman asked me
to be his welcome buddy
and now he just
follows me around everywhere.
JULIAN: Well, that must stink!
That must stink.
(KIDS LAUGHING)
AMOS: Oh, yeah. Just like him.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
- (GROWLS)
- (LAUGHING)
Nobody puts Baby
in the corner.
Always blows my mind how much Daddy looks
like Patrick Swayze in this movie.
- Ew!
- (CHUCKLING)
Ew, no!
Honey, tell me
what's going on with Miranda?
It's not just the pink hair.
She's just...
She won't even talk to me.
I had a friend in high school.
We went through
this exact same thing.
And what I did, which fixed it
almost immediately...
Yeah?
Was, um, to eat an entire
jack-o'-lantern bucket of candy.
- (CHUCKLES)
- (PHONE RINGING)
Mmm. Hello.
Yes, Mr. Tushman.
He's nauseous?
Does he have a fever?
What did the nurse say?
I'm so sorry.
All right. Okay. Thank you.
I will be right there.
Honey, I have to go, your brother
just threw up at school.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV)
(TV TURNS OFF)
(CLATTERING)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
ISABEL: Nate, do you know
where his helmet is?
He's asking for it
and I've looked everywhere.
I don't know.
Something at school.
He won't say.
He won't come out of his room.
And now he says he doesn't even
wanna go trick-or-treating.
I know. Okay. Thank you.
Just get here.
VIA: Come on, get ready.
It's almost time
for the Halloween parade.
You're supposed to knock!
- (KNOCKS ON TABLE)
- Go away!
Mom says you won't say
what happened.
Did someone say something?
Someone always says something!
Well tell me what happened.
It's none of your business!
You took my day with Mom,
so it is my business.
I heard Jack Will talking
about me behind my back.
He said he'd kill himself
if he looked like me.
Jack Will?
Isn't he the nice one?
There are no nice ones!
I wish I'd never gone
to school in the first place!
But you were liking school.
I know you were.
I hate it, okay? I hate it.
Auggie, I'm sorry, but you're not
the only one who has bad days.
Bad days?
Do people avoid touching you?
When a person accidentally touches
you, do they call it "the plague"?
No.
Jack Will was all I had.
So just don't compare your bad
days at school to mine, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
Did you notice that Miranda
doesn't come around any more?
What?
You didn't. Shocker.
Yeah she went away
to camp this summer
and now
she doesn't like me anymore.
Why?
Because school sucks.
And people change.
So if you wanna be a normal kid,
Auggie, then those are the rules.
So let's go trick-or-treating.
Okay?
Because right now we're
each other's best friends.
Really?
Yes.
So come on.
I'll let you have
all my Halloween candy.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
AUGGIE: I'll trade you
my apples.
VIA: Okay, no.
I know that I said that
you could have all my candy,
but I was really just saying that
to get you out of the house.
AUGGIE: What about
the chocolate?
- VIA: No.
- And the Smarties?
Gummis, licorice,
the Reese's, the Hersheys.
- No!
- And everything else.
All right, I'll let you have
all my candy.
MR. DAVENPORT: Okay, Via.
You are next please.
Let's hear it for Via.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(SIGHS)
Daisy,
do you wanna help me
take back my corner office?
Hey, Auggie!
You feeling better?
Are you okay, Auggie?
Yeah.
Sure? 'Cause you're acting
really weird.
I'm okay, Jack, okay?
Okay.
They want me to do what?
(SIGHS) Give a tour
through the school.
But Mom, it's summer vacation.
I know.
But your teachers told Mr. Tushman
you're known as a good egg.
- No, I'm a bad egg.
- You're a good egg.
And I'm actually really proud
they thought of you for this.
Mom, enough with the guilt.
And you know they gave you
a scholarship, right?
Mom...
Who else is doing it?
Uh, Charlotte and Julian.
- No.
- Why, what's wrong?
Charlotte will just talk about
Broadway the whole time.
And Julian is the biggest
phony on the planet.
So I'm sorry, but no.
Jack, it's for that boy.
Who?
The one
from the ice cream shop.
Oh.
Yeah.
So if a nice kid like your little
brother cries when he sees him,
what kind of a chance do you
think he has in middle school?
(SIGHS) Okay.
Thank you, kiddo.
JACK: Four things I've learned
about Auggie Pullman.
First of all,
you do get used to his face.
Now,
it's not like regular ice.
You can't touch it
with your hands, okay?
JACK: Second,
he's really smart.
He's ahead of me
in everything.
In science, he's ahead
of the whole school.
Everybody watching?
- Whoo!
- (ALL LAUGH)
JACK: Third of all,
he's actually pretty funny.
But fourthly,
now that I know him,
I would say I actually do
wanna be friends with Auggie.
At first, I admit it,
I was only friendly to him because
my mom asked me to be nice.
But now I would choose
to hang out with him.
Like, he's a good friend.
Like if all the guys in fifth grade
were lined up against a wall
and I could choose anyone I wanted to
hang out with, I would choose Auggie.
Hey, what's wrong?
Go away.
JULIAN: Oh, hey, Jack,
come sit with us.
Yeah, come on, man.
I wonder what happened.
XIMENA: Maybe
Jack touched Auggie
and couldn't
wash his hands in time.
Jack finally got "the plague."
CHARLOTTE:
That's not very nice.
What? We didn't start it.
Where you going?
Hi. I'm Summer.
I know.
We're in the same homeroom.
You don't have to do this.
Do what?
You don't have to be
my friend.
I know Tushman talked to you.
I don't know what you're
talking about, Auggie.
I know Tushman talked to some
kids before school started
and told them they had to be
friends with me.
He didn't talk to me.
Yeah, he did.
No, he did not.
No, he didn't,
I swear on my life!
AUGGIE: Okay, okay.
You don't have to get mad.
I don't like being
accused of things, okay?
Okay. I'm sorry.
You should be.
- He really didn't talk to you?
- Auggie!
Okay, I just...
Why are you sitting here then?
Because I want some
nice friends for a change.
Me, too.
Cool beans.
But you'll get "the plague."
Good.
Summer has "the plague."
Shut up!
So what happened
with Jack Will?
Promise you won't tell?
I got it! I got the part!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you. (LAUGHS)
She got it! She got the part!
Oh, my God! Bet she got Emily.
- Yep.
- (SIGHS)
What'd you get?
Emily's understudy.
I'm not saying poison or anything,
but just a little Benadryl
to knock Miranda out
before the show.
Okay, enough.
Look, just learn her lines and it'll
give us an excuse to hang out more.
We can start rehearsing
the kissing scene on page 110.
Wait. George and Emily?
There is no page 110.
So I'm thinking, I really
wanna kiss you right now.
But I don't know
how you'll respond.
What's wrong?
I'm not an only child.
Mom?
One sec, Via.
Auggie, let's go!
I thought
you were at the library.
Er, um...
Yeah, change of plans.
Hi, I'm Justin.
- I'm Isabel.
- (DOOR OPENS)
Daisy threw up again.
Bucket loads.
ISABEL: Bucket loads.
VIA: Um, Justin, this is
my little brother Auggie.
- Hey, dude!
- AUGGIE: Hey.
What's that in your case?
A machine gun?
(LAUGHS)
Er, no. It's a fiddle.
You should tell people
it's a machine gun.
That's way cooler.
You know what?
That's a great idea,
you're right.
We're on our way
to the grocery.
Mom's making...
What's it called?
Feijoada.
Feij... Mom's making feijoada.
It's Dad's favorite.
You're welcome to stay
if you want, Justin.
Oh, thank you very much.
It was nice meeting you.
ISABEL: Nice to meet you, too.
Psst. Oy! (SNAPS FINGERS)
Bye, Auggie.
Nothing to see here.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
It's a gene.
Well, it's sort of two genes,
but two genes
that are identical.
And the trouble is
that both of my parents
carry the gene
at the same time, which is...
Well essentially,
he won the lottery.
Backwards or something.
And in another world,
I'd look like him.
I'm sorry for telling you
that I was an only child.
Sometimes it's nice
to hide a little.
I get it. It's okay.
(VIA LAUGHING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
MIRANDA:
Major Tom, is that you?
Miranda!
It's so great
to hear your voice again.
Sorry, Via's not here.
I was actually calling
to say hello to you.
How have you been?
Good. Did you know I'm going
to a regular school now?
No way.
Do you like it?
Yeah, I guess.
It's not as hard
as Mom's home school.
Yeah, I'll bet.
How are the kids?
Are they nice?
No. But I made one friend.
Her name's Summer.
We started
a summer names club.
Summer, August. Get it?
Good for you, Auggie.
(CHUCKLES)
Um, where's Via, anyway?
She's out with her boyfriend.
Really?
Yeah. We met him last week.
He's super nice.
I've missed you, Major Tom.
I miss you too, Miranda.
And can you tell Via
that I've missed her, too?
Well, but why don't you just
tell her yourself?
Listen, I gotta go, my mom's
calling me, but, um,
you know that you can call me
any time, right?
Yeah.
Okay, so call me any time.
I will.
Merry Christmas, Auggie.
Merry Christmas, Miranda.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
- NATE: Get after it.
- Open it. Rip it apart.
MIRANDA: Via and I have been
best friends since kindergarten.
AUGGIE: Oh, my God!
MIRANDA: Her family's always
been like my second family.
Auggie's always felt
like my little brother.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- How does it feel?
- Awesome.
- Good.
MIRANDA: And for a few years even our
family's spent Christmas together.
ISABEL: Everybody say
"Merry Christmas"!
ALL: Merry Christmas!
MIRANDA: But now my dad's busy
with his new wife.
Who was his old boss.
And my mom, well, she's busy
not getting over that.
I got a job at a summer camp.
Just so I'd have somewhere
to go that wasn't home.
One day, and I swear
I didn't plan this, but...
I started playing this little make
believe game with the girls in the camp.
I said I lived
in a huge brownstone.
On a nice street.
With my two awesome parents.
And my awesome dog
named Daisy.
And my awesome little brother
with a facial deformity.
And, oh, my God,
everyone went crazy.
"What do you mean,
'deformity'?
"What does he look like?"
Suddenly,
everyone wanted to talk to me.
And by the end of summer, I was
the most popular girl in camp.
When I got home,
I wanted to call Via.
But she would've asked me about
my parents and about camp.
And then I saw Via audition
for the play.
And I remembered
how cool she is.
And how I understood
why everyone in camp
loved me more
when I pretended to be her.
She used to let Auggie
hang out with us all the time.
I was the one who bought him
his astronaut helmet.
He was so into outer space.
And I wanted him to know that the
world was bigger than his room.
And now he's out there.
And I didn't even know.
I could've helped him.
Maybe he could've helped me.
I don't know.
But I could sure use
some help right now.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION
AND LAUGHTER)
(SUMMER AND AUGGIE WHOOPING)
(LAUGHS)
That was awesome!
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, look, there's Jack Will.
Let's find another hill.
You can't just keep
avoiding him forever, Auggie.
Come on, let's go!
CROWD: (CHANTING) 9. 8. 7.
6. 5. 4.
3. 2. 1. Happy New Year!
(ALL CHEERING)
- Happy New Year!
(GRUNTING)
Thanks for the help, Daisy.
Way to put your back into it.
MILES: What about you?
Christmas was awesome.
We drove up into the mountains
where they had the most
amazing snow I've ever seen.
- It was like powder.
- Nice.
What about you, Jack?
I went up Skeleton Hill.
It was the best.
AMOS: Skeleton Hill?
I hate that place!
Should be called Garbage Hill.
I know, right? I left my old lightning
sled up there last time I was up.
It was the crappiest
piece o' junk.
Went back the next day
and someone had taken it.
JULIAN: Hey, maybe a homeless
guy wanted to go sledding.
MILES AND AMOS: Yeah.
MR. BROWNE: New precept.
Your deeds are your monuments.
Archaeologists found
these words inscribed
on the walls
of an ancient Egyptian tomb.
Can anybody tell me
what they mean?
Summer?
Oh, uh...
I think it means
that the things we do
are the things
that matter most.
MR. BROWNE: Excellent.
Anybody else?
Hey, Summer.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah. Fine. Just...
This is gonna
sound stupid, but...
do you know why
Auggie stopped liking me?
You should ask him.
I have, but ever since Halloween,
he just won't talk to me.
I mean... You know what?
I don't care. Sorry.
Ghostface.
Wait, wait, what?
That's all I can tell you.
Okay...
Now that we've finished
our tests,
I want you all
to start thinking about
our fifth grade
science fair projects.
Which you will need to work on to
have ready after spring break.
Okay? Now it could be
about anything.
(VOICE FADES)
(INAUDIBLE)
MS. PETOSA: The point is to create
something you're excited about.
Something you're proud
to show.
Mr. Will?
Something more important
to think about?
No.
So, it'll be teams of two.
Your partner
will be your tablemate.
JULIAN: Uh, Ms. Petosa?
I know we're supposed to be
in pairs,
but Jack, Amos and I had
this science fair project idea
that we wanted
to work on together.
MS. PETOSA: Okay,
maybe we can switch.
Uh, no.
Sorry?
What?
No, um, it's okay.
I'll stay with who I've got.
I'll stick with Auggie.
Hey! What did you do that for?
Dude, I don't want to switch.
Why not? Do you really wanna
be partners with that freak?
(INAUDIBLE)
JACK: Dear Mr. Tushman, I'm
very sorry for punching Julian.
It was wrong of me to do that.
I know you may need
to expel me,
but I'd still rather not say
why I did what I did.
It might get Julian
in trouble, too,
- and that's not fair.
- Stop!
Sincerely, Jack Will.
MR. TUSHMAN: Dear Mr. Will, one thing
I've learned in 20 years in education
is that there are two sides
to every story.
So I think I can imagine
what started the fight.
While nothing justifies
striking another student
I know good friends
are worth defending.
So, after your
2-day suspension
your scholarship
will be waiting for you.
Just keep up the good work.
And keep being the fine boy
we all know you to be.
Sincerely, Mr. Tushman.
VIA: What's so wrong with me not
telling you about a stupid play?
I'm not even in it.
I'm just doing the lights.
Well your boyfriend is in it.
And don't you think
we would like to see him?
No, I don't!
Look, let's all calm down
for a second.
You know,
you've been really good
at leaving me alone
my whole life.
So why are you suddenly
so interested, huh?
Are you bored now
that Auggie's in school?
Your thesis not going well?
Nate, could you please
excuse us?
- Izzy, she doesn't mean it.
- Nate!
(ISABEL ARGUING INDISTINCTLY)
What are they saying
down there?
NATE: They, my friend,
are saying a lotta things.
None of which concern us.
Let's see
your new Minecraft world.
'Cause we might
be moving to it.
So, are we going
to see the play?
Um...
I hadn't realized
what the play was
and I don't think it will be of
any interest to a kid your age.
Yeah, uh,
you'd get totally bored.
AUGGIE: Are you and Dad going?
Daddy'll go. And I'm gonna
stay here with you.
What?
So now you're gonna punish me
by not going?
Well, you didn't want me to go
in the first place, remember?
Well, now that you know about it,
of course, I want you to come.
What are you talking about?
BOTH: Nothing.
You're lying.
It's just something to do
with Via's school, honey.
You just don't want your
fancy high school friends
to know your brother's
a freak, huh?
- ISABEL: Auggie!
- Auggie, that's not true.
Stop lying to me, I'm not an
idiot, I know what's going on!
(DAISY WHIMPERING)
Daisy girl?
Auggie. Come on.
AUGGIE: It's okay,
I don't wanna go
to your stupid high school
anyway. I don't care.
Auggie, not everything
in the world is about you.
(VIA SNIFFLES)
What's wrong?
(DAISY WHIMPERING)
You're gonna be fine, girlie.
Daddy's gonna meet me there.
Take care of your brother.
VIA: Yeah.
Okay. All right.
Did Daisy really bite Mom?
Well, um, she was whimpering.
And then Mom tried to pick
her up and Daisy bit her.
Do you think
the vet can fix her?
She was in a lot of pain,
Auggie.
She's really old.
Auggie?
I want you to come
to my play. Okay?
Really?
Really.
(CRYING)
(SNIFFLES)
AUGGIE: Every time I came home
from the hospital, Daisy was here.
She was a real friend.
And real friends
are hard to find.
(BEEPS)
(LAUGHS)
Excuse me.
Sorry. Thank you.
- This is perfect.
- Here we go. Good seats.
Here. See if you can find
Via's name in there, honey.
Glasses. Oh, no! (GASPS)
I think I forgot my glasses.
Auggie, you're missing a great
episode of Hoarders, right here.
- Starring your mom's purse.
- (CHUCKLES)
You ready?
Are you supposed to be
in the girls' dressing room?
Just wanted to wish you
good luck.
"Break a leg",
not "Good luck."
You, too.
Anyone cheering
you on tonight?
Uh, yeah, my mom invited
- the entire block.
- (CHUCKLES)
It's gonna be
really embarrassing.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
- You?
Uh, my dad is
on his belated honeymoon.
And my mom's in a funk.
But maybe
she'll come tomorrow.
Well, um, Via's family
will cheer you on.
You'll be great tonight.
Honey, just enjoy the play.
Okay.
All right, go get 'em.
- Mr. Davenport...
- Hmm.
I'm really sorry,
but I can't go on tonight.
I don't feel well.
I think I might throw up.
Okay, everybody gets nervous.
You know,
when I did my Hamlet,
I threw up every night.
You're gonna be fine.
Just do it. You'll have all
of spring break to recover.
Mr. Davenport, you're not
listening. I'm not going on.
Are you kidding me?
I'm really sorry, but Via knows
all the lines. She can do it.
Then go find her then.
Thank you.
(EXHALES)
Hi.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
This play is called Our Town.
It was written
by Thornton Wilder.
The name of our town is Grover's
Corners, New Hampshire.
Just across
the Massachusetts line.
Is this...
Is this really happening?
Yes, you're going on as Emily.
Only you don't have much time.
Well, I don't even know if I'm
gonna remember all of my lines.
You'll be great.
Justin'll help you through it.
MR. DAVENPORT: Where is she?
Via, you're on in two minutes.
Why, why are you doing this?
I told you. I feel sick.
We've got a factory
in our town, too. You hear it?
Hey, it's okay.
Hey, break a leg.
JUSTIN: Makes blankets. Cartwrights
own it and it brung 'em a fortune.
MRS. WEBB: Children,
now I won't have it.
Breakfast is just as good
as any other meal.
And I won't have you
gobbling like wolves.
It'll stunt your growth.
That's a fact.
(WHISPERS)
Miranda looks so different.
(WHISPERS) That's not Miranda,
it's Via.
- What?
- It's Via.
Oh, great.
MRS. WEBB: As for me, I'd rather have
my children healthy than bright.
I'm both, Mama, you know I am.
I'm the brightest girl
in school for my age.
I have a wonderful memory.
MRS. WEBB: Eat your breakfast.
(PLAY CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
Hmm. Your stomach flu
got better fast.
Sorry, sir, just jitters.
I'll be ready
by tomorrow night.
She's doing very well.
I can't. I can't go on.
It goes so fast.
We don't even have time
to look at one another.
I didn't realize.
So all that was going on
and we never noticed?
Take me back. Up the hill.
To my grave.
But first, wait,
one more look.
Goodbye. Goodbye, world.
Goodbye, Grover's Corners.
Mama.
And Papa.
Goodbye to clocks ticking.
And food. And coffee.
And hot baths. And sleeping.
And waking up.
Oh, Earth...
You're too wonderful
for anybody to realize you.
Blow out the candles.
Ready? Take a big breath.
(BOTH INHALE)
Ha! We did it.
Did you make a wish?
I wished for a brother.
You did?
Mmm. Wow.
- Happy birthday, honey.
- (NATE CHUCKLES)
(ALL CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
(ALL CHEERING LOUDER)
Whoo!
NATE: Via!
Oh, my God!
That was incredible!
- It was just a play.
- It wasn't "just" anything.
- You were amazing!
- AUGGIE: You were great, Via!
Amazing!
VIA: Oh, Auggie.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
ISABEL: And then
there was the nurse...
NATE: Yeah.
...who farted, and I don't use
that word a lot, about 100 times.
- Honey, that was you.
- (ALL LAUGH)
To put it delicately.
I don't know
how else to say it.
It's not true.
- Busted now!
- ISABEL: No, it's not...
Anyone? Raise your hand
if you wanna change the subject
and save us from this story.
All right, I will. I will.
Um, what is that?
Oh that is Jack and Auggie's
science fair project.
Not to be confused
with an eyesore
- in the middle of the room.
- (ALL LAUGH)
No, but what is it?
Well, I don't know.
I guess it's like a... Yeah.
Follow me, you'll see.
Oh, okay.
AUGGIE: Come on!
JUSTIN: All right.
- Sweet.
- What?
Are you kidding me? I cannot
believe you just did that.
Go, go, go. Okay.
But just no kissing.
Seen a lotta horror movies
end this way.
We're gonna open
the apertures in 3, 2, 1.
(CHUCKLES)
It's a camera obscura.
Yeah. He's ten.
Oh, my God, that was so cool.
Cinema history come to life.
All right, people,
single file.
Step right up for an amazing
camera obscura.
Step right up to witness Earth's
greatest mystery, the volcano.
Okay, we're gonna open
the apertures in...
BOTH: 3, 2,1!
- KIDS: Whoa!
- GIRL: That's awesome!
(BEEPING)
Jack and Auggie.
BOTH: Dude! (LAUGH)
- See, you have to go...
- No, I did.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(ALL CONTINUE LAUGHING)
(KIDS LAUGHING)
(BURPS)
(ALL LAUGH)
- (BURPS)
- (ALL LAUGH)
AUGGIE: Okay, now I'll go.
- (BURPS)
- (ALL LAUGH)
(KIDS CHATTERING)
MR. BROWNE:
Let's go, let's go.
Everybody get in here.
Find your seats.
We good today? It's gonna be
a good one, guys.
All right. Everybody inside.
Come on.
New month, new precept.
- (KIDS LAUGHING)
- BOY: Look at him.
JULIAN: Hey, where's Auggie?
Right there.
Hey, hey, hey. Why are we
running in the hallway?
Auggie, you okay?
Yeah. Everything's fine.
I'm late for class.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Auggie, you know if you need
help you can ask for it.
You're not alone.
I know.
Amos.
You know something about this?
MR. TUSHMAN: You understand?
We take bullying
very seriously at this school.
There is zero tolerance.
Excuse me, can you explain
what's going on here?
Wasn't Julian the one
who got punched in the mouth?
If there's any bullying
going on, it isn't my son.
JULIAN'S DAD:
You wrote that, Julian?
Yes, sir.
That one note was on the back
of a class photo.
Your son photoshopped
Auggie out of it.
No. No, he didn't. I did.
Of course, I didn't think that
he would bring it to school.
But when our friends come over
and they see that picture,
I want them
to ask about our son.
Not the Pullmans'.
MR. TUSHMAN: Mrs. Albans.
When we pressed Auggie,
he showed us these other notes
that your son left
in his locker and his desk.
Chair.
Okay, look,
if no one else is gonna
have the courage to say it,
then I guess I will.
These kids are too young to be
dealing with this sort of thing.
Julian has had nightmares
because of that kid.
- Did you know that?
- Sarah.
We had to take him
to a child psychologist
to help him deal
with his night terrors.
It's just
a two-day suspension.
You'll stay home
from the nature preserve trip.
That's all.
Two days for a couple of notes
from a kid?
After all the money that we
have poured into this school?
We have a lot of friends on
the school board, Mr. Tushman.
Oh. (SIGHS)
(EXHALES) Well, I have more.
SARAH: So what would you
have us do?
Bend over backwards for every
single person in the world?
Nobody can get
their feelings hurt ever?
(CHUCKLES) You are not doing
these kids any favors.
(SIGHS) Mrs. Albans, Auggie
can't change the way he looks.
So, maybe we can change
the way we see.
SARAH: Yes.
I will be sure to tell that
to the real world.
Thank you for this.
We won't be back in the fall.
Mom. I like this school.
- Mom. I have friends, Dad.
- (SIGHS)
JULIAN'S DAD:
Let's go, Julian.
Come on.
JULIAN: Mr. Tushman.
I'm really sorry.
I know you are, Julian.
(KIDS CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
- He's not even looking at us.
- Oh. (CHUCKLES)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
This is gonna be epic.
Race ya!
(KIDS CHEERING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
- (BLOWS WHISTLE)
- (ALL CHEERING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- ISABEL: The sound of joy!
- NATE: Ah...
All right. I want you
to close your eyes,
because I have
a surprise for you.
- Do you take requests?
- (LAUGHING)
Not before 9:45.
Okay.
Open your eyes.
No! Are you...
You finished your thesis!
- Let's get drunk.
- (BOTH LAUGH)
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
Wait a minute.
A double surprise, surprise.
Okay.
- Go ahead.
- Nothin's gonna
- jump out at me, is it?
- No.
Givin' me the eyes. (CHUCKLES)
What's in here?
I'm kind of scared...
(LAUGHING)
Good, right?
I'm just gonna keep that
in the box for now.
Does that merit a kiss?
Come here.
ISABEL: More than a kiss.
Thank you.
MAN: Alright, kids! Let's give a big warm
welcome to the William Heath School!
The Glover Academy!
And Beecher Prep!
Last chance to get popcorn!
Hello.
MAN: Okay!
Welcome to the 23rd annual
Big Movie Saturday in the
Broarwood Nature Reserve!
(ALL CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
Whoo!
Tonight's movie will be...
The Wizard of Oz!
- Yay!
- (ALL APPLAUD)
(WHISPERS) Hey, dude.
You wanna go outside?
(WHISPERS) Why?
We can watch this movie
any time.
(MOVIE CONTINUES PLAYING)
(AUGGIE AND JACK LAUGHING)
Aw, man, I need to pee.
Wanna go back?
Nah, I'll just go over here.
Like in the subways?
That's gross.
No. This is gross.
(INHALES AND BURPS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
Look at that.
What? What are you lookin' at?
I'm going up there someday.
Well, I'm going down here
right now, so...
I gotta go, too, now.
You go there. I'll go here.
Don't look.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
EDDIE: What do we got here?
Couple of losers stinkin' up
the woods.
- (GASPS)
- Holy crap! Look at his face!
BOY: He's a freak!
EDDIE: Jesus, I've never seen
anything that ugly in my life.
BOY: Maybe it's an orc.
- Dude, let's go.
- EDDIE: Go where?
Hey, talkin' to you, Gollum.
This the one mask to rule
them all? My precious.
Hey, what's your problem?
(GROANS)
EDDIE: Your boyfriend's
my problem.
AUGGIE: Hey! Leave him alone.
(SCOFFS) What are you
gonna do about it?
- Get outta my way.
- No.
EDDIE: I said
get outta my way!
I said no! (GRUNTS)
AMOS: Yo, Jack,
what's up, man?
EDDIE: What's this?
More little freaks?
What you call us, hick?
Come on, prep boy.
(GRUNTING)
GIRL: Guys, stop!
Guys, stop it!
Guys, stop!
Just stop, please! Stop!
- (GROANS)
- AMOS: Just go!
(AUGGIE GRUNTS)
Oh, man! Dude!
Come on! Let's go!
Let's get out!
(BOTH PANTING)
- AUGGIE: Are you okay?
- Uh...
Dude, you're bleeding.
(RUSTLING)
What was that?
Something's coming.
Amos?
AMOS: Jack!
- JACK: Over here!
- AUGGIE: Amos, come on!
They follow you?
I think we lost 'em.
Whoa!
(ALL LAUGHING)
JACK: How did you guys
know we needed help?
We saw them follow you
out of the lodge.
I think they were seventh
graders. They were huge.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- Thanks, guys.
You totally saved our butts.
Yeah, thanks, guys.
You know, it was cool how you
stood your ground, little dude.
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBBING)
- (FIREWORKS BURSTING)
- (KIDS CHEERING)
ISABEL: Hi!
Oh, my gosh,
I missed you so much! Mmm.
- See you later, Auggie!
- AUGGIE: Bye!
How are you?
Good. And guess what?
I got in a fight.
(GASPS) Oh my God,
you're bleeding! Are you okay?
What happened?
ISABEL: Auggie got in a fight.
NATE: That's terrible.
I'm sorry.
- Did you win?
- Nate!
Well, I'm getting a vibe
like maybe he won.
Did you?
Yeah. And guess what?
They were seventh graders.
- (EXCLAIMS)
- Yes!
MILES: See you later, buddy!
Bye!
NATE: Fighting is bad, Auggie.
- Bye, Mr. and Mrs. P.
- NATE: Goodbye.
See you at graduation, Auggie.
Looking sharp.
Thanks, Dad.
I'm talking about me.
Hey! Ah, you look good, too.
I think it's safe to say the
Pullman men are crushing it today.
- You've come a long way, huh?
- Yeah.
Auggie, I am proud of you
for sticking it out.
You didn't think I would,
did you?
'Course I did.
Okay, well, come on.
I mean, when you started
you were still wearing
the astronaut helmet
in public.
I love that helmet.
I wish I knew where it was.
It's in my office.
What? Dad! That was a gift.
You had no right to hide it!
Auggie, Auggie,
please, don't be mad.
You gotta understand, you
were wearing it all the time.
I never got
to see you anymore.
I missed your face.
I know you don't always
like it, but I love it.
It's my son's face.
I wanna see it.
Do you forgive me?
No.
Yes.
Does Mom know?
(WHISPERS) No.
God, no, she'd kill me.
But I can maybe find it,
if you need it back.
That's okay.
(CHOIR SINGING)
- (WHISPERS) Mom.
- (WHISPERS) Yes?
Thank you.
For what?
Making me go to school.
I was so mad at you sometimes.
But I'm really happy
to be here.
You really are a wonder,
Auggie.
You are a wonder.
(CHOIR CONTINUES SINGING)
Whoo. (CHUCKLES)
Thank you, choir.
That was beautiful.
Ladies, gentlemen,
boys and girls, graduates.
Final award this morning is
the Henry Ward Beecher medal
to honor students who have
been notable or exemplary.
Usually, it's a "good works,"
a service award.
But I came upon a passage
that he wrote,
which made me realize that
good works come in many forms.
"Greatness," he wrote,
"lies not in being strong
"but in the right using
of strength.
"He or she is the greatest
"whose strength carries up
the most hearts
"by the attraction
of his own."
Without further ado,
this year, I am very proud
to award the Henry Ward
Beecher medal
to the student
whose quiet strength
has carried up
the most hearts.
So,
will August Pullman please come
up here to receive this award?
(ALL CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
Whoo!
You're the best, dude!
AUGGIE: Walking up towards that
stage, I felt like I was floating.
My heart was beating so fast.
I didn't really understand
why I was getting a medal.
It's not like I blew up
the Death Star.
All I did was get through fifth
grade, just like everyone else here.
Congratulations.
Here you go. That's for you.
AUGGIE: Then again, maybe
that's kind of the point.
Maybe the truth is,
I'm really not so ordinary.
Maybe if we knew what other
people were thinking
we'd know that
no one's ordinary.
And we all deserve a standing
ovation at least once in our lives.
My friends do.
My teachers do.
My sister does
for always being there for me.
My dad does
for always making us laugh.
And my mom does the most.
For never giving up.
On anything.
Especially, me.
It's like that last precept
Mr. Browne gave us.
Be kind, for everyone
is fighting a hard battle.
And if you really wanna see
what people are,
all you have to do... is look.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard