Hello. You have breakfast?
Hello. Yes, thank you.
I picked mushrooms.
I make you fry?
No, thank you. I'm not hungry.
Thank you.
OK. Good day.
By the way ...
you have horses in the hotel?
No, not horses.
Really?
I've seen pictures on your site.
Yes, it's true. There are many
wild horses in the area.
In fact,
it's just to illustrate the site.
I see.
Hello, Mr. Aydin.
- Where have you been?
- I'm here.
The customer is there for breakfast,
there is no one to serve him.
Where is Hidayet?
Around.
I bring you your coffee, Mr. Aydin?
Want your coffee?
I found mushrooms.
Oh, where?
Nihal is standing?
Ms. Nihal got up early.
She took his breakfast.
She is in her room?
I do not know. I guess.
And Necla, she lifted?
Ms. Necla has not yet fallen.
Good.
Brings my coffee in my office.
WINTER SLEEP
- It does not fear anything with the dogs?
- Do not worry, Mr. Aydin.
Ekrem!
The horse I'll take for you
is the strongest race
Turkey.
Stop, I saw 600 pounds.
They had what age?
In what state were their legs,
tendons?
And their lungs, their heart?
You do not know anything.
You are going to buy one
and then regret it.
You pay 500
and you resell 300.
I caught you a young,
robust.
It will keep you company
all your life.
What more?
- You can choose the color?
- Of course.
There is a choice.
I just have to check the hooves,
to be sure it is sturdy.
I caught one, there are two years.
I did participate
the endurance race of the Jockey Club.
He won the 80 km.
The guys laughed:
"Looks like a donkey."
"Donkeys guide the camels!"
I told them.
That's Anatolian horses.
He put them 45 minutes.
They were hippies.
- 45 minutes ...
- There were 27 horses.
These are the horses of our ancestors.
They are beautiful and durable.
We can do this when?
When I have time
and as the weather allows.
Next week?
When the mud has dried.
I'll let you know.
And the other,
he paid since the relaunch?
No, Mr. Aydin, still nothing.
Thanks to the complaint, the lawyer says
we will expel him in two months.
How are we going to do?
The law is the tenant side.
They do not know all that, Mr. Aydin.
They did not even have a lawyer,
I believe.
Sometimes I tell myself
family heritage or not
I should sell off everything.
They know you are tender,
that's why they do not pay.
Otherwise, here, it does not exist,
defaulters.
Do not pay the rent ...
But, Hidayat,
What can I do?
What I am tender?
I stick them a trial.
What to do?
As a matter of fact,
there would be plenty to do.
But nevermind ...
Son of a bitch!
Come here!
Arise.
Not move or I'll glue you one.
- What happened?
- I caught it.
Why it is tempered?
He fell into the water.
He wanted to jump
over the brook, he slipped.
- He hurt?
- No, it's just wet.
And why he threw that stone?
Tempered as it is,
it is better to be brought back quickly,
before he catches cold.
I'll tell you, Mr. Aydin.
OK.
Come down.
- I'll tell them two words.
- OK.
Hamdi Hodja!
Returns.
Hello.
- What happen?
- Nothing.
The boy fell into the water,
it was quickly brought back.
- It happened where, how?
- Almost Issiz.
He slipped trying to jump
over the creek.
What is he doing there?
He hid
to watch our car.
He threw a stone
who broke the glass.
I could hardly hold the steering wheel
and brake to avoid the accident.
- My son Ilyas?
- Yes.
He broke a window with a stone?
You can go see.
How a kid
can break a window with a stone?
To you tell me, Ismail.
He's your son, after all.
Cut the crap.
Say what you seek.
What I seek?
The glass is there.
It is for you to explain.
This is not nothing, anyway.
We almost off the road, Ismail.
I should say anything?
I am wrong?
We will pay anyway.
It's not a question of money.
Call your son
and ask him what took him.
He refuses to talk to us.
We almost stay
with his shitty little pebble.
This is serious, Ismail.
Ilyas.
Come here.
It was you who threw that stone?
Is that you?
Ilyas!
You threw that stone?
Returns.
It was not worth it to do this.
We must not exaggerate either.
But it's important.
That's why I'm talking about it.
Hidayat.
And like that, okay?
Is that better?
You feel better?
A slap against a broken window?
That enough?
Or I recall and I continue?
What happens Ismail?
Hidayet?
Nothing, Hamdi. The small fell into the water,
they brought him back.
Badly we took.
Ilyas broke their glass.
- Their window?
- Yes.
They came to make us pay.
I said that myself?
I have not said that I brought
for he was not cold?
This is good.
The fridge and seized TV for rent
misery. That's not enough?
You will take the small?
- Ismail, none of that with me.
- What?
- Stop it back.
- I back myself?
Ismail, not looking me ...
What you got, you?
- All right, get out!
- How can you talk to me?
Cut the crap.
You just piss me home?
Who do you think you are?
I have no time to lose ...
- Let go of me, Hamdi.
- Ismail!
Bring up! You'll see!
Do not add.
Ismail, I speak to you ...
Let me go, I'll stuff it, this con.
Stop!
I'll nab, the bastard!
I'll rot your life!
Get out, motherfucker!
- Jure not son of a bitch!
- Shut up!
Ismail, enough, we go.
Come!
Screw you!
Make him go.
- What a moron ...
- Monte.
You answer to a drunk ...
But it does not stop swearing.
I'll see.
Crap.
Hidayat, I'm really sorry.
I'm as shocked as you.
I do not know what to say.
What happen?
What is this circus?
Beats me.
Without you
it does not allow everything.
No ... The broken window,
we will pay you.
Rent arrears also
as soon as possible.
We have not forgotten.
I will come myself to pay you.
We are in a bad way.
We did not come to that.
It's something else.
But we do not forget our debts.
M. Aydin's father knew well.
He never had to complain about us.
We got along very well.
You could do without this gesture
and we avoid shame.
Do not you think, Hidayet?
We have our dignity.
None of that, please, Hamdi.
We said nothing for months.
It is for us to justify ourselves?
All right, Hidayat.
But to send
suddenly a bailiff ...
You could talk to us.
Communication, it exists.
Hidayat, here we go.
We did not talk?
How many times I told you, Hamdi?
I told you or not?
I told him a thousand times.
Enough is enough. You will pay it later.
We do not tell you
it was going to work out?
So what? It has arranged?
It was arranged, Hamdi?
Come on, it's good.
Excuse me again, Mr. Aydin.
I'll settle this window history.
I will come myself to pay you.
You'll see that later.
No problem.
I'll quickly.
I'll come to see you
when you arrange it.
- OK.
- Do not worry.
You're wasting your time with anyone.
Poor guy. Species less than nothing.
- Sorry again.
- Less than nothing.
Come on, goodbye.
Good road.
Son of a bitch, asshole ...
Fatma ...
Come here.
What is this?
In your opinion?
Put it down.
Take that.
Pose.
- I put them where?
- Behind the terrace.
Be careful, do not break them.
Softly.
- Give me that.
- It's okay.
I am going to replace the glass.
- OK.
- Anything else?
Not.
I take an original
or a generic?
Where you going to find a home?
Nowhere.
That's why I ask.
Huh?
Come on, Hidayat.
- We have guests?
- Levent, the teacher, is there.
- They took the tea?
- And then they want coffee.
Hello.
- It was your trip?
- Yes.
- You need anything?
- No, thank you.
- Are you hungry?
What are you doing?
Not much.
My brother's tea.
How nice.
Thank God you're here, you.
- This is sage, not the lime tree.
- It will be fine.
Continue your work.
I go through magazines.
Yes, I beg you.
You write your editorial?
I try.
I read it last week.
I liked.
Which one?
The loss of the aesthetic sense
in the villages of Anatolia ...
- OK.
- It was good.
How you doing to find always
interesting ideas?
That you really enjoyed?
Yes, it was good.
You see,
it's not about money.
There has always been poverty.
Even three olives can be
beautifully arranged in a dish
or caught
the bottom of a bag.
I see what you mean.
You know, we went
at our tenant, the Hodja ...
Yes?
You should have seen the filth,
a real mess.
- Are you in?
- No, just the garden.
The house is in ruins.
Yet there was a woman who lives there.
Still, for a religious ...
We must lead by example
to the community,
be clean, impeccable.
Who is it? I know him?
Not.
An old tenant
time of our father.
I do not recognize him in the street.
One type ladle, a little shabby.
I do not know, me ...
religious
must lead by example, right?
Especially in the countryside.
Perhaps I should write about that?
Just thinking about it, it gives me the creeps.
Yes, write about what you want.
More ...
it would not be better to write
for a major newspaper
instead of that rag?
With all the evil that you give yourself ...
I do not feel
give me harm.
I do not know, I see you pat
all week on your computer,
I think ...
if you do not pricked me this journal
I do not even know it exists.
That's why.
I do not care of major newspapers.
My kingdom is admittedly small,
but at least I am a king.
But who reads this newspaper?
Who buys it?
Sorry, my dear Necla,
I disagree.
Not at all.
I get sometimes
letters from readers
that strengthen me
in what I do.
Despite all the evil that I give myself,
as you say,
I think it is worth it.
- For example, yesterday ...
- Yes, but sometimes on the internet
I see very bad authors
get to extol.
Everyone has his little fan club.
It should not take that seriously.
In any case, it can not be
a reference for you.
But hey, keep writing,
I will not distract you.
I'll get there,
quietly.
Not easy to mount
with the mud.
You do not want to put gravel?
I like to tourists,
it's natural.
I do not tell you to tar.
The gravel, too, is natural.
I lose half my customers
with gravel.
Already we have not
many people winter ...
Obviously with this mud!
good
if it discourages some.
A place like this, it must be earned.
A small sprint?
- OK.
- Here we go.
- Shall we?
- Yes.
Let's go.
You have grown or what?
- What?
- You've grown?
Not at all.
My stomach is emancipated
We do listen to me.
- Watch out, not let yourself go.
- And why?
I buried my wife.
I'm on my own.
It is you who should make you worry,
with a young and beautiful woman.
If this continues, we will ask you
Nihal is if your daughter.
You're exaggerating, I'm not so bad.
Did not you see the carnage on your head?
There is a little thing ...
You know Garip,
the village next door to you?
Yes, but I have not been there.
No matter ...
He has a daughter of an association
who wrote to me.
I usually do not care
this kind of approach.
But then I was hit,
will know why.
It may be age.
I wonder
whether to take it seriously.
I would like your opinion.
She asks what, a donation?
Not much.
The question is ...
Between Fatma.
... That is if it is sincere
or is looking for something else.
As you're psychologist,
you'll know to read between the lines,
I'm sure.
That's all.
Mr. Aydin, I put it where your tea?
On the table.
- Let me see the letter.
- She's on the computer.
- Go on, read it.
- OK.
Thank you, Fatma.
This is the area of Nihal,
good works. It is called?
Yes, if you want.
- It would be nice, right?
- Yes.
If available ...
Nihal?
Suavi Here, we discuss.
You can come if you're not busy?
We need your lights.
Yes, in my office.
Okay, for now.
- It happens.
- Okay.
Suavi, how are you?
Very well. And you?
Well, thank you.
It was long.
All is well?
Yes, it will.
I do not go out of my farm.
What problems I may have?
And you? Your activities?
As usual, life goes on.
This time it will be me
the secret of your youth
and your eternal beauty.
That's very nice, thank you.
And your daughter,
Sometimes it comes to you?
From time to time.
She came to the end of his studies
and death of his mother.
And that's it.
- Always in London?
- Yes.
Why do not you go
live with it?
I?
Do not talk about bad luck.
I can not stand her English husband
who responds "Oh, lovely" to everything.
You exaggerate ...
So I summed up for Nihal.
Suavi already knows.
I received a letter the other day.
One young woman who teaches
sewing in a village in the area.
Basically, it asks for help.
I do not know what to think,
I'd like your opinion.
Help for what?
The letter is there, I read you?
Yes, go ahead.
Okay, I read it.
So ...
Here it is.
"Dear Mr. Aydin,
"First of all, I must tell you
"I am your admirer
"and I watch
every week your editorial
"in our local newspaper
'The Voice of the steppe'
"eager to benefit from your wisdom
and your bold ideas.
"We, the teachers
the Technical Education Institute
"are proud to count
a person of your stature ... "
etc., etc. We spend all this ...
And here we again:
"Our group of teachers
wanted to build
a small building in Garip,
"our village so destitute,
to teach sewing and writing
"women of the village.
"The mayor has supported us
as he could.
"But despite our best efforts
and lack of resources,
"building remained unfinished.
"The prefecture rejected
support our request.
"We are abandoned to our fate
in the open steppe,
"with good intentions
and hopes.
"Trying to find a solution,
"I remembered your article
'Flowers of the steppes'.
"To believe that you had written
for us.
"We've all read back,
to tears.
"Far be it from me
tenderize you.
"Know that I do not feel
no shame to bow
"before a man of your status
to seek help
"in favor of left-nots
these drylands,
"I am proud to be born.
"I will not waste your time.
"We know that you have links
with affluent locals
"and with the administration.
"You also have relationships
to Istanbul.
"That's why we are writing.
"Thank you,
whatever your answer.
"With all due respect."
There you go.
That's it.
I do not know ...
It looks like a good girl,
intelligent, well-intentioned.
It is idealistic,
persevering, courageous.
It probably deserves to be supported.
Can not find?
Nihal?
Frankly ...
I can not find.
I receive every day
emails like this.
Good.
What does not suit you,
exactly?
Well ...
it would be luxury
construct a building for, right?
In a backwater ...
Normally, the village mayor
they find a place,
they decorate it a bit and that's it.
I find there,
she asks too much.
Even Prefecture
does not help.
Now if we go by the logic
Administration ...
I do not know.
And Suavi, what do you say?
I do not know what to say.
We could not meet you,
I and other notables of the area
to help them?
Aydin, I have a significant head me?
Only my belly that is notable.
And again, he emancipated!
Anyway ...
I must say that your reaction
surprises me Nihal.
Why?
Because ...
thanks to you, this place is more like
an NGO than a hotel.
Where are you getting at?
Say ...
How you, philanthropist patented,
who have helped the smallest school
in the region,
rejettes so firmly that request?
I do not understand.
Simple Explanation.
It is a matter of priority.
Primary schools
of leaking roofs, broken windows.
Children wear gloves in class.
It seems logical to me
to begin with, right?
We are trying for months
to raise funds,
but it never made you interested.
And there,
you have a sudden fit of generosity.
Well, I expect the world
I'll leave you.
Suavi, spend me
before you go?
Of course.
So I do not greet you.
At right away.
You know what I think?
Misery, poverty,
it is a natural disaster.
God, somehow.
We can not oppose the destiny.
But God has endowed us with intelligence
to address those issues.
That is true.
That's true, but still,
there are people who came
on earth for that.
You have to let them do their job.
You, you're a creative artist.
Why you'll meddle in this?
Take care of your work.
Mr. Aydin, Hamdi is there.
- What Hamdi?
- Hamdi Hodja, the imam.
I'm going. You can get it here.
Rest a little.
I have plenty of things to do.
The work of the farm.
I'll walk Suavi.
You can install the Hodja here.
OK.
Welcome, Hamdi Hodja.
Thank you, Mr. Aydin.
You could keep your shoes.
It's not very clean here.
They were full of mud.
It's better that way.
- I think you're slippers.
- Do not bother.
One minute. The floor is cold.
Fatma, you can bring slippers?
With tea and cakes.
OK.
Sit down, Hamdi Hodja.
So Hamdi Hodja, I'm listening.
In fact, Mr. Aydin,
I do not know where to start.
You came home the other day,
it was a little ...
Sorry ...
Air is missing here. I can?
I open a little.
Yes?
Really, I do not know
how you say ...
It was very embarrassing for us.
We're sorry, really.
But nobody thought wrong.
The boy made a mistake.
He took it badly what happened.
But it's a kid.
Of course.
You asked
why he did that?
Because this incident ...
could have serious consequences.
Of course, I asked him.
So what?
In fact, Mr. Aydin,
it was very marked by the seizure.
That's why he made this mistake.
Especially because his father
was beaten up.
Beat?
When they came for the capture,
of course, Ismail wanted to prevent.
And the police were there.
So it has degenerated.
I see.
So, this is our car taking,
is that it?
That's about it. I'm sorry.
But now,
the little one wants.
He regrets.
He wants to come kiss your hand.
It's no go.
It takes, really.
As I have said,
we have always paid our debts.
I have a little money on me.
I came to pay for the window.
How much?
No, it is not important.
You will see with Hidayat.
I do not know.
I think it's in the 70 pounds.
It is better to talk to Hidayat.
70 pounds?
70 pounds for a single window?
Yes.
And again,
this is not an original part.
Hidayet can show you the invoice.
In fact ...
I do not know if I have enough.
Wait, I check with Hidayat.
But hey, it does not matter,
It can wait.
We will not make a fuss.
This is only a glass.
You think?
In this case, I will not stagger.
I will pay all of a sudden.
It will be simpler.
Hello?
Are you there?
Nothing, actually. I wanted to know
the price of the repair of the glass.
I had retained 70 pounds.
Really?
I was wrong then.
Okay, thank you.
No, it's not worth it.
I was wrong.
It was not 70 but 170 pounds.
170 pounds?
How so?
This is the price, that's all.
Hidayet can show you the invoice.
Though. I have not asked
if he had taken.
That's incredible.
Glass, still ...
It's weird.
There is always a mistake, Mr. Aydin.
What is it?
There were not men?
No, we do not use it at the hotel.
Fatma took them home.
Will do. As long as it keeps me
touching the ground ...
Where do I put the tea?
There. I take that.
Hamdi Hodja, come here.
Thank you.
Listen, Hamdi.
I own several houses
and shops in town.
Not to me only, actually ...
They also belong
my sister Necla.
If I had to take care of it
personally
I could not work
on my books and articles.
Do you understand?
That's why Hidayat and lawyers
caring for rent and trial.
I am not aware
what they do.
And if I say, I forget.
The other day your brother
elder or younger ...
My older brother.
He said displaced things.
But things are clear ...
not to mention the seizure,
I did not even know
you were my tenants.
These procedures are automatic
in case of unpaid rent.
Do you understand?
But of course, Mr. Aydin,
that goes without saying.
You have to do this.
You have been very forgiving
to us.
But as Ismail out of prison,
it has not been able to recover.
We do not give him a job.
I do not know why,
but it's like that.
So we need a little time
to return.
And then if you could just
ensure
that we may not be expelled ...
We will find a solution
quickly.
We are committed to this house.
I spent my entire childhood.
If you leave us a little time ...
What can I say?
I understand you, but ...
you have to talk to Hidayat.
I am not aware of anything.
You spoke to Hidayet?
- No.
- Talk to him.
Do you understand?
Hidayet and lawyers are there.
It's not me you should come and see.
It is they who know everything.
Do not come back to me.
I do not want to mislead.
"In a country with 99% Muslims,
"the people did not he deserves
religious
"clean, educated, well behaved
"that emit a reassuring image?
"The weekly sermon
prepared by our imams,
"through their readings,
"would be received by believers
with pleasure and admiration
"and raise them.
"Islam is a religion
civilization and high culture. "
So what?
That's good.
It's not too hard, was it?
Not.
Nothing that can be confusing?
You do not talk
directly from religion.
You speak of the practice,
of those who apply.
And in the end, I say that Islam
is a high cultural religion.
That's it.
Frankly, I do not care a bit.
But this is a sensitive subject.
This type was so pissed
I could not help but write.
In fact, it has managed to become
the subject of my article.
With this foul air,
sneaky, always to tack ...
See?
I played an imam once
I had good reviews.
And then, when I see this guy,
I tell myself that I had it all wrong.
Full details escaped me.
You had seen this room?
Which room?
The one where I was an imam.
"Wounded Bird".
I do not feel anything.
I went on stage
seeking the toilet.
It had to be
when I was abroad.
I came running:
"Where are the restrooms?"
- No ... It was a comedy?
- Yes.
- And before ...
- It tells me nothing.
I have a question to ask you.
Do not oppose evil,
it inspires you what?
How?
What does not oppose evil
for you?
Do not oppose evil?
How do you understand that?
I do not know ...
Make yourself attacked by robbers
and you do not opposing you there?
I guess that's it.
I do not want an example.
A logical definition.
I see no logic in that.
A logical definition ...
Do not oppose evil,
it remain indifferent to acts
condemned by morality.
It suits you?
And if we were
make this absence
opposition to evil
the principle of our behavior,
what would our lives?
What would they look like?
Thieves, killers,
pulluleraient nerds,
the world would be ablaze.
- What's left?
- It would ...
the crippled and crazy houses.
I know, me.
You may be right.
But I could not pass me
as you do.
What I scrolled me?
You should think about it.
You went fast.
There's nothing to do more.
It hurts you, you will not opposing you there.
That's it.
What else?
I feel
they hide their faces
in the fight against evil.
As if we did not
touch on all aspects.
Who, for example?
Fatma, this honey is frozen.
There else?
I'll see.
Otherwise, put it in hot water.
Instead of striving against evil,
why not do the opposite?
If you do not want
that you steal this table,
it may be best
propose to the thief.
That may be a better solution.
So if I want to marry a girl
for the money of his father,
it should jump on my neck
to counteract my cynical calculation.
Is that it?
It might feel shame,
remorse
and acknowledge his fault.
We must give him the opportunity.
What nonsense!
Let the crowds get slaughtered
hoping remorse killers.
Even in a soap opera,
it does not happen!
You can say what you want.
My choice is made.
I see no reason to oppose
the evil that would seek me personally.
Someone intends to kill me?
Welcome!
If I was defending myself,
the murderer
without departing grew up.
But you could stay alive.
It would perhaps be up?
Not so sure, believe me.
We stop this discussion.
It depresses me.
You say what, Nihal?
As a matter of fact,
I do not understand the issue.
Where did you get this need?
What makes you feel that way?
This is not a need but an idea.
She wants to help the trouble making.
Do you mind? Is your solution
to eradicate evil?
Or to achieve peace?
She wants to make life easier
malefactors.
No, I say let
luck to the one who hurt
to feel regret.
A chance bastards, it's good!
Do not pretend
not understanding.
That's what I understand, my heart.
How did you do, my heart?
That's what she said:
Help the bastards,
they may have shame.
- That's not it.
- That's what I understood.
How can you understand that?
What do you understand?
It is very clear what she says.
If you hurt me,
a thief or anyone,
I do not show resistance and therefore,
I make it conscious ...
But, stop!
What fly has stung you?
What is this story
help the evil?
Who said that?
It's supposed to fight?
You we provoked, there.
I tell you what I understand,
my darling.
It's very simple to understand.
She said that if you hurt us,
not to oppose it may encourage
the thief to give up, to regret.
How is this possible?
That's not the issue.
I say we can try.
Jews should have gone
voluntarily in the camps,
it would have rested Hitler.
He would have said:"They are already there,
longer worth gassing "?
- Are you kidding?
- No, that's what I understand.
Helping criminals to do evil
to make them regret it.
Never heard of such a thing!
Either I do not understand,
or you do not you expressed
quite clearly.
Mr. Aydin ...
they are still there.
- Who?
- Hamdi.
- What Hamdi? Hamdi Hodja?
- Yes.
- Is he here?
- Yes, there.
I saw the other day.
He wants what?
He tells me nothing.
He mysteries.
Please, not him.
You told him that I was there?
I said that I would see.
Tell him I'm not there.
He may want to leave something.
It came yesterday too.
He left nothing.
- He came yesterday?
- Yes.
You did not tell me?
But if.
You were in bed, I returned.
Really?
- Small is still with him.
- What a?
One who broke our glass.
He was there yesterday too.
I feel it's going to be complicated.
You can talk to him.
They did all this way.
What do you fear?
Nothing, that's not it.
He whines, he did not finish his sentences ...
It annoys me.
But they are there.
We will not return.
Well, okay, let them in.
We'll see what he wants.
I'll apply your lesson,
to see if I understood.
Hamdi arrives,
I will accept all of it without flinching.
- But it does not hurt you.
- Who knows?
It is not yet known.
But I will leave me.
We'll see if I understood.
- You're afraid he has a knife?
- May be!
Between Hamdi Hodja.
Welcome, Mr. Hamdi.
Thank you.
Sorry to bother you.
You do not disturb us.
You buffet breakfast with us?
Thank you, ma'am. We did not go hungry.
Sit down.
Fatma brings tea for our guests.
And cakes for breakfast.
The valley is muddy.
Sorry,
we are covered in mud.
What were you doing in the valley?
- You have arrived where?
- By the shortcut.
I saw two figures.
That was you?
- Surely.
- Yikes!
You have come to the foot of the village?
So, why?
Because it is far away.
Yes, it is far away.
That is true.
The last time too,
you were on foot?
Yesterday, I mean.
Yes.
Say ...
Why did not you say anything?
Hidayet could take you home.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing.
It is as sport to us.
There is no harm.
Aydin, they are standing ...
Fatma brings tea there.
Sit down.
You do not have a moped?
I'm going to buy a
when it will get better.
- It would be nice.
- God willing.
Fortunately the house
is next to the mosque.
Otherwise, five round trips per day,
I would have struggled.
God bless you.
This is your son?
- It suits you.
- No.
He is the son of my elder brother.
I have no children.
By dint of working,
I have not been able to get married.
My destiny, I guess.
It will come. You're young.
Ilyas is like my son.
Of course.
You're what class, Ilyas?
Say it, my child. Which class?
CM2.
Mr. Aydin ...
I go to the industrial area.
- What for?
- Servicing the door.
It can not wait?
If, but there is also
the engine whines.
He whines?
Yes, as a vibration noise.
This is perhaps the cylinders.
I would not want to damage the engine.
Okay, go ahead.
Mr. Aydin,
as I have already said,
since the incident,
little is really sorry.
- What incident?
- The broken glass.
It's ancient history.
But the poor little
feels really bad,
he feels guilty for that day.
It is not easy
to apologize.
You have to be mature
to learn to repent.
But as resentment
persist,
we can not find peace.
Our Prophet said:
"Repentance is the penance."
If someone convinces us
she regrets his actions,
we have no other choice
to forgive him.
So, believe me.
Our Ilyas is smart
and he has a heart of gold.
Despite his young age,
he listened to my advice.
He thought about it and gave me reason.
And he wanted to come with me
today
to kiss your hand.
I said to him:
"This is what you must do.
"Shows you regret
and Mr. Aydin certainly forgive you. "
Is not it?
This is not necessary.
All that does not matter.
But if it is necessary.
Otherwise, it will be his fault.
This would be the worst danger.
Right, Ilyas?
It's nothing.
I do not like the hand kissing.
My father also does not like it.
They fought for power
kiss her hand. Right, Necla?
No, otherwise it would not be at peace.
Is not it, boy?
Come on, come on,
will kiss the hand of Mr. Aydin.
Ilyas?
We did not say we would
both without telling Dad?
You want me to shame
in front of everyone?
Come on, my boy,
will kiss the hand of Mr. Aydin.
Well, okay.
Come on, Ilyas. Mr. Aydin expected.
Do not shoot! Soft.
Go ahead, shoot.
Let him breathe.
Stay away.
Wasabi.
It goes up the nose, right?
In Japan too, we like spicy.
You do not eat in Japan?
When I was little,
I did not like that.
But now I love wasabi.
How cold!
I'm frozen to the bone.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Where is Aydin?
I do not know.
Perhaps the village.
It is not in his office?
Not.
I'll make some more coffee. Want some?
You want a coffee?
I'll take, yes.
I do not know what to do
with the new good.
She put the glasses that I love
Dishwasher safe.
She broke both.
She told me.
They are so thin. It's obvious
they do not go in the dishwasher.
I will perhaps make him pay
so that she understands.
Do not exaggerate. Forget it.
I am not exaggerating.
There are objects that we take.
I had bought in Istanbul.
We find them anymore.
I understand,
but these are just the glasses.
You may be right. I do not know.
It may be you who reason.
I know I've become
very irritable these days.
I'm worried.
What kind?
There are too many things in my head.
My ex has become alcoholic.
- Who? Necdet?
- Yes.
He always had
a good run, right?
That is true.
But he drinks more
since our separation.
It seems that it starts in the morning.
You can not help it.
I know.
But sometimes
I wonder if we are not worse
since the divorce.
Him there, in this state,
me here, unhappy ...
- This is really what you think?
- Say ...
I am trying to understand
where I planted me
why we got there.
If you have not found, from the time,
Perhaps that is wrong
is not on your side.
Do not you think?
You want me to rally the flock
those who believe
that evil always comes from the other?
Not.
But you're not
necessarily fault either.
That's what I say.
Why deny that?
Because I do not see any interest.
A sensible person should care
as its share of responsibility.
I think a little of blindness
can not hurt.
But hey, if you insist,
where do you deceived Thee?
I do not know.
I think, for example,
if I had missed
all the harm he did to me,
if I was not against me,
divorcing, for example,
I would perhaps put
facing the wrong.
I do not know.
I wonder what would have changed
if I had acted differently.
You think that if you were not you
opposed to the evil that was you,
he was full of remorse
of himself?
Yes, you did say,
that's what I think.
It may seem absurd
but it is not.
Sorry, Necla,
but that does not make sense.
I think after a certain age,
People do not change.
On the contrary,
bad habits settle.
So do not protest against evil
only serves to reinforce the other
in what he does.
I think he regrets now.
This is what makes me say that.
I feel it.
I think he would come find me,
if the opportunity arose.
If I lived elsewhere,
he would have already done.
But after all that has happened,
he fears some Aydin.
You know what crosses my mind,
sometimes?
On the go and ask his forgiveness.
At Necdet?
Yes.
But you did nothing wrong.
Exactly.
This is the beauty of it.
Put another embarrassment.
And perhaps the best out of him.
You should not have abused a little
serials, lately?
What relationship?
Only where you see it.
But there is nothing to say.
It's your choice.
I find it absurd
but if you want to,
no one will stop you.
Do what you want.
But it will assume
the consequences.
Do not forget that.
That's what I think.
These small expressions
sarcastic, ambiguous,
these small lip movements
cynical ...
I am really fed up.
I hate them.
Necla, do not go too far,
please.
Basically, if I ask for forgiveness Necdet,
it would be just to get rid
you and all that.
I can see it now.
Nobody is going to stop me?
Thank goodness!
I do not need permission.
I am in my father here.
I go and I come as I want.
And
I already morfl
when I told you your truths.
And I am the only one.
looks
Omar Sharif.
How?
The photo. This is Omar Sharif?
Yes, he made a film here.
Here at the hotel?
No, in the corner.
This is a very simple man.
He took pictures with everyone.
- Really?
- Yes.
We do not believe that a star.
It is not like that.
What was this movie?
I knew.
I do not want to say stupidity.
Hello.
Mr. Aydin, what movie they filmed here
Omar Sharif?
- "Monsieur Ibrahim".
- That "Monsieur Ibrahim".
That tells me something.
They turned where, exactly?
In the vicinity.
At Ishtar, among others.
- Ishtar?
- Yes.
Interesting.
I'll see where it is.
Where are the others?
You mean Nihal and Necla?
They were there earlier.
What are they doing?
They were talking about.
They were there in the entrance.
Oh ...
I came out a minute
they were gone.
They spoke normally?
How does it normally?
No matter.
- Make us tea. Want some tea?
- Yes, thank you.
You can do?
It's right next door, Ishtar.
In front of Akkoy.
All right, I've found. It is 20 km away.
You know better than us, bravo.
No, that's not it ...
What do you doing?
Your job, I mean.
You guide?
No, not at all.
I explore.
It's not hard motorcycle winter?
Preferred when it is difficult.
Who's "we"?
The motocross riders.
I see.
I made this stuff
when I was in college.
Really?
All Europe by hitchhiking with friends.
When rowing,
we jumped on a train.
It was the big time.
We slept anywhere.
The world belonged to us.
Life seemed endless.
The energy of youth.
It's not my thing, the stop.
I need autonomy.
I want to
support myself.
That's why I prefer the bike.
And you sleep in hotels?
No, I have a tent,
but then I did not want to mount it.
Here is a bit of a cave,
as natural a tent.
And then I had stuff to write.
What do you write?
What I saw.
Travel blog?
There are also notes of trip.
These are the kinds of tests.
They will be published in book form.
That's good.
I also write a book.
Really?
A large keypad, although seriously.
"History of Turkish theater."
There has not been a serious study.
Alas.
I do a lot of research.
Archives, articles,
books ...
I'm almost done,
it remains for me to write.
- The hardest part is getting started.
- That's right.
- You are a former actor, right?
- Yes.
Hence the subject.
That's right, yes.
I prefer to say "actor".
The actors are in disgrace
these days.
I did 25 years on stage.
I can proudly say
I have turned in any soap opera.
Despite tempting offers.
I have never forgotten
that said Omar Sharif.
When he knew I was an actor,
he told me with that look:
"To play, to be honest."
He's right.
Class ...
- By the way, we bought a horse.
- Really?
It can be mounted?
He must rest for a few days.
Later, perhaps.
You stay long?
- Here?
- Yes.
I know.
I have not decided.
I live from day to day.
No tomorrow.
Otherwise, it's not a journey.
We lose the sense of adventure.
How to tell?
A life all mapped
is not a real life.
As the saying goes:
"While we are busy making
projects, life happens. "
This is very true.
You did not have to go to the market
Fatma?
I told him to go alone.
I did not want.
Have you finished the book I lent you?
Long.
So what?
What do you think?
It deserves to be translated?
No, I do not find
it worthwhile.
Can I ask you a question?
Of course.
Unless the opposition to evil, in pity.
I have a nice seam.
I would like to write fast
and send the paper.
Given your enthusiasm,
it must be mine.
Not really.
This is a result of the latter,
which aroused much interest.
- Really?
- Yes.
According Vehbi.
He has received calls
full of innuendo.
You know, your Vehbi.
It adds the reactions
to give importance
to his newspaper.
Your article was not controversy.
Indeed ...
but you never know.
And
why you thickets your nose in it?
You're an actor,
write about what you know.
Imagine that does not always choose
what we write.
This is the subject that chooses you.
Of course, everyone is free to write
on what he wants.
But then you reap what you sow.
How so?
Between an expert point of view
who devotes his life to a subject
and that of an amateur,
no picture.
You do not think that outsider
may be relevant?
Not in the field.
What material?
I'll tell you:The other day,
I have carefully read the article
you gave me.
I could not stop
and I read the old ones.
So what?
I may have been distracted before.
But there they seemed different.
What?
I do not know ...
Nihal has read them?
I do not think so.
My articles do not interest him.
She has no interest
writes to her husband?
Should she?
She reads them may secretly.
That's a kind.
This is a specialist
the silent criticism.
Anyway,
it would not be objective.
Let ...
- And so?
- As a matter of fact ...
I would not have the courage.
That is to say?
Well ...
lecturing
on topics that I know evil.
Give lessons?
This is more serious than I thought, then.
I'm not saying they are bad.
It's something else.
Anything else?
Another thing, what is it?
They are ...
Mediocre disembodied?
I can not find the adjective.
Harmless?
Is that what you mean?
I do not know. Maybe.
You are very generous today.
I try to be realistic.
That's good, bravo.
But I can stop being realistic.
Too late,
the genie is out of the bottle.
You should know.
You ask me,
I give you.
That's right, my faith.
Before, you made our admiration.
it was believed
you would do great things,
you percerais.
This did not happen.
The mountain gave birth to a mouse.
Sorry to disappoint.
You have nothing to do.
We had set the bar too high.
That's good, I feel reassured.
And "Flowers of the steppes"
What did you think?
While there,
it is precisely this article
that opened my eyes.
Tell me more.
How to tell?
This syrupy romanticism,
this naive self-persuasion, low ...
No risk.
The author just looking ...
at truism
for the sake of convenience.
And this lyrical dressing
that stinks sentimentality ...
I see. It's unbearable to you, actually.
I acknowledge that I do not like this style.
Listening to you,
I should stop writing.
But no. This is only my point of view.
Fortunately, other
do not think like you.
Certainly.
Who?
It intrigues you, I see.
No, it's because you mention.
- I have not offended you?
- Not at all.
Are you sure?
Just a little while.
Sometimes authors
are very likely on their writings.
But I will survive, do not worry.
The trouble is that you do not do
a clear critique says.
Seems that there is an implied
in what you say.
It's annoying.
I think that it might be me
you hate, not my articles.
This is absurd.
But it's true.
We must say that we are very different.
It must be recognized.
We have differences on everything
on life.
I guess it is in order
of things.
The older we get,
the more we become fussy, hard.
So, finally,
it is normal that you do not like them.
The opposite would have been amazing.
I might even be rejoicing.
Do you understand?
Finally ...
I do not want to dwell on the subject.
Amazing how are you always going out
with a pirouette.
A good word to justify yourself, always.
You can stop, please?
You had a question to ask
arriving.
It is done.
What you wanted to know?
The subject of the article
you just sent.
No, I do not believe you.
If that was my question.
Either. Religion, morality ...
nothing that would interest you.
I see.
You found your scapegoat.
You're going to exploit it fully.
Record peace to this poor guy.
Necla, you start to get irritated.
Why do you say that?
You what to do with religion,
faith, spirituality?
You have already set foot
in a mosque?
You have already prayed,
to talk about spirituality?
I have to go to the mosque
to talk about religion?
It's crazy, that!
You say Mullah stinks feet.
What do you care?
He made 10 km walk in the cold.
What it can do
when he gets there?
What do you mean?
You know very well.
No, I do not understand.
Then I'll explain.
I do not think is right
a man talks about spirituality,
while he never cried
on the grave of his parents,
there has never been the same.
There are ways to cry
you do not know.
OK. So continues.
If only I had
your ability to blindness
I would find a lot of things
newsworthy
who would stand to be
this boredom.
I do not understand
you do not you tired of rehashing
the same subjects.
Perseverance
is the only way to deepen a subject,
to create something new.
I do not know
what trouble you speak.
I never had a second
to annoy me.
In this day and age,
the trouble is a sacred luxury.
And before, it was not?
If agreed. The problem has always
was a luxury. It suits you?
How can we be
at this point the antipodes?
To believe that we are not brother and sister.
This is normal. That's how
all siblings.
One is a hard worker, the other lazy.
One is bright, the other beast.
One is sociable, the other introvert.
It's a fact.
- So what?
- So, this is normal.
I still can not explain
how could I leave Istanbul
to come and bury me here with you.
I dpris in this hole.
I feel good,
where I have my room and my books.
It could be anywhere.
We know how to create a world in itself,
occupation, or we do not know.
You're bored because you do nothing
of your days.
You let yourself go.
It was good when you translating.
You do not even do it more.
Obviously, you're bored.
In life, you need a job,
a passion.
It is said that idleness
is the mother of all vices.
it depends
what is known to work.
I do not think so
it wants to say, stir the air.
What does that mean, then?
When we reflect,
it is very active.
Even if we do nothing.
So you're busy thinking, right?
Maybe
I do not know what to do.
I have no passions that drive me.
And you, what do you do?
You're wasting your best years
with things that do not concern you.
You did not start to tinker
as an alchemist?
Just to see you, it depresses me.
But what you have, Necla,
damn it?
You've raised the left foot?
The more I take upon myself,
more thou Acharnae.
- Calm down.
- Finally, let's see ...
I understand why you divorced
after so many years.
No man can bear
such a viper's tongue.
Birds of a feather flock together.
How so?
- I understand it.
- You mean that?
Of your half.
You have become the same.
Now it is the turn of Nihal?
I know you think that about me.
But I do not care.
This is my opinion.
Nothing like Nihal.
It lurks in giving tunes
benefactor of angel.
While she goofs off.
Aside launch contemptuous looks.
It's our fault if you do nothing?
Go on, do something, too.
Who you back?
She struts
and call it charity.
The woman redemption ritual
who has never won his life.
What redemption is not known.
What do you want her to do?
Charity, it is not throwing
a bone to a hungry dog,
is to share it with him
when you have so hungry.
Everyone does what he can in his own way.
Where is the problem?
Ask yourself what makes you work.
You're not listening to me. What relationship?
You keep digging
where others have already found everything.
Stop you struggle in vain.
It is useless.
He shall go out anything new.
Tell me, you,
which would again.
You're the great thinker, not me.
I will not teach you.
It is the universal interests me.
Even if it's dj vu.
For once,
be a little realistic.
Just this once.
It is you who speak of realism?
Deal of art and help
spiritual development,
it's alchemy for you?
Not. That's what I said:
If, you, the thinkers,
you atteliez to more serious problems,
the little things that haunt you
would resolve themselves.
Taking the height
to observe a city,
also see the trees
rivers, meadows ...
But no, you hang
a tiny dot,
laziness and cowardice.
It turns round again.
We are not obliged to agree.
Why quarrel?
You know what your problem is?
For fear of suffering,
you like you hide the face.
But, yes, that's it.
But we must have the courage
to face the truth.
If you are looking to achieve truth
sometimes you do not hesitate
to destroy, my dear Aydin.
But good actor, you forgot the true,
forgot to be yourself.
You exchange identity like a shirt.
We must learn to live with you.
You want me to be realistic?
So listen to me.
You are doomed to loneliness
and boredom for the rest of your life.
Because you're a coward,
because you're lazy.
- Me?
- Yes.
You live like a parasite,
hooks to the other.
The whole world is indebted.
Who knows why.
- You'll calm down?
- I am calm.
You think you can say and do
what you want
and others must accept it.
- How is that possible?
- I do not want that at all.
Where you come from that?
Realism? You're totally in
without unknowingly.
- Me?
- Yes.
It's the best.
I assure you,
as soon as you walk out that door,
I pray that you do not spear me
a pike that exasperates me.
When you're sitting behind me,
I feel your eyes looking
the conflict for boredom.
My back went numb.
I have powers that escape me.
As if someone was rubbing my back
his calloused hand.
It gives me chills,
it prevents me from writing.
What are you talking about?
You are obliged to be always
as brittle?
You want me, say so.
That's why you're all alone.
Neither husband nor friend, person.
Alone in the world.
Am I wrong?
Enough realism or I continue?
This is a very personal realism.
You're right.
Reflection as supreme activity.
We have heard it all.
The old excuse
cowards and phonies.
You count thee away with this?
Beautiful tirade.
Hello.
- How is it going?
- Good and you?
Well, thank you.
I would like to pay for the room.
Really?
Yes, we leave early tomorrow morning.
Already?
- OK. Already the start?
- Yes, sorry.
- You will be missed.
- Thank you.
- You have rained here?
- Yes of course.
Was it good?
Yes, I was very happy
to stay in this hotel.
Very nice room.
The better.
- How are you?
- Hi.
I did not know you were here.
It was I who invited Suavi.
I doubt it.
Something we celebrate?
No, it was a meeting.
- A meeting?
- Yes.
What a mystery!
It is a military council?
I had not told you? If ...
When it?
I do not know.
You had answered:"Hmm."
I found strange
it does not interest you.
I said "Hum"?
I do not remember.
No matter.
It's not about you anyway.
You knew very well.
- Nihal?
- Yes?
You told me where exactly?
I do not know.
Did you hear?
That does not concern you!
I take your coat?
Where is Necla?
In his room.
Why? She is angry?
Not. I can go to,
if you want to.
Not. She came down this morning?
Surely.
Why you ask?
All right, go ahead.
So what?
I thought you did not go out.
But no, I assure you.
But I could not deny Nihal.
listen
to watch out not to get fleeced.
They are insatiable
and you can not say no.
I look so stupid as that?
I warn my old friend.
I would not
have to regret it.
Can I get a coffee?
I drink my coffee and I'm off.
Rest.
No, not for me.
- Just a little.
- No way.
- Levent! Between, welcome!
- Hello, friends.
- How is it going?
- Well, thank you.
I take your coat.
Where were you, Mr. instit?
I was leaving.
I was in the military office.
The wife of the commander was there.
So what?
In public,
these types pamper their wives.
But if given the opportunity,
they would put them in bags
and throw them into the water!
Hello. Aydin, the husband of Nihal.
Delighted.
I Levent, the teacher.
- I suspected it.
- Why?
You often go.
I've heard of you.
I do not know
what you do ...
Nihal you explain the better,
but raises funds
to help underprivileged schools.
Since the arrival of Nihal,
has made enormous progress.
- Well done, bravo.
- Thank you.
Do not stand, friends.
I beg you.
Levent, what you want to drink?
I will
of your delicious coffee liqueur.
Of course. Someone else will?
Suavi?
Just now, thank you.
And I, a tea, Nihal. Thank you.
So, Bulent,
there are how many schools
in the area?
Levent, no Bulent.
Three in the center.
How many students?
We, we have 75 ...
150 there ... in total, 250-300.
Why?
That's it? I would have thought more.
Look, it's snowing!
If this continues, it will be hard
mounting the coast.
Aydin!
Can you come? There is a lamp
does not work in the kitchen.
I'm coming.
Which one? That?
Forgiveness.
I said that to make you come.
Do not get me wrong,
but it's supposed to be
a private meeting.
So what?
It should enable us
to arrive
the efforts together
for months.
So what?
You can leave us?
Talk about what you want.
You have something to hide?
That's not the issue.
You do not realize
it is disrespectful?
Why disrespectful?
I simply say
this is a private meeting.
You have to see it to believe it.
You're surrounded by men
and you vires your husband.
Do not be ridiculous.
There are women in the room.
And others are coming.
But when you're here,
it complicates things, that's all.
You meddle in everything.
Let us make our way.
If I organized a meeting of this kind
and you came to it,
I would never have
so rude with you.
I do not understand you.
I do not understand these things.
It's been a year since we work.
You never showed the slightest interest
and in the end you arrive.
I do not understand what you seek.
I seek nothing.
I would have soon felt
and I would be out of myself.
What makes me angry,
it's your aplomb.
You dare tell me that.
I did not say in front of people.
I ask you here nicely.
What more?
I do not know.
But I know that I,
I never would've done that.
I'm sure.
The same old scenes
that repeat.
I do not want it.
OK.
Do what you want.
I go, you can stay.
So what?
- I'm leaving.
- Already?
Go for It.
There may be black ice,
it's dangerous.
It's okay.
You have to live dangerously.
Class ...
- Where are you going?
- We'll see.
Where the road will lead me.
Hidayat was down?
- Yes, I have checked out.
- I do not say that for that.
You need anything?
A snack?
No, thank you.
Well ...
That's it.
- Good road.
- Thank you.
Do not forget us.
Nihal, I mind?
No need to hide things,
I have just one question.
I'm listening.
I was told that there had been
a fundraiser yesterday.
Really?
Yes. So what?
Why you did not tell me?
I should do it?
You did not have to,
but it would have been nice.
Maybe I wanted to do
a large donation.
I do not think so
this is a good idea.
Everything is going well.
We do not need you, thank you.
But let's see ...
we still need ...
I am a rich man, after all.
What more natural than to support
an educational project?
We asked you to do anything.
But neither are you, darling.
And yet, you have created an entire committee
home without telling me.
Right?
Listen, Aydin, please.
We live in peace for two years,
without regard to each other.
Why the sudden change?
Yesterday you wanted to humiliate us,
my guests and me.
- I saw.
- Who, me?
Not on your life.
C'mon ...
I have not slept all night.
If our disputes of the past
were to resume,
I could not stay, know it.
- Is that a threat?
- Why I would threaten you?
I warn you, that's all.
Okay, you go.
Where would you go?
When I can, I do not know.
I will go to Istanbul.
I will find a job, I will work.
My little Nihal ...
You did not start rehashing
the same, since the time?
As if I was holding.
I have prevented you from leaving?
Pars anytime. You should try it.
A job at minimum wage.
8 am to 18 pm.
You'll see if you remain time
and energy to save the world.
I will do it if necessary.
It's better than wasting my life
and being the parasite
an arrogant man.
Thanks to you, my life is completely empty.
I live in your hooks,
I spend your money.
But that's the price of my freedom
and my useless fidelity.
You know what it feels like
can give the money to the other?
No, I do not know.
You know why?
Because I have always toiled
not to know it.
I had no childhood or youth.
A life too easy,
that's your problem.
Gratitude, it is unknown to you.
I ask you ...
to stop these secret meetings
in my house.
I only get close to my home.
These scoundrels go to
their charity elsewhere.
Nobody will grow
at night cheers at home.
I will not allow it.
This asshole instit did nothing to make.
The school needs this, that ...
It only seeks to trap neurotic
bad business, in your genre.
Why do not you understand me?
Why are you unfair?
I swear that my only goal,
coming yesterday
was to help you, to support you.
Aydin, leave me, I beg you.
It takes a bit of distance.
Either you go or I go.
Or we part, I do not know.
OK. No need to shout.
I'm leaving anyway.
It is long since decided.
I'll stay a little in Istanbul.
I have things to do there
for my book.
But your fundraising care.
This is very serious.
First I have to fix that.
So please, come sit.
We'll talk
like civilized people.
Come on.
Nihal, I ask you kindly
come sit down.
Come on.
Nihal, come here, dammit!
Nihal, darling ...
It is obvious that you assembled this group
because you love people
and that you are conscientious.
I see no conspiracy.
I will support you all the way.
I respect your intelligence
and your heart.
Especially your heart.
But I can not let
a sensitive operation,
which could cause us
unpredictable disaster,
be completed by you and these vultures.
Despite all your good intentions.
Hell is paved with good intentions.
First, you lack experience.
You know nothing of life.
You packed you.
You let yourself be fooled.
You do everything on trust.
You've surrounded
all these improbable acolytes.
It's a slippery slope, Nihal.
You want me to tell you frankly?
There are two traps
you have no way to avoid.
First, nothing will happen
in schools.
And then you will lose lots of money
because you do not know how.
Your name will be soiled.
The money, you tell me,
it's nothing, I could pay.
But if your name, our name was dirty?
Once that happens,
nothing we can do against gossip.
They will accuse us
of pocketing donations.
And there, you'll find yourself alone.
Gone, friends.
It will fall on us.
Where are you getting at?
So I tell you this:
This is fine,
your fundraiser.
But frankly, it worries me a little.
These things are not made
with the ardor of lovers.
That's why
I felt obliged to intervene
to avoid problems in the future.
- The obligation?
- Yes.
I was leaving for Istanbul
but first I have to take care of it.
This is serious, these issues.
This is not child's play.
There was so much business
scam recently.
You know the new legislation?
Do not beat around the bush.
What do you want?
See the list of donations and expenditures.
And the names of your acolytes.
I'm sure they are reliable,
but one is never too careful.
Are you serious here?
Nihal, let's be reasonable,
please.
You do not trust my experience
and honesty?
I do not understand what you seek.
What could I look?
What interest would I?
I'm just trying to avoid trouble
to our family.
It is my right, right?
Come on,
show me the list
donations and expenditures,
I see immediately
if there is a problem.
I want to see where you are.
I have nothing to hide from anyone.
Everything is there, will see.
That there?
pardon,
but I can not find my way there.
You do not have a picture of donations?
There are all signed documents.
Nihal, darling ...
you have no idea what you're doing.
How is that possible?
You do not have
a summary table?
We must keep copies
receipts to donors.
You have them?
Not.
For donations of money or property,
must systematically invoice
or receipt.
You have established them?
Either.
But it's very important.
Very important.
And if they want to deduct the donation
their taxes?
If one of them the tax fraud?
It will fall on you
and you'll end up in prison.
Sorry, but these details
are crucial.
Receipts must be numbered
and listed separately.
You did?
I do not believe.
I'll take it all supported.
Go.
Do what you want.
OK.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
I take it all with me
in my office.
I have the right software
to check everything.
When I have peeled, I tell you.
OK?
That part of it?
Good.
You sure that's it?
If there is anything else, I am too.
Take.
Take everything. Let nothing.
That's all I had left in life.
Take it to me.
Take me everything.
But what happens to you, Nihal?
Go ahead, help yourself!
Everything is for you, take it!
Do not forget that.
Look!
- Take all.
- What are you doing?
Nihal, darling ...
You act like a child.
I do not know what to say.
When you know the importance of it,
you come to thank me.
You'll see.
Nihal, listen ...
I bring you all that.
I have not really looked.
A Change of Mind.
I'm not going to interfere in that.
To be honest, I'm too lazy.
I'm pretty busy like that.
So do as you see fit.
In fact, I'm leaving tomorrow.
It's decided.
At least until the end of winter.
The hotel is quiet. Hidayat is there.
I leave tomorrow in Istanbul.
Nihal, stop, finally!
I'm leaving. What do you want more?
Thank you. Your altruism moves me to tears.
Remember?
One day you told me
that if I changed some things
home,
you forgive me.
Remember?
It means that, for you,
I have a fault to make me forgive.
So I would like
in few words and quietly,
in a way that I can understand,
Finally, you tell me
what is my fault.
I'm too tired to talk.
Maybe later.
What kind of mistake?
What I did to you?
You tell me, you're young and beautiful,
you want to live your life.
I'm older
and you hate me for that.
That's my fault?
I have not forced you to marry me.
I never restricts your freedom.
You lead your independent life,
on your side of the house.
You even built this large committee here.
If you still want more freedom,
take it.
I do not hold back.
Seriously.
If you want a divorce,
I will not stop you.
I do not want any of that.
Of course I wanted to marry you.
Is not your fault
being older than me.
I do not want to be free
to love another.
I have always felt
older than you.
But you're an insufferable man.
You're selfish, dismissive, cynical.
That's your fault.
It's possible.
That may be true, I do not know.
But at least, I sometimes
to recognize my mistakes.
But I have never seen you
admit any harm.
Am I wrong?
If you intend to overwhelm me
all night
know that I have no strength
to answer.
I do not want to overwhelm you.
But I repeat my question.
I want to know.
What is my fault?
What kind of mistake?
What I did to you?
I agree
you're a grown man,
honest,
fair, honest ...
Overall, it's true.
I can not say anything against that.
But sometimes you use these qualities
to stifle others
belittle,
humiliate, crush them.
Your great moral serves you
to hate the world.
You hate believers
because for you, believe is a sign
archaic and ignorance.
You hate unbelievers
because they have neither faith nor ideal.
The old reactionary seem to you,
limited, unable to think freely.
Young people have for you
too free thinking
and are iconoclasts.
You sermons constantly the general interest,
but you suspect everyone
being a bandit
and so you hate the people.
Which find favor in your eyes?
If only for once,
you could defend a position
makes you uncomfortable or
or a sense
that do not flatter yourself.
It is not possible.
You always knew prevent
our separation.
I guess it suited me.
I was too young to leave.
I had neither the courage nor in money.
Or a better place to go.
But you,
you've never been remorseful
proud to see a young woman
in good health,
dissolve
in emptiness, boredom and fear?
The early years, I was afraid.
Now I am ashamed.
I wasted my best years.
I lost all my qualities
in my fight against you.
I became hard, harsh,
timid, suspicious.
I do not know what to say.
I do not know if I can
express anything.
Our paths have separated,
under one roof.
Hit the Trail.
We could have a better life.
It's too late.
You can not understand.
You have to have grown up, like me,
in a village without electricity
to enjoy the happiness
to be in a nice cozy
as the latter,
to listen to the voice of his wife,
even if it is to agree
scream of horror.
We had a lackluster youth.
We have not learned to be happy.
Or to make them happy, apparently.
But as I said,
we were not malicious.
Our intentions were good,
our innocent and pure dreams.
We just wanted a better world.
Pardon me, but I do believe you anymore.
I know this speech.
You're not on stage.
Everyone has good intentions.
But as you say,
Hell is paved.
All this is gibberish.
I can not hear
your romantic spiel.
Whenever you come away,
I know you offal your last card.
But I do not know
what you want from me, basically.
Anyway,
I ask it again:
Even if you see this activity
as a lure or a female fad,
leave me peace.
Because I do not have
other consolation.
I spent my youth
to fight against you.
Through this work,
I have my confidence back.
I found a meaning
the dreary existence that I have here.
A goal which I am very proud.
So let me that.
Nihal, darling ...
You are a generous woman,
fine, rational.
Everything you say sounds very sensible.
Really.
More ...
idealise a man into a god
to then blame him
not to be a god,
Is not it unfair?
I wanted to be this great actor
Charismatic you dreamed.
But I'm not.
I am a simple man.
The worst part is that I intend to remain so.
Let ...
I am leaving in the morning.
I will come back in the spring,
do not worry.
But before leaving,
I want your list to make a donation.
Go ahead, I do not care.
The list is there, write what you want.
I made an anonymous donation.
I leave the money there.
OK?
Nihal, I hope all will be well.
Do as you wish.
Do not forget that I'm here,
if necessary.
But beware of the teacher.
It seems sneaky and manipulative.
I feel by far those.
I advise you to surround yourself with people
with a conscience, principles,
a moral sense.
One day you will understand me.
Conscience, morality,
ideals, principles ...
The purpose of life.
You have those words in his mouth.
You are abusing and uses in
to hurt and humiliate people,
to denigrate.
personally,
I think someone
pounding these words
is inevitably suspect.
I'm tired.
I want to sleep, if you allow.
Necla?
Come on.
We should call to be safe, right?
It's already done.
Flights are canceled,
but the trains.
Are you sure?
Yes, I have to have them.
Trains run smoothly.
Not to worry.
OK.
Let's go.
Hello.
The train to Istanbul circulates
Is not it?
Yes, it happens.
No delay?
If, of course,
half an hour to one hour.
- Half an hour, an hour late?
- That's it.
- Sure it happens?
- Yes, there is no reason.
Okay, thank you.
- The train arrives with a delay ...
- I heard.
Your luggage is there.
I may be back to the hotel.
If they need me ...
- I stay or should I stay?
- How?
If they need me at the hotel ...
I stay or should I stay there with you?
Rest.
Will you let me instead?
There is an air flow there.
We are together.
You can shift you?
Simply put you there.
And the road to go to Suavi?
- At the farm?
- Yes.
It's far, Mr. Aydin.
That's not my question.
It practicable?
No, Mr. Aydin.
It would take the village road,
can not.
Very well, then, let's go.
What a blast!
Exprerience,
I came to visit you.
You did well.
Come in, it's best.
Come in, come.
- Thank you.
- This way.
- Sit down, warm up.
- Thank you.
I expect Levent.
I thought it was him that sounded.
But with him, you never know.
It is capable of not coming.
See you all Saturday afternoon.
On Sunday morning, we go hunting.
Two old bachelors, what.
We support each other.
Suavi, I can extend my leg?
- I beg you.
- I have a cramp.
Put the above, go ahead.
You're good here.
It's beautiful, warm,
comfortable sofas ...
You must be cold.
I have something for you.
One gulp, and forget the cold.
You tell me the news.
This is what we take for hunting.
One puts in our flanges.
There, the cold does not laugh.
The teacher is young,
strong as an ox.
But me, I need fuel.
I think I'll avoid.
I do not usually.
You have a lime or sage?
You will take in your home.
Here is me, the leader.
Well, okay. Thank you.
This is my new guilty pleasure.
We deserve that, at our age.
I'm warmed up.
Thank you.
It heats well, this stove.
I will not heat everywhere.
Since the death of my wife,
I closed parts
I use to store.
I installed the stove here.
It became my refuge
I just curl up.
And I save, suddenly.
By the way, what did you do
for the letter?
What letter?
The one you read Nihal and me.
Daughter Garip
who wanted to help.
I did nothing.
This is our teacher!
Mr. Aydin, nice to see you!
Thank you, Levent.
- Do not get up.
- I am numb leg.
As long as it's just that ...
Hello.
We went in the corner,
we visited him.
Very well.
The roads are difficult?
Terrible.
I had a lot to come to harm.
Mr. Aydin, I'll wait outside.
OK.
- Hidayet ...
- Yes, Mr. Aydin.
Come here.
Forgiveness.
listen
do not tell anyone at home
I'm there.
Of course not.
What do I tell them?
Nothing.
But if asked?
You invent. No one must know
I did not go.
- OK.
- I trust you.
I was very happy
to meet you, the last time,
but you disappeared.
Thank you. Yes, I had an unexpected.
I had to sneak out.
I have better luck today.
- This is for you.
- Thank you.
Wood, it will put you back
the ideas in place.
Hello? What's new?
Listen ...
do not tell Ms. Nihal
or anyone,
but we are at Suavi, on the farm.
There is no party.
He changed his mind.
I know, me.
You want to ask him?
But why I lie?
You're crazy?
How you say?
Do not start again, Fatma.
I'm trying to peel me out.
You delusions or what?
Come on ...
When I was little,
I was playing in the garden here
and I felt that this life
my parents would last indefinitely.
Where is this?
When is this house
was emptied?
When do
the little boy his mother
became the lonely old drunkard?
I got married.
I had a child.
Where are they?
My wife underground,
my daughter at the end of the world.
That's why I say:
Since there are things
we can not change,
you have to be a little flexible.
Do not judge people.
Accept things as they are.
It's hot, right?
You can open a little?
Of course, opens the window.
We too will thereby Levent?
OK.
- Go ahead, I'll get something.
- OK.
It's hot, I'm a little drunk ...
I feel dizzy.
I would not have had to drink.
Too late.
Tell me, Levent, how old are you?
35.
- You do not!
- But if.
You have a family?
My family is in Yozgat, home.
My mother and my older sister.
You did not get married?
Say ...
it is fate.
It did not.
I have not met the right person.
And I do not really have the means.
I'm in no hurry.
To live here,
your salary widely enough.
That is true.
But I send half to my mother,
that sets aside for my sister.
It is a priority for the wedding.
For me, we'll see later.
It's how long you're there?
This is my fourth year.
You gonna stay?
I could go, but you get used to.
And then there is the work
with Nihal.
I can not leave him.
This is not a problem, that.
There will always be someone
to replace you.
Of course, you're right.
When I was little, I stuttered.
- Really?
- Yes.
I spent my childhood in silent.
That's why I talk too much,
now.
So, sorry if I knock you down.
We must tell me.
But no, talk all you want.
You totally deserved it, my friend.
Anyway, I prefer to listen.
I have warned you.
Hot chestnuts!
Cursed be that do not taste.
Hot to hot.
We used split chestnuts!
Yes?
Good Evening.
Sorry to bother you.
I just see Hamdi Hodja.
Is he here?
A moment.
Ms. Nihal?
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
Sorry, I was inside,
I could not ...
What can I do for you?
It is I who apologize
to come so late.
No, please.
Come in.
It's not too late?
No, of course.
Come in, please.
- Thank you.
- Do not stay in the cold.
Thank you.
Go sit by the stove.
This is fine here, thank you.
It's cold near the door.
Keep your shoes.
Thank you. I will not stay long.
As you like.
All is well, I hope, Ms. Nihal?
Excuse me, but to see you alone ...
I wanted to know how was Ilyas.
It worried us the other day.
We got the news,
but I wanted to visit.
Ilyas is much better.
Thank God, he has no fever.
It goes very well.
We were worried,
but yesterday he opened his eyes.
It is a little bored at home,
as he missed school.
But it is well, thank you God.
It is not easy.
I was concerned to learn
it was pneumonia.
But his mother had to take care of him.
He has taken his medication
and it is healed, big boy.
That's it.
Thank you.
Mr. Aydin is not with you?
No, I came alone.
Really? Welcome.
You must be cold. It freezes.
It was tea ... Sevda!
I go to the kitchen.
- Do not bother.
- I beg you.
You work?
Is that it?
Yes.
- What is it?
- Some math.
Do you like math?
Yes.
You want to do what? Engineer?
Not.
What, then?
Policeman.
Why?
Good evening, madam.
Good Evening. Who are you?
Mom, Mrs. Nihal,
the wife of our owner.
She reports on TV?
No, Mom.
That's another story, that.
Come on, Mom.
I watched the imam. I want my TV.
Ms. Nihal did not come for that.
She comes to visit Ilyas.
- You knees hurt?
- Very.
- Must cover.
- I do not want.
OK.
You do not take me to the doctor.
Do not embarrass us
before Ms. Nihal, Mom.
- You do not want to go.
- There were too many people.
I will not go there.
I want a private doctor.
But anyway ...
I offered to take you there.
In our cousin Samet ...
You forget what his mother did to me?
His mother is his mother.
Him, he's a doctor.
I want a doctor
come here.
Okay, I will bring one.
He will take care
my mother's home.
Sevda, bring me my rosary.
I'm sorry.
I beg you.
Young, we are taught respect,
later, compassion.
God bless our seniors.
If youth knew,
if old age could ...
I do not want
bother you long.
I would like to talk to you.
I beg you.
Will you be it in private?
Sure, why not?
You can go next door
but it might get cold.
This is not serious.
Let's go. Sevda!
Put wood in the fireplace.
I take your tea.
- Thank you.
- I beg you.
You have how many pieces?
There were two.
Thereof was added.
Courtesy
Your father-in late, Mr. Sami.
We have three rooms now.
This is my room.
It's colder there.
It was a fireplace.
I turn it on when the winter is harsh.
Fortunately, not this year.
That is true.
Hamdi, I would
ask you something.
I beg you.
Your younger brother, Ismail ...
- My older brother ...
- Oh, sorry.
What does he do for a living?
He did more work.
Before, he was in the mine, Tozlu.
But unfortunately,
He got into trouble.
It has been six months in prison.
Since he is unemployed.
If I may ...
why he was in prison?
What has he done?
It's really embarrassing for me.
I do not want
you see us like this.
But I will not hide
God already knows.
The noise had to run, anyway.
There were thugs
harassing his wife Sevda.
We only learned later.
One night, we heard Ismail
who had risen to great sound.
He ran after the guy down the street.
I am ashamed to say ...
They came to steal underwear
Sevda of the string.
He could not catch them.
He lashed out at Sevda that night.
The poor man was not even
report.
The next day at the market,
crossing Ismail,
these thugs mocked him.
Ismail took out his knife
and injured one.
It took six months for that.
It has always been a bit wild.
Not one to be approached.
From prison
it is even more wary and shy.
He does not talk to anybody in the village.
He got fired.
He shut and began to drink.
But not at home.
He does not work.
We had to pay for the operation
and allowances for the guy.
There has been much indebted.
As we only have my salary,
it is difficult.
We could not pay the rent.
I understand Mr. Aydin.
Trouble we created him
with these months in arrears.
But I hope to find
a second job.
I understand.
I hope it will work out.
Exactly, my visit
has to do with that.
I do not want to keep you,
It's late.
Take that and accept it.
What is it?
Open.
Do not get me wrong.
I want to give you this money.
Take it, please.
Yes, but I do not understand.
Why this money?
Why you give us?
Do not worry.
I do not want anything in return,
or that you reimburse me.
Accept it as a friendly support.
I'm sorry, Ms. Nihal.
I do not know what to say.
This is a large sum.
How can I accept it?
There are almost
enough to buy a house.
- What will people say?
- Mr. Hamdi ...
No one will know.
It will stay between you and me.
Welcome.
Thank you.
- Sorry to bother you so late.
- I beg you.
Ismail, Mrs. Nihal,
the wife of Mr. Aydin.
I know, it warned me.
What happen?
Come sit.
Come on.
Ms. Nihal was worried
for Ilyas.
She came to visit him.
It's there for.
And that?
Ms. Nihal brought us the money.
It's very nice.
What's the occasion?
Do not get me wrong.
There is no specific reason.
I thought you needed it.
You might get your things.
Mr. Aydin, what he said?
It is not know.
And he did not know.
Very well.
But all that money ...
it's not too much?
It corresponds to what?
What you thought
bringing us so much money?
- I have not thought of.
- Excuse him.
We are sorry. It is a little surprised.
Ismail, you do not want
you put water on your face?
No, it's okay.
I'll get you some coffee, then.
It will do you good.
Ms. Nihal, I bring you another tea.
It is cool.
- Do not bother.
- Yes, yes.
Sevda ...
So ...
let's see ...
if the account is good.
That it must be for ...
the small Ilyas who risked his life
to save the wounded pride of his father.
And this ...
for selflessness brother Hamdi
who went to kneel apologetically
to have four mouths to feed.
This ...
for Ismail dad drunk
who was beaten up in front of her son
and the shame of his family.
But it still remains.
That's our heroine,
Ms. Nihal
that relieves his conscience
giving alms
to those who are less fortunate than her.
So the account is good.
You have calculated.
It's really nice of you.
But what you remember,
Ms. Nihal,
is that you have in front of you
dirty drunkard unable to appreciate
your generosity.
When I see all that,
I look ...
I say, it's not a life we have,
this is a bad room.
It is a kind of life!
- That's right.
- I am not mistaken?
You're right.
We must stand up.
Straight, upright.
Stiff as stakes.
And say, "Go, go, hits!
Hit me if you want. "
Standing, like real men.
We will not yield, we will not whine.
Stand up!
It's like that, Mr. Aydin.
Today, our moral values
come religions,
many reject and deny,
all around the world.
If I am against these values, why
I still base my life on it?
In this case,
it is completely bogus, my life.
So either we need to strengthen
the basis of these values,
either have to create new ones.
Suavi, brother,
must be created.
- It's good if you can create them.
- Yes, but listen ...
We try to live better,
but there are not that miss you,
you looking mess.
So when you cross their path,
it's frictions, inevitably.
But those who are strong, innovative,
they go forward, they do not care.
Oddly, the conflict, it feeds them.
They are flexible enough to accept it.
The conflict, it opens their mind,
it nourishes creativity.
When I see them,
I think they do not care critics
because they are brave.
We should do the same.
Of course, one could say:
"You drink like holes,
you empiffrez you
"and after, you want to help
poor school. "
But we must not listen to them,
we must move forward.
For example, during the earthquake,
there are six,
when you have not opened
Hotel victims
but relief,
to make you money ...
This is what some have thought.
It's interesting what he says.
They even blame you
to be rich.
- It is possible.
- Wait ...
One second, please.
What's the connection?
How did you come by that?
I give an example.
You insinuating something here?
If we did not welcome the victims
there was reason ...
What's insinuations,
without knowing anything about the story?
Hundreds of people landed
from abroad, it was necessary to put where?
Could accommodate where?
These people trapped under the rubble,
which would have left?
- I said nothing.
- Nobody thinks that.
I gave an example.
Frankly, I'm surprised you,
this kind of judgment, Bulent.
- I do not judge.
- That's not good.
I may have misspoken.
I meant ...
- You evil words, Levent.
- But no.
There is truth in what you said,
but you've misspoken.
I'm just saying that there are people
like this ...
What to do with me and my hotel?
I'm just saying
people can say ...
More ... wait ...
This is exactly what I say.
I can not stop making donations
years.
Bravo, but I not talking about that.
Just yesterday,
I gave a large sum
for fundraising.
Besides, I have always done
anonymously discretion.
- That's right.
- Well Done.
But I did not say otherwise.
He misspoke.
I continue to stuff me
this kind of innuendo
and sarcasm,
Just because we have a little money?
I wanted to say:
There are people like that
and I fuck!
I too Fuck them.
But it is not possible to judge
without knowing the situation.
I misspoke.
A bit of morality and conscience,
Please!
Come on, my boy,
Tell him your misspoke.
It has nothing, is absurd.
That's not what he meant.
What is morality and conscience
come to that?
I can not tolerate
this kind of judgment.
If you attack him personally ...
Listen, I closed
for fifteen years.
My words beyond my thought.
I should have shut up.
It is normal that I do attack
because I have the money?
It was I who invented the world?
This is the system!
God created it that way.
What can I do about myself?
In nature either,
there is no justice.
Here as elsewhere.
- I mean those who ...
- I have nothing to do.
I wanted to say the same thing,
and you leave me
morality and conscience.
- I had trouble expressing myself.
- He would not ...
He thought not bad.
You let yourself go, little one.
But you said things well, too.
Must first think.
- That's right.
- We can not ...
I ... whatever.
We ate well, drank well.
I'll go to bed.
I have not slept in two days.
Come, my boy,
I'll give you a blanket.
Thank you, my friend.
The pochtron will stop
to break your ears.
I'll shut up,
but before leaving,
under your control,
dear Mr. Aydin ...
I beg you.
I will quote Shakespeare,
in conclusion.
"Consciousness ...
"is just a word to the use of loose
"invented first
to keep the strong in awe.
"That our strong arms
be our conscience,
"our swords our law."
Good night.
Minute.
Allow me then to contribute
this evening with these words,
in reply:
"Our relentless fate
"is the disillusionment
in all our businesses.
"Every morning
I conceive of brilliant projects
"I spend my day to wander."
That's it.
You shoot at you well again.
It's okay?
It's nothing, relax.
- Let yourself go.
- Sorry.
- It's nothing.
- I'm sorry.
Look at this mess.
It's nothing, leave it, come on.
- I'm sorry.
- Stepping Out.
Come take a good breath of fresh air
in the snow, it'll do you good.
Come, my friend, come.
Come on, do not force.
Come on.
- I'm sorry.
- Stepping Out.
Follow me.
So far we advance and that's it.
It must be light,
it does not sink.
- Hidayet, stop.
- What up?
Pull over.
I'm afraid
we can not leave.
- Back off a little.
- What?
Make a reverse.
Stop.
Mr. Aydin?
Nothing, that's good, let's go.
Fatma!
Nihal ...
I do not party.
I could not.
I become old or crazy,
and then another man?
No matter what you'll think.
I do not know.
But this new man in me holding me back.
You either do not hunt me.
I know now
nothing'm in Istanbul.
Everything is foreign to me,
there as elsewhere.
Know that I have no one else
than you.
I miss you every minute,
at every moment.
I will never confess to you,
my pride stop me.
I know it would be terrible,
if not impossible for me,
to separate me from you.
Just as I know
than you love me.
I know our past
will not return.
I do not regret it.
Take me as a servant,
as a slave.
Continue our life together,
even in your own way.
Forgive me.
"History of Turkish theater"
artistic Director
Director of photography
mounting
scenario
Inspired by the new Anton Chekhov
Co-producers
National co-producers
executive producer
producer
director