-Hello
Documents Please
Yes
Can I ask you a question?
This ticket was actually paid by a company
Do you know if you can place the miles
Under my name?
No. This ticket doesn't include miles
Oh, well. In that case I won't ask anything
They are already boarding through gate 3
Thanks
I'll help you
All right
Work or pleasure?
Both things, I hope
What do you do?
I'm a model
Excuse me, I should've imagined
Thanks
Fashion show or advertisement
Fashion Show
You?
-What do you do?
-You killed me there
Why?
That "you" dropped me to the 5th level of hell
I will need to fix myself right up from this
I'm a music critic
It sounds horrible, I know
No. Rock?
Now you want to fix it?
Classical music
My first boyfriend was a classical musician
In fact he studied classical music
What's his name?
No, he is not known
He tried to present some works when we
were together
But as far as I know he never published
Or edited...No... How do you say it?
You choose the term you want and I'll install it
in the artistic community
Pasternak. Gabriel Pasternak
Pasternak
Knowing this I would've told you I'm grave digger and not a critic
He presented his thesis in the contest of the conservatory
when I was a the president of the jury
I kicked him out of it
Yes, I was with him at the time
It was tremendous what they did to him
He passed a week in bed after reading the critic
Sometimes it's like that. I have to hurt a poor devil's self esteem
In order to protect the ears of a whole population
Eventually I can make mistakes, but in this case this was a...
An unpresentable abomination
Do you still see him?
No, we didn't end up very well
I still care for him, though
He wasn't a bad person
I don't know that, but to present something like that in a contest
Some problem he has to have
Gabriel Pasternak, how can I forget him
We all laughed at it for months
Sorry I interrupt you but
I was eavsdropping the conversation
I can't believe so much coincidence
I was the teacher of Gabriel Pasternak in the school #7 of Palomar
I had the difficult task of informing him that he was repeating the year
I can testify that the kid had problems
In thirty years of teaching I've never saw something like it
He screamed and cried like a newborn baby
-Mrs. Leguizamón?
-Yes
I'm Ignacio Fontana. Do you remember me?
Ignacio Fontana. This is incredible
There's a cosmic connection here
-Wasn't pasternak your classmate?
-Yes
-Are you friends?
-Oh yes, best friends
Poor dude. We used to bully him a lot
This is more than incredible
I was a Home Depot manager, where this fellow that you speak of
worked for a while
Since he always had a problem with his clients I had to fire him
-When I...
-Sorry, someone else knows Gabriel Pasternak?
-Yes
-I know him
-I do
Why are you in this flight? Did you buy the tickets?
No
I worked for real estate and they sent me to see some farms for sale
In my job they made an appointment for me to go see the
secretary of tourism
I won it at a raffle, they said I couldn't change the date
I either flew today or nothing
Gabriel Pasternak is the captain of this flight
We trained together. We were friends, but when he invited me out
and I said no and he started to...
It doesn't matter now. After we took off I gave him coffee...
The door is locked. The pilots are not answering.
I'm desperate, I don't know what to do
I cheated on him with his only friend
With him
Gabriel! Are you there?
I'm Victor Llensen, speak to me please!
-Who are you
-I was his psychiatrist for years
At some point I augmented his session time.
He got angry and he never came back
Gabriel, listen to me
You don't have to blame yourself for anything
You are the victim of this situation
I'm saying it plain and simple. The ones who ruined your life
were your parents
Since you were born they've been asking you for too much
The placed on you all their frustration.
They are the responsibles of your suffering
All of us here, Gabriel, don't have anything to do with this
Good evening, a table for one?
I see you're good at math
One, yes
Sit wherever you want
The special for today is lentils with rice
Sounds delicious
So?
Hey
That guy is from my town
An usurper
A corrupt politician
He auctioned our house
And because of him my dad committed suicide
Two weeks after the burial
He tried to hit on my mom
He stalked her so much
That we had to move here
Do you know for how long I've dreamed to have him like this?
In front of me
I will have to and say something to him
Say something to him?
Thanks to that guy your father committed suicide
And the only thing you plan to do is to insult him?
Why don't we put rat poison in his food?
There's in the back
A good dosis and in five minutes his heart will explode
A lot of work today?
Not with this rain
I'm asking because I've been calling you for a while
You have to look over here, darling
My apologies
Do you know what are you going to order?
Bring my fries with eggs
If I'm still hungry I will ask for something else
Any beverages?
Diet Coke
Diet Coke?
Diet
Coke
Fries. With eggs
Do you want me to write it for you?
I hate him. I hate him
Make him some fries with eggs
[RAT POISON]
Are you crazy?
Do you want me to go to jail?
Jail?
Do you believe the FBI is going to make an autopsy
on that prick?
Fires with eggs
They are going to think that it was the cholesterol
Can you make him the fries with eggs?
Can I ask for your opinion on something?
Since you seem to be an atentive girl. Come here
Which one do you like. This one?
Or this one?
I'll choose the red one
The red one. Wait. Wait.
Do you think I look too serious in this picture?
No, I think it looks fine
Thank you
Besides jail is not that bad
It just has bad publicity
They give you food
You don't pay rent
You live with no worries
And if you have good group
you'll have a lot of fun
You play bridge
You were in jail?
For some time
And I can assure I felt more free there
This is a shithole
And wht did you do?
Nothing that I regret
Besides he is going to run for mayor
That son of a bitch. Can you believe it?
How am I not going to believe it when those bastards
rule the world
Wake up, girl!
What do you say
Do we make a favor for the community?
Perfect
You put the rat posion!
Don't play like a naive girl. Tell me you
didn't noticed it
That's how this country runs
Everybody wants give this characters what they deserve
but nobody wants to move a finger
Feel proud about it, girl
For once in your miserable life you are
doing something worthy
Hey! I'm not doing anything here
No? You keep discussing with me instead of taking away his plate?
Calm down. You don't have to worry about anything
In the investigation I'm going to say that this morning
I was placing poison in the kitchen
Because everything was full of bugs, which on the other hand
it is completely true
And that coincidentally a little rock got inside a pan.
What are they going to tell me
This is madness
Hey, this shit wasn't expired, right?
It doesn't say the expiring date
How was it?
When a poison is expired
Is it more or less deadly
-Everything fine?
-Yes
Sit right there
What will you drink, Alexis
I don't know. A Fanta?
-What if I got heat these up a little?
-No, no, leave it there
If i need you to heat them up I'll ask you
Could you bring him a Fanta, please?
I'm fed up with this girl
We have to do something, both are eating now
Do we put more posion?
He's a kid!
But he is going to grow. Like father like son
It's better if we finish with all the weed right now
Hey, I don't think I'm feeling right
What is happening to you?
Are you ok?
-Excuse me, this has to be freezing by now
-No, leave it there!
Who the fuck taught you to work like these
Could you let people eat in peace?
Will you look at these fucking bitch
Wait, dad
Now you are going to pick them all up
You are going to pick them up
-Isabel, call the ambulance!
-One by one!
Take this!
Here you go!
I'm going to butcher your liver like a chicken
Come on. Move, moron
What's up with you, dude?
What a shameless douchbag
You're a motherfucking wetbag
Jerk!
Mother, give me patience
I can't believe it
Hello, I'm here around the 60th km
Of the route the connects Salta with Buenos Aires
Yes, U-I-A 7-1-9
Diego Iturralde
Very good.
I was telling you that I got a flat tire around
the 60th km
Of the route that connects Salta to Buenos Aires,
with Cafayate
And I wanted to know how long will you guys take
to come here because
The car is new and I'm not that good with the jack
What happened?
Did you get scared?
Come on, man, keep going
Come on. Go on
Please, I don't want to fight
If I offended you, forgive me
I'm sorry if I offended you
Well
Happy?
Are you done?
Wacth out with the...
What are you doing? Stop!
Come on, man, I didn't do anything to you
Why don't you shout me again what you said before.
How did it go?
Oh God
My god
I already told you I'm sorry, I don't know what else
do you want me todo
If I get to get off the car I will, but I think
it's unnecesary
Motherfu... Stop!
Motherfucker
Good afternoon, officer.
I'm around the 60th km of the route that connects Salta
to Buenos Aires with Cafayate
There is an individual who is attacking me
It is armored, you'll not be able to break it!
Fag!
The license plate of the man is.
I cannot see it, but could you bring a police car right now?
Perfect
Hurry up. This man is out of control
I'm sure they'll be coming now
Well, stop now, man. Please!
You destroyed my car! Go away!
What are you doing?!
Fucking shit. This motherfucker
No, motherfucker. Fuck your mother, asshole!
No! Motherfucker! Asshole!
Please. Please!
Fuck
Faggot!
What are you doing?!
Asshole!
You're dead!
I know your license plate, asshole!
Did you hear me?
I know your license plate, U-I-A!
I'm going to search you and I'm going to kill you!
Recalculating
Base. This is unit 29. Can you confirm the km, please?
Attention, base. Attention
What hypothesis do you have, detective
Crime of passion?
How is everything outside?
Everything is ready, Simón
Thanks
Let's go
Attention, we are going to detonate
Five, Four, Three
Two
[RESTRICTED AREA]
There, thank you
Sign here
Yes, honey.
No, I'm going to go to my office to check the voicemail
and then I'll leave
I'm going to be there at 5 with the cake.
Don't worry
At 5 I'm there with the cake. Don't worry,
I'll not forget it
I hope you like how it looks
Yes, she's going to love it. Thank you
It will be 360
Was it imported?
One, two... Can you give me a bill?
Yes, we have croissants, "vigilantes"
The ticket. Bill
Oh! yes, of course. I'll bring it
They had to be a bunch of douchebags
[SMILE, WE ARE FILMING YOU]
Next!
Hello
Look, I parked my car...
Your license, please
Yes
Talk to me nicely, please
I'm talking to you nicely, sir
More or less
The towing service will be 430 pesos and you we will
send the fine to your address
Yes, but you're not listening to what I want to explain
The sidewalk was completely unpainted
There was no possible way that I could know that the place
was a no-parking area
I understand
I see. Now, if you want to retreive the vehicle from here
You will have to pay the towing service. Ok?
Later, if you want you can make a withdrawal from monday to friday,
from eight to fourteen hours
In the address Carlos Pellegrini 211, first floor
Hmm. No. Do you know what we are going to do?
I'm going to ask you to go and talk to whoever you have to
I want to take my car without paying a penny
I want you to give me what I paid
for the taxi to get here and
And that you give my respective apologies
What are you laughing about, I'm being serious
Where is the office where they give you your apologies
when they make a mistake?
We are all in the same boat, sir. Hurry up, please
Look. The ticket said your car
was in a no-parking zone
We don't need more proof than that.
I'll repeat again
If you want to take your car you have to pay
If that's not the case I'll ask you to leave
and let me continue working
And if I don't have cash?
You can pay it with credit, debit,
or you can come another day.
However, we will charge you for the car
parked here
Did you know that you're a criminal?
-I'm doing my jobe here
-No
The ones who work for criminals are
other criminals
Well, it's a way of looking at it
Miserable public worker
Of this corrupt system
Thank you, have a nice day
We were with you when you were born
When you received your first toys
[I'M ARRIVING]
[DON'T COME, ALMOST EVERYBODY LEFT]
Happy Birthday to you. Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday dear Camila.
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday, honey
Tell them to sing again
Don't even talk to me, Simón
Hello, darling. Happy Birthday
Hello kids
How are you, Antonio
Hello, dear! Everything's good
-Hello. How are you
-We were leaving
Wait, I'll come with you
Couldn't you take a taxi and take the car later?
-No! No!
-You missed your daughter's brithday, Simón
Everything is so easy for you.
I'm just tired of people taking my money
The sidewalk was absolutely unpainted!
Do you have any idea of the anger this produces on me?
Do you have any idea of the anger this produces on me
that you always blame everything?
That you have to blame society for everything
Today it was the car. Yesterday it was the traffic.
Tomorrow will be the protest
The truth is that you were perfectly capable
of leaving earlier
You could've helped me organize the party
And you would be ready to receive your daughter's guests
But no. Everything is a priority except
your family
-No
-And I am standing here like an idiot
Thinking that you'll change
And you know what?
Society will not change
You will not change
And I am tired of it
What does that mean?
The engineer here is you.
Make the math
The goverment lets a private company
make money for nothing
Obviously in exchange for a payment that
we all have to choose
It's indignant, but it'ss like that
And you have two choices
You either pay and work a little
Or your heart explodes due to stress
And you know what, man
I have a lot of reasons to live
I want to sail.
Travel the world with my grandchildren
Don't get angry
-Hello. Good morning
-Good morning
They filed this fine, and I already payed
the towing service. But there's an error
-Because the sidewalk was unpainted...
-Would you let me see?
Yes
It is 560 pesos
Look. I'm a little nervous here
So I'll ask you to listen to me
The sidewalk was unpainted. I think you should
send someone to the address where they took my car
In order to verify that I'm right
Then, ask the city's government to
forgive me, because I'm right
Give me back the money I paid.
AND pay me for all the time I've been wasting
The ticket says that the car was
in a no-parking zone
And that is considered enough proof
The fine is 560 pesos that you HAVE to pay
If you don't pay we will start charging interests
Are you listening to me?
Enough proof? Fuck off.
I'm telling you
the curb was not painted yellow
First, I'm going to ask you
to stop insulting me
Because I'm working here
Second, you should inform yourself
of how the law works
The fact that you don't know the laws
does not excempt you from braking them
Tomorrow you kill somebody and say
"I didn't know you couldn't do that"
You'll go to jail
That's fine, maybe nobody explained it to you
But you still go to jail.
Is it understandable?
This example that you just gave wasn't
very accurate
With that criteria I should know by heart
the streets where I can park and the ones where I can't
Without taking in account whether they are painted or not
Exactly. The information is available in the website
of the Department of Mobile Vehicles
Ok. I need to talk with your manager, please
No, there's no manager to call
No?
Who do you think you are?
The president of the country, moron?
Sir, there's a lot of people
If you don't want to pay I'll ask you to let me work
What does it feel like to be a criminal?
Come on, tell me
Security in station seven
Are you calling for security? Great!
I am making a claim. I am defending as a citizen
and I'm a criminal
You have to be behind there
and call for security
Do you want to call security?
Call security! Call it!
Now call for security!
Leave me!
Sign here, please
-My god
-How are you doing
They didn't rape you, right?
It's unbelievable.
Really unbelievable
What a madness
Seijas sent a lawyer from the company
and told him to be in charge of everything
I hope he plays it good because lately...
Yeah, more or less.
Your name and last name appear there
[VIOLENT REACTION IN THE DMV]
They mention that you work for the firm
Seija's partners didn't like the shit you pulled
The city's government is one of our main clients!
They are going to cut you off, Simón
It has been decided
I understand that at this moment you don't have a job, Mr. Fischer
Yes. Why you ask?
Is it a crime?
I didn't say it was a crime, right?
Right. But I think I perceived certain condemning tone
It is not a crime, but it's a problem at the time
to be pay the living of your wife
The lawyer is talking about the living expenses of Camila
that includes clothes, school...
Excuse me
I've been in charge of the yearly expenses of my wife
since I know her
And my daughter will not be missing anything
If I have a problem, don't worry because I'll fix it
Luckily Ms. Malamut DOES have a job at the moment
So we don't see the necesitty of granting Mr. Fischer
the shared expenses
I'm sorry. Excuse me
I've been in charge of everything for years
And for a month where she has a job and I don't
I don't have the right to share the expenses of my daughter?
I hope the judge will take into account
how unfair this situation is
What the judge won't take into account is the violence
that you are using with your wife
WHAT violence?!
I'm describing a situation.
Where do you see the violence?
I see violence, Mr. Fischer.
In a lot of places
I see violence in the street.
I see violence when the TV is on
Without going very far. I can see it
in an article of this newspaper
And I'm convinced that the less contact a small kid
can have with this type of episodes
It would be better for its psychophysical integrity
Victoria
Do you want to take away my daughter?
No, it's not that
Then what is it?! Are you going nuts?
All right. My client and I will end the mediation
And we will mantain silence until we see each other in Tribunales
You're not planning to say anything?
Who hired you. Her?
Mr. Fischer, calm down. Please
-Hello
-Good evening
I'm Simón Fischer
I spoke with Mr. Ederer's secretary
-I'm supposed to leave my resume
-Sure, I'll give it to her
I'd rather give it to her personally..
and if Mr. Ederer's here,
I'd like to have a word with him
I worked for over ten years...
at Seijas Raffo Martinez and Associates
I'm not a rookie
The engineer is on a construction site
-And his secretary?
-She's out for lunch
It's 4 pm
I don't handle her schedule
You know what?
I won't leave you a damn thing
You can all go fuck yourselves:
you, Ederer and his secretary
Especially his secretary.
Everybody can go fuck themselves!
Lunch at 4 pm?
They must think I'm an idiot!
The blue Chevrolet?
You are being rude, and this is completely fascist
-I have to pay first and discuss later
-Exactly
Until a tragedy happens you will not stop
[IT WAS A TERRORIST ATTACK]
[THE DEFENSE PROCLAIMS THAT
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT]
[THE ENGINEER WAS WORKING WITH EXPLOSIVES.
THE MOVEMENT OF THE CAR CAUSED THE EXPLOSION]
[THE ATTORNEY ANSWERS
"THE FACT THAT HERE ARE NO DEATHS PROVES
THAT THE ENGINEER CALCULATED THE RADIUS OF EXPLOTION]
[IT'S THE FOURTH TIME THEY TAKE MY CAR!!!
#HelpMeBombita (Little Bomb)]
[PLEASE #BOMBITA: BLOW UP THE
MINISTRY OF ECONOMY]
[INSURANCE COMPANY DOESN'T WANT TO PAY]
[THE FAULT IS FROM THE TOWING COMPANY
FOR NOT STOPPING THIS TYPE OF ACCIDENTS]
[THEY ARE QUESTIONING THE LEGITIMACY
OF THE TOWING COMPANY'S CONTRACT]
[IN SOCIAL MEDIA, THOUSANDS OF USERS ASK FOR
THE LIBERATION OF THE ENGINEER POPULARLY CALLED "BOMBITA"]
[#BOMBITAFREE]
Happy Birthday to you!
Happy Birthday Bombita!
Happy Birthday to you
Dad
What happened?
What happened, Santiago
Speak!
Promise me they will not send him to jail
We are going to make everything that's possible
It happened moments ago in the Libertador Avenue
A driver ran over a pregnant lady and ran away
He didn't stop to help the victim
Santiago, tell me the truth
What did you drink.
Did you smoke weed?
The car was not able to be identified
At this moment the police is analyzing
the security cameras
A hit and run. Another sad moment done by an
assassin in the north area of Buenos Aires
Under what name is the car
-Mine
-And the adress under the car?
This one
What di I do, what did I do
What did you do?
You ruined our lives, asshole!
-Help him, Mauricio!
-Take her away
Santiago, listen to me.
I need you to answer some questions
Did you have any passengers?
-Did you tell anybody about it?
-No
Let's go see the car
It has tinted windows
Do you remember if you had your windows up?
-I think so
-Please remember
Yes, yes I had them up
Did you went out to see what happened?
Or was it a hit and run?
Hit and run
And where were you coming from?
From a bar, downtown
Did anybody saw you come here with the car?
Friends, or any girls?
I don't know, I can't remember
We were just informed that the woman and the baby
died on their way to the hospital
The police is still finding evidence
And also asking different witnesses...
-Thanks a lot, Mrs.
-Please
I'm really embarassed
to propose this to you,
But we've known you for years
And I feel we have this
kind of a bond
Besides you are a father,
and you want the best for your family
So I think that an arrangement
like this one will help you
If you say that you took the car last night
while we were sleeping
And that you drove during the accident
I will place the best lawyer that will
get you out of jail as quickly as possible
With good conduct you're out in less than
year and a half
-Does it work that way?
-It does
And for that incredible favor
I'll offer you 500,000 dollars
You will never win that amount
of money with your job
You will be able to provide good education
and well-being to your family for the rest of your life
You know Santiago.
He would not survive in a jail
José, sit in the car please
Grab the steering wheel with both hands
Touch it as much as you can
Good
You drank a glass of whisky and your boss
was sleeping
When you came to park the car like every night
You felt the need to go drive outside
If they were going to ask you about it,
what are you going to say
That you just went to check the tires
Suddenly something crossed your path
You felt a bump and from then on
you don't remember anything
Yes
José, I can't explain how
grateful I am with you
No, don't touch each other. Please.
It's fine, Mrs.
Excuse me
I'm thinking that... I don't know
I would like to talk it out with my wife
No. She can't know this, José.
At least for now
We can't run the risk if she talks
And if she talks, the arrangement we did
finishes and you still go to jail
For lying
My darling
You two take my SUV and go to the ranch
When you pass the tollbooth look down,
and don't stop at any gas station
And if you want to buy something
pay only in cash
Santiago, let's go
Let's go
José, sit again in the car
He sits in the back
Move the sit forward
You two go to your room and go to bed
Nobody knows anything about this
Calm down and be quiet
I'm in charge of this
Mauricio Pereyra Hamilton?
I'm his lawyer
I was about to call the police.
Please, come in
What a horrible tragedy
About an hour ago my client heard something
in the first floor
He thought that burglars were trying to get in
When he goes down to see what happened
He finds the housekeeper
Sitting in his car, drunk and in shock
Then he heard what happened in the news,
he connected everything and then he called me
Mauricio Pereyra. This is the attorney
in charge of the case
-Good morning
And the gentlman here is José
-Hello
-He has worked for the family for...
-...15 years?
-Yes
...The husband of the victim.
Sir, what's your reaction about this?
What's my reaction about this?
How am I supposed to react
Turn it off, it's unnecesary
...I'm only going to say one thing
Whoever was it is going to pay for this
Can you hear me? It doesn't matter
where you hide
I'm going to fi...
What happened, José?
Excuse me. José. I want to remind you
that you can stay in silence
I'm going to represent Mr. Torres
by request of my client
There has never been a problem
and he is the father of two sons
Could you tell me the story of the accident?
Yes, well...
I always park the car of Mr. Mauricio
And for a while I always wanted
to take the new car for a ride
Run it a little, you know? The BMW
And last night
I drank a little, to be honest
And...well. I felt excited so I went out
I never imagined that something wrong could happen
And I was going down Libertador Avenue, and..
And I was going a little fast, to be honest...
...Very fast
And suddenly something crossed my path.
I couldn't see what was it
I though it was a dog
I felt a very hard bump
And I got scared because I thought
I ruined Mr. Mauricio's car
And I wanted to come back fast
so I could fix it before Mr. Mauricio woke up
Excuse me
José, would you be kind enough to sit
in the front seat?
-Do I touch it?
-Yes, grab the steering wheel
Sit back, please
-Could yo close the door?
-Sure
José. Do you ever use the rearview mirrors?
Rearview mirrors? Of course!
How am I not going to?
Because in that position you can
only look at the ceiling
It's a miracle that you only ran over
one person
May be they moved with the bump
All of them at once?
Yeah, you may be right
I would say that his car was drived
by someone taller than you
Who else lives in this house?
Yes. My wife and son... The dog
Let the dog sleep
I'd like to meet your wife and son
Of course! I'll let them know that you
want to see them
Do you give me permission
to make a negotiation?
How did it go?
Everything's fine
He is willing to negotiate but...
it won't be cheap
How much
-One million
-Dollars?!
He saw how you lived and
the house you've got...
He won't ask for less
The good thing is that he will
be in charge of everything
He knows the chief of police,
most of the jury
And he would help us reinforce
our story
The one of the housekeeper?
We cannot take him out of the deal?
No, there has to be a responsible for this
There were two deaths involved and it's
in every news channel
That's fine, but I don't know if
I have that amount of money in cash
It's 1.5 million dollars!
I know, and my part is also in that
Your part?
My part because I'm the person who is fixing
everything for you
I pay a lot of money to your firm every year
But that is for other things, Mauricio
This is not an every-day fee
I'm risking my repuation here
I was about to give my SUV to your family
so they could escape
I think your being inconsiderate
How much are talking
I don't know...
Another 500,000 dollars?
If you want to call another lawyer
it's fine,
My work would be done here
Go finish this
Is everything fine, José?
Actually, no.
Why?
For two years in jail I'm going
to get the same as that lawyer?
I know I'm poor, but...
Did you know it's very bad what you
ar doing now?
Bad?
In that cas you go to jail
Last night I watched a cowboy's movie
I drank some liquor, and I was in bed by 11
like every night
What else do you want?
And be clear because there's no time
The money we agreed and...
An appartment in the beach
Mauricio. José
Can we all have a talk?
Mauricio
Justice! Justice! Justice!
Let's talk fast, gentlemen.
Because we don't have a lot of time
And we don't want any misunderstandings
The story that you made up will not be changed
I will ask you and your family to testify
in a few moments...
So nobody goes anywhere
You'll leave here handcuffed
and with your head covered
Outside we will find the news, a mob
They're going to ask you things.
They're going to insult you
-But you will not answer back
-Sure
We have to stop the rumors and let
the case go with no friction
Let the jury make the sentence and
everyone's happy
Mom, stop!
He says he wants to confess
and go out in the street
It's the right thing to do!
Please, explain him he doesn't understand
Calm down, Santiago
Your mom is right
Everything will be fine
Could you, please, close the door
and take care of Santiago?
-Yes. Let's go.
-Don't worry, Santi.
May we continue?
From now on you'll be the connection
between all of us
Me and Mr. Pereyra are not going to talk again
except when he declares the facts
And you, José, stay away from all sort
of communication with anyone who isn't your lawyer
Perfect
I'm going to need some cash for
any expenses I have to pay
Around 30,000 dollars
That you'll send me on monday at
first hour of the morning
I'm sorry I ask...
What would those expenses be?
Outside there's the whole police
If somebody saw or heard anything
we will have to put them in the story
We have to be ready against any loose
ends this story might have
-So if everyone agrees...
-I'm sure that the money will arrive you on monday...
But it comes out of the money
we talked earlier
I'm not paying one more cent
Mauricio, please stop
Exactly. Please stop! That's the same
thing I want to say. Please stop
Understand that I'm in a complicated situation
But I'm not going to let you
take my money like these
Mauricio. What the attorney is saying
is understandable
Don't let yourself go by 30,000 dollars
Then pay them yourself
Pay them from your part
Gentlemen, this is not the time for
a discussion like this
If you want to finish, this is the time
Or why doesn't it come from your part.
You'll collect from this a million dollars
And you are asking me 30,000 more
for expenses
Who is getting a million dollars?
No. He's right.
The million dollars includes expenses
The expenses plus your part adds up
to a million
Don't touch my part, all right?
You know what, guys?
I'm done with this. There's no deal
No. Mauricio, what do you mean there's no deal
It's done. It's done. It's no more.
They'll be nothing for anyone.
Anyone!
Santiago!
Didn't you want to confess what you did?
Sounds perfect. Go outside and do it.
I gave you the best education.
And you always did whatever you wanted.
So now go fuck yourself!
Mauricio.
Mauricio, calm down. Could we talked about it!
What happend? What happened?
They are all a bunch of vultures.
That happened.
But it's over. I did not kill anyone.
Mauricio I'm asking you, please!
We are in the heart of San Isidro
where a tragic accident happened this morning...
Mauricio.
Can you open the door? I have something important to tell you.
Can we talk in a civilized way?
What's up?
It's done. We reached into an agreement
and the 30,000 dollars will be paid by all.
I don't want to hear anything else. It's over! Get out of my house.
Mauricio I remind you that there were two deaths.
If Santiago is found guilty this will cost us
a lot more.
However, José, is poor.
So who is going to pay the victims' families?
The money should go there.
This piece of garbage has a salary that
comes out of my taxes.
Go find out what happened.
You want to defend my son, set your fees with him.
If he can afford it, I'm fine with it.
Do what you have to do. Go talk!
Look. We already had a deal.
A gentleman wouldn't get out of it like this.
I ask  for apologies if I offended you.
But since I am here, I haven't done nothing else
but to defend your family.
I thank you a lot! You are an angel from God!
Will you let me talk to them?
To see if I can improve the situation.
Excuse me.
Well.
I think we have a better proposal.
José will accept the initial 500,000
and says you should forget the appartment.
The attorney and I will share a million. The end.
Not one more cent.
We have to do it now, Mauricio. The news is outside.
And the attorney says that he cannot delay
anymore the entrance of the police officer.
No.
I'll pay a million in total.
And you share it however you want.
-How come just a million?
-It's that or nothing.
If you like it, fine. If not, go away.
If you hit the door with any other deal
and I'll denounce you for extortion.
TYou and the attorney.
Mr. Could yo reveal us the identity of the assassin?
At the moment nothing will be said.
The only thing I can say is that the case is practically solved.
There is one single suspect and in a few moments
he will be presented to the judge
Thank you very much.
Baldie, you are naked in every picture!
And now,
The time has come
To stand up
in order to receive
our dear
Romina and Ariel.
I'll leave you my father-in-law.
I'll watch you
I'm looking at you
Yes, yes
Thank you!
I wish you a happy evening!
Everybody look at the camera.
Whisky.
Whisky!
Let's see a smile.
Very good. Thank you very much.
Thank You. Thank you very much.
Well, enjoy.
Romina.
Yes?
Here's a little present for you.
Oh, please. You didn't have to.
The gift here is that you came.
-Are you having fun?
-Everything's beautiful.
Your family is very kind and funny.
It's a shame the insecurity in the country
Last night some burglars robbed his wallet
without him noticing.
Oh, I can't believe it.
Sounds terrible. Oh well, little by little...
-Beautiful people. Are they friends?
-Yes.
Okay. That's the table of the guys from the country club.
We had not seen each other for 13 years
but met up thanks to Facebook.
With Facebook.
The ones in the back are college friends with their boyfriends.
Well, the ones who have. Right?
Those are ...
Coworkers of Ariel.
Are you having fun?
Yes, you?
Yes.
Everything's very ... standard.
Your so much fun
-Have fun.
-You too.
Do you know a good place to learn tango?
Yeah ... No.
No, but I assure you that my cousin does.
I'll present her to you.
Hello.
Oh, fuck.
What happened?
But... I'll take away the wine?
No, it's not the wine.
Shut up, shut up
Ariel, what's the name of the girl with long hair?
-Which One?
-That one.
Your coworker.
Lourdes.
Why?
No. No.
And how does Lourdes knows your guitar teacher?
What, my guitar teacher?
When I asked you a couple of months ago about this number,
you said it was your guitar teacher.
Since I found it strange I saved the number.
And it's weird that when I call him this girl, Lourdes, answers.
Right?
-I have no idea what you're talking about.
-You don't know what I'm talking about?
About that, Ariel
That with all the celular companies that exist
And all the promotions they have, it's weird that this girl
has the same telephone number as your guitar teacher.
Especially if they have never met
Isn't it an incredible coincidence?.
-So?
-What?
Give me an answer, or otherwise I'll go ask her.
-Romi, please ...
-"Romi" Fuck off!
Answer my question.
Ariel
Does the entire table 27 knows that you've fucked that girl?
Did you invite all those assholes to our marriage? What did you do?
Sorry to interrupt.
Would allow me a dance with the prince?
Of course. My queen!
Here is your prince.
What happened?
Romi, are you okay?
One second, please.
Romi.
Baldie, would you let me one more dance?
My love.
Honey, stop it.
Let's enjoy the party.
Were you with that bitch?
Please, I beg you!
I need to know!
Yes, I was.
But for me it meant absolutely nothing.
Romi, please don't make a scene in front of everyone.
I was stupid. I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
I want to be alone.
-What's up?
-Did you see her?
You are asking me?
Are you all right?
Should I call someone?
But are you okay?
Obviously you're not.
No.
Calm down, what happened?
I just learned that my husband is cheating on me with another guest.
Oh, that's bad.
And now I don't know what to do.
With all the people there.
Relax, these things happen.
They're overcomed with time.
Here.
If you want him, on the long run you'll be able to forgive him.
-If hee is your husband.
-No, I do not know if he is what I want.
I don't know if he's my man.
He is an asshole.
Oh, well.
In that case take the opportunity.
And th guests? Well, don't feel like you were the first ont to be cheated on.
Also, if you are going to care so much of what others say then ...
You're done, darling
Are we cool?
Look.
If I was you I go there.
I accelerate everything so the party finishes early,
and then, the next night at home,
you break up with him. What happened to you is terrible.
I will not deny it.
But you must move forward.
Better?
Romina?
You leave right now from here and you don't say a word!
You don't have any idea of who you are dealing with!
I'll get every cent from you,
I'll get every single property that your father has bought for you
in order to evade the Treasury.
We are married,
Legally married.
I will dedicate my days to sleep with every person who gives a minimum shit about me.
With whoever who gives me athe most little gram of love.
And when you want to have a divorce,
I'll take acting classes
to sit in front of the judge with a puppy face,
and tell him that I'm fighting, I'm struggling.
That way our marriage is prolonged indefinitely.
I will divulge all your secrets through Facebook,
I'll put my finger in the cut and stir it until cry you of pain.
You'll go through so many humiliations,
that your only escape will be throw yourself off the balcony.
And then, when death do us part,
when YOUR death do us part,
I'm getting with everything.
Ariel!
Ariel, calm down.
Come on, skinny.
Go, go.
Ariel.
Bitch! Where were you? Everything's okay?
Bring me down, assholes!
Idiots! Are you listening?!
Get me off!
What is he saying?
-Ariel, watch out.
-Fuck you!
Asshole!
Bring me down!
Are you already leaving?
Please, no. Come.
-No, it's ...
-Seriously, everything's fine
Come with me, Lour.
Please stop. I'm getting dizzy.
This is great!
Stop it! Seriously!
Did you used to go to our club, or were you younger.
Did you know that they closed it because
someone got kicked there?.
She threatened him saying she was going to get everything
up to his last property.
...Yes, it's better.
I'm deeply sorry for what happened.
However, the party was wonderful.
Excuse me, please.
Most of wounds are superficial.
They will heal well.
However, we will still take to ensure that she did not cut any tendons.
Does she have a good insurance company?
Romina, Please ...
Go back to the hall!
I'm just wondering if she has a good insurance company.
Sounds good. Stay inside!
I'm fine.
Romi, dear. Are you okay?
Yeah yeah. Stay calm.
What if we use this hole for the cake?
Come on, girls. Do not leave me standing like this.
Come on, girls.
I had a very shitty moment but now I want to enjoy
my marraige.
I do not think I'll get married again.
Ready?
Romi.
Oh my God, Mili. You?
I can't believe it.
A picture with Mili.
Picture.
Do you want to marry Mili?
Oh, no, Romi!
Let's show that everything here is a lie,
but that the ring is true.
Wouldn't it be great?
Romi, stop
Kiss her! Kiss her!
-Romina.
-Yes?
Now comes the bouquet and the Rio carnival ...
I don't know if you want to continue or...
Suspend it.
End it.
But why? Why are you being so bitter?
Girls, here it goes!
We are also missing the pastrami, right?
You know how much did it cost?
Say the truth, Ariel.
We argued for a whole week about the hot pastrami.
We decided to pay for it and now I want to eat it. Is it possible, sir?
Romina. Stop!
Let the people go home.
Isn't it a stupid thing what you are doing now?
To give you an idea, my family lawyer says we should sue you for threats you made.
Don't tell me this was a plan from your mom.
Romina, seriously. Cut it.
Your mom is a real ...
-wedding planner.
-Stop it!
What did I do to you?!
I didn't do anything compared to what you're doing to me!
Dear.
Please, I ask you to stay calm.
Please.
Oh my God ...
Shoot this, Néstor.
Nestor, shoot this please.
You too, come.
Shoot, please.
If I get married again,
If I get a guy who's worth it,
I'll put this as a blooper on the big screen.
No...
I'll even watch this with my kids.
Instead of fucking Dora The Explorer, I'll put this video.
I know!
I'll put in those electronic portraits that go on a loop
all day.
Get your hands off my daughter, bitch!
You better get the fuck away
I'm here to help, Baldie!
Leave her
Darling, are you okay?
Doctor!
Take care of the lady, please. You deal with the gentleman.
What did he drink?
Nothing. Emotional shock.
Can you walk?
-Here, over here.
-Hello, Romina.
I'm going to ask you to calm down. I'm going to take your pressure, okay?
Romina
Sit here.
Can you take his blazer off, please.
Take a sit, Romina
Sit down
Are you okay? Don't worry, Calm down.
Romina.
Can I bother you with a glass of water?
Yes, please.
Oh, no. Romi, no.
Don't worry, Romi
Wait, Ariel
Calm down, Ariel.
Quiet, quiet.
Nothing happened, we're fine.
-Quiet.
-It's okay.
Let him be
Stop, Ariel. Stop.
No! Ariel!