Sort of ...
Dirty fucker ...
Hello?
Top thy wave pool!
Sorry, Ms. Després.
It shoulds-have-been Preventing you bring your bikini.
Z'avez school is laughter?
You sign my contract expulsion of Steve
and walk out with Him.
What do you mean that? It can because it two minutes?
Do you speak French, you there?
Maybe not the French of France, yes goal, I speak French.
At 24:15 today, its Was your Cafet '
with oven --other residents
When a fire was started.
Little Kevin Julien Went to hospital urgently
burned in the second, except the third degree.
... You want me to do you a drawing more?
It's your kids? They are cute.
You paraphez down next to me and sign the last page.
So what do we do?
Y-Step "on", Then Mme.
This is good! Not on "you and me!"
On "me, kid," I'm not stupid.
Depres, Steve HAD His luck here.
If you can not take it back,
I'll send it to our wing custody.
Pardon?
Do not pretend to fall off your flesh, really!
It's Hardly your sound, it is not a passport to go to jail!
It won't head?
My kid not go to jail. You m'la not do.
You kidding bad in there They Go They Go out more.
Worse ict keeps telling me educ
he made progress in His positive attitude.
He keeps telling me He Has Improved, so ...
It is a closed center Depres here, eh?
Young people are Improving, yes.
Until They relapse.
You thought the little Kevin Julian, Who Will keep
the marks of the fire to the rest de son life?
Kevin Little, little Kevin ...
We shall canonifier Him? Him shit statue?
That's life, Jackie! Crazy not your head in the microwave and it will go!
- Jacqueline for Jacques. - Listening.
It happens.
Received.
Listen ...
Diane ...
I have seen and I see young people Spend here.
It survives in a few,
Resigned is hjälper l'autre.
We were Given To Steve.
Special schools Gave Steve;
Gave Steve shelters;
HAS Given the center here Steve.
It's your turn.
Oh, and what do I do with myself, DURING THE day?
I'm not lugging to work!
J'peux not all fuck up and carousing with my kid.
Already we-have more of a tune.
A little more, the RMI and RMI me, it's not.
When he turns 16,
he Will Be eligible to juvenile detention.
I Will Not! I will not send my kid in a jail of small quail
Who play the big boss, they'll make Him blow a hose.
And uh ... if not ... do ...
you thought the S-14 law?
The new law ...
All right, let concrete.
As a last resort.
I Never Do That to my kid!
The worst thing you can do for a sick child,
is to believe or believe invincible.
It's not Because we love someone we can save Him.
Love has nothing to do with it.
Unfortunately.
Skeptics ...
BE ashamed.
Good luck, lady.
Jacques for Jacqueline. The small Després Was untenable,
Suddenly, It Was Necessary to bring in the isolation room.
Fucking asshole to lick!
Touch me, I fucks you, tafiole!
- You calm! - Sale prick skin face!
Eat my ass, big foot!
Received.
I'm glad to see That You-have enriched His vocabulary.
Damn, you're a bomb! Te embellished, you!
Every time I see you, you embellished.
You rejuvenated, it's funny!
And it's funny When You crazy fire to the Cafet '.
I'm sick of myself piss.
It is as if I have the fire in the ass, Has To come out.
Enjoy to get out of your head as qu'tu're There It Could serve.
I have not failed you?
I think about you all the time in my head.
You got your head in the ass fuck!
You manages to see me there? It Must Be dark!
It is as dark as the butt of a Black goal I see you anyway!
Jeez! You're damn Where your car?
Was Y reliable to car. We'll take the bus.
Bars! LOL!
Very LOL, yeah! Mate a little blood here!
Who did this to you?
I got back in by an asshole, just now.
Gone checkout. She died.
Y Has To sell the shares on the web!
Forget it. Hell, I'm not missing my foot!
Women!
I Could more blairer em, stupid morons thesis!
Give a Z'en me!
I smoke here!
Ben stops PRECISELY.
I stopped aussi. For my birthday.
Damn, you're shit.
Eh oh! Listen to me, you!
Will-have to make rules at home.
If you want to stay with your mother, if you want no hassles ...
qu't'aides be your mother.
And it starts with mutual respect!
Then you send me no shit, got it? I do not want that!
Shit.
Are you deaf?
- We live now Where? - In Saint-Hubert, near the 116.
The class.
I have a room?
I still tune enough to give you this, banana!
I will not sleep spoon 40 banks.
- At 46! - Shut up!
You do not blunder in the decor, huh.
I rented it to an old woman Who has clamser it's not two months.
Was so much wallpaper, buddy ...
We Could start a business.
- That sucks! - That sucks, I can not tell you.
Finished it, There Remains a taf.
Jeez, you-have kissed Not Even me.
Are you kidding, I have done Just That.
I do not remember.
- Little entubeur, go! - Again! Again! Come on!
Fucking entubeur, hey, you!
You're really the son of your father!
Well, well, Diane Later!
How is!
Well, she continued.
It's not your kid, anyway!
Obviously, that's my kid.
It is the ... school.
- Paul. - Steve.
Beautiful mundane! It's nice.
You just put down the TV a little, just to zap, cushy.
I make pesto pasta sprocket, without fuss, without fuss.
I believe not, Paul.
Another time Perhaps,
We Will purpose settle quietly.
Good. Do it again, Then!
Wraps, do it again!
"It is moving, do it again!"
You gonna fuck you all to back up, it starts.
"I make pesto pasta sprocket"
- Idiot. - "How is!"
- Who's c'connard? - A neighbor!
A neighbor ... to others! Y cop wants you, Surely for.
"For sure!"
Qu'c'est not safe in the dictionary, That.
Is This It
It Does not look!
It's in the dictionary, right?
It Will Be comfortable.
There's the green, and the green, is health.
Y Has Two bathrooms?
Bidet and Jacuzzi, as well?
Where's my room?
At the bottom!
It's not the Parc des Princes, here!
Two radios at the time Sami, it breaks me!
What?
You farms His beak at that!
Two radios on at the Saami time! That's cacophonous!
Therefore I shit in this mess!
Where are the pictures of Dad?
Why do you want it there?
Are in ...
In the room, I know! I awash in cartons.
Fuck ...
It schtarbée fucking.
Bloody hell ...
Steve, this is the last time I tell you!
Another annoying thing: It always repeat The Whole time from noon to 14h!
It's not in my contract!
I want to catch the bus or it 45 Schedule changes
and with the bus 11 hours, We Will s'coltiner caps.
Come on, saque up!
Damn, damn!
It smells the beast here.
Type Before You Reviews entering, whore!
It's not complicated. Are you stupid or what?
Changes tone. I typed.
You have not typed! You're back live!
It's not 24 you're here and it's already the area!
You Will Have ranges, eh!
Is there a way to polish Before quiet?
Give me your calebar, I'll wash it.
And handkerchiefs in a ball, nice for the guests!
In short'll-have better manages handjobs
shoulds and we get out.
You're going to hold my noodle When I pee, too?
Should you already know target!
Mom?
What's the matter, love?
"What we-have won ..."
- We won what? - The game?
- A female name. - So It Takes ...
- It takes an E. - Congratulations.
299.51, please.
Pardon?
That is $ 300.
And That Is?
It is to make beautiful?
If It Would cost 300 balls, i would not come here
this morning frolicking in traffic!
I year I need pens thesis there, They tear the fuck!
Madam, frankly, is the catalog of school.
Really? Because the price of a textbook exchange with the season?
Of course, of course!
Of course, of course! Of course, of course!
I'm really stupid, me!
It Must Be written in purple on the ass people!
Madam, our discounts are valid DURING THE school year.
- After the ... - Well, we-have no choice.
It smells damn strawberry!
I write and it smells like strawberry, whore!
No need for That, Steve. Moves not the stuff for nothing.
We'll try that.
Mom, wait!
It Remains that!
Forget it!
Purpose I need it!
I'll make school I not open a shop stickers!
My year!
Magne up! I'll be in a rush to work.
Ass fuck ...
You Should not talk to your mother That Way, young man.
You've stuck your head in the ass with a red, or what?
I not buy cash on the internet!
I do not want to Spend my life to the garage!
We just need you to do and you goof Negotiate the hard way.
I know the market.
You check suspensions, mileage ...
You know the market? And I'm Marilyn Monroe?
Damn, it's better than whores Taking nozzles and metro
His Money and burn in a taxi.
Let me handle the budget and take care of the ball handkerchiefs.
Jeez, respects me! Treat me like an adult!
Mutual respect, it tells you something? Mutual!
You can calm the drums there? It sucks shit, shit!
The driver's listening drums if he wants, we get there!
Damn, Where we are now?
I Had not Told you St. Helena!
We can not turn, We Will enter the work!
You never Told Me That, Then. Had Told Me That before.
It s'fout me! I Said, "Take no St. Helena!"
It Could not be clearer!
And you take St. Helena as a chef!
Listen, boy, do not you talk to me like that, huh!
Turn around, sir.
I can not turn around, my friend.
- It's not your friend! - Steve, let me handle this!
There, sir, that's your problem.
I told you not to take St. Helena.
You did it just so it costs me more ...
You insult me ​​thief!
Okay, relax.
You say to me That I want to rip you,
and your sound. After That, you scream in my car?
- You scream in my ears? - Fuck, Kirikou!
Steve!
Get out of my car right now! Pull Both!
- Band fools! - Purpose shut your mouth!
Moron!
Wild!
It starts well! You're gonna bring me luck, I feel it!
I'll call the police!
Me too, I'll call to complain!
What! I'll break your face you, little bastard!
You, lift up your sound! Bitch!
- How can you insult my mother? - Calm down!
How you insult my mother, dirty race?
Come here! I do not want to hit me the cops!
Fucking negro!
- It won't, right? - Shut up, you, whore!
Come on, motherfucker dirty rat! Get out of your car!
"Fuck dirty rat", now! A negro and a rat!
Back into your palm juggle your coconuts!
Te envahiras not my country, asshole!
Stop being white racist, Steve!
I'm not racist, whore! This is a negro!
You sit you there, you shut your mouth.
Hello, Diane. Unfortunately ...
Crushes!
I'm really sorry ...
Hey! 40 minutes ...
My beautiful Diane, I'm glad to see you.
Mr. Gravel is on sick leave.
It's disappointing, right? I beg you. Sit down.
Ask me the Service That You Were going to ask my husband.
I'm all ears and I can not wait to Accommodate you ...
Hey! You!
It Tempts you I show you a technical relaxation?
Are we-have the opinion of May Ghislain?
Forget the opinions, baby.
Do not call me "my dear."
Ghislain, It Has more strength, and I have full authority here.
I'm sour he Would Have-been very sensitive to your charms,
order now it's me Who Decides.
You no right to do That.
I have the right! You have no CDI.
I'll give you your pay and everything is legit.
Will more Courier heart?
Yes, it's a real goal journalist Who Will write it.
I have talent. Ghislain Told me.
That He Told me I had a sense of rhythm.
Yes, nose buried in your boobs There Was to love your own pace!
Aim for me, here, your talent is to classify, Photocopied,
oven and serve coffee days a week.
If you-have your its full-time and you can come over,
take your clicks and your slaps and sayonara my bitch.
Why do weasels in my bag! Drop it!
This is my business!
You and me, Diane, this is not our first galley, eh?
Look at me.
We Will team up, okay? Us.
I will learn to control myself.
I'll take care of you.
I'll protect you.
You, your priority is school, okay?
Me is at your age that got me
and now I'm stuck like a bitch!
No training, no degree, no, fuck!
And Dad?
What would he-have Said?
- He Would Have Said ... - You know.
Eh, you know?
"In front Réjean ..."
- "Not from behind, Robert." - What?
"Not from behind, Robert!"
Fandar it, anyway!
What do I look?
Okay, the then is eh?
Are you kidding!
- Aim if it's going. - It looks like a raccoon.
I have big brands. May Day!
You know I always Did That in the center?
When I was pétais cable j'me not care Into ice water.
Me an, you listen to me when I talk to you?
Jeez, where is it ...
Your translator HAD let you down. So, I Had translated ...
a children's book. It was very cute.
A small collection ... Remember?
Pile that! Exactly.
Yes, so I Told myself That if ever ...
to all the opportunities ...
if You Had Reviews another small ...
Reviews another small job in kind to give me ...
I know, Martha, I have no CV
or skills to translate ...
Ken Follett has paved, but ...
I know! Ken Follett!
Yeah, it's too much for me,
order something for children ...
You go out the Larousse and it is flared.
It's not ...
Just a hobby, a pastime for ...
to pass the time.
Purpose yes, I Understand, Martha.
But no, it's okay!
No, no, no, it's fine.
Steve returned to the house, so we begin ...
A new chapter Begins, As They Say.
V'la me, damn it!
Where were you?
I Waited like a bitch for your classes.
We'll Do That tomorrow.
I'm still in the fashion meeting.
What is this crown?
A course!
And That Is?
Shit ...
Can you tell me yes or shit what is this fucking cart?
Ben, a caddy!
No kidding, what purpose is he doing there,
and why it is full of stuff are you doing in my closet?
Matte Some c'que I brought` you back, it Lacks in decor c'te pad.
Change the subject!
This is the food!
I am willing-to cram in my sack, but ... wait ...
When I Said That I Would take care of you ...
Fucking moron of a con asshole, you've been finished to piss or what?
- It Has cost how much, c'foin? - It's not your business.
Of course I do, asshole!
If the Blues come down Because my son is a thief!
I have not stolen. It's a gift.
That's right, Steve,
it is not intended Because it is a gift That You About did not steal!
Where did you steal this?
I have not stolen!
Tell Me Where all stock Then stole you, and We Will Reduce everything ...
I have not stolen, holy shit! You're deaf or what, bitch!
I have not stolen!
That Crazy yourself in your fucking skull degenerate, bitch!
You're quiet. You do not make a crisis.
Mom is not angry, We Will all go back ...
It is to you!
We Will bring-shit, shit!
It is to you, ass fuck! Touch anything, damn!
You touch something, I'll rip your mouth bitch!
Steve, calm down, my love. Calm down, my love.
My name is not "my love" to catch you, shit, shit do!
Stop Taking me for a calibrated, whore!
J'te make a gift!
Listen, Steve ... it's a wonderful gift.
Mom is the beautiful, your present. Mom is very happy.
But is ...
you'll calm down, you'll breathe ...
- And you're gonna take your sedative. - Give me ...
Stop!
You tails me your shit and I'll kill you, Understand?
I kill you, fucking your race!
You poke a hole into my ass with your fucking meds at the con!
I'll fuck 'em in the toilet, for crying out loud!
You Understand That, dirty whore!
You pump me there with your fucking meds!
Stop!
Mom She Would not hurt you, baby.
Mom Would not hurt you.
Purpose Mom ...
Was choking.
You choked me, Steve.
Show me your head.
I will heal you and It Will calm down together. OK, Steve?
You attack me, fucking entubeuse?
Mom Has No purpose! Mom Was scared, you know?
You wanna play petty, dirty pig bitch!
You attack me! Perfect, well me too!
- Stop! - Me too, bitch! 50-50!
You'll see if I mug, bitch!
Stop, stop!
You got the balls to fight too?
Stop, Steve!
You cut me, dirty whore!
You cut me, bitch! You cut me, bitch, I'm bleeding!
I need you to calm down, OK?
You have to calm yourself, mom Otherwise won't help you.
You're dangerous. I need you to calm down. You're in crisis.
We need to Log take your sedative, okay?
I am dizzy, damn it!
Stop fucking Steve ... Stop ...
You can not do this to me!
Mom knows what to think! I'll freak the fuck!
If I go, I want you to be quiet! I want more we yell at Each Other!
Answer me when I talk to you, shit!
I'm going crazy!
Answer!
Steve, are you?
Fuck!
Do you?
Do you feel dizzy?
Should ...
Would really take Him to the hospital.
I Do Not. No hospital.
At Every time, her ass feels in pink, it's written in the sky.
Give Him a lot.
- Shut up. - Shut up, you.
What is c'gros spliff there?
Y Do That in Hospitals. To bear the bread.
That's it, is it terminal. Give me that!
You ...
I love you, you.
Goal you hurt me.
Purpose When it hurts, it feels good.
Do not worry, it's always you my favorite, Even if you beat me.
You breakages me, damn!
I laugh there, damn it! Breathe!
What's your name?
There.
Two syllables. Good, eh?
I'm kidding.
Do you want a coffee?
A juice? Do Not?
I was like this aussi-have kit.
She's in a box somewhere.
Me too, I Could-have Him put bandages.
Goal I find my kit ...
"When our children hangs in a material,
"How to bring it further Top?"
The farther the better.
"A matrix is ​​a column matrix Having a single column."
Hello?
Hello!
Let me introduce myself. Diane Després. I am the opposite neighbor.
- OK. Hello. - Good Morning.
Does Kyla's there?
Kyla, no ... Uh, yeah ...
Purpose sleeping. Do ... I Can conveyed the message?
It is not spread, it is drunk.
She came this afternoon.
She was very nice.
It was really nice, so ...
I wanted to give Him That.
What did she do?
Nothing.
Nothing ... 'end anyway ...
You'll Give Him That. It is not know. We'll vouvoyer.
Hello.
If you-have nothing to do at night venneriez you dinner?
Jeez, it's pain in the ass, your thing!
Welcome to my life, darling.
Good, easy on the greens, it makes me puke me. You Know That.
Your father was small, your mother is not super best,
so if you want to stay québlo 1 m50, Z'en cutting vegetables.
Onions?
Gold, semi-golden ... I weigh the vegetables ...
Balance vegetables.
... Would be in the general hospital in critical condition.
A postponement That freezes the blood,
Maude Lajoie selon Montreal police.
Smoker over the food! It'll taste the butt-have!
It's like bread, it all Absorbs Odors.
Goal you're like a con sleeve!
Indeed, as you Said,
quite a stir here, Especially a lot of fear ...
Is Kyla?
Disturbing testimony of people ... Who Knew the young Asselin.
Z'êtes not come with your guy?
She Was cute, the little neighbor.
I just wanted to play with.
- That was When We Lived in Laval ... - This is my story!
Yes, goal Give Him the context Otherwise You Will screw up your fall!
Purpose it is Laval Laval, whore!
People speak English in Laval.
Increasingly.
But me, I not speak a damn word of English!
It's starting to take me cabbage, Those "damn damn damn!"
Not a fucking word of English except me and Dad year,
When To not want me to Understand what They Were Saying,
They spoke in English,
goal it always ended by "shut up" and "fuck off!"
So Barbara, the neighbor, I said:
"Hey Barbara Come play with me!"
No wonder He Was playing alone, That One.
Dunno hold me, whore!
He HAD always good people skills.
Have you seen a little?
Fat pig, aim it's not wrong?
"Interpersonal skills" whore!
Do you like Kyla?
It's in the dictionary, "people skills"?
Put yourself Z'en.
Yes, thank you.
Otherwise ...
Otherwise, apart from repair my sores on my thigh,
what do you do in life?
I'm on sabbatical.
What do you mean that?
It's a holiday, a break.
A station wagon.
A break from what?
What is your job?
Teacher.
Yuck. Primary? College?
College.
Young people your age. From the fourth to the third.
You're getting better!
It makes long sentences.
Fool!
Ben what?
This is not easy.
I've always beens a little shy, drank there ...
The language problem That, it's been two years.
It semble it is a 7-year cycles.
Until it finally comes and ...
Then one day you're in discarded.
No need to get rid of you. It's sex.
Ben what? It's true That it's sexy!
You, Steve ...
I Saw That You Had a skate in the hall?
It's not a skateboard is a longboard.
You know? I Do Not? Let me explain.
The difference is que la longboard ...
It is longer.
I tell her it is longer! I'm not stupid!
It is to her That I speak.
It takes a lot more ... You're moving less ...
- Less mobile but ... - Stop! It is I who says!
I would make me one second. And you?
- A little shooter? - A little.
Bless You.
Health.
You Moved on the South Shore
you, you're on sabbatical and your guy, he does what?
It is computer programming.
OK. It's a head.
And why you left Quebec?
J'peux take you one?
A cigarette? You smoke?
No, more ...
We celebrate. Huh?
You bet ... Here.
Should not Be Deprived tonight.
My lighter.
This is the first time I go out since we Moved.
This is not true!
It is in transition entre Quebec City and ...
Where we do not know!
It Will depend on ... the work of Patrick.
Then you, your work?
Oh, I ... I'm ...
I'm not ready to work with children again right away.
We too ... We start something, too.
Steve ...
ADHD ...
Between-Provoking ...
And Worse ... he: has a disorder ... Apparently ...
attachment.
I remember the name.
When He Was Little, it was fine. We thought it was just ...
Hyperactivity! Hyperactivity, that's it.
Aim Then His Father died 3 years ago and ...
Move back two minutes. It schlingue smoke here.
Because the air or else ...
It smells musty, with tuxedo.
You know, Steve, there ...
This afternoon ...
Steve is violent.
It's a good kid, full of charisma, but ...
When he fired up His cable, better not be around,
Because everything goes.
Goal I ...
... I do not touch my kid.
- I Understand That. - No, no, no, no ...
This is Because at the hospital, They Quickly jump to conclusions.
I saw. I know the drill.
The DASS, blue ...
They Would Be damned to get me to return to the center, etc etc.
Goal Steve is no place there. Right?
You do not know, you saw goal.
I'm glad, for cons ... It Was tough to see my kid.
There, I have all mine.
And it is a real phenomenon ...
We get bored with Steve!
Not the time to piss off Steve.
Well, it starts.
Buckle up, it takes off.
The cow ...
Bitch!
This is a compilation That His Father made us.
With all the songs we Listened
When We had rolled to California.
We typed the Entire coast bad we ended up in Los Angeles.
He Listens loop now.
May Day. A minute ...
Fuck! What you feel good!
Eau Sauvage, Christian Dior.
My uncle HAD Given me His remaining bottle.
I always wear. It smells good. You know, Eau Sauvage?
Not Touch That, you!
What are you doing here?
Drop it two minutes. Dance with your sound.
You know the words?
This is very ...
very well known.
Come on, sing! This is our national treasure, damn!
She pushes the note our Kyla! Te insured!
If you insured!
May Day ...
Oh, fuck ...
Hi, Kyla. I do not bother you?
It's just ... That I wanted
I ...
I just wanted to say That it was nice yesterday.
It was great, it's true. It Was the bursts.
Listen ...
Do you think You Could make me
a small service?
As I told you,
fancy, I called Marcel After your call yesterday.
Our youth translator left the South with --other models.
Then he has one more less.
So timing side ...
You spot sounds serious.
Really, Martha, you saved my day.
But still if it's a hobby, like you Said l'autre day.
We always find a way to have fun entre old neighbors.
For the number of times you Gave me serviceable.
What's new in your life?
How It Will Steve?
It makes me sweat!
What is it for me to crap Know That Then?
We had a deal.
An agreement? My ass, yeah! It was you wanted to Who Do That.
J'm'en pat myself!
Music, Steve ...
Drop it there!
Why no fucking orange juice
fucking in the booth?
There REMAIN ten minutes our tren ...
Thirty!
Thirty! Thirty minutes! Say it, damn it! Go! You can do it.
Steve ... Ten minutes.
Then Afterwards we dance.
D ... ten minutes!
Then After We ... d ... d ... dance!
Calm down there.
Steve! Steve ...
Not, Steve ...
I do not accept that!
Come on! Fight-old baltringue!
Pat me on the mouth!
I do this as a service, Steve ...
Your little girl necklace, huh! Your daughter necklace?
Get off me, bitch!
There you shut your mouth!
You shut your dirty mouth and you touch me more!
And you make me my gold necklace away I marave you to your face!
Get it? You Understand that?
That's what you want, right?
Is that what you like?
I'm talking about your dead father, me?
Do I make you shit with that?
So shut up,
crazy your ass on the couch and moving.
Steve ...
Go away, j'te hate it!
Up bar!
Take your time, Diane.
OK.
What?
No, it's nothing.
You got no right.
No, no. It's stupid ...
Oh, to others!
No, that's stupid ...
I know I'm not your first choice ...
Stop with your manners!
It makes me frills, I dream!
- It's stupid. - No, no, no!
It's nothing.
You're bread in the ass!
It was great chatting with you!
Say it to me.
You won't be disappointed, I Will Do That to you nickel.
Need you to tell me there.
Say it to me or I'm going to bed Saying
"Bug, what she wanted, It Was important, important not ..."
I need an advance.
In denominations of 20?
Diane! In denominations of 20?
This is for you, eh ... I, I do not mind.
In denominations of 20.
OK, everything in denominations of 20.
I'm a good guy, you know.
Diane!
Wait a minute!
Wait, I'm coming!
Not lucky this morning!
No, goal There Is mornings like this. It's share of life.
Then it rolls to you?
That way, you?
Well, you and your kid.
It is well.
And you, you do not stop now?
We at the City Court is non-stop.
We see green and not ripe, As They Say.
I guess.
Oh, the cow ...
I screwed up my preserves.
Anyway ...
You're not wrong ...
not bad ...
... Quite beautiful.
You bet! I fringuée like a bag!
Hello pace on all fours on the tarmac!
No, no, to others!
Well you see, that's it!
This is what is sexy!
Is that you Not Even know.
Paul, you're funny ...
It's clean end here!
Last House on the Left or what?
You're out?
Surprise!
Damn, damn! Band nerds! I Almost Had a crisis of the heart!
I Held my pee so I wanted to see your face!
I wanted too see you freak!
We ended Earlier maths, so we improvised a small snack slab.
Did you notice she stutters least one?
This is Steve effect. What you want ...
I put them all at ease.
Excuse the ...
I can do something to me?
All is done, the table, everything ... Covered ...
You can relax!
Relax! Breathe!
It can?
Blah ... What happens shutters closed ...
Well ... thank you, Kyla, thank you!
Worse Me I'm a piece of shit?
You, you're far from a bunch of crap.
You, you're a prince, my wolf. That's qu't'es. You're a prince!
Worse us, we already brought` you a queen, His Mother!
We live like kings! We at Versailles!
Fuck! Mate just that!
Versailles!
The beautiful all rolled salami!
Y to do a picture. A minute!
Bring you!
- Come here. Come on, Kyla. - Wait.
Aim the then is my hair ...
Are beautiful, your hair!
I do not like that light me.
Not that side.
We Learned in March ...
End of March 2010.
Three weeks later, I did the paperwork for the coffin.
Bingo!
It Was zarb.
We Moved.
We left Laval.
Worse Then Richard, he HAD debts,
I hurried to sell, c'te home
thesis liquidate debts and the then is everything back to zero.
And this Is Where Was Steve stuffed
in vandalism, theft, bad temper, shouting,
bullshit ...
And the diagnosis and I fell placed.
There, I placed.
I Abebooks web sites you, you have-nots goal Answered me ...
Why you Moved to Quebec?
I know the feeling, Quebec.
Often We Went, for the job of Richard.
What He Was doing, Richard?
Richard, It Was in the field of the invention.
He HAD invented ...
I Never Understood What Was c't'affaire,
finally, if, but ...
It was a trick with microwave.
It Was the called Expired Heater-Waver.
You know?
The Heater-Waver! Yes I Do!
No kidding! Then Ben shit!
Purpose sold it. It worked really well!
Everyone Had the Heater-Waver! My sister, my sister!
Really? Oh yes ...
Of course!
We got the money, With That. Purpose It Was short-lived.
Because Richard Has Seen big, too ...
Aim it was great, too!
Think big is better than small, it's clear.
Worse Then the Americans arrived.
- Are never far away, the Americans. - Are strong, the Americans.
When There is money to do ...
They put hands on it and ...
Whores of entubeurs!
That's it ... But the past is the past ...
The job? You are looking for?
A friend Gave me a small translation job.
I myself know no more than that, hey goal
Will it help me cover up my frais NIEO, though.
NIEO, it happens Quickly, but ...
There I have a mess of furniture I know what to do with ...
They are in the basement, I have no place here.
It is an old life.
I have more to do with it, I think.
I thought I might put it on sale, what.
A great garage sale, what.
Dunno what it's worth ...
Something, something to make a small exit ...
Small lot of money left, small lot of money right,
in the end, it's a big package!
It is good, this little wine!
Worse you? You see someone? You got someone in your life?
The great chésseresse.
Excuse me.
I meant "drought," goal I said "chésseresse."
It's amazing, that ... You're beautiful!
You're beautiful, The.
You're very kind, but ...
Beautiful or not ... I always j'dis ...
Life is like a poker game,
if you is not got a good hand, you're wrong barred!
Not easy to make a good shot!
No poker for fat! Will hit the sack you!
Sit on the sofa and Worse have fun alone.
You watch TV.
I have Not Even a TV! No poker no Drucker!
No nipples in my 34A!
But big praline in my mouth!
This is good. This is my favorite.
Jeez, she's tough, That One.
She fights back, say so!
I'll pass!
Qu'ça BE happening in the hole!
Stop, Die!
Excuse me ...
You'll make me die, Die!
Did They picked you?
Oh, fuck your face!
You scared me there ...
It's just me. Do not worry, baby.
My name is not "baby".
No problem. I'll say more.
It's okay.
You've finished your history paper?
I Was about to finish,
purpose I see nothing with the power cut ...
Here.
Jeez, I assure, did you?
Mom?
Dad Asks Where candles and flashlights.
In a box, in the basement. He Knows Where They are.
OK, thank you.
I wanted to tell you ...
Things seized ...
this morning ... I apologize, first.
I apologize for the worse ...
I like it When You make me lessons.
I Understand When You explain to me.
For That reason, it's what Brings me
to ask if you can continue.
Mom, dinner is served!
Thank you, I'm coming.
Like this ...
I Could do my exams at the end of the year.
Worse When I Am age,
I would like it to go to an art school in the States.
At Juilliard.
Worse die ... she likes you, I think.
It's good.
Worse you, you're on sabbatical, so if you stay with me,
it Would Be a bad day job summary business.
I do not want to bother you, it's best goal hot.
Show me how!
Get out of there!
Going on the bike path!
Leave me alone!
Little bastard shit! Not expect me to come looking for you!
What are you doing!
Thou Encouraged! Stop!
I try to raise this kid!
Liberty!
You love them al dente, do you?
There's several schools,
I order just like a hair, a tad harder al dente.
Purpose There They Are al dente.
Put Me That in the colander, illico pesto!
- You sucked a clown today? - Purpose shut up, you!
They say the mustard mayo peut.
No problem! It says the Saami for biscuits.
J'blaire not c'te crap.
You put two spoons. Just two, okay?
Let'S See ...
Mets not dressing right away, It Will soften it.
Kyla, you can cook the pine nuts over low heat?
Otherwise it'll burn.
In person!
In French, you-have-been Given Form, ma'am.
Good evening.
It does not matter: It can Contain traces of mustard.
The gears are ready.
Hall of skillet to not that it continued to cook.
Put the lid on to keep em moist.
Can we change the subject?
Steve, put the dressing.
You stop to spread my face blush with your two balls!
I'll look like a slut.
You've already Looked like a fucking bitch!
Stop!
Fuck!
Vire c'pull me, it is too small.
You have a brown spot on your back. You bind you in a bunch of crap?
It is you, the pile of shit!
Mixes up to your ass, suck balls!
The kid Who set fire to the Cafet 'is a shit, HIM?
That His Mother Will meet the neighbor across the street,
volunteer to help us with our file
not for you to go back to George-Étienne Lemieux!
- I can not go! - I know it well, big con!
Purpose damn, That There Must Be Defended, eh?
When we-have justice in the ass, It Was the ass!
Now what? We sit in the living room and wait St. Glinglin?
Well, There is something here!
It makes me a big ball!
Wait, wait, wait ...
Defeat more!
No, I know ...
Fucking redneck ...
I, at 10 battery, I tear myself!
Nobody I did not say sweaters, Understand?
Steve, we need you to do.
You're going to die! It Will take two to three hours max.
Damn, do shit.
"Fuck! Fuck!" Stop you with your big words!
Let go of me!
I open the ass of c'langage!
We Will make a good impression tonight!
You like well, when i pick you like this?
You're too stupid to See That this guy won't want to help us, just fuck you!
It happens!
No Soucy
Kyla, as usual, thank you ...
- Good luck. - We Will do what we can.
This is for today, Bozo?
Wait for me a minute.
Stay here.
Listen: There's no 10000 solutions.
Mom jobs right and left,
order to pay for food and bills,
not a pursuit, not a lawyer.
If not blind, if not defend ...
Tonight we put water in our wine.
Huh, baby?
You Understand it, this phrase? "Put Water In His wine"?
Tonight we stick together. You're There For mom, and vice versa.
Is it good?
Where are we going?
Good!
It's scary how There's nothing here Has Changed.
Even More It's scary c'te secret sauce!
It freaked me secrets these!
I do not understand the principle.
I do not understand the principle!
Burgers of all flat-dishes.
Who cares, other tourists,
hamburger was crushed like a pancake?
I Was That You surprised offers to come here.
Who wants it, good homemade burger class
with a spicy sauce
Worse cottage cheese INSTEAD of bright orange cheese whore
American snack obese Sows off at the con?
It Had To Be a tourist bastard, father?
Nice atmosphere this beautiful light and successful, eh!
Anyway, Steve, I hope you like that karaoke!
I Prepared year Entire evening! I Organized everything that!
We love karaoke! He likes it, it.
I told you over the phone: He sings it.
I not sing, damn, I dance!
You can do Both Sami at the time, you're not stupid.
And if you're going to eat like a jerk of pig shit long?
What I Was going to say ... When I sing Eye of the Tiger,
It Will Decomplex you quickly.
You're out of it Indefinitely!
Since 82, I've never won.
I saw maybe eleven times.
It's like I never know how it Will end.
Scarface, I post it on my fridge.
More ... over ...
- At my request ... to Steve, there ... - Yes.
Yes, Because our Steve, he put in a bit ...
... Big trouble, As They Say.
It's a professional.
There, it starts to urger,
BE taken care of That case, this hay there ...
I'm your man.
I know.
- So you sing us what, Steve? - Yeah, so?
I can not believe whore! No, are you kidding me purpose!
Carp eyes, mouth six feet long!
He Does not Know what to do, it is planted there.
She Took expensive c'te poor girl!
The guy landed in the middle of the night.
He grabs her and the stripper,
the stick coming out of slibard!
A big cock!
So, Steve!
We sing what?
I have an idea!
We Did a duet!
We sing to your mother a beautiful song
for a beautiful woman.
Missy! Two --other! même thing! You want another one?
Go ahead and send!
That's the Saami thing twice.
Thank you.
Then Paul ...
Steve and our record is,
It Could Be a dot on it Before It is Too flared?
I never flared myself.
No, gravement goal, my Paul,
You, You Could not Live
our direction
Where one can take c't'affaire?
You have to Understand
That thesis boxes in there,
- It's all in the angle. - Oh, yeah ...
The angle you take.
Is it this one?
Or this one?
I do not know. You're the boss.
Its just different, That.
No, it's Reviews another way.
It is fragile, it's the goal angle.
Seriously there, why INSTEAD m'voir not you come tomorrow?
I do not feel good talking about it Before Steve,
When we are about to celebrate. It relaxes.
Do you like the cottages?
Well, chalets ... You m'sors it like that, you, "cottage"!
We Could Spend two or three days at my cottage
When I have my daughter not Worse Than you ... I do not know ...
Are you ...
- You're the song Vivo per lei? - What?
The song Vivo per lei?
Andrea Bocelli, yes. I have sour For That.
You did the duet version of the girl with bad guy?
- Yeah. - It Tempts you to sing with me?
Ah, yes! It Could Be cool.
- OK. Go ahead, I'll join you. - Thank You.
Hey, hey, hey! This is our international Steve!
Steve, it's awkward at first,
purpose ounce it is hot, Be Careful in there!
Yes, Steve, He Has good people skills.
Surely not Qu'y'a Many People Sing that here.
Jeez, There is a star in the place!
Who's c'pédé?
Spy it, guys!
Come on, sing, baltringue!
There you shut your mouth Worse shit you let me sing my song!
If my word That I marave you fuck up!
- There you calm yourself! - Go and die, asshole!
Steve, Stop That to you right away!
Motherfucker, I'll kill you, scumbag, kill you!
There you steer you golden blue disembark quickly!
So clear off!
- Steve, come here! - No, I return home.
Do what you want, fuck it, I give a damn.
Steve, listen to your mother. Come here, we're going to talk to adults.
Did you really look like an adult, with your 27 beers blood!
It is for You That does it all! Not for me!
I have no bullshit with the law, me!
We are looking for solutions.
In a fucking karaoke?
Open up your eyes, Diane! He just wants fucked you!
Pay Attention to your language! Speaks better you are older qu'toi!
It is not seen.
Steve! Stop!
Why? Singing licks ass while this moron?
That's enough, asshole!
Paul, not add, damn!
- You're talking to your mother better! - We are all souls ...
You think you are?
Do You Realize the shit you put your mother in?
She does everything for you bad you cost Him more arms!
Worse you, what you find to thank?
I spit in the face and go beat you in a bar?
Shut up, you!
With your fucking job to small con lawyer crap!
You Manipulate my mother to suck your dick ...
You motherfucker!
Screw you.
Sort this out with your fucking pathetic problems.
That's it, go away, damn. Barre up!
Up bar!
This guy is ...
Would he help us, asshole.
Help you, you, Steve.
There's someone Who can help us. They are all the same, damn!
There's just you and me. The rest is shit, shit!
I have no problem. You dig that?
You know what is my problem? It's you!
I have more job because of you, I have more wheat, more than life!
The drugs, the leap correctional center
and pursuit, now!
Do I have a fucking break in life?
I Will Not! Steve, ladies and gentlemen!
A break! C'mon!
She dreams in color, Després, whore!
The bursting father, his comprehensive!
Great program! And When There Is More, There Are again!
Because you still fucking-have a great idea
parte balls for it!
And I, the pitcher, I pick up shit!
Tape yourself Mongolian, Mongolian pat yourself fucking!
Is, is ...
Can I help you?
Where were you?
When?
Selon you?
I Was sleeping. I sleep.
May it one day
you love me more.
That May Be this kind of thing.
It happens.
Goal I ...
I'll always be there for you.
I ...
you're my priority.
Row 2, row 3 ... Fucking shit!
It sucks the aisles Where They indicate indication nothing!
Calm down. We Will find good.
It is donf, it is in-phase to the cleat. It Will cost me candy.
- What? - Key to nothing.
- A phase it ends. - Yeah, yeah ...
It goes down.
Here, Kyla, I will lead half of my list.
It saves time if you do it for two.
I go there.
You, you touch your ass.
I do not know your mother as much as you, Steve, but ...
I know what is to Be a mother
Then There is no malice in it.
Y is not. It's just fear.
This is His fear talking.
I do not care if She Would like me anymore.
Wanted. She wants you, of course, Steve. Stop there ...
As is, you're going to focus you, okay?
We Will Focus on your and your 3rd 4th.
After That, well ...
We Will make your request at Juilliard.
You'll see one day we Will receive a beautiful letter,
in a beautiful envelope
Then your mother Will Be proud of you.
Shoot.
Shoot, whore! Come on say the words.
What?
What you got jerked off, do you?
Let'S See ...
You and me, we still love you?
Us, this is what we do best! Come! Come here!
Wait! Help me, Kyla.
You come back later?
You're going to cook something or I order?
I'll be there for dinner, drank still command.
I won't-have to head it on the way.
The Following Against urn contains balls oven ...
numbered from 1 to 4.
Successively drawn without replacement and two balls of the urn.
Balls ...
That is to say, It Does not call the first ball drawn in the ballot box
Before drawing the second ball.
Ball.
Must move forward.
The result ...
It Was At That beautiful white car, Before?
It makes you get wasted?
Where do we take you, miss?
She is old, modern goal. There's Even a dead heat.
Have you seen? There's a button there!
I too gets off!
That Does not happen in the life of a mother she dislikes her son.
You Understand that?
OK, yeah ...
The only thing That Will Happen,
is That I'm going to love you more and Stronger.
Worse is you Who will love me less. Aim this ...
it is kind That does it.
It's like that.
This is the natural order of things. You learn That, at a time.
You Understand what I say?
Do you understand?
You made your luggage as I Abebooks web sites you?
Have you done your luggage or crap?
Not tickle me!
Not forget the sandwiches, eh?
Look What Was in the fridge.
Look!
It's not for me to take care of That.
The back door is locked?
Will it really make a great trip!
Do I put this in ... in ...
No, keep it in the crate.
OK, we all?
It Has everything?
It's green.
It's okay?
I have to go to the bathroom.
I'll shoot here.
Me an eastern portion pee?
I do not crush you like this?
Kind of a bitch shit sow!
Calm down! Calm down!
Touch me not, motherfucker!
- Touch me not, tell me about it! - Calm down, man!
- Calm down! -. Quiet We are here to help you.
Why are you doing this to me, bitch?
It's for your own good! To protect you, my baby!
You do that for me, fucking traitor!
You scales here as a waste of fucking shit fuck!
You love me, whore! You can in addition to my mouth!
It is useless to Be violent, Steve. It is useless.
Shut up, motherfucker! You're going to leave a Taser shot me, asshole, right?
Is that what you want! They electrocute me, damn!
We not touch you if you in the hospital Among, OK?
No, I'm not freak the fuck!
I Will not Be in a hospital! I look like a fool to me?
You do not look crazy.
Stop! No, damn! I not go!
Mom, I wanna go there. I not go!
Mom, you can not leave me here, damn it! Do not do that!
Mom!
You and the spineless wimp of a bitch! You too, bitch!
You are all mounted Against Me, whore! The Whole band!
Not touch me!
This is not required, it fucking!
Madam, let us do our job, OK?
- Let go of that! - You're hurting me!
You're going to calm down, man!
Calm down!
Let me go, damn!
Let Him Go!
Dirty bastard!
Fucker!
Let me do my job, ma'am!
He hit!
He hit! He hit!
You've signed the paper!
You let us do our job! Enough!
I have not signed for you bastonnez my kid!
Clause retraction lasts 24 hours!
I fuck thy clause!
- Come back in 24 hours! - Mom! It hurts!
It's me mother! It is I Who Decides!
No longer!
What Are They To Him doing? I've changed my mind, sir.
Get out!
Bastard!
That's the forest ...
That is still the forest ...
That's the beach.
Hello. You are on the answering machines of Diana Després.
Leave a Message me
and I will call you.
Thank you. Goodbye.
That's me.
You have to BE doing your household. So ...
I'm pretty shot, what ...
I called you to tell you that ...
Damn I foncedé, Diane.
If You Would see me,
you foutrais you serious in my mouth!
I Thought You Would say.
I wanted to tell you that ...
I just wanted to say
I thank you for being white patient with me.
I Understand That I am not convenient.
As she Grandma Said, When I was little,
I Was not convenient.
Now I Understand why she Said That.
So I apologize.
And ...
and when ...
When I think of the time ...
and when to I think of the times I've maybe done wrong ...
later, when i go back down and I calm ...
It Gives me the fucking balls
Because You really deserve better than a calibrated Mongolian like me.
So ...
the significant thing is That I think of you here, Diane, and I love you.
You tell Kyla I Tell Him hello too. OK?
It Was going?
I mean, is That I was ...
I rank.
I have not Even Heard. It must walk.
I'm washing the porch. It's crazy as is dirty.
It's okay?
Yes I Am. It's good!
And you? How long have you're not coming to see me!
You want to go? Have a beer.
Mater or TV. I finally connected, TV c'te my balls!
She Had to serve a purpose!
Go home, go home.
Come-have a beer,
gold left to eat. Can be pasta.
Come!
There!
We'll take that.
I came to tell you Abebooks web Moved to Toronto.
For the work of Patrick.
Aim it rocks!
This is great news! Toronto!
It's stupid, I just beer!
If I Would Have Known I Would Have Bought A chic thing classier!
Well gosh!
You know I've Lived in Toronto me?
It's for ages, for cons.
It was just Before Steve Was Born.
... I Kept addresses.
I Had a nice big book filled That I Could give you.
Because Toronto, it's no air,
goal if you do not know well, it Can Be boring to death.
Goal I Had full address ...
Good restaurants, good shopping, not tourist stuff.
It is not possible, That I Threw That.
When are you going?
Well, that's it ... We had to leave in two months.
But is ...
It's been ... suggéré weekend in two weeks.
Finally ...
Look, it's the next weekend.
Do Not? You kidding!
The next weekend?
Oh, the cow!
Jeez it throws you project! This is not nothing! This is not nothing!
You move to Toronto next weekend!
You have to be happy!
I admit I did not think You Would react like that.
How do you want me to responds? It's heavy!
It's amazing! Extraordinary!
Here, You Will write to me.
If you are not writing, I arrived! I just see you strength!
I have to go finish my boxes.
But still, take at least one beer.
Or just eat tonight.
In fact, all my apples are eaten by bugs,
They All Fell, Almost. I Could make a good pie.
It tells you a beautiful pie? I ... ice to put on.
Yes, I'll come back ... I Could come back later.
Come with Patrick!
Come with your daughter!
Since the time.
I do not want you to think
That It Has not-been significant to me in recent months.
With you.
Me too.
Me too. It Was important.
We had a blast!
It Has cracked the mouth confess!
It makes us good to us too, you're here.
In my life.
You kiffes you more pies or crumbles?
It's just That I can not give up ...
... Leave my family.
This is not what I meant.
You know, Kyla ...
Each Was how we manage.
You manages your life, I manages my own. It's like that.
If I Placed it there ...
It Is Because I have hope.
You dig? I am hopeful, okay?
The world is a place Where There is not much hope.
Purpose think ... I love it
it is full of people, full of hope, That hope.
And that's damn good to us Because We Can change things.
A world full of hope with Many People Hoping more
It Does not give much. You go not far away, like that.
I did what I did ...
Because, like this, There is hope. OK?
So I win.
Down the line.
I go out winning this. Everyone wins.
So ...
Pie or crumble? What you want?
Dr. Fawcett will go later to change icts requirements.
Gradually, maybe We Will put in a room.
Micheline not working tonight.
She Moved to St. Paul this morning, drank she returns.
- It's her Thursday. - She goes over Thursday.
It Does more Thursday. Asks no questions.
Do not try to understand.
What you want ...
It is with ...
He returned to booze and she resettled with ...
She not Understand? It was not Him In His skull?
There's nothing to Understand, man.
She tries to save Him, like ...
Fucking human kind, man.