Sometimes when I wake up
me cry.
A dream I had never could I remember.
But...
there is a feeling that I was missing something
lingering long after I woke up.
I'm always looking for
something, someone.
This feeling came over me which I think has been since that day ...
The day when the stars fall.
It was almost like ...
like a scene from a dream.
Less like
... a beautiful view. / ... a beautiful view.
How I wish the trip words
Up to the end of the world
without disappearing
Then what becomes of those words?
To promise that will not fade Let us say in a matter of 3
Your wish may be realized on several levels
My eyes could not see this greeting
Since when and why? I do not know
At which point the rain begins and ends, where the rainbow begins and ends
Place where my life fades,
I always believe that there is something being chased
One day we would go to all living beings never been there,
Give tos and kiss at an unprecedented feeling, unexplored
Although all five dimensions of teasing but I still see you
Let's make a gesture to say "Nice to meet you"
And chased your name
Terjemahan & Sync  IrfanZM (Otakunime-ind.blogspot.com)
Such. Such.
Do not you remember me?
My name is...
Mitsuha!
Mitsuha, what are you doing?
It ... feels like a real ...
What? "Mitsuha"? / In fact ngelindur? Breakfast!
Hurry!
What? What?
What?
Grandma had leftovers from last night?
You can eat it.
Good morning. / Good morning.
Mitsuha, you're late! / Tomorrow I'll make breakfast.
Is this the most? Maybe.
You normally today.
You crazy yesterday. / Are you talking about?
Good morning, everyone.
This announcement from City Hall Itomori.
In connection with the election of mayor
which will be held the 20th of next month, the selection committee ...
A comet with an orbital period of 1,200 years will pass within a month.
The comet will be seen by naked eye for a few days ...
Just make it up with him.
This is adult business.
... JAXA is preparing space observations show this century.
We're leaving now!
Study hard!
Mitsuha!
Pagi, Sayaka, Tessie. / Pagi.
Come down. / Why? Stingy.
You is heavy. / Coarse really.
You two are a peaceful stroll.
No!
Your hair looks okay today.
What?
Ya, apa nenekmu habis merukyahmu? / Merukyah?
Kamu kaya kerasukan it!
Do not be ridiculous. Mitsuha just stress, right?
Huh? You're talking about?
You do not remember it?
The most important,
improve the city's finances to continue the revitalization project!
Only when this is achieved
can create a safety and security of the people!
As the incumbent mayor ...
Besides, she will be elected again.
I heard he distributes pork.
Hey, Miyamizu. / Good morning.
So the mayor and his son contractors also walk together.
That one.
Mitsuha!
Walk more confident!
He firmly with his family. / I'm impressed.
Very humiliating. / Damn if I were him.
Mitsuha.
In front of many people...
"Who are you?"
"Tasokare" means "Who is it" and says his home is "Tasogare-doki".
Twilight, it's not a day or night.
When the nebulous world and people might see something that is not human.
Length of expression including "karetaso-doki"
dan "kawatare-doki".
Tanya! Bukan "kawatare-doki"?
Kawatare-doki? Guess that accent the locals.
I heard the elders Itomori still use the classical language.
However, we in the woods.
"Who are you?"
Good, then, Mitsuha.
Ya.
Oh, you finally remember your name today.
You do not remember?
Yesterday you forget the location of benches and cupboards lockermu.
Your hair is disheveled and not wear the ribbon.
What? Impossible! Is that true?
It looks like that time you again amnesia.
Well, I've been feeling lately I had a strange dream ...
Dreams about the lives of others?
I do not remember clearly.
I know! It is...
Your life before!
Or maybe your subconscious is connected to the group nature of the parallel Everett ...
Do not say that. / Oh! Tessie, you who write in my book?
Nothing.
But Mitsuha, you are indeed a bit strange yesterday.
Do you feel okay?
It was really weird. I feel fine.
Maybe it was because of stress. Habit could arise, is not it?
Oh, do not remind me!
I can not stand in this town again.
The city is too small and crowded. I want to graduate and go to Tokyo.
I do not blame you. Indeed, there was nothing in this town.
Trains come every 2 hours.
The store closes at 9 pm.
There is no bookstore, a dentist.
But two pubs for some reason.
[PUB MOTHER & PUB EYE-Cats]
There are no jobs.
There is no bride. / Sunlight short.
Give me a chance! / What?
I mean ... what if we popped into the cafe?
Café? / Really?
Where?
Halo.
Is this a cafe? / Weve no such things here ?.
Mitsuha to return tuh.
I bet he experienced something heavy.
Well, he lives in the middle of the hill.
Ya.
Hey, Tessie.
What?
What are your plans after graduation?
Why? You inquire about my future?
Nothing special. I would probably still live a normal life in the city.
I also prefer to do that.
You're not ready, Yotsuha.
Listen to the sound of the string.
When you embroider like that,
emotions will slowly begin to flow between yourselves and thread it.
Knitting do not talk.
What he means, "Concentrate".
1,000 years of history reflected in the webbing Itomori us.
Listen, 200 years ago ...
He started again.
Mayugoro bathroom slippers maker on fire and burn all of these areas.
Temples and old documents were all destroyed
and this is known as ...
Kebakaran Hebat Mayugoro.
Fire called by his name? Mayugoro poor.
Then the significance of the festival we be unknown and only live performances.
But although the term is lost, the tradition must be inherited.
It's our job which is important in Miyamizu Temple.
But the foolish law ...
As if leaving the Shinto clergy and the house is not enough,
Now politics? He can not be expected.
Drink again, my friend.
I count on your help again.
Leave it to me.
You will be selected from Kadoiri and Regional Sakagami.
How's that woman? / Not that easy.
I smell the scent of corruption.
Do not be ridiculous.
Bring us more hot sake.
Good.
Katsuhiko, finish the scene this week.
Learn how to use explosives.
Ya.
I can not hear? / Yes!
We both have weight problems, is not it?
What it Yotsuha? He was great.
They are both beautiful as her mother.
Hey.
/ Hey.
It is the oldest in the world's sake.
By chewing rice, then released, and let it ferment, would be alcohol.
"Kuchikamisake", what the gods sake brewing appreciate it that way?
Of course.
O Liht. ITU Miamizu.
Oh! I would not do it!
Was he not a shame?
I can not believe.
Cheer, Mitsuha. Who cares if some classmates to see?
I envy with less attention in the period before puberty.
Why not sell just kuchikamisake lot and use the money to go to Tokyo?
Where did you get that idea?
Sell ​​it to be photographed and video. And given the title "Holy Virgin Sake".
You will get the money!
"Holy Virgin Sake"
No. It violates tax law Beverages.
That's the problem?
I hate this town! I hate this life!
Please make me your Tokyo handsome guy in the next life!
You idiot ...
Totsuka Ku
Ow!
Ouch ...
Where...
There's something in here ...
Ow! / Taki! You woke up already?
Now it's your turn to cook. Get up on time.
Forgive me.
I go now. Drink all of its miso soup.
Good.
Go to school even if you're late. See you later.
Have a nice day.
It was a strange dream.
"From Tsukasa: Hurry up, you're late!"
What? Of who is this? Tsukasa? Who is that?
I have to go to the bathroom.
It's too realistic.
"Shinjuku Station"
I was in Tokyo.
SMA Jingu
Dari mana kamu mendapatkannya? / Daikanyama.
Opening act at the next show ...
We just miss his club and went to a movie.
Such!
Late, huh? Let's have lunch.
Kamu mengabaikan text message.
Oh, Tsukasa? / At least apologize.
You lost? / Yes.
How can you get lost the way to school?
Uh ... gini ... I ... / Huh?
Ane!
Daku?
I?
I too forget themselves. Very crowded in Tokyo.
You seem to have problems with dialects.
Where was your lunch?
Gosh. / Do you ngelindur?
You bring something? / Sandwich-egg croquette sounds good!
thanks.
Let's go to the cafe.
Cafes it? OK. You go, Taki?
What? What? What?
Kafe?
Structuring good wood.
Yes, pay attention to every detail.
Taki, you order?
What? This price can not make me live a month!
Of era what more are you from?
Hmm. Oh well, it's just a dream anyway.
It's a great dream.
Oh no, what should I do? I'm late for work!
Rota are you doing now?
Then go. / Oh, yes.
Oh! A...
Emangnya I work where?
What?
Tables 6, 7 and 10 are waiting!
Meja 12! Taki!
Ya.
This please.
Uh, zucchini and tomato salad ...
We did not order it.
Taki, I say no more mushrooms!
Taki, I did not hear?
Such!
When is this nightmare going to end?
Hey, hey, waiter.
Oh, ya?
There skewer teeth in our pizza.
We could get hurt.
Fortunately I saw it. What can you say?
Uh, well ...
But ... no toothpick in an Italian restaurant ...
Excuse me.
What are all okay?
Let this kuatasi.
What's wrong with you today?
Please accept our apologies. Your food for free.
Oh really? / I hope you do not get hurt.
A...
Okudera ... / Nona Okudera.
Nona Okudera, terima kasih ...
A disadvantage today.
No, uh ... / I'm sure before it is set.
Handle in accordance with instructions, but ...
Oh, Nona Okudera, rokmu!
You got any?
What happened? / Cuts.
The jerk that just now?
How about now? Do you remember her?
No.
Follow me.
Hey, This!
Remove your skirt.
Oh, I'll find another way!
It soon anyway.
Done!
Wow, Taki! Better than before!
Thank you for saving me today.
Actually, I'm worried about you.
Looking frail but angry.
I like you much better today.
Do not know if you have a feminine side as well.
"JR Yamanote line: 7 MINUTES"
I think it's very realistic dream.
Oh, he kept a diary.
He's very organized.
Hopefully I can stay in Tokyo as well.
Oh! There he is!
Gebetan, perhaps?
The road to the Miss Akudera same station after work, thanks to the power of feminine! "
"Who are you?"
"Mitsuha"
Totsuka Ku
What is this?
"Mitsuha"
Water ... water ...?
"Thanks to the power of feminine!"
What happened?
Let's go to the cafe again. / I'm sorry, I must go to work.
Do you remember where you work?
Tsukasa, do you work on cell phone and ...
Oh, never mind. See you later.
Acting normal today.
Yesterday attitude rather sweet.
What?
Water ... water ...?
Taki, you try to beat us!
You go home with him!
Really? I went home with Miss Okudera?
What happened after that?
I really do not remember.
Oh right, right now?
Excuse me.
Hello friends. / Hi.
We made were good.
They, Taki?
MONDAY, 12 SEPTEMBER
"Mitsuha, who are you? What are you?
You do not hold-hold your breasts today.
Breakfast is ready! Quick!
Breast?
Good morning.
Why are all staring at me?
Gini, acting rather strange yesterday.
Huh?
TUESDAY, 12 SEPTEMBER
"Stay alive for drawing"
Did you see election posters?
It does not matter who wins. All just a matter of how to manage the funds.
Shh! A person's livelihood depends on this.
What they mean I'm right?
Mm, ya.
Hey, Mitsuha!
Wha ... What ...? What is this?
Mitsuha?
What is this ... what this might ...
What might be "we" really ...
In dreams "we", the guy was and I ...
In dreams "we", the girl was and I ...
PASSING PLACE?
So you've finally awakened,
then why can not you see with your eyes?
You're late, you sputter,
but I have been trying to get here as well
I began to understand what was going on.
Taki is a guy my age who lives in Tokyo.
I swapped places with Mitsuha randomly,
several times a week unexpectedly.
Sleep is triggered. The cause is still a mystery.
My memory is not clear after I woke up.
But we certainly swap places.
It was clear from the reactions of people around us. So...
So we set some rules to protect each individual lifestyle.
All the things that happened during the "exchange areas" and a list of "prohibited".
We also agreed to write a report on our smartphones.
To work together to solve this mysterious phenomenon.
But...
That girl! / That guy!
"SO NOT!"
"PROHIBITED BATH - stare - TOUCH!"
"DO WASTES! DO NOT USE dialect! DO NOT be late!"
From the beginning of life-before I began to investigate you
I'm getting used to laugh awkward
If you're missing missing missing like dust in space
The guy looked at! See the skirt! Really, this is not it wonderful!
"Pake KALO hati2 ROK!"
Or will create a natural we start from zero again
Do not spend my money! / It's your body, and I also work!
Knitting ... I can not do this!
Schedule your work too much! / For ye are wasteful!
Can we do it better?
Our future, untold misery?
What I did not tell you?
Together we can smile and reply
Coffee with Miss Okudera. You two do the fun!
Mitsuha, do not change my relationship!
Taki, why a girl in love with me?
You are more popular when I was you.
Do not be yourself completely! Do as you're together cewekmu!
You do not have a girlfriend guy!
I I...
"foolish"
I'm single because my will!
I do not have to obey "him".
Do you really believe like breasts.
We're leaving now! Be prepared!
Tiamat comet has been visible invisible for several days.
When and where the comet could be seen?
"Comet Tiamat reach Point Tracks"
Tiamat comet moves from east to west seem to follow the sun.
So this is visible above Venus ...
Why wear a uniform?
Grandma, why the temple of the god we are very far away?
Aku tak tahu penyebab Mayugoro.
Who is that? / What? He's famous!
Here, the grandmother.
Whoa, Mitsuha.
Mitsuha, Yotsuha, kalian ahu "Musubi"?
Musubi? / Musubi adalah cara lama untuk memanggil dewa penjaga lokal.
This term has a very broad sense.
Knitting yarn is Musubi. Connecting with people is Musubi.
Aliran waktu adalah Musubi.
It's all the power of gods.
So we make knitted
is the art of god and represent the flow of time itself.
They connect and create a form.
They rolled up, tie
sometimes decompose, break up, then connect again.
Musubi ... mengikat. Itulah waktu.
Drink. / Thank you.
I want too! / It also Musubi.
Whether it's the shape of water, rice, or sake,
if a person consumes something and fused with his soul, that Musubi.
So the show today
is an important habit that connects gods and men.
Hey, I saw it!
Ituk Tubh Deva skilled Miamizu?
Above this location is "kakuriyo".
Which means hell.
This is hell!
In exchange for returning to this world, you have to leave
whatever's important to you.
Kuchikamisake.
Kuchikamisake?
You give it to the body of a god.
Half of you.
Half of Mitsuha ...
Ini sudah senja "kataware-doki".
Kataware-doki?
Oh ya,
maybe I could see kometnya.
Comet?
Oh, Mitsuha,
Now you're dreaming, right?
Tears? Why?
"I'm almost there, wait!"
Nona Okudera? Dia bicara apa?
Mitsuha what has been done this time?
Date?
A date with Miss Okudera tomorrow!
Meet at 10:30 am at the station!
... itulah yang akan kurencanakan, tapi ...
Such.
Sorry, what you've been waiting long? / Yes No...
A...
I just got here. / Good. Let's go.
He was lucky. They now have probably already shared ...
Hey?
I...
Why?
I want to go on this date,
but when that occurs, eventually you are going, you'd better enjoy it!
However I'm sure you never go on a date before,
I do not know what to say ...
So below are links to help you, you're a slow learner.
Seriously?
"You can also get the girl!"
"I suffer from anxiety but can be a girl! What can and can not be on SMS."
"He" pranking.
PHOTO EXHIBITION: NOSTALGIA
Such...
You're like a different person today.
Um, Miss Okudera, you hungry? How about dinner ...
Leave off today.
Ya.
Taki, you ... I'm sorry if I'm wrong.
You had a little crush on me right?
But now you're like everyone else.
No, I'm not anyone else!
Very? / No! That's not true at all.
I am curious.
Oh okay. Thank you for today. See you at work.
Download Anime Only: Otakunime-ind.blogspot.com
At the time of an end date, the comet will be visible in the sky.
What did he say?
"Mitsuha Miamizu"
Oh, you, Tessie.
Oh, I just did not want to go, that's all. I am fine.
What? Festival? Gini ...
Oh yeah, the comet. The highlight of today's brightest right?
Good, all right, see you later.
You had wanted to meet him in yukata.
What !? Not!
That will not happen to me.
Hey, he looks sad.
Maybe you neglect him.
Seriously! / Sorry, I'm late.
This is it! / Finally!
You ... dick ... / Oh! What happened, Mitsuha?
Your hair!
Rasa looks funny huh?
Do you think the reason for a guy? Dumped, perhaps?
Why guys interpret it with a hair cut off and the relationship?
He says, just pingin haircut alone.
Very? He wants to cut all that hair?
Oh! Hey! You can see it!
Wow!
The number you call is not active ...
I'll tell you, "he" dating disaster next time when we switch places,
I think so. But...
For some reason, after that,
Mitsuha and I would not trade places again.
"Mountains in the Region Gifu"
"Hida Mountains"
What ... what are you doing here?
Tsukasa told me and here I am!
Tsukasa, I ask you to take my place in the home and in the workplace.
Takagi which replaces your work schedule.
Leave it to me! But you've got debts to eat!
It's not funny.
We were worried about you. / Huh?
You can not go alone. What if this action is counter?
Measures cons? / You see a friend online.
No, not ...
I think he's using dating sites. / No!
You're acting strange lately. We are watching you.
I'm not a kid!
"Turn-place" has stalled. SMSku telephone and incoherent.
So I decided to go see Mitsuha directly.
I want to see him, but ...
What? You do not know the purpose? Petunjukmu only views of the city?
Ya.
And you can not call him? Actually this is about?
Serious. It's an ugly tour planner.
I'm not planning a tour! / Oh yes, we'll help you find him.
Oh cute! See!
Really annoying. / Oh, he's moving!
So however this is impossible ... / What? After all the trouble we've been through?
You did not do anything.
1 Ramen Takayama.
Oh, lalu 1 Ramen Takayama. / Baik, 3 ramen. / Baik.
Can we go back to Tokyo today?
Maybe we could find a shortcut. I'll check.
thanks.
What can you use it?
I started to feel like I was barking up the wrong tree.
Why are young children, is not that the city Itomori?
It's a very nice picture. Do not you, dear?
Yes, this city Itomori. Brings back memories.
He was born in Itomori.
Itomori ...?
Yes! Itomori city! That is! It's near you?
What are you ... Itomori it ...
Itomori? Impossible!
What is a comet that place ...?
prohibited from approaching
Hey, what is this place?
Impossible! Taki was definitely one to remember.
No. I'm sure this place.
It's the school yard. Mountains. I vividly remember this high school!
That can not be right!
Surely you remember the disaster that resulted in hundreds of lives passed away 3 years ago!
Died?
Died 3 years ago?
Impossible.
I still remember that he left behind ...
"NO NOTE"
Everything disappears ...
Tiamat comet, with an orbital period of 1200 years,
"THE LOST CITY ITOMORI"
Earth approaching three years ago in October.
No one is predicting meteor core will be split at the point of its trajectory.
"METEOR blow swept through the town"
CITY LIBRARY
"THE CITY THAT DESTROYED"
"More than 500 people are dead or missing"
"Itomori, Lost City"
A comet fragment into a meteor that hit Japan.
"Itomori, comets, damage"
It was a celebration of the autumn festival.
Tabrakannya point here.
At 8:42 am, a meteor crashed into a place where people gather for the festival.
"List of Names of Victims"
More than 500 people died, a third of the city population,
and now no longer living in Itomori.
Tessie dan Sayaka ...
"Mitsuha Miamizu"
Is that him? It may be a mistake. This man was dead three years ago!
New 2, 3 weeks ago, he told me that the comet will be visible.
So...
You now are dreaming ...
I...
right?
What was I ...?
Excited over the line.
Sorry, we only get one room.
No problem.
How to Taki? / He was reading an article about Itomori.
Newspapers and magazines at the time at random apparently.
What? / No. I do not know if you smoke.
Lately I wanted to stop, but ...
What do you think about the story Taki?
I like him.
His attitude lately, he's always been good, even better lately.
Looks like he's trying hard, that's cool.
What he said did not make sense to me ...
But I'm sure he has met someone and that person has changed him.
I think, I believe so.
"Disaster Comet Itomori Most Severe"
DIARIKU: it takes Ada CATATAN
All of it was just a dream.
I recognized the scene because I remember the news from three years ago.
If not that, then what ... ghosts?
No ... what are kukhayalkan?
His name ... was it?
Tsukasa pergi mandi.
Oh, Nona Okudera. Aku, uh ...
I have talked about strange things. Thank you for participating today.
No problem.
"Iron Work Location Tatara"
"Knitted Yarn Itomori"
Crochet thread. Very beautiful.
Is that what you're wearing yarn?
Oh, it's ... I think someone gave me this first time.
Sometimes I wear it for luck ...
Who gave it?
Why do not bathe too?
Yes No.
The person who made the yarn previously told me ...
This knitted represent the flow of time itself.
Rolled thread, binding, decomposes, and connected again. That is the time ...
Perhaps in that place ...
Totsuka Ku
"Around here?"
Such.
Do not you remember me?
"I have to go somewhere. Go back to Tokyo without me, I'll be back. Thank you."
Such...
Eat it there.
Figure Itomori-mu, good.
They connect and create a form. They rolled up, tie up,
sometimes unraveled and then connected again ...
Musubi ... mengikat. Itulah waktu.
That's the spot!
The place is really there!
It was not just a dream!
From here is hell.
This sake that we carry.
Which is owned by his sister, and that's mine.
Before the comet ... So Mitsuha I know is derived from three years ago?
Our timeline is not aligned.
Half her ...
Musubi.
If time could be turned back,
Give me one more chance ...
A comet!
Your name is Mitsuha.
You two are my precious.
You are now an elder.
"As soon recover, mother."
I'm sorry, dear.
Dad, when the mother can go home?
I could not save him. / And be yourself!
Who cares about the temple?
You are the son-lift! / I love my wife Futaba, not Temple Miyamizu.
Get out of here!
Mitsuha, Yotsuha,
from now on you with my grandmother.
Who am I? No, who are you?
Do not be yourself completely. Not like you were with cewekmu.
He was lucky. They must have been together now ...
I...
I will go to Tokyo. / What? Hey, Mitsuha!
Grandma, can you help me?
Oh yeah, the comet.
Today the most shining peak ...
Mitsuha! Do not just stand there!
Mitsuha, get out of there before the comet hit!
Mitsuha, go out from there!
Mitsuha! Mitsuha!
Mitsuha!
I Mitsuha! He is still alive!
Mitsuha, apa kau menyentuh ...
My sister!
Yotsuha!
Mitsuha finally mad.
I left without him.
He's crazy.
He's so crazy.
Scary.
Tiamat comet has been visible to the naked eye for a few days now.
Tonight comet finally reached the point of its trajectory around the clock 7:40,
and will achieve maximum light.
Happened tonight. There is still time.
Good morning, Mitsuha.
Oh...
Kamu bukan Mitsuha 'kan?
You know, Grandma?
No, look at the acting lately trigger some memories.
I also remember seeing a strange dream when I was young.
Although now I've forgotten what life I dreamed of.
Forgot...
Valuable experience. The dream will disappear after you wake up.
At some time your mother and I had a similar experience.
Maybe the dream was experienced by people Miyamizu
is about what will happen today.
Grandma, listen.
A comet will hit Itomori tonight and everyone will die.
"No one will believe it"? It was the usual answer is surprising, grandma.
Will not let them die!
Oh! What happened, Mitsuha?
Ram ... hair!
Oh, this. Previous look better, huh?
Oh, that's it?
Enough already! If you do not do anything, everyone will die tonight!
If we have to act!
Why are you not in school?
Uh ... we must save this city.
Without a system of community-cable? / Yes, the speakers, you see everywhere.
"Superimposition, the frequency"
I know! It could work! You are wonderful, Tessie!
Hey! Do not get too close!
What, shame huh? Hey, hey!
Stop! You have a big girl!
"Clubs Terminated - No Closer"
You are a good man!
Can already be. It kembalianmu.
Maaf, Sayaka.
It's fine.
Really cheap wages. / Just accept it.
How about you? Did you create evacuation plans?
What? Bomb?
We had a water gel explosives for construction in our warehouse.
Plowing broadcasting?
No-cable system the city is easily hijacked by using the startup frequency.
So we could broadcast a warning evacuation of the school.
Schools are outside the disaster area, so people can be evacuated here.
This ... this is really a crime!
You are doing the broadcasting.
Why? / You come broadcasting club.
I was responsible for the bombing. / I'll talk to the mayor.
At the end, the city council has mengevakusai everyone.
I was her daughter. I can persuade him.
It's a perfect plan.
Oh, whatever. This is merely an illusion "if", right?
What? Gini ...
No need! Do you know what Itomori lake formed?
"A meteor crater lake was formed 1,200 years ago."
It's a meteor crater! So meteor ever hit this area thousands of years ago!
Oh! So that's why ...
You're right, Tessie!
Let's do it together!
What actually are you talking about?
I said we should mengevakusai everyone in this town before dinner or ...
Shut up.
"The comet will break up and crash into this city"?
CENTER CITY ITOMORI
"More than 500 people will die"?
How dare you spit that shit?
If you are serious, then you're crazy.
Madness must have come from the Miyamizu.
I'll call people to take you to the hospital in the city.
I listened to your words after the doctor will examine you.
Dasar kau bring ...!
Mitsuha! Tidak ...
Who...
Who are you?
See you at the festival.
Let's meet at the temple.
Do not be late. / Dah!
Bye. / See you later.
You can not go there!
Go away from this town. Tell your friends.
This you say what? / Mitsuha!
What was that? / Let's go.
What are you doing?
Can Mitsuha ...
Can he persuade them? Is this a fault?
Youtsuha, leave this city with grandmother before nightfall.
You will die if it stays here!
This you say what?
Yesterday you suddenly go to Tokyo. What is wrong with you?
Tokyo?
Hey, Mitsuha!
How to deal with your father?
Hey, Mitsuha?
Why him?
I have no idea.
Are you there?
There is something there?
Here I borrow your bike.
Hey, what are you ...
Hey, Mitsuha! What about our plans?
Prepare according to plan!
Please!
I Taki again.
What do Taki here?
The city is ... gone.
At that point ... what I've ...
die?
Such. Such.
Do not you remember me?
I went to Tokyo. / What? Now?
Why?
Date.
You have a girlfriend in Tokyo?
Not a date.
I'll be home tonight.
If I suddenly appear, what I'm going to interrupt him? Surprise him?
He may not like.
The number you call is not active ...
There was no way we could meet.
But what if we met?
What should I do? What would I ignored him? What will be awkward?
"Comets Approaching Earth Tomorrow will Tiamat"
Or maybe...
he was quite happy to see me?
The number you call is not active ...
There was no way we could meet.
But...
one thing is certain.
If we meet, we'll know.
If you're the one that is in me.
If I'm the one who is in you.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
At that time three years ago, before I knew you ...
Such.
Um ... it's me.
Do not you remember me?
Who are you?
Sorry.
But he is Taki.
Strange girl.
Hey!
What is your name?
Mitsuha!
Namaku Mitsuha!
It was 3 years ago, you came ...
to meet me!
Such?
Mitsuha!
You are here right? In my body!
Such!
Taki, where are you?
Itu Mitsuha.
I can hear it, but ...
Taki, where are you?
Such!
Taki, do you ...
there?
Itu senja "kataware-doki".
Mitsuha.
Such.
Taki. This is true of you.
Taki! / I came to see.
It is not easy because you're so far.
But how? At that moment, I ...
Aku meminum kuchikamisake milikmu.
You drink it?
You are stupid! Very rude!
Oh yes, and you touch-touch your breasts!
How do you know?
Yotsuha beholder.
Oh! Sorry, I can not stand! It was only once.
Just once?
It does not matter how many times! Fuck.
Sorry.
Oh, this ...
Oh. Really, why do you want to see before I know you?
There was no way I could have known you.
This. I've kept it for 3 years.
Now you save.
Ya.
How?
Not bad. / You're lying!
No, I'm ... sorry.
You are so ...!
Mitsuha, there are still things you must do. Listen.
Already arrived.
Do not worry. You still have time.
Yes, I'll try.
Kataware-doki sudah hampir ...
ends.
Hey, Mitsuha. So we remember when we wake ...
Let each write our names. This.
OK!
Mitsuha?
Hey, Mitsuha?
I want to tell you.
Wherever you are in this world, I will find you.
Your name is Mitsuha.
All right, I remember.
Mitsuha. Mitsuha. Mitsuha. Namamu adalah Mitsuha.
Your name is ...
Who are you?
Why am I here?
I'm here to see him.
To save him. I want him to stay alive.
What is her name? Who? Who would I meet?
A person dear to me. I do not want to forget it. I can not forget!
Who? Who? Who? Who?
What is your name?
This world seems to still want menjinakkanku
If so, I will fight hard with honor
Such. Such. Such.
All right, I remember. Au will not forget!
Such. Such.
Your name is Taki!
And met in the most distant places of separation
"Underground station Itomori"
Tessie! / Mitsuha! Where have you been?
She said sorry for ruining your bike.
Huh? Who? / I.
Explain everything later.
The comet will fall? Is it true?
Yes! Saw it with my own eyes!
What? You saw it, huh?
So then we have no choice. Now both of us are criminals!
"Press Room"
What? I really have to?
When the city power off, the equipment there will work with backup power.
Please Sayaka! Convey this news as soon as possible!
Woo-hoo! You can!
Oh, to hell with this!
You think, soon? / I have no idea!
What's that? What's that noise?
Hey, look!
The experience, knowledge and character to grow with bold
Let kuselami yourself with unparalleled speed
In sleep in warm cola
I dream of a place that is not here
Outside the classroom window
In the morning away by car
Hey, look!
These Itomori City Hall.
An explosion has occurred in the subway station.
Accident? / Explosion?
There is a dangerous explosion and subsequent fires.
The residents in the following areas, please evacuate to high school Itomori.
Kadoiri territory, region Sakagami
Broadcast not from here? If so, who is it?
Wilayah Miyamori ...
Oyazawa region ...
Ayo, Mitsuha!
Tessie!
Everyone, run! Forest fires!
Forest fires! Evacuate quickly!
Run! Fire! / It's not safe here! Evacuate quickly!
Our time is tight! Mitsuha!
What's up?
Her name ... I can not remember her name.
Look, I do not know. You started it!
We can not evacuate all the people alone!
Go and persuade your father!
Everything is run! Go to High School Itomori!
Oh, Mitsuha.
This is not a terrorist attack! What is said to be part of Chubu Electric?
They still check it out!
The forest has not been burning? You are sure?
OK!
Stop broadcast! Find out where it came from!
Calls from the sensor station Takayama!
The high school?
Once again, residents in the following areas, please evacuate to high school Itomori ... Oh!
What are you doing? Turn it off!
Sayaka! / Oh tidak.
Apa yang telah kau lakukan, Sayaka!
These Itomori City Hall.
We now examine the accident.
Please do not panic and remain in place waiting for further notice.
Remain in place, they said.
What happened? / So we silent?
Come on, you all had to evacuate! Itomori ensconced in high school!
Katsuhiko!
What are you doing?
Maaf aku, Mitsuha.
All is over.
Meteor actually split!
Look at that! / Wow!
Let me see! Kometnya split into 2
and the meteor fall!
Nobody predicted this.
We see here a mystical scenery.
So the comet nucleus split?
What is the impact of tidal waves ...
Comets are not within the Roche limit so the point itself certainly ...
In the past, Comet Shoemaker = Levy 9 smashed and crashed into Jupiter in 1994.
At least 21 fractions.
I'm going to see it!
It is likely to melt before reaching the ground
and the possibility of a small residential area meteor crashing ...
To predict the areas ...
Being a witness to extraordinary events space, and ...
When we witnessed this firsthand
is very fortunate for us that live in the present.
Hey, who are you?
Who? Who?
Who is that?
Were a man who loves me, not to be forgotten, I do not want to forget!
Who? Who? Who are you?
What is your name?
Kometnya already broken!
So we do not forget when we wake up, let's write our names respectively.
"I love you"
Even the way you love, already smelled of scent
Even the way you walk, it sounded like laughter
The day before you disappear from this world
I can not remember your name with this ...
Better so my job than my right
To burn a whole into my eyes
Father!
Mitsuha! / Mitsuha!
Do you again ...
It was almost like a scene from a dream.
Less is more like a beautiful view.
Let us fall in love on the spot
where words like destiny and the future of reach
Taking a hand movement as they glance view us
A kind of world would we live, the lives we live,
all about life
What am I doing here?
I always find something.
This feeling came over me sometimes has.
I apply for a job because ...
Views of people who inhabit ... To build a view of the city ...
You will never know when Tokyo might also disappear.
So I helped build the scenery was left touching memories ...
How many interviews did you do?
I did not set the path.
Can not see you land a job. / Thank you very much!
Perhaps this is because the outfit.
We're no different!
I had two job offers. / I've got 8.
"LINE: You have 1 new message"
I'm not sure if I'm looking for someone or somewhere,
or if I'm just looking for a job.
Oh, ye seekers.
I'm not so lucky.
Perhaps this is because the outfit.
What I look that bad?
What brings you here today?
I came to a place near here for work so I figured what's wrong with me greet you.
"8 years since the catastrophic comet"
We never went to Itomori right?
You used to be in high school, so when it ...
5 years ago. / As long as that?
It seems that a lot of things I forgot.
I, too, do not really remember the first time events.
Maybe we clashed, two others returned to Tokyo without me.
I spent the night alone on a mountain.
That's all I remember.
But on the one hand, I can not understand images
on the events surrounding the comet.
Half the comet destroy one city in the disaster.
"evacuation of school to high school has been ensured"
"There are no deaths, 104 injured"
But almost the entire population of the city was miraculously tdak injured.
The whole town incidentally held emergency drills
"The natural disasters of unprecedented"
"The safe"
"A disaster foretold?"
"Hidden Agenda Mayor Miyamizu"
"mysterious explosion in the subway station"
and almost the entire population is outside the blast zone.
Luck thin and various newspapers circulated simultaneously.
I diligently read the articles events of that time.
What is very interesting my interest now is still a mystery to me.
Even I do not know anyone in town.
Thank you for today. This has gone far enough.
You also may one day be happy.
I feel I'm always looking for something, for someone.
"The construction company, a job interview"
I wanted to go to another wedding exhibition.
All the exhibits are the same. / Style-Shinto also nice.
You want a wedding in the chapel.
Oh, and Tessie. Losing beard before pernihakahan. I will lose 3 kg.
You eat one cake.
I'll begin tomorrow.
Totsuka Ku
"Itomori, Lost City" "October 4, 2013, Itomori disappeared"
Why view of the city
are no longer kept sticking into my existence?
A little longer, a little longer,
Will you...
let's stay together
A little longer, a little longer,
Will you...
let's stay together
I'm always looking for ...
looking ...
someone!
We are aviator-time, we are climbers-time
Do not want to get lost in this game of hide-and-seek
I will not let you go, will never forget this
My hands were finally catch up
You're crying loudly, asked me to menghentikamu
But when I saw the tears I already knew I was denied
You cry when you laugh happy when sad
Mastering yourself because your heart
Hey!
Have we ever met?
I thought so!
Your name is ...?
The wind that blows between us
Whence this wind brings grief?
Sky that we face in tears
It seems very bright
http://otakunime-ind.blogspot.com and 29 January 2017
Harsh words my father as usual
Somehow feels warm today
Do not know how to be nice and smile or talk about dreams
I should follow you all
A little longer, a little longer,
Will you...
Let's stay together
We are aviator-time, we are climbers-time
Do not want to get lost in this game of hide-and-seek
You cry when you laugh happy when sad
Mastering yourself because your heart
Toys that once I'm asking the stars in the sky
lying on the floor in the corner of my room
I begged demand 100th day
I will sell everything for one purpose someday
Talk to a girl who is usually quiet
"See you later" I say after school
Sometimes it is good too for a change, breaking the habit
Especially when you're near me
A little longer, a little longer,
Will you...
Let's stay together
We are aviator-time, I know who you are
Long before I learned my name
There must be some sense in the world without you
But without you the world as of August without a summer holiday
like Santa Claus without a smile
How sad the world as it is
We are aviator-time, we are climbers time
Do not want to get lost in this game of hide-and-seek
It's not okay, yeah this was a small
I'm on the way
We are aviator-time, we are climbers time
Do not want to get lost in this game of hide-and-seek
You're crying loudly, hoping I could stop you
But when I saw the tears I know I rejected
I wept when I'm happy I laugh when sad
Because my heart is overtaken
SELESAI [Otakunime-ind.blogspot.com] snyc City IrfanZM