Taxi!
Okay, okay.
Ohh. Ohyo.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Bye.
Bye, Bubu.
Baba, goodbye. Bye, bye!
More hot water.
Make it 48 degrees, exactly 48.
- What is this?
- What?
A blue jumpsuit. It's a boy.
Blue, blue!
Um, but Sanjay said it's a girl.
The baby in 440, boy or girl?
Zahra Kashani, did she have
a boy or girl?
- Boy.
- Girl.
Put one of each.
Dilip? Dilip?
Where am I tonight?
Shamiana. Shamiana Restaurant.
Yeah, okay. Thank you very much.
I'll call. Bye.
Prahba? We have another
VIP guest on the way.
Mrs Kashani's daughter's
arriving shortly.
Zahra Kashani.
She's just had a child
with an American.
- He's just sleepy.
- David Duncan.
- Hey, how far to the hotel?
- He's an architect.
- About two blocks, sir.
- Perfect, thank you.
I think it's like 45 minutes?
Their suite is ready
so head to the main lobby
and greet them.
They should be arriving
any minute now.
Namaste.
Congratulate them
on the baby
but do not mention the wedding.
They're not married?
They are, but Zahra was
already pregnant
so the mother insisted
on a private ceremony.
No publicity.
Oh, wow!
- Hello.
- Namaste.
- How are you, Prahba?
- Splendid to have you back.
- Oh, thank you.
- Namaste.
And this is Sally,
our nanny.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
Namaste.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you so much.
- And welcome. Namaste.
- Namaste.
- Thank you.
- This is cool.
- We hope you have a good stay.
- Thank you. Thanks, Prahba.
And so, please,
if you'd follow me.
Everything that you ordered
has been placed
but if you need anything else,
please feel free to ask.
Prahba?
Nisha's taking them up now, sir.
Have you booked
their dinner reservations?
Yes, sir. 9pm at the Shamiana.
Just book a table for
them in all our restaurants.
If she changes her mind
and we don't have room,
her mother is going to kill me.
Doing it now, sir.
This way.
Welcome back to the Taj!
Wow!
I've drawn a bath just
to your liking, 48 degrees.
Thank you, Jomon,
that's too kind.
- Oh, look at that!
- Where's my little boy?
- Want to go see Mum?
- Hello, my gorgeous boy. Yes!
- My God, how cute is this?
- Champagne!
I still think he's a bit warm.
- Oh, you think so?
- Yeah.
- Hey, baby, where's the...
- Corner cupboard.
Corner cupboard.
Shall I call a doctor,
just to be on the safe side?
Yeah. Just to be
on the safe side.
And your 9pm reservation
at the Shamiana?
I don't know. What do you think?
You want to just get
room service?
Oh, no, no, you two should go.
You could always nip back up
when he gets here.
I'll keep your reservation and
you come at your convenience
or not, as you wish.
Thank you, Jomon.
Let's go.
You're my sweets.
Come on. I'm going to go change.
Let's go to dinner.
Naughty Daddy, naughty.
There's a whole 'nother room
back here.
What's going on?
Hands.
Very good.
Turn around.
Okay, good. Very good.
Show me your socks.
Mm. Okay, relax.
You need a neat cut,
not this stretching down.
Good. Nice. Relax.
Good.
Is this a joke?
Forgive me, sir,
I... I lost my shoes.
They must have fallen
from my bag.
Go home, Arjun.
Everyone else, let's move.
- Sir, sir, please.
- Please what?
You look like a beggar.
Sir, please, I'll find some
shoes. I need this shift.
You need to leave.
Sir. Sir, please.
My wife's going to give birth
any day now.
Please.
There's an extra pair of shoes
in my room.
Under the desk.
- Thank you, sir.
- Hurry up!
..metropolis built
across seven islands
on the edge of the Arabian Sea.
Here in India's wealthiest city
rises majestically the 5-star
Taj Mahal Palace Hotel.
It's been home
for over a century
to statesmen and celebrities
across the globe.
Experience for yourself
its other-world luxury...
Armed gunmen have
just attacked CST Station,
Mumbai's main railway terminal,
gunning down more than
100 passengers and staff.
Security cameras captured
images of these two suspects
who fled the scene,
firing at pedestrians and...
The biggest worry at
this point in time
is that there is a fear
amongst the cops
who are still trying to figure
out the source of the firing
and if a police car
has been hijacked
by the perpetrators
of this gun battle.
This is the biggest fear
right now in the minds
of the police because
there was a point where
there... there came a car...
Well, there you saw,
you saw a police van,
a police Toyota Qualis
being driven...
..and indiscriminate fire.
So, these are for the Sindhi
wedding in the Ocean Room.
The kimchis are for the
trade delegation in Wasabi.
The MPs are already
at the Harbour Bar, quite drunk.
Mm-hm.
More lemongrass, huh?
Arjun!
Stop limping.
Yeah, more lemongrass.
- What about the Russian?
- Booked into the Shamiana, sir.
He has party later,
he wants help.
Okay, everyone.
Everyone listen in, please,
come on. Leave that.
Come on, come here, come here.
Yes. Okay, come on, hurry up.
Yep.
So...
..we have another VIP guest
dining at the Shamiana tonight,
Vasili Gordetsky.
- Sir.
- He can be difficult.
Mr Gordetsky,
so nice to see you again.
Whatever he says,
just smile, be polite...
..be courteous.
Remember always,
here at the Taj, guest is God.
Under no circumstances
you are to recommend seafood
to him.
He's allergic to it.
Never, ever serve him drink
in a glass, always a bottle.
And make sure that you open
the bottle
in front of him, directly.
The tall one. She has
big nipples or small nipples?
Good. Okay, send them both.
Who speaks like that?
After dinner,
Mr Gordetsky's having
a private party in his suite.
He will need a waiter.
Of course there will be
large tips.
- Sir? Olga speaks Russian.
- No.
Never a female staff.
We can't have a repeat
of last time.
Sir, I would be honoured
to serve.
No, thank you, Arjun.
Sir, please, I'll ensure that...
You will ensure that you arrive
in the proper footwear.
Sanjay, you will serve
at the Russian's party tonight.
Go to Elia's and get two bottles
of Vernier Dejeune.
- Wanjidon. Thank you, sir.
- Hold on. What did you say?
Wanjidon? What is Wanjidon?
It's Vernier Dejeune.
Verdijan?
It is Vernier Dejeune.
- With 'V'.
- 'V'. Verrrr...
- With 'V'. Vernier Dejeune.
- 'V'...
Don't repeat 'V'.
Just say Vernier Dejeune!
- 'V'...
- Not 'V', Vernier Dejeune!
Wanjidon!
Vernier Dejeune.
It's a cognac.
Go!
Wanjidon. Wanjidon.
Thank you, sir.
Wanjidon.
You won't believe
the kind of women
he's got coming over tonight.
The Russian guy, yeah.
Ha. I heard they're knockouts.
Ten out of ten, man!
Yeah. Coming in an hour. Yeah.
Oi!
What are you looking at?
Go.
Go!
Check these
dudes out. He's going off, look!
They are going nuts!
Look at him, look at
the little angry butler!
- Look at him! Check him out!
- Babe, babe, hi. Eddie!
I'm putting money
on the little butler man.
- Taj.
- Taj. Yes, let's go.
- Alright.
- Let's go.
We're going to the Taj.
Um, hang on. Let's go...
Ah, excuse me, sir.
- Namaste, mate.
- Namaste.
Um, I think we've got
a little problem here
because we didn't order
this pork thing.
Yes.
No. No, no, no, no.
I don't think so
because if you just look here,
we didn't actually...
Fuck. Bree, get down!
This way.
Come on! Come on,
come on, go! Go!
Run!
Go, babe. Go!
Come on, go. Come on! Come on!
- Are you hurt?
- I don't know. Don't think so.
If I may, ahh, 2003 was
a very good year for Bordeaux
due to the exceptional heat wave
that year.
Ah, the Château Latour there,
amazing depth,
powerful yet silky dark fruit.
A seamless finish,
it's a very good wine.
- That sounds nice.
- Yeah.
Um...
You know, why don't you just
bring me a JD and Diet Coke?
- Really?
- Yeah.
And you know what?
Bring us a cheeseburger,
for old times' sake.
Chicken or fish, sir?
No, just a regular burger. Beef.
Oh. They don't have beef here.
Yeah, they got everything here.
Honey, cows are sacred in India.
I am so sorry,
I completely spaced.
It's OK.
OK, so what do you recommend?
What's...
The lamb kofta is
very popular...
Hey, Sally.
Hey, Zahra.
No, I've just checked in
with reception.
They said the doctor's
still on their way.
No, no, he's more than fine.
Yeah, he had a big feed
and I just put him down.
Sure, I'll call you then.
But, really, we're all good.
OK.
Enjoy.
- Good evening, Taj Palace Hotel.
- Hi, there.
Just checking about the doctor.
OK, so next trip,
I have an idea,
let's go, just the two of us.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Bree! Go!
Bree, run!
Run! Go! Run!
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Wait!
Wait!
Door, man,
just fucking open the door!
Security.
Can we get security now?
Dilip, look.
We've got a reservation, mate.
Let them in!
It's OK, let them all in.
Bree, Bree.
Thank you, thank you.
Bree, come on.
Excuse me.
- Let's go somewhere else.
- Lani, is it?
Sir, I have no record
of your booking.
- Please, if we could just...
- Sir...
Listen, can we just please
call our family?
Lights. Switch off the lights.
Down. Down. Everyone down! Down.
Please. Under the tables. Down.
Bree!
No, no, no.
Under the tables. Down.
Down, down, please.
Please, down, down, sir.
- Who are they?
- Sir, down!
- They have machine guns.
- You must hide!
Go.
It's okay, it's okay.
Pick up, Sally.
- Hello?
Sir, this is the reception.
What?
- This is the reception.
- Sorry?
There's a security issue, here.
No, please don't leave
your room, sir.
I'll be in touch, sir.
Yes, yes.
Room service!
Laundry.
Hey, hey. Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Sh, sh, sh.
You're okay. Come on, Cameron.
Sh, sh, sh, sh.
Coming.
David?
Sally, thank God!
Where are you?
Sh, sh, sh. Sorry, what?
- Where's Cameron?
The doctor's here now.
Just a second. Sorry, it keeps
breaking up, I can't hear you.
Don't answer the door!
Sally!
Oh, my God!
Zahra.
Zahra, this woman just...
Sally, what's happening?
Sh, sh, sh, sh.
Sh, sh, sh.
- Houssam.
- Huh?
Come out!
- Come out!
- Imran.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Shh.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
What is happening?
Where's Cameron?
There were men with guns,
just boys.
They came in but we hid.
Shhhh.
- They came in our room?
- Oh, my God, David.
And they shot someone, David.
They just came in and they...
Okay, okay.
You stay right where you are.
- I'm coming there right now.
- Hey!
Shut your fucking mouth!
You'll get us all killed.
Look at me. I need you
to stay right here.
I need you to be strong, okay?
I love you so much.
We need the police right now.
Right now.
We've called you five times.
Please send someone.
- Sir, please, please.
- My kid's upstairs.
Sir, please.
Please, sir. Please, sir.
- Do you have a family?
- Yes, sir.
And I hope to stay alive
and see them.
- I'm going out that door.
- No, no, sir. You cannot...
- I need to piss.
- You can't.
I need to piss!
- I need to pee!
- Sir.
- Use this, please.
- Huh? You piss in this!
- I'm not an animal!
- Madam, please.
- Get out of the way!
- No, madam. Please.
Madam, this way, hurry.
Sally!
Oh, God, David.
Thank God you're here.
Oh, my God.
Where's Cameron? Where is he?
David.
Hey. Hey.
It's okay.
Hi.
Thank you. Thank you.
Who are these people?
What do they want with us?
Hey, sh, sh, sh.
Will you message Zahra for me?
Can you tell her
we made it okay?
Yeah.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay. Shhhh.
It's going to be okay.
Mumbai under siege.
Chaos has erupted
in India's financial capital
with multiple bombings
and reports of armed gunmen
rampaging through the city.
Many of Mumbai's
most popular tourist sites
are under assault.
The CST Station, restaurants
and luxury hotels
are all under attack.
Local police are simply
not trained or equipped to deal
with multiple military grade
attacks of this magnitude.
What you're seeing now is chaos
outside the celebrated
Taj Hotel.
Terrorists have laid siege
to the landmark property
with as many as 1,000 guests
and over 500 staff
trapped inside.
Mumbai has no special forces
units of its own,
meaning tactical units must be
sent in from New Delhi
over 800 miles away.
They are hours away
at the very least
and it is bedlam here
on the ground at the Taj.
Help! Help me!
Help!
My girlfriend, my girlfriend,
she's still in there. Bree!
Bree! Bree!
Bree!
Okay, okay. CCTV room.
They're still shooting
downstairs
and in the east wing.
The safest would be go up
to the Chambers Lounge.
Yes. Sixth floor.
Okay, Arjun.
Okay. Call me
if you hear anything.
Service stairs are all clear.
But our guests are trapped
all through the hotel.
I think we should try and gather
whoever we can
and take them
to the Chambers Lounge
and wait for the police
to arrive.
Sir, Olga made it
through the back exit.
We can do the same.
Yes, but our guests can't.
Not all of them.
- Sir, I have four kids at home.
- I know, Dilip.
Nobody's forcing you to stay.
So whoever wants to try
and make it out...
..this is your time.
I'm sorry, sir.
Don't apologise.
Go.
Many of you have wives...
..parents,
families at home.
There is no shame in leaving.
I've been here 35 years.
This is my home.
- I'm staying too.
I'm with you, sir.
Guest is God, sir.
Follow me.
Here. Wrap that
around your head
so they know
you are one of them.
I'm not one of them.
Sir, madam,
I just spoke to my boss.
He says we should come upstairs
to the Chambers Club.
- We'll be safer there.
- Why? You know something?
How many there are,
where they are?
I'm not sure, sir,
but the Chambers is the most
secure place in the hotel.
I know what
the fucking Chambers is.
Is the passage clear?
Yes, sir. We'll go
via the service stairs.
We'll leave
in a couple of minutes, okay?
An unknown number of gunmen
now fully control the Taj Hotel
and, according to this witness,
are methodically executing
hotel guests,
floor by floor
and room by room.
They had bombs.
There was a lot of smoke...
Shhh, Dad, you need
to calm down. I'm fine.
I don't know what they're saying
but I promise you I'm okay.
No, I know. I'm safe
and I'm in the hotel room.
They wanted anyone with
British or American passports.
The police are here now
so I'm sure we'll be out of here
any minute.
The fourth floor.
No, they haven't come up here.
They won't.
I've got to go, Dad.
I'll call you when we're out,
okay?
..inclusion of Chabad house,
a Jewish centre,
on the list of targets
adds credence to the view
that Muslim fundamentalists
are responsible.
The eight hostages at Chabad
include Jewish-American
Rabbi Gavriel Holtzberg
and his wife, Rivka,
who is six months pregnant.
Wait here.
I'll signal if it's safe, okay?
Come, come.
Come, come. Quiet.
Mr Oberoi, sir, are you there?
Sir?
Sir? Sir, it's me Arjun,
from Shamiana.
Okay.
Arjun.
Please come. Come, come.
Nothing to fear.
Please come.
Yes. Please.
Hi.
How are you, sir?
It's okay. Everything's fine.
Have a drink inside.
Mr Vasili, how are you?
Come, come this way.
Please, please, this way.
Take a seat.
You have water?
- Ma'am, I'm so sorry.
- Jomon!
I'm so sorry.
Everything will be fine now.
You're totally safe.
Sit anywhere you like, okay?
No problem.
Please, please.
- Can I help you, sir?
- I'd like a cognac.
- Vernier Dejeune.
- Of course, sir.
Quickly, quickly, quickly.
Take a seat, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention,
please?
Can you come closer?
Arjun, can you just help them?
A little further. I don't want
to speak loudly, please.
Can you come closer, sir?
Sir, ma'am? Please?
Sir, can you come forward,
please?
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm Hemant Oberoi,
head chef here at the Taj.
We are all terribly sorry
for everything you've
had to endure here tonight.
But please be rest assured
the worst is behind us now.
The Chambers is
an exclusive club,
very difficult to access.
As you can see, there are
no internal windows
and every entrance
has been secured.
We will be safe here until
police comes and fetches us.
- When will that be?
- What's taking so long?
Ma'am, they're outside right
now. It's just a matter of time.
Yes, what's important is that
we remain calm and quiet
because we want our position
to remain a secret.
REPORTER, TV:
The situation inside the hotel
is becoming utterly desperate.
Footage just in of this man,
forced to flee on a rope...
Come on. We should get going.
Going where?
Staff's moving everybody
up to the Chambers Lounge
on the sixth floor.
- They said it'll be safer.
- No way.
Sally, come on.
You can go.
I'm not going anywhere.
David, there are men with guns
killing people in the hallway.
There's no way
that I'm going out there.
I know. And Zahra's out there
and she's by herself.
They came in here and they
fucking shot her, David,
like a fucking rabbit
and if we move
and if the baby wakes
- they're going to shoot us too.
- Okay, okay.
I mean, the cops are already
outside.
Can't we just wait for them
to come and get us?
Yep. Okay.
Kanu!
It's been a night and a morning
of gun battles in Mumbai.
Perhaps never before has a city
been attacked
in a coordinated yet random
and completely mindless manner.
There's been hours and hours
of indiscriminate terror
on the streets of Mumbai
and we still don't seem to be
at the end of it.
Let's get you the big headlines
from Mumbai.
At least 78 people are dead
and nearly 200 injured
in a series of attacks
in South Mumbai.
Three five-star hotels,
a petrol pump in Colaba,
the CST Station,
the Cama Hospital,
all come under attack.
Mumbai's majestic Taj Hotel
is still burning
as gun battles continue between
security forces and terrorists.
Would you like a drink?
How much longer, Mr Savanth?
You're the Chief of Police!
What's going on?
The head of our terror
squad was gunned down
in his car tonight, Mr Oberoi,
and special forces
are yet to leave Delhi.
Still in Delhi?
Then send somebody from here.
Use the police force,
for God's sake.
We sent in a local squad
an hour ago
but we haven't heard a word
since.
I'm sorry.
I just want to be home.
Who were you speaking with?
What?
Who were you talking to
on the phone?
None of your business.
She's one of them.
- What are you trying to say?
- You're talking that language.
- Are you calling me a terrorist?
- You were talking that language.
- Just say it!
- Why won't you answer?
Why won't you tell me
who was on the phone?
- She's with me.
- I need you to tell me!
- She's one of...
- Hey! Shut your mouth!
Shut up! Walk away.
- Your behaviour is disgraceful.
- Go fuck yourself. Walk away.
Madam, come. Come.
It's okay, sir. Come.
With everything going on,
that's what she tells me?
- You're okay?
- No, seriously.
Don't worry,
she is total bitch.
- Come, come.
- Look at that face.
She's not been fucked
for ten years. Minimum.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
Fine.
It's a crazy situation
but we just have to wait.
We'll be fine.
Arjun. Arjun.
Sorry.
Yes, sir?
See the English woman
over there, at the food station?
Yes.
She's worried about your beard.
My beard?
Also, your turban.
Hang back in the kitchen
for a little bit, huh?
Good boy.
Madam, I'd... I'd like
to show you something.
This is my family.
This is my... this is my child.
It's Seva.
That's my... my wife and her
quite... quite awful sister.
This is my... this is my pagri.
To us Sikhs it is...
It is sacred.
It's a... It's a symbol
of... honour.
And courage.
Since I was a small boy,
I've... never gone outside
without it.
To do so would bring shame
to my family.
But while we are in this hotel,
you are my guest
and I am your staff,
so if it would make you feel
comfortable, I will take it off.
Would you like that?
No.
I'm just scared.
We all are.
But... to get through this
we must... we must
stick together, okay?
Yes. Indeed.
- Thank you.
I will bring you some water,
okay?
Okay.
- Hello? Mrs Watson?
- Yes, yes.
This is Lani
from the hotel reception.
Yes.
Ma'am, the rescue team is
on your floor.
- They are?
- Yes.
- They're on their way, ma'am.
- Thank God.
Yes, yes, I can hear them.
Alex, Alex, let them in.
What are you doing? Don't open
that door. What, you crazy?
- You're going to get us killed!
- Be quiet!
Mr Oberoi, sir,
it's Prahba.
- It could be a trap!
- I know what I'm doing, sir.
Oh, my God, Prahba.
It's not my blood. Come.
Sh! Sh!
Arjun, attention!
It's okay, come, come,
please come.
Please.
Please, please.
Be quiet!
It's okay. Madam.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
Is there a doctor here, please,
a doctor or a nurse?
- I'm an ophthalmologist.
- Please come.
I'm not sure if there's much
I can do but I can try.
I need to see the wound.
Sh!
Quiet! Be quiet!
Okay, we need to tape
this hole shut
and we need to make
a sling for her arm.
- Elastoplast, Sellotape...
- First-aid box!
Come, hold this, hold tight.
It's not good. I think she's
bleeding into her chest cavity.
There's no way to save her
without getting her to hospital.
- I'll take her.
- Too risky.
If she stays, she'll die.
Sir, please let me take her.
We'll go down the back stairs,
straight out the service exit.
Arjun, if they find you,
they find us.
But if I make it,
we'll have a way out.
Sh! Sh!
We can't just let her die here.
Okay.
Call me when you get out.
Deep breath.
Shhh. It's okay.
Madam, madam, madam.
I'm going to get you
out of here, okay?
But... but there are some stairs.
Do you think you can stand?
- Yes.
- Yes? Okay, come on.
Slowly. Come on.
That's it.
- Ma'am, you will be fine.
- Okay.
You'll be fine. Arjun is
with you. Don't worry.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay, madam.
It's okay, it's okay.
Sorry.
Staff. Staff.
Staff, staff. Hotel staff!
Please, please. Hotel staff.
Go, go!
Imran?
Go, go, go.
David!
Open the door. Open the door!
Sh, sh, sh.
Okay, sir.
Hey!
- Yeah, the front lobby here.
- Uh-huh.
Western entrance hall.
Our Ocean Room.
There is still some of
the good stuff left.
Single malt. 20 years old.
What the hell was that?
Hey. Stay here and stay down.
It's chaos out here, sir.
We're doing all we can.
- Have you sent the men in?
- I'm sorry, what men?
- The rescue squad?
- Yes, Mr Oberoi.
We sent in a squad hours ago,
but most were killed.
Have you sent any Mohit Singh
as part of the squad?
Shit.
Yes, Mr Oberoi, Mohit Singh
was part of the squad.
We lost contact hours ago.
We thought he was dead.
Okay, thank you.
Arjun, I cannot...
Don't open the door, it's them!
Sir? Sir?
Move! Out!
- Move!
- Down, down, down, down!
Okay.
Thank you.
Sh, sh, sh,
quiet, quiet, quiet, quiet.
Down, down, down. Down, down.
Down, down.
No, no, no, no.
Hey, hey, hey.
It's okay. It's okay.
REPORTER, TV:
That was an explosion.
There's lots
of firing inside the hotel.
Here they come. They're coming
down the steps of the Taj.
We're right here at the Taj
where this action is unfolding.
"My darling David,
"as I write this letter
"I'm hoping you'll never
have to read it.
"That I get the chance to tell
you these words in person.
"You said to me
when we first met
"if you're feeling scared,
just jump.
"You might fall,
but you might just fly.
"And you were right.
"And we did.
"I don't know
what kind of crazy kismet
"made our worlds collide.
"But if we worked,
it was because of you
"and your patience
with my family.
"Your belief in us made me feel
as if anything is possible.
"Even now.
"Even in this nightmare.
"I know you'll raise our son
to be the man that you are.
"Please remind Cameron
every day how much I love him.
"And how much I love
his father.
"Forever, Zahra."
Stop it! Stop it, Miss Kashani!
Miss Kashani, please, stop it!
- Open it!
- Please come and sit here.
I have to be with my family.
Open the door.
I know it's hard but
police are very near now.
No-one's coming.
We've been here six hours.
Six hours! For what?
No-one's coming for us.
My baby's out there.
Please open the door.
She's right.
Open the door.
- I want to go.
- Me too.
Please, we cannot evacuate
everyone without being detected.
It's not everyone.
We are six people, that's all.
We're going. Open the door.
Sir...
..if they hear us going,
we will all die.
They know we are here.
If they come back, we all die.
If they bomb the building,
we die.
If we leave, maybe we die.
We take our chances.
Open the fucking door.
Now.
Very well, sir.
- We'll be praying for you, sir.
- Yeah, fuck your prayers.
That's what started this shit.
Let's go.
Zahra!
Hey!
This is stupid. Go. Let's go.
I'm getting my baby.
Run!
Hey!
It's okay.
They won't kill us.
They want us alive. It's okay.
Where's Cameron?
You don't know me.
Indian? Huh?
Animals.
No!
No, no, no, no, no! No!
These images,
taken around 4am,
show the moment security forces
and angry citizens
confronted the two gunmen
beating them with sticks.
The gunmen had earlier
hijacked a police van,
and are thought to have been
behind the CST station attack.
Both men suffered
multiple bullet wounds
from which one died,
while the other, Ajmal Kasab,
is now in custody.
The city is really on edge.
At the moment,
there are still terrorists
at loose in Mumbai.
The military seem to have
worked out that they are...
- What...
- ..is...
- ..your...
- ..name?
I am nobody. I'm salesman.
My name is Peter.
I'm nobody.
Hey, hey.
Vasili Gordestky.
You know who I am.
- Vasili Gordetsky?
- What?
The president and co-founder
of NV Capital,
former officer
in Soviet Special Forces.
So fucking what?
You want money? Hm?
I can get you money.
Your money will not
save you here.
You will die for what you did
in Afghanistan.
You know what I did
in Afghanistan?
I fucked your mother!
I fucked your sister, you prick!
Please. Oh, no.
Stop, stop, please, please,
please.
Staff, staff. I work here.
Please go this way.
Sir. Please, they'll shoot you.
Sir, they'll shoot you. Please.
Trust me. Trust me. Follow me.
Please, I'm staff, follow me,
sir. Please follow me.
Follow me. Please, follow me.
This way.
Come.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Sir!
Sir.
Sir. Open the door!
Shh.
- Sir, sir, it's Arjun.
- It's Arjun. Open the door.
Oh, my God.
Please come.
Please, come this way.
Go, go, go. This way, sir.
Please come, ma'am. Yes, ma'am.
Come, come.
This way, sir.
Zahra! Zahra!
Please, don't worry.
Sorry, sir. There was
nowhere else to go.
They set fire to the hotel.
It's a baby.
What do you want me to do?
Sally has Cameron.
They're in the utility closet
next to room 415.
4... 1... 5.
No.
David. David.
Sh!
- Shut that baby up.
- Please listen. Please listen.
- They'll get us killed, Oberoi!
- Please listen, sir.
The central part of the hotel
is burning.
Security forces will not be here
in time.
We must leave
by the safety stairs
and out through the kitchens.
They'll find us,
they'll shoot us and kill us.
Sir...
Sir, the hotel is burning.
This is our only choice.
And everybody trusted you!
We're not safe anymore.
Sir, please keep quiet.
Sir. So please switch off
your mobile phones
and be as quiet as possible.
If we are together,
we'll be fine.
Mobile phones off, please.
Switch off your mobile phones
and keep quiet.
- Sir, please, please.
- Mobile phones off.
- Sir. Sir!
The fighting is
still going on.
Let's speak to Pranav Sahni,
who is on the ground
at the Taj. Pranav.
We have one of
the trapped guests on the line,
RX Capital's Mr Vijay Goswami.
Good to hear from you, sir.
Listen to me, nobody knows
what's going on here, okay?
We're in the Chambers Lounge,
north wing.
There are many
important people here.
- What are you doing?
- We need help immediately!
What are you doing?
- I was trying to get help!
- They'll find our location!
You're supposed to be
on my side! Hey!
We've just been
informed of a daring escape
now underway at the Taj, with
reports of up to 100 guests
breaking out of the
exclusive Chambers Lounge,
located deep inside
the burning hotel.
No, please, sir, no!
I have kids that need me!
Argh!
No, please!
No, please don't!
No.
I love you so...
Excuse me. Sorry. I'm sorry.
Sorry, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Let's go. Come.
Sh, sh, sh. Hey, darling.
Come.
Go! Go! Go!
Move, move. Move!
Go, go, move, move, move!
Go. Come on!
Run, run!
Sir!
Sir, please.
Sir! Please, sir!
Sir, go! Please, go!
Run!
Run, run!
Move! Move! Go!
Go! Move!
Help! Help!
Up, up.
Okay, ma'am. Okay.
Sally?
Sally? Sally?
Zahra!
- Sally!
- Zahra!
- Zahra! Zahra.
Thank you.
Thank you, Sally, thank you.
One, two, three!