Spanish subtitles in white
[ Mixteco subtitles in brackets ]
Other languages not subtitled
You need a bath, Borras.
- [ Manita, manita. ]
- [ Yes? ]
- [ It's almost 1pm. ]
- [ I'm coming. ]
- Manita, my keys...
- [ There they are. ]
- [ I'm leaving. ]
- [ Take care. ]
Borras, stay.
- Don't let him out.
- Hi, Borras.
[ Manita, manita!
Fermín is on the phone. ]
What are you saying?
- [ Go away. ]
- [ Ok, but I want to know. ]
- What are you saying?
- Go upstairs.
Stop talking like that.
Go.
- [ What did Fermín say? ]
- [ Just hello. ]
[ Yeah right. ]
You're dating!
[ Of course not. ]
He's just a friend.
- Besides, you introduced us.
- I'm just messing with you.
They're home.
Borras.
Borras, stay.
Come in.
So that kid was throwing water balloons
at cars that were driving by.
Then an army jeep drove by,
the kid throws a balloon at it,
the solider gets mad,
he gets out, and shoots him.
Oh God! Is he ok?
He shot him in the head.
He's dead.
How awful.
Adela?
Mrs. Sofia is here
and the kids want strawberries.
Hurry.
Thank you.
- I got an A plus.
- That's great!
And Sofi did, too, I imagine.
Cleo, my husband's two suits
need to be taken to the cleaners.
But do it today, please.
He needs to pack, he's leaving Friday.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Thank you.
- Dad's going away?
- To a conference in Quebec.
- Where is that?
- In Canada!
- You're so stupid!
- I didn't know, so what?
Not for Sofi, she'll get fat.
...when I tell you that I'm poor,
you won't ever, smile again...
...I long to have it all,
and lay it at your feet...
...But I was born poor,
and you'll never love me.
- You shouldn't be up here.
- I'm taking care of him.
Your mom won't like it.
Don't go near the edge.
- You were supposed to die.
- Why me?
- 'Cause it's my game.
- Then I don't want to play anymore.
Well, I don't want you to play it,
you little sissy.
And what's up with you?
Aren't you gonna tell me?
- Can't talk. I'm dead.
- Then resurrect.
- I can't. I'm dead.
- Alright then.
What are you doing?
Tell me.
I can't. I'm dead.
Hey. I like being dead.
Here, Borras.
Dad's home early!
- Who's here?
- Daddy.
- Hello.
- Who are these kids?
- I'm glad you're home early.
- What a surprise!
-Money for the hurdy gurdy?
-I don't see any.
No, money to get one.
- So tell me Your Excellence.
- Your Excellence.
Thank you, sir.
-Have you heard the latest news?
-What about?
Hawaii, Doctor.
I'm very well, thank you.
-Cleo, can you get the Doctor a tea?
- No! She's with me!
- She'll be right back.
-Just a few more minutes.
[ Scoot. ]
[ Hey! ]
Make Dr. Antonio a chamomile.
[ Move. ]
Angel of God, my guardian dear...
...to whom God's love commits me here.
Ever this day, be at my side...
...to light and guard,
and rule and guide.
[ Little one, sleepy little one. ]
[ Sleep with the angels. ]
Time to sleep, my darling.
- Good night, Cleo.
- Good night, Sofi.
I love you.
I love you too.
Sweet dreams.
You too.
Toño, go to sleep!
...and if your mom asks
when you'll be back?
I'll call her.
Where's my brown tie?
- I'll ask Cleo.
- This house is a mess.
The fridge is full of empty cartons
and there's dog crap everywhere.
- [ Why so long, manita? ]
- [ Pepe turned on the lights again. ]
[ He's a prankster. ]
- Yes. My boy.
- Little devil.
Yes. But I love him.
Turn off the light.
[ Mrs. Teresa doesn't
like it on. ]
[ Oh that Mrs. Teresa.
She is probably spying on us. ]
Yeah, she's there stalking you.
- Hurry up.
- She probably stays awake.
Taking care of us.
Taking care we don't
waste electricity.
- Ready?
- Yes.
One.
Two.
Three.
[ Mrs. Adela. ]
One.
- For the tamales.
- They were yummy.
Two.
For the tortas.
- [ I won. ]
- [ We drew. ]
- [ No, I won. ]
- [ But the car! ]
[ Let's eat. ]
No movement yet.
Professor Zovek is used
to challenges.
[ Do you remember 'pushy' Moises,
from home? ]
- [ He kept sending me letters. ]
- [ What did they say? ]
[ That he can't stop
thinking about me. ]
[ That he needs to see me. ]
[ Then my cousin arrives carrying
a bunch of letters. ]
[ And I recognized Moises'
handwriting on one. ]
[ So I grabbed it and opened it. ]
[ "I can't stop thinking about you.
I want to see you." ]
- [ Sweet thing. ]
- [ Yeah right, 'sweet'. ]
- [ That letter was for another girl! ]
- No!
The bastard sends exactly the
same letter to all the girls.
Why so lonely with your tacos?
Hello, Ramón!
Hello, Fermín!
- You guys want a bite?
- Thanks, we ate.
If you're done, let's go.
I like watching the previews.
Let's go.
- You really feel like seeing a movie?
- I like movies. Don't you?
But it's so nice outside.
Yes, it's nice.
Want to go to the park?
Sure.
Give me a sec.
What, you not coming?
- It's really nice outside.
- Look at you.
I'd rather play in the dark.
Tell me everything later.
Shall we?
- What?
- You train every day?
I must.
I owe my life to martial arts.
I grew up with nothing.
My mother died when I was a kid.
I moved with my aunt to the slums.
There my cousins beat me.
And I met the wrong crowd.
And I started drinking, and then huffing.
I was dying.
But then I discovered martial arts.
And everything came into...
...focus.
Just like when you look at me.
[ Kitty, kitty,
sleepy kitty cat. ]
[ Wake up as here
comes the mouse. ]
- Good morning, my princess.
- Morning, Cleo.
Time to wake up.
I need to pee.
- Good morning, Sofi.
- Good morning, Grandma.
Paco.
Wake up, my angel.
Come on.
It's time.
- I want one!
- They're mine.
- I got them for everyone.
- But I put them in the freezer.
Give Sofi one and I'll
get you a box.
Hurry up kids, it's 7:20.
Nah-huh, it's 7:17.
Here. Get fatter.
- Turn that off!
- No!
- Turn it off!
- Ok, I'll turn it off.
- Cleo, hold the dog.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Get out my way!
- You get out of my way!
Shotgun!
- Put on Radio Exitos!
- I'm up front. I choose.
- Be careful.
- Move over.
- Change the station!
- No, it's Creedence vs. Beatles.
- Move!
- Calm down, for God's sake!
You choose when
it's your turn.
- Settle down.
- Shut up.
- I'm not going to shut up.
- You too, quiet!
When I was old, you were there,
but you were someone else.
- When you were old?
- Yes.
- Or when you get old?
- No, when I was old.
- And when was that?
- Before I was born.
- And what did you do then?
- I was a pilot.
- A pilot?
- Yes, a fighter pilot.
- Did you like it?
- No, it was scary.
Was it?
I'll be right back.
- [ Good evening. ]
- [ Why didn't you wake me? ]
God forbid you'll get tired.
Prepare Dr. Antonio's oatmeal.
- Mom!
- Good morning!
Your juice.
Pepe will wait to say
goodbye to Daddy.
- It's fine if he's late.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I'll take the bags, Doctor.
- Thanks.
- Hi, Daddy!
- Your oatmeal is ready, Doctor.
Pepe waited to say goodbye.
Morning, Pepón!
Yuck! Cigarette!
- Damn...
- Mom, Daddy stepped on dog poo.
- Let me help you, Cleo.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Bye, Pepón!
- Bye, Daddy.
- Take care.
- You too.
- Go with Cleo.
- Yes, Mom.
- We'll be here, Antonio.
- It's just a few weeks.
Goddamnit! I've told you
to clean up the dog shit!
I'll take him. Come on.
- Bye, Cleo!
- Bye.
Hey, I have to...
It's just that, I'm late.
I think I'm pregnant.
Ah, well.
That's good, right?
Yes?
Yeah.
- I need the bathroom.
- But it's almost over.
Yes, but I have to go now.
I won't be long.
- Want an ice cream?
- No.
No strings!
No tricks!
Boom!
Bones is dead!
It's raining, it's pouring!
The old man is snoring...
[ Manita. You take it. ]
[ Don't be afraid. ]
- And when they ask about their dad?
- Say he's on a business trip.
Thank you, Cleo.
Mrs. Sofi? When you have
a minute can we talk?
Sure,
but just call the kids first.
Ok.
- Stay calm.
- Paco, Toño, your mom is calling you!
- You have to be strong for the children.
- Okay, Mom.
Sofi, Pepe, your mother
is calling you.
Come, sweetie.
We'll come back after.
- I got more hail than Sofi!
- I got more than Pepe!
- No, I got more.
- You both have the same.
- I'm going to the stationers.
- You can go later. Sit down, Cleo.
I have news.
- We're going to Disneyland!
- Yeah, Disneyland!
No. We're spending Christmas
at your uncle's.
- It's so boring there!
- No it isn't, my cousins are there!
And New Year's,
we'll go to the Bárcenas' Hacienda.
Are the Richards going?
- And the Larssons.
- When's Dad coming?
His research is keeping
him in Quebec a little longer.
- Until January?
- He doesn't know.
But I brought paper so you
can write him a letter.
Tell him that you love him and
to please come home soon...
I'm going to the store.
You're not going anywhere
until you're done with your letter.
- Where are you going?
- Can't I write it in my room?
No!
- Sure. Go to your room.
- Then I'm going up too.
Sofi, I need to talk with Cleo.
Help Pepe write his letter at the table.
Help him write,
"I miss you a lot, Dad".
- Make lots of pretty drawings.
- Let's go, Pepe.
Wait, Sofi!
Come, Cleo.
What's up?
What is it?
Are you alright?
- Yes.
- Sure? What's wrong?
- Is your mom alright?
- Yes.
- Oh, Mrs. Sofi...
- What's wrong?
It's just that I think
I'm pregnant.
- What do you mean you "think"?
- I haven't gotten my period.
- Since when?
- I don't know...
- Who's the father?
- Fermín. The cousin of Adela's boyfriend.
- Does he know?
- He's gone.
Silly.
- Are you going to fire me?
- Fire you? Of course not!
We have to take
you to get checked.
- Look, Mom! I drew a plane.
- Let's see.
Why is Cleo crying?
She has a tummy ache.
Pain, pain, go away.
I don't want this pay to stay.
Sofi! I told you to help Pepe
write "I miss you a lot, Dad".
He wouldn't let me help!
Sorry.
We have an appointment
with Doctor Vélez.
- Under what name?
- Cleodegaria Gutiérrez.
Here she comes.
- Sofía!
- Margarita! How are you?
Thank you for seeing us.
Remember Cleo?
- Hi, Cleo, how are you?
- Fine, thank you, Doctor.
I'm going to check her
and we'll see you later.
Ok. I'll go to say
hi to Dr. Zavala.
It'll take about 40 minutes.
Cleo, come with me.
When was your last period?
About when?
Three months.
Are you sexually active?
You are.
When did you start?
Has it been long?
- Not long.
- One or two years?
- Less.
- But more than three months?
How many sexual partners
have you had?
Just one?
Don't worry. This is common.
We'll examine you from the waist down...
...she'll get you in position.
Lie down, carefully.
Put one leg here.
And the other here.
I'll see you in a month.
Any questions?
There she is.
I'll go with you.
He hasn't even
called the kids.
- Mario!
- Doctor.
- How's Cleo?
- Cleo is fine.
She's three to four months
pregnant.
With some rest she'll be fine.
- When's she due?
- Around the end of June.
- Thanks for seeing her.
- It's nothing!
- Take care.
- You too.
- Mario.
- Doctor.
- Take care.
- Thanks.
Cleo, why don't you go to see the
newborns...
...while I finish up with Dr. Zavala?
You have to talk to Antonio.
- Look at your little sister, Azucena.
- I'm glad she's a girl.
Yes. So you can play with her.
I'll do her hair, and bathe her...
Soon we'll take her home so
you can play with her.
Earthquake!
Kneel.
Get the babies out!
- Don't run!
- Use the stairs!
"Our Father, Who art in Heaven..."
Hurry, the babies!
Are they gonna be talking in English
the whole time?
Yes. And Ricky isn't even Gringo,
he was born in Mexico.
- Yes, but his mom is Gringa.
- Leslie scares me.
She makes me feel like I stink.
Because you do stink, fatty.
You smell even more, idiot.
Stinky.
Shut up, idiot.
- Comadre, welcome!
- Hi, "commy".
- That belly of yours?
- I'll tell you later.
- Yes, you will.
- Sure, but give me a hand.
You sure you
can carry it all?
I'm pregnant, not sick.
Why, you tired?
- As if!
- You've got so old since last year.
Mountains are old,
but they're still green.
Here! You're pregnant
and forgetful?
- That's one bed.
- This goes here.
And there's the other.
This one's for Paco.
They were in storage.
They're all the dogs
that lived here.
Look. That there
was Pirata...
...he died in 1911.
- Do you remember Canela?
- Yes, where is she?
Look at her.
She died last summer.
They say she ate a poisoned rat.
But I'm sure it was the villagers
angry with Don José over the land.
Come on.
What do you think
of these city folks, Celso?
- Should we send for more bullets?
- There's plenty, Doctor José.
Paco! Don't go there!
Cleo, get him.
Paco, I'm telling you.
Stay there!
What? Women don't shoot?
No, no, no. Not that.
Leslie is our representative.
- Doesn't count, she's a Gringa.
- Ok, I'll go.
You look great, Lola.
Watch out Pepe! Your wife is
going to join the guerrilla!
- She's going to expropriate your hacienda!
- Nah, I'll whack her first.
- Come with me.
- Where?
- Just come.
- What about him?
Is the boogeyman coming?
Where are we going?
Don't ask.
The city's made you distrustful.
No, Benita.
- Look at the dogs.
- They're tired.
The kids won't leave
them alone.
Be careful, don't roll down
with that belly of yours.
No, Benita.
- There's a lot of music.
- It's New Years!
Should I call Lupe and Yola?
No, no, no.
We don't want those city nannies here.
They feel fancier than their bosses.
Come on.
- They allowed you out?
- Move aside.
Sit here.
- What are you drinking?
- Nothing, thank you.
You're not going to toast the
New Year with us?
- It's not good for the baby.
- A little won't hurt.
Celebrate while you can!
See that man over there?
They killed his son in
August over the land dispute.
- You're carrying life, right?
- Yes.
- So then? Mezcal?
- No, just a little pulque.
That's the spirit!
Here.
To a beautiful 1971 and
your baby's health!
- Sorry, Manita...
- Go dance, Gloria!
Don't worry.
I'll pour you some more.
Here.
Clean yourself up.
Salud!
- What's wrong with you?
- I know you need it.
- Billy, no!
- I just wanted to comfort you.
- You're drunk.
- You're not even that hot, comadre.
Fire!
Fire!... Fire!...
The forest is burning!
Everybody! Quick!
Fire in the woods!...
Come on! Move!
This way, everyone!
Careful!
Cover that side!
- Come here. Now!
- We need water!
Make a chain!
We need water!
Pass the buckets!
Kids! Stay back!
Kids! Don't step on the flames!
Cleo, help the little ones
get water.
Just the little fires.
That's it, Andy!
Gerardo, Cleo will help you.
Not too close to the fire!
I got one!
It ran away!
Got it!
- We'll reach the hill skirt and come back!
- Skirt?
- The hillside.
- The hill has a skirt?
- The slope then!
- Alex! The hill has a skirt!
If we look under we
can see its panties.
- What are you doing?
- Peeking at the hill's panties.
Hills don't have panties.
- Neither do you!
- Asshole!
I'm going to tell your parents!
This feels like my village.
It's drier there.
But it feels like it...
The animals do that too.
It sounds like this.
And smells the same.
They repaired the Galaxy.
It looks like new!
The Cowboys won because
Baltimore got cocky.
- We won anyway!
- Baltimore got cocky...
- Who likes the Cowboys?
- And Cruz Azul champions forever!
- Hello, Beto.
- Afternoon, Señora.
- Can we go to the movies?
- To see what?
- Marooned.
- I wanna see it too.
- Only Beto and me.
- Why?
- I wanna go too!
- No!
- Everyone can go!
- Not fair!
- I'm going.
- You're not.
- Everyone goes!
- That's not fair!
If you don't like it,
go live elsewhere!
Mrs. Molly is on the phone.
- I'll get it upstairs.
- I'll take them.
No! You won't like it.
- I like movies.
- Not this one.
Eat poo!
- Is it a cartoon?
- No, it's not.
- You don't know what Marooned is.
- Yes, I do!
We're late!
Are you coming?
- Grandma, we need to go.
- Toño, let's go. We're leaving!
Wait! I'm coming.
- Catch him!
- Hurry up!
Come on, we're late!
What are you waiting for?
Don't run!
- Toño!
- Run!
- Cleo, get them!
- I'll see you at the movies!
Control your children!
- Check her out!
- Look at her!
Antonio.
Hey, watch out!
- Look, your dad!
- Run, Antonio, run!
- No, it wasn't my dad.
- Yes, it was your dad.
I said no!
Put the magazine away!
Your grandma is worried.
Come on, let's get the tickets.
...following our illustrious governor
instructions...
...to improve the infrastructure,
I've come here today...
...to respond to your
demand for water.
This can only happen by
uniting the will of the people...
...with the leadership of our illustrious
President Luis Echeverría Álvarez.
Excuse me, do you know
where this address is?
- That way.
- Thank you.
We will move... above and beyond!
Ramón!
Hold up.
Wait.
- What's up, Cleo?
- Hi.
I just came to give
Fermín his jacket.
- I'll give it to him.
- But, I need to talk to him.
- He's not here.
- It's important.
But we're rehearsing.
Adela said you
would help.
One sec.
Hold on to this.
Can you give me a ride?
Let's go.
Hold on, let me
put on some pants.
Here is where he trains.
Thank you, Ramón.
- Don't tell him I brought you.
- No. Thank you.
Right flank!
- It's Zovek.
- No! Really?
Yes! Look at him.
- The Professor Zovek?
- Yes!
Does he always come here?
No. But sometimes
he trains them.
Welcome!
May the energy dwell in you.
You.
You...
...and you as well!
You can become a warrior!
Every human has a great potential...
...that can be developed
through physical training.
Yes! But most importantly through
the evolution of the mind...
...and the spirit.
You can develop this potential.
But don't expect a miracle!
The only miracle resides
within your own will.
Remember, the mind
is the motor for the physical.
And next up next...
an act.
This act requires total
physical and mental focus.
Only the Lamas, martial arts masters
and a few great athletes...
...have been able to master it.
You.
Yes, you. Come here.
Please cover my eyes.
Make sure they are properly covered.
Thank you. You may return to
your place.
What? Disappointed?
What did you expect?
For me to levitate or lift a jet?
You are witnessing an
incredible feat!
If you don't believe me?
Then try it.
But with your eyes closed.
Hey, Lobo!
Hey, Fermín.
What about the new trainers?
- The Korean coach is good.
- Yes, but tough.
Fermín.
Do you have a minute?
Piss off!
- Hi, Cleo.
- Hi, Fermín.
What brings you around?
I've left you messages,
but I couldn't find you.
I'm sorry, training has been intense.
They even brought a gringo coach
and a Korean.
Well, the American was already here,
but the Korean is new.
- Is it for the Olympics?
- Something like that.
Who told you I was here?
A neighbor's brother-in-law
trains here with you.
- It was Ramón.
- No.
I'm gonna kick that
fat fucker's ass.
- It's just that I'm pregnant.
- What's it to me?
- It's that... The little one's yours.
- No fucking way.
- I swear it is.
- I told you, no fucking way.
And if you don't want me to beat
the shit out of you and your "little one"...
...don't ever say it again,
and don't ever come looking for me again.
Fucking servant!
Hurry up, Fermín!
He went with his mistress
to Acapulco.
He hasn't sent a dime,
and it's been six months.
He says he's short on money
and doesn't have any to send.
But now he likes diving,
and is buying all the gear.
You know how much that costs?
He sent the kids a letter
pretending he's in Quebec.
Just bullshit he invents:
That the landscape is beautiful...
That he misses them
but his research is delayed.
Lies!
- Ok, don't worry, I'll call you later.
- Paco, come here.
Are you spying on me?
I'm sorry, my love. I'm sorry!
And you! Why did
you let him? Why?
Why are you still there?
Don't you have anything to do?
Get out!
Please, don't tell your siblings.
You're winning by two laps!
He's passing you, Paco!
But I'm still winning.
- I want to play!
- No. Move!
- Move, Pepe.
- No.
- Move!
I said move!
- That's mine, Paco!
- No, it's mine.
Cleo!
- They're fighting.
- I'm coming.
Paco, Toño, stop!
You're going to get hurt!
You're not animals!
Let him go!
Paco, drop that!
What are you doing!
Drop that!
Don't be an idiot!
Are you stupid?
You could've killed him!
It's very dangerous.
[ Hey manita. ]
[ I heard the government
came to the village... ]
[ ...to seize land, and they've
taken your mom's. ]
- [ How can I help her? ]
- [ You could go see her. ]
- [ Like this? ]
- [ Don't worry. ]
[ Go rest, I'll open the gate. ]
We are alone.
No matter what they tell you,
we women are always alone.
We'll have to park here.
The students are protesting.
Oh, God. I hope they don't
beat them again.
Look. Someone's leaving.
Go ahead.
Good afternoon, Señora.
My maid needs a crib.
Can you show them to us?
- She'll show them to you.
- Thank you.
This way, please.
How about this one?
- Do you like it, Cleo?
- It's very pretty.
How much is it?
No, but with a
long-standing client discount.
Let me ask the manager.
We bought the furniture for
the boy's room here.
Which is now in
Sofi and Pepe's room.
- The blue set?
- Yes.
Please help me!
They're killing us!
Where is he?
Get in!
Leave him alone!
Move!
- Shut up!
- Come here!
I said shut up!
Fermín!
Let's go!
Let's go! Now!
Help me!
Help!
Be calm, Cleo.
Ignacio!
Help me!
Jorge, please, let's go!
Why?
Help!
Help me!
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee...
Dr. Vélez!
- Dr. Vélez!
- Get in line!
- You have an appointment?
- Her water broke.
- Find Dr. Vélez.
- Here she comes.
Doctor, your patient is here.
Orderly, please.
Sofía just called me.
Hello, ma'am.
Cleo, you're having contractions.
Let's get her to delivery.
You'll have to fill out some forms.
Paty, take their information.
We're going to delivery.
Yes, doctor.
Please, come this way.
- What's her full name?
- Cleodegaria Gutiérrez.
- Her middle name?
- I don't know.
- How old is she?
Her date of birth?
- What's your relationship with the patient?
- I'm her employer.
Is there any family
member here?
- No. No.
- That's fine.
One last question.
Is your patient insured?
Good evening.
Careful.
Let's go.
One moment, please.
Excuse me.
Doctor.
Hello, Cleo. How are you feeling?
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
Isn't it, Dr. Vélez?
How many babies have you delivered?
Hundreds, doctor.
Give me your hand.
And breathe.
- We must hurry.
- Yes, doctor.
Excuse me.
Over here.
This way.
Dr. Vélez won't let me go in.
You'll do great, Cleo.
Feel free to come if you like.
- I can't. I have an appointment.
- Come on, let's go.
I'm taking a patient to delivery.
Ask admissions for her file.
Please assist me.
Pass me the partogram.
Let's examine her.
Yes, doctor.
She's in labor.
Her water broke.
Cleo, when was your last period?
September.
I'm removing your underwear
and shoes.
We're moving you into position.
- I'm going to listen to your baby.
- When did your water break?
- Around two hours ago?
- We couldn't get here quicker.
- Don't worry. Breathe.
- I'm uncovering your belly.
Easy, Cleo.
Breathe deep.
- How is the heart rate?
- I can't hear anything, doctor.
- A glove, please.
- Glove, doctor.
I need you to breathe deeply.
I'm going to inspect you.
It'll bother a bit.
- Relax. Easy, please.
- It's going to hurt a little.
- How is it?
- Complete. Direct. Third plane.
- Meconium liquid, doctor.
- We need to canalize.
- Moving patient to surgery.
- Let me listen to your baby.
Easy.
- I'm not hearing anything, doctor.
- Let's move.
Get the stretcher.
Cleo, breathe deeply.
We're taking you to surgery.
Ok. One, two, three.
- Let's go!
- Easy.
Patient coming through.
Call pediatrics!
- Call pediatrics.
- No scrubs. It's an emergency.
Turning on lamp.
Everyone ready?
One, two, three.
Pediatrics to surgery!
Move your waist
further down, please.
Doctor, she's crowning.
No time for your scrubs.
- Pediatrician to the room!
- He's in the room, doctor.
- Doctor, she's crowning.
- I'm checking.
Where is the pediatrician?
I'm here, doctor.
Patient ready to deliver.
The head is out.
Edwin, please.
Cut the cord.
- Tongs.
- Cut the cord, please.
Cutting.
- We couldn't hear a heart rate, doctor.
- Bulb.
Your stethoscope.
We're going to give you
a few stitches.
- I can't hear a heartbeat.
- Listening.
It's in arrest. Begin resuscitation.
Your placenta is coming out.
- One, two, three.
- Ventilating.
Listening.
Your placenta is coming out.
Ma'am, I can't hear
a heartbeat.
Placenta coming out.
- One, two, three.
- Ventilating.
Listening.
No response.
- Another cycle, doctor?
- Let's continue.
- One, two, three.
- Ventilating.
- Here it is, doctor.
- Listening.
No response.
We're suspending CPR.
- Doctor, what's the patient's name?
- Cleo, doctor.
Cutting...
Cleo, I'm very sorry.
Your baby was born dead.
We did all we could, but
there was no response.
Would you like to hold it?
Here is your baby.
It's a girl.
Say goodbye to her.
I need to take her now, Cleo.
Let me have her, please.
I need to prepare her.
Allow me...
- Prepare her, please.
- Yes, doctor.
...Gutiérrez, Cleodegaria.
Here's the file, doctor.
There's a bit of bleeding.
We gave you a few stitches.
We're very sorry, Cleo.
Cleo! The knife sharpener!
[ Shake yourself off. ]
- Toño! Sofi! Come!
- Mom bought a new car!
- You like it?
- How fast does it go?
Why not a Maverick?
Too expensive.
I wanted a smaller car.
- I've had it with that Galaxy.
- I like it, Mommy.
- What about the Galaxy?
- I sold it.
- It goes next week.
- Does Dad know?
No, it's a surprise.
- Do you like the new car, Cleo?
- Yes.
And speaking of surprises.
We're taking the Galaxy
for a goodbye trip.
- Where to?
- Tuxpan.
Where's that?
- I've got a match.
- Skip it.
Tuxpan is near Veracruz.
- Is there a beach?
- Yes.
The beaches in Veracruz are ugly.
And we're going to invite
Cleo along, right?
Yes!
Will you come?
Come on. It'll do you good.
-Right, Adela?
-Yes, ma'am.
Besides, the kids will miss you
if you don't come.
But she'll be on vacation,
you can't make her work.
- Will you come?
- [ Go Manita. I'll take care of the house. ]
So, you're coming?
Perfect!
Would you help me pack?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Let's go pack.
[ Go. It'll lift your spirits. ]
- I'm gonna help her pack.
- Pepe, bring the guns.
Stop changing it.
- La Pantera doesn't reach this far.
- I just heard it.
- That's not true.
- Yes, it is.
No, it's not! It's only in the city.
Look! The sea!
Mom, stop, stop!
- Let's go to the hotel first.
- No. It'll be dark by then.
Beach! Beach!
Alright.
But just for a little bit!
Yeah!
Let's go.
- Come.
- No, I don't know how to swim.
Come on.
You go.
I'll watch you from here.
- Which way?
- Follow me.
- Can we go back again?
- Yes, of course.
- But now a hot bath.
- Yes.
I want to go back.
It was amazing!
I jumped over a huge wave!
Ow! Mom. Ow! Don't!
- Ow! It burns!
- I'm almost done.
Did you like the waves?
I did.
Do you know how to dive
under them?
Have you gone mute?
No. Let's go.
- I told you to put on a t-shirt!
- But it was cloudy!
The glare burns the most.
Dressed already?
Yes, but Cleo's gone mute.
- Thank you, Cleo.
- You're welcome, ma'am.
You two smell like salad.
Children...!
Kids! Listen!
I have something to tell you.
Your dad isn't in Ottawa.
- Is he back?
- No. Your dad never went away.
Well he did, but only for a week.
Your dad isn't coming back home.
We came here so he
can take his things.
- What things?
- What he says are his things.
His clothes... his books...
the bookcases...
Are you getting a divorce?
- He doesn't know.
- He doesn't love us anymore?
Of course he loves you,
a lot.
- He says he wants to see you.
- When?
He doesn't know.
But soon.
There's going to be changes.
But we'll be together!
And it's going to be an adventure!
I'm starting a full-time job
at a publishing house.
But you're a biochemist.
I know, but your dad
hasn't sent us any money.
And teaching isn't enough.
And I love books!
And I never really liked biochemistry.
It'll be another adventure.
And we must stay together,
really close.
- Right, Cleo?
- Yes.
Very, very close...
Darling?
Are you finished?
For dessert, we have ice cream...
...coconut, strawberry...
...vanilla, banana...
...and flan.
Ready for the picture.
- Are you coming in?
- No, I have to go check the tires.
We're leaving early tomorrow.
Want to come?
- No, it's our last day.
- I want to stay too.
Ok, but no swimming.
Cleo can't swim.
- But it's really calm.
- If you want to stay, that's the rule.
- Near the shore?
- Ok. But only near the shore.
- Yes!
- Can I swim too, Mom?
- Yes, but only near the shore.
- Yeah!
Can you watch over them?
I won't be long.
Stay close to the shore!
Paco! You heard your mom.
Otherwise, you're getting out.
Sofi! Paco! Closer to the shore!
When I was older,
I used to be a sailor.
But I drowned in a storm.
The waves were huge!
- Sofi! Paco! Near the shore!
- It was dark...
...and there was lightning,
and I didn't know how to swim.
Wait here.
Paco! Come closer!
Sofi!
Paco, help your sister!
What happened?
Are you ok, my love?
- Cleo saved us.
- Thank you... Thank you.
Are you ok?
- I didn't want her.
- What?
- They're ok.
I didn't want her to be born.
- We love you so much, Cleo. Right?
- Poor little thing.
We love you so, so much.
- I love you, Cleo.
- I love you too, darling.
Hey, Toño, Sofi, Paco, come help.
Don't play dumb.
Hi, Borras.
- Hi, Adela.
- Hi.
- Hello, kids.
- Hi, Adela.
- Welcome, ma'am.
- Can I leave this with you?
- Yes, ma'am.
It looks awful.
Without the bookshelves,
it's awful.
- I like it like this.
- It's awful.
- What's awful, Mommy?
- He misses the bookshelves.
- Which bookshelves?
- The ones that were there.
- [ I'm going to make dinner. ]
- [ I have so much to tell you. ]
- They've switched the rooms!
- Where's mine?
- Why change them?
- It's better this way.
- I liked the old way better.
- Go check yours.
- How did it go?
- Sofi and Paco almost drowned.
Hi, Cleo.
Mrs. Sofi's room is there.
- It's bigger.
- More comfy.
- Cleo, check out my room!
- In a bit, ok?
I love it, Mom!
And we'll have more adventures!
We'll travel a lot.
We'll go to Disneyland!
We can't afford Disney,
but we can go to Oaxaca.
- Yes, and visit Cleo's village!
- Great idea!
Sure, whenever you like.
Mrs. Molly is on the phone.
- Tell me, you almost drowned?
- Yes, the current pulled us.
- The waves were 15 meters tall.
- No, they were only two meters.
- No, they were taller!
- And Cleo saved us, right, Cleo?
- Cleo, can I have a smoothie?
- Yes.
- Me too.
- Are there any Twinkies?
- Let me check.
- Yes, I got a box.
[ Wait, ]
where are you going?
- [ To buy ham. ]
- [ But I have so much to tell you. ]
- [ Did you have a good time? ]
- [ Yes, it was very nice. ]
[ I want to hear everything,
I'll be right back. ]
[ But just get the ham.
No flirting. ]
For Libo.