Go there.
Shyam
I'm not Shaym, my name is Ram
- My name is Shaym and
I had appIied for a job.
- Go there.
- No, no - go there.
I don't understand. Why are you
shuttIing me from here to there
Hey, come over here...
what's the matter?
Who was the former empIoyee?
- My father
The name?
- Shyam.
So when did Mr. Shyam die?
- Shyam is my name.
My father's name was SunderIaI...
he died on December 3, 1992.
There was another person who
died with your father in the
hospitaI - Shiv Shanker...
- Yes.
His next-of-kin has aIso
appIied for this job.
As he was senior to your father
so he gets the preference.
Sir, my father died first how
can he be senior?
I see, but in the hospitaI
both died on the same day.
As per hospitaI seniority my
father died 9 min 28 sec sooner
So he had the first right?
- Perhaps .
SimiIar probIem arose 10 months
ago as my father was 8 min Iate
Now I've the death certificate
and sent a copy to head office.
Give some time to resoIve it.
- Some time? - [Yes.]
It has aIready taken 6 years -
I'm indebted to dogs and cats.
I'II rather commit suicide than
return to my viIIage -
No don't take your Iife, I'II
recommend - rest is your Iuck.
What is this, yes teII me...?
- Sir, it's the suit.
OriginaIIy it was a suit -
it is no Ionger a suit!
I thought you're educated so I
put you on ironing job, but ...
you burnt a bIouse, then a
trouser and now a suit
You're progressing negativeIy -
what thank you - in fact you
working hard to destroy me -
work hard to progress you idiot
Idiot, I won't work hard but
earn a Iot by shortcut methods.
Sorry boss!
- That's aII right.
Hey ... Give me my purse ...
I'II kiII you!
Take out ...
- What?
Give me my purse ...
- Oh you idiot!
Over there -
get him!
Can I taIk to Devi Prasad?
- This is not his home!
What? He's not home?
Where is he?
Go to a tempIe for goddesses
Prasad - this is a garrage.
This is star garrage and I'm
its owner Baburao Apte.
Is Devi Prasad home?
- He died 10 minutes ago!
Died!
- Idiot, can't diaI correctIy.
HeIIo, is Mr. Baburao home?
- No Devi Prasad here - speak!
Is Baburao ji here?
Yes!
Sir, I want to rent...
I see - where are you from?
- Gurgaon.
Very good viIIage - peopIe are
sweet Iike sugar. -
Yes ... Maruti...
- You can get everything here...
Maruti, Esteem, Tata but at
this time I've onIy one.
But sir I don't need a car!
- What? You don't need a car?
Brother Maruti has sent me.
- Which Maruti?
Who has a restaurant in Matunga
- Oh Maruti Rao, he's good man.
He said you're aIso a very good
and sympathetic man.
TeII me what's your probIem?
- My name is Shaym
If name is your probIem change
it! Why have you come here?
I came in search of job.
- I've no job for you.
ActuaIIy job is not my probIem
I've no pIace to Iive.
First be sure about the probIem
is it name, job or house?
House sir!
- Go right, you'II find many.
I don't have money to rent any.
You changed your probIem again!
PIease aIIow me to stay here -
your heart is Iike ocean.
OnIy my heart is ocean, rest is
Iike saIted sea. That's probIem
I won't increase your probIem.
- The pay 3000 rent a month.
But I came with onIy 500!
- WeII, 500 wiII be fine.
But I've aIready spent 200.
- How much is Ieft?
Three hundred
- WeII take out 300.
I need 100 for pass.
- Okay give me 200.
God you gave for wine tonight.
For Iowering rent compensate me
by heIping me with work -
Can you cook? - [No.]
Okay then cIean the utensiIs.
Come, I'II show your room.
My neighbor's hen, it's Iike me
- Does it drink?
Its heart is Iike ocean - Iives
there but Iays eggs in my home.
In fact I don't need to take
any rent from you.
But if I don't you'II think
you own this house.
I've to keep this room cIosed.
It was rented to a dram company
Mohini Theaters was their name.
Didn't pay rent for 18 months.
I threw them out and
confiscated aII their materiaIs
You wiII share this room with
another man. This is his bag.
You'II Iive here
Don't go to his side.
You wiII get your drinking and
bathing water from this weII.
It is very deep.
- You don't have to dip inside.
Just draw a bucket and
take bath outside.
Let me show you the toiIet.
Why don't you hoId the door
or show presence by singing.
Can you sing?
No.
Better Iearn, otherwise you
waIk 2 miIes to raiI Iine.
Why?
- ToiIet has no Iock.
EarIier there was no door.
Don't foIIow - go to your room.
Can't you put a Iock on toiIet?
- It's nothing worth Iocking.
Then at Ieast don't aIIow
garrage visitors to use it.
He has come to Iive in
home not in garrage.
You gave room to this crook.
- Crook, he said he is Shyam.
He's not Shyam.
He's a pickpocket.
Baburao he's a misunderstanding
- Get out of here, now
Don't push me your with hands
Hands! I'II push with my feet.
I want to hear from Baburao.
- ReaIIy?
I'II see how you
won't get out from here.
I swear to God I'm not a thief.
Don't be infIuenced by him.
If I was a thief, wouId I
come this far to seek a job.
PIease trust me and aIso
make him understand.
Don't make pathetic stories!
- Babubhaiya pIease stop him.
Raju, what's this? Come out.
Why are you doing this.
You don't say word. I mean
don't speak in between us.
HoId a minute what's your name?
- Babubhaiya...
That's my name not yours. I'm
I'm owner, I've right to speak
You may be anybody - pick up
your Iuggage and go inside.
If he goes in, I'II go out...
- I've no probIem with that.
Why you're so keen to keep him?
- Because he pays rent.
I'II pay his rent.
You've not paid your rent for
two years why wiII you pay his?
I warn I'II go. - [Good.]
I'II go. - [Okay.]
I'II go myseIf tomorrow.
- Yes, you go.
Okay, I'm going.
- Why don't you go.
No, I won't go. I'II go after
paying two years' rent.
That means you'II never go.
Are you sure you're not thief.
- No Babubhai.
Take this. Don't thank it's for
buying a khamba (wine) for me.
What's Khamba
- A bottIe of orange wine.
Hi hero - Iiving on fiIm buds.
- Yes.
When wiII you cook rice?
I'm very hungry
Ask your new friend to cook.
Good idea. He'II pay rent,
do cIeaning and dishes.
Now he shouId cooking too.
- Yes.
ShouId he do Iaundry tomorrow?
And you'II rest aII day.
- Yes.
What day is tomorrow?
- Friday.
It's very auspicious. You pack
cIothes and vacate your room.
Where wiII you roam in the
night - Ieave in the morning.
I'II cook onIy rice.
- then better Ieave now.
I'II cook daI but I won't fry.
Okay, I can Iive with
non-fried daI.
What's this indecent behavior?
- You won't see indecent...
Why are you standing
here Iike a watchman.
See Baburao...
What's there to see.
Ask him to come out
I've to go for interview.
ToiIet isn't a pIace
for interview.
Raju you come out, Iet him go.
- You don't interfere
He isn't doing anything in
there. He's just teasing me.
I've kept the door open
just come and have a Iook.
You're a mature man you go in.
- Oh God - do I have to see?
Oh, he broke my chest!
Pick up.
I don't know her how can I pick
her up? She's about 40 kiIogram
If you've some probIem
I can come Iater.
Not reaIIy - we're
practicing karate.
Who is Shyam amongst you?
- I'm Shyam.
WouId you come here?
You've some work with me.
She has come for me.
Saw?
- No, I had covered myseIf.
I'm not taIking about this.
There are girIs after Shyam.
Maybe she is his sister.
- And so fair! How do you know?
Because she's wearing gIasses.
- You wouId be their father!
Why do you aIways go to
ICI Bank and create scene?
For getting a job!
It doesn't Iook good
for a man Iike you.
It's their mistake! They want
to give my job to someone eIse.
Bank manager knows who deserves
that job. You just sign here.
I was confident of getting this
job one day. Where do I sign?
What does this mean?
- You no Ionger need this job.
So that Shiv Shanker's
next-of-kin can get this job.
I'II not sign. As Iong as I'm
aIive he won't get this job.
I'II get the job as I'm next-
of-kin of Shiv Shanker.
But think by defeating me you
can be happy in this city.
Why? Are you the city queen?
- I'm the Bandit Queen?
Sister, pIease Iisten.
- What is it?
I want to heIp you and you
are being rude to me.
I don't want your heIp.
- OnIy I can soIve your probIem
How?
- I can get you the N.O.C.
I know he'II not give that
Ietter but I can get it for you
If you don't want my heIp
it is okay.
PIease wait...
Can you reaIIy do it.
I never Iie. You Iook Iike my
sister so I want to heIp.
Shyam is my chiIdhood friend.
He'II do whatever I teII him.
But I saw you two fighting.
This goes on between
two Ioving friends.
But we have fought
on this matter.
You don't worry. TeII me
what you want in the Ietter.
In BoriviIi a tenant has beaten
his IandIord and kicked him out
A tenant choked his IandIord
because of his girIfriend.
Affair with women is very bad -
men kiII their parents...
it's so easy to kiII a IandIord
Homeowners are fooIs.
They take tenants for money and
don't get anything in writing.
Do you have a house in viIIage?
- No, why?
What if Shyam throws you out
of this house? Where'II you go?
HoId your tongue!
- See he is so defensive.
He'II bring so many girIs that
they'II throw you out of house.
According to my horoscope
I must commit one murder...
And must murder a murderer.
- See, he's taIking murder!
For your safety ask him
to sign on a bIank paper
otherwise you'II read a tenant
broke his drunken IandIord's
head with bottIe of wine and
siphoned off his property.
He's taIking aII nonsense.
Maybe he is right.
You sign a bIank paper.
Don't you trust me?
- He's some trick in his mind.
I pay rent you don't.
- So what, I'm ready to sign.
I'm ready too.
- What are you waiting for?
You both go out and
bring the paper.
Oh God! Why have you trapped
me in their fight.
CaII me to YourseIf.
- No, caII them to yourseIf.
See, I've signed the paper.
He has not signed.
There is something in his mind.
I'm signing.
Now what? Sign it.
What do you want?
Did you hear the song?
- Song?
He is making excuses ...
- You sign.
You reaIIy don't hear the song.
I hear it so cIearIy.
He's very cunning -
he's not going to sign.
Can I taIk to Mr. Devi Prasad?
- No. Now what wiII you do?
Sir, what happened to my fish.
- I fried and ate it.
What are you doing here?
What's that girI doing here?
- She's our new empIoyee.
With whose permission?
What's this nonsense?
Sir sweet baIIs.
- For what?
To ceIebration Anuradha's
appointment.
So you're impressing everybody
by offering them sweets.
Go and ask the manager.
- SureIy I wiII ask?
You're misusing your position.
- What's the probIem?
How did you give
my job to that girI.
HoId a minute. You repIy is in
this Ietter. Isn't it yours?
Letter!
Yes sir. You've written that
for now you don't need this job
I've written no such Ietter!
No! Then how is your signature?
Isn't it your signature?
Stop him! Govind! Rajaram!
Security! Get that Ietter.
He ate it!
- Sir open his stomach.
You just wait and see what I do
to your bank.
I wiII teII everybody you took
bribe to appoint this girI.
I'II get you both terminated
so there'II be two jobs for me.
I'II be trapped.
So you better terminated her
and appoint me here.
I've appointment Ietter -
nobody can terminate me.
I'II see you, first Iet me deaI
with man who gave you Ietter.
You bastard
I'II kiII you today.
I'II take your Iife.
Have you gone mad?
Babu bhaiya save me...
He'II kiII me.
What're you doing, you're
breaking everything...
He has gone mad...
Babu bhaiya you don't interfere
You're bent upon destroying
whatever is Ieft of garage.
Babu bhaiya counseI him.
- About what?
Where's my signed paper?
- What paper?
The paper I signed and gave you
- Look into the cupboard.
He wrote on it that I don't
need job and gave it that girI.
You move from here.
- PIease stand between us.
Shut up!
I'm not afraid of going to
jaiI but I'm sparing him
because I want to see myseIf
working in a respectabIe job.
You go from here. And remember
if you break anything
I'II make you sIeep with RamIaI
- Who's RamIaI.
The street dog!
If you had not come between us
I wouId have broken his teeth.
Did you steaI that paper?
- Yes.
WeII, you're not hurt, are you?
- No, not at aII.
Then why were you shouting?
- It's Raju's styIe.
And this is Baburao's styIe!
So you pIanned this together.
- Don't touch me.
In the bank I'm a manager -
but here we are friends.
Then hoId hands and start
singing a duet.
You can make good jokes.
Don't bore me. My Iast warning...
terminate her, give me my job
Otherwise you'II Iose your job
and retirement benefits.
Now our Iife is in your hands.
- What can I do?
You can do a Iot -
- just think, you're a woman.
What shouId I think?
You're cute and young. You can
controI him Iike Menaka.
I don't know anything.
- I'II train you for that.
Assume he is Vishwamitra who's
praying for job.
Like Indra I'II dress you Iike
Menaka so you can divert him
and obtain other NOC from him.
No I can't act this Iove scene.
Try to befriend, otherwise we
both wiII Iose our jobs.
You did a nice setting for them
- It was hard but God heIped.
Can you fix me with someone.
- What?
Have you some other beauty?
- Who do you think I am?
Pimp.
- I'm a manager not a pimp.
Okay, I'II treat you with
respect - show me some pictures
Listen, money is no probIem
I'II pay as much as you want.
Go away or I'II beat you.
- How about tomorrow?
Why are you foIIowing me?
- What a manIy gait!
Mine or yours?
- Your anger is attractive.
Aren't you ashamed - may I
shout to caII poIice.
No need to be rude. If you
Iike I can resign from the job.
Just give me 50,000
for this favor.
What? Fifty thousand!
Don't shout, I'm asking 50,000
not 500,000. PeopIe are ready
to pay 100,000 for this job.
You're trying to cheat me.
I won't give a singIe paisa.
Can I diaI a IocaI
number from here?
There is a caII from CaIcutta
for Savitri from her son.
HeIIo, my son.
- How are you mom?
I'm fine, when are you coming?
As soon as my Ieave is approved
I wiII fIy and come to you.
I want to see you son.
- I'II come, you don't worry.
I want to taIk to your son.
- Matron wants to taIk to you.
Don't give phone to matron
aunt - I'm in great hurry.
Bring 25 bIankets from CaIcutta
- HeIIo, I can't hear anything.
Can you bring 25 bIankets?
What?
- BIankets?
Can't hear anything.
She has been shouting bIankets
and you say you can't hear
CouId you hear? - [Yes.]
- Then you send the bIankets.
You may hide anywhere -
but I'II find you.
What's this noise? What's
going on? Who's this man?
Not you. He's my friend. He has
borrowed 35,000 from me.
Are you Iooking for Shyam?
- His name is Ghanshyam.
But he doesn't work here.
- I know he works here.
Stop. Get out -
what type of man he is?
Come out Ghanshyam otherwise
I'II ruin your office.
Sis Ghanshyam took 35,000 and
promised to return after
getting a job. You heIp me get
my money otherwise I can't
arrange my sister's marriage.
He said he got a job in bank.
Now he isn't here.
- Shyam Iives in BoriviIi.
Where?
Either east or west BoriviIi.
Go to your seats and work.
He has created so much nuisance
And this Shyam has made
my Iife miserabIe.
Where does Ghanshyam Iive?
- Second house in first street.
WiII be in his home?
- No, he died 5 years back.
How can he die. I'II kiII him
after recovering my money.
Are you Iooking for Shyam?
One who wears gIasses...
If I show you where he Iives
wiII you beat him?
I wiII beat him.
Don't teII him my name
otherwise he'II run away.
Shyam some one has come
to meet you.
Come soon.
I am coming...
You Ieft viIIage to hid here.
- Why you get angry to see me.
You bastard.. you disappear
whenever you see me...
What is going on ?
Babu Bhaiya you don't interfere
Iet them fight.
What is going on ?
I am choking his neck..
This is his styIe to show Iove...
What a strange styIe to
embrace tiII other chokes.
He shouId have broken his bones
you spoiIed the wrestIing show.
I had given him 35,000 rupees
at the death of his father.
Brother Khadag in this worId
Love is important not money..
Your introduction..
- Baburao Ganpatrao Apte.
You've money today, you may
not have tomorrow.
Can you give me money now?
Now onIy one week remains in
Bano's marriage. If I don't get
money then the marriage can't
take pIace. You didn't intend
to return money so you Ieft
viIIage and came over here.
Do you know what Bano said when
was coming to search you?
She said don't compeI my
Ghanshyam brother
whether her marriage can
take pIace or not.
You idiot she treats you more
Iike brother than me.
If a girI's marriage doesn't
take pIace you'II have to
suffer for 13 Iives.
Don't say such things - Bano's
marriage wiII sureIy take pIace
I wiII definiteIy pay you by
Sunday.. this is my promise..
Don't you trust me that much.
- This or that I don't trust.
I want to hear from him
Can you give me the money?
Why wiII he give you money?
He did not borrow from you.
Come on Friday.. I wiII make
arrangement of the money.
We'II get her married together.
- God! Can it happen.
Okay I'II come on Friday - but
I'II bring 4 persons with me.
Not for beating you, but if you
don't pay I'II kiII myseIf
and they'II carry my body.
It's not good to heIp others.
Even my shoes have worn out.
How wiII you pay on Friday?
I'm sure I wiII get money..
But how ?
My heart says Bano wiII be
married definiteIy.
Oh God you give him money..
I have to taIk to you...
what?
can you come out pIease...
you remember having said
to me that if I pay you 50,000
then you'II Ieave this job.
WiII you do it?
I had said that because
of your troubIes.
But I don't have 50,000 -
not even five paisa to give.
Whether you remain on the job
or pass it on to someone eIse.
I wiII sign on whatever Ietter
you want.
But can you give me 35,000?
You can Iose the job. Are you
wiIIing to take this risk
You're a cIever girI, that is
why I am accepting the defeat.
You recognized my cIeverness
so soon.
Okay, come to my home to
get the money.
Mommy!
My son where have you
brought me..
Last time you had taken
me to some other pIace..
Yes that was our bungaIow
see I have made this Office....
Sir petroI..
What is the rush.
WeIcome! So you've come from
CaIcutta. Was train in time.
I came by morning fIight and
picked up my mom.
Mother he is our contractor
for bricks and mortar.
Namastte mother...
He aIways taIks about you.
Do you aIso Iive in CaIcutta?
- No in the KoIiwada...
No mommy I phoned him to ask
how work was progressing.
Come out.
You were over acting...
Give him 200 deduct 50.
Why shouId pay?
You pay to him we'II adjust.
But what about petroI?
You add the water, pIease.
give me money..
come tomorrow.
This is my personaI cabin and
here I'II put daddy's photo.
Raju when did you come
from CaIcutta?
My son who is he?
I'II teII you mom. Raju is my
best friend.
When I first met him on road
I thought he is a pickpocket.
Pickpocket!
Yes he Iooks Iike that...
Why are you so shy before mom.
The job I had been searching
for 6 years he got me in a day.
I touch your feet mom.
- Long Iive my son..
I'm Shyam. Raju's room partner.
- He's aIso business partner.
Remember we decided to start
the wine shop behind office.
Wine shop?
He means the crackers factory -
we required the gunpowder...
Why are you hiding from mother
I had said I'II repay aII you
have done to me. Now give purse
for Ghanshyam Baba.
Ghanshyam Baba?
Yes we seek his bIessings for
our progress.
Ghanshyamji is a great saint...
he isn't giving the money..
you give 100 for the petroI.
I can reveaI your reaI seIf
but I don't want to spoiI
the happiness which I
see in her eyes.
Okay mommy...
Hey Babu!
Babu instead of Babubhaiya! I
must increase your rent.
Babubhaiya today is the
happiest day of my Iife...
What are you happy about?
My sister wiII never be wedded.
and viIIage house won't escaped
you couId not get the money.
Babubhaiya there is nothing
with that woman...
no don't throw me out...
After father's death her
mentaI condition deteriorated.
I couIdn't pay the rent of the
house for 2 1/2 years.
LandIord threatens to throw us
out from the house
That's why I asked 50,000 from
you. When I reaIized that you
too are in debt, I smiIed. I'm
resigning my job for you.
You may be abIe to do something
from that position.
Now if I take your job, God
wiII never forgive me.
So she has nothing
except the big heart.
Don't taIk about big heart.
I've big heart - but no money.
Oh God - hearing aII this
burns my stomach.
Babubhaiya may I teII you
where I got money for wine!
Raju - he's the biggest cheat
and he'II cheat us any time
He is cheating his own mother.
Is it true Raju?
Where are you going?
Why don't you teII me...
I doubt whether that Iady
is his reaI mother.
Not a word. She's my mother.
I cheat her to make her happy.
She think her son works for
a very big company in CaIcutta.
and earns Iakh of rupees.
He'II buiId a house for her.
But why did you Iie to her.
So, what eIse couId I have said?
That her son is unempIoyed
and does petty jobs
I remember my mother use to do
cIeaning jobs at schooI
She remained hungry to
.. feed me.
I cannot see my mother in
distress
And that is the reason for aII
the Iies.
Then what shouId I do?
TeII my mother that the dream
she has wiII never come true.
I want to see her happy.
I need money for that.
And I wiII cheat anybody for
Money..
If you wouId have toId her the
truth today
Then she wouId have probabIy
died.
PIease..
Forgive me for aII the troubIe I
have caused you.
You are stiII angry with him?
See we aII have worries.
My father..
BuiIt this house and garage
after hard work.
Then my mother became sick and
my father
Had to take a Iot of Ioan and he
died repaying the Ioan.
I have to fuIfiII my fathers
dream.
Before I die I want to pay the
debt of my father
Then onIy I can reIax
in peace
This is my dream..
Happiness increases by sharing
sorrow decreases by sharing
Let's share our sorrows
and Iive happiIy.
Who is it
HeIIo.
Kabira speaking
What?
Okay Okay
Was it correct?
Idiot it was wrong,
Check the number
Idiot! He is testing the mike.
Is this Star Fisheries..
Before disconnecting the phone
TeII me...
Devi Prasad your Rinku is in
my custody.
O.K I wiII teII my son to rescue
Rinku.
What happened?
It seems that the oId man has
gone mad.....
I need to go and pee
Babu bhaiya get up...
What happened?
Listen, whose phone is this?
It seems as if someone is crying
Yes she is my granddaughter..
Your granddaughter. When did
your son get married?
First Iet me marry...
That is aIright but whose phone
is it?
He was repeatedIy saying
Kabira speaking
It's a good name...
Why Devi Prasad you are stunned?
You have earned so much money in
Star Fisheries.
If you want your daughter
aIive...
keep 10 Iakh rupees ready.
Kabira wiII CaII you again
tomorrow morning at 10 a.m.
I wiII teII you when and where
to deIiver the money
Don't try to inform the poIice
or find us.
Otherwise I wiII make smaII
pieces and feed it to the dogs
Whose phone is it?
And what is he saying?
Some Kabira is on the Iine and
he is saying that if ..
he does not get 10 Iakh rupees
then he wiII kiII the granddaughter
of the owner of star fisheries.
Is it his father's ruIe?
I feeI that we shouId caII Devi
Prasad and Let him know everything.
But where wiII we find the
number for star fisheries?
CaII up Kabira and ask him
Yes, ask the thief where he is
pIanning to do the theft.
Check in the directory
Let it be.
See this...
What?
You go and get your eyes
checked.
This is the number for star
garage.
No this is the number for star
fisheries.
There are two Iines for the same
number.
this is star fisheries...
This is probIematic..
Now I know why the phone Iine
has been bothering me.
They have Iisted Star Garages
number against star fisheries.
And Star fisheries against
Star garage
If you caII star industries
the phone wiII ring in garage
if you caII star garage the phone
wiII ring in star fisheries.
You go and teIephone.
What wiII you teII him?
That his granddaughter has been
kidnapped.
Why not we pIay a game?
Which game...
What do you want to say?
I want to say that why did aII
this, happen to us onIy...
Why did it happen?
Because this is
Ishwar(God)'s wiII...
Which Ishwar? That merchant...
The merchant that sits in heaven
If he wants us to become rich
then what is the probIem?
The game is simpIe.
Kabira thinks that we are Devi
Prasad. We can caII...
Devi Prasad and teII him that
the girI is with us
And we wiII take the money from
him and Give it to Kabira.
But what wiII we get out of
this?
We wiII ask Devi Prasad for
doubIe amount of money...
No, this is a wrong way to get
money
Babubhaiya see god has chosen us
to save girI's Iife.
If we get some money what is the
harm in it.
The Goddess of weaIth has chosen
us and you don't want it
This is not wrong.
What do you think.
Shyam you go and caII
Did you peopIe hear something.
You diaI it....
HeIIo - Kabira speaking
- Who?
Are you giving an interview?
TaIk in a strong voice.
Kabira speaking ...
- Which Kabira
Your granddaughter is in my
custody.
HeIIo.. Babu it seems he went to
caII the poIice..
What happened sir?
Nothing.. you go to sIeep.
I said go back.
HeIIo from where are you
speaking?
Do you want the address?
Write down Ganeshwadi ...
What're you doing idiot.
He is asking our address
I asked where are you
speaking from?
Give him the same message that
Kabira gave us for him
You scare him.
If you try to trace us or caII
the poIice
Then we wiII kiII your dog and
feed it to your grand daughter.
What are you saying? Who cuts
a dog to pieces?
We wiII kiII your grand daughter
and feed her to dogs.
See, I wiII not caII the
poIice..
But don't do anything to my
granddaughter.
He is weeping...
Okay tomorrow morning we'II
caII you again at ten.
We'II teII you where and when
to bring money.
I'II give you whatever you want.
I'II give you aII my weaIth.
You teII me how much you want.
How much? 20 for Kabir, pIus
12 1/2 for me - say 20 Iakh...
Twenty Iakh.
- Yes 20, I'II give even more.
What happened? Didn't agree?
- He agreed.
It seems that now aII our
probIems wiII be over.
How?
I'II get Iot of money soon.
Oh. So you'II be abIe to
marry Bano.
And aIso I'II pay money owed
to your house owner.
Won't you accept my money?
No I was thinking how I wiII
return such a big debt.
So you don't return.
- Then I'II not take the money.
Okay, I'II think it is
Ioan to you.
and that wiII give me an
excuse to see you.
How wiII you get aII that money?
Don't ask - I don't want to Iie.
But I'II teII you the truth
after I compIete this job.
What're you doing.
- Checking if phone is working.
Are green Ieaves ready?
- Green Ieaves?
Do you want money or
beteI Ieaves?
Stop taIking rubbish.
Is money ready?
TeII him it's ready.
- Yes it is ready.
Okay, come at 2 p.m. behind
Videocon factory.
You bring the money we'II
bring the girI.
And Iisten - come aIone.
Don't bring your driver.
Have you ever seen Devi Prasad?
- No.
Ask him...
- What?
Have you seen Devi
Prasad before?
I mean have you seen me before?
No. I've not seen you but if you
come aIone I'II identify you.
Otherwise we'II cut your grand
Daughter to pieces
and feed her to dogs.
- I'II come.
HeIIo, I am Devi Prasad here.
I was waiting for your caII.
Where and when do we meet?
ExactIy at 1 :30.
You come behind the Videocon
Factory near Hanuman TempIe.
WeII you come aIone and don't
bring your driver.
I'II come.
Otherwise we wiII cut your chiId
to pieces and feed to your dog.
I'II come.
- Good.
What's the matter?
Why did you caII?
Rinku is missing.
She has been kidnapped.
What nonsense are you taIking.
It's true, she is not in home
You can search the house.
Is Devi Prasad home.
- He has Iocked himseIf in room
and asked servants to go
home for 3-4 days.
It's a very serious matter.
I'II hand it over to poIice.
Owner of Star Fisheries is my
Neighbor. His grand daughter
has been kidnapped but he
is not teIIing anybody.
You watch him, who he meets,
what he does, and inform me.
I know you're a great taiIor
but stitch my cIothes urgentIy.
I've dhoti, give me siIk Kurita,
a siIk cap.
Why do you need to measure?
Make dress, measure Iater.
Paint everything don't Ieave
even a smaII corner.
Use pIastic emuIsion on whoIe
house.
And put waII paper on both
Sides of the weII.
It wiII cost 15 per feet.
- Don't worry about the cost.
Why don't you show your faces?
Why are you ashamed of asking
your own money.
How much do you want?
Mine is 7,200.
My 8,300.
My principaI is 9,100 - with
interest it comes to Rs.10,000.
But I can forget the interest.
Why? You take 10,500, you 9000
and you 8,000.
Remember to take it tomorrow as
I don't want burden on my head.
And Peter I don't want to buy
a bottIe each day
You bring a tanker of wine every
fortnight to fiII my
overhead tank so whenever I want
I'II fiII a gIass from tap.
Raju, Babu bhaiya is happy as if
he is getting married.
It seems that poIicemen wiII
be part of his procession.
And change tyres on aII cars.
Take the money as advance
Have you won any Iottery?
No. Nobody caIIed me?
Not even wrong number.
Potatoes are ready come and eat
You're caIIing them tomorrow?
Cow is eating grass and you're
inviting them for yogurt!
Don't buiId castIe in air. CaII
after money is in your hand.
There is change in program.
You come on Sunday.
Babubhaiya you're drinking wine
so earIy, what is the matter?
Tomorrow dreams wiII come true
I want to remain in my dreams.
But why are you wasting money...
- No probIem
Like rain, when God gives He
gives in abundance.
What're you doing to my head?
How are you rich Shyam?
Let's wear heImet today
tomorrow it'II be goId cap.
But if we don't succeed
it wouId be prisoner's cap!
Oh god I wiII have to
take my medicine again.
Why are you drinking wine
so earIy in the morning...
It's not wine, it's medicine
for controIIing tension.
He'II bIoody increase our
tension aIso.
Why did you abuse?
- TeII me.
Don't mind he abused me
- Never say it.
Can't you see?
How can I see with heImet over
my head and no gIasses on eyes.
Don't shout I'II find
your gIasses.
You wait here. I'II go and see
if he pays money we wiII go back
otherwise you may carry
my dead body to my viIIage.
The name of the God is true...
- Oh shut up, I'm not dead yet...
Who're you peopIe?
- Oh Khadag Singh!
That's my name...
how can you be Khadag Singh?
We're Sham's friends.
- Friends?
You aII Iook aIike -
are you twins?
No, we're tripIets.
- I know.
Where's Ghanshyam?
If I don't get money today
I'II put buIIets in my head.
No don't do this. Shyam Ieft..
- Where did he go?
He went to return your money...
- He asked me come here today!
He got the money yesterday
so he Ieft for your viIIage.
Then I wiII rush back to
otherwise he'II make an excuse.
Oh God saved us. Come into
the care Iet's go.
I've reached but nobody's here.
- Just wait... he wiII come.
Sir a white Mercedes is coming....
It'II have the money.
As soon as you get money
caII me I wiII bring the chiId...
Sir Mercedes went eIsewhere.
- Another wiII come.
What's this pIace ...
- Just sit quietIy.
What's this sound -
- He is peeing.
I toId you not to drink
- Didn't we sit for peeing.
It's quite naturaI after
drinking 4 Iiters of wine.
Shut up and don't caII
each other by name.
Yes. You are correct and
Don't take anyone's name..
Seems this is
Devi Prasad's car.
Did you bring the money?
- Yes...
Where is my granddaughter?
- Give money quickIy ...
You'II get your granddaughter
first give the money.
Give me bag
I'II count the money.
Stop - return the bag.
He wants empty bag.
Take out the money.
Come on where is the girI?
ChiId is not with us.
- TeII me otherwise I'II shoot.
No, who caIIed you here?
It's my personaI matter..
I came here to perform my duty
And you Iet me do my job...
I don't need your heIp...
I want my granddaughter.
You wiII get your
grand daughter.
TeII me where's the chiId
otherwise I'II shoot aII three.
No.. actuaIIy a man phoned
and he asked us to....
Drop your guns!
Go quickIy and get my chiId..
What're you doing - run
- I'm sitting on the motor bike
Stop otherwise
I wiII shoot you..
Oh god Devi Prasad has caIIed
both the army and the poIice...
You army men may go now.
- Remove your heImets.
I'm not with them I needed some
money and they trapped me.
Babu bhaiya come on -
- I can't run.....
Oh god I wiII do the cooIie work
sweeping, beg on the road -
but I wiII never adopt a short
cut to make money...
I was mad to go with your pIan.
This happened because of you.
Why because of me? You needed
money too.
I needed it but I didn't know
poIice wiII come to share it.
I think this is Kabira's phone.
BIoody....his...
No Shyam it is dangerous
to taIk on this phone...
I know what I have to teII him..
Raju get aside.....
Grandpa, they wiII kiII me ...
pIease save me...
Devi Prasad did you hear?
For dirty trick you pIayed by
caIIing the poIice, I can
break granddaughter's Ieg
and make her a beggar or seII
her for prostitution.
I'II give you one Iast chance.
I'II phone you again and teII
you where and when you've
to come with money.
but this chance wiII cost you
doubIe the originaI amount.
Shyam what happened?
What did he say?
Because of our fooIishness
the Iife of an innocent girI ..
is in danger. I cannot toIerate
the burden of this sin....
Now where are you going?
To teII Devi Prasad that he
shouId save his granddaughter....
Shyam you cannot go now...
- Raju get aside otherwise...
My specs
You idiot Ieave him!
What are you doing?
I wiII kiII him....
Neither he nor I need money
obtained by wrong means -
why are you so adamant?
Because I promised my mother
to move her to new house.
Very good....
- You know her?
Yes I know her very weII and
she is a good dancer.
She wouId be very rich...
- No she is very poor....
How do you know?
- I'm her father. She's unIucky.
At birth her mother died -
her eIder sister become widow -
younger brother got TB -
I'd Ioss in fish business
It's very kind of cIub peopIe
that they caII her for dancing
If you arrange such programs,
can you pIease engage us.
At Ieast give me your name and
address so I can contact you.
What are you doing?
My five rupee biII.
Why - it's haIf -
now you keep it!
Tore off 5-rupee note! What
a man - wait I'm coming...
Oh Shaym - come her.
- I've urgent matter to discuss.
Yes have a seat -
- Anu I want to teII you...
WiII you take some tea?
Take a cup it's ready!
Anu I wanted to say ...
Don't ask us to Ieave if you
want take aII our stuff.
CooI down mommy don't worry.
He'II give money tomorrow
I'II give that to the IandIord.
- Why doe he come to troubIe us?
Sorry - what is the matter
you wanted to discuss.
That it's important to
pay to the IandIord.
Yes
- Okay, I am going.
I made a mistake, but I'II pay
the money within 4-days.
Sure
- I swear to my mother.
Babubhai aIways teIIs the truth
He wiII even seII his garage.
Shut up aIways taIking nonsense
you go I wiII pay you the money
If we don't get consequence
wiII not be good.
Yes the money is hanging on
trees - you come and get it.
Think about the viIIage debt and
your sister's marriage.
Wash hands food is ready -
There is hot and tasty daI too.
Some peopIe wiII Iive in
poverty, and die of starvation.
but wiII not give
up their honesty.
Here's Kabira's caII - I'II teII
him onIy honest peopIe Iive here
so go ahead and cut the chiId -
feed her to dogs, we're busy.
What is this Raj,
- I am ready.
Me too..
- FinaI?
FinaI.
Then pick up the phone -
see who is caIIing ...
HeIIo Devi Prasad ...
what's today's rate for the fish
Disconnect you... we're going for
Iife and death - you want fish.
Devi Prasad, this is the Iast
chance to see your chiId aIive.
Tomorrow night you come to
Bhaidas Stadium with 20 Iakhs
If you try any mischief you know
what I can do with her.
You Iisten now...
This is your Iast chance...
This time the ransom is 40 Iakh.
If you try to be cIever...
No, don't do any such thing...
I'm bringing you the money.
This time we shouId not faiI.
We must catch the criminaIs.
This time I don't want to
take any risk. AbsoIuteIy not.
We'II be caught if we go in
heImets Iike the Iast time
Let's go without the heImets.
- So poIice can shoot my head.
I don't want to go with you.
- Then teII me how we'II go..
Let me show you the treasure.
Treasure?
It's artificiaI - not saIeabIe.
Okay what do you want to wear?
Babu bhaiya it's aII useIess.
- You don't taIk - your pIanning
faiIed - this time do as I say.
You don't know about kidnapping.
Babu Bhai how about this one?
If you put on this God wiII
make you Ravana in next Iife.
This - materiaI is good.
- Forget this.
It's Draupadi's sari! It's so
so Iong that by the time you
wrap it Devi Prasad's
grand-daughter wiII grow up.
These are most appropriate.
Where have I to go.
- You'II misdirect the poIice.
I'II go there another way.
- I am so afraid.
You are not doing anything
just sit in the car.
Brothers you Iisten carefuIIy
And no one wiII make any noise
Otherwise he'II run away.
Do you understand?
Be happy by taking
Name of True God.
What's this procession.
It's the Death procession
Whose?
- Yours, Khadag Singh has come.
Now what shaII we do.
You guys do watch here...
You come with me...
Shyam come out of hiding
or I wiII break everything
Are you Sham's uncIe? TeII me
or I wiII break your mouth.
I am his friend.. he befooIed
but I'II not go without
taking my money.
- I'II give you.
Why wiII I take your money?
Am I a begging?
He means we've to get money
if he gives we'II pay to you.
Thank you brother -
Let's search him.
UncIe you go and search inside
and I wiII search outside...
TeII me brother why you aII
wear same kind of dress.
So that you'II not recognize us
What?
So that Shyam wiII not
recognize us.
Your goggIes have faIIen.
Ghanshyam now I won't Ieave you...
Sir Devi Prasad dodged us.
He sent his servant in car.
This means he's gone in other
car - find out from the servant
It Iooks Iike Devi Prasad car.
Shyam come over...
This is your money....
Stop! First you bring me my
granddaughter - then money.
First you've to give money...
No - first my granddaughter.
She is here but you've
to wait for sometime...
PoIice is aII over the city -
what if you're kiIIed, what'II
happen to my grand daughter.
There is no time for discussion.
- But how I couId trust you...
You'II have to trust us
There is no other way.
Our main concern is to bring
your granddaughter safeIy.
If you stiII don't beIieve us
then you Iook at us
I am Shyam
- I am Raju
I am Baburao
- Baburao Ganpatrao Apte
If you stiII don't trust us -
you can take back your.
Okay I beIieve you peopIe -
okay you take the money.
You wait here whiIe we go
and get your granddaughter.
Shyam you keep haIf the money
and give other haIf to me...
If you wiII take haIf each
then what wiII I get...
Shut up we have to
pay to Kabira aIso...
Who are you?
- Devi Prasad.
Why did you come dressed
up Iike a joker?
So that nobody can recognize.
Where is my granddaughter?
Granddaughter!
Yes. Where is my granddaughter?
When did you marry?
In chiIdhood -
but where is my granddaughter?
Have you brought the money?
Yes, as per your demand, but
first bring my granddaughter.
Grandpa.
Give money and
take your granddaughter.
Ghanshyam you have become so
wicked after coming to the city.
You don't have money to give my
sister you are giving Iakhs here
Do we start shooting?
Let's first see their drama?
He does not have any money and
he is buying this girI...
How are you my daughter?
- He is not my grand father!
Seems Iike he's a poIiceman.
ChiId! I am a friend of your
grand father...
No one wiII move from his pIace.
you give bag and baby to me...
He is kiIIing -
he is kiIIing my friend.
Let's do something.
- In the Name of the True God.
Whose gun is this? Take it.
Don't teII Iater that I stoIe it
Got both bags...
How did you get the second bag?
Yes totaI forty Iakh. You take
her to Devi Prasad
I wiII meet you in home...
Grandpa!
Hi Babu Bhaiya - who're you
Iooking for - nobody foIIowed us
We are safe -
and we're miIIionaires!
No one has seen us and no
one has identified us!
we went for 20 Iakhs and came
back with forty Iakhs.
Oh God whenever you give
you give generousIy.
Don't stop me today...
it's Iast time for home-brewed
From tomorrow I'II
have imported.
Where are you?
- Raju the miIIionaire!
Raju the miIIionaire...
Perhaps he counting the money.
It has been five hours
but Raju has not come!
Yes!
- He shouId have come by now!
Whom are you caIIing?
HeIIo kasturba Vridhashram.
pIease caII Raju's mother?
Raju took her 4-5 hours back..
What happened?
He Ieft with his mother!
What?
His bag is aIso not here....
What are you saying?
Yes Babubhaiya
I think he ran away.
We were waiting for him
and that man cheated us
We were waiting for him here
and he has Ieft the city
with aII the money..
He has cheated us...
he has betrayed us.
He had dishonest intentions.
He couId do anything for money.
No we wiII not spare him.
He wouId be trying to
Ieave the city before morning
but we wiII stop him.
You caII the poIice..
Here we'II die in starvation
and he'II enjoy Iike a king.
No you caII the poIice..
Three more peopIe were invoIved
in the kidnapping case.
You don't know them - names are
Raju, Baburao and Shyam.
My name is Shyam. Star Garage..
BoriviIi west.
MyseIf and Babu are here.
You can come and arrest.
Our friend Raju has run away
with the money.
The car number is B.M.W 253.
There is a oId woman with him.
She is his mother.
Babubhaiya we are Iucky!
We got 40 Iakhs!
Now there is nothing to worry..
There is so much money..
Whenever the God gives
He gives in abundance.
What happened brothers?
Why such Iong faces?
Where have you been
aII this time..
I went to so many pIaces.
First I went to Khadag Singh.
Gave him 30,000. His sister's
marriage wiII be performed.
Then I went to my mother in that
rotten car without a spare tire.
It took five hours
to get a tire fixed.
But you were gone with your bag.
My mother's papers were in bag
I took those to get discharged.
When we didn't see you we
thought you've cheated us.
Then what?
We informed the poIice.
What?
Yes. PoIice wiII be here any
minute and we cannot escape.
What have you done?
My mother is sitting in the car
What shouId I do now ?
Arrest them..
Shyam I don't want to see my
mother in this condition.
Inspector Sahib pIease take
us out from the back door.
These peopIe are not the
criminaIs..
The money they have
has been give to them by me.
You pIease Iet them go free.
My grand daughter says they
risked their Iife to save her.
I am very thankfuI to them..
It was our need that made
us do this..
I understand. You guys k
keep the money with you.
You saved my grand daughters
Iife, take this as your prize.
What?
- Yes.
Oh dear PoIice officer,
can you do something about this.
According to Devi Prasad's
statement there's no case.
ConstabIe - reIease them.
Sir, this phone is for you.
No, its for you. Pick up
otherwise it'II be disconnected.