Fo Shan's citizens were well off
and practiced kung-fu as a hobby.
Martial clubs became popular,
turning Fo Shan into a province
renowned for martial arts.
Martial Arts Street in Fo Shan, 1935
Another competitor.
Okay, let's start practicing.
Come on, ready...
One...
Two...
One... two...
Sir, a Master Liu is looking for you.
May I know who you are?
I'm the patriarch of the Liu Fist Sect.
I just started a martial club in Fo Shan.
Congratulations.
I hear that Master Ip
is a Wing Chun expert.
I'd love to practice with you today.
Can we do it some other day?
It's not convenient right now.
Since I'm already here,
let's just play around for a bit.
It's all private.
No one else shall know who wins.
It's not a matter of winning.
I'm having dinner.
In that case... I'll wait for you.
Master Liu.
Have you eaten yet?
Please join me.
You want one?
No, thanks.
Is the food all right tonight?
Very good indeed.
That's good.
Very quick.
Leave it, Uncle Wang.
Close the door first.
Master Liu.
Please!
Are you okay?
I'm fine...
Let's start again!
Okay, here I come.
Touch!
All touch!
Thanks for being lenient, Master Liu.
Thanks for teaching me.
I've learned a lot.
The pleasure was all mine.
Regarding this private duel, Master Ip...
I won't tell anyone. Don't worry.
Thanks so much. I'm so grateful.
Goodbye.
Farewell.
So long.
With "Move 1000 Catties with 4 Taels",
Ip pushed Master Liu's whole body away.
Isn't "Move 1000 Catties with 4 Taels"
Tai Chi?
I thought Master Ip practiced Wing Chun.
Anyway,
he pushed him away with one hand.
Liu refused to admit defeat.
Ip kept chasing after him fiercely!
But Liu remained
indignant after being hit.
He jumped at Ip like a hungry dog.
These tea leaves are
pretty good and cheap.
Thank you.
Got to go.
Farewell.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, see you next time.
Who put these here, Uncle Ping?
Your brother.
I thought Liu was good
but he's so bad at defence...
and was beaten up like a pighead.
He co-owns his dad's
restaurant. He's always idle.
Ask that kid to serve the customers.
Good morning.
Brother Ip!
Morning, Master Ip.
Is Quan here yet?
He's waiting for you upstairs.
Been here long, Quan?
You're always late.
I'm busy.
Busy with what?
Drinking tea, eating, practicing.
What else?
This tea smells nice.
I'm talking about you.
Have you ordered yet?
I got something to discuss with you.
Let's eat first and then we'll talk.
This just came out of the oven!
Try it...
Heard that you had
a duel with Master Liu...
and had beaten him quickly.
Is that true?
Who told you that, Lin?
My brother.
Should've told me earlier.
I'm his disciple now!
But you've been
a disciple of every master.
Was it a private duel, Brother Ip?
We have things to discuss.
Leave us for now.
Then I won't disturb
your private conversation.
Good!
- Morning, Master!
- Morning.
Morning.
Master.
I heard that you were beaten by Ip Man.
Everyone in Fo Shan knows about it now.
Nonsense! Who told you that?
Yuan at the restaurant.
Everything is expensive
in Fo Shan these days.
So what?
That means the
economy is good in Fo Shan.
Everybody can afford to spend money.
Is that so?
Clothing is the most
important in our daily lives.
There will be lots of
demand for future clothing.
I'll open a cotton mill
to provide cotton for them.
I want you to be my partner.
I don't know anything about business.
But I do.
I'm not in need of money.
Who's Yuan? Show yourself!
I am
You rascal. You ruined my reputation.
I must teach you a lesson!
Master...
He's my brother. Let's talk.
Calm down. Okay, Master?
Your brother?
He ruined my reputation.
He said I was beaten by Ip Man.
What's gonna happen to my martial club?
Who will want to be my disciples?
Apologize!
I didn't do anything wrong.
I told the truth!
You're bullshitting again!
You... Master...
Master Ip is upstairs.
Seek him out if you have guts!
What? Go!
Take it easy, Master...
Master...
Don't be angry, Master.
I've been wronged, Master Ip.
Master,
please tell everybody...
you've defeated Master Liu in a duel.
Master Ip...
You got to clear my name.
You liar,
why're you bothering Brother Ip?
I'm no liar.
I saw the duel when
I was picking up my kite.
Your kite got lost
and fell into Brother Ip's house.
You saw the whole duel
between the two masters.
Isn't that too much of a coincidence?
That's exactly what happened.
Even if it's true,
you shouldn't have told everyone.
You're not supposed
to tell certain things
What's wrong with
telling the truth?
That might cause
embarrassment for others.
What embarrassment? I don't know how!
This is embarrassment!
You don't need to do that, Lin.
Why're you laughing?
You think I'm invisible?
Captain... it's no big deal.
What's no big deal?
- Leave!
- Don't you leave!
Captain, it's no big deal.
I saw everything. I'm warning you...
I'll nab whoever causes
trouble in my district.
I didn't cause any trouble.
Someone ruined my name.
I'm here to claim justice.
What justice? I am justice.
You hooligans are fighting all the time.
What age are we in now?
Still talking about martial arts?
We're talking about arms and guns!
Guns. Got it?
You know, Captain Li...
We martial artists are energetic.
Sometimes we might be a bit too loud.
But that doesn't mean
we're not civilized.
We're civilized folks.
Please don't pull the gun.
Cut me some slack.
Lin, set a table for Captain Li.
It's on me.
Yes... Captain Li, this way please.
What you looking at? Get lost
Don't stare. Don't stare...
Get out of the way.
Please.
Master Liu.
As you please.
Why so secretive?
I'm really not good at business.
Take this to set up the mill.
Pay me back if you make a profit.
It'll be a while before I can repay you.
Take your time.
Another request:
Take my son as your disciple.
There're so many martial club masters.
Ask them.
None of them is better than you.
We're similar.
Brother Ip.
Lin.
Brother Quan.
I learned some new moves.
Practice with me
You got so much time.
You found your brother?
Let him be.
He'll come back once
he spent all his money.
Let's try.
Dad, did Uncle Ip agree?
Let's go watch over there.
You draw very well, Zhun.
What new moves have you learned?
Let's see.
Brother Ip, my master says,
this move is offense
and defense all in one.
Attack while defending.
Defend while attacking.
Aren't they the same?
Go away, ignorant kid.
Here I come.
This move attacks the midrib.
Stop reciting mantras.
Hit your target.
Mom, I'm done with my drawing.
So beautiful. Show it to Dad.
Hit to disperse.
Disperse while hitting
My last move was
"disperse while hitting"...
Dad, look.
Wait. I'm busy at the moment
- You don't get it?
- No.
Come again if you don't get it.
Try again
Dad doesn't want to see it.
There you go.
What?
That was "disperse while hitting"
Once more, Master Ip.
I couldn't see clearly.
See? What do you wanna see?
You guys fight every day.
Aren't you tired?
You okay, Brother Ip?
Sorry, Mrs. Ip.
Goodbye, Mrs. Ip.
I wasn't talking about you.
No, there're things to
take care of at the mill.
Yao.
I gotta go, Uncle Ip.
Okay, see you next time.
Bye, Ip.
Talk to me if you're not happy.
No need to throw a tantrum.
Okay, please take a look
at your son's drawing.
Spend more time with
him and less with your pals.
Let's go inside, okay?
Go.
Brother.
Where's the martial club street?
Martial club!
Go straight ahead.
One, two...
Which martial club should
be challenge first, Bro?
One... two!
One...
Back!
You teach martial arts here?
Come in if you wanna learn.
Who's the patriarch?
I am.
My name is Jin.
I came here because Fo Shan
is famous for martial arts.
I'd like to practice with
Fo Shan's martial artists.
Practice?
Yes!
Provocation, more likely.
I'm obliged.
Okay!
Stand aside.
See how I'll beat these out-of-towners!
Not here. Stand over there.
What about it?
Wait and see!
Very good!
Where's your master?
Here!
You wanna hack me to death?
Our master is not here.
The weather is so treacherous
in Fo Shan these days.
Let me...
What are you drawing, Zhun?
He's ignoring you.
Spend more time with him.
Okay.
So early, Lin?
Yes.
I'm not here to fight. Just a few words.
What's the matter?
Some out-of-towners
are provoking all the clubs.
Their kung-fu is too good
for all the masters.
Can you look into that if you can?
That good?
Yes.
I gotta go, Mrs. Ip.
Hang in there, Master Liu!
We depend on you, Master Liu!
Damn it.
No one in Fo Shan
knows martial arts at all.
I thought everyone
was Wong Fei-hong here.
It turns out you are just bums.
You can't even fight,
let alone defend yourselves.
Brothers,
our efforts have not been wasted.
Nobody in Fo Shan knows martial arts,
so we'll be rich this time.
Brothers, let's keep it up.
We open a club here
to show them our might.
We will be No.1 in Fo Shan!
You think you're good
by beating a few nitwits.
Wait till you beat the best.
Who's the best in Fo Shan?
Ip Man, of course!
Go!
Come with us!
See how we shall defeat Ip Man.
Dad, there're lots of people outside.
How can I help you?
Sir... they...
Are you Ip Man?
I'm Jin. Heard that Fo Shan's
famous for kung-fu.
I understand, Master Jin.
I understand.
You bring a crowd here
to challenge me to a duel?
Of course.
We're opening a club
here to show our might.
To open a martial club...
you need a good site.
No need to fight with me.
Please leave!
Uncle Wang, take Zhun inside.
Ip Man!
Don't dillydally. Are you scared?
You think our house is a martial club?
Who's going to fight with you? Get lost!
You heard that. I won't fight with you.
Please leave immediately.
I heard Wing Chun
was invented by a woman.
That suits you just right.
Are you afraid of your wife, Ip?
No men are afraid of their wives.
There are only men who respect their wives.
Don't worry, Mrs. Ip.
I won't beat him to death.
If you fear he'll lose,
I'll use only one hand.
If that's not enough,
I can use no hands at all.
Fight with him, Master Ip! Beat him up!
I'm too disappointed by Fo Shan. Damn it!
So many martial artists
but none of them good.
Shut up!
Don't break my things.
Get out of my way!
You rascals.
You come at the right time.
This place is too small.
Please get outside...
and close the door on your way out.
You have to redeem our honor.
Ask them to leave. Hurry up!
Can I just watch?
Get out!
Hurry up! Get out!
Get out! Get out!
Wing Chun, Ip Man.
I really wanna see...
how a man can fight like a woman.
Good kung-fu does not
depend on age or sex
but on how well you fight.
You will know later.
I'll pay!
Good!
Dad, Mom said if you
don't start fighting,
everything in the house will be broken.
Okay.
Little brat.
Watch your language.
Bro...
You all right, Master Jin?
I'm fine!
How about that, Master Jin?
My kung-fu isn't too bad, eh?
That's enough.
My northern boxing has
lost to your southern one.
No, it's not a matter of
northern or southern style.
The problem is you.
So who won?
Look how depressed he is.
He must have lost.
Get lost! Go back to your hometown!
Get lost, you out-of-towners!
Master!
You fought very well, Ip!
You've redeemed the
honor of our martial clubs.
I was just lucky...
Don't be modest.
You are Canton's treasure!
Thank you.
Take a look. It's imported.
- Master Ip, flowers for your wife.
- Thanks
How much, boss?
On the house, Master Ip.
I can't let you pay.
You saved our honor.
How can that be?
You're running a business.
Don't stand on ceremonies.
Next time then.
Okay, next time
Fruits, Master Ip.
- You're too kind. I can't...
- For the kid.
Thank you.
Please come again. Goodbye.
Buddy.
- Say thank you.
- Take this.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome... Farewell.
How are you, Master Ip?
How are you?
That isn't bad at all.
Yes, this is the best in our shop.
Really?
It's our honor if it can
be placed in your house.
Thank you.
What's the occasion?
Uncle Man. Auntie.
So you plan on opening a martial club.
Why didn't you inform me first?
When did I say that?
Everybody in Fo Shan knows about it.
Everybody in Fo Shan but me.
Let me help you, Uncle Man.
Please accept me as
your disciple, Master Ip.
Master.
Madam.
Bro.
You must be the one spreading the rumor.
Keep order for me.
Come. Go yourself.
I don't care.
Yao has to be your first disciple.
Come on. You've known me long enough.
I don't like having disciples.
Be quiet.
Stay in order.
Stay in order and hail:
Master Ip! Master Ip...
On July 7, 1937, the Marco Polo Incident
broke out. Japan invaded China,
robbing its people
of their livelihood
and causing rampant starvation
all over the country.
In October, 1938, Fo Shan
was occupied by the Japanese army...
...who destroyed factories,
infrastructures and buildings.
The population of Fo Shan shrunk from
more than 300,000 to just over 70,000.
Only a dozen factories in the whole city
remained in operation.
Ip's residence was also confiscated
and turned into the headquarters
of the Japanese army.
Ip's family was rendered homeless,
living an abject existence.
Cheng, I'll step out for a sec.
Will be right back.
Wait.
It's cold outside. Wear a Jacket.
Hurry up. Me this side, you that side.
Be careful, Zhun. Don't hurt others.
I'll give you more, Master Ip.
Thank you.
Don't push! One by one.
Don't push.
One by one.
You get out of the way!
The mill may be old
but it's still productive.
Fo Shan is very chaotic these days.
You left already. Why did you come back?
Who's going to feed
the workers otherwise?
All my money is invested in this mill.
I can't pay you back for now.
Don't worry. I almost forgot.
No, I'll consider you a shareholder then.
Let me calculate...
you should have ten percent shares.
It's really not necessary.
Stay and help me out,
now that you own it too.
Uncle Ip.
Yao.
You'll be helping out? That's great!
Everyone will be lively
under your leadership.
And I can watch you practice Wing Chun.
Ip, stay for lunch.
It's lunchtime for the workers.
Yes, let's have lunch together.
No, thanks.
I can't. Next time.
Goodbye.
Dad, why didn't you
ask Uncle Ip to stay?
He doesn't like to owe people favors-
Dad, you used to
practice martial arts, right?
Why did you stop?
I get hungry when I exercise.
So I need to exercise less, okay?
Got it. I won't play outside from now on.
You'll only stop playing today. Go eat.
Hurry up and eat.
This congee is a bit too thick.
But you need to eat some.
Be careful, it's hot.
How much rice is left at home?
Don't worry.
I've pawned everything worth pawning.
I am strong. I can look for a job.
It's not the end of the world.
You look for a job?
I didn't need to work.
But it's different now.
There's always a first time.
We have enough people here.
We don't need to hire more. Sorry.
Boss, are you hiring?
No.
Thank you.
You want to hire me, Boss...
Boss...
You, you, you... Come up here...
You want to hire me, Boss...
Here.
You're looking for a job, Master Ip?
Come, come up...
Thank you.
Brother Ip!
You can't dress like that to work.
I didn't expect to pour coals here.
How are you, Master Ip?
How are you?
So many martial club masters here?
The boss here used
to practice martial arts too.
That's why he likes
to employ martial artists.
By the way, are you still practicing?
I'd rather use my
time to scrape a living.
I can't finish it all. Help me, okay?
Eat some.
How're your wife and son?
They're fine. Thank you.
Did you find your brother?
I couldn't locate him since he left.
Don't know if he's still alive.
I didn't even have
the chance to say I'm sorry.
What have you lost?
I lost an iron box.
What iron box?
Japanese solders are coming!
Dear workers,
this is Colonel Sato.
He appreciates Chinese martial arts.
He knows Fo Shan is
famous for martial arts.
He wants to find Chinese martial
artists to fight with the Japanese.
Would anyone want to go?
Master?
You want us to be sandbags?
There's no door, I tell you!
Airhead.
Whoever wins will
get one sack of rice.
get one sack of rice
I'll do it!
Lin...
Don't get into trouble.
I'm going too! Me too!
They took all our rice.
Now I can get them back.
The world is fair.
Forget it.
Help me find the iron box.
Let's go. It's okay. Come.
Be careful.
Come, let's line up.
Come, come, come...
Anything else?
- No, let's go.
- Yes!
Master?
General.
Thank you, General!
Got to beat them all.
Let me join in the fun.
They're not good enough
for General Miura.
I'll show the Chinese what
Japanese kung-fu's like.
Find three men to fight with me.
Give them rice even if they lose.
Yes, sir!
I've done you a favor again.
General Miura will fight
with three of you.
You can get rice whether you win or not.
The rice is not important.
I just wanna beat them.
Who will be going?
I will...
Let go of me... Stop shouting!
Lin, you and you...
The three of you.
Okay!
You've spit blood.
Stop fighting.
We've lost.
General, they admitted defeat.
Your really wanna die?
You asshole!
Lin, how are you? Lin...
Lin...
Were you tired today?
Pouring coal is not tiring at all.
I saw Lin today.
Really? How is he?
Not bad.
I didn't expect to see him again.
Master Li, Master Hong.
Master Ip.
Did you see Lin?
Lin? No.
No, I didn't.
Let's eat first.
Many of us received rice yesterday.
General Miura was very satisfied.
Anybody wants to go today?
Anybody? Li...
Li...
Where's Lin?
Anybody wants to go?
I'm asking you. Where's Lin?
I don't know.
Of course you do.
You took him away.
Anybody wants to go?
You'll get rice if you win.
Me!
If Master Ip is going, I'll go too!
Me too!
I wanna have a good fight
with the Japanese.
Anything else I can do?
No, you can go.
Thanks.
Can I fight three more people?
He said he wanted to
fight three more people.
That's it for me...
Why did you open fire?
Li! Why did you open fire?
Who let you open fire?
He took the rice even though he's lost.
so... I wanted to teach him a lesson.
This place is for tournaments only.
Never open fire here anymore.
Got it!
Please calm down, General Miura.
I'll arrange the next tournament for you.
Continue!
Who else wants to fight?
Me!
Li! Open the gate!
Master... Open the gate!
Tell me, was Lin beaten to death?
Open the gate.
Master...
Open the gate!
Please open the gate.
I wanna fight ten people!
You crazy? Please don't.
He said he wanted to fight ten people.
Ten?
Yes
Let's see how good he is.
Unit 5!
Unit 1, Unit 3, Unit 5.
Start!
Be careful
Stay back!
Come back again.
He wants you to come back again.
I'm not here for the rice.
He said... he would come back.
What's your name?
He wants to know your name.
I'm just a Chinese.
His name is Ip Man.
Be careful in the future.
I don't know what Miura might do.
Lackey!
Why am I a lackey?
Their deaths got nothing to do with me.
I'm just an interpreter.
I need to scrape a living too!
Scrape a living?
You watch your countrymen get beaten
to death. Where's your dignity?
I don't have any.
You do. You have lots of it.
If you have the guts, go beat them up!
Beat as many as you can!
I'm an interpreter, not a lackey...
I'm a Chinese!
I'm back.
Daddy.
You're back?
Have you been good?
Yes.
Good boy.
Are you tired today?
Go wash your face first.
You're so good.
I realize today I'm useless.
I can't do anything.
I practiced marital arts before.
But so what?
This world...
is minuscule.
I'm so useless.
I don't care what the world is like.
I only know I'm very happy now.
As long as you, me, and Zhun...
can stay together,
everything will be okay.
It's essential for a
family to stay together.
Get off! Get off!
Get off...
Stand over there! On the side!
Stand over there...
Who's the boss? Come out!
I am.
I just took your goods.
You can buy them back.
Is that okay?
I don't have money.
Don't beat my dad anymore!
Wing Chun?
Damn it! Wing Chun?
Don't beat him!
Do you have money?
I don't.
Do you?
No...
I'll keep beating you till you have!
The goods haven't been sold...
I don't have money.
Uncle Ip! Uncle Ip...
Please save my dad.
He's almost beaten to death.
What's the matter, Yao?
Auntie.
Let me go see what happens.
It's okay.
I'm very reasonable.
It's fine if you don't have money now.
I'll give you some time to raise it.
As for the goods, I'll keep them for now.
Master Ip.
Dad, are you okay?
I'm fine. Go help Uncle Fu.
How can I help?
I thought your martial
arts were impractical.
Now I know it's very useful.
I should've learnt some
martial arts from you.
At least I can defend myself.
Uncle Ip,
please stay and teach us martial arts,
so that we can defend ourselves.
Master Ip.
You're such an expert. Please teach us.
Yes, Master Ip. Please teach us.
I'm a businessman.
I know nothing other
than running a business.
I can't protect them, but you can.
In peaceful days,
it's okay if you refused to teach.
But in bad times now,
shouldn't you do something?
Teaching martial arts is very costly.
Are you paying their fees?
You owe me again?
Uncle Ip, I'll be your first disciple.
Dad, I wanna be taller.
Taller?
Why hasn't Ip Man come back?
I... I don't know...
Find him.
I don't know where he is.
I don't know how to find him.
How big is Fo Shan?
How difficult can it be to find him?
Fo Shan is indeed very big.
No...
Please don't...
I really don't know where he is...
Useless thing! Enough!
Asshole!
Paper, stone, scissors!
You lost.
You colluded?
Hide well.
10, 9, 8, 7...
Zhun.
That way.
3, 2, 1
I'm coming. I'll find you guys
Master.
What're you here for?
Miura wants you to go back and fight him.
Go away.
I can't.
Why not?
Why not? What do you want?
What do you want?
How pretty!
Shit.
Let's go. It's not safe here.
Let's go, Cheng.
Li.
You're a piece of shit!
How could you let Ip run away?
I'm sorry...
Even Colonel Sato could not stop him...
I've tried my best already...
Sorry.
Shut up!
Utterly useless!
Tell them...
to dig Ip out! This is an order.
Yes, sir.
Little Sis.
Brother, eat something.
How's the master?
Okay. They are all fine.
Master.
Coming...
Madam.
See if it fits?
So are you well adapted here?
Yes.
That's good.
I'll let you know when the meal is ready.
Li...
I'm fine.
I really don't know what to say.
Thank you.
It's okay.
We better leave Fo Shan
as soon as possible.
Quan is trying to find a solution for us.
Where shall we go?
Hong Kong.
In fact, it doesn't matter where.
I still have some friends in Hong Kong.
If something happens to me...
What can happen to you?
Nothing will happen to you.
They are here again! Let's scram!
They are here! They are here!
Have zou got the money?
We won't give you money!
What did you say?
I'm not afraid of you!
You can't bully us!
You want me to beat you up?
Damn it! Whoever dares to resist...
just beat him up!
Stop it!
No wonder they dare to resist.
They've found a bodyguard.
You spurned me for
opening a club in Fo Shan.
And today, you wanna mess with me again?
You wanna chase me away?
No one wants to chase you away.
Ip, have you ever been hungry every day?
Everybody is hungry nowadays.
The first day I came to
Fo Shan, I told myself...
I would never be hungry again.
I will never be hungry again!
Keep beating!
Beat them!
Yuan, why you still idling here? Go!
Kill them!
Go.
How can we get near him?
Let's go!
Master, you were so good!
Yuan.
Stop there!
You know what you're doing?
I know. I'm a robber.
You're robbing the Chinese.
I'd rather be the bully than the bullied.
I want everyone to be scared of me!
Your brother asked me to give this...
Don't talk about him!
You know your brother is dead?
He's beaten to death by the Japanese.
He looked for you everywhere
but couldn't find you.
Everyone needs to choose his own path.
Master.
That guy told Miura
you're at the cotton mill.
Don't go back, ok?
I gotta go.
Remember, don't go back.
Scram! Hurry up!
Where's Ip Man?
Where's Ip Man? Tell me!
Don't say a word.
You, come here.
Where's Ip Man?
Tell me!
I'm asking you!
Hang in there. I'll figure something out.
Speak!
Speak! Speak up...
I'm here! I'm Ip Man...
I'm here... Li!
Wait! Wait!
Please wait!
Li, tell Miura the workers are innocent.
Ask Miura to release them.
I told you not to come back.
Why did you?
Tell him!
Shit!
Sato!
He dares to hit me...
Can't we put him to death?
I know what I'm doing.
- Li.
- Yes.
Since the day you resisted
the Japanese army,
you've already been a dead man.
But you're talented,
you can be useful to us.
So I'll give you one chance to be loyal
to the Japanese Emperor.
Teach our army Chinese kung-fu.
That way, we might still spare your life.
He wanted you to teach
the Japanese kung-fu.
I won't teach the Japanese.
You wanna see me fight?
I'll fight with you.
He said he would think about it.
He wants to have a
duel with General Miura.
Take him away!
Quan, take my wife
and kid away from Fo Shan.
Master Ip...
General, you really wanna fight with Ip?
Of course.
He's an expert.
But he doesn't look like...
he wants to teach the Imperial Army.
He must have other motives
trying to fight with you.
General, don't fight with him.
Let me simply shoot him dead.
He challenges me to a fight...
because he thinks he's better than me.
If I refuse to accept the challenge...
but shoot him instead...
isn't that the same as admitting defeat?
Fighting with a Chinese...
is not just a matter of
personal honor for you.
It has to do with the
national honor of our Empire.
Are you saying I will lose?
I only fear for the worst.
I will win for sure.
I'll let the whole China know I've won.
Yes! I understand!
I want you to teach us
instead of killing you,
because I appreciate your talent.
But I don't think Chinese kung-fu
is better than Japanese.
We will fight in front of everybody.
That's why we need a fair tournament.
You invaded our country
and killed our people.
Stop being hypocritical.
Excuse me.
Let go of me! Let me go back!
Let go of my mom...
I promised Ip nothing
would happen to you.
It's too dangerous to go back.
I heard the Japanese
are fighting the Chinese.
- Who's fighting?
- Ip Man.
Look, the whole place is sealed up now.
In the past...
I wished he could be with me every day.
So I always complained
about his practice.
Every time he had a duel with someone...
I would throw a tantrum.
I never truly supported him
doing what he liked.
Now...
This could be his last duel.
I fear there won't be another chance.
Why don't you give me this chance?
Why?
General Miura says...
For the sake of Sino-Japanese
cultural exchange,
he is having a fair tournament
with Master Ip today...
to share their knowledge
in a friendly manner,
and to bring true peace
between the two countries.
Fair tournament? Is that possible?
That traitor will surely
be killed by the Japanese.
That's right.
Shut up!
Here comes Master Ip!
General Miura talked about a tournament.
But I don't give a damn!
Listen up.
If you win,
I will kill you.
Remember this!
Yes!
You better let Miura win later...
or he won't let you live.
It's more important to stay alive.
Although martial arts
involves armed forces,
Chinese martial arts
is Confucian in spirit.
The virtue of martial arts
is benevolence.
You Japanese will never
understand the principle...
of treating other people
as you would yourselves.
Because you abuse military power.
You turned it into violence
to oppress others.
You don't deserve to learn
Chinese martial arts.
Ip Man! Ip Man!
Ip Man refused to be subjugated
by the Japanese army...
...and used his fists to call forth
the unity of the Chinese people.
Assisted by his good
friend Zhou Qingquan,
the wounded Ip Man successfully
fled Fo Shan with his wife and son.
On August 15, 1945,
Emperor Hirohito of Japan announced that
Japan would surrender unconditionally.
The Chinese finally won and ended a war
that lasted eight long years.
In 1949, the Grandmaster Ip Man
settled in Hong Kong.
He started his first Wing Chun class
at Kowloon Hotel's Staff
Association Headquarters,
turning a new leaf in his life.
In 1967, Grandmaster Ip Man started the
Wing Chun Athletic Association to foster...
...the spirit of Wing Chun
with a group of like-minded enthusiasts,
fulfilling the most cherished dream
of his later years.
Until now, Wing Chun has become a world
renowned branch of Chinese martial arts.
The lineage of Grandmaster Ip Man's
disciples has exceeded 2 million people.
There are lots of talented people
among his disciples,
including the most illustrious
action star of all, Bruce Lee.
edited by rogard,
made by unknown