Get to it.
Jackson! No!
Ahh.
Roger.
You're a wonderful man, yes,
and you're a great lawyer.
We're just not meant to be together.
No, I don't wanna marry you!
Are you crazy?
The hell's the matter with you?
Roger, we're done.
Oh, my God.
Fuck! God!
Hurgh!
Fucking men!
- Did he cry?
- Yeah, he cried. He laughed.
He yelled at me.
You know, whatever.
- You broke his heart, Mama.
- I did the right thing.
- Ally, garbage!
- It just wasn't right... Oh, hey, Bryan.
- Can somebody else do it?
- Let her shine!
It's your fucking turn!
- Oh, my God!
- Who's he talking to?
OK, I'll see you upstairs.
Come on, Bryan!
She's performing tonight!
Here we go. Taking out the trash.
Wipe your mouth.
You can go early if you finish your job.
Well, you gotta keep your mouth clean.
OK?
Ohh. Where the fuck are we?
We are uh...east of the city.
- Is there any more?
- No.
No, sorry, Jack.
And it's... It's about an hour, 40,
with traffic till we get there.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Think we can find something around here?
No, I'll find something.
I'll find something.
How's your kid?
How old is he now?
- He is 17.
- Fuck me.
And he got a scholarship
to play baseball in college already, man.
- Wow, that's great.
- I'm proud of him.
My little guy is not so little any more.
I don't wanna go home.
Wish I could find you a spot.
- Sorry, Jack, I don't know this area.
- Would you make a right here?
- You sure?
- Yeah.
All right.
Here we go.
That looks like a fucking bar.
- Here?
- What's that say? "Bleu Bleu."
Here, let me just try this.
Oh, shit.
Wait, wait.
- My man, my man, I... Aren't you like...
- This is a bar, right?
- Yeah, but not your kind of place.
- They got alcohol?
- Well, yeah, but...
- Oh, it's my kind of place.
Oh, shit! This is crazy!
How are you doin', papo?
How am I doin'?
All right, if I can get a drink.
- You good?
- Yeah.
- Oh, yeah. There's the bar.
- This is my home girl Giselle.
- How you doin'?
- Oh, yeah. That's Jack.
Can we get this man
anything he wants, please?
Can I get a gin on the rocks...
Papo, wow.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm freaking out right now.
- Hey, is this a drag bar?
- Yeah, papo. Yeah, yeah.
But, look, we do this every Friday night.
Yo, it's crazy. It's so lit, though.
I thought maybe I was in
some sort of hallucinogenic state.
- Or something.
- No, no. All are welcome.
A dress or something.
Gonna have something?
Let me get you a drink.
OK. Yeah, um, wow.
You better kill 'em tonight.
All you ladies, kill it tonight, OK?
- I'm ready.
- I always do!
Make sure you've turned in
your music already.
Don't make me
have to come get you tonight.
This is a professional show.
Oh, yes! Oh, you stayed!
- That's good. I like it.
- Everything good? You good?
Yeah, I was just talking to Nicki.
You know Nicki?
- Hello, Nicki. How you doin', baby?
- She's telling me her life story.
- Fascinating.
- My home girl's about to perform.
Y'all know her well
because she used to work here as a server.
But, tonight, the only thing she's serving
are some fabulous, French live vocals.
Is she really singing,
or is it one of those karaoke things?
No, she's really singing, papo.
I promise you. Watch this. Watch.
Would anybody like
some French tips tonight?
Yes, baby! Yes, baby!
Oh, fuck.
- Oh, papo, you crying?
- A little bit.
You have...
You have to meet her.
- What's that?
- You have to meet her!
- Oh, no, I can't meet her.
- Yes! Come on.
Donte, you got a rag, honey? Thank you.
Miss Ally, now you sang in French,
you gonna pick something else next week?
- I don't know.
- Look at her, doing languages.
- Do Moroccan.
- No!
- This is my friend, Jackson Maine.
- Hey.
- This is Jackson Maine.
- Hey. How are you?
- Hey! Oh, my God!
- Right? This is my friend, Ally.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- I thought that might be you.
- What'd you say?
- That's me.
Thank you! Do you wanna sit down?
- No! You've been on your feet all night.
- No! You're our guest.
- You sure you don't mind?
- A little drink?
- I'm here watching the show - you guys.
- Word.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Sign my boob?
- Sure. Yeah, I can do that.
- Oh, my God!
- Give me a sharpie!
- You know, it's BYOB around here.
- Yeah?
- "Bring your own boobs."
Oh, God!
Oh, those aren't really her boobs?
Wow!
So, why are you in here, hon?
- Sorry?
- What brings you here?
I was playing right around here tonight.
I'm a musician.
- How'd your show go?
- I think it went all right.
- OK, here we go. All right.
- Thank you!
- That's all right?
- Oh, my.
- Aahh.
- Which one should I do?
- Do 'em both! I don't care!
- Slut!
- Why don't I do it across?
- Bitch, Jackson Maine!
- I'll just...
- Oh, my!
Ohh, she will stop at nothing.
- You gotta blow on it!
- I did it pretty big. Oh.
- Oh, you got it. OK.
- Thank you so much!
You all gotta go home
but you know the phrase.
You gotta get the hell up outta here!
Cos I'm not losing my virginity
or my liquor licence
over you bitches, so pack up!
- That's right!
- That's enough cocktails!
Clear it out!
Hello, goodbye, Roger.
Have fun!
- Bring the drinks on out!
- Do you do that often?
- Do what?
- The show.
Yeah, yeah.
The girls are so nice to me here.
I mean, they would never normally
let a girl sing at one of these shows
but they've always loved my voice.
They used to beg me to sing.
It's an honour, really.
I get to be one of the gay girls.
Is that your real eyebrow?
Um... No. No.
I... I make it out of tape.
- Oh, so it's, like, stuck on?
- Mm-hm.
Can I try to take it off?
Uh... Yeah, sure.
It's incredible what they do.
- Look at that.
- Yep. There it is.
- I should put her down somewhere.
- OK.
There we go.
Why are you covering your eye?
Just cos I don't have
my eyebrow on any more.
Oh, no, no.
The whole point is I can see your face.
Yeah, there we go.
Why did you come back here?
Your friend brought me back here.
I'm glad he did.
Can I buy you a drink?
Oh... I... I gotta change,
and I've got paint in my hair.
- And my eyebrows are...
- That's not your real hair?
No, my hair's like your colour.
- Oh, OK.
- But I paint it with this...
- ..makeup.
- I'd love to see what that looks like.
I'll wait for you.
Um... Yeah, OK. Sure.
Yeah, if you wanna wait,
I'll come have a drink with you.
Sure.
Bitch, can you get down off that stage
and come help me close this bar, please?
Don't talk to me like that
in that bus driver wig, girl.
Oh, I know you did not. What, you have
a street appointment tonight, sister?
Excuse me! Mr Maine, would you mind?
Uh... What do you want me to do?
Just come play a little song for me.
- I don't know.
- Can you leave the man alone, please?
I showed you mine, you show me yours.
Come on.
He already signed your tits, honey.
Say, "No, sir."
- Show off for me a little bit.
- Only because you already performed.
You're so nice. Thank you.
Lord, the man is here for Ally.
Not for you, sister.
- Oh... She's nice. Yeah.
- Isn't it cute? Little arts and crafts.
- Yeah, and light.
- Mm-hm.
- Did you do this yourself?
- Yeah, all me.
Looks great.
Does this mic work?
Oh, yeah. Fuck, all right.
What do you want me to play?
I don't care,
just look at me while you do it.
- Oh, Lord! Somebody kill me now.
- Let me see what I can... All right.
You're ready?
- You know I would!
- OK.
- It's a cop bar.
- Cops?
Yeah, that's why they serve
all night long.
- Can I ask you a personal question?
- Oh. Sure.
Do you write songs or anything?
- I don't sing my own songs.
- Thank you.
Why?
I just... I just don't feel comfortable.
Why wouldn't you feel comfortable?
Um...
Well, cos, like,
almost every single person
that I've come in contact with
in the music industry
has told me that my nose is too big
and that I won't make it.
- Your nose is too big?
- Yeah.
Your nose is beautiful.
- Are you showing me your nose?
- Yeah.
- I've been looking at it all night.
- Oh, come on.
I'll be thinking about it
for a long time.
- You're full of shit.
- I'm telling you the truth.
- Can I touch your nose?
- Oh, my gosh!
- Let me just touch it for a second.
- You're very lucky.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hm.
- Yeah, not really.
My nose has not made me lucky.
I could've had maybe a hit song
if it wasn't for my nose.
- That's fucking bullshit.
- Yeah.
No, it's not bullshit
because you go into these rooms
and there's all these fucking men
in there
and they're just staring at you,
listening to your record, going,
"Oh, you sound great,
but you don't look so great."
You know, I had a thing
when I was little...
I was born with this thing in my ear.
Couldn't hear.
What do I wind up being?
A singer. So, you never know.
Look, talent comes everywhere.
Everybody's talented.
Bet you fucking everybody
in this bar is talented
in one thing or another,
but having something to say...
and the way to say it so people
listen to it, that's a whole other bag.
And unless you get out there
and you try to do it, you'll never know.
That's just the truth.
If there's one reason we're here,
it's to say something
so people wanna hear it.
- Understand what I'm trying to tell you?
- Yeah, I do.
I don't like it, but I understand it.
Oh, I think you like it a little bit.
I think I'm getting through a little bit.
I can see it.
No, you can't.
It's a good thing we met.
- Yeah.
- For both of us.
- Trust me.
- I don't know what is going on.
- Honestly, what...
- Who does?
I'm in a cop bar, with Jackson Maine.
It's, like...
- Jackson Maine!
- I'm gonna wake up in a minute.
When you get famous,
people start saying your full name.
- Well, what do you want...
- Just "Jack".
Speaking of...
Come on.
- What?
- Did you put that on?
You put that on.
When did you even go to the jukebox?
Oh, God!
I hear that song,
and I just wanna turn it the fuck off.
- Jack Maine!
- I fucked that song up.
- No! What? Come on.
- Oh, my God!
Hey, I know that
we're not supposed to do this.
I know that we're not supposed
to bother you.
That's all right.
You got your camera?
I don't have mine. Excuse me, one sec.
- My ex-girlfriend was fucking this guy.
- OK.
- Who looks like you, she said.
- Shut up.
But I gotta take a picture of you
to send to her
to show her that you look
nothing like that fucking guy.
- Jack, I'm sorry.
- Take a picture.
Will that help you?
Will that make you happy?
- OK. Take a picture?
- Want someone to take the picture?
- No. It's OK.
- Excuse me.
- Get the fuck off, you little whore.
- What? What?
- Hey, come on. Stand up, yeah.
- What?
- I got you.
- I'm sorry, Jack!
- It's all right.
- Oh, my God! Why did I...
I'm fine, honestly. I'm OK.
This is so stupid.
No, you gotta get ahead
of the swelling.
Just trying to find some...
- This is so embarrassing.
- ..peas.
Here we go.
Yeah, put that on there.
Gotta wrap something up with it.
Find it.
- You like Cheetos?
- No, like gauze.
- Some gauze or something.
- Gauze?
Try to do that. With that hand.
And do that hand.
You play piano?
- Yeah, we gotta take care of this, then.
- Oh, OK. Thanks.
And that's it, yeah.
Keep that on there. Hold on.
Can you do that? Yeah.
Did you get it?
It's already gotten warm, hasn't it?
- Should we have gotten two?
- No, it's OK.
Thanks.
I'm sorry. I... I had to.
That's all right.
- It's not really all right, though.
- Have a good one.
Be careful, she'll hit you.
These rings are gonna get stuck
if you don't take them off.
- Does that hurt?
- Yeah. That's OK.
- May I?
- Yeah.
Safekeeping.
- Put this on there.
- You're a sweetheart.
And we'll just wrap it up.
You'll be good to go.
How the hell
do you deal with that all the time?
- What's that?
- People just...talking to you
like you're not a real person,
or taking your picture.
- Is that too tight?
- Ah, it's OK, thanks.
- Whoo... That hurt you?
- That's fine, it's OK.
There we go.
Now you're mobile.
Swing it around.
- I look like a pirate.
- Right?
I told you it was worth coming here.
How do you do that?
- Do what?
- Don't change the subject.
- Is that what I'm doing?
- Nobody ever asks you about you, huh?
- Not sure.
- Where are you from?
Arizona.
- Arizona boy.
- Mm-hm.
Dad had, like, a midlife crisis, I think.
So I've been told.
Made his way to Arizona, started working
for this family on a pecan ranch.
- A pecan ranch?
- Yeah.
Knocked up the family's daughter.
She was just shy of 18.
Uh-oh.
That's when I came into the picture.
- OK. The son of an 18-year-old.
- Yeah.
Well, she died at childbirth.
- Then, my dad...
- I'm sorry.
He...
He died when I was 13, so I guess...
my brother would tell you
that he raised me, but...
..I don't know.
I don't know who was raising who.
Just 127 acres of nuts, Navajo,
and nowhere to go.
Is that me?
That's you.
- Did you just write that now?
- Yeah.
It's pretty good.
I started writing this song
the other day, and...
..maybe that could work,
like as a chorus or something.
I have to think if I can remember it.
Ah...
Holy shit.
What is this?
Was this supposed to help me?
Can I tell you a secret?
I think you might be a songwriter.
But don't worry, I won't tell anybody.
But I'm not very good
at keeping secrets.
You're a real gentleman.
I think.
Thank you, sir.
It's on the right.
- Right there?
- Which one?
- This one.
- Oh, yeah.
- What's all this?
- Oh, it's my dad.
It's a long story.
What's he, a sheikh?
No, he's a driver.
Hey, I got a gig.
You wanna come?
- When?
- We're headed to the airport now.
- Tonight.
- Tonight? No, I can't.
I gotta go to work later.
I gotta go to bed.
Who's gonna take care of your hand?
I messed it up.
- Me.
- No, no!
- I'll take care of it.
- It's my fault.
- That's OK.
- No, listen. Hey!
- You have my number.
- OK. All right.
- Hey.
- What?
I just wanted to take
another look at you.
Maybe I fucked that up.
No.
- Hi, Dad.
- Pretty late, pretty late.
- Oh? Is it late?
- Yeah.
Look at you. You don't even know
where you're walking.
- Come on.
- Well, I wanna go to bed.
No, come in for two minutes.
It's Wolfie's birthday. Come on.
- Two minutes!
- OK.
- Wolfie!
- Yeah, sweetheart?
- Who was the guy in the car?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Hey, Ally.
- How's it goin'?
- Happy birthday.
- "Happy birthday"?
- Yeah.
- It's not my birthday.
- What do you mean? Come on.
- No, I was just saying...
What the hell happened in here?
My God!
- This place is a mess!
- "Starting gate" is "shuppatsu geto",
- and "bad beat" is "warui bito".
- What's going on? Leave the butter out?
Who the hell's betting on horses
at breakfast time in Japan?
- It's not breakfast time.
- They're loading!
- Joe, come on!
- You're crazy!
Have a sizable investment on this.
What did I say
about smoking in this house?
- Outside!
- Who are you?
- It's my house.
- I know it's your house.
- But you smoke too.
- All right, forget it.
Sweetheart, you're happy here,
aren't you?
I'm happy, Dad.
I'm just saying, she's got no space.
- What are you saying?
- Sweetheart.
- She's got no space.
- Wait a minute.
I want my friends to look at you.
Take a good look.
With a voice like from heaven,
but you know what?
It's not always the best singers
that make it.
You know? I knew a couple of guys
could sing Sinatra under the table.
But Frank, he'd come on stage
with the blue eyes,
the sharkskin suit,
the patent leather shoes...
he becomes Frank Sinatra.
And everybody else,
all these other guys...
that really got it,
that really have it inside...
..just a bunch of nobodies.
OK. Everybody, let's go.
Time for work.
Unfortunately,
you keep blasting the hearing...
it's not gonna come back.
I think it's time we reconsider
the in-ear monitors.
We talked about that with Bobby
a couple of weeks ago.
If we put the in-ear molds in,
we can use those
to amplify the high frequencies.
- OK, great.
- Cut down the sound.
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna talk to Bobby
- and get something set up.
- Sold. I'm sold.
- All right, Jack.
- Yeah, call Bobby.
- Stubborn son of a bitch.
- Ready. One, two, three, four.
- We're trying...
- You gotta put 'em in, man.
I told you, I can't wear those.
When I wear 'em, it's just in my head,
and I need to be here.
The doctor said it's the only way
to manage this thing, Jack.
You're not gonna get back what you lost.
It's the only way we can manage
what you still got.
Oh, wow. Ha!
I think we're managing pretty good.
What do you want me to do?
- The door's wide open if you wanna go.
- You know what? Don't start that shit.
Show a little fucking pride
in what you're doing, buddy.
I just wanna know
if she's on her way or not, that's all.
Who's coming?
What the fuck?
Who's here?
I have no idea. He won't tell me.
- Hi, Ally. I'm Phil.
- Hi.
- We met last night.
- Yeah.
- Jack sent me to take you to the gig.
- Oh, my God.
Um... But I gotta work.
- I can't go.
- He's really looking forward to this.
I appreciate that, but...
I can't leave, so I'll be in my car
right down the street.
Tell him, "Thank you, but no, thank you."
Say it like that.
- Wait, Ally. What are you doing?
- The fuck is that shit? This is crazy.
- This is great.
- What the hell's going on?
Look, a guy like that
invites you to a show...
- It could be a great opportunity.
- Dad, don't start with me!
Listen. Does he know you sing at all?
Did he hear anything from you?
- I gotta go to work.
- It's the opportunity of a lifetime.
I don't have the same disease you have.
You get around celebrities
like they're gonna rub off on you.
- What are you talking about?
- "Oh, you know who I drove?"
Like magic, now you're famous.
- And you're not. It's not magic, Dad.
- Sweetheart.
He's a drunk!
You know all about drunks.
Sweetheart, he's still there.
You fucking hit a cop?
Yeah, he was being an asshole to Jack,
so I fucking popped him in the face.
That is so gangster!
Then we ended up in a parking lot
and he put peas around my hand to fix it.
Then he was singing and I was singing.
I don't know what's going on.
Now he's got his driver
following me around.
He's been following you
from your house to work?
- Yes. It's crazy!
- You're fucking late.
I'm what?
I said you're late!
Are we doing this?
Hey, Bryan, I'm out.
- Find somebody else.
- Bryan, I'll be back.
- Papo, I promise.
- See ya. I won't.
- Did you see Bryan's face?
- Hey, great! Let's do this.
Let's go.
What are we doing?
You know, if I didn't know Jack...
I would call you a stalker.
Yeah, sorry about that.
Yes, man!
Lay on that couch right now!
I'm gonna take my shoes off.
- Oh, my God!
- This is nice.
How this shit works?
- They just told you no.
- Oh, OK. I'm so sorry.
Oh, shit!
I could get used to this shit.
You need to date more rock stars,
baby girl, you know?
We're not dating.
Hi, Ally. I'm Gail.
- Hi.
Leave your bags.
We'll grab 'em in a sec.
- Ready?
- OK, sure.
- OK. Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Did you have a good trip?
- Yeah.
Passes.
- Thank you.
- Put 'em around your necks.
Ear plugs. You'll need these.
It's loud up there.
Yeah, I got 'em.
We're coming in.
I'll bring you guys to the side stage.
Guys, guys, guys. This way.
Wrong way.
- Sorry. This place is so big. I'm just...
- Come on, this way.
Oh, watch yourself.
You guys good?
Hey, boys.
He's so excited that you're here.
Thank you very much.
That was great.
There's a friend of mine
who came a long way to be here
and she wrote a great song,
and I'd like her to sing it.
I think it's pretty fucking good.
- How are you?
- I'm good. Hi!
- It's so good to see you.
- How are you?
- You were so good.
- The trip was fine?
- Yeah.
- Phil didn't bother you?
Gail was so nice.
So, listen, we're gonna
sing that song, all right?
I did an arrangement -
kind of not so great -
- but stick with it.
- No, I can't.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah, you're coming.
Please. It's not funny.
Jack, don't fuck around.
All you gotta do is trust me.
That's all you gotta do.
I'm gonna sing it either way, so...
- Steve...
- "Trust me." OK.
- You have to go sing.
- I'm not going out there, no.
- Oh, my God! There's so many people.
- Pretty fucking good, man.
Pretty fucking good.
The way the guitar started...
I thought maybe I set it in the wrong key,
and the tempo was too fast.
- No, it was so beautiful, and...
- I wasn't sure...
- Ally, you OK?
- Jack?
Jack?
You. You, move!
- Isn't that the girl who sang?
- Good concert, man!
- Thank you, yeah.
- Love you, man.
- Thank you.
- Hey, Jack. Killed it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Hi! Oh, my God!
Where's my key?
I don't fucking...
Ah! Ha-ha-ha.
Oh, fuck!
I'll be right back. OK?
Just give me one second.
Is this the bathroom?
Where's the fucking...
OK.
Hey.
Jack?
I don't know, wake him up.
- I can't wake him up. He's drunk.
- Yes, you can!
Shake your titties in his face
or some shit, and just fucking...
Know what I'm saying?
Take two shots.
Thank you so much for your help.
You are so helpful.
Let me know how it goes, baby.
Come on, pal.
He's out.
You think maybe he drinks
a bit much?
Sweetie, you have no idea.
Tell you one thing, though.
He's never brought a girl
on stage before.
And it's been a long, long time
since he played like that.
Well, that's good to know.
One time, my brother came home,
I was playing on this upright
we used to always have in our den.
And I was, like, in my own world.
No-one was ever home,
and then he comes home
to take care of my dad,
who was sick.
And he's sittin' there,
and he's looking at me.
I swear to God, he looked at me
like I was special or something,
and it just kind of filled me up.
I should've never told you that.
I don't know.
Why?
- Cos it's embarrassing.
- It's so sweet.
Cos you're nothing like my brother,
let me just say.
- Yeah, I don't look like your brother?
- He's a fucking old man, OK.
My dad had me
when he was 63 years old.
63 years old?
- And we have different mothers, so...
- Huh.
What's that number down here?
That is how many people looked at it.
Get the fuck out of here. How do
they know how many people looked at it?
I think it's...
They call it an algorithm, or...
What's an algorithm?
It's like a beat.
- A beat?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Like in music, a beat?
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. I think, I don't know.
- Do you believe this?
- No.
- Wow.
- And you see this?
- Yeah.
- That's how many people have watched.
- Yeah, we're just telling...
- They was telling him.
- How the fuck do they do that?
- I've watched it 200 times myself.
- I'm 200 of those people.
- Go, Pops.
Oh, jeez!
My God, you're so fast! Jack!
French toast is gonna come out.
First one to hit the bed.
- Beautiful. You wrote this with him?
- He's so talented.
- Can I watch it again?
- Yeah, it's good. One more time.
- I'll be up all night watching this.
- Or 500. Come on!
Christ!
Oh, my God.
How did you get in here?
Your dad let me in.
What?
I don't feel this way about everybody.
Well, good. Then we're on the same page.
You come and sing with me.
Where?
Well, first stop's Arizona.
I'm never getting on that thing with you
when you've been drinking.
I haven't even thought about drinking
or anything else.
We'll see how long that lasts.
Go wait downstairs.
Actually, when I was in my 20's and 30's,
I was like a crooner.
As a matter of fact,
a lot of people thought I was...
better than Sinatra.
Frank Sinatra?
What are you writing down in here?
That's my songbook.
I usually use a typewriter, but...
I had this idea on the bike...
and I didn't wanna forget it.
How do you hear it?
Aren't you excited to be home
and play for all your Arizonian fans?
I don't really come back here.
- You avoid your home?
- I don't know.
It's like the hot air and...
..the history, I don't know.
Bought the ranch, though, I grew up on.
Gave it to my brother.
We buried Dad there, and so I wanted
to make sure that nobody...
paved over his grave or...
- any of that kind of shit.
- Is it around here?
It's not far.
Why don't we just go there?
It's nearby.
Mm. Mm.
Mm.
Jack?
Yeah, if he shows up!
These guys have been vamping out there
for a fucking half an hour.
It's time to fucking get on.
Don't you get tired of being...
You sold Dad's ranch!
They turned it into a fucking wind farm!
I bought that for you.
Where's his grave?
He washed away in a fucking storm.
His grave isn't there any more.
I told you, but you were fucking drunk.
You were fucking loaded...
and already pissing yourself
a swan song.
Fuck if you shed a tear
for that piece of shit
you idolise for
no goddamn fucking reason.
All Dad ever did for you...
..was make you
his fucking drinking buddy.
And you'd be right there with him if he
was still alive and you fucking know it.
What did you think...
that I was gonna
fucking take care of it...
..while I'm fucking cradling your ass
all over the goddamn world?
Yeah.
That's a good excuse.
Raising a little brother
so you don't have to deal with the fact
that you were no fucking good.
If I was no good,
why'd you steal my fucking voice?
- Huh?
- Cos you had nothing to fucking say.
You were too proud to sing
any of the songs I ever wrote.
Well, I got something to say now, pal.
I'm done being your fucking errand boy.
I quit.
Yeah, my voice just got up on me
a few months ago and...
..another shot of steroids
is better safe than sorry.
Thank you for that. We should be good.
Hey.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Well, let's play.
All right, I got an idea for the end.
- Sorry...
- That's OK.
- It's gonna be a little different...
- Cheers. Where's that joint?
We're gonna be a little different
for the end, OK?
- Do the encore and the thing that I said.
- OK.
All right?
Come on, let's go back out and do it.
- What are you doing?
- Go, go, go.
All right, listen to me.
Here's what we're gonna do.
You're gonna do the song
that I said I wanted you to do.
- The one that I love.
- No. I'm not.
- Please!
- Do the one that I love. It'll be great.
- Jack, please...
- I said I always...
- You promised to do it. I love you.
- I always say...
Always remember us this way.
Everybody, we're gonna
bring out Ally to bring us home...
and she's gonna sing an original song.
Thank you.
Ally! Ally! Ally! Ally!
That was fucking beautiful.
No, you were fucking doing it.
I was there, I fucking...
- Our car's over there.
- Ally, that was unbelievable.
- Thank you.
- That was unbelievable what you did.
Thank you.
I don't know if you know about me,
about where I've come from.
I'm Rez Gavron.
I know who you are.
What you have right now
goes way beyond just this.
There's people who need to hear
what you have to say musically.
This is not normal stuff.
It's really amazing what you're doing.
I think you have it all. I do.
And the question to you is,
"What do you want?"
I'm in that position,
to put you wherever you want to be.
I... I don't... I don't have...
I gotta talk to Jack.
He said that he thought Interscope
Records might really wanna sign me.
And he said that he has
this wonderful studio
with a beautiful live room
and these amazing producers
he wants to bring in
to record my songs.
And he loves Look What I've Found.
Remember the song we did in the diner?
- Remember, when we were driving?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
I mean, it was so nice talking to him,
and he really believes in me.
- You all right, Jack?
- He's OK. He's fine.
He does this all the time.
Hey, Jack.
Thanks.
What's going on? Hm?
What are you doing?
Oh.
You jealous fuck.
I'm so happy for you.
Oh, you are?
Oh... Jackson!
Oh, my God!
Jack. Stop!
Why are you so jealous, boy?
Hm?
What are you doing?
What's wrong? You upset?
You want me to make you less...
I know, do you wanna play?
OK, let's play.
What the hell is this?
- I'm so sorry.
- No, you're fine.
- You sound great, OK?
- You're doing great.
We'll do it again.
I'm gonna cue you in.
One second. Listen to my cue.
We'll come right in, OK?
So, should... Well...
I'm sorry,
but will I sing in the beginning?
You're gonna hear the second line,
and then I wanna start recording.
I think I got an idea
that might help out, all right?
- Please. Be my guest.
- That was really good up to that point.
- I'm gonna go in there for a second.
- All right, Jack.
- I've never sang with a track before.
- I think you need your piano.
- If you're playing it and singing it...
- Yeah, I always play it on the piano.
I'm gonna have them fly one in,
and we'll try it there
- and see where it goes.
- You think that's OK?
- OK. Thank you.
- I got you. You're doing great.
- You OK?
- No, I'm so nervous.
- You look so beautiful.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Oh, so you guys have already met
the new girl, have you?
- Rez! What's the plan?
- What's up?
Thanks for doing this, man.
I appreciate it.
This is pop music, kids.
We have a battle to do, OK?
You are the troops,
so if I call you "troops",
just know that we're going into battle.
What is my lyrics, Ally?
This is just fine-tuning
and creating an image.
I know. I just don't wanna lose
the part of me that's...talented.
I'm not gonna let you lose that piece.
OK.
What are we gonna do with you?
What are we gonna do with...
Oh, he's beautiful!
- "You can't send me back. I'm too cute."
- Hey, he's got your eyelashes.
He does. He's got your eyelashes.
Hey, bud!
This has never been done before,
just so you know.
It actually has been done before.
Would you please...
Please. Do it for me.
No, I can't in the water.
Mm.
You comin' with me to Memphis?
- What are you talkin' about?
- I gotta go do this...
You know, it's one of those paid things.
Soul-crushing work, really,
but it's kind of never
what I thought I'd wind up doing, maybe.
I don't know, but...
I've made peace with it, though.
Anyway, if you wanna come, I thought...
we could have a laugh, at the very least.
Rez wants to keep me here because,
you know, they rushed out the single
and they were so excited
that they want me to finish the album.
- So I'm working on that.
- Listen to what you're saying.
Listen to what you just said.
People wanna hear what you have to say.
That's the stuff.
- I... I can't...
- Hey, hey.
Take it in.
Thank you, by the way.
- Thank you for what?
- Giving me a home.
This place never felt like one before.
Oh, fuck.
Jack, you OK?
Jack?
Is there a reason
why you're not up there?
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my... Oh, my... Hey!
- Pretty incredible.
- Did Jack show up?
- I haven't heard from him.
- What do you mean?
- I can't find him.
I called him three times.
What happened
with the dancers there?
I just thought that I should do it alone
cos it's so overwhelming.
OK, but you can't go rogue on me.
You have to understand
that this is what I do
and you have to trust me, OK?
So, if I give you a couple of dancers,
don't not use them
and then miss a couple of steps, OK?
We also have to change your hair.
We have to change the colour of your hair.
What's wrong with my hair?
- I'm thinking platinum, or...
- I don't wanna be fucking blonde.
I am who I am,
and I'm worried about Jack.
I will find Jack, OK?
I will find him.
Jack.
I feel like we've done this before.
Didn't think we'd do it so soon, man.
Come on, bro. Get up.
All right. There we go.
In my mind, I made it to the door.
I almost didn't wake you.
You looked so comfortable.
- How you doin'?
- I've seen better days, I guess.
I apologise for...
- disrespecting your property...
- Not necessary.
- ..or whatever I did.
- You want some coffee?
Put some on,
and we'll come in in a minute.
OK.
That's him, right? That's your boy.
Jack, he's as old now...
..as you were when I met you.
Saw you on YouTube.
- That video with the girl.
- Yeah.
It made me happy, man.
You looked like you.
You were just...
just doing it, bro.
She writes too.
- She wrote that tune?
- Yeah.
Bunch of others too.
Got hooked up with some manager guy,
wants to...
You know.
- She's good, bro.
- I know.
Maybe she's a way out.
Ain't nothing to be afraid of, bro.
You know, it's like...
I don't know... You... You float out...
..float out at sea,
and then...one day, you find a port,
say, "I'm gonna stay here
for a few days."
A few days becomes a few years.
And then you forgot where you were goin'
in the first place.
And then you realise you don't really
give a shit about where you was going,
cos you like where you're at.
That's how it is for me.
I like where I'm at.
I didn't even realise
I liked it so much...
..till I saw your ass
sleeping in the grass this morning.
Yeah, come on, man.
You can rest in my daughter's room, bro.
I thought of, like, a million things
to say to you on the plane...
and I can't remember.
Jack...
Glad you're here.
You make it to Memphis after all.did
Fuck.
I won't do this again.
I won't come and find you.
Next time, you can clean up
your own mess.
You understand me?
How was the show?
It was fucking awesome.
I cut the dancers.
- Dancers?
- Yeah.
Ah.
Good.
Fucking dancers.
All you do is need to sing.
- You made me so upset.
- I'm sorry.
I saw that video on YouTube.
- Oh.
- It was great.
Thank you so much.
Excuse me one second.
- What's going on?
- Do you have, like, a plier?
Jack's OK?
I wanna cut the guitar strings,
not too crazy.
There used to be pliers
or something like that.
Ah... Yeah, yeah.
I don't know where my mom is.
- Yeah. I understand that.
- I think you're pretty.
Me?
You think I'm pretty?
Thank you. I think you're pretty.
It was real great,
and then Jack tells me you wrote the song.
Yeah, he got me to start singing
my own songs again.
- He has a way of doing that.
- Yeah, he does.
Does anyone want some
more mac and cheese?
Yeah? Here, sweetheart,
you want some?
Ah. There he goes.
What's up, man?
I understand what you said.
What the hell are you...
Are you kidding?
- That stupid?
- No.
- It's not stupid.
- It wasn't a stupid thing I just did?
Is that what you were doing
when you left the table?
He told me
he was looking for some pliers.
I didn't know what he was gonna do.
I didn't think he was gonna "do it" do it.
Oh, she has another ring!
Well, that's just temporary.
No, no, no, no, no.
Jack, wait a minute.
Let's anoint this.
Let's do it today.
- Yo, for real.
- It's a good idea!
No, you get the dress.
I'll call my cousin right now.
It's Saturday.
Nobody's gonna be in there.
- Let's go.
- You really wanna do that?
That place has a magical quality to it.
It what? It has a magical quality?
- It does.
- What do you mean?
- That church is special.
- We can go.
- I'll take you to get a dress.
- There you go, right there.
It'd be great! OK, you're coming with us
for sure because you're...
I can't believe this.
What am I doing? OK, sure.
- My brother. Good to see you.
- Hey, hey!
- Jack!
- Good to see you, my man.
- Thank you so much.
- Welcome to the Lord's house.
With the power...
I think that's how it goes.
Do you take him...
Do you take him?
I do.
Congrats, man.
- I listened to what you said.
- I'm glad you did.
I can't believe he did it.
- One thing at a time, OK?
- What?
Oh! I didn't understand.
- Lot of people downstairs?
- Yeah.
- She better come out before they leave.
- Want me to check on her?
Well, I think we're gonna
have to go pretty soon, so...
All right.
Ally.
I'm coming in.
What are you doin' in the tub?
This is so weird.
I don't know who the hell
I think I am. I...
One song is fine, but...
..to put out a whole record,
I don't know what the fuck I was thinking.
I don't know about all of that,
but you definitely look like a star.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What do you think of her hair
and the look and the...?
- I discussed it with her.
- Yeah.
- It looks great.
- Was that your choice?
No, it was actually hers.
- No drink?
- What's that?
No drink?
No socks?
Touché. Touché, mate.
Yeah, I could never get used to that,
the idea of not wearing socks.
- Your feet get all...
- No, actually I am wearing socks.
They're these kind of
little female insert socks
- that work with these shoes.
- Oh, you are. You're hiding them.
Yeah, I'm just hiding them.
That's right.
OK, now is this thing...
Yeah, there it is.
Oh, that's a good light.
Here, hold this for me, baby.
Hey, Ally, girl!
Wait, hold on. Come on.
Sookie, Donte. Come here.
I put my Jackson titties on!
Hi!
Baby, listen, we just wanted
to say congratulations.
- Congratulations!
- We love you!
- I love you too.
- Girl, please come back soon.
We done put Etta in your station, girl.
- The queen is here!
- Stop!
- Wow!
- What do you think?
Well, it's beautiful.
You. SNL. Alec Baldwin hosting.
- Did you get it?
- Season finale.
- No fucking way.
- No, got it.you
- No way! Oh, my God!
Oh, gosh!
- That's incredible! Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Bitch!
- Oh, my gosh!
- Get downstairs.
- Everyone's waiting.
- OK.
Can I just talk to her
for one second outside?
Just one sec, sorry.
Just be a second, yeah.
It doesn't do you any justice,
I'll tell you that.
You always said you liked my nose.
- I love your nose.
- It's real big up there.
I wish it was bigger up there.
The whole thing should just be
your fucking nose.
Fuck all those people
who ever said anything.
Just put a billboard
of your fucking nose up there.
Just the nose?
That's so ridiculous.
Listen, if I just don't say this,
I'll never forgive myself.
What?
If you don't dig deep
in your fucking soul...
..you won't have legs.
I'm just telling you that.
You don't tell the truth out there,
you're fucked.
All you got is you,
and what you wanna say to people.
They are listening now. They're not
gonna be listening forever. Trust me.
So you gotta grab it.
And you don't apologise, you don't worry
about why they're listening
or how long they're gonna be listening,
you just tell 'em what you wanna say.
Cos how you say it
is the stuff of angels.
Pop! Six to the right, and hah!
Ball, change. Down.
Hah! Ball, change.
- Attitude.
- Whoo!
- The last part.
- I know.
All right!
30 seconds.
Red mark.
Alec in 20.
15.
Stand by, guys.
Here we go. Ready? Song one.
Stand by, Alec.
- In ten, nine...
- Alec in ten.
- eight, seven, six...
- Ready 4. Dissolve 4.
Alec in five seconds.
- Four, three, two, one...
- And go 4. Dissolve 4.
- And cue Alec!
- Ladies and gentlemen, Ally.
Dissolve 1.
The caterpillar becomes the butterfly.
What the hell are you doing here?
I'm in town for a gig.
Been working for Willie.
- I've been working for Willie.
- No shit.
Yeah. Thought I'd stop by
and check her out.
Is it gettin' worse?
Nah, I've just been with my wife,
and it's goin' real good.
Funny to run into you, cos...
..I was thinking about asking you
to come back out with us.
I gotta say, it's easier without you.
Listen.
You run into any trouble...
..call me.
Thank you!
That light's beautiful.
Oh, God, here we...
Yeah, that's it, Ally.
Yeah, that's it.
That's it, Ally. That's it, I love that.
Oh, my gosh. It's so early.
I've been here all night.
- Early for me, late for you.
- Hi, it's nice to see you.
- How you doin'?
- I'm kind of...
- He's amazing.
- What do you think?
These fucking photos.
- They're so beautiful.
- Look at that! Look at that!
- That's incredible.
- It doesn't even look like me.
You've just been nominated
for three Grammys.
Including Best New Artist.
They just announced it now.
Everybody!
Grammy-nominated artist.
Have you been drinking?
Are you fucked up right now?
I'm out a couple.
It's the morning.
Yup.
Hey, buddy.
You're nominated for three Grammys,
and it's fucking great.
Thank you.
How did you find that out?
Bobby told me.
He called. He said that...
..they wanna do some Roy Orbison tribute.
They want me to sing and shit.
- Great.
- Some, like, supergroup thing.
But the point is, you got nominated,
and it's great.
I'm just trying to figure it out,
that's all.
"Why do you come around me
with an ass like that?"
- My lyrics?
- "Why do you walk around in jeans?"
"Why do you come around
with an ass like that?"
Yeah, that's my song.
What about my song?
I fucking listened to it
over and over in the fucking...
You're not making any sense.
Yeah, just keep drinking.
- That'll give you the answer.
- Maybe I fucking failed you.
- That kills me. I'm sorry.
- You what? You failed me?
Yeah, you're embarrassing,
and it's just...
- I'm embarrassing?
- I feel bad for you.
- Yeah...
- I'm not embarrassing!
- I have to tell you.
- You're embarrassing!
You're so embarrassed of your fucking
self that you gotta put me down.
You're worried that you're ugly,
and you're not.
So you need to get approval
by all these people.
- Why can't I just be enough for you?
- I don't need approval.
I'd like for my boyfriend to love me.
For my to love me.husband
Who's your fucking boyfriend?
You have a boyfriend?
- Yeah, I've got a boyfriend.
- That hurts.
- I have a boyfriend.
- Call me your fucking boyfriend.
You're my boyfriend. You're my boyfriend
if you don't treat me like your wife.
I don't even know
what that fucking means.
It means clean your shit up.
You're fucking messy.
- That's what it means.
- Well, that's not true.
- Oh, it isn't?
- Uh-uh.
Let's go. You wanna be my drinking buddy?
Wanna practise?
- I don't think you could handle it.
- You don't? Let me see.
Know why? Cos you're too worried about
what everybody else is thinking.
Here we go, Jack.
You want me to be your dad?
- Be your drinking buddy?
- Yeah.
Yeah, you couldn't be my dad
if you fucking tried.
He had more talent in his finger
than you have in your whole body.
So don't even fucking go there
about that, all right?
- That's over the fucking line.
- Why don't you have another drink
and we can just get fucking drunk
until we fucking disappear, OK?
- Do you got those pills?
- You're just fucking ugly, that's all.
- I'm what?
- You're just fucking ugly.
Get the fuck out!
Get out!
I said, get out!
Fine.
Good evening.
Seven and eight and huh.
Two, three, four, five, six, seven, up!
Pull it!
Six. Come on, feel it. Ooh-huh.
Down, up! Hah! Swing it!
- That was great.
- What are you doin' here?
Something fell through, so I was able
to come back a few days early.
I think I might have said some things...
Just...how I acted.
You hurt me.
You really hurt me.
Sorry.
You haven't been drinking.
What'd you say?
I said you haven't been drinking.
I can tell.
No, I haven't. No.
- I have to get back to rehearsal...
- Oh, yeah. Can I watch?
Yeah, OK.
Meet me at home.
Or I can wait and drive you home.
- Just meet me at home.
- OK.
What do you mean,
they don't want me to sing?
They hired this fucking kid
at the last minute.
They didn't tell me a fucking thing.
Look, we've been
on that other side before.
More than once.
Yeah.
Truth is, I didn't deliver.
Well, it's a good thing I know the...
..how to play the guitar.
It's fine, I'll do it.
- You're gonna do it?
- Sure.
Hey, where's the wedges?
Can't fucking hear with the...
But, yeah, like I said,
it's a real, real honour.
Yeah. Oh, honour's mine.
Yeah, you're great. It'll be fun.
- Yeah, hope so.
- Yeah.
Who coulda been a crooner?
Right? You remember what Paul said.
Paul Anka
told me I had more natural talent...
- ..than Sinatra.
- ..than Frank.
- That's it! Do not...
- Direct quote!
Know what Paul Anka actually said?
- No, what did he say?
- He said...
"Would you please pull the car over
and let me out over here on the kerb?"
All right, but... Oh, my God!
Sweetheart.
This is unreal.
The Grammys.
- Hey, look at everybody. How are you?
- Hey, there he is!
- Oh, thanks.
- How are you?
Are you OK?
- What's that?
- Are you OK?
- Oh.
- I'm great.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm great.
They have me going in early,
so I gotta go now and then...
But I made sure that they tell me where
you're sitting so I can go right after.
- OK.
- I don't wanna miss the award.
- It's right before it.
You just got that look on your face.
I do? Watch. It's gone.
Amazing. Gonna get to see
you perform tonight,
get to see you sing.
Hey, Jack, that's an incredible...
collection of vinyl you have in there.
Take whatever you want.
It's yours.
- Take whatever I want?
- He just said, "Take whatever you want."
He's talking to the wrong guys.
I thought he was supposed to be singing.
Oh, it's over? It's over?
- You good?
- I'm fine.
And the nominees are...
- Right here?
- Roxy Carlile.
Hi. Are you OK?
Come on, baby.
Sit down, sit down, sit down.
- Hi. You OK?
- I was trying to go to the men's room
- and they rushed me over here.
- OK, put your legs inside.
- I had to go to the bathroom.
- Put your legs inside.
They're announcing your fucking category.
Keep quiet.
- And the winner is...
- Yeah... Oh...
This is exciting.
How great.
Ally!
Oh, my God!
- What happened?
- We won!
- Is that why everybody's...
- Yep, that's right!
Where are we going?
Just stay right here.
Go sit back there.
I'll stay here.
Oh, my gosh, thank you!
You look beautiful. Thank you!
Oh, wow!
Oh, my gosh!
I can't believe I'm holding one of these.
Thank you to Rez Gavron, my manager.
- Thank you for believing in me...
- Wait, did you win?
..and telling me to get back from
behind the piano and onto the stage.
Did you just win?
Thank you to my...my...
to Jack Maine, my husband.
- Should I come up there?
- I love you so much.
I always wanted to be a singer
on a big stage
and because of him, I am.
- We're having a lot of fun tonight.
- Yeah.
- I...
- Shit.
Look.
- If I haven't thanked you yet, just...
- Did you see you're up there?
Yeah, I do.
I started out singing
with this beautiful man
and I'll sing with him for life.
- Right, baby?
- Yeah.
I'm so blessed to be in the company
of such wonderful musicians.
This is a dream come true,
and all I can say is...
..believe in yourself and don't give up
because there is a spot
on that stage for you.
- Oh, shit. Oh, fuck.
- Good night.
Oh, I think I peed...
- I think I peed myself.
- Turn around.
Oh!
- I think I...
- Baby, baby, can you...
- That's a bad come down.
- Holy shit!
- Take him to the shower.
- Follow me, Wolf. Ally, go inside, OK?
- It's on the left, Dad.
- I got it.
- Go inside!
- They got him.
- They got him!
- It's my job!
- Don't do this to my daughter!
- Hey, hey!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Get off!
Damn it!
Watch his fucking head.
Watch! Watch!
Bobby'll take you there.
You have Bobby's number?
No, Jack, you gotta sit up.
I don't want you to choke, baby. Sit up!
Sorry, I...I might've taken too much.
- You all right in there?
- I'm fine.
He's fine.
So, everybody has their journal...
and we remember
the homework assignment -
the three things that I wanted you
to write down.
- Jack, hey.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry I'm late.
You can't be late, Jack.
Understood. Sorry.
Good. Where's your journal?
- It's in my room.
- No, no, no, no. No.
Sit down.
So, it's all agreed.
Nobody's ever late here, right?
OK. Good.
Anything you wanna tell us?
Um...
I'm grateful to...
..to be here and...
..trying to hold it together.
I'm Jack. I'm an alcoholic.
Jack.
Drug addict.
Oh...
- This is all my fault.
- You don't have that kind of power, Dad.
Eat your dinner. Eat your food.
Sorry.
I don't even know what meal it is.
Go on, have some fruit.
How many times did you carry
my piano up the stairs?
How many times did you sit there
while I wrote a song?
- Always.
- OK, it's OK. It's OK.
You didn't do anything.
It's not your fault.
You're just the greatest person
in the world.
How long have you been here now?
Two months.
Can it be fixed?
Well, you would know that, don't you?
Once it's gone, it's gone.
- I don't know what you have.
- Oh, the tinnitus, they say, once you...
- Well, tinnitus can't be fixed.
- Right.
Well, I just hear that tone, that's all.
The tone, yeah.
The ringing.
- I have hearing aids on, as you...
- I know. That's why I asked you.
You know, I'm convinced that...
..it happened when I was younger.
I used to...
My dad had, like, a Victrola,
you know, an old record player.
My head was just about the size of it
when I was a kid,
and I used to love to just
put my whole head in there.
He was big into the blues, so...
Cos you gotta figure,
it's just me and him all day long.
My brother's out there
tryin' to make something of himself.
So I took one of his belts.
I put it around the...
..ceiling fan and...
..tried to do the deed.
The whole fucking fan
came out of the ceiling.
Had a big cut on my fucking forehead.
I was more mad about that
than it not working.
And he didn't even notice.
He didn't even fucking notice.
- Cos he was drunk?
- Yeah.
That fucking fan stayed on the floor
for about half a year.
How old were you then?
I was just shy of 13.
Oh...
You smell good.
You smell good,
and you look good too.
- I've been swimming.
- You've been swimming?
- Yeah, there's a pool.
- I love that you're swimming.
- That's a great pool there.
- Yeah.
How's Charlie?
Oh, Charlie's sweet.
He just sort of sits
by the door like this.
Waiting for Daddy.
We're both waiting for Daddy.
What, three weeks?
You gonna come back, right?are
- What do you mean?
- You gonna come home when you're done?
- Do you not want me to?
- No, I want you to.
- I'm just wondering if... I just...
- Where else would I go?
- I don't know. I guess I just thought...
- Why...
- ..there's Jack...
- Wait, wait.
- Wait. Why would you say that?
- I don't know. I guess...
I wondered, without the booze,
if you would want to come home.
Cos when you met me,
you were drinking, and now you're not.
I wasn't drunk the whole time
we were together.
I know, but...
But it got bad when we were together.
It's OK. I mean, it's fine.
I just was wondering, that's all,
and whatever you want is OK.
Whatever I want?
I wanna be with you.
- That's why I'm here.
- OK. I know, I know.
I just want you to be happy.
I'm working on that.
I need to stick with you.
I brought something.
I wanna know...
..what this is.
"My Love."
You hiding love songs?
No, I wouldn't...
I wouldn't say I was hiding it.
I just um...
I started puttin' it down to paper
when we were at home.
I don't know, it sort of fell out of me,
I guess, and onto this page.
And I put it in here, and I thought...
I thought maybe you'd find it when...
..when you came back to you, maybe.
Well, I found it.
Listen. Um...
Um...
I'm sorry.
It's OK.
It's OK. It's not your fault.
I'm sorry I did that.
It's OK.
It's not your fault. It's a disease.
No, but I embarrassed you.
- I embarrassed you, and I...
- I'm not embarrassed of you.
It was so wrong.
And then your...then your dad...
My father loves you. It's OK.
I know, but I...
- It's OK.
- I know, but I...
It's OK.
I have figured out what I think is
the best solution for both of us.
Jack should come out on tour with me.
We'll start with our duets.
I know he's gonna be able
- to play by himself.
- You realise that's not an option.
He's... He's so inside of his art
in a way he has never been.
- He can hear himself again.
- Ally, there is no way
that you can take Jack on tour with you.
There's no way.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
If you can't make that happen,
then fucking cancel the tour.
I don't know what to tell you.
I think if we had a better band name,
we might've made it.
Or maybe it was cos we looked like
a father and son duo.
Not many of those around.
I was not a good look for you,
that's for sure.
Not my fault I couldn't find
a better guitar player
in the whole goddamn state.
Where in the fuck is it?
Right here.
Thanks for the ride.
Sure thing, Jack.
Hey, you know...when I...
..when I said I...
you know, when I...
..took your voice, you know.
It was you I idolised. It wasn't Dad.
Come here.
What was that, guy?
Hey.
I wanna know how you hear this.
That sounded unbelievable,
what you were playing.
- Thank you.
- It's nice to hear it.
Thank you, and I had
the beautiful backdrop of you and Charlie.
I only heard it in my mind
for so many weeks,
so it's good to hear it... You know.
- The words are beautiful.
- ..in the real thing. In the real thing.
- Well, you want me to do that?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, God, I don't know.
I knew you were gonna ask me.
Back from the dead.
- Hey, sorry. Were you waiting long?
- No, no.
Uh... Ally's not home.
No, I told her I'd meet her here,
if that's OK.
Of course, yeah.
Here you go.
Hey, thanks for taking care of my girl
when I was gone.
Anything for her.
She told me about that European leg.
That's a hell of an accomplishment
this soon out of the gate.
Shit, I remember it was like...ten years
before I even went across the pond.
It was summer, 2004.
Shit, was it?
We're not exactly friends here.
While you've been away,
we've been back here in serious triage,
trying to clean up your fucking mess.
Barely finding our way through it.
You almost single-handedly derailed
her whole career. You understand that?
She's never gonna say this to you.
She loves you too much.
Just by staying married to you,
she looks like a joke.
It's embarrassing.
Let's be honest, we both know
it's only a matter of time
before that's pushed aside again
for the real thing.
And when that happens...
..I don't want her anywhere near you.
Hey.
I have some good news.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hm.
I'm not gonna go to Europe.
We're gonna cancel the rest of the tour,
and I'm just gonna be here all summer.
Isn't that great?
- What happened?
- Nothing happened.
The label just loves the record,
and it's doing so well
and they wanna keep with the momentum
and have me make another one.
Rez is super psyched, so it'll be great.
So tonight's gonna be my last show.
Going out with a bang at the Forum.
Great.
Yeah.
Why don't you come with me?
We can sing Shallow together.
The fans will go crazy to see you.
Come on, cowboy.
Yeah, why not? OK.
Yeah?
OK, good.
I'll have a car come get you.
When I... Once I get there.
I'll go meet you there.
I'll see you soon, OK?
Hey.
What?
I just wanted to take
another look at you.
Bye, honey.
Bye.
Come here, Charlie.
Come here.
Thank you so much
for bringing us all here together.
Please look over
all of the dancers tonight and the band.
And my husband, Jackson.
We're so excited for him
to be here with us.
We got a big night.
We're at the Forum, LA.
Let's do this.
- Is he here?
- He's not here.
- He's not here?
- We have to do Shallow regardless, OK?
The guitar's up there.
Everything's gonna remain the same.
- What?
- The guitar's up there.
Everything's gonna remain the same.
Both verses.
- I'm sure it was just a bit much for him.
- Please send somebody to the house.
- I'm doing it right now.
- I have 15 seconds.
Give it up for my husband, Jackson!
I can stay, if you want.
Aargh!
Some kid started singing one of his songs
in a bar I was in the other night.
They're playing his songs everywhere.
At first I got angry.
I don't know why.
I guess I felt like...
.."How can any of these people
feel like they knew him?"
Who he really was.
But then something changed.
And it soothed me.
That it wasn't...
wasn't all for fucking nothing.
The last thing I did was lie to him.
Listen to me.
It isn't your fault.
It just isn't.
You know whose fault it was?
Jack.
That's it.
No-one else.
Not you, not me.
No-one but Jack.
I just keep...
..going over and over it,
over it in my head.
Jack talked about how music is
essentially 12 notes between any octave.
12 notes and the octave repeats.
It's the same story.
Told over and over.
Forever.
All any artist can offer the world...
is how they see those 12 notes.
That's it.
Hm.
He loved how you see them.
He just kept saying...
.."I love how she sees them, Bobby."
Hello, I'm Ally Maine.
Thank you for being here tonight
to honour my husband.
He wrote a song for me.
I'd like to sing it for him tonight.
And, with your help, maybe I can.
Thank you.
Really.
Black Eyes