Gentlemen, go back.
We'll do the Economics test.
- El Djebena.
- Good morning.
- And the batteries?
- Large ones.
- Mali.
- Sophie.
Am I crazy or do they multiply?
Soon the carpets will come out.
We used to control the court.
Good thing they're dumb.
If they'd stop thinking with
their balls, they'd evolve more.
You should get closer
to see what's going on.
I don't understand.
What don't you understand?
- Want me to get a beating?
- Why would they beat you?
- Are you crazy? To them I'm a Corsican.
- What? Their eyes are blinded by shit.
Sends some guards to mingle with them.
They will eat from your hand.
Good thinking.
Just another Arab
thinking with his balls.
YOU ONLY LIVE TWICE
Let me introduce you to some friends.
The man in Marbella.
- This is Khalid!
-Your brother.
This is Mishka!
This is Damien. And here is Olivier.
Say hello to Mali.
- What's your name?
- My name's Fernanda. And I love cocks.
Marbella!
There, in Block C. What are the
Muslims doing? Smuggling? Drugs?
- They do their own things.
- Really? You get nothing?
Don't you think it would be nice
to send a pair of strong guys?
- Press them a little bit.
- Why press them?
Why? To show them who's boss,
which hand they have to kiss.
Isn't it obvious?
Before you were 20. Now you're 5.
Can't you see the difference?
- What kind of difference?
- I can't do for 5 what I did for 20.
- No, it's all right.
- What's all right?
- I'll manage. I'll see what...
-You'll manage?
Use your head! Tomorrow you tell
me what you can do for me.
We have a problem, brother.
- Make a petition. What can I say?
- Maybe Luciani can do something.
I don't understand. I was his lapdog
and now you ask me to lick your ass?
Not for myself, for our brothers.
To stop being his slave and be yours?
If you want a favor, learn to ask.
- What do you want?
- What could I want here?
- Respect.
- Do I look Corsican?
-You think they trust you?
- I'll see what I can do.
Luciani.
- Now the meetings are here?
- It's cozy, warm, with a sea view.
- Sit down.
- I'm fine here.
- So, what do you want?
- I have a problem in Marseille.
A cousin of yours, Brahim Lattrache.
I want you to pass a message.
Tell him Luciani wants to talk
to him face to face, okay?
- I'll see. What about the guards?
- I'll take care of that.
Brahim Lattrache in Marseille.
See the guy in red? He'll go to the end,
turn around and start again.
The 2 that are running...
See the little guy with the hat?
He'll do some push-ups.
Check the game.
Look at the hoop.
- Missed. Fuck him!
- No, the other.
For me you see nothing?
Yes, snow.
Ok. I'll move aside.
Fuck you...
Quick, quick!
Ok
Latif, the Egyptian. They let a car
pass and then ambushed Riyad.
He was caught with hash.
Now they want money.
Who are those guys?
What do you know?
Nothing. I know their boss is called
Latif, the Egyptian. From the south.
They use the same road.
They know the secrets.
What do we do?
Give them what they ask.
Boss!
- Any news of his friend? - None.
What should I do? It's been 3 days...
Calm down! There are many people
here and we have hash.
If anyone knows the Egyptian
we'll know, don't worry.
And he's going to hurt when I find him!
- How are you doing with the beards?
- Getting along.
Talk to them... and investigate.
- I need a favor.
- What is it?
- I need information about someone.
- Who? - A black, Latif, the Egyptian.
Latif? What can I do?
- Tell me who he knows here.
- His brother-in-law.
- What's the deal?
- Nothing. It's my business.
See him?
The one over there.
With the blue cap.
Are the other 2 with him?
- Seems that way.
- Will the Muslims help?
- They give us 2 guys. - No problem.
If we plan well, everything'll be fine.
Shut up!
Boss! His ankle.
He needs a doctor.
Lights!
Mohammed Gaziler?
You know the Egyptian?
-You know him?
-Yes
Sit down.
Ouassila is your mother?
Is her address on the visitors' list?
Look.
If you want to see her alive, tell Latif
I want my friend and my stuff, okay?
- Okay?
- Agreed.
Call.
- Where were you?
- At the registrar's office.
Everything Ok?
- Have you eaten?
- I have to see a guy.
It can wait.
Come for coffee.
Help yourself.
I want to talk to you. I've seen you in
the yard with this tall guy, the Gypsy.
What's the business?
Hash, pills?
- Hashish.
- A lot?
- Want apart?
- No. It's your business, your business.
- How does it come in?
- The visiting rooms, the kitchens.
- So you bought off some guards.
- No. A dealer. Frozen food.
- So that's how it works?
- For the moment, yes.
What if you get caught?
The hole.
And no furloughs.
What did I say last time? To be careful.
Not to risk your outings.
What do you do? Fight with some guys.
Lay down your law. What's your game?
You're valuable with furloughs, Djebena.
If not, what good are you?
Get out.
Get out!
Bastard!
I'll kill you...
You don't fear me any more?
If you get around,
it's because I made you a porter.
If you eat it's thanks to me. If you
dream, think, live... it's thanks to me.
You say you have no guards.
Bullshit!
You have Luciani etched on your face!
You live for me, Djebena!
They look at you and they see me.
Who else would they see? Can you tell me?
Are you here?
Come here.
Enough already.
Come here I said.
I have something fun
to tell you.
You're going to Marseille.
Your next leave will be to Marseille.
From Brecourt to Marseille in a day?
There is a flight at 9 am
and a return flight at 3.
There you will see Brahim Lattrache.
Should I take anything?
No. You talk and listen.
Find out the cost of cutting
ties to the Italians.
Tell him I'm interested in negotiating
without Jacky Marciaggi and the others.
Sampiero will contact your friend
for payment and expenses.
Have you ever flown?
Good morning, Truette.
- Morning, El Djebena.
- Good morning, sir.
Open up, please.
- Look at the time, I arrived on time!
- Careful! Don't talk to me like that.
- How should I talk? I'm at risk here.
- Okay, okay. I understand.
This car is a piece of shit!
A lure for the police.
-You're becoming an idiot.
- Enough is enough. - Why enough?
Who made you the boss?
If you want to split, say so.
Keep that for Latif's trunk.
Get Latif out of your head.
I'll find him and I'll finish him.
You won't finish anyone. Wake up.
Business has stopped.
It's nothing personal.
That bastard has blocked everything.
We got back the hash,
but we can't move it.
They even fucked us up in the city.
I swear I'll finish him off.
Fuck them!
You look like a lawyer.
Boarding at 9:55,
gate 33, Terminal 2.
Bonvoyage.
Come forward.
Raise your arms.
- Hands!
- Why?
Hands!
Move.
Is this necessary?
I'm not worried.
What does Lucianiwant?
He wants to know your price to quit the
deal with the Italians in the casino.
If you agree, he'll guarantee your
position with the slot machines.
How will he guarantee our work?
With his ration card?
No, with the Council.
Sampiero will guarantee your place
with Marcaggi and the Corsican Council.
- How long have you known Luciani?
- From prison.
Have you worked for him
all this time?
How was it? Did you arrive
and begin to work?
- Does he protect you?
- No. I work. He doesn't protect me.
-You're his Arab. He protects you.
- No. I work for them.
At what price?
Are you the mole?
Do you send messages?
- Do you suck him off?
- What the hell is this?
Why does an Arab work for the Corsicans?
Do you belly dance for them?
Are you his girl? I had a friend there.
He never came out.
His name was Reyeb.
Sound familiar?
Was it Luciani who killed him?
What do you know?
Animals coming!
Watch out!
There! 2 more!
Kill it!
What are you about?
How did you know this?
What are you? What are you?
A prophet or what?
I killed Reyeb.
Fuck. You've come a long way.
- What's your name?
- Mali. - Mali.
- I'll wash your shirt and pants.
- The pants aren't dirty. -You sure?
Then give me the shirt.
Here's your shirt, son. I washed it,
but the blood stains won't come off.
Hey, prophet! Tell me. The Muslims want
to talk about Luciani. Is that it?
You speak with the Muslims,
the Corsicans, you come here...
You deal with everyone. That's
not good for your balls, you know?
Do you also talk to Lingherri?
Looks like someone is spying among the
Corsicans. Does your boss know?
-Are you sure?
- Sure.
- Do you know him well?
- I think so...
Well, tell this to Luciani.
I accept his offer with one condition.
Find the spy and clean the house.
His name is Latif, the Egyptian.
You know him?
What can I do for you?
Can you tell him we know each other?
That we work together?
We work together...
You think I can say that?
Let's eat before you go.
- Can I go to the beach?
- Whatever.
Hurry!
Has everything gone well?
-You'll see Latif and talk to him.
- Really? With that asshole?
- Lattrache will talk to him.
- What does he have to do with it?
His problem is the Corsicans and ours,
Latif. We'll help each other.
I proposed a deal. Let's be partners. We
share everything. Caches, cars, vendors.
-We occupy the market and control it.
- Know what you're asking, brother?
We'll settle all accounts when the time
comes. For now we leave it as it is.
I'm sick again.
The test results are not
good. I need more chemo.
Will you be okay?
Take care, brother.
You're 30 minutes late.
You know the rules.
- All day working with car doors...
- Spread your legs.
I'll let it go this time, but think
about your probation, moron.
Use your watch.
I don't care about Marcaggi's gratitude.
What I want is for him to move
his ass and fix this.
As we speak one of us is sleeping
with the Italians. I want to know who.
- Does he know? -Yes
- So?
He's negotiating with him...
- He thinks of himself.
- Same as Lattrache.
- Do you know who he is?
- No.
Wait, Cesar. Jacky wants
you out of this.
Neither on one side nor the other.
Out!
- He says if you need anything...
- Okay, okay. Understood.
I have good news.
About creating a hotel company. I've
found someone. A Basque from Pamplona.
- Why do you say "good news"?
-You asked me to look for someone.
Wait. We are talking about
Jacky, Sardinia, casinos,
You tell me not to interfere and
suddenly you speak of good news.
- The ones before were not good?
- Yes.
- Why then "good news now"?
- I didn't say "now".
- I can tell you 2 good things.
-Yeah? Why did it take you so long?
Thanks, boss.
Pass the papers.
-You got the results?
- Which match?
Why do you make coffee?
Because you're still a servant?
You go out for me, you see Sampiero,
you see Lattrache.
You take care of my business...
The casinos, the Lingherris.
And when I ask for coffee, you make it.
- Don't you have anything to say?
- Which is the question?
Why do I do it, or how I feel?
I do it because you ask me to.
- Want to know how I feel?
- No, no. I'm not interested.
- Do you still need me?
- It's you who needs me.
Can I go?
You hear me?
When will I see Latif?
Listen. Give my whole part
to Imam Moussab. All of it.
No idea.
Try the mosque.
I want him to know the money
is from Mali El Djebena.
He'll know how to find me.
Do as I say. Leave me
a message afterwards.
Move that ass, nigger.
- How you doing?
- Okay.
Is the money at the mosque yours?
Is it dirty money?
Of course it's dirty!
But it's better in his hands
than in mine.
Do you think the Imam will accept it?
It depends on you, friends.
I understand what you do here and I
respect that, but you have no power.
The Corsicans control the guards.
You pray in pigsties, you sleep in
shitty places. You rise...
and they crush you again. Perhaps the
Imam knows how to use that money.
What do you want?
Just like you, Hassan.
A better life for me and my brothers.
You think I'm stupid or what?
You just want to use us. That's all.
So? As long as it's good for everyone.
Listen. If you ever talk to
the Imam again, you're dead.
You talk money to me.
It's between us, okay?
Is that why you gave him the money?
To talk to me?
- From a killer to a killer?
- Leave that shit.
Just kidding.
Christmas
Handmade. No gifts, no Christmas.
- I am the gift. 100% hand made.
- What a gift!
Want some?
Help yourself.
Is it made from wild boar?
Are you kidding?
Shall we stop?
Can we talk honestly?
Why?
I have to ask you a favor,
but not because you work for me,
but because I trust you.
Do you see the difference?
I'm not sure.
I saw Vettori. He has some information.
He knows that I'm dealing
with the Lingherris.
Form a team.
How are your guys?
- A team for what?
- To eliminate them.
- Eliminate the Lingherris?
- The Lingherris and Jacky Marcaggi.
Kill Marcaggi? Is that it?
Kill your boss?
Nobody must know. You, me,
Vettori and nobody else.
It will be in Paris.
Vettori will provide the stuff.
He'll help, but we must remain invisible.
Can you do that for me?
Any plans for when you get out?
When we have the casinos,
we'll need someone to manage them.
With Lattrache.
We'll do it. We'll do it.
I only have 6 months.
- 6 more months and that's it.
- Maybe they're wrong.
Give me time.
What's the problem?
- Kill those guys?
- Speak softly.
We don't know them.
What do we care?
Think about when you get out.
I won't be here.
You can think of your future, I can't.
Mali... there's Djamila.
There's my son.
- What'll I leave them? A fridge? ATV?
- What are you saying?
You'll take care of them.
That's what I ask you, brother.
You'll say we agree.
And we'll do it.
I talked to my outside friend.
We'll do it.
He's put together a first class team.
I'll talk to my people. Give me the
number. Vettori will call your friend.
Have you tried this?
I'll give you some.
Are you listening? It's bad.
Our guys are good for drugs.
Not for other stuff.
-You were the one who wanted to do it.
What now? - I can't force them.
When the Corsicans took out the
guns they ran away. Like devils.
That bastard Vettori
treats us like shit.
There was a fight on the way.
Now Khalid wants to kill him.
- Find some other guys.
- Now?
- For a contract?
- Who cares?
You got a minute.
I lost my time and money
with this group of idiots and...
just look at him!
- Be careful what you say.
- I will deliver you from your misery!
- Hands off!
- Calm down!
Hush! We will do it our way.
- What?
- I'll try to explain. May I?
- Listen. We'll kill them.
- Promise.
We'll kill them,
but they can't know how.
- I'm going to hit you. Lower you head.
- What?
I'll hit you and you lower your head.
I get it. Can I go on?
Pick me up without the others.
You and I will deal with this.
Will you be able to do it?
Guard!
Are you ready to complete your
insertion and rehabilitation project?
- It's a support center for detainees.
- I know Imam Moussab's Center.
You requested 2 days.
It seems excessive.
I propose a practice module of one day.
From 7am to 7 pm.
- Is that all right?
- Yes, very good.
Muhammed, peace be upon him, reached
the top of the mountain and fell asleep.
The angel Gabriel appeared.
Do you know what he said?
He said, "Pray, pray, Muhammed.
Pray to God because He created you."
"He created mankind from scratch.
Pray what He taught in his writings."
Wonderful!
Wonderful, brother!
Prayer.
The door.
Have a good day, Djebena.
- What about the others?
- In the back.
The car comes out here.
A bodyguard and a driver. The guard
gets out first to open the door.
He wears a bulletproof vest.
We let them get out.
We hit the bodyguard first,
then the others.
Come on.
They're coming out.
Coming.
Black car.
Wait for them to come out.
I'll go for the bodyguard.
What's going on?
Come on, come on!
See them?
Yes, now I see them.
- 3 cars in front.
- Follow them!
It's turning. What do we do?
They stopped!
- Go on. I'll kill them.
- How? It's an armored car.
I tell you it's armored. If they don't
come out, there's nothing we can do.
What's he doing?
Buying tobacco.
- I'll go.
- It won't work.
Macarggi here!
Down!
I can't hear!
I hear nothing!
This blood is not mine.
It's theirs.
We've fucked you up, pigs!
Are you Jacky Marcaggi?
Don't talk. I can't hear. Just signs.
Do you know this guy?
Your friend Luciani sent us to kill you.
I won't do it. He's all yours.
- Get revenge!
- I'll take care of him.
- Are you sleeping?
- No, no. I'm exhausted.
- Have you talked to Djamila?
- I'll sleep in the kids' room.
-You won't go back tonight?
- No, I'll go back tomorrow.
- They'll put you in a punishment cell.
- As the Corsicans kill each other.
Need anything?
I'm not doing chemo.
You're screwed.
Watch your sleeve.
You're rubbing it on the plate.
- Eat a little, Riyad.
- I'm eating.
-Want some more?
- No thanks.
- Any good?
-Yes, delicious.
El Djebena, Mali.
35114T.
40 days - 40 nights
Are you there?
Make sure you have everything
and sign here.
Garbage.
Your exit papers.
The door.
- Good luck, Djebena.
- Good day, sir.
Subtitles: Arigon
How are you?
- It's cold.
-Very.
It's not a good time to come out.
- Have you come by bus?
-Yes
- When's the next one?
- Half an hour.
-Want to walk a little?
- If you like.
Do you know where you're going to live?
Come home. I'll sleep with the
child and you use his room.
- I don't want to disturb.
-You won't.
Okay.