JUNE 4, 2015
A YEAR BEFORE THE ATTACK.
CHANDEL DISTRICT, MANIPUR
INDIA.
DUPLEX MILITARY UNIT.
♪ The day you came in ♪
♪ Oh my queen ♪
♪ With a smile on the
embroidery and dress ♪
♪ This is certainly the truth ♪
♪ I'm changing my beauty around you ♪
Retreat.
TENTH OF JUNE 2015.
INDONESIA-MYANMAR BORDER.
Sartaj.
Sir?
Kilang.
Kilang is a protector.
Because there are professional shooters
The situation is even harder.
We must be twice as careful.
Sir!
Should we wait for backup team?
Negative.
It will take morning
for them to reach here.
We will lose the element of surprise.
And maybe
we wont get this chance again.
When all the terrorists
from Nagaland and Manipur
are together at one place.
Karan
Make an outer parameter with 10 commandos
mainly snipers.
From the left and right
and I am in charge.
And the other commandos
are moving straight.
If someone left our siege area
You are in the veil.
Not even one terrorist should
escape.
Copy-Copy.
Good. Best of luck!
Best of luck!
Sartaj.
Anyone spot kilang?
Negative Sir!
- Commandos?!
- Yes Sir.
- How's the Spirit?!
- High Sir!
- I said how's the Spirit?!
- Long live India!
What's the background of major Vihan?
NDA topper.
Para-commando gold medalist.
Father colonel Maher Singh Shergil.
Who was martyred in the Kargill War.
He was honored with Mahavir Chakra badge.
After special forces training,
Vihan was posted In Kashmir
and Jaisalmer and Manipur.
And.
Along with eastern command planning of
this mission as well was from major Vihan.
Hmm.
Boys.
Major Vihan Shergill.
- Good job!
- Who headed the operation Sir.
Nice to meet you.
Honored to meet you too Sir.
Major Karan
very proud of your officer.
- Thank you so much Sir.
- Well done.
Thank you.
- Captain Sartaj.
- Sartaj.
Thank you Sir
I've heard a lot of courage
and bravery of your team.
You stopped a lot of terrorists.
We are proud of you all.
Thank you Sir.
According to intelligence the rest of
the terrorist forces want a settlement.
After the Special Forces mission
the enemy other than accepting settlement
don't have any other way.
Vihan!
Arjun Ji was saying that
you applied for a premature retirement
on compassionate grounds?
- Why?
- What has happened?
Sir.
My mother has Alzheimer's.
Stage Six!
She is forgetting everything slowly.
And not feeling well these days.
My posting is in eastern command.
And she lives her in Delhi
with my sister
before she forgets me as well
I want to spend some time with her
good job.
You are a good son that you want to
Take care of your mom.
But protection of the
country is also necessary.
She is mother too!
Is there any other way
other than retirement?
There is a way.
If you are transferred to
Delhi army office.
You'll stay close to your mother
and close to us as well
what do you say?
RightSir
that's good.
- Mr. Govind-
- Yes?
For their mother
Hire a 24-hour nurse.
Yes Sir.
Let's go.
You start your dinner
I'm sure you're hungry.
No matter how many times
you read this report.
Nothing is going to change.
I have only one request.
When my sickness gets severe.
Please don't leave me alone in hospital.
Mommy.
No one is going to put you in hospital
I'm afraid of being alone.
Come on, take medicine
come on.
Eat.
Neha promised me.
Hmm?
- Mommy.
- Mom!
I'm trying my best.
I swear
I know
I know you are trying your best.
Mom!
Eat the medicines.
I will get it.
Hi uncle.
Why did you take so
long to open the door.
These are all the mom's clothes.
Only books are left
I'll bring them later.
OK?-
Also,
Did you give her medications?
I did
where is she?
Sitting in her room.
- Uncle.
- Yes?
At what age did you get black belt?
Sixteen!
Check this out.
Green belt.
In some years
I'll get black belt.
Then you need to be careful
around me!
Don't try to make me angry.
So what are you going to do
after the black belt? Ms. Karate.
First like uncle
I'll be an army officer.
Then I will be the first
female general of India.
Good job.
Wanna be uncle!
Your father is joker right?
You don't consider him a officer right?
Suahana.
Go get the scissors.
Vihan Please go and help Karan.
Why?
He's tiring himself in
order to throw you a party.
My house looks like 8-10
grenades blew up
seriously
- scissor.
- Thank you.
Let's go meet your papa?
A nurse will come for mum today.
Guest room is ready for her
Vihan?
Yes Mom?
When did you come
mom..
He came today.
He wanted to surprise you.
Vacations for how many days?
Ten days.
He is going to take you to aunt in Dehradun
right?
You go, Karan is waiting.
Mom you saw Saregama show?
- Yeah.
- Suhana go do your homework.
- Did you eat anything since morning?
- Yeah
I'm so hungry.
Uncle!
Let's go?
Uncle-
Yes?-
Daddy taught me the war
cry of your battalion.
Really?
Tell me.
♪ Go ahead with courage! ♪
♪ The country is like a religion ♪
War cry this cold?
When you scream the war cry.
The energy of the troop must get high.
Enemies must get fearful
pee in their pants.
That's the real war cry
and for breakfast
start eating eggs from tomorrow.
Don't eat green leafs like your mom.
Go change.
Then lets do the homework, okay?
Go.
Sartaj?
Today was your date right?
You didn't go?
Wait, you don't know?
What has happened?
He got completely ready
to leave using Armani perfume and suit then
he got a text from his girlfriend.
That I'm tired from this relationship,
I'm breaking up with you. It's over
I'm really sorry, I didn't know.
Listen first.
In a few minutes,
my lady sent a message again.
Sorry, baby
I sent this message by mistake
on your number
sir, I mean girls these days
anyways.
How are you going to
do staff work in Delhi?
Person like you will get crazy
doing staff work in south hall.
Till today your planning in any mission
was never gone wrong Sir.
Your real need is on border Sir
Not in Delhi.
Look Bro.
Every soldier has to
do this job as well.
An you both know this
I have to do this.
Don't get sad now, come on
give me some cotton cheese to eat.
Mother's reports came in?
Yeah.
It's spreading aggressively.
Enjoy everyone.
Karan.
Here's your drink!
Thank you, cheers.
This is nothing captain.
Vihan's father.
In fact, used to brew the
best brandy in the world.
Sometimes we escaped from school
And we went drinking.
Very soon, his father got suspicious
to escape from the beating
we together
we transferred half the bottle of brandy
in our school bottle
and panicked
to fill that half bottle.
We fill it with urine.
Not us, it was him only.
And Unfortunately that night.
His uncle from foreign arrived
uncle came yeah.
To try the latest badge of brandy
he drank it and said, listen listen.
He drank it and said.
Exquisite!
Hello, Sir.
When did she sleep?
A few minutes ago.
Got her medication?
Yes Sir.
She has a habit of sleep walking
if something happened.
Call me, I'm right here.
Do not worry, Sir
it's my job.
If you want to rest take the guest room
no problem I am good.
Thanks
what is your name?
- Jasmine!
- Jasmine.
- Jasmine Almeida.
Sit.
Listen, Stop spreading lies.
You are creating a narrative.
The whole world knows,
how much peace we want.
Wherever a small attack
occurs in your country.
You blame that on us.
I say prove it
prove it
The things you say are right
three terrorists.
At 5:00 AM,
entered via Ravi river.
Shot some Punjab roadway buses.
Some people got injured but
driver used his brain and
did not stop the bus
went straight to the government hospital.
Where are the terrorists now?
They are hiding near the Dinanagar police
station in a under-construction building.
But swat team has began to
retaliate.
Keep NSG on standby.
Yes Sir.
Which group are the terrorists from?
Sources say they are from
Lashkar.
How many people died?
Four citizens to this moment.
And
11 people are severely injured.
Sir!
IED bombs found on Pathankot
Amrisar rail tracks.
Probability of finding more.
Sir!
Yes.
Please excuse me.
Sir.
Swat team has arrived in Punjab.
IED bombs found in Amritsar and Pathankot.
Sorry Sir.
We are doing everything from our side.
Yes Sir.
PALAM AIR BASE NEW DELHI.
♪ Life ♪
♪ It was a distance ♪
♪ It was your fault ♪
♪ And it's my fault ♪
♪ Life ♪
♪ The complaints
we had together ♪
♪ We've left behind ♪
RESISTANCE COMMAND HEADQUARTERS.
NEW DELHI.
♪ Life ♪
♪ It was a distance ♪
♪ It was your fault ♪
♪ And it's my fault ♪
♪ Life ♪
♪ The complaints
we had together ♪
♪ We've left behind ♪
♪ I will continue to
your path to your will ♪
♪ Sometimes you pay attention to me ♪
♪ I will continue to
your path to your will ♪
♪ Sometimes you pay attention to me ♪
♪ I'm moving forward ♪
♪ But my traveler,
I do not know where the destination is. ♪
♪ I'm moving forward ♪
♪ But my traveler,
I do not know where the destination is. ♪
SECOND JANUARY 2016.
ARMY WAR ROOM BLOCK B,
HEADQUARTERS OF THE GOVERNMENT NEW DELHI.
♪ Yeah, we've met each other repeatedly ♪
♪ So why are you still ♪
♪ Do you like strangers with me? ♪
♪ The destination is all here ♪
♪ But we're still on the way and lost ♪
♪ No matter how much I come to you ♪
♪ Why do not we ever distance
ourselves from each other? ♪
♪ I will continue to
your path to your will ♪
♪ Sometimes you pay attention to me ♪
♪ I will continue to
your path to your will ♪
♪ Sometimes you pay attention to me ♪
♪ I'm moving forward ♪
♪ But my traveler,
I do not know where the destination is. ♪
♪ I'm moving forward ♪
♪ But my traveler,
I do not know where the destination is. ♪
January 25, 2016.
The attacks are still not
stopping.
Non stop attacking on the.
EDI building.
One of the part of building is on fire.
We heard two soldiers are wounded.
But no other information is available.
- Sir!
Sir!
Why are you here.
Sir My case is under investigation.
First posting was on July 2014
in Srinagar
was still trying to understand the job
on September 1 it rain so heavily
that a dam broke in Jhelum.
The lower areas of Srinagar started
getting flooded with 15-20 feet of water
we all MI-17s
and group pilots immediately
started working on rescue missions.
Without sleeping
or eat something.
We started saving people from low lying
areas
7th night at 3 am.
A distress call came in from
Rajbaug.
A severely injured 7 years old
kid with her mother
stuck on the roofs of their house
alone.
Due to rain
The field of vision was completely zero.
The commander stopped all the
rescue operations until morning
but somehow.
The thought of that kid
did not go out of my mind.
I had to do something.
This is the girl, Sony.
Is there someone in
your family in defence?
Father?
Mother? Brother?
No Sir.
I had a husband.
Captain Jaskidr Singh Ranghi.
Season Punjab regiment.
He was martyred in Nowshera sector.
He was a patriotic man.
I sit here now and I'm afraid that
will ever get a chance
to show my patriotism
to jaskidr Singh.
Mom.
Mommy
Jasmin?
Where is Mom?
Inside sleeping.
Stay here.
Peacefully.
More peaceful.
Neha!
Did mom come here?
No.
I am extremely sorry
I am sorry.
It was really an emergency
if it was not necessary
you know me.
Otherwise, I did not answer my phone
whats your real name?
- Jasmine Almeida.
- What is the name of the real Jassimin?
- Sir I just told you.
- Where is my mom?
Vihan!
One second! Neha one second.
Now you listen to me.
Me or my family.
We do not need any protection
I'm enough for that
especially someone like you
Incompetent.
And a fake nurse
We do not need it at all
tell the intelligence service
that by hook or by crook.
Find my mother and bring her home.
Call.
Can I answer?
Yes you can
hello.
Where?
OK
They found your mother under Dwarka
flyover
the day I came here
I put GPS trackers on all her clothes
so we could track her every movement
should be home soon.
I might be an incompetent nurse.
But I'm a damn good agent Sir
I'm sorry, should be home soon.
Long live India, Sir.
Long live India.
A few more minutes for breakfast.
Can you get some tea?
Shakil.
Sir heavily armed
4-5 terrorists expected.
Sir-What's the update?
Two are hiding behind Westin.
Major Awasti team is counter firing.
One on top of Eden block and
one behind the T6 wall.
- Sartaj!
- Sir?
Bring my Draganov from target room
I'll kill these idiots from range easily
hurry.
Rohit.
- Thapa.
- Sir?
Cover me
sartaj.
From west wing
go inside fuel depot
you both reach near T6 bunker as well.
- Sir!
- Best of luck guys.
- Go go.
- Yes Sir!
- Guards!
- Be ready!
♪ Go ahead with courage! ♪
♪ With power ♪
♪ With audacity ♪
♪ The country is like a religion ♪
I don't care what UN and US say
right now.
The language which Pakistan understands.
We need to teach them a lesson
in their own language.
If we won't retaliate against
this cowardly act.
The trust of our army and
people will get destroyed.
Their beliefs will be lost.
People do not accept
the government anymore.
Sir for war
We can get ready in three days
I can send our tanks and
artillery on LOC in 6 hours
I think we should stop the water
from our Indus treaty
when people put pressure
on Pakistani government.
Maybe their attacks will stop
Pakistan is below their army
army is not below Pakistan
they will let their own people
die from hunger and thirst
but won't stop funding terror.
We need to find a better way to solve this.
That is true.
Govind.
Surgical strike, Sir.
Surgical strike!
We enter POK.
(Pakistan occupied Kashmir)
We destroy all their
terrorist launchpads
all their leaders
all their handlers, guides.
We will finish everything.
Given Pakistan's background
they will never accept that.
There are such groups in their land
as a result.
According to them, there is no terrorist.
There was no attack
when there was no attack.
No war and no international pressure
more important than that
to avenge Uri.
Best opportunity.
The risk of a tactical attack is not high?
If we want we can use fighter jets
to destroy their bunkers
nearby LOC border.
At unique Olympics
Israeli athletes were
killed by PLO terrorists
Israel did not take revenge
by launching missiles
they performed an operation
called: "Wrath of God"
each and every terrorist
they searched and followed
they killed them in their own house.
In the history of India till now
We never attacked any country first
Pakistan is taking advantage of this
from beginning
1947, 1965, 1971,1999
In fact Sir,
they are taking advantage of our tolerance.
It's time now
to put fear in their hearts.
They should be taught
India will not stay silent now.
This is a new India.
We'll invade their homes.
And hit them where it hurts.
Ravindra Ji.
We do not have war with Pakistani people.
Our war with terrorist groups.
I think govind is right
Arjun.
I think it's a good idea
well then
within ten days
Pakistan for the first time
We will see our surgical strike.
Dear Ravinder.
Prepare a team with Arjun.
You will take complete
responsibility for this.
With you.
All the planning will be yours.
Daily Progress Report.
Direct to me Yes.
You all keep Pakistani authorities
busy.
Remember.
Ask them Uri proofs
ask them answers
but no one
under no circumstances
should not get get aware of our plan
make sure.
These meetings don’t get logged.
Did you eat anything?
NoSir I do not want to.
Sit, ill get you something.
I’m in hurry.
I just received orders.
There's going to be an
operation in Kashmir.
I do not know the details
maybe.
They want to send answer for Uri.
Karan Sir always said.
No one will die when we have
Vihan with us
when we have him with us
even death is scared of us.
Really wish that
You were there to lead us Sir.
Inside karan's stuff.
I found 2 dirty shirts.
I don’t understand what to do.
I don't want to wash them
and don't want to give it to anyone
they
it has smell of his empathy.
Sir! You said one time in your speech.
There exists a thin line between
responsibility and irresponsibility.
I don't want to be that line Sir.
If I don't fight for my country
and my men now..
..then I'll be irresponsible
in my own opinion
and, I cannot live like that.
I promise you, you can send me to any
god forsaken corner of this world to fight
I'll bring back each and every
soldier safe and sound
sir please
let me be a part of the Kashmir mission.
I request you Sir, Please!
Vihan!
In the next 8 days you are going to
carry out a surgical strike in POK.
Tomorrow morning
Gen. Grayval at the commando base
will give you all the details
of this operation
all the on ground plannings
you will plan alongside him
prepare a great team
and revert back to me on 23rd night.
With thorough details
understood, Sir.
I wish you all the best.
Thank you very much!
I've been looking at
this map for forty years
when I close my eyes
I don’t see my kid's face.
I see the divided Kashmir map
and for the same I tell you.
Going inside POK will be easy.
But the problem is returning
after the attack.
I understand, Sir.
We will plan for anything
did you finalize the team?
Sir, in Uri we lost most of the soldiers
from Dovra and Bihar regiment.
I suggest that.
Other than special forces
we need few soldiers
from this regiment as well.
Because sometimes to win a war,
except training we need some motivation
and fire inside soldiers as well.
I want to use their anger and fire
in the right way possible.
Stand At Ease.
Commandos.
My name is Major Vihan Shergil.
And he is the captain Sartaj.
Everyone take your phones out.
Now send your family a text message
that until the morning of September 29th
you will live in Udempur for
a special tactical training
during this training.
You will not be allowed to speak
or send a message to anyone
up to seven days later.
Turn off your phone
write.
Sent?
Yes Sir that's good.
Put your phone in this bag.
Now you will get your phone on 29th morning
what I want to tell you.
You will not forget these words
until your death
the night of September 28th
I'm giving you a opportunity
to get your brothers revenge
that were killed in Uri
just like how they killed without mercy
like cowards they killed our brothers in
their sleep.
The answer to that cruelty.
We their head off.
Are you ready for this mission?
Yes Sir!
Is your blood boiling for revenge?
Commandos
who are we?
The Indian army.
The Indian Army did not start this war.
But we will bloody hell
finish it!
Yes Sir!
- How's the Spirit?!
- High Sir!
Good!
Yes Sir!
No it's our mistake ji.
Yes, I'll search it.
Yes, it's indeed necessary
you do not worry.
Yes, yes Good bye.
You are a classy fool.
Dumb, rubbish, bitch.
Do you have children or not?
Do not have children.
From past 1 month I'm telling you.
There is a person in our department.
That is informing to India.
And you have not found him yet?
I swear to God.
I feel that
is the spy one of you?
Do you know how much I'm under pressure?
Within a week
if before one week
you do not find that informer
then I'll cook one of
you for my breakfast.
And I swear by God.
I will not even burp!
You stood up to me, what?
Get out of here!
Kareem Give me that file
I'm miserable.
Yeah, mum this is me.
Hello. How are you?
Yes you are right.
You asked for mobile number
of aunt of Belgias right?
Take pen and write.
Three, four.
Four, no.
Five, eight
eight
seventy four.
Twenty-one.
Two.
Yes.
No no I do not feel good.
Sounds like that.
This is because of gastric gas
I have STD in my stomach.
You also note your Uncle Mono's number.
Sir!
We got the coordinates
total 7 area locations
all close to LOC.
But the exact location
of the launchpads
we have to find it physically
call Shrinivas from ISRO.
Tripura, Assam pictures are not coming
due to heavy rains
hello.
Govind here.
From the Ministry of Defense.
Hi, govind!
Tell me
listen!
I'm sending you series of coordinates
satellite 1 or satellite 2.
One of these satellites
for six days
I want you to focus on
these coordinates
and don't let it move
no matter anything happens.
- OK.
- Another thing.
Relay all the images directly
to the ministry of defense
we have only two hours of time.
OK
You and the army intelligence office
together.
Sit down and search each and
every location of these coordinates
we can send our soldiers only
when
we have all the details of
each and every location.
- Correct?
- Yes Sir.
Done Sir.
Send this feed directly
to the defence ministry.
Sir!
We have the feed.
Palavi.
Palavi Sharma.
That day you asked my real name
I'm really sorry about that day
it's okay.
If I were in your place
I showed the same reaction.
How's mom
she is
she's fine!
Now Neha is living with her.
Also we got a full time nurse
so..lets see
I'm hope she is better than me.
I think it's time.
We should get going.
I will look into this.
Sir!
- Sir!
- Welcome Vihan.
Have a sit.
Team selected?
Yes Sir.
How about the training of the commandos?
Already started Sir
that's good.
Ms. Palavi.
You get started.
Sir.
Sir 5 launchpads of Hizbul,
Lashkar and Jaish are confirmed.
Two in the Leepa valley.
Two in Kel.
And one in Bhimber.
All these launchpads are
in isolated areas.
That's why it was easy to find them
and two other
they might be in forests of
Muzaffarabad
sir using satellite images
of crowded locations
finding the exact location
is difficult
I'll tomorrow.
Give DRDO a visit to see
if they can help us
find these launchpads
and Ms. Palawi.
You keep updating Vihan about all
the details of these launchpads.
Right Sir.
Vihan any suggestion?
Any question?
Which of these launchpad
was used for Uri attack?
We have suspicion that muzaffarabad
launchpad was used by the attackers
and who was the handler of that attack?
Information about that
we don't have it yet, sorry.
These sigma-5 drones are
our latest inventions
developed along with the
Israeli intelligence.
Sir.
Their range is approx 50 kilometers
and it can fly 2 kilometers
above the ground level
that's all good Brian, but.
How close can it fly to the ground?
Without anybody noticing it
what do you mean?
I mean I want a drone that can
fly near an enemy's window
still he won't understand.
Sir!
Such technology has not yet been made
I thought as much.
Sir he is our intern!
What's your name son?
Ishaan
Ishaan Vatal Sir
what is this?
Sir its an unmanned aerial vehicle
shaped like an eagle
uh huh.
What is it called?
Garud.
What?
Garud, based on the legend of Vishnu-
Legend of Vishnu, yes.
Sorry Sir ...There are many
projects under construction here
I use waste parts to pass
some time
Ishaan.
Show me how it fly’s, come on.
Sorry Sir.
Sir.
Sir when I say.
You need to run fast
and with all power
throw it in the air
wait one minute Sir.
Sir Get your hands up.
Higher, Sir.
Sir A bit more.
Sorry Sir.
Sir Three.
Two.
One.
What's the range?
Sir it can fly up to the distance
of 12 kilometers
and at least 4 hours of battery
backup on single charge.
Has GPS, infrared, night vision
enabled.
It has a 16 megapixel camera and 7.2x
digital zoom.
For take off and landing it can hover
at one place also.
Like.
This
for take off and landing it
can hover at one place
then why did you make Brian run?
- Brian.
- Yes Sir
I want 4 of these until tomorrow
- until tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Sir, this is just a prototype that
this kid made just for time pass.
This is not commissioned
and might take a month for it.
Can you make 4 by tomorrow?
Huh?
If the whole team is helping.
Why not Sir?
Good. Brian.
Yes?-
Stop all other work..
Start a new assembly line and
tell all technicians
to work only on this.
Until tomorrow afternoon I want Ishaan
along with 4 guards on Kashmir's flight.
OK?
Uh huh.
You might have just won us the war son.
Good job!
Sorry Sir.
Sir!
It's time to show Jaskidr
Ji some patriotism.
You are going to be my pilot Sirat.
Sir.
Excuse me.
Hello.
Army intelligence has caught
two guides near Baramula.
It's likely that they
have information on Uri attack.
Govind Sir wants us to lead the
interrogation.
When are you leaving?
In two hours.
Balaampor airspace.
Who was the handler of
Uri attack?
Where did the planning took place?
Mam, we don't know anything.
We work in walnut business.
Don't you lie
or I'll break your balls!
Mam I swear to god, believe me.
The pain! The pain!
Who was responsible for the attack?
I want the names!
Who was responsible for it?
Who was responsible for
the attack on Uri?
The pain
I want the names.
The pain.
Who was in the attack?
What is his relation with you?
My brother, Sir.
What's his name?
Faizal!
Listen, faizal.
We have very little time
your brother has only two ways.
One.
He tells us calmly who was
the handler for Uri attack.
Two
I'll pull your intestines and put
them on his lap.
Want some tea?
Man please stop him!
He is just a kid.
Mam please.
Mam please, he will die please
I'll tell you.
Idriss.
From Baghdad.
He made the plan.
Jabbar Firozi was the handler
this is the doctrine.
And that's the point.
Before Uri attack, Pampur attack
was carried out by them.
Planned by these two And led.
Idriss from Yalcourt.
And jabbar from Gilgit
seven years ago in a training camp of
Jaish E Mohammad
they meet each other at a training camp.
And a few years later
under the supervision of the same group.
These two made their own
special terrorist group.
Sirat-ul-jannat.
In the forest area of ​​Mozaffarabad
near the village of Chacoty
their launchpad is located.
From the nearby forest
around the launchpads
using the natural caves around there.
Their guide, help terrorists
to reach India.
We have given the location of these
caves to the army
there are under the supervision.
And for additional surveillance
4 drones from DRDO
will reach Kashmir tomorrow.
Now from tomorrow.
Enhance the defence on LOC border.
And for 3 consecutive days, increase
it slowly
so that by 28th of night.
We will reach Shailin border
especially around
the areas from where our commandos
are going to enter PoK.
♪ I fight ♪
♪ There is so much
determination in me that ♪
♪ Going with me in a hurry ♪
♪ every drop of blood tells me ♪
♪ Come out of your camp♪ ♪Shade ♪
♪ Come out of your camp ♪
♪ Destroy all your enemies ♪
♪ Shade ♪
♪ Fight with all power ♪
♪ Destroy all your enemies ♪
There are some hills for cover here
but at 60 meters distance
there is Pakistani forward post.
Remove all the flight records
of all the choppers.
And paint them all similar
to Pakistani air force choppers.
♪ This war is in love ♪
♪ Our heart is full of passion ♪
♪ We are on our side and in our hands ♪
♪ this is the home ♪
♪ that the whole world ♪
♪ We will remember our name as an example ♪
♪ I fight ♪
♪ There is so much
determination in me that ♪
♪ Going with me in a hurry ♪
♪ every drop of blood from me says ♪
♪ Come out of your camp♪ ♪Shade ♪
♪ Fight with all power ♪
♪ Destroy all your enemies ♪
♪ Come out of your camp♪ ♪Shade ♪
♪ Fight with all power ♪
♪ Destroy all your enemies ♪
As of 0900 hours
India has increased defence at
the border.
It seems that India is still looking for an
answer To our PM's speech at UN.
Sir, perhaps the defence
at border
is to distract us?
If there was a second attack plan
then our intelligence agency could
have got some clues until now
India has no capability to think
of another attack.
Already there's a bad situation
in Kashmir.
There will be drama for few days on LOC.
Our actors and singers will be banned.
The stock market will
get slightly up and down.
Then everything will go back to normal.
But we should not underestimate the enemy.
We cannot not repeat this mistake again.
- Zubair?
- Yes Sir?
- Afzal?
I want the slightest news.
Any number of weapons that you
can send to the Kashmir border.
Our retaliation should not be
any lesser.
Is that understood?
- Yes Sir.
- That's good.
What happened in your meeting today?
Your shots look messed up today.
The talks at the LOC are
getting pretty serious
Indians are making us work hard.
Today there were some important decisions
in the meeting.
Anyways!
Check my shot now.
See this blow.
No Zameer.
Today, you are very distracted.
Let's do this.
Come to my house today
I'll tell my wife to make you
some Biryani.
And some sweets.
No, not today.
Today have to stay awake all night
to work alongside major
and Tomorrow.
Maybe will have to visit LOC.
We will plan it some other day.
Do you have any other plans on 28th?
On the night of 28th?
!Yes bro
28th sounds good sure?
- Yes bro.
- For sure.
Let's go look for the ball.
Can you get me a closer shot?
Yes, Sure-
Go to the right.
Good job Ishaan. good job!
Hey
come and sit.
Get it out now, Ishaan!
I'm trying
Ishaan!
Come on!
Toy!
Yes Yes
try! come on Ishaan!
Sir this is B2 launchpad and
training center
from where terrorists for Uri attack came
38 highly trained terrorists.
Two floor building
and 5 exit points.
This information is confirmed
by our intelligence office?
Yes Sir
I personally checked each and
every launchpad.
What is the plan of the attack?
Sir Our 80 commandos are ready
28th night, 12th hour.
When our defenses are
at their peak.
Then from our forward post by
4 MI-17 helicopters
we will enter POK
(Pakistan occupied Kashmir)
And exactly at 2am we
will start our attack!
Our 80 commandos are divided into 4 teams.
Each team includes twenty people
Each team must eliminate two targets
Alpha team.
Along with Major Wihan
they will get B1
and after that.
Jabbar and Idris's
they will destroy B2 launchpad
similarly
Tim Bravo, Charlie and Delta
in Leepa, Bhimber and Kiel.
Destroy their targets.
The positive thing is that all the targets
are nearby LOC.
That means from landing to take off,
This all operation will be completed
in 45-50 minutes
which means
that by 3 am we should
be back in our choppers
and by 5am
our soldiers will reach our Srinagar base.
Tomorrow there will be no meeting here.
As you all are told
in front of press and public.
You should carry out a normal day.
On 28th night.
We don't want anyone from our ministry
here in the defence building.
Apart from military intelligence
Arjun and Govind has my permission
to stay here.
Vihan when are you leaving for Kashmir?
Sir, we will leave from northern command
tomorrow morning.
I heard that you promised that you will
bring all the troops alive and well?
-Sir.
-With your permission.
Me and my commandos on the 30th of night
would like to have dinner with you.
Long live India.
Long live India, Sir.
Captain Vaid!
Akram
Bali
you three will lead bravo
Charlie.
And Delta.
As soon as we para drop in PoK.
We all will be easy targets
that's why everyone.
Be careful,
stealthily.
Must reach their target
launchpads.
Once we reached.
Again.
Outer parameters sniper.
Inner parameters assaulters.
Each team will have a signal jammer
so that during the attack.
Terrorist wont use radio signal
and mobile calls.
Remember boys!
Our return
is the toughest part
our backs will face enemies.
And they shooting from behind.
So we have to be quick.
Is there a question?
NoSir.
I promised that you all
will return to India. Alive!
And bloody well intend to
keep my promise.
Long live India-
Muzaffarabad and Kkel's assets
have updated us.
Its reported that India will
enhance their defence.
Across the border.
Excuse me.
Sir!
Commandos!
It's time!
To make them bleed for their deeds.
They want Kashmir and
we want their head.
Are you ready for the boys? -
Yes Sir-
- How's the Spirit?!
- High Sir!
- Long live India.
Go! Go! Go!
All the best!
It was very dark.
We were also very scared.
How should we know baby's
belly can also get blown.
Asma!
Yes?
Bring some ice for Zameer ji
help yourself.
Come on! why are you
working so much in kitchen!
We are getting bored here.
Come Sit with us.
Zameer ji while cooking biryani
we cannot do 2 works at a time.
Just few more minutes.
Today you are looking a lot better
you were looking distracted
from so many days.
What can I say
Indians are bothering us so much.
Don't know what other plans they
have with border defence.
Our informants are no less though.
We took all the caution as well.
Did you taste these Kaggers?
Thank God.
Biryani is ready!
Now make me peg as well
with some ice cubes.
And zameer ji.
How is your wife doing?
Yeah she.
She has gone Birmingham.
Graduation Celebration
of my little kid.
For that
I wanted to go as well.
But the problem at LOC
has messed up all my programs.
What can we do.
Cheers.
Wait.
Since when did you
started drinking whiskey?
What do you mean?
You.
You drink wine right?
Actually the wines caused me migraines.
So I thought.
Drink whiskey.
Oh well, woman who drink whiskey
are very special
let's go
be quick
Central government office.
Zameer!
Zameer ji!
Zameer!!
Today in meeting what was
the decision against India?
Today at the meeting
♪ surgical strike♪ were these words used?
♪ Surgical strike♪ were these words used?!!
Zameer!!
Wife! what are you doing to me? -
What was the decision today at meeting?
Nothing.
What did the minister say?
Zameer!!
The informants told us that
near the border.
Helicopters painted as Pakistani
helicopters were spotted.
Helicopters were painted Sir
maybe to escape the radar.
They fly at low altitude and
attack our forward post.
How should we stop them?
Excellency.
We need to launch A-Vac radar
from Uri sector.
After than even if by mistake
enemies helicopter
come close to border at least 20 feet
then our anti aircraft missiles
will shoot it down.
Hello
Alpha team needs to abort the mission
I repeat
Alpha team operations should be stopped.
What.
Sir!
We detect air activity at LOC.
Prepare anti-aircraft missiles.
- Sir?
- Palavi!
Vihan's chopper already left?
Yes Sir.
They will cross LOC in 10 seconds.
Connect me to Vihan now!
Vihan!
I'll patch you to govind Sir.
Sir!
Vihan is online.
Vihan do not cross LOC!
I repeat! Do not cross the border.
Turn around the chopper!
Turn around Turn around.
Vihan they have launched Evac radar
in muzaffarabad sector.
So Alpha team cannot cross by air.
You have to abort the mission.
Palavi listen.
During the interrogation
Farook told us
they brought terrorists in India
via caves.
That our army is monitoring.
Send me its exact coordinates.
If we cannot go through the air
we will go through the land
but in any way we will
complete this mission today.
Bravo charlie delta.
Follow the plan.
From this moment there will be
radio silence between us 4 teams
we will only be in touch with army
intelligence directly
they will keep me posted.
You're right.
Bravo charlie delta.
According to the information your
areas are completely safe.
So move ahead as planned.
Whats the status?
Sir we have figured out the coordinates
thank you welcome Sir
!let's go.
Sir entering a cave blindly without
monitoring
this is way too risky.
Rangers, terrorists
anyone can be guarding these caves.
Vihan wait!
Ishaan online?
Can he hear our voice?
Yes, Sir he can.
- Ishaan.
- Yes Sir?
Can you see GPS of all the
4 teams?
Yes Sir I can see it
that's good
from now on you are going to be their eyes.
Tell all the operators, all the 4 guards
will stay few meters ahead of team leaders.
And you keep tracking
their position by GPS.
As soon as you see any danger
warn the team leader.
Sure, Sir.
Sir!
Sir.
We are in Pakistan occupied Kashmir.
Good job Vihan!
Other teams are reaching their
primary targets as well!
Kunal!
Get your gun fast.
Get a quick look.
Say hello to your 72 virgins..
..and ask them to hold
the celebrations on.
We plan to help them with
a lot more guests tonight.
Sir
The first operation was successful.
We have destroyed B1 launchpad.
What's the status of other teams?
Bravo and Charlie have attacked
their secondary location.
Delta's mission is complete
and is about to return.
Not a single casualty
that's good
let's go
Abdullah-
Yes?-
Come.
Drop zameer ji at their house
he drank a lot today.
Come here Go out.
Where is Idris.
Where is Idris
!Camera
!Camera.
Found Idriss?
Not yet Sir!
I think he is not here.
He is here.
Someone alerted the police.
They are just two minutes away.
Vihan!
Be quick.
Copy Sir!
But Idriss must die.
But, Vihan.
Sartaj
move.
You came to my house
and killed my brothers right?
Today I came to your house
and I'm killing your brothers.
Under the name of Indian Army.
The Indian Army.
Ishan!
Where to?
Sir lower east side
from the farm!
Who is there?
I'll shoot you!
Sartaj!
Let's go... let's go
let's go.
Move faster Faster
Pakistani choppers are firing at us.
Vihan.
We are sending jets for your covering fire.
It will take up to 10
minutes for them to reach!
Copy Sir!
Sir our ammunition is about to finish.
We can't hold till 10 minutes
whatever happens.
Our each and every soldier
will reach India alive!
Sirat
now!
Jaskidr ji!
It's for you.
Sir!
We did it!
Bravo charlie delta?
What's your status?
Every mission was successful.
Not a single casualty
I'm proud of you boys.
Yeah.
Thank you Sir.
Congratulations Sir.
Sir!
Mission complete
commandos
Yes Sir?-
- How's the Spirit?!
- High Sir!
Long live India-
♪ Your face is like eating ♪
♪ Your face turned on ♪
♪ your hands filled with ♪
♪ Light lights ♪
♪ Your face is like eating ♪
♪ Your face turned on ♪
♪ your hands filled with ♪
♪ Light lights ♪
♪ How can I oppose you? ♪
♪ How is there such a
craving for someone? ♪
♪ When you sit down, shine ♪
♪ When you fly, shimmer ♪
♪ As a bird flies for the first time ♪
♪ When you sit down, shine ♪
♪ When you fly, shimmer ♪
♪ As a bird flies for the first time ♪
♪ This is a new look ♪
♪ A flying bird flies first ♪
Vihan.
♪ It's my anger that has come up ♪
♪ I'll get my chance, I'll do it again. ♪
♪ A flame burned ♪
♪ I do not need another friend to try ♪
♪ It's my anger that has come up ♪
♪ I'll get my chance, I'll do it again. ♪
♪ A flame burned in my face ♪
♪ I do not need another friend to try ♪
♪ Let's celebrate our victory ♪
♪ We won ♪
♪ That victory is our motive ♪
♪ This is my motive ♪
♪ You are my motive, motive ♪
♪ Shall we write a new story ♪
♪ Write spoof ♪
♪ Wait enough ♪
♪ No longer tolerate, enough ♪
♪ The one who waits is not revolutionary ♪
♪ Listen to your heart ♪
♪ My heart is razieh ♪
♪ Why are you so scared? ♪
♪ This time we get the game ♪
♪ Shaping a New Story ♪
♪ Write spoof ♪
♪ Let's celebrate our victory ♪
♪ We won ♪
♪ That victory is our motive ♪
♪ This is my motive ♪
♪ You are my motive, motive ♪
♪ It's my anger that has come up ♪
♪ I'll get my chance, I'll do it again. ♪
♪ A flame burned in my face ♪
♪ I do not need another friend to try ♪
♪ We have the power to push the storm ♪
♪ Shadow that we are still young ♪
♪ We do not accept force ♪
♪ Let's do what we do ♪
♪ We have the power to push the storm ♪
♪ Shadow that we are still young ♪
♪ We do not accept force ♪
♪ Let's do what we do ♪
♪ Let's celebrate our victory ♪
♪ We won ♪
♪ There is a boom in our veins ♪
♪ We win ♪
♪ If we went out of this stairs ♪
♪ Again, the sky is under our feet ♪
♪ There is a boom in our veins ♪
♪ We win ♪
♪ If we went out of this stairs ♪
♪ Again, the sky is under our feet ♪
♪ Do not wait for the dreams of a storm ♪
♪ Do not wait if you can fly if you want. ♪
♪ Do not wait,
you can aim with your eyes. ♪
♪ If you will, make a rain of fire. ♪
♪ You can ♪
♪ Out of yours ♪
♪ you can ♪
♪ What you have right ♪
♪ You have to hand it over ♪
♪ Do not be afraid ♪
♪ What you have right ♪
♪ You have to hand it over ♪
♪ Do not be afraid ♪
♪ The victory we dreamed is ours ♪
♪ Now we are going ♪
♪ I'm not too short ♪
♪ Today I smell all sweet ♪
♪ I gained this pride for you ♪
♪ I'm not too short ♪
♪ Today I smell all sweet ♪
♪ I gained this pride for you ♪
♪ Do not wait for the dreams of a storm ♪
♪ Do not wait if you can fly if you want. ♪
♪ Do not wait,
you can aim with your eyes. ♪
♪ If you will, make a rain of fire. ♪
♪ You can ♪
♪ Out of yours ♪