And no one could refuse the Witch
any favours
It has to be tonight
I can't take it any more. Not even for you
Soo-kyoung, a thief released before me
found out where Baek was working
Seong-eun, a smart college grad...
...was later released and got a job
at the same place
She then informed me of Baek's
intention of getting a new car
Later, Baek was visited by
a pretty car dealer, Park Yi-jeong
It'll be used wisely for the Lord's work
Hello?
Darling
Have you had dinner?
I'll wait and have it with you
You can go ahead without me
I'll wait for you, so hurry back
He hasn't eaten yet. I'll go and make
him eat first
It's okay. Don't worry
Bye
Geum-ja
At that moment, Geum-ja held her
breath and struggled to break free
Even in this desperate situation
she never forgot the gun's firing range
Got an English-Korean dictionary?
Don't think that I forgive you
I think mothers who dump their kids
should go to jail
When I was younger, I often thought of
taking revenge out on you
But I couldn't imagine the thought of
killing you
Reason being that, I didn't know what
your face looked like
Anyway, since we're on better terms
now, give me your reasons at least
Saying sorry is not enough
You should say sorry at least 3 times
Ungenerously your daughter, Jenny
Left turn
I remember when I first had you, Jenny
As you grew in me, I felt like my wallet
was getting fatter
But even before you could celebrate
your first birthday, I had to go to prison...
I had to give you up
You are a sweet child you'd smile your
pretty smiles to complete strangers...
I knew anyone will be happy to have you
anyone will be able to love you
After I'm done with this man...
I'm planning to return you to Australia
My sins are too great and too deep...
for me to take care such a sweet child
like you
You're innocent, but
but I made you grew up without
a mother...
But, also part of the punishment
I must take
Listen carefully
People make mistakes
If you commit a sin, you have to make
atonement for that sin
Atonement, do you know what
that means?
Atonement
Yes, that's it
Big atonement for big sins...
Small atonement for small sins
OK?
Because he made me a sinner
This man killed a little boy...
And...
I helped him
I was happy...
Too happy for a sinner
Jenny
I'm truly sorry
Farewell
Get up, teacher! Time to go to work!
Geum-ja, what's with that eye shadow?
Do you know why those kids...
Hey! Here's another one!
Hello?
If you'd found the real killer back then...
These children wouldn't have died, right?
You know how this feels
There were four!
- I told you I can't come to work today
- It's not that...
- Someone's here looking for you
- Who?
- Well, the thing is
- They won't say who they are?
I don't know what they're saying
Can you speak Japanese?
Mommy!
Please hurry and come get me...
Mommy...
There, there. Don't cry. Don't cry...
Mommy... please hurry
Mommy, I want to go home
Please hurry, mommy
There, there... Don't cry. Don't cry
Mommy, where are you?
I know it's difficult but take a good look
at this man
Next is Se-hyun, killed in 1995
Dad... I can't...
Daddy
This is Eun-joo, in '96
I can't breathe...
I'm scared. Please don't kill me, sir
Wait just a minute
This is Yoo Jae-kyoung, 2000
Mommy
He was a teacher at English schools
in affluent neighbourhoods
He'd pick his victim, kidnap and kill
them, then move on to another school
He'd never pick a child from one of
his own classes
Which is why he was never under
any suspicion
Coffee or green tea?
Children annoyed him, so he would
tape them right after kidnapping them...
And killed them straight away
The voices you heard on the line while
negotiating the ransom...
...were taped off the videos
after the kids were already dead
Now, you have two options
If you want lawful punishment...
We will hand him over to
Chief Choi here
But if you want a speedier
more personalized death for him...
You can have it right here and now
Does he have a child of his own?
He is supposed to be sterile
Then what did he need all that
money for?
He put it in the bank
Of course, the money will all be returned
to you...
With no kid, what did he need all that
money for?
He... was going to buy a yacht
The police have big sticks but they
don't know how to use them
If we leave it to them, there'd be nothing
but never-ending trials...
And all those bloody reporters...
How about we leave it to Geum-ja?
It'd be easier since she's been to jail
and all
That's cowardly! They're our kids
Then, let each person choose if
they want to be in or not
I'm for individual choice
Why don't you just let him choose
his own death or trial, then...
Individually?
Little while ago, you wanted to hand him
over to the police
Then you wanted to leave it up
to Geum-ja...
Now you want to be left out alone?
What the hell do you want?
Won-mo's family has to follow the
majority, too
You know that, right?
She has a weak heart...
Hey, mine's weak, too
Then Won-mo's father can represent
the family
One person per family should
be enough
Alright?
What if Won-mo's mom informs
on us later?
She couldn't. Her husband's in on it, too
They could always get divorced
We can leave some evidence, then
How about we all take a picture?
So that...
...even if we feel guilty later... - Guilty?
Guilt for killing that bastard?
We'd feel guilty if we didn't kill him
when we had him. That's guilt!
Let me say a word
I killed when I was in prison...
I'm also the one who caught Baek after
13 years of planning...
If anyone here informs the police...
I won't say any more
Shall we go in one at a time?
Or all together at once?
One at a time for what?
Let's just go finish him off
There's no need to share such a
personal matter with other families
Isn't that right, dad?
Won't it be scary going in alone?
And it could be dangerous
Just think of it as using the toilet
In any case, it's a private affair
Each to his own. A la carte...
We don't all have to get the same
set menu
Please, honey...
We're divorced
This isn't a couples thing!
We don't have to go in together
Excuse me, I think...
- It'd be too easy if we did it all together
- Honey!
I brought along a sedative
You couldn't even touch that finger
remember?
Alright, then...
Won-mo's father is out, and his mother
will go in alone...
...Jae-kyoung's and Dong-hwa's are
going in together...
- Is that right? - Yes!
Let's do it then!
Wait! Just a second!
Shouldn't we decide what order you
go in?
Will that be enough for you?
I can lend you mine after
Well...
I think I'll be okay
Honey...
Everyone pay attention
If you grip it like this, the tip of the knife
will slip and not penetrate deeply
You could also cut your hand
So grip it like this at all times, please
Or you could just...
...stab him like this
Why did you do it?
You look like a normal person
Why?
Ma'am, there's no such thing as
a perfect person
This...
...isn't going to bring our son back
is it, honey?
Right?
You all look very well off
Take a look at that
She took her boots off, so's not to get
blood on the suede
Does that make any sense to you here?
My mom had to scrub hotel floors to
send my brother to that school
We ran around like dogs to come up
with the ransom
Now we've lost our house and our
relatives won't see us
My daughter-in-law killed herself and
my son left the country
We all have our own stories to tell
Dad!
We're not the last, dad. Eun-joo's
grandma's still waiting her turn
Dad...
Come on, give me a hand!
Mister, get up
Please. Get a hold of yourself!
I'm sorry, but...
Could you step aside a moment?
Thank you
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday dear...
I'm sorry
It felt like a birthday to me...
We can say it is, then
Happy birthday...
...to you!
Will you wire the money into
our accounts?
My account number
In France...
...when there's a break in the
conversation like this...
...they say an angel is passing
It's snowing!
It's snowing a lot
- When did it all pile up so much?
- What time is it now?
The traffic...
The roads will freeze soon
Won-mo
I have...
Along the path on green grass...
A lady in red heels goes...
Click, click, click with her heels
Where might she be going?
Won't she look back...
Are you really going to send Jenny back?
...back my way for a glance?
Are you?
One step, two...
The lady in red heels takes another
step away, alone...
Lee Geum-ja made a great mistake
in her youth...
And used other people to achieve
her own goals...
But she still couldn't find the redemption
she so desired
In spite of this...
Actually, because of this...
I liked Geum-ja
Farewell...
...Geum-ja