Hey, it's Marsh.
Mmm-hmm.
Hmm.
Okay.
When are you just gonna give
up on that thing and get a new one?
Well, you know me.
Love a lost cause.
Where are you off to?
Oh, new start down at
Tonto National Forest.
Ate up 40,000 acres yesterday.
Fixing to triple that today.
You got something to say to me
before you walk out that door?
Well, I guess I said some shit
last night I shouldn't have.
Yeah. You did.
Why?
Because.
Because what?
'Cause you're smarter than I am,
especially when we squabble.
And it pisses me off.
Well, I can appreciate that.
I bet you can.
I guess we both made
some mistakes last night.
Yes, we did.
Let's make better
ones next time.
Okay.
God, I love you,
Manda-bear.
I love you, too, Shortstop.
- See ya.
♪ Ridin' down the highway
♪ Goin' to a show
♪ Stop in all the byways
♪ Playin' rock 'n' roll
♪ Gettin' robbed
♪ Gettin' stoned
♪ Gettin' beat up
♪ Broken-boned
♪ Getting had... ♪
Bla-blow wants to go with you.
What did you say to me?
Bla-blow wants
to go with me?
Crazy little guy.
Come here.
- Can you take this little stinker?
- Yeah.
He's not a stinker.
- No, you're a stinker.
- No, I'm not.
Mmm-hmm.
She's a stinker.
Bye. Say bye.
Bla-blow says good-bye.
Put me down. Put me down.
Oh, boy.
Go, Mack!
Come on, buddy.
Get that can, would you?
Just 'cause you got
a crack in your ass
don't make you a cripple,
Jesse. You get it.
Air Attack Helicopter
741 en route with a full tank.
Crew 7, can we get
a ground fix on the fire?
Helicopter 741, this is Crew 7.
Fire's running north-northwest
two miles out from our location.
Copy that,
Crew 7. Thank you.
Confirmed.
Clear to drop.
Good work, 741.
Copy that.
You saw men, take five!
Bravo Squad, take five!
Powwow?
Breaky.
Yo!
Huddle up!
- Hey, agua me.
- Yeah.
Alpha!
I've got to throw
a new on the saw!
Rosie.
Chaw.
Hot sauce.
You look like a bag
of smashed assholes right now.
You all right?
I had a crazy night, bro.
I finally hooked up
with that gal Cheyanne.
- Yes!
- Cheyanne?
The Cheyanne? The girl from the Emporium
with the tattoos and the beautiful eyes?
- That's the one.
- Outstanding.
What's up? Dude, Whitted,
Mack closed that girl
from the Emporium last night.
Cheyanne?
Yeah.
I see her at church now
and again. She doesn't talk.
Yeah, she doesn't
need to though, right?
I mean, like, unreal.
Hey, guys.
Guys, guys!
The man is clearly an artist.
Let him share his gift.
MacKenzie, proceed.
I mean, she went
full-blown medieval on me.
I had to buckle in at one point.
- Oh, God.
- I want to buckle in.
I mean, there was just one thing that
she said that just threw me, though.
Don't worry about it.
What? Dude, you can't say
there's something and then
"Don't worry about it."
What was it?
All right, all right, all right.
Postcoital, we're laying
in bed. I grab the remote.
Okay? I turn the TV on. I'm
flipping through the channel.
I end up on an infomercial.
In the background...
there's Mount Rushmore.
And I'm trying to make
conversation at this point.
It's awkward.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I'm like, "Wow,
that's amazing."
Right.
Her rebuttal to this?
"Especially when you realize
it's a natural thing."
What? What?
Oh, that's not good.
What?
You mean to tell me
that this girl believes that the
faces of our four presidents
showed up on a mountain
through the process of...
natural erosion?
Yeah!
Wind and rain
carved out the presidents.
Many forms of
intelligence, Mack.
I love wind and rain!
Oh, my God.
Hey, honestly, Mack,
this girl is perfect
for you, man.
She's like a match
made in heaven.
I'm proud of you.
I haven't slept.
Whitted, where you at?
Whoo!
We got a chain left
to finish the mop-up.
All right, just get it done.
Aye, aye, Papa.
All right, boys, back to work.
Jesse!
Yeah, Supe!
I'm gonna go scout ahead!
You got it!
Tree coming down!
Falling!
This showcase
is gonna burn, baby, burn!
Nicole, welcome to the showcase!
Zachariah,
welcome to the showcase!
Guys, pay close attention
to the first showcase,
because it could go to
either one of you. Here we go.
Good luck.
This five-station
home gym centers around
a fully adjustable
weight set to help...
I can't read that shit.
What's it say?
From Hatch.
"Saw Natalie working
Murph's last night.
"Did you know she was pregnant?"
Who's Natalie?
Some chick I rolled with
a couple months back.
Some rubber in your new car!
What are you doing?
What are you up to?
Yeah.
Bless your little black heart.
What's up, Supe?
The fire's gonna do
a 180 off the line.
Division Charlie, it's Crew 7.
Go ahead, Crew 7.
Yeah, I think the fire's gonna go
toward homes to the southwest.
What we'd like to do
is take my crew down
to the eastern edge of
the creek and prep for a burn.
Negative. We've got an inbound
hotshot crew to your division.
They'll make the call.
Copy that.
Goddamn it.
How y'all doin'?
Eric Marsh, Crew 7.
My captain, Jesse Steed.
Well, this fire's
gonna shift down here.
I figured you and your crew should go
down and prep that creek for a burn.
I don't mean any disrespect
to you California boys,
but I was... Just been watching
this line for a few days now.
The fire's gonna shift, probably jump over
to that neighborhood right over there.
Okay, let me stop you right
there, okay? Marsh, is it?
Yeah, it's Marsh.
Yeah, well... Um...
You guys are Type 2,
and we are hotshots.
So, why don't you do
what deucers do best,
which is stay in the back
and mop up our shit?
Ladies.
Maricopa County Sheriff's Office!
This is a mandatory evacuation!
Get in, Trevor!
- Hey, Supe.
- Yeah.
You're not gonna like this one.
Smith and Landau are
cutting bait on us.
What? God.
A few slots opened up
on the Blue River Hotshots,
and Ferguson's rolling out
the red carpet.
Well, Blue River's a good crew.
Ferguson's a solid Supe.
They'll probably make double
what we gave 'em.
We could've saved
all these people's homes
- if we ran the play that you called.
- Mmm-hmm.
The boys are pissed.
So am I.
Hey, Sturgill.
Amanda.
Where'd you find this one?
Tweaker lab outside of town.
You arrest the guys that did it?
Didn't need to.
Dipshits blew themselves up
mixing a batch.
Good.
Attaboy.
There you go.
We were gonna put him down,
but then Steinbrink said
we should call you.
So, what do you think?
You're safe now.
I promise.
You're all right.
Lie down.
Good boy. Lie down.
Come on. Lie down.
Who's this?
New friend.
Your friend got a name?
Roscoe.
You're dirty.
You're filthy.
You smell.
So do you.
I've been thinking about inviting
over some ranchers from the area,
showing them the benefits of
having the horses go barefoot.
Maybe I can drum up
some new clients.
I'm pregnant with triplets.
Willie Nelson is the father.
I like Willie Nelson.
Well, that's good.
I'm sorry.
It's just some shit
happened out on the line.
Yeah. Shit always
happens on the line.
You want to talk about it?
Or you want to do
your John Wayne thing?
There's nothing to talk about.
Same problem.
It's just getting worse.
Have you reached out to Duane?
Well,
maybe...
He can help you
get the crew certified.
Hmm.
What?
Why are you so good to me?
Hell if I know.
Bye, have a nice night.
Thank you so much.
Hey.
Yes, it's yours, I'm sure.
Damn.
Uh, all right, how long
have you been pregnant?
Five months.
Five months? Are you serious?
Dude, you're not even gonna tell me,
maybe earlier or something?
Brendan, 'cause I don't
wanna hear it. I don't.
Well, look, I deserve
a say in all this.
Okay, then what
do you wanna say?
I called you, I've...
Say something!
I don't know.
You don't care about me.
You never did.
You broke up with me with a text.
Yeah, I know.
Look, I didn't know.
Yeah, and what if you did?
What would you have done?
Marry me?
All right.
Look, that is part mine, okay?
It is. So...
I'm gonna be responsible for it.
You're not responsible
for anything.
My family and I
have this on our own.
I want you to stay away.
If that's what you want.
Damn.
We catch you doing that shit in here
again and we'll make you choke on it.
Asswipe.
Shit, B.
You okay?
I've been dreaming of this.
The day you bring me
up here to the point.
Oh, God, would you stop?
What the hell are we doing here?
Take a good hard look out there.
What do you see?
Fuel.
Lot of good folks lost
their home down at Cave Creek.
Bitch kicked your ass, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
But had I been able to cut and burn
the lawn, we could've kicked hers.
Tough beat.
We've been training
for over four years.
We've got all our hours,
all our qualifications,
can out-hump any
hotshot crew out there,
but until we're certified, we ain't
nothing but a bunch of deucers.
We can't do anything.
Can't do shit.
Well, I told you
it wouldn't be easy.
Doing something that's never
been done before takes time.
You know I lost two more
good dudes to Blue River?
City council and mayor have got
my ass on the chopping block.
We ain't got any more time.
Neither does our hometown.
Sooner or later, the fire,
she's gonna come a-knockin',
and when she does, this whole place
is gonna go off like a powder keg.
And when she does, my crew won't even
be able to set foot on the line.
Eric, that attitude
that you got right there,
that cost you a lot of friends
in the department.
I don't care.
Friends that could've helped.
Come on, Duane, you're
the Wildland fire chief.
You started this thing.
Well...
I need your help.
Please?
Hey. Now, that's nice.
That's a good start.
Come on, we'll get this thing.
Look, listen, I'm in...
Camp Verde Jail.
And, uh...
Nah, it was just, like, a
misunderstanding, or whatever, honestly.
But the bail's, like,
a grand, so I was...
I was seeing if you
could post that.
Hello?
Mom?
Now, there are two things
that'll make the mayor move.
Sorry, baby.
Fear and greed, right?
Yeah, but until the fire's knocking
at his door, we don't have the fear.
Yeah, once the crew gets certified
as hotshot, then the city,
they can charge 49 bucks
an hour per man
when they're working a fire on
federal or state land, right?
This is bringing money
into Prescott.
Wait, don't they have to get
evaluated so they can get certified?
I'm gonna get them
their evaluation.
Now, if you're willing
to commit your boys
to working more than what the average
hotshot crew covers in a season,
I'm talking about
a lot of overtime, now...
Yeah, it's no problem.
We'll work the full
fire season, no breaks.
I'm so sorry.
You okay?
Yes, thank you.
It's not easy sharing your man
with a fire. I know.
I'm just being a baby.
You know, I don't even know why,
when I went into this
with my eyes wide open.
Doesn't mean you can see
everything that's coming.
It's important to him.
I'll make it work.
Hey. Just one.
Well, at least you don't have kids
and grandkids to worry about.
Right.
...Sunday, 8:00 p.m.
Temperatures 115 to 122...
I don't wanna talk about it.
Yeah? Neither do I, Brendan.
What is this?
I'll be home at 7:00.
When I get back,
I want you gone.
Dude, are you serious?
Dude, what... Oh, my God.
You boys been
beating me off with this scheme
for the last three years, and the city
still hasn't made a damn dime yet.
Huck, you saw the numbers.
This crew, it's a real moneymaker
once they get certified.
Well, when's that gonna be?
As I understand it, they've done all
the time and obligations needed.
This is the first city
to ever start its own crew,
so the Feds see us as outsiders, like a
threat to their way of doing things.
They're trying to put us off
by stalling our evaluation.
That's right.
Look, the people of Prescott
don't understand why they're
paying for their own hotshot crew.
And the city council, well,
they think it's overkill,
like having a SEAL Team Six
do the job of a sheriff.
The Rodeo Fire, it torched the rim above
Payson before they could get on it.
The Indian Fire burned
right up to our doorstep.
It's only a matter of time before
Prescott is gonna be dealing
with a massive wildfire.
That's right.
And when it comes,
the people living here, they're gonna be
thanking their bold, long-sighted mayor
that they've got their very
own SEAL Team Six of hotshots
to put it down quick.
Are the Rusty Pistols gonna
play at the rodeo this year?
Oh! Wouldn't have it
any other way.
Are you gonna ride that big old
mule of yours to the show?
Oh, shit, yeah.
You got to the end of the season to
get yourself evaluated and certified.
And you got next season
to prove your worth.
But it's all on you, Duane.
Appreciate this, Mayor.
You will not regret this, sir.
Well, I hope not.
Now, you boys
keep your powder dry.
Thank you.
Hey, Dave. Good to see you.
That's our mayor.
Hey, Brendan.
Your daughter Michaela was born
six minutes ago. Congrats.
She's totally healthy?
Nothing wrong with
her or nothing?
No, she's perfect.
How's the mom doing?
She's all good.
Now, listen, they're gonna put the
baby in the nursery in a little while
so mom can rest.
I'll come get you, okay?
Yeah. All right.
All right.
Thanks, man.
Yeah.
Wade Scott Parker.
So, your father's a captain
on Chino Valley Fire?
Yes, sir.
Huh.
So I'm assuming you
know the difference
between structure and
wildland fighting operations.
I do.
Um, wildland firefighters,
they dig line,
they cut trees, light
backburns to corral the fire.
They try to control it.
Yep.
We fight fire with fire.
What does the word
"integrity" mean to you?
For shit's sake, Jesse, can we
please get to the good questions?
What? Okay.
When was the last time you lied?
Um, I... I guess
to my mom, this morning.
About what?
I told her that this job isn't as
dangerous as working structure.
Are you lying to me right now?
No, sir.
You a short-timer?
A what, sir?
A firefighter's son
looking to use my crew
as a stepping stone to a gig
on the structure side.
No, sir.
Now, you'd better not be,
'cause if there's one thing
I can't stand, it's that.
Yes, sir.
You got any running gear?
I do, sir. In the car.
All right, we're gonna go for a little
hike in a bit, me and the boys.
Come along, we'll
give you a look-see.
Thank you, sir.
Why are you still here?
Sorry, sir.
I like him.
Ah, nice shot!
One point.
One point for these guys.
♪ Freezing
♪ Rest his head on a pillow
made of concrete
♪ Again
♪ Oh, feelin'
I got it.
♪ Maybe he'll see
a little better
♪ Set of days
♪ Ooh, yeah
♪ Oh, hand out
♪ Faces that he sees
come again ♪
Clown was in my EMT course.
Serious burnout.
What's he doing here?
I don't know.
Let's find out, shall we?
Brian, right?
It's Brendan.
Right.
You were in my EMT class.
What's up? You...
You lost, or...
No, I was just checking.
You know, I heard you guys
had some slots available.
Slots are all filled, man.
Sorry, dude.
All right. Thanks, man.
Yeah.
Hey.
We got one slot open.
You want to interview for it?
Yeah. Right now?
Yeah, right now.
All right.
I'm Eric Marsh,
superintendent of Crew 7.
Brendan McDonough.
When was the last time you used?
Don't think, just
answer the question.
Three months ago.
Ever use needles?
No.
Never.
Do you have your qualifications?
Yeah. Uh...
Wildland fire, fire science,
and just completed my EMT.
You know the difference between
Type 2 crew and Type 1 IHC?
Yes, sir. Hotshots are
on the front line,
and they get to
engage the fire directly.
Good.
You got a record?
Yeah.
- Felony larceny.
- Hmm.
You ever do any time?
Three days.
And I'm on probation right now.
What are you doing here?
I made a lot of
mistakes in my life,
and I've done a lot of things
that I'm ashamed of
and I'm embarrassed by,
honestly, but...
I just had a daughter...
Her name's Michaela
and I just really wanna
give her what I never had.
If you give me a chance,
I won't let you down.
Okay.
All right. The crew's
gonna go on a little hike.
You got any running gear?
Uh... No.
What size shoe do you wear?
Ten.
Hand 'em over.
They're... They're
brand-new, Supe.
Yeah, I don't give a shit.
Hand 'em over.
McDonough!
Come on.
They're... They're
limited edition, sir.
Yeah? Okay.
There you go.
Thanks, man.
Are those limited edition?
Shut up.
What's up with that Brendan kid?
You're not serious
about him, are you?
It's up to him.
This kid's a train wreck.
Mack was in his EMT class,
said he's into dope.
I'm talking hard shit.
What you doing, Supe? We're trying
to get certified as hotshots here.
All you rookies that are
just coming on as slot contenders,
I want you all to breathe in
this beautiful vista.
Breathe it in deeply.
'Cause after you all
get baptized,
you're never gonna be able to look out into
the wilds and see that pure beauty again.
Once you get a real hard taste
of the bitch at work,
there's only one thing
you're gonna be able to see,
and that's fuel.
So think about that.
Meditate on it.
Then decide if this job
is for you.
Line it out!
Come on, guys, line it out.
You think he dropped
dead on the trail?
Definite possibility.
If that shit stain died in my new
kicks, I'm gonna kill him, Supe.
Oh, well.
- Hey, Supe.
- What?
Check it out.
What?
Oh, my Lord.
Uh-huh.
All right.
See you 6:00 a.m., Monday.
You all right?
Yeah.
Yeah? Can you drive?
Okay.
Pound tons of electrolytes, take
some Motrin, get some sleep, buddy.
You'll be all right.
Hey, I got your kicks.
You owe me a hundred bucks.
Duane saw it headed this way.
Thought it looked lost,
too young to be on its own.
She came through here.
Who dumps a young horse
here to die?
Like it was nothing.
Well, we'll find her.
That way.
Let's go.
Ten minutes!
Come on, 10 minutes, shitbirds!
Hey, let's go, Bravo! Let's go, Bravo!
Kick it up, max level!
You don't wanna be buying
Alpha's rounds all night!
Come on!
Norris, pop quiz.
You're cutting a line on a
side hill below the fire.
Debris and logs could start to roll down
and cross your line. What do you do?
Build a cup trench and move the logs
so they're up and down the slope.
There it is. Outstanding.
Hey, McDonough, pop quiz.
What's your 11th watch-out?
No, don't look at him. Look at me.
The fire line you're cutting
hasn't been anchored.
Wrong.
That's the 8th.
You're getting
spot fires across...
That's 16th!
Alpha Squad, hold!
What's your 11th watch-out?
Unburned fuel
between you and the fire.
Firefighters died for us so we
could learn all these watch-outs.
If you get another one wrong,
I will choke you out.
Yes, sir.
Alpha Squad,
hundred off the deck. Now!
My bad, guys.
Let's go, Bravo!
Hey, McDipshit,
can you get any more challenged?
You got dick right
since you've been here.
Zero.
Goddamn donut.
McDonut.
I know you're doing this for your
baby girl, but I don't know, dude.
I've heard some shit
about her mama.
You sure that kid's
even yours, bro?
Whoa!
McDonough!
Do it. Throw that punch.
Do it. Come on.
Do it.
Quit on yourself.
Go home. Die.
All right, Bravo,
get back to work!
That was way out of line, Mack.
I don't mind you sweating the rooks,
but you don't bring in family.
You hear me?
Crew 7,
keep it moving, keep it moving!
Deploy! Deploy!
Deploy!
Rookies on the inside!
Flames over that way!
Feet to the flames,
feet to the flames!
Go, go, go!
Bottles and radios
in the shelter!
Let's go, let's go! Move!
Get rid of your tools!
Go, go, go! Hurry it up!
Boys, let's go, let's go!
Come on, speed it up!
Fire's chasing us!
Move it, rookie, come on!
Go, go, go, go!
Seven, six...
Everybody in!
Five, four, three, two, one!
All right, listen up.
Burnover is seconds away,
and it sounds like a hundred freight
trains right on top of you.
The wind ripping
like a hurricane,
heat coming on
1,000 plus degrees.
It's the apocalypse.
And remember,
stay locked down, bury your
face in that cool dirt,
'cause as long as you can
breathe, you can survive.
When this thing
finally sweeps over you,
it's gonna feel like
the end of the world.
No matter what you hear,
no matter what's going on...
What the...
Who's in there?
Rose. Rose.
Is that your sock
next to your shelter?
What?
That's Rosie's
beat-off sock, sir.
I asked you a question.
No, it's definitely not my sock, sir.
I don't...
Then why is your name
written on it?
'Cause it's his sock, sir.
Mack, out of the shelter!
I don't wanna come out, Steed.
I don't blame you.
Get out of the shelter, MacKenzie!
Come on, California boy!
Come on up!
Stand up.
You're such an asshole.
Do you think this is funny?
I wear anklets.
Ankle socks.
Is he a joke to you?
Yeah.
Hi, this is Marsh.
What's up?
Just running a deployment drill.
What you got?
New start in the
Chiricahua Mountains.
Ate up 9,000 acres
since yesterday.
They ordered up
a Type 2 ICS team.
So, mount up.
This is it, Eric, game time.
What do you mean?
I called in a favor
with an IC that owes me.
Hayes.
You're being evaluated.
I'll hit you with the details.
Good luck.
Okay, got it.
I feel like your mother.
You're my second-favorite son.
All right, gather up!
Got some news.
We're heading to
a fire down south.
And we're getting
our eval on it.
Settle down, settle down.
Remember, when we do this,
act like we've done it before.
Hey, Ryder.
Hey, I'm sorry I'm missing
your birthday again, buster.
But you know what?
We're having a second party
when I get back.
It's gonna be even better, okay?
"Good night, stars.
Good night, air.
"Good night, noises everywhere."
When I come home a hotshot,
what are you gonna do?
Babe, babe, I just...
I just need a little motivation.
I mean, give me something deep,
give me something nasty to think about.
Ooh, I like it. Mmm.
You got to go?
Okay.
Okay, bye.
Donut.
Rookie.
My girl, Cheyanne.
Nice.
Nice?
I mean, that is a world-beating
piece of ass right there.
Look at those superstar
titties of hers.
I mean, if we get certified as hotshots,
she's gonna do things to me.
Do you understand?
Hey, bring it in.
Bring it in.
Come on, just nice and tight.
I hope you do understand,
because we've been working to get this
eval for over four years now, bro.
And a lot can happen to a little
puke like you out on the line.
And if you do anything, I mean anything,
to mess our shit up,
something's definitely
gonna happen to you.
Okay, good chat.
Look at you, looking like a cat
eating shit out of a hairbrush.
This is it, Papa.
We're gonna crush this eval.
Yeah, let's just do what we do.
Weather's working
against us right now.
Wind's gusting to 20
and the humidity is dropping.
Fire's got two heads
at the moment.
Hotshot crews in Division Echo will
look at cutting direct line here.
Division Alpha will build
an indirect line here.
Now, that line
is our trigger point.
If the fire crosses it, we'll look
at evacuating the city of Portal,
five miles to the northeast.
Good luck. Be careful.
Are you Marsh?
Yes, sir, Eric Marsh, Crew 7.
Hayes.
Oh, pleasure, sir.
- My captain, Jesse Steed.
- Nice to meet you.
All right. So,
what are we doing?
Oh, well, it looks like
we're in Division Alpha.
We're gonna cut a line along the
base of this hill right there.
Yeah, there's no direct access
there, so we'll helo in, spike out.
All right, well,
let's see what you boys got.
Whoa!
Hey, don't puke, you pukes.
All right.
Bravo Squad!
Bravo Squad,
watch that slope there!
Jesse, where you at?
Scouting two ridges over.
Got brands coming in, spot fires.
Nothing crazy, but she's
definitely headed our way.
All right, why don't you work
your way back down to the crew?
I'm gonna go scout ahead.
Copy that.
You got a high-speed,
low-drag crew,
but how long can you
run them at that pace?
Well, as long as it takes.
Bad cut!
Tree coming down!
- Falling!
Division Alpha, this is Crew 7.
You got a spot
weather forecast for me?
We have a storm
cell kicking up from the south.
High wind advisory.
25 to 30 miles per hour.
All right, copy that.
Thank you.
Want a piece of my Carolina ass?
Come and get it.
Fire's making a run
toward our line.
By the time she gets here, she's
gonna be too strong to hold.
It's gonna crown that ridge, spot
over, and run straight into town.
If we backburn
this side of the mountain,
by the time bitch comes over,
she'll have no fuel to feed into.
That's a god-awful idea.
All the conditions
favor the fire,
and when that blaze
comes down that mountain,
it's gonna kick your ass and use
your burn to get even stronger.
We won't be able to stop it.
Okay, well, our line's not gonna
hold unless we burn it off.
But it'll slow it down,
maybe give us a chance to
get other resources up here.
Okay, what you don't
understand, sir...
Well, what you don't
understand is 40 years, son.
I was on the job when you
were still shitting yellow.
So, if you think you're gonna
make a big move and impress me,
I'm telling you
right now, don't.
Due respect,
you're just an observer.
So let us do our job, okay?
- No, you're not a...
- No, no, step off!
Now. Step off.
Damn.
What's y'all's comfort level?
Are you down for the cause?
Let's get after it, then.
Get some.
Boss.
Division Alpha, this is Crew 7.
Is that a rosary?
No, prayer beads.
Buddhist, huh?
Well, this thing goes sideways,
nothing's gonna save you.
Not even Buddha.
Holy shit, dude.
Can't believe we're about to light
up a couple thousand acres.
Chill, bro, this is what we do.
Once you light that fuse, you throw
it deep into the fire, all right?
Yeah, cool.
Mack, Steed.
Putting fuel on the ground now.
Make sure you stay ahead of us.
Copy that.
Here we go.
Nice. All right, uno más.
Hey, you all right?
Shit.
Dude, shit, go.
Bees, man.
Bro, run. Bro, go.
Go! Go!
Run! Bees! Bees, man!
Oh, shit!
They're stinging my balls!
Who said that?
Oh, dude, karma's a
bitch, ain't it, Mack?
Rose.
What?
That went in my asshole.
Jesus.
You ever read the Bible?
Yeah. I mean,
not like you, but...
Yeah, it's good.
Well, that worked.
No matter what Hayes thinks.
Mmm-hmm.
Get some sleep, Papa.
It's for my boy, Ryder.
I bring him home a rock...
Snag!
Shit!
Holy shit!
Everybody okay?
- Yeah!
- Yeah, we're okay.
All right, keep it moving!
Thanks, man.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- What?
- Where's your chinstrap?
- My what?
- Your chinny!
- You can't fly without a strap, Donut!
Shit, I don't know.
I just had it, man.
Hey, we got to run.
I got no time for this.
Mack, set him up!
Donut!
Hey!
I think this is yours!
Hey.
However this shakes out,
just know we saved all that.
Jesse. Jesse, what...
What happened?
Hey, hey, settle down,
Manda-bear. It's me.
Oh, Jesus Christ, Eric.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to scare you.
I got my phone
smashed up this morning.
So, you're on your way back?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
How'd it go?
I think I really messed up.
What do you mean?
What happened?
I called a play out on the line, and
I know it was the right thing to do
and I'd do it again,
but I think it's gonna cost us
our certification.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah.
Well...
I peed in my pants today.
You...
You what?
I peed in my pants.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I was working with a colt
over at Sam Lapeer's ranch,
and I had to go really bad,
and the colt just reared up
and came down hard on my foot.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I'm fine except I
peed in my pants.
- Did anybody see it?
- Everyone.
They did?
I felt like a jerk.
And then I had to borrow pants
from Sam just to get home.
Oh...
You know how much I love you?
Go back to sleep.
I'll see you in a little while, okay?
Okay.
Thank you for that.
See you soon.
- Night.
- Night-night.
This is Marsh.
Hey, Eric,
how did it go on the eval?
Did you find out?
Do you know if you're good?
- Dale.
- What?
- I... I can't talk right now, Dale.
God.
Where is he?
Office.
Hey... Oh.
Come in.
God.
What the hell
happened out there?
I did what I thought was right.
And the boys, man,
were they a sight to see.
I've never been so proud.
Deploy.
I mean it. Deploy now!
Let's go, boys!
Move, move, move!
Fire's that way!
Come on, let's show
him how it's done.
Hey, make some space, Rosie.
Come on, man.
Face to the floor!
Twenty bucks I beat you, Mack.
Mack, what are you
doing? Hurry!
Five, four, three...
Come on, get down, get down!
Two, one.
Thirty-two seconds.
That's very, very good.
I know you boys had a
rough go of it out there,
but if you're looking
for sympathy,
the only place you're gonna
find it is in the dictionary,
somewhere between
"shit" and "syphilis."
All right, come on out.
Here's the deal.
I spoke with Hayes.
He thinks your Supe here
is a real cocky sucker,
but he thinks you all are one of the
best damn crews he's ever seen.
Congratulations.
You're hotshots.
- Nice!
- Hell, yeah!
Hotshots!
Sweet!
Ah, Woyjeck!
All right, hey.
We... We need a name.
How about Thumb Butte Hotshots?
Boo!
I got it, I got it, I got it.
The Firelords.
No.
Why not?
That's the name
of your band, bro.
Yeah, and we slay.
Yeah, you slay,
in your mama's garage.
Granite Mountain.
Yeah.
Granite Mountain Hotshots.
There it is!
Yeah.
There it is.
Hey.
I appreciate you
making the effort.
Leaving the stuff.
Yeah, yeah. It's no problem.
Wow.
Wow, you look...
Yeah, I know, I'm pretty filthy.
We were just...
We were doing a fire down south.
Chiricahua.
Yeah, I heard that
you were working for Crew 7.
Yeah, actually, we just...
We just got certified today as hotshots,
so we're the
Granite Mountain Hotshots.
That's amazing. Congrats.
- She's so pretty.
- Yeah.
Do you wanna hold her?
Nah, I'm...
You know, I'm so dirty.
I don't wanna mess up her clothes.
It's okay, really. It's fine.
Here. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'd love...
Yeah, please.
Ooh, a little gas.
She's so pretty.
Yeah.
She looks like you.
Nat...
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You ladies better listen up
and listen good.
If there's one thing I know,
it's applesauce.
Go ahead and try that, darling.
Okay.
That's right.
Mmm.
That's right. Yes, it is.
That is good applesauce.
Best dang applesauce
you ever had.
Okay, it was cute at first.
Now I just wanna scream.
Is that yours and that's him?
- That's both.
- That was...
And who's that? Is that his?
This is the one we lost.
That's yours. Okay, keep that
away from the kid. Make sure.
I'm gonna get some water.
What? Okay.
Smoking is over for you.
It's over.
Sound familiar?
You got that...
Stay still, stay still.
Wait a minute. I'll wipe...
I'll wipe that off for you.
You must be Brendan.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm Amanda, Eric's wife.
Oh, so nice to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
How's it going?
It's good.
Yeah?
Yeah. I...
You know, I really
appreciate the opportunity.
And...
I really respect
your husband a lot.
So, I hope to be
more like him someday.
You guys have more in common
than you think.
Hang in there.
Thanks.
Where are you taking me?
I want to show you something.
All right.
What?
For me?
You gonna take care of this one?
Yeah.
God.
- What's up, Mack?
- What up?
Everything all right?
No, dude, far from it.
Anything you wanna talk about?
Um... You remember
my gal Cheyanne, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, well, I came home
and found the slut
had been cheating on me.
- Right?
- Really?
But you know what the kicker is?
The kicker is she's banging
some dude on Flagstaff PD.
Yeah.
I mean, whatever, you know.
Whatever.
I mean, what I got to find
is a new place, 'cause I moved out
of our apartment into my car.
Bitch.
I mean, hey,
I got an extra room.
Seriously?
Yeah.
You know, if you need a...
Spot to crash for a little bit.
Right on, dude.
Man, I just got to kick out my
buddy from the Flagstaff PD.
He...
Oh, funny guy.
Yeah, his name...
His name's... His name's Dave.
Man, I'll tell you,
as true as I'm standing here
and as strange as this is,
I'm happy.
I'm happy and
grateful to everyone,
the families, my crew,
Duane, Amanda.
You know, Granite Mountain
is the first municipal hotshot
crew in this entire country.
Can you believe that?
That's saying something.
I'm not gonna sugarcoat it,
this first season as hotshots
is gonna be tough.
We're gonna be traveling
all over the country.
We're gonna be working harder,
going longer,
so it's important that this Granite
Mountain family pulls together
and looks out for each other.
'Cause we can't do this
without your support.
That's right.
Esse quam videri.
"To be, rather than to seem."
And everybody here
has lived up to this creed.
No Supe could be prouder,
right now, of his boys
than I am of you guys.
So, to commemorate
this occasion,
I had some tees made up.
All right?
Now, you can only wear them
if you're a hotshot.
Right?
Okay, so it's sleeping
with a hotshot, too, okay?
There you go.
Oh!
There she is, little Michaela.
You want to show Mack your dog?
Your dad and
Uncle Mack are stoked
you're having your
first sleepover with us.
She's got a puppy...
Dude, what did you do?
I, uh,
baby-proofed everything,
like the bathroom cabinets,
the kitchen, the whole house, basically.
So, we're good.
That's awesome, man.
Thank you.
Aw, why not?
She loves this dog, man.
Yeah.
Family, bro.
Let's get the bunny, huh?
You like the bunny.
Yeah, he's a friend.
Hello.
Dude, what took you so long?
She's, like,
she's really hot, man.
How's she doing?
She's, like, burning up.
Oh, God.
I know. I know. It's okay.
This is your friend.
She's your friend.
Hey, bro. The other way.
Okay.
The other end. No.
This?
What?
One hundred and three
point four! Dude!
No bueno, man.
Call a pediatrician, man.
I called him like five times.
He's not picking up.
What do you mean,
he hasn't picked up?
I don't know, he's
being an asshole!
We gotta go to the hospital.
Yeah, right, man.
It's my first night alone with her.
Natalie will never let me see her again.
Yeah, you're right.
Turbyfill! His wife, Stephanie!
I think she's a nurse.
Hey, how's she doing?
Her temperature's coming down.
Her coloring's good. She's fine.
Yeah, she's good?
Infants burn high fevers sometimes.
It's totally normal. Yeah.
All right. Good. Thank you.
Yeah, I didn't know that's
how you took a temperature.
All right, men. I
think we're good.
Whew!
She's, uh...
Yeah, she's happy, so...
Good, man.
Yeah.
I really appreciate
you guys coming by.
Ah...
It's what we're here for, bro.
Man, like, I've been through
some pretty crazy, intense shit,
but that was, hands down,
the scariest thing of my life.
Seriously.
Welcome to fatherhood, dude.
Yeah, I'm gonna pump
the brakes on having kids.
Just the thought of fire
season starting makes me lonely.
Well, once this crew proves
itself this first season,
we'll be able to
slow down a little bit.
You know, the other wives,
they always say,
"At least you don't have kids.
It's so much harder with kids."
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
It's starting to
get under my skin.
Really? Why?
'Cause those kids give them
something to hold onto and love.
No matter what.
You know what?
What?
If I could put you in my pocket,
- I'd take you wherever I go.
- Yeah...
- I would.
- Don't do that.
Don't do what?
I want to talk about it.
Well, okay, what?
Kids?
Us.
Having a family.
Look, we had an understanding
when we got married.
And you agreed to it.
Yeah, I know, I agreed.
I guess I never felt like I was
worthy of being a mother before.
Yeah, but what makes you feel
like we're worthy now?
Shit. Look, I didn't mean
that you're not...
Amanda, I'm sorry,
but my feelings about this
still haven't changed.
Yeah.
I thought we'd already...
The fire's
crowning along Jericho Road,
running north.
We're gonna get in front,
try to box her off and drive
her toward the canyon.
Copy, Granite Mountain.
We have a heavy air tanker
working in that area.
Assholes waited too long
to get a handle on this.
♪ I'm the one
♪ You people make me do it
♪ Now it's time for your fate
♪ And I won't hesitate
♪ There's a job to be done,
and I'm the one
♪ So come on
♪ Jump in the fire
♪ Come on... ♪
All right, guys.
First order of business,
I want to protect this
structure, and then we're gonna
cut a line 30 feet off
the road, all right?
Hey, we're flying solo on this
one, so let's stay on point.
- Understood?
- You got it, Supe!
Shit, he doesn't know
we're here, man.
Take cover! Take cover!
Holy shit!
Whew!
So much for
protecting that structure.
- Y'all okay? Yeah?
- Everyone all right?
- Fine.
- Yeah.
All right, gear up.
Get to work.
Come on, let's go. Damn.
I'm heading out!
Why don't you have Marvel
set up the spare room for you?
Drive home in the morning.
Come on, it's a long drive
back to your place.
Thanks, Duane. I can't.
I got that big talk
at the ranch in the morning.
So, got to go back
and get ready.
Yeah, I'm sending some
people over to listen.
I'd appreciate that.
Could use some new clients.
Ah, you'll get 'em.
All we're doing
is lacing together this fuel.
Just slow strokes,
back and forth.
Wide spread.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
- You sure? All right.
I'll light you up.
Our last chain, all right?
I'll be up the slope.
Hey, Supe! My torch!
Shit.
What happened?
Hey, Supe?
I just tossed it.
It was freaking out.
It's all right.
It was a bad mix.
Steed, we're on our way out!
Hold off on the burners!
Copy that.
Come on!
Come on.
Whew!
Holy shit!
Yeah!
That's an 8.5.
No way.
The last one was better.
Oh, here she comes.
Yeah!
That's another one!
Shit!
Hey.
Hey, Supe, I just want to thank
you for pulling me out earlier.
It was definitely an ass-puckerer,
wasn't it?
No doubt, man.
I thought I was done.
If this ain't the greatest
job in the world,
I don't know what is.
You got that right, Supe.
Wait for it. Wait for it.
That's a 10!
Yeah!
That's a 10.
♪ Hello, my friend
♪ Can't sleep again
♪ Got too much on
♪ My mind... ♪
All right, thanks for the ride.
You need anything,
give me a call.
Yeah.
All right.
Confining a horse to a stall
or a small paddock
inhibits blood flow,
and it damages receptors
in the hoof capsule.
Horses are designed
for movement.
Depending on the damage,
I recommend a two-to-three-month
transition period.
Thanks for coming!
Later!
Why didn't you call me?
Why do I have to find out
from Duane,
who found out
from a goddamn EMT?
Thought you were
out on the line.
Didn't want to worry you.
Mmm-hmm.
And I was fine. I am fine.
You're not...
Look at your face, your wrist.
- Look at the damn truck!
- No, no, no!
Wait a minute!
You don't get to do this, okay?
I've had to learn how to live
my life without needing you,
and now you're pissed
at me because of it?
Screw that! You don't get
to have it both ways!
Hey, sweetie, come here.
Oh, no.
It's okay.
Daddy can't get
a kiss from you? No?
Brendan, she's barely seen you
for the past few months.
Yeah, I know. It's been
a really tough season,
and I'm, like, doing the best I can.
You know?
I know, but she doesn't
understand that.
You're doing great.
Young kids just
need consistency.
Yay!
Who's a big girl?
Yeah, she is.
Look at you. What?
What is that?
All right, we got a new
start-up by Granite Mountain.
We're looking at the Doce Fire.
Started up 8 miles
southwest of town.
- Kicked up big last night.
- How big?
Over 1,000 acres burned already.
Burned through dry brush
straight towards town.
We got a Red Flag Warning
in effect,
40 mile-per-hour wind gusts
and a relative humidity
as low as 3%.
- A real ass-kicker.
- Hell, yeah.
Two days off, right
back at it, boys.
Hey, guys, listen up.
The state has ordered
a management team.
IC has asked me to head up
Division Bravo,
so Steed is your Supe
on this next one.
Nice one. Yeah, Steed!
We got six
hotshot crews coming in.
What's our deal?
Well, no one knows this area
better than we do,
and that's why I'm giving
you guys a special assignment.
Fire's threatening Prescott,
and we get stuck on
some chicken-shit detail
- to protect a tree?
- Ah, it's lame, man.
Lame-ass tree is a national treasure.
It's over 2,000 years old.
But more importantly,
that tree is on our line.
If the fire gets past our line,
it goes to our town.
Quit your bitching, Turby.
All right, well,
now I feel like an asshole.
You are.
Damn.
- Now, that's a tree.
- That's something.
That is definitely a tree.
Wow.
I thought
it was gonna be bigger.
All right.
Let's prep 30 feet around her
and burn her off.
All right.
Come on, let's go to work!
Let's go, Alpha!
All right, let's move!
That's right, Donut.
Next tree, let's go.
Hey, Donut,
grab this other tree.
National treasure.
Take more, guys.
Take more.
Good job, Bravo.
Hey, tie it in and let's go.
Keep the line tight, move.
This is our front door
she's knocking on.
- Come on, move.
- Yeah, let's go.
Let's get this nice, man.
Here she comes.
Spot fire! One scrape!
Hey, I've got a spot!
I need two! Let's go!
Now that's what I call a line!
All right, guys,
let's mop it up!
All right, Alpha!
Get it on!
- Let's go!
- Nice work!
- You heard him!
- Nice.
Little Woyjeck!
Bravo, let's go, with me!
That's you, bro.
Hey, nice work, nice work.
Let's get something to drink.
Bottoms up.
Move up the hill
and mop it up up here.
Alpha boys, let's go!
- Ready?
- Here we go.
Hey, you're stepping
on my asshole.
- Come on.
- Tight.
Granite Mountain on two.
One, two...
Granite Mountain!
Hey, man, how are
things with our little girl?
It's rough, man.
I mean, when we came back
from that last fire,
it's like she didn't
even recognize me.
But Steed and Turby
seem to have it figured out.
You know, whatever that is,
I want a piece of it.
Oh! Dude!
- Shit.
- What?
Ah, dude.
Oh, that's a rattler.
No way did that
just happen, man.
Where was your crew
working when you got bit?
We were cutting line around an
old tree near Granite Mountain.
The big juniper?
Yes, ma'am.
My husband proposed to
me under that tree.
Describe the pain, one to 10.
It's pretty bad.
It's, like, moving
up my leg right now.
So, Brendan, we're gonna
move you to another bed here.
Gonna need you just to relax,
let us do the lifting, okay?
Sir, I'm sorry, who are you?
I'm Eric Marsh, Granite
Mountain Superintendent.
Hey, Donut, how you doing?
I don't know. Ask them.
Vitals look good, stable.
You give him antivenom?
No, and I'd rather not.
Why?
I would like to save that
bullet for when you really need it.
Antibiotics and a morphine
drip will do the trick.
No, I don't want any morphine.
No painkillers, either.
The ride's gonna be
a lot rougher without them.
Are you sure about that?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Hey, Donut,
what's your fifth watch-out?
Uninformed on strategy,
tactics and hazards.
There it is.
You're gonna be fine.
I got to get back to ICP, okay?
I'll see you on the other side.
Hang in there.
Don't you worry about your boy.
We'll take good care of him.
You all are heroes.
Hang in there.
See you, Supe.
Mack.
Bro.
Yeah, man.
You got to go.
You smell like shit
and you keep snoring so loud.
- Am I?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Are you good?
Yeah, I'm good.
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean, I love you,
but you also smell pretty bad.
I get it.
- I'm glad you're good, bro.
- Yeah.
I appreciate you coming.
Oh, shit.
Before I forget...
A little keepsake
right there, man.
Whoa, dude!
We hunted that bastard
for 45 minutes, bro.
That's good luck.
- It's good luck.
- Yeah, it's good luck.
- It is.
- You take it, then.
Okay, really?
I mean, you can't
let a brother get bit
and let him tell
the story, you know?
Nora, this is, uh...
- This is my good buddy, Mack.
- Hi.
- How you doing? Pleasure.
- Nice to meet you.
You, too.
Hey, okay, you need to put that
away 'cause your family's here.
Okay.
- That's your nurse?
- Yeah.
Dude, she's actually, like,
really cool and smart.
- Really?
- Yeah, went to college somewhere good.
What?
I know. I picked her for you.
Thank you.
I know your type.
Yeah, you do.
Hello, family.
Hey.
Hi.
- Hi. How are you?
- Good.
- Sweetie.
- Look who's here.
Thought you could
use some huggies.
- And some kissies.
- I could.
Daddy get kissy?
Mwah.
- Yeah.
- Sweetie.
I missed you so much.
How you feeling?
Uh, I'm feeling all right.
Yeah, he's gonna be okay.
What'd she say?
I think she's hungry.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
We'll go get a bite,
and then we'll come back.
Okay. All right, I'll be here.
- Okay.
- Aw.
- Bye.
- Yeah. See you in a few.
I love you.
Daddy loves you.
See you later.
Look at this.
Made the papers.
Oh, wow.
Front page, huh?
Man.
The whole
town's talking about it.
You know, Brendan,
there are lots of other things
you could do
that aren't as dangerous.
Your daughter needs you.
Yeah, I know.
♪ An old cowpoke went riding
out one dark and windy day
♪ Upon a ridge he rested
as he went along his way...
Hey, guys.
Hey, Mack.
Gentlemen.
Yeah, don't kick my ass tonight.
Have a good night.
♪ Their brands
were still on fire
♪ And their hooves
were made of steel
♪ Their horns were
black and shiny
♪ And their hot breath
he could feel...
He's alive!
Donut!
Welcome back!
He's alive!
There he is.
Hey, Donut!
Hey, you want a drink, man?
Hey, it's all on the house.
You're a huge pussy, man,
you're huge, but I love you.
Hey, Donut, come on.
Come on, show it to us.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Show it to us.
Show us the wound.
It's all bandaged.
- What?
- Don't be afraid.
No, it's all bandaged.
- Oh, shit!
- Oh!
Hold him down, hold him down!
Get it. Hold him down.
Show it.
- Just show it.
- It's okay.
- I'm a doctor.
- No, you're not.
Look at this.
All right, all right.
One, two, three!
♪ Ghost riders in the sky ♪
Hey, hey.
I love you, brother.
Glad you're back, Donut.
Let's have another big hand
for Duane Steinbrink
and the Rusty Pistols!
I just wanted to
take this opportunity
to extend a heartfelt
Prescott thanks
to our very own
Granite Mountain Hotshots.
Yeah!
Now, I believed in you guys
from the very beginning,
- and I'm so gratified...
- Bullshit!
To see that gamble pay off
for the old juniper
and the citizens of
Prescott, Arizona.
Come here, you fine thing.
Kenny, a shot of whiskey
and a beer, please.
You got it.
Hey.
- Why, hello.
- Hello.
How you doing?
You're Mack, right?
I am Mack.
Have we met?
No.
What's up?
It just says your name on the
sock stuck to your back.
Are you serious?
You've got some great friends.
- What?
- What, man?
We made it for you special.
Yeah, man.
- Yeah!
- Oh!
Hey, Supe.
Hey, buddy, how's
your leg feeling?
It's good.
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Good, good.
Hey, Amanda.
Hey, Brendan.
Hey, I was wondering if I could
talk to you outside for a sec.
Yeah. Right now?
Yeah.
♪ Now Daddy ran the whiskey
in a big black Dodge...
You're looking about as anxious as
a cat about to shit a peach pit.
No, man, I just wanted to...
You know, I wanted
to talk to you for a sec.
What? About what?
Well, I wanted to thank you for
everything that you've done.
I didn't do anything.
All good.
No, you took a big chance on me.
I know that.
Oh, the world's full of people
taking chances, Donut.
Jesus, Supe, why can't you
just say, "You're welcome"?
'Cause I'm uncomfortable
with gratitude.
I don't like it.
All right, well, too bad.
That's what this is, gratitude.
Okay. All right.
I can live with that, I guess.
Oh, God.
So, we good?
There's something else I do
want to talk to you about.
I've been doing
a lot of thinking,
and after this
fire season's over,
I want to move over
to the structure side.
And I was hoping maybe that you could put
in a good word with Chief Ellis for me.
Okay.
All right.
All right, let me just
see if I got this down.
So, you brought me
out here to thank me
for giving you a chance
that nobody
on the face of the fucking
Earth would give you,
and your way of
showing appreciation is
to then say to me that, what,
you're gonna quit on me
and this crew?
Look, Supe,
I'm having a hard time.
It's tough.
I'm having a hard time being
a good dad and doing this job.
Okay, everybody's having
a hard time
because most of the men
on this crew have families.
And I don't hear any of them
bitching, do you?
Yeah, look, I can't
speak to that, okay?
I don't know. I...
No, you can't.
I didn't have a dad growing up.
He wasn't around
for me, so when...
I'm not gonna do that
to my daughter, man.
- That's it.
- So what?
So what, Donut, huh?
I mean, do you think
anyone's gonna hire
a cheese-dick like you
on the structure side,
an asshole with
a record and a rep?
That's just never gonna happen.
And then what? Huh?
You're gonna be
washing dishes, miserable?
How long you think
you're gonna stay clean then?
Now, listen to me. Listen.
If you quit this crew,
you're gonna either end up
dead or behind bars.
♪ Copperhead Road
Hey, come on, let's go.
Come on.
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
♪ Copperhead Road ♪
- Happens all the time.
- Yeah.
Guys are always leaving crews
because of family.
- Uh-huh.
- Right.
So why are you
so pissed at this kid?
'Cause a year ago he was a
junkie, tonight he's a hero.
Huh.
I mean, come on,
this job saved his life,
and now he'll probably end up
right back where he started.
Well, if you think
that he might relapse,
maybe you should take him
to a meeting with you.
Does he even know
that you go to meetings?
It's nobody's business
but my own.
Okay, so you're pissed
'cause you think
he owes the job something more
than his own daughter.
I didn't say that.
Oh, maybe it's 'cause he made
the choice that you're avoiding.
His thing has nothing
to do with me, okay?
I think it's got
everything to do with it.
No, no. I don't,
I don't want to do this.
Well, you know what?
You've had one day off
in the last month,
which you spent sleeping,
so when are we
supposed to do it?
What? What?
I'll tell you what!
You live your life
in a glass box
with a sign that says,
"Break in case of fire"!
You are 90% hotshot,
you are 10% mine,
and that is not enough!
What is that? Is that an ultimatum?
Is that what that...
No, I'm telling you how I feel,
and that's different.
I want a family
with the man that I love.
You knew exactly what the deal
was when we got into this, okay?
I've been straight with you...
Yeah, fine.
I don't give a shit!
From the first day that we met!
We were in the same place then!
That was six years ago,
and people are supposed to be
changed by their relationships!
That's what happened to me!
I let you in!
I've been changed by you!
I'm a different person!
I have moved on from my
addiction, and you are still
fucking feeding yours
with another kind of drug!
Where are you going?
For a walk!
I didn't know who else to call.
Sit down.
Do you know
where I'm at right now?
Oh, yeah.
I've been there.
I don't know what to do.
Yeah, well,
you got to ask yourself,
"What can I live with
and what can I die without?"
You know what I mean?
No, I don't.
Yeah.
I don't know.
You know, when I was
a Globe Hotshot...
Maybe 26, 27...
I worked this blaze
near Big Timber, Montana.
It was night, and
she just wasn't laying down.
Conditions going
from mean to wicked.
And me and my crew pulled back into
the black of this wide-open grassland
set right at the foot
of this sprawling forest,
just a few thousand acres
of tall, dense pine,
all of it green
and packed with resin.
And all of a sudden,
this savage wind kicked up,
and it carried with it this
tidal wave of brands and fire,
just sweeping through the trees.
And just in the blink
of an eye, the whole stretch
turned into a blast furnace,
just fire everywhere.
And then,
charging out of these flames,
all of a sudden comes this bear.
And the bear's on fire.
And he's running.
And he just barrels
right past us,
and keeps running,
hard-charging into the darkness.
That bear on fire
was the most beautiful and
terrible thing I've ever seen.
I'm feeling a lot like
that bear right now, Duane.
I'm yours.
I'm yours, Manda-bear.
Yeah, this is Marsh.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Hey, Jesse.
We got a new start down in Yarnell.
Lightning strike.
Yeah, go ahead, ring the bell.
We'll see you in a few.
What's up?
Oh, a skunker down in Yarnell.
It's no big deal.
Kiss.
Yes, ma'am.
Hmm.
I love you, Shortstop.
You, too, Sugartits.
Go back to sleep.
I'll probably be
home for dinner.
Not a skunker anymore, Supe.
She's moving fast.
Jesse, this is gonna be
my last year as Supe.
The job is yours if you want it.
Fire's threatening homes
in Peeples Valley,
so we've ordered
three more hotshot crews.
In the meantime,
I want Granite Mountain
to set an anchor here on the
southwest heel of the fire.
Keep it from running at Yarnell
if the weather shifts.
Now, there's a safety zone here
at Boulder Springs Ranch,
fireproof, built of nonflammables.
The vegetation's been cleared.
- Ferguson?
- Yeah.
You and
Blue River will cut here,
east of Marsh's crew, and your
fallback will be this two-track road.
We've established
three trigger points.
First trigger for Yarnell evac
should take an hour.
Second trigger,
all crews retreat.
Third,
no one should be
near Yarnell, okay?
- Come on, keep it tight!
- Tight!
Tight!
Tight.
- Steeder.
- Yo.
Tell me
we're gonna be off this shit
and home by
tomorrow night. Please.
Hope so.
- He's got a big date.
- Yeah? With who?
That barely legal hottie
from the party?
That right? She got a sister?
Look, guys, back off.
He met a girl that he really likes.
No way. Who?
One of the nurses
who took care of me.
She's, like, 27,
gives a great IV.
She's nice.
- So, you closed?
- Like I said, brother.
Not like that.
What, is she playing
hard to get?
More like hard to forget.
Oh, that's, like,
the cutest thing I ever
heard you say, man.
I know, dude.
This girl scares
the shit out of me.
That's good, brother.
That's how you know it's real.
Ah, shit.
Hey, hold up.
- Hold up.
Gonna establish our anchor here.
Alpha down below,
Bravo upstairs.
Not even 10:00 a.m.,
105 and climbing.
Embrace the suck.
Operations,
this is Granite Mountain.
We got clouds forming
above Peeples Valley.
They start to grow, the fire's
gonna get a lot worse real quick.
Our line's ready
to burn right now.
Copy, Granite Mountain.
You got the green light to burn.
All right, copy that.
Tie it in!
Tied in.
Tied in!
All right, Jesse, flip the torches,
get ready for a burn.
Copy.
Back to the anchor!
- Bravo Squad, swap that brush.
- Get ready to burn!
- Let's go, guys!
Uh, hey, Donut.
Come with me for a sec.
Listen, uh...
I'm sorry about last night.
Now, I don't know how to explain,
but sometimes we...
We don't see things as they are.
You know, we see them as we are.
You understand that?
Yeah. Think so.
What happened wasn't about you.
It was about me.
I was you.
I will help you out in any way I
can, so long as you walk the line.
Do you hear me?
Thanks, Supe.
All right.
Light it!
After we burn this off,
we head back down, boys.
Woyjeck, put more fuel down.
Watch for spots.
Burners,
pace off the guy on the line.
Shit!
- God!
- What an idiot!
Air Attack, Granite Mountain!
Your tanker just
dumped on our burn.
Repeat, Granite Mountain.
You're putting out
the wrong damn fires.
Hey, Supe, none of this shit's
gonna light off now.
What's your move?
All right, tie it off here.
Take the line
all the way up the ridge.
Hey, Donut, come here.
How's that leg, buddy?
Think you can handle a lookout?
Yeah.
Good spot right over there.
Just make sure you got
your weather kit handy.
Keep an eye on those clouds.
You got it, Supe.
Heard you on the TAC channel.
- You moving the line?
- Yeah, next hill over.
Goddamn air tanker
really screwed the pooch.
We're moving to a secondary line,
but we'll adjust to you.
You mind taking my lookout,
Donut here, give him a lift?
No. Hop on.
- Cool to hop in the back?
- You got it.
All right.
See you later.
This side or the other, brother.
Later, Donut.
Don't miss me too much.
Get out of here, Donut!
Granite Mountain, line it up!
Thanks, man.
You got it.
Granite Mountain,
stand by for weather.
Yeah, how does it look?
Temp is 104,
RH 6%, so I'll keep
an eye on that.
Wind is 10 to 15 from the south,
and those clouds are building.
Yeah, I see 'em.
Keep an eye on it.
Shit.
Granite Mountain,
winds are changing here.
It's 25 to 35 from the north.
Yeah, we feel it.
What do you see?
Fire's picking up, and it's
moving towards my location.
Okay, time for you
to get out of there, Donut.
It just hit the ridge.
I'm gonna make my way back
towards the dozer.
Copy that, Donut.
All right, hey,
I'm at the dozer.
Copy.
Hey, shit, man, it's too close.
I got to move!
Donut, stay calm.
Follow the two-track road.
That's your escape route.
Hey, my escape route's been...
Granite Mountain,
the fire just hit
the first trigger point
much faster than we expected.
We need to move.
Ops, Granite Mountain.
Dozer and retardant line
have been compromised.
- We're pulling back into the black.
- Copy.
Granite Mountain,
pack it up! Let's go!
Pack it up!
Donut, what's your position?
Come on, Donut, copy me, man.
Hey!
Heard you on the radio.
Boys, I've got your lookout.
Fire's making its push.
We're gonna go back and bump
your buggies.
Copy that. Thanks for
looking out for our boy.
I'm gonna go up top,
take a look up there.
Copy.
Blue River,
can you burn your line off?
Negative. Line is overrun.
- Pulling back to Yarnell.
- Copy.
You get your Supe truck.
We got your buggies.
Let's go.
Granite Mountain, Operations.
What's your position?
Ops, Granite Mountain.
- Still holding in the black.
- Copy that.
Hey, so, uh...
Next Thursday,
my band's playing.
- Ooh, yeah, sorry, got a thing.
- Don't...
With your immediate
negativity, okay?
We're not coming, dude.
- Why not?
- Because the Firelords suck ass, man. They're terrible.
We're not the
Firelords anymore, okay?
- We changed it.
- Yeah?
- To what?
- Hour of the Wolf.
Still suck.
If it was the other way around,
I'd be there supporting each of you guys.
Oh, boo!
Fine, fine.
Brewskies are on me.
- Yeah!
- Oh!
Suddenly we're free.
Air Attack, Operations.
Where are those
heavy air tankers?
They're inbound,
but still 10 minutes out.
Come on, knock it out, man!
Granite Mountain,
can you redeploy to Yarnell?
The fire's advancing
on trigger point two.
How long is he gonna
keep us safe in the black?
I mean it, Jesse,
I don't want to stand around
like a worthless piece of shit
while this town burns.
Easy, brother.
None of us do.
Steeder.
What's the plan here?
Well,
they're not doing anything to
slow you down at all, are they?
Air Attack, Granite Mountain. What's
the status on the air tankers?
Granite Mountain,
air tankers have been delayed.
We got homes burning in Yarnell,
and base camp's being pushed.
Jesse, I think we should move on
to our escape route,
head down to the ranch
and work the fire from there.
We're the only crew in
position to save these homes.
You and the boys down
for getting back in the game?
You guys hear that?
Let's go to work, Supe.
All right, back to work, boys.
Back to work.
Come on, man,
this is what we were born to do.
Let's break a sweat, boys.
Let's get it!
- What?
- Let's put this bad boy out.
Let's go, Ashcraft!
Ops, Granite Mountain.
I want to pass on that we're gonna
make our way toward our escape route.
You guys
are in the black, correct?
Yep. We're gonna pick our way
through the black,
and then on toward the ranch.
Copy that.
Donut, fire just hit trigger
point two. We're pulling back
to the restaurant.
Copy, Blue River.
Ops, Granite Mountain.
We're going down our escape
route to our safety zone.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
We're just moving.
Copy.
Steed, you with me?
Yeah, we're with you.
Coming off the black and into the canyon.
I'm almost at the ranch.
Looks good.
Be able to reengage
the fire from there.
All right, guys.
Keep the pace and watch your footing.
Watch your footing.
Come on through.
You, too. Let's go.
Hey, how can I help?
Just wait here with my crew.
I'm gonna check in
with Operations to get orders.
All right.
Hey, thanks for picking me up.
I owe you one.
Just sit tight, all right?
Air Attack, Operations.
We've got a storm cell
that's developed to the north
with heavy wind gusts
toward the southwest.
Fire has just hit
trigger point three.
It's making a run.
I copy, yeah.
We're getting 50-mile-an-hour wind gusts here.
Oh...
Hey, Supe!
Prepare deployment
site right here. Now!
We can't go back up there.
There's no time, Jesse.
Deployment site! Right here, right now!
Let's go!
Deployment site!
Breaking in on Arizona 16!
Granite Mountain Hotshots!
We are in front
of the flaming front!
Burning!
Burn around the perimeter!
Ashcraft, next tree!
Granite Mountain, we're
gonna bring you the air tanker, okay?
You got it! That's exactly
where we want the drop!
Operations, Air Attack.
Do you have a firm location
on Granite Mountain?
Air Attack, Granite Mountain.
How do you read me?
Air Attack, Granite Mountain!
Drop!
Air Attack, Granite Mountain.
Okay,
Granite Mountain. Air Attack.
Okay, I'm here with
Granite Mountain Hotshots,
and our escape route
has been cut off.
Come on, man.
We are preparing
a deployment site.
We are burning out
around ourselves...
In the brush.
And I'll call you
when we're under our...
The shelters.
Okay, copy that.
So, you're on the south side
of the fire, then?
Affirm!
Deploy!
Get your feet to the fire!
Water! Get your water!
Feet to the fire!
Rookies on the inside!
Jesse!
What?
You, too!
Oh, God. God, help me.
Mack?
It's gonna be okay!
Okay. Okay.
Granite Mountain, Operations.
Now, I need you
to pay attention.
And tell me when
you hear the aircraft, okay?
'Cause it's gonna be a little
tough for us to see you.
Okay, we're working
our way around there.
We've got several aircraft
coming to you.
I'll see if we can't
take care of business for you.
Granite Mountain,
do you hear a helicopter?
I got eyes! I got eyes!
Operations.
Yeah, go ahead.
Uh, medic on scene.
Nineteen, confirmed.
Okay, I copy.
Let's go ahead
and obviously secure the area.
We'll go from there.
No, no, no, no!
Bringing all the families
over to Prescott Middle School.
Setting up a whole thing
for the fallout.
That's where I want to go.
I don't think that's a
good idea, Brendan.
Let me just take you
to your mom's.
Take me to the gym.
- Yeah?
- Duane,
I just talked to the sheriff.
He's saying 19.
You're sure?
I'm afraid so.
But he told me that
one of them got out okay.
Is that confirmed?
I don't know.
I'm so sorry, Duane.
I know.
Thank you, Kathy.
Duane.
It's just not good.
Oh, no. No.
Duane.
Duane, what's going on?
- Are they okay?
- I'm gonna find out right now.
Please, just hold on.
Huck, what's going on?
What did you tell these people?
Nothing.
We can't tell them until
the grief counselors get here.
- Well, how long?
- Twenty minutes.
They're driving in from Phoenix.
We heard there was
one survivor. Is that true?
Would you please tell me if
my husband is alive or dead?
Okay, hold on, now.
Brendan, come on.
Let me get you home.
Brendan.
Brendan!
- Should have been me.
- No.
Yeah, he was better than me.
- They were all better than me.
- No. Shh!
Don't say that.
Look at me. Look at me!
Don't you dare do this!
We can't do that.
Do you understand?
I'm glad that
you're alive, Brendan.
Eric is, too.
Ready? Whoa!
♪ If it wasn't known
♪ That our love will carry on
♪ I will be the wind
♪ That echoes on the canyon wall
♪ We never say good-bye
♪ Just let me hold the light
♪ If you walk the ridge
♪ You will find
the marks, the scars
♪ Kneel down by the tree
♪ Under the setting star
♪ We never say good-bye
♪ Just let me hold the light
♪ I'll see you on this side
♪ Or the other where
♪ The desert sun kisses the sky
♪ Baby, hold the light
♪ And keep it in your eyes
♪ And promise that
you'll dream of me
♪ Beyond the walls of time
♪ In the end, we lay beside
♪ Just look up at the light