In new delhi and wise man
thinks to otherwise man..
That every war don't took
place on border.
They teach that its not cleverness
to sit at home but kill them in their house.
Had been many meetings,
and after wasting tax payers money..
It was decided to test for elite programe
I'm incharge of this programe.
12 people were selected
from enforcement.
If they'd ever gets coughts.
Means two things.
their courty will deny to accept them.
And secondly they're only bank
account number for their government.
We were on test run for 5 years.
Therefore we kept our
black army name baby
in 4 years.
baby made deep assets.
And prevented 24 blast
in whole country
we did 13 most wanted arrest.
and 8 encounters.
After 4 years..
my team of 12 only 4 were remaining.
It was the story of the
last mission of baby
WE WSFS Wrong.
We got info about rakesh..
his photo is being change on his phone.
His family may not see it.
Jamal turned over,
their plan is for serial blast.
Where..
in delhi somewhere.
When..
today...where is ajay
whats happening.
One person wants to help
other is preventing it.
Someone is using rakesh phone,
sameer is sending your cordinates.
Yes sir..
what's the status.
He's not doing good.
Where is the location
where is location jamaal.
Where is in delhi
prominent mall
how much time..
how many boys are there!
What did you say...
what's the time?
How are you feeling]
Bring the whole family
ofjamal to the mall
right now..
all of them.
Wife zoya..
sister noori and got kid?
I want to see you laughing
on their death.
You can't do this to me..
you don't remmeber I can do anything.
Handover the jamaaL.
Why you did like this?
You were ours.
this year are many diwali
till how many times
can you stop
hey bilal..
a lawyer has come from your side.
Has to sign something.
Taufeeq was asking that.
Date is coming near..
if you tell us where to drop stuff.
Say taufeeq that if he's worry
about dates so get me outta here.
He's not agree.
says ..call the neighbour
first he need freedom.
then will give address for delivery
aren't you got cought?
He's mrtyred.
Do you know why our
little plans are being failed.
You got to india jawed.
Its time to bring out the bilal khan.
I got the news
that america has annouced the
reward on my head for 1O million dollar
and hearing that india
is very happy
I to america and india..
to both of them
wants to advice.
That your money..
your time your country
spend for your people.
And our muslims brother
and sister lives there..
Spend on there protection
and success.
Because muhammad rehman
can't be get cought till.
America from pakistan
and india from Kashmir don't go back
india says..we killed some
people on border of them
what were they doing on our land.
India is always behave like this.
That mistake is ours.
What rakesh doing in istanbul.
we had a agentjamal
he was recruitmentor for
jahidis
rakesh went to kill him..
Jamal was our man..
used to work under me.
Its our failure that he give us up,
and stayed in enemy's camp
jamal was indian
zabiuddin ansari gave instrution
for taj attack from karachi
and for terrorist camp,
our people are being inrolled..
And after training they
can return from any country
today sitting on facebook,
anybody can make riot in any country
the work they can't do while
sitting at home, they're doing inside.
Its third day.
our shuklla is busy to turn on computer.
He's sweating..
people thinking what's happening.
Then later we came to know..
shukla sir didn't turn on power button.
Why do you make story
after coming back.
I can understand you
can't share your work with me.
There must be any story..
If I goes .
and never come back so?
There's must be a story about me.
For you people.
I forbid you to not marry me.
Why you used to wander
around my office.
Never wanted to loose you
bilal khan who was arrested
in serials blast case.
Who is successfull fro escaping.
You both won't go to school today
where will we go today..
for shopping.
Don't die..
Sit.
What's your age..
I'm 23 years old.
Tell me aftab..
what do you want to say?
I was in second year
engineering. when all started.
Sameer and junaid were my friends
and they intro me to taufeeq bhai
after that..they called me
and showed me some videos.
After that.
I was receiving this kind of links.
Approx 6 months ago..
I was told..
Me and junaid and samer
are going to nepal for special training.
And we were told that
we're selected in thousands.
I lied to parents.
That we're going to college trip
at landing on
Kathmandu airport we shifted.
Next to we carried on border.
Approx our training was
running on for 2 weeks.
We were tought
to assemble explosive device.
I want to talk to you
for 2 min mntaufeeq
they loves them a lot?
Till you people are here.
they will stand out
how do you come?
where is bilal and jawed ali khan?
What will you take in meal?
no I'm in hurry.
I need only two people..
where is bilal and jawed
I'm telling you a short story
do you remember
the bomb blast of 2008
after two years.
police came here.
They got news that
indian mujhideen are here.
Till 3 days...
they interogate.
We knew that.
but we were silent.
After two days.
the safely reached to their destination
somewhere any bastard betryed,
but we didn't..
Do you know about the colum
of religion
we write MUSLIM
in bold and capital.
And now...
the answer of your question
who bilal..
Who jawed ali khan.
A small story from my side.
I was paramilittary..and I was deploed
in gujrat hindu muslim riot.
Got alert that muslim family
is stuck in somewhere.
And radical hindu orginization
got news about it.
My collegues were busy and
I reponde because I was near.
I reached to location
that family thinks I've come to kill them
very hardly I satisfy them.
At evening hindu orginization
reaced with weapons.
I fought alone for 24 hours.
I got shot too
7 people were died by me.
But I didn't let that family hurt.
Look...if I got only bruises.
Why will scratch.
The people who are standing
out don't know your reality
they don't know that
you're ISI agent.
The address you've given..
if I couldn't find him there..
I'll show the clips,
and will see how much they loves you
tell me about the alligation
from the india.
The terrorist attack
and escape of bilal khan.
In all those matters.
you're mentioned
what do you think about it.
India is a troubled country
why?
their behaviour
he's troubled by pakistan.
Whatever happens in india..
they accuses pakistan.
India give sign that if we don't
co-operate so they'll do surgical strike
yes sir..
okey sir.
We can't find the chance
to find the bilal again.
When to do ?
in next 24 hours.
Without telling nepal?
It will be done
what's the plan.
Take this.
thanks
don't need to stay more
than 5 min, fix meeting in hotel at 11.
Will you guide me the address.
From where have you come..
from mumbai.
To whome do you've
come to meed...abdul haq.
His keen has sent me
come.
Abdul has gone for meeting,
I leaved the msg for him
tell me what can
I do for you
don't be afraid..
I'm very close to him
who send you ...?
From taufeeq..after his mrtyered,
I was instructed to deliver this packet.
Who sent you.
they don't have names.
I got a phone call
and received tickets,money in envelope
are you alone..
I've a companion with me.
Sent us like spouce.
Where's the packet...
in hotel.
How did you recognized the abdul
I want to connect him to india.
He'll tell me to give
packet or not.
You just send him
at my hotel at 11 morning.
5T0 P
I'm going on that way..
I'll drop you
I'll go by myself.
I'm saying there's
no problem so lets go
yes rafiq..
whafre you doing?
Doesn't marten.
bye.
Who was it..
the companion of mine.
I'm abdul haq.
I'll take this packet now.
Taufeeq used to say
good about yo
you sit.
I'll be back
sir he has come with me..
keep him busy...I'll be there.
Yes tell me.
are you in confrence?
No..
tomorrow is ananya's birthday
can you come..
offcourse.
Call at home and invite the guest.
anjali..
Why?
I asked you earlier.
are you busy you said no
it contains some money
found it..
bringing by road.
Send me the car detail.
Inject it.
What's this.
rod.
And that.
gel.
5T0 P
we're businessman.
you're hitting us.
First that madam 'mtted me
now you.
ask me what do you
want to know.
Where's bilal..
you just stay away first.
You come in front please.
You don't understand
what I'm saying..we are businessman.
Work for money
where's bilal..
First you promise me
you'll release me.
We don't concern about
your india pakistan hindu muslim.
I just give service.
and earn money
bilal is in aldeara..
tomorrow is his big meeting.
For finalizing next plan
and funding.
What's the next plan..
I didn't think any thing.
They thinks all that.
I'm just businessman.
Whafre they thinking.
Did you heared about
nannay mujahid
further work..
Yes.
I want to meet
minister sir.
He's very busy..
you call back tomorow..gupta..
Come..
I'll arrange.
I said every thing..
so why you hit me.
I'm used to for it
we found bilal khan.
the story is .
Indian mujahideen
and lashkarwere planining.
And suddenly bilal khan
gets cought.
Iashkafis leader
wants to execute the plan.
Waseem mobilize
the fund from nepal
jawed comes pakistan
from india.
And help of him..
bilal success to escape.
If we've to stop them.
we've to stop bilal khan.
Its intel that bilal khan
will activate the jumbo jet unit.
Jumbo jet room is the arrier
attack unti of lashkar.
Which base is in karachi..
this unit contain 150 people.
They're trained to attack
like 911 and every.
We had ex-officer who
warned me for many diwili
jamal publish the megaznine
for people..nanney mujahid.
Its banned in pakistan.
and this is being upgrade.
Bilal is in saudi for
palnning for group and funds.
He'll go directly to karachL.
and will try to execute this plan.
They'lll attack
we cought 3 important man
in two days.
We've confirmed intel
about bilal.
After killing bilal..
we'll show waseem to media
that we're not backward,
but we're forward.
Its big opportunity.
Where's bilal..
Its risky..
but its not dumb idea.
We've deep asset in aldera.
we we can make it possible.
I goes at 1% too
sir like nepal..
it will be coword operation.
When you says this in front
of this officer..
We finds some officers...
little crazy..
In their brain..
there's on patriotism.
They don't want to die
for country..but live for..
So till the last breath.
they can protect country
what do you want along.
an back..and technition.
Take shukla.
where are you stucking me.
I talked to him..
he said shukla is coming.
I don't want to work
with this man.
I don't want to..
he always makes stuck
because of him..i got hardly
survive in iraq and bangladesh
and saved you Mme.
and made me stuck too
he changes the plan
in last min..and screws the mission
its call...impovisation
no I don't want to work with him
don't worry sir..
me and jay will do it.
Trazan and hulkjointly
will handle operation.
No sir..
I don't want to work with hm
our first step what to make
backgroud of our team.
We eastablish a gujrat base
oil company overnight.
And gave it 15 years history
and gave a backgroud for
3 employees.
As hfaq g roomed ajay.
He was in aldera for last 4 years.
We helped him for set up his business.
Ashfaq's work was to supply
us local support.
He was very reliable.
we was arrest many times.
Always he comes out
in half hour.
We knew about aldera
more then america.
Bilal is staying in desert resort.
On the name of firdos ali.
Bilal has much security
will you do all the planning today?
You're going to die.
We've to catch the flight.
Any update.
no sir.
What will we do..
we'll wait.
When their meetin will over,
when we'll go to sleep.
He's started again sir..
We'll see 'IO mins more.
I knew this will happen.
to working with you means.
What?
Meeting is about to over.
We'll not wait for their sleep,
as the guest are gone and bilal is alone.
Then we'll start.
no ajay
remaning is in your hand.
So bilal had come to meet him
hurry UP
lets take him
should we tell him..
so he'll not turn off electric fence.
Won't let us go out.
He's layed
he's gone made.
he found molana so he didn't kill him
he brought him here.
and saying we'll take him to india.
Tell him that.
shoot him and finish it.
Hand over the phone..
yes sir
what did you think..
we'd try all life but never finds him
he knows a lot..
We've to take him to india
anyhow.
But how..
I don't know I need time.
They both will go as plan..
I'll contact you..
Me and jay is coming..
he's staying here.
Ashfaq you've to come with us.
we need a local resident.
What's the plan..
to be patient.
Suppose you've a uncle.
and he's sick
but you gave the application
in Chennai hospital, and its in queue
and today suddenly your uncle
is serious sick and coincedentelly
and today you gets the mail
from Chennai hospital that donor is ready
you come and bring your patients.
Just has a only problem.
my uncle's visa.
It will be done..
I think you don't understand.
If my visa is done.
so my uncle's health inspection is needy
firts uncle inspection will be done..
he'll check first.
Then he'll give approval on form,
then he'll get the visa.
And this form will be check
on every check point.
Now we've to admit him in hospital
we don't know to whome
will they send.
Yes shukla.
we need the visa from here to india.
We need money too.
I'm texting you name
and number to you
bilal hasn't come out yet.
How much time the door
is closed...8 hours.
Where're you bilal sir.
I need every guest passport,
who checked in and checked out.
And what's the status on cctv footage.
He's not abbas shaikh..
and neither he's from quwait.
Check your data again
inspector is reaching hospital at 3 o clock.
and has bad news.
What? bilal's murder is being
investigating by hanni mohammad.
He allready got the passport
details of all guests.
And seeing cctv ..
I've missplaced your details.
If only our will be miss place.
so doubt will be on us.
Tell your contacts.
missplace more
where're you..
at exchange point..i'll meet you at hospital
put the Chennai sim card.
and keep it ready for use..
Verification mail should mention
this number.
Tape the Chennai hospital landline,
and should be divert calls to you.
You go now..
me and ashfaq will handle everything.
Youi know what you have to
do if you got cought.
What's your problem
they'll doubt..
wait.
Here..
Show me..
leave it.
Call the doctor.
Bring the bag
which is in my car.
Yes. mr.feroze..
want to meet minister.
Today is very hard.
is the urgent.
No ..
nothing urgent.
I'm in confrence.
I'll call you back.
Are you allright?
I was worried..
and heart beat gone up
are youallright?
I'm allright.
Where's the kids.
in school
confrence is going to finish.
Don't die just.
Airparamedic is on other side.
near gate c.
You stay there..
I'll complete the formality
I want to about the security.
excuse me..
Greetings.
how are you
I'm fine..
thanks.
I want information of passengers
traveling to india..
I want to check this pasport
numbers.
They are traveling together..
Is there someone in medical
condition in plan.
Any airpramedic.
Yes sir..there's local resident is going
for liver illment
no problem
molana's captures were not
made public.
We found what we wanted
after 6 weeks .
when he hadn't anything to tell us.
So we took him srinagar.
There the army did what they
do with militants.
Baby which was only
5 years trail..
And was shut down..
and our elite programe got perminant status.
But we love the name...
Baby!