Subtittles by sergiowr@gmail.com
This is my contribution for the
web community. Enjoy it.
"Dend Hill is though to invade"
"We will have fun killing our enemies."
"And I'll tell you how things work here."
"We don't take easy even with DRE."
"Even BOPE tremples to come here."
"We don't take easy with the army,
local police or military police."
"I will tell you something, my friend."
"Dend Hill is also land of God!"
"Faith in God! DJ!!!"
"Let's go!"
Rio de Janeiro got more than
seven hundred 'favelas'.
Most of all rulled by drug dealers
armed until their teeth.
People with AR-15,
pistol Uzi, HK and so on...
All over the world these
weapons are used to make war.
On Rio, they are
the crime weapons.
A shot by .762 goes through a
car just like it would on paper.
It's stupid to think a policemen would
enter the hill just to keep the law.
Policemen got family, my friend.
Policemen has afraid to die too.
Let's go, this way. Go, go!
It is why, in this city,
every policeman got a choice.
To corrupt himself, to disguise
himself or to go to the war!
Most of peoples don't like war.
Major Oliveira wasn't an exception.
Every friday they went to
collect the "arrego".
Wich is the money they charge the
dealers for them to keep their activities.
Attention, Marcim!
- The worms are comming!
- Let them come, it's all right.
Drug dealers live on war,
but they also wants to survive.
Why shoot the police if they can negotiate?
But that night there was a policeman
who wasn't there to collect money.
It were Cpt. Fbio. He was there against
his will. And he was also scared to death.
If Fvio wasn't on that "Patamo", Neto
and Matias wouldn't be entering the hill.
Neto and Matias would never disguise
themselves, neither corrupt theirselves.
They were honest.
- Did they exit the car already?
- Do you see Fbio there?
- Don't do this, captain.
- The hill is sweet today.
- Will you left me unarmed?
- Let's go you sick fuck.
- Do you see Fbio there?
- Let me handle this.
Are you seeing?
- Do you see Fbio there?
- Take it easy, man.
What's up, Oliveira?
The truth is that peace in Rio
depends on a fragile balance
between the dealers ammo
and the police corruption.
Honesty is not in the game.
- Do you see?
- Let me handle this.
- What the fuck...
- Have you already seen Fbio?
What's happening, man?
What...
It's a unsteady balance
that can be broke with a
single breeze. Storm has blown
hardly that night on Babilnia.
Matias and Neto dicided to
go to the war on that night.
- Who did you shoot?
- Let's go, let's go!
- What the fuck is going on?
- Two worms running here!
- Stay with me!
- Who did you shoot?
Fuck!
Fuck that shit, Marcim, Activity!
Activity there, Marcim! Two
worms going to your direction!
Fuck you, are you messing with us?
What do think? Are you messing with us?
We're so fucked up!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Out of the way!
Son of a whore!
Fuck! We're so fucked up!
We are going to die, man!
We are going to die!
Don't stop shooting!
- We are going to die!
- No! Just keep it cool, buddy.
I am running out of ammo!
- Tranquility, calmness! Just this!
- Let's go up there and do our job
with tranquility and calmness!
- It may be a crowd up there because
there is a funk dance party today.
- So we are going to reach there slowly.
It may be injuried cops there.
- So we ought to stay calm!
If there would be only
the common police in Rio,
drug dealers would have
already taken control.
It is why there is BOPE, special
operation squad of the military police.
- Who among you knows Babilnia hill?
- I know, zero-one!
- So you're going to lead the operation!
- It is nearby the main avenue.
On the theory, BOPE is a
part of the military police.
On the real world, it is a
completely different police.
BOPE symbol makes clear what
happens when we invade a "favela".
And our uniforn isn't blue. It's black.
- BOPE arrived! Let's go there!
- Nobody will enter!
- You'll stay right there where
you are! Nobody will enter!
BOPE was created to interfere when
the common police isn't able to do so.
And it happens all the time on Rio.
- Knife on the skull and nothing on
the wallace! (No identification).
My name is Cpt. Nascimento.
I was the BOPE alfa team leader.
I was on that war since a long
time ago. And I was tired of it.
BORNING
- Oh, dear! I wish I could be there
with you now, but I'm working here.
- Can you hear his heart?
Put it there for me.
- "Caramba", it beats
so hardly, doesn't it?
- Very fast, isn't it?
- My love, I really have to go
because I'm working here!
- No, it isn't necessary, I'll warm it
up on the micro-waves when I arrive.
- All right!
The only way to stop this war is to
take over all the criminals weapons.
- The target is locked up, captain.
It is why the main objective of
BOPE isn't arrest drug dealers.
It is to capture weapons!
- What's up, Pompeu?
- Did you bring the pieces?
- Yes, I did.
- Bring them!
- Ok!
On my time, Military Police had 30000
unable and mispayed men with weapons.
BOPE had only 100 cops.
- Holy dick, how I wish to shoot
all those sons of whores...
- Wich one, my captain, just tell me.
- These PM (Military Police)
sons of whores!
For each weapon we captured,
three more used to replace it.
- 14, let them make their delivery!
Renam will catch them down there!
I have lost count of how many nights I
spent cleaning up some cop corruption!
- 01, we could kill two rabbits
with a single strike here, hum?
- Is it 100%, 14?
- Skull, my captain!
- So "Load the Finger" (shoot)
at this shit!
For me, who helps drug dealers
to get weapons, is their abetter.
Oh, yeah, my friend, I have to admit!
I was really with a short pavio.
And my life was turning out to
be even more complicated yet.
- Good morning!
- Good morning, my love.
- Let me take it before I...
- Wait, I have set up the table...
- I got to go now, I got
to arrive earlier there.
- Damn, Beto, you have already arrived late
yesterday and is going out on a rush now?
- I have badly slept tonight!
- Are you ok? Is the baby alright?
- How can it be alright if I stay here
waiting for you? He feels my anxiety.
- He hasn't gained weight
last time, had he?
- What do you want me
to do? Stop working?
- If I knew you wouldn't quit,
I would not get pregnancy!
A war always charges its price!
And when the price becomes too
high, it is time to get out!
- Wait, my love, take a
little bread... Beto?
If you miss the time, you can loose
the chance of get out in one piece.
I was in need of a substitute.
But it is not easy to
become a BOPE Captain.
And to find someone honest, brave,
someone who had a police heart
and a police mind to replace
me would be almost impossible!
- Captain Fbio, manutention boss
and commander of the 1st. company.
- Captain Oliveira, 3st. session
boss of the Major State.
When the guy is an idealistic one and
studies three years to become a cop,
the first day on duty matters.
But with time, most of them slow down.
- Welcome. Do not forget you will
be  daily evaluated since now,
- by me and by my Major State!
- I want you to know that this team,
wich I have the honor to command,
- is more than a big family. It is one
among the best on the coorporation.
- Estvo, take them to their functions.
- Yes, sir!
I didn't know Matias and Neto.
- Dismissed.
I didn't know I would need one's
brain and another's heart!
If I could mix them together
this story would be different!
It would not be difficult to quit BOPE.
But who said life's easy?
- It is here where you
are going to work...
- Is this shit a workshop?
- Yes, it is. Any problem?
- Sir, couldn't you give me another
function? I know nothing about cars!
- Officer pay attention: there are 46 cars and
12 bikes! Your job is to make them roll!
- It is not moving...
- How are you guys?
- Captain!
- Confortable.
- Officer.
- They are your assistants.
- How are you?
- Boss, 249 will be running
today as I promised to you.
- Not without a long time.
- Oh, yeah. But the new parts
you asked for haven't came yet.
- It's true!
- This is why I'm working
on the gear here...
- But this car is brand new one!
- Is it here just because
the glass is broken?
- You can say the glass is
broken, but look at this.
- I had to fix the engine,
the gear is not working...
- All rigth, all right. I don't want
to know about this shit anymore.
- It is not my "dick" (problem)
anymore. It is his "dick"!
- Hello there, my princess!
- Officer!
- Lieutenant!
- Comfortable!
- Make yourself confortable too, officer.
- Bread with ham, coffee, cold water...
- I'm not hungry!
- Let's start work! I don't want
to stay here all day long.
Let's go!
- No parts, no job...
- You got to talk with captain Fbio!
- He knows what to do to get the parts.
- All right. So let's stop
talking and start working!
- I don't want to stay
here all day long!
- Drop this bread and go to work!
- Sir Lieutenant, no parts, no job!
- I don't want to know. I want
to see everybody working here!
Neto was an impulsive guy!
He uses to act before thinking.
Matias uses to think
a lot before acting.
Do you see this stack of papers?
Each paper is an occurrence, a crime
PM didn't prevent from happening.
On Neto hands, this stack
would become a pyre!
On Matias', it would
become statistics.
This is officer Matias, he will work
here with you starting today!
How are you, boss?
Officer, they will be your assistants.
Cabo Bruno and Soldier Machado.
Your job is to keep the radio on
and to tabulate the occurrences.
- Is it alright?
- Yes, Sir!
- That is your desk!
- Sorry, boss!
- Any question you can call me!
Good job for all of you!
None of both were at my level!
But one of them would replace me!
- All right, class. Well...
- One of these ten books
will be the subject...
Matias was smart and dedicated!
A guy who borns black and poor on
Brasil doesn't have many chances!
- You will have to form a
group of four members...
- Let's go. I want to do the Foucault!
- Doesn't matter to me.
- We have three members,
we need one more...
But Matias accomplished to study at
the best law college on Rio de Janeiro!
- Hey, are you already in a group?
- Yes, I am!
In his head, to study law had every
thing to do with his work on police!
For him, a lawyer and a cop
had almost the same job!
They had to defend the law!
- He will not even notice
there are only three members!
- We had to form the group first!
- Someone will take the Foucault!
He will not notice, I'm sure!
- Is it here the sociology class?
- What's your name?
- Andr!
- Andr what?
- Andr Matias! Why?
- You are in our Foucault
group, all right? - What?
- I will explain to you.
Wait a second!
Matias head was in an ideal world,
far from reality of Rio de Janeiro.
- Hi, my name is Maria.
- Nice to meet you!
- They are Dudu, Roberta, we
will do a Foucault homework...
But to be a BOPE officer, a guy
needs to know where he's walking!
Matias had a lot to learn!
- You know this citizen
comming up, don't you?
- What you don't know is that he will
sleep one night here at Turano hill!
- Are you kidding, Carvalho?
- We are going to guarantee
his sweet dreams with angels!
- Turano hill on war and Pope is
going to spent one night there?
- I'll pay for him to stay at copacabana!
- I spent one month telling
the Defense Secretary so.
- But not even God can
change Pope's itinerary!
- He will sleep there and this is it!
- We have around three months to
stop this war on Turano hill!
- We're going to do daily incursions!
- I'm sorry, but do you
agree with daily incursions?
- Will we go there at night and at day,
with no surprise effect, under heavy fire...
- Nascimento!
- People are going to die!
- Nascimento! It's what is going to
be done. Operation starts tomorrow.
- Did I made myself clear?
- Yes, Sir!
- Dismissed.
I know the Pope can't take
the blame of my problems!
But he has already came to Rio twice!
Didn't he know how it is around here?
Of course, no politician wants to
see the Pope getting shot at his city!
If Pope wants to sleep nearby a "favela",
what do you think the governor will do?
Take the chance of Pope getting
a lost bullet in his head?
Of course not!
He will call BOPE!
- Fuck, Neto. Stop this shit, brother.
- I am studying here, man!
- Fuck you, you got to stop studying!
Let's go take a walk around the city!
- Will you need the car tomorrow?
- What for do you want my car?
- I'm going to the Pleasures Hill!
- Are you crazy? What are you
going to do on a "favela"?
- My college group decided to
gather there to do a research!
- You're a cop. You can't simply
go there! They can kill you there!
- Do this research only by
yourself, you can do it!
- Keep cool, nobody on
college knows I am a cop!
- Be carefull!
Pope was in need of BOPE!
BOPE was in need of me!
And I was in need of a substitute!
It would not be easy!
I would have to keep invading
"favelas" because of the Pope!
But I would invade armed, buddy!
And wearing a black uniform!
A problem that occurs to a cop who
wants to study at a college is that,
with a first glance, students are
good people! And there are lots of
well intentioned girls!
- It is good to see you!
- This is Rose!
- Nice to meet you!
- This is Lhana!
- Hi there!
- This one is handsome. The
other one was so stonewashed!
- So horny...
- That's what we need.
- Don't look up, hun?
- Enjoy yourself!
- Sorry for make you come here,
but we have a lot of homework!
- This is the administration room!
- This is Rodrigues
- Rodrigues, Andr!
- He's our sponsors representant.
- Besides, he's a great friend of mine.
- Do you got a name for senate?
Now you do!
- Senator Magalhes, 451!
Take more to give to your friends!
- Take More!
- Don't forget: 5 - 1 = 4!
4 + 1 = 5! 451!
I recognize at first
sight it's hard to resist!
Rich student likes
to help poor children!
Who doesn't feel sorry
for poor children?
- Romerito, this is Andr!
- What's up, big boy?
- Let's go to the flip, godmother?
- Godmother can't go today,
I got plenty of homework!
- What about you?
- I'll do it later!
- What have you promised
to me about studying?
Matias was unexperienced
and he had a big heart!
It was natural for
him to get involved!
- He's not going well at the school.
- Do you know what's happening?
- He simply doesn't want to study!
- Maybe there's another reason!
He has to impose limits
on the rigth time.
If a guy doesn't take care, he
could be seducted by his friends.
The right thing to do
was to bust them all.
A policeman has to impose the law.
Matias had just started the college
and was already taking easy with them.
- Romerito? Didn't you tell me
you would go home to study?
- Nah...
- Blinding...
If he wasn't really taking care,
he could turn out one of them.
- Wait, wait! Wait a second!
- Would you borrow me your hand?
- What are you going to do?
- I think these kids are right...
- What letter is this?
- It's an 'A'!
- All right! Now, what letter is this?
- I'm not seeing...
What letter is this?
- It's also an 'A'!
- An 'A'?
- He has to wear glasses.
Haven't you ever realized that?
- It might be why he's
not going well at school.
- I had the same problem at his age.
- Let's go tell your mother!
- Come on with us, Andr!
- But where is it? Up there?
- Yeah, it's very close...
To be a BOPE captain, Matias would
have to learn to show no mercy!
Drug dealears don't forgive.
- What's up, Tim?
- I did that test!
- Did you pass?
- It was very easy.
- Do you see it worths to study, Romerito?
- Don't worry. They got social conscience!
Keep cool, don't worry!
- I am cool!
- Be my guest.
- Hey Alex!
- Bye, Roberta!
- By guys!
- I don't want to wear glasses.
- He also wears glasses.
- Hey Maria
- What?
- I got to go.
- Already?
- It is time to take back my friend's car
- About his glasses, I will pay for them
- I'll take him to the
doctor and everything.
- It's not needed. We can
get them through the NGO.
- Someone did it to
me when I was a child.
- I want to do it for him.
- That's rgith then...
- I'll come back to visit you some day.
- It's an appointment, hun! Bye.
- What's up, Baiano!
Baiano was in charge
on NGO "favela".
I know how Baiano story ends, but
I don't know how it had started.
He probably got a fucked up childhood.
He could have had no option!
- I've noticed it's snowing on the mountain!
Things are goo up here...
- Hey, "galego" (white guy),
"what worths" (what's up)?
- This worths!
- Xaveco, "bring two"!
What fucks me up is guy who borns with
all chances and throws them all away.
I have said it before, but to me, who
helps drug dealers is their abetter.
Got to be arrested.
- Hey, what's up?
- Hey, Bruno, are you ok?
- Hi Paty!
- Excuse me...
- Just a minute, bro.
- Come on in.
- That's it.
- On hands.
- Only two?
- Do you think it's easy
to take it with no money?
- So you can bring me more!
- Check this out. There's R$2000,00 here.
- Keep it.
- If there is more of this one, you
bring me more. People are calling.
I'm wondering about how many kids we
lost for each joint a playboy smokes!
- You go with your team through
the alley but be very carefull.
- 117's entrance is near to the college.
- There will be a lot of students.
- I know that!
- I've already said it's not right.
- Nascimento, orders are orders.
- Everybody will gather
at the complex's center!
- Understood?
- Skull!
A strategy is a good one only
if its objective makes sense.
Pope operation was a stupid thing.
On usual conditions, I would be just
pissed off. But my son would be born soon.
I had to really take care.
I didn't want to lose everything!
- On the floor, on the floor!
- Where's the "vapor"?
(the one who carries the drugs)
- I haven't seen him...
- Every body aligned here.
- Sit there!
- I'll ask just one time!
- Who was with the "cargo"?
- I don't know!
- I'm a student!
- Speak it up! - I'm a student!
- Are you what?
- Here!
- Put your face there!
- Do you see this hole?
- Who has killed this guy?
- I haven`t seen...
- Haven't you seen? You have seen!
Speak it up. Who has killed him?
- Speak it up!
- You may speak!
- Who has killed him?
- It was one of you!
- One of us my cock!
- You have killed this guy!
- You fucking fag! It is you
who finance all this shit here!
- You fucking piece of
shit pot smoker junk!
- We come here to undo
the shit you've done!
- It is you who finance all this shit!
- You fucking fag!
- Who was with the "cargo"?
- 07, bring the little bad seed!
- Let's see it...
- Speak it up. It's now! Point at him!
- Point now at who was with "the cargo"!
- This one in a jacket?
- It's you, son of a whore.
- It's not me!
- What to do with him?
- Take him to station with "the cargo".
- Got lucky, tramp!
- I'm not kidding at this shit!
- Well, teacher. We've concluded that
the law works like a web on Brasil
wich creates many repressive structures.
- Unfortunately on our country
it results on a State that
protects rich people and punishes
almost exclusively the poor people!
- All right!
- I think Maria and her group
said clearly how power relations,
and not just the State,
create evil institutions.
- We could now make a case analysis.
- can someone give me an example
of one of those institutions?
They kill "fogueteiros"
who breaks down!
And I knew that!
"Fogueteiro"'s mother made
me feel really sorry!
And it's a very dangerous
feeling for a BOPE captain.
I realized Rosana was rigth.
It was time to put
someone to replace me.
Neto had the police in his heart!
He wanted to solve all the problems
But a simpleton guy
can't be a BOPE officer.
Neto needed to know that to be
a serious cop on Rio de Janeiro
is not easy!
You got to stop "punching knifes" (to do
something that will not bring any result).
To effectively do something,
you ought to use the system.
PM Barracks had been abandoned by
the defense secretary politics.
With no corruption, with no "brazilian
way", military police would stop.
The first time is always
for a good reason!
Well, if you corrupt yourself for the police
you will certainly do it for your family!
It's the System's logic!
It is why when someone wants a police
car pattroling his store region
He got to pay for it.
Police job is to protect, isn't it?
System turned it into a business.
But someone who puts a price to
do what he's already paid to do
also puts a price to do a "thick sight"
(to pretend not to see when a law is being broken.)
- Ademar is battalion's friend.
- Don't take it bad. I'm following orders.
- Whose orders?
- Bira's.
- What Bira?
The System takes all spaces.
Government was so fucked up that it
hadn't have money to buy some tows.
So they gave the job to a third company
and started to pay to them to tow.
The System took its advantages.
Each captain took a tow
and started to tow them all.
- Colone, it's Fbio making
a mess on our tow scheme!
- You cut his little wings!
- Go home! It's my area now!
- Now is it you who controls this area?
- I am incontrol of this shit!
- Ask him about my parts!
- Hello... son of a
bitch hanged on my face.
- What abou my parts?
- Isn't that commandant's bike?
- Friday! Commandant's bike
goes collect "bicho" "arrego"!
- That's why it can't stop.
To collect "bicho" "arrego"!
- Fuck! Now I understand this shit.
- They used to share the money. But
now it is just for commandant's men.
The System got no limits.
The System got no borders.
It is a part of the police culture.
- This commandant is
fucking with everybody!
- You too?
- Sgt, since last tear I'm on
the scale to take my vacation
- Now my wife finaly got
permission to take her vacation
- So we're going to take our
vacation together next month!
- I just want to ask you to
report it on the "boletim"
- So I can take my vacation.
- It is not easy like this. I
got 40 people still waiting here,
eight already on vacation and the
Battalion cannot lose another man.
- but... who knows if
I could talk to the major, tell him
your story and see what happens...
- Because we got a good procedure here
- But sgt! Sgt Rocha...
- What I'm asking is my rigth.
I don't take any vacation
for far four years! You just
write it down on the "boletim".
- I really could help you...
- I mean, I will help you!
- I want to help you!
- But you got to help me to
help you, you know what I mean?
- Soldier Paulo, one
who wants to laugh,
oughts to make laugh first!
- Oughts to make laugh first!
- Understood, sir.
Asking permission to go!
- Permission given, soldier.
- I know nothing about cars, sir!
- Couldn't you send me to
the "favelas" operation?
- You have just arrived and already
wants to change your function?
- I don't want to change my function!
I want to really help!
- I'm a good shooter!
- Well, if you fix 70% of
those cars on the workshop
- I will think about
your demand! All right?
- But sir, I...
- Dismissed!
The System drive the cops crazy.
And that's not different on BOPE.
- What's up, dear, are
you climbing or what?
- Are you all right, my love?
- Are you feeling ok?
- Beto?
- Are you ok?
- I'm ok!
- Are you really ok?
- Fuck, I'm so sick!
- Stay calm!
- It's not the heart!
- Stay calm, it's not the heart!
- My arm is badly hurting...
- Trust me, it's stress!
- Nascimento, your exams are perfect!
- Check this out again!
- They are just perfect!
- There's a lot of heart issues on my family!
- My father died with a heart failure...
- Your heart is iron made
- Sometimes it begins
with a noise on my ear.
- Hand starts to tremble...
- It is an emocional problem...
- What's that?
- You are feeling stress...
- I'll take you to the shrink!
- What the fuck?
- It doesn't hurt, man...
If you work correctly on police
you will certainly be fucked up
By one way or another.
Matias worked two months to do the city
crime map with that stack of papers.
But it's not the way police works.
Police works for the System and it
doesn't work to solve society issues
It works to solve its own problems.
- Fuck, Stvo, this
report will fuck me up!
- 12 corpses in a month!
- How can I report this?
- Well, I have followed his work
- and it seems it's correct!
- Are you sure this report...
- Do you want to fuck with me?
- No, sir!
- You go call cpt. Fbio here!
Come on son, go , go!
- He will explain me about
these four corpses on Tabajara.
- Colonel, this report has statistics
base, look at the crime map and...
- Do I want to know about numbers? This
bastard wants to teach me where to put my men!
When it occurs a crime on the battalion
area, the responsible got to do something.
But to do something means
a lot of work sometimes...
-
- A lot! I want to know what does it
mean these four corpses on Tabajara?
- It is not may fault. I've done
exactly what you told me to do, but...
- Mar-zero, negative on corpse
localization on Mar-19 area!
- The corpses, according informations,
had been localized on Mar-2 area!
It's much easier to move
corpses than to find criminals.
There are a lot of lazy commandats that
move the corpses to another commandat'a area.
But even on PM, you cannot be a simpleton.
- Mar-zero, the corpses are
localized on Mar-19, copy that?
- Those sons of whores, colonel.
They keep throwing the corpses here!
- They throw here, I throw there!
- I want this shit done!
- But colonel...
- Understood?
- yes, sir.
- And you will remake this report!
- Look at this! A corpse
found on the beach.
- Death on the beach,
son, is a drowning!
- But commandant, it was perforated...
- Are you a legal doctor?
- No, sir.
- I want a new report on my desk
on Monday because this one...
- had never existed!
- Dismissed!
I have tryed to change the
convencional police too.
But my plans also have failed.
- If you say nothing it will
be very difficult to help!
- I know, but, it is...
...it's complicated to talk!
- More than usual because I'm
not sure if you have to report
what I would tell you to the commandant!
If you have to, I would
prefer to tell you
about a friend of mine
who is going to be dad and
is getting some trouble!
- Captain!
- I can answer your question only
if you tell me what's going on!
- Besides, it's not a confessionary.
- It is the Military Police shrink office!
- Come on captain! Have
you already wondered if
I had to report everything
I hear in this office?
- Police would stop on Rio!
- You simply decide
if you want to talk!
- Excuse me.
- Nascimento. I will find
a substitute when I can!
- But colonel...
- Captain, I need you
on the Pope's operation!
- Mission accepted is
mission accomplished to me!
- Do you understand?
- Yes, sir!
- You can go!
It was ironic. The same day I lost hope
of quitting BOPE, another story began.
A story that would affect many
people. Nicely and badly too.
- Hey Neto!
- Too long...
- Are you with my car keys?
- What are you doing with the city crime map?
- I've figured it out how to
get out of that workshop!
- Come with me, I had to explain
the plan to Fbio. Come with me!
- What plan! What the fuck is
this guy talking about...
Fucking crazy...
... that workshop smells shit!
... to much work...
- You two complain too much!
- It is me who is getting fucked by
that commandant on the battalion!
- What do you mean, Fbio?
- He took away my schemes, Matias.
I don't have any money, buddy!
I'm fucked up and with no money!
- Look at Oliveira there,
that son of a whore.
- Do you use to take money from here too?
- Come on Neto, I got family!
I get R$500,00 per month
from my salary on the police!
Do you think I'll take the chances
to take a bullet in the head
for R$500,00 per month, buddy?
- How did you get money from here?
- They were honest schemes!
- Do you think he does something for free?
He goes there to collect the dealers' "arrego"!
- How muck he uses to take
on the "bicho"'s "arrego"?
- About R$6000,00 per week on my time!
It might be more by this time!
- R$6000,00 per week?
- It's too much money!
- I'm working on a scheme
for us to take this money!
- Wich scheme? And how
much do I get from it?
- How much do you what?
- How much do I get?
- Are you going to keep
all of the money for you?
- We don't want any money!
- I'm going to buy the
parts for the police cars!
I'll fix them all and get out of that shit!
- I understand it, I just want to know
how much do I get. Just it!
- Don't you want to fuck colonel up?
- I think you are trying to fuck me up!
Do you know what? I'm going to piss
I'm going to urinate! What the fuck...
- What's wrong?
- Don't fail on me with this shit!
- Look at me, bro!
It's true that Neto's plan "washed
the souls" of all honest policemen.
It was all on the plan. Matias would take 40
minutes to collect "Jogo do Bicho"'s money.
The greatest "arrego" on the city.
And there is where Neto starts.
- Give it a charge,
let's see if it works
- I'm so fucking late...
- Leave it to me!
- If commandant sees me
here I'll get fucked!
- "Do you want easyness?
'Eat water' upside down!"
- Sucker...
- It will work now!
- Will it?
- It will!
- I should be on the street now, Tio!
- Come on.
- Call Paulo at once,
let's fix it quickly!
When Neto has released the bike,
Matias has already taken the money.
- Big Sardinha! This is the man!
- What's up, Santos? Did you get better?
- Better of what?
- A buddy of yours came here,
he said you were fucked up!
- Me? Fucked up?
- Yeah. I have already
gave him the money!
- What buddy, Sardinha?
- A fellow of yours came here in the
name of captain! I gave him the money!
Fucking mother fucker,
what a big son of a whore!
It was genius.
Neto used the System against itself.
It was a brilliant idea
but also very stupid.
- More 10 cars ont the streets now, Matias!
There would be a payback.
Neto did it to try to fix things.
Matias was "insisting with the mistake".
- I got things to do!
- I'm going with him.
- Ok, bye!
- See you!
- Hey, where have you been?
- Hi...
- Look at who's comming there!
- Hide the weed!
- Unbelieveable!
- What's up, guys?
- All Hail Mary!!!
- Where have you been?
- We were talking, we spaced in the time!
- You're so beautiful!
- Are you going to be sitted there?
- Let's dance we two!
- Ok, I'm going to dance. See you!
- Is it just because we got
an apartment on Leblon?
- Check it out! I'll make a mess
with this son of a bitch!
- You don't get any trouble, ok?
- Check this out! They
want to get me mad!
- Leave it away!
- Don't worry!
- Let's keep dancing!
- You put more potatles on it!
The System protects corrpted cops.
Colonel couldn't complain
about the robbery.
But he could take a revenge.
Matias went to the kitchen.
Neto fixed the cars but he
was still at the workshop.
- What are you doing here, Paulo?
- Taking my vacation, lieutenant!
- And learning to never
complain about that sgt.
- What about the workshop?
- Well, it gots Tio!
And they lost their best mechanic.
- I told you this shit
would get fucked up!
They were lucky because colonel thought
they were just following someone's orders.
Someone who already knew the System.
- Fbio! Come here!
- Are you on dutty tonight?
- yes, sir!
- I want you to go to check out an
occurence at Babilnia hill tonight!
- Me, sir? - Yeah!
- Yes, sir! Tonight?
- Tonight! - As you want, sir!
- Dismissed!
The punishment to him would be much worst.
And there's where Matia's and Neto's
story starts to be a part of my story.
- You can see he's moving, love.
- He looks like an E.T., but it's
the most beautiful thing in the world!
- I miss you so much here...
... wait, I'll put his
heart sound on the phone!
Every time I thought about my son
I recall "fogueteiro"'s mother.
It's totally fucked up to be
unable to bury your own son.
- You guys get ready!
We're moving out!
- Where are we going to, my captain?
- We're going to Turano hill!
- We're going to get that "fogueteiro"!
- Hey, guys,  colonel asked me to
check out a funk party occurence tonight
The hill is nice tonight, even sweet...
If we do everything right, we can
make some money, but Neto cannot know!
- All right, captain!
- I'm ready!
- What the fuck are you
doing with this rifle?
Don't fuck everything up
there, for the sake of God !
- It's all rigth, captain, trust me!
- I'm in charge here!
- It's all right, no problem!
- Hey, captain! Cabral is already
in charge of this "Patamo"!
- Colonel asked me to go in it!
- No, no! You go with me on my "Patamo"!
You drop this rifle and go fix colonel's bike!
- Let's go!
- Neto? Did you take "bicho"'s "arrego"?
- Yes, we did, sir!
- Let's go, captain!
- I'm comming!
- I think they will "fry" me, Neto!
- Matias! It got fucked up!
- What happened?
- They think Fbio took the money!
- Come with me!
- What are we going to do?
- "Hold it for me"!
- What the fuck?
- What the fuck! Worms are going crazy!
- They are shooting each other!
- Fuck!
- Shooting my dick, you sick fuck!
You cover me, motherfucker!
- Shoot these fuckers!
- You do something!
- I got just one bullet!
... just one bullet, fuck!
- This shit is out of area!
- Leave a message, captain, leave a message!
- Go fuck yourself, you piece of shit!
- It is an honor to support
you on next elections...
...but if Cabral here got promoted,
it is another battalion!
- Things would be pretty better!
- How much better?
- Just a minute, please!
- What's up, Oliveira?
- Colonel, call BOPE...
- What?
- There are surrounded cops on Babilnia hill!
It may be wounded cops on the area!
- All teams are on Turano hill!
- So, what do I do?
- What the fuck...
- Nobody here is in a rush, son!
I can spend all nigth here...
- Where's the "fogueteiro"?
- I don't know, boss...
- What don't you know?
- You are sitting there, with a pistol
in your hands! What don't you know?
- I'm not a "vapor", boss, I don't know!
- You are going back to the bag!
- He passed out!
- Throw water on is face...
- Wake up, you sick fuck!
- 01, priority on Babilnia
hill, surrounded cops, sir!
- Understood, Carvalho! We're comming!
- Fuck, they do the shit we got to
clean it up! Let's go to Babilnia!
- What to do with this worm, captain?
- Put it on the Pope's account!
- Turn to the wall, you worm!
- I'm just a...
- We're going to die, man!
- They are shhoting us from down there!
- From down there they will
not hurt us! Stay down!
- Shoot, you son of a whore!
- We're going to die, Neto!
- To die my balls, shoot these suckers!
- Shoot these motherfuckers!
- I'm out of ammo!
- Stay quiet!
- Stay down!
- Shoot them, fuck!
- Drop the weapon!
- "PM", "PM"! (Military Police)
- There are two of us...
- Out of this hole!
- Sit there, come on!
- Sit there, sit there!
- 01, 19 have founded these two!
- Hey, Boco, identify this one here!
- This is Marcinho, the hill owner!
- Let's take him with us!
- Are you ok? - Yes sir!
- Is anyone of you hurt?
- No, sir!
- Have anyone of you got shot?
- So today you're going to
learn how to carry a corpse!
- What are you waiting for?
- Let's go, let's go!
- 02?
- Speak it up, 01!
- Now you're in charge!
Let's take just the owner
- Because my son is about to be born!
- Let's go, let's go!
- Take him, come on!
Neto decided to join BOPE
because he enjoyed war.
His dream was to fight the
crime on Rio's "favelas".
And he saw it was exactly
what we use to do!
Matias came with him
because he believed in law.
- Wait, this shit is hurting so badly!
- If you don't come here, I
would be "fried" at this time !
- BOPE took your weapon!
- Help us to carry the body!
- Wait a minute, my friend...
- What the fuck? Get out of here
with this shit, you sucker!
- Sgt. Excuse me,
but how can I know this unit of yours?
- You just do your
inscription on the trainning!
- What trainning?
- It's on the "PM" oficial paper!
Neto knew what he was doing.
Matias did not.
- Colonel?
- Rest!
- Sorry, I'm late!
- No problem!
- You tell me something...
- Is it a boy or a girl?
- It's a boy, Rafael!
- Congratulations!
- What is that, Renam?
- It is a sor eye!
- What a fucking ugly thing...
- Put these glasses on!
- You pay attention. This is a gift!
- But it is not for you!
- It is for Rafael!
- From here we'll pick two names
that will replace you and you!
- Saint Rafael!
- Colonel, I will coordinate
the best trainning you ever
saw on Special Operations!
- Ok, let's start with this.
This 01 here,
- Andr Pedrosa!
- This one is on the "bicho"'s list!
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely sure!
- He will become statistics!
- Colonel, Orlavo Carvelli, on my class!
- What about him?
- Criminal! He's at the gamble business!
- He will become skull candy!
- We have skipped this Fbio!
- I have heard about this Fbio!
Cpt. Fbio Barbosa, isn't it?
- This is a bad one, whore pimp at Copacabana!
- Leave him to me!
- Renam? Are you seeing anything there?
- Perfectly, sir!
- He looks like a owl!
- Blinded Skull!
- Batman! - It's beautiful, isn't it?
- Come on, let's go!
- Renam, what about those privates?
- They are those who have been
rescueded by your team on the hill!
- Colonel Estvo said they are great!
- Oh, yeah?
- They had a nice beggining!
- Now, I'll tell you something!
- I don't want to know about
pierced spandrel on the first class!
- I don't want to know about cutted hands!
Is it clear?
- About the cutted hands, it was an accident!
- The student had grabbed the blade
and the instructor had pulled it!
- About that spandrel, Carvalho
gave him a big...
- I haven't meant to hurt him!
- Haven't meant it?
- He deserved, colonel, he deserved!
If you want to be a BOPE officer,
you cannot date dealers' friend.
The truth is that Matias was divided.
He wanted to be a cop, but
he also wanted to be a loyer.
If Matias had a police heart he would
have told her the truth since the begining.
He told her he would travel.
And said nothing when she told him she
could get him a job with her NGO friends.
- He's working with us here
on our NGO for almost one year!
- He is being great to us,
solved all of our problems!
- Ok, but...
...he had to travel and he'll spend two weeks!
- Can it be on the week after next week?
- Great!
A divided guy isn't welcome on BOPE.
Matias would quit the academy
quickly, I thought at first sight.
- I have just achieved that work for Matias!
- It is better for you to
find another boyfriend, Maria!
- What's up, Baiano? Is everything rigth?
- You tell me!
- Do you recognize anyone on this picture?
- Aren't you recognizing this piece
of shit boyfriend of yours, are you?
- It cannot be...
- Can't it be? This brother he killed...
... was my friend, my comrade!
- Now, what?
- keep it cool, Baiano!
- It has nothing to do with you!
- I have brougth him here!
- Maria didn't know that, Baiano!
- I knew nothing about this!
Now I know everything...
- Nobody knew that, Baiano!
- Are you bullshitting me?
- Are you bullshitting me, you fuckers?
- I will tell you what! Here on the
hill, Military Policemen are enemies!
- They are "german" (rival faction)!
- Nobody is bullshitting you...
- Shut up, I haven't finished yet!
- Who are the ones who guarantee
the peace here on the hill?
- You answer me now!
- It is the Command!
- It is the Command, sister!!!
- And the Command is us! And I am the boss!
- To stay here, you ought to join us!
- We have joined...
- Do you join what, playboy?
- It is us, Baiano...
- It's us!
- Indeed! it's us!
- It is us, Baiano!
- I'll charge it all!
- You may charge!
- You shut the fucking up!
- Catch him, Xaveco! Son of a whore!
- Talking must be straight!
- If it's twisted, it is with you, you know?
- Now you study this fucking paper...
- Let's go!
When they arrived, a
corrupted cop came with them.
If Fbio was not there,
he would get killed by colonel.
Poor guy.
He didn't know that colonel is
a lady in comparison to me.
- You arrived here by your own legs!
- Nobody, absolutely nobody,
had invited you!
- And none of you,
none of you is welcome here!
- Prepare your souls!
- Because your bodies
belong to us already!
- I declare open the 9th
Special Operation trainning!
- You'll never be!
- Skulls! Forward!
I know it is like some religious shit.
But that's the way it is got to be.
Our soldiers got to be tough.
A guy must prove he can handle
pressure to become a BOPE officer.
- Do you think we don't know you
receive money from drug dealers?
receive money from the "bicho"'s gamble?
- Do you know why your number is 01?
- It is because you will be
the first one to quit!
- And I'll make you quit!
- You ask to quit!
- You ask to quit or else
you'll quit under my punchs!
- I quit! I quit! I quit!
- 01 quited!
Only 5 PM in 100 complete the training.
When I have trained, buddy, we were 3!
Not even "Israel" army trains like we do.
To fight at this war you must
be able to handle anything.
- The strategy concept...
... 'strategia' in Greek,
'stratege' in Latin,
in French,
'strategie',...
- Are you writting it down?
- Yes, sir!
- I'll ask this on the test!
... in English, strategy,
in Dutch,
'strategia',
in Italian,
in Spanish, 'strategia'...
- Mr. 05?
- Yes, sir!
- Please...
- Mr. 05, if you drop this grenade
you will explode all the class!
- You will explode your friends,
you will explode my assistants,
you will explode me!
- Are you going to sleep, mr. 05?
- No, sir!
- We're all trusting you, mr. 05!
- Let me retake...
... my thinking line!
- The strategy concept,
'strategia' in Greek...
- Sheriff?
- Yes, sir!
- Is the class ready to lunch?
- How much time do you want to lunch?
- 10 minutes would be fine, sir!
- Are you fucking with us?
- You are such a braggart, sheriff!
- You will got 10 seconds
to lunch!
- Nobody touchs the food until I say so!
- When you're finished, I want
to see a clean ground here!
- Understood?
- Yes, sir!
- Go!
- 3 seconds already gone!
- 02 isn't eating!
- Your time is over!
- Time is over, time is over!
- Can you explain me why this
food here is on the ground?
- There was not enough time, sir!
- Do you think it's fair,
on a country like Brasil,
where people are starving to death,
mr. 06, you leave this food here on the ground,
just because you're mourning, mr. 06?
- No, sir!
- Why didn't you eat, 02?
- I couldn't reach the food, captain!
- Can you reach the food now, mr. 02?
- Yes, sir!
- So get down on your knees,
and eat the food now!
- I want to see you eat all of this food, mr. 02!
- No mourning, 02!
- Yes, sir!
- If you don't eat all of this food, everybody
will spend the nigth on the water, mr. 02!
- Ah! Are you getting sick, 06?
(He says 06 instead of 02!)
- 02, if you vomit on your friends food
they will have to eat this shit
with your vomit, because you've vomited!
- No, sir! I will eat it!
- Everybody will eat this shit! Now!
- Blame it on 02!
- I want to see a clean ground!
- Stop the song, stop the song!
- Sheriff!
- This is the worst class I
have ever seen on my life!
- You all keep walking, Sheriff!
- I said to stop the song,
not to stop the walking!
I want you out of this water!
The first stage of the trainning
is meant to be violent.
The objective is to make the weak to quit.
Specially the corrupted cops.
And when I am the instructor,
corrupted cops get fucked first.
- 14, can you borrow me your medicine?
- You borrow him, mine is over!
- 02, wake up!
-  Take off your boots!
- Let me sleep...
I can't! If I take it off I will
not be able to put it on again!
- Your feet are wet! They will be fucked
up if you don't take off your boots!
- Your feet will be shit! Take it off!
- Attention, 02!
- Mr. 02, I got some news for you!
- Yes, sir!
- You are the new Sheriff, 02!
- You got one minute to put
everybody on the formation!
- Let's go, let's go!
- It has passed one minute and 20 seconds!
- Yes, sir!
- Is everybody on the formation?
- Yes, sir! - Look behind you!
- Yes, sir! - Are you sure?
- What about your untied boot?
- You animal!
- You piece of shit!
- 02, follow me!
- Yes, sir!
- Are you seeing that boat?
- Since you got an untied boot,
you will take off your equipment
and bring that boat here!
- Yes, sir!
- Do you think you can do that, 02?
- Mr. 02...
... do you know why you will not achieve?
- Yes, sir!
- It is not just because you're a weak!
- You will not achieve that because
to have this skull here, mr. 02,
you ought to got character, mr. 02!
- A thing you don't have!
- Your place is among whores!
- Your place is among whore pimps!
- Ys...sr...
- Your place is on abortion clinics, 02!
- We don't like corrupted cops here, mr. 02!
- Corrupted cops don't join BOPE, mr. 02!
- Will you bring me that boat?
- Yes, sir!
- So let's see if you'll achieve that!
You all look forward!
- Go away, 02, you're a weak!
- Ask to quit, you'll not achieve that!
- Ask to quit you piece of shit!
- I can't handle it anymore, captain!
- I haven't heard, 02!
- I haven't heard!
- I can't handle it anymore!
- I quit!
- Louder!
- For all to hear you're such a weak!
- I quit!
- You piece of shit!
- Attention class! Rest!
- Special Operations!
- You'll never be!
- Ever! Never!
- Attention, 12!
- Yes, sir!
- You are the new Sheriff, 12!
- Sir, I quit, sir!
- You piece of shit!
- You gentlemen are making me very happy!
- Many thanks!
- Attention, 08!
When the first stage ended,
there were only 8 of them.
It was time to choose a substitute.
Matias surprised me.
He got through the first stage.
But he had the bad idea
of come back to college.
- Do you know who told me you're "PM"?
- What happened?
- The hill owner! Do you understand?
- Do you got any idea of how much
time I've worked to be on that NGO?
- How much time I've worked for
all those things to happen?
- Take it easy, Maria!
- I'll not take it easy!
- You had no right to put
me and my frinds in danger!
- You're not understanding!
I have been threatened!
- You have putted our lives in danger!
- I couldn't tell you!
- You still cannot tell me anything!
- Let me speak! - I don't believe in you!
- Do you need to believe to talk to me?
- You are a big son of a whore of a lier!
- That's what you are!
- You listen to me...
- I will not listen to you anymore!
- Wait a minute...
- You just tell me if I do something wrong!
- You are doing fine.
- It cannot be open wide!
- It also cannot be very tied!
To choose a substitute isn't
easy like it seems to be.
- Is there anyone good on the trainning?
- There's a guy who's pretty good!
- Are you serious?
- Very good one!
- He looks like me on my trainning time!
The question wasn't to choose
the best one on the trainning.
The guy had to... had to do
the job exactly like I do.
I had to be sure before quitting.
- What a good new!
- In one month I think I can quit!
If Neto had Matias' brain
my life would have been easier.
But who said life's easy?
- Walking to the target! Fire!
On the second stage, we teach them
to kill effectivelly and with dignity.
Believe me. It is possible.
-
- Good one, 06! Pattern!
- Shooting with my rifle makes things easier!
- Skull!
- Now, you four... 23?
- Aren't you using your "bandoleira"?
(like a belt to carry the weapon)
- Almost finishing the trainning
and aren't you using it, 23?
- Let's see, your partner falls wounded
and what will you do with this rifle?
- Will you drop it on the ground?
- No, sir!
- Will you stick it up your ass?
- So put the fucking "bandoleira" on!
- Fuck!
- 20 years of trainning, fuck!
Only foreign people think all
"favelas" are the same thing.
They are not.
Some are reachable only by climbing.
At others it is better to
invade through the jungle.
- Target at 90 degrees, understood?
- Ok! You may call the squad!
We don't arrive shooting
when we invade a "favela".
We invade using strategy.
We walk alley by alley.
- If you're covered you may go!
- Foccus is ahead!
- Look ahead! "Close" your face!
It's indeed a bad guy face!
- If you're covered you may go!
- Look at me. Now it's slowly, 06!
- Slowly, easy!
Progression on a "favela" is an art!
And you got to be an artist
to become a BOPE captain.
- "Sliced", got through!
- Good one, 06, good one my boy! That's it!
We don't admit any operation mistakes
while conducting a "favela" progression.
- What are you going to do
now? Are you covered? Yes!
- No rush! It can be a mess out there!
You will do everything nice and easy!
- Look ahead! Can you go?
- Then go ahead.
- That's it, 06! Pattern! That's it!
Man in a black uniform
enters a "favela" to kill
never to die.
My substitute needed to know that!
- Captain, captain?
- "Fogueteiro" ran away on that direction!
- Was he alone?
- Is he alone?
- I will catch him!
- Wait! Wait!
- I'll catch him!
- Come back! Come bak now you fuck!
- 06 is going to die, Renam!
- What happened lieutenant?
- Let's go, let's go!
- He's up there, Renam, up there!
- Come back, you fuck! Come back!
- Come back, come back!
- Take off this black uniform!
- Take off this black uniform
that you don't deserve to wear!
- You are not skull!
You are a fucking kid!
- Have you heard it?
- What medicine is this?
- This one got no problem!
- Let me see!
- Everybody takes this one!
- No problem at all!
- You will not need to take it anymore!
- You will quit and this will be over!
- Am I quitting where?
- Where am I going to quit?
- You are going to quit BOPE,
aren't you?
- What happened?
- You are going to quit, aren't you?
- Everything is allright!
- What happened, tell me!
- I choosed the wrong guy!
- What does it mean?
- I choosed the wrong guy! I got fucked!
- There was two kids, I choosed one,
Azevedo choosed another! Mine's crazy, so...
- Why does Azevedo got the priority?
- You tell colonel that now you got a son...
- Azevedo gots two kids! He gots two kids!
- Low your voice, your son is sleeping, fuck!
There was just one thing that pisses
me off more than an operation mistake.
Do not "turn him off" now, let him
continue! Didn't you tell me he
was good? You choosed him, the
guy was great! What happened?
It was Rosana trying
to tell me what to do.
- When do they graduate?
- Everything is going to be ok, my love!
- Everything is going to be ok, I love you!
- That's it, brother!
- Is it?
- Are you sure?
-Let's do something! Look at these books!
- We got a beautiful indian here...
- Indian my dick, buddy!
- Knife on the skull, brother!
We are "speeded up" when we finish training
and Neto uses to enjoy some action.
Since he becomes a BOPE captain he
"falled inside" the Pope operation.
He wanted to garantee Pope's dreams.
More than 30 tramps had already
died since he began at Turano hill.
The training prepares them to war, and
it's bullshit to tell me it's inhumane.
Rio de Janeiro is a city at war.
If drug dealers got money to buy weapons
the war goes on.
Every BOPE policeman learns that.
Matias was right.
He had to confront those pot heads.
- I'm leaving, people. I'm gone, bye!
- Hey, you, I want to talk to you!
- Take it easy!
- Keep cool! I will not arrest you now!
- Who said I'm afraid of it?
- Then take that smile off of your face!
- Do you see these glasses?
- I do!
- It's for Romerito! - Give it to me!
- Take your hands off!
- You have never payed attention on the kid!
- I will give them to him!
- If you show up there you'll get killed!
- I don't walk with junks
neither with tramps!
- That's what you're going to do!
You'll settle a meeting
tomorrow at noon on the flip!
I will give them to him!
- I will not do anything! Ask Maria...
- Have you lost you danger sense?
- If you don't do this shit for me,
I will arrest you, understood?
- You fucking shitty little drug dealer!
- Do you think I don't know you sell it here?
- Tomorrow noon!
- I will put platinum on your nose!
- You're sniffing a lot, hun?
- It is us!
- Xaveco?
- There's the cargo, "galego"!
- I won't take anything today, Baiano!
- Things are "dirty" at the college!
- What commedy is this?
- Why is it "dirty"?
- That "PM" son of whore threatened me!
He said he would arrest me!
- What's that, boss? "PM"?
- What story is this?
- What's going on here?
- It is just this...
- What has he said, brother?
- What has he told you,
you fucking asshole?
- Hey, Neto!
- What's up, Andr?
- There's a message for you!
- What message?
- They call from the loyer office!
They settled an interview with you!
- Tomorrow 10 am. I have confirmed!
- I don't want any favor from Maria anymore!
- Are you crazy, Andr?
- Fuck! That's your opportunity!
That's why you're studying for!
- Take this fucking job, my brother!
- Come on, playboy, talk that talk!
You don't hesitate. Talk a straight talk!
- That NGO we work at...
- "Your ass NGO my dick", you fuck!
... so, there's a kid who's a "blind-O"...
- Fuck, it will not work!
- Tomorrow morning I got do
deliver Romerito's glasses!
- That kid has been born blind!
Can't he wait one more day?
- Where will it happen? Talk the talk!
- Fag! - Ok, I'll say everything, ok...
- He will bring it here!
- No, no, not here...
- You know it is important to me!
- You know that!
- Where have you arranged the meeting?
- It will be at the flip! - What time, fuck?
- Talk your talk, brother!
- It will be at noon, brother!
Matias told me Neto have insisted
with him to go to that "job interview".
But he really wanted to be a loyer.
I haven't had choosed the wrong substitute.
- Can I have another coin, uncle?
- Are you winning or losing?
- Losing...
- You got to win, kid!
- Give him more coins, Z!
- Romerito?
- Let's go, boss, he arrived!
- Easy, brother! There's a kid there!
Chill out! The guy is surrounded!
- Are you Romerito?
- Yes, sir!
- I got a little gift for you!
- There it goes! Now you can see better!
- Where is he?
- He's working! Try it out!
- Wow! - Now you look like a man!
- Stop bugging me!
- It is better for you to go, uncle...
(some people call 'uncle' even the dogs)
- Don't shoot! I will
finish this son of whore!
- What's that?
- What the fuck is that, brother?
- Fuck that shit!
- The son of a whore is a BOPE officer!
Activity, activity! Fuck!
- Take his body away! Take his body away!
- He's alive, he's alive!
Stop that car, stop that car!
- Get out, everybody out of the car!
- Get out, you fuckers, get out!
- Look at Lombada! Take Lombada away,
take Lombada away, fuck!
- Take Lombada away, fuck!
- Put the worm in the car!
Activity, activity, fuck!
A man who controls a "favela" can
be crazy. But he cannot be stupid.
Baiano knew that to kill a BOPE officer was
the same of to sign his own death sentence.
Drug dealers also take their revenges.
If Neto died, Baiano would be fucked up.
- Hi...
Only rich people with social
conscience don't understand
that war is war.
- Oh yeah?
- What's that, man?
You can't enter here like this...
- Where's Baiano?
- Shut the fucking up!
- Put down this weapon, Tim!
For the God's sake...
- What's going on, Tim?
- Can you tell me where Matias is?
- Over there!
- He may scape, Carvalho!
- Nascimento, he took two
bullets on his back!
- They brought him at once, didn't they?
- What do you want?
- Is your friend allright?
- No.
- I went to the police station, Andr!
- They told me they can't help me!
- What about Romerito, is he allright?
- He's fine! He's with me at my house!
- But...
... they took Roberta and Rodrigues!
- Don't worry! Baiano got social consciense!
- It's serious, Andr. Rodrigues was bleeding!
- Didn't you tell me you were a honest cop?
- Ah! Am I a cop now?
- Besides, at this time,
they must be already dead!
- I told you, didn't I?
- Burn this "X9" (rat), boss!
- No, no, please...
- Burn! Burn!
- You'll burn!
- Stop it!
- Fire!
- No, no, no...
- You never open your mouth again
to talk about my job at this house!
- Do you understand?
- What happened?
- I am in charge of this shit and you'll
never say a word about my battalion here!
- Are you understanding it?
- Have you understood?
- I am in charge of this shit here!
- Dear, listen to me!
- Go to your mother's house with the kid
and just come back with a message of mine!
- Where are you going, tell me,
where are you going?
- I'll stay around here!
'Two carbonized bodies were founded
at Pleasures hill last night!'
'Police believes that the
bodies are of Roberta Lungi,
the businessman Alceu Lungi's daughter,
and of the social agent Pedro Rodrigues!'
'Our reporter, Ana Luza, is there and
has interviewed the security secretary!'
- What happened?
- Is everything ok?
Neto's death was a tragedy to Matias.
They were friends since childhood.
I realized I could use that feeling.
I still had my mission to accomplish.
- What are you doing here?
- It is not time to discuss, Andr!
- I am not discussing with you!
- I am asking what are you doing here!
- I think I can help you!
- In wich way can you help me?
- I know someone who can help you!
- Who?
- I will tell you if you
promise me you'll not hurt her!
- Ok! Who's she?
- It is Rose!
- Now this bitch will speak it up!
- Will you speak it up now?
- Where's that piece of shit boyfriend of yours?
- I don't know, I don't know!
- Look at me, where's the guy?
- I don't know!
- That's it. It's over! You say it now!
- It is now! Speak it up now!
- You've "lost it"! Hands up!
- I'm a worker, brother!
- Worker is the bicth who gave you born!
Look at me, you don't do any fucking thing!
- Where is Baiano?
- I don't kn...
- Where is Baiano, you sick fuck?
- You got to take an answer quickly,
or else he starts twisting the truth!
- Where's the fucking Baiano,
you son of a whore?
- Where is Baiano?
- Speak it up!
- The playboy...
... playboy said he was
"PM" not a BOPE officer!
- What playboy?
- Who's this playboy! What playboy?
- Captain, captain!
- Captain, this one I know, captain!
Nobody goes to a protest
whem a policeman dies.
Protest is against rich people's death.
When I see a protest against
violence, buddy,
I feel a will down inside
me to kick some ass.
- Son of a whore!
- Stop Andr!
- Stop!
- What are you doing?
- Leave me alone!
- Stop it!
- Son of a whore!
- You sick fuck! I'll fuck you up!
- Stop it! Get out of here!
- You don't hold me!
- Stop Andr!
- He killed my friend, fuck!
- He killed my friend!
- You leave me now!
- What's this, Matias?
- What? Will you fight with a cop?
- Leave him!
- You're a bunch of sons of whores!
- Just like him!
- A bunch of rich motherfucker tramps!
- Get out of here, Andr!
- What, you bitch?
- You're just like him!
- A bunch of pot heads sons of whores!
Matias wasn't just taking his revenge.
He was becomming a real policeman.
- Open this door, you fuck!
- What's this?
- What for this weapon?
- Where's the fucking pot?
- Where's the fucking
pot you son of a whore?
- Where's the fucking pot?
- Ok, ok!
- Ok, allrigth, fuck!
- Then bring it here now,
you faggy son of a whore!
The question was if he would got heart
to go all the way through the end.
My mission wasn't to garantee
Pope's dream anymore.
It had been already accomplished by Neto.
What I needed was to
come back to my family
and to find a good substitute to replace me.
- Out of the way! Out of the way!
To do that, I had to catch Baiano first.
What I was doing were not right.
- Pull over, take off your
t-shirt! Turn back! Go away!
I couldn't mess with all "favela"'s
inhabitant to find a criminal.
But at that time, everything
was worthy to me.
Nothing would stop me.
- You do a 3-6-0 with your team at that
entrance, Andr! - Yes, sir!
- There's nobody on the "road"!
- Yes, sir!
- We will take them out house by house!
- Open it up!
- Police, hands on the table!
- Wake up, tramp, wake up!
- Good morning, son!
- I would like to ask permission
to search your house, could we?
- Yes, sir!
- Can I be your guest?
- Be my guest!
- 04, search this wardrobe here!
- Look at this, 01! These shoes
worth more than my wage!
- How did you get these shoes?
- I earned it, sir!
- You haven't earned it!
You've lost it!
- This will become shit, captain! Inhabitants
are seeing everything we're doing and...
- Renam, Renam!
- The guy killed Neto,
I came here to catch him!
- I will "break" him today!
If you want to go away...
- Do you want to go away?
- We all will end up at the
police station, captain...
- If you want to go away, take
your team with you and go away!
- Take these with you! Are
you pitty? Take them with you!
- Those who stay are
those who want to stay!
- Are you student?
Do know how to fly, student?
- Let me tell you something!
I don't want to hurt you!
- I don't want you to leave
wounded, do you understand?
- Where is Baiano?
- I don't know, sir!
- Speak it up, kid!
- I'll introduce you to the bag!
- Get him on his knees!
- Son, where is Baiano?
- I don't know!
- Where is Baiano?
- I don't know, sir!
- Where is Baiano? - Speak it up!
- Where is Baiano?
- I don't know, sir!
- Put him in the bag!
- Where is the fucking Baiano, you
son of whore? - I don't know, sir!
- Speak it up! - You're going to die!
- I don't know, sir!
- Captain, it seems he'll not talk!
- Drop his pants!
- What? Are you crazy?
- You're going to speak it up,
you fucking son of a whore!
- I'll show you how crazy we are,
you fuck! Leave this shit to me!
- Leave this shit to me!
- Stop it, fuck!
- Will you tell us or won't you?
- Drop his pants! - I'll tell you!
- Speak it up at once!
- I'll tell you, I'll tell you!
- What? Will you tell us?
- I'll tell you!
- Come on, take him!
- Fuck, Xaveco!
- It has been a long time since
they contact us through the radio!
- It's allrigth, boss! Let's
stay here! It is calm down there!
- There's something wrong!
The hill is too much calm, brother!
- It is calm, it's allrigth, boss!
- Calm my dick, you fuck!
- Go get some water and check it out!
- Here it is!
- Nobody else in here, captain!
- Let's talk, my chief, let's talk!
- I got many things to
learn from you, my chief!
- Take me to the hospital, my chief!
- You have already lost it,
you son of a whore!
- Come on... - You have already
lost it! You are going to die!
- Not at my face, chief,
to do not ruin the funeral!
- What?
- Not at my face to do
not ruin the funeral!
Baiano was dead, my friend.
- 07, bring the shotgun over here!
- Let this kid go!
Now I would work Matias' heart!
And then my mission would be over.
I would come back to my family.
I would know that someone
worthy would replace me.
- "Fry" him! He's yours!
- Wait a minute man...
- Wait a minute, fuck...
Not at my face, fuck!
"There's something very wrong with a
society that only aproves its police
when police acts just like criminals"