Come on, come on over.
Have something to drink with us. Come on, drink with us.
Drink it! Drink it! Drink it! Drink it!
Do you want gold?
Yes.
You are excrement.
You can change yourself into gold.
You broke the looking glass,
now break the stone.
This stone has a soul,
formed by the work of millions of years.
The tarot will teach you
how to create a soul.
To know.
To dare.
To want.
To be silent.
The same force the vulture uses
so siege the ox
is needed by the ox
to receive the vulture.
The fish thinks about his hunger,
Not about the fisherman.
It is the master
who seeks the disciple.
You want to know the secret,
but man can achieve nothing by himself.
To accomplish the alchemical work.
you will have these companions.
They are thieves like you,
But on another level.
They are the most powerful people
on the planet.
Industrialists and politicians.
My name is Fon.
My planet is Venus.
My business is devoted to the comfort
and beauty of the human body.
Beds, mattresses, fabrics
clothing, cosmetics...
My father is the creator
of this empire.
He is deaf, dumb and blind.
Before making a decision
he consults with my mothers mummy.
He puts his hand into her sex.
If it's moist, it's "yes",
If it's dry, it's "no".
These are my wives.
I make love to them
only during working hours.
They begin as workers,
Then I promote them to secretaries.
We know that people want to be loved
not for what they are,
but what they appear to be.
so we have created a line of masks
that have the texture, warmth
and smell of living human beings.
A customer can have any face she wants
Every face is unique and lasts a lifetime
She can wear her artificial face to the grave.
Or make-up department for corpses
eliminates the appearance of death
not only do we beautify cadaverous,
we also equip them with electronic devices.
They can kiss their family goodbye,
participate in their own last rites,
or give a live show.
My mane is Isla.
My planet is Mars.
Every morning I wake up my male secretaries.
I manufacture and sell weapons.
We produce bombers, hydrogen bombs,
rayguns, deadly bacteria,
animatter waves, cancerogenic gases, etc.
We are experimenting a drug
to create delusions of grandeur.
Another drug turns harmless people into wild beasts.
Young generation need arms
with its marches and sittings.
We have psychedelic shotguns,
grenade necklaces,
rock'n'roll weapons,
mystical weapons for Buddhists,
Jews,
and Christians.
My name is Klen.
My planet is Jupiter.
My house.
My wife.
My chauffeur.
My lover.
A thousand a week.
My art factory.
We produce a line of art every season.
We created a love machine.
To make it live, the spectator
has to work with it. Guide it,
receive it, give himself to the act of love.
With this electronic rod
he will rub its mechanical vagina.
The skill of the spectator will determine
the machines ability to reach climax.
My chauffeur is a bad lover,
he didn't know how to satisfy it.
But this woman...
I know her techniques very well.
We'll produce the electronic orgasm.
Frigid!
My name is llamo.
My planet is Saturn..
We manufacture war toys.
Workers needed in the miniature plastic bomb shop.
We have an electronic computer
programmed with the politics of the government.
The government is our client.
We feed the computer data of
coming wars and revolutions.
It tells us what kind of toys to produce.
to condition children from birth.
For example, if the government calculates
that it will be necessary to wage war against Peru
our machine studies Peruvians
and tells us what to do.
We manufacture hyper-sexed brown native vampires,
who can only be destroyed
by a cross the colour of white skin
We create a laxative that induces vomiting,
We name it after the capital of Peru
an tint with the color of the natives.
We started a comic book campaign
For fifteen years in advance
we condition the children
to hate the future enemy.
In fifteen years these children
will go off to war
to kill Peruvians With pleasure.
My name is Berg.
My planet is Uranus.
That window is wrong sized.
I don't like it.
Berg. Why do we have that enormous hole in the wall?
Close it up!
Our little baby is hungry.
- Have you finished the report?
- No.
The president wants the report.
Hurry up! Hurry!
I am financial advisor to the president.
"To save the country's economy
we must eliminate four million citizens
in the next five years."
Begin the operations of the gas chambers,
gas schools, gas universities,
gas libraries, gas museums,
gas dance halls and gas whore houses, et cetera.
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
My name is Axon.
My planet is Neptune.
I am the chief of police.
This is the most beautiful day
of your life.
Of your own free will you came to
surrender a part of your body to me.
You decided to undergo the initiation
that 999 other heroes
have passed.
Your sacrifice completes
my sanctuary of one thousand testicles.
This is the Holy Book.
Learn to believe in me.
Axon is the truth, and the power and the light.
My name is Lut.
My planet is Pluto.
My business is architecture.
When we built this multi-family complex
we made a big mistake.
We lost money.
We gave them small gardens and windows,
we installed water,
lighting and heating systems.
This was a wrong concept.
A man doesn't need a home,
all he needs is a shelter.
If we can sell him on the idea of a shelter
we can make millions.
Worker will come here only to sleep.
He won't need electricity or water.
You won't have to cook.
We'll condition him to eat at the factory.
These are communal latrine trucks
for the entire building.
You have power and money,
but you are mortal.
You know you can not escape death.
But immortality can be obtained.
In all traditions
they speak of Holy Mountains.
The Meru mountain of India.
The mount Kuen-Luen of the Taoist.
The Karakorum of the Himalaya.
The mountain of the Philosophers.
The Rosicrucian mountain.
The cabalistic mountain
Of San Giovanni della Cross.
The are many other other Holy Mountains.
The legend is always the same one.
Nine immortal men live on top of the mountain.
From the highest peak they direct our world.
They hold the secret
to the conquest of death.
They are more than forty thousand years old,
they were once like ourselves.
If others have succeeded conquering death,
why must we accept it?
I know where the immortals live
and how to obtain their secret.
In this ancient Rosicrucian manuscript
I found an etching of the nine immortals
and the place where they live.
The Holy Mountain of Lotus island.
Some men join forces to assault banks
and steal money - pieces of paper.
We should unite our forces
to assault the Holy Mountain
and rob its wise men of secret of immortality.
but to conquer the wisdom of immortals
we too must become wise men.
The elements of chemistry are many but finite.
So are the techniques of enlightenment.
To reach it more quickly
we will combine the techniques.
With the correct formula
any human being can become enlightened.
The immortals are a group.
If we are to succeed,
we must seize to be individuals
and become a collective being.
Burn your money.
If you don't want to die,
kill your money
We shall destroy self-image
unsteady, wavery,
bewilder, full of desire,
distracted, confused.
When the self-concept thinks:
"This is I" and "That is mine"
he binds himself
and he forgets the great self.
- The feet stink like a rotten dog.
- He has beautiful teeth.
I can't stand the smell!
When he'll put all your bones back together
you will like his smell.
Man learned to cultivate the earth
by weakening the plants.
Wild plants remain as they were
at the moment of creation.
They are the humble guardians of the secret.
The flower knows.
You don't need to ask it.
The dog will take your senses away with him.
He can't see for you.
The delicate scent of flowers.
It is the fragrance of the universe.
I eat the flower
And its perfume is my blood.
Together we form a dog
in search of the sacred flower.
Together we form a flower
in search of the sacred water.
This is the moment
when the word is made flesh.
How many people are you?
One, two, three, four, five...
We are nine.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
- One is missing.
- Yes.
Here's the missing one, he drowned.
He drowned.
This is the ceremony of death.
The grave receives you with love.
Surrender yourself to death.
Return what was loaned to you.
Give up your pleasures, your pains.
Give up your friends, your lovers.
Give up your family, your past.
Surrender what you hate,
what you desire.
You will know nothingness.
It is the only reality.
Don't be afraid. It's so easy to give.
You're not alone. You have a grave.
It is your first mother.
The grave is the door to your rebirth.
Now you will surrender
the faithful animal
you once called your body.
Don't try to keep it,
remember - it was a loan.
Surrender your legs,
surrender your sex,
Your head, your blood,
Your organs, your bones.
You no longer want to possess.
Possession is the ultimate pain.
The earth falls over your corpse.
She comes to cover you with love.
Because she is your true flesh.
Now you are an empty heart,
open to receive your true essence,
your own perfection,
your new body,
which is the universe, the work of God.
You will be born again, you will be real.
You will be your own father,
your own mother,
your own son,
Your own perfection.
Open your eyes.
You are the earth, you are the green,
You are the blue, you are the others!
You are the essence.
Look at the flower.
For the first time. Look at the flower.
Now you are a group.
Do you want to perform miracles like Christ?
See what would happen if you did.
Concentrate on this starfish.
When you see it the size of an elephant,
you will never miss the target.
Our thoughts have forms.
You have a monster in your mind.
We will help you.
Throw that monster into the water!
He can't swim, he will drown.
Fool! Destroy your illusions.
Free yourself from the past.
We have crossed the great waters.
Bravo! Congratulations!
You made it to our shores. Oh, this deserves a toast.
You're not the first to come to Lotus island
in search of the Holy Mountain.
I drink alone.
Because the newcomers are always abstainers.
In time they realize
that the best liquor in the world
is at the Pantheon Bar!
Come, come, come.
I have everything.
Food, drinks, beds, baths, men, women...
These illustrious travelers
came here to find the Holy Mountain,
but they preferred the Pantheon Bar!
The real Holy Mountain is here,
In my words, in my poems.
If I write "rose", it blooms in my hand
and the bees come to feed on my poetry.
Our bees make honey,
but your flies make shit.
The Cross was a mushroom
and the mushroom was also
the Tree of Good and Evil.
The Philosophical stone of the alchemists
...was... LSD.
The Book of the Dead is a trip
and the Apocalypse describes
a masculine experience.
In these flasks
are all the Holy Mountains.
and in this beautiful young man
is eternity!
To conquer a mountain is easy.
I can go through solid matter.
Nothing stops me!
In a minute I will cross the Holy Mountain.
Wait for me here.
I got to the other side of the mountain
in less than a minute.
- How long till you reach the summit?
- I don't know. I can only advance horizontally.
And that's enough.
From bottom the top I can't do,
But anyway, I am a champion!
I conquered the Holy Mountain Horizontally!
I am a champion!
I founded the academy! I give you awards!
Here you can win a trophy every year!
Idiots, you don't know what you are losing!
You could have made history,
and we are already forgetting you!
Help me!
I can't go one step farther.
You are not afraid of falling,
what frightens you is climbing.
- Rub your clitoris against the mountain!
- You're terrified of success!
Give yourself to the world!
I can't lie anymore.
My hand is frozen!
You were never able to forget your body,
never able to pry yourself from that love
and now the thing you love most
is stopping you from reaching the top.
You must sacrifice part of your body.
Cut off your fingers or go back.
We have mastered
the difficult part of the mountain.
Now the way we be like a garden.
Nevertheless at this height
our mind will decompose,
and we will suffer the vision of death.
- Lies!
- If you don't believe, wait for us here.
When I return
I will show you the difficult way.
Meditate here for three hours
before you attack them.
And you?
You don't need a master now.
You can win by yourself.
Goodbye.
This is the way we must reach the summit.
Then we will master our bodies.
If you know what you must do,
you don't need anyone.
You are the master.
Cut off my head.
Now you can begin to learn.
Unite yourself with this wood woman
who came here
only because she loves you.
Forget the summits.
Reach eternity through love.
Return to your country.
I leave you my tower
and my alchemical rooms.
Teach your family and your people.
Change the world.
Sit down.
I promised you the great secret
and I will not disappoint you.
Is this the end of our adventure?
Nothing has an end.
We came in search of secret of immortality.
To be like Gods.
and here we are, mortals,
more human than ever.
If we have not obtained immorality,
at least we have obtained reality.
We began in a fairytale
and we came to life,
but... is this life reality?
No.
It is a film.
Zoom back camera.
We are images, dreams, photographs.
We must not stay here.
Prisoners!
We shall break the illusion.
This is magic!
Goodbye to the Holy Mountain.
Real life awaits us.