# Won't you come home,
Bill Bailey? #
# Won't you come home? #
# I moan the whole night long #
# I'll do the cooking, honey,
I'll pay the rent #
# I know I done him wrong #
# Yes, you did #
# Remember that rainy eve #
# She threw me out #
# With nothing but
a fine-tooth comb #
# But I know she's to blame #
# Yeah, ain't it a shame #
# Oh, Bill Bailey,
won't you please #
# Bill Bailey,
won't you please come #
won't you please come home? #
# When the red, red robin #
# Comes bob,
bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
# There'll be
no more sobbin' #
# When he starts throbbin' #
# His own sweet song #
# Wake up #
# Wake up, you sleepyhead #
# Get up #
# Get up, get out of bed #
# Cheer up #
# Cheer up, the sun is red #
# Live, love #
# Laugh and be happy #
# What if I've been blue #
# Now I'm walkin' through
fields of flowers #
# Rain may glisten #
# But still I listen #
# For hours and hours #
# I'm just a kid again #
# Doin' what I did again #
# Singin' my song #
# When the red, red robin #
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
# There'll be no more sobbin' #
# When he starts throbbin' #
# His own sweet song #
# Wake up #
# Wake up, you sleepyhead #
# Get up #
# Get up, get out of bed #
# Cheer up #
# Cheer up, the sun is red #
# Live, love,
laugh, and be happy... #
I want to go over
to my place...
and start,
you know, getting it on...
I was terrible.
Yeah?
Did you ever, uh...
take ballet?
Be thankful.
Do you have a quarter for them?
Yes, I do.
# Bob, bob, bob, bob,
bobbin' along #
# Wake up #
# Wake up, you sleepyhead #
# Da da da da da da #
Well, what about me?
You'll see.
A lot of fun you are.
You're supposed to tease me...
give me hints,
make me guess, you know.
Oh, look. That's terrible.
He's not hurting anyone.
Neither are we.
Oh, God.
Every time I see
one of those old guys...
I always think the same thing.
What do you think?
I always think...
that he was once
somebody's baby boy.
Really, I do.
I think he was once
somebody's baby boy...
and he had a mother
and a father who loved him...
and now there he is...
half dead on a park bench...
and where are
his mother or his father...
all his uncles now?
Anyway, that's
what I always think.
How's he doing up there?
When they had
the newspaper strike...
We're gettin' better than 40%.
How about second position?
It's not so good.
Uh-oh. What have we here?
Come on, babies,
wet your lips there.
Give me some tongue.
Just a little tongue.
Come on.
How about a nice
wet French kiss now?
Come on. A nice wet one.
Pay attention
to your recordings.
She's coming in loud and clear.
Look, Mark. Do you see him?
The man with the hearing aid
like Charles.
There with the shopping bag.
Well, that's it for Paul.
They spotted him.
Give me the phones.
He's been following us all around.
It's nothing. Don't worry about it.
We're spending too much time
together here.
No. Let's stay
just a little longer.
I got burned, Harry.
She looked at me.
I know. We heard.
Oh, did we hear.
What do you think?
I got some
good pieces, maybe 25%.
Paul, I'll call you
in a couple days...
if I need you.
Paul, you going
to the convention tomorrow?
You bet.
Hey, how about you, Harry?
Yeah. Maybe.
Little party like we did
two years ago?
Huh?
Hey, Stan?
See you, Harry.
Okay.
Here.
He's a nice guy for a cop.
You go.
I'll stay here a while.
Who's interested
in these two anyway?
I don't know for sure.
The Justice Department?
No.
I figure it must be
the Infernal Revenue.
Their tapes always
put me to sleep.
Since when are you
here to be entertained?
Sometimes it's nice to know
what they're talking about.
I don't care what
they're talking about.
All I want is
a nice, fat recording.
Hello, Mr Caul.
And happy birthday.
Happy birthday, Harry.
Happy birthday.
Hello.
Hello, uh, Mrs Evangelista?
Uh, yes.
This is Harry Caul
from upstairs.
Uh, uh...
Yes.
Well...
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
Yes, well,
you're really very nice.
Yes.
Uh, but...
I know, uh...
Yes, I found it. Yes.
But what I wanted to talk
to you about was, uh...
How did you put it
in the apartment?
Uh-huh.
Right.
Well, what about the alarm?
Oh, you did?
Well...
uh...
I thought I had the only key.
Uh-huh.
Well, what emergency
could possibly...
All right.
Yes.
Well, see, I would
be perfectly happy...
to have all
my personal things...
burned up in a fire...
because I don't
have anything personal.
Nothing of value.
Nothing personal
except my keys...
which I would like
to have the only copy of...
Mrs Evangelista.
Mrs Evangelista...
how'd you know
it was my birthday?
Nah. I don't remember
telling you.
Would you like to take
a guess how old I am?
44. Well,
that's a very good guess.
Mrs Evangelista...
as of today, my mail
will go to a post office box...
with a combination on it
and no keys.
Goodbye.
Morning, Harry.
Morning.
There's an article in here...
about the convention.
It mentions your name.
You're one of the notables...
who's going tomorrow night.
I told them I'd be there.
Listen to this here.
Listen.
"Among those
pre-eminent in the field...
expected to attend...
are Hal Lipset and Harry Caul...
from San Francisco.
Kenneth Sperry will speak...
on Surveillance and The Law.
Wait a minute.
Listen to this.
Where the hell is it?
"Also attending
will be William P. Moran...
of Detroit, Michigan."
Since when did William P. Moran
of Detroit, Michigan...
become pre-eminent in the field?
Oh, he's very big there.
You want some coffee?
He's the guy
that told Chrysler...
that Cadillac was
getting rid of its fins.
It was a while ago...
but it was a big thing
at the time.
December 2nd, 1 p.m.
Shopping bag...
unit "A".
December 2nd, 1 p.m.
Parabolic, unit "B".
City of Paris, unit "C".
# Wake up #
# Wake up, you sleepyhead #
# Da da da da da da #
What do you think?
I don't know what I'm going
to get him for Christmas yet.
He's already got everything.
He doesn't need
anything any more.
Well...
I haven't decided
what I'm going...
to get you yet.
...get him for Christmas yet.
He's already got everything.
He doesn't need
anything any more.
Well, I haven't decided
what I'm going to get you yet.
Well, you better start looking.
Well, what about me?
You'll see.
Whoo! A lot of fun you are.
You're supposed to tease me...
give me hints...
make me guess, you know.
Does it bother you?
What?
Walking around
in circles.
Oh, look. That's terrible.
He's not hurting anyone.
Neither are we.
Oh, God.
Every time I see one
of those old guys, I...
of those old guys...
I always think
the same thing.
What do you think?
I always think he was once
somebody's baby boy.
No, really, I do.
I think he was once
somebody's baby boy...
and he had
a mother and a father...
who loved him...
and now there he is...
half dead on a park bench...
and where are his
mother or his father...
all his uncles now?
Anyway, that's what
I always think.
I always think how, when
they had the newspaper strike...
more of those old guys died.
50 of them froze
to death in one night.
Good afternoon.
May I help you?
Yes. Extension 746, please.
One moment, please.
Director's office.
Uh, yes, this is Mr Caul.
I have the material.
I'm calling
for an appointment.
I'm sorry.
The director has already
left for the day.
We'll call you back
tomorrow morning.
May I have
your telephone number, please?
I'm at a payphone...
and I don't have
a home telephone.
Hold on one moment, please.
Mr Caul?
Yes?
2:30 tomorrow afternoon.
2:30 in the afternoon?
Is that payment in full?
Whatever was arranged.
Thank you very much.
I'll be there.
Harry?
Hello, Amy.
I didn't think you were coming.
I brought some wine, um...
someone gave me
as a birthday present.
I didn't know
it was your birthday.
You want some?
Yeah.
I do.
How old are you, Harry?
42.
Sweet.
Does something special
happen between us...
on your birthday?
Like what?
Something personal.
What?
Like, uh, telling me
about yourself...
your secrets.
I don't have any secrets.
I'm your secret.
You do have secrets, Harry.
I know you do.
No.
Sometimes you come over here...
and you don't tell me.
Once I saw you
up by the staircase...
hiding...
watching...
for a whole hour.
You think you're going
to catch me at something.
You know?
I know. A woman can always tell.
You have a certain way
of opening the door.
First the key
goes in real quiet...
and then the door
comes open real fast...
like you think you'll
catch me at something.
Sometimes I even think
you're listening to me...
when I'm talking
on the telephone.
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
I just feel it.
Really, I do.
# Wake up #
# Wake up, you sleepyhead #
# Get up #
# Get up, get out... #
Why are you singing that?
It's pretty.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
It's just that, uh...
somebody else
was singing that today.
A girl?
Yes.
Who is she?
No. No. If isn't...
I'm jealous.
No.
Just somebody at work...
and she, uh...
She reminded me of you.
Where do you work, Harry?
Oh, different places,
different...
jobs, you know?
I'm kind of, uh,
a musician, you see.
Oh.
Freelance musician and, uh...
Uh-huh.
Where do you live?
Why can't I call you
over there?
'Cause I don't have a telephone.
Do you live alone?
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
'Cause it's your birthday.
I don't want people asking me
a lot of questions.
I want to know you.
Yes, I live alone.
Oh.
I don't feel like
answering any more questions.
Your rent is due.
Here's the money for it.
You never used to ask
a lot of questions.
Harry, I was so happy
when you came over tonight.
When I heard you open the door...
my toes were dancing
under the covers.
But I don't think I'm going
to wait for you any more.
I have a package
for the director.
All right. I'll take it.
No. I'm supposed to
hand it to him personally.
I have an appointment.
Are you Mr Caul?
Yes, I am.
A Mr Caul is here. All right.
Make yourself comfortable.
The director's assistant
will be right down.
There are some nice
Christmas cookies I made. Want one?
They're good.
No, thanks. I...
What do you see?
Oh, not much.
Here's your money..
$ 15.000 cash, as you asked.
These are our tapes?
I had an arrangement
with the director.
I was to give those
to him personally.
I understand.
He's not here this afternoon.
He's out of the country.
He asked me to get the tapes
and give you the money.
I guess I can just wait on this.
Now, look, don't get involved
in this, Mr Caul.
These tapes are dangerous.
You heard them.
You know what I mean.
Someone may get hurt.
Mr Caul, be careful.
Well, what about me?
You'll see.
Whoo! A lot of fun you are.
# When the red, red robin #
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
Who started
this conversation anyhow?
You did.
I did not.
Yes, you did.
You just don't remember it.
Pretend like
I just told you a joke.
Ha ha ha ha.
Does it bother you?
What?
Walking around in circles.
Oh, look. That's terrible.
He's not hurting anyone.
Neither are we.
Oh, God.
Every time I see
one of those old guys...
I always think the same thing.
What do you think?
Yeah, what do you think?
I always think
that he was once some--
Hey, Harry, what do you say
we take a break?
We'll go to AI's Transbay.
I'll buy you a beer.
No. I want to finish this.
I thought you turned
those tapes in.
Stan, be quiet, will you?
Do you think we can do this?
I'm tired of drinking anyhow.
What a stupid conversation.
Stan, please.
I'm trying to work.
I'm tired of mostly everything.
Tired of me?
Tired of you... but not today.
What the hell they talking about,
for Christ's sakes?
Stanley, please,
I'm trying to get this done.
All right. Don't get excited.
Well, I'm getting fed up.
About what?
About your asking me questions
all day long.
Jesus.
Don't say that.
Well, for Christ's sakes!
Stan, don't say that
again, please.
Don't use that word in vain.
It bothers me.
What's the matter, Harry?
Your work's getting sloppy.
Later in the week,
Sunday maybe.
Sunday definitely.
We'd have a much better track...
if you'd paid more attention
to the recording...
and less to what
they were talking about.
Why do questions about
what's going on bother you?
I can't explain
the personal problems of my clients.
Jack Tar Hotel.
3:00.
Room 773.
If you filled me in
once in a while...
Ever think of that?
It has nothing to do
with either of us.
It's curiosity,
goddam human nature.
Listen, if there's
one sure-fire rule...
I've learned
in this business is...
I don't know anything about
human nature or curiosity.
That's not part of what I do.
This is my business,
and when I'm...
I'll see you later.
I think he's been
recording my telephone.
I love you.
We're spending too much time
together here.
No. Let's stay
just a little longer.
I think he's been
recording my telephone.
He'd kill us
if he got the chance.
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
It's been three months
since my last confession.
I...
These are my sins.
I've taken
the Lord's name in vain...
on several occasions.
I...
On a number of occasions, I've
taken newspapers from the racks...
without paying for them.
I...
have deliberately taken pleasure
in impure thoughts...
and...
I've been involved
in some work...
that I think will be used...
to hurt these two young people.
It's happened to me before.
People were hurt
because of my... my work.
I'm... I'm afraid
it could happen again...
and I... I was in no way
responsible.
I'm not responsible.
For these and all the sins
of my past life...
I am heartily sorry.
Hi. Can I help you?
You could explain
your system to me.
Mr Caul,
I'm Jim Storey.
How do you do?
Come in and take a look
at the system.
This is for
the surveillance...
of telephone
communication systems.
I see.
Now available.
Here's the new LT 500.
If you're in surveillance,
you belong into the LT 500.
You can hear...
and know exactly which door
has been violated.
And you got your local alarms
on the doors...
which I'm sure you've heard.
It's quite noisy.
It has a Super 8mm
camera in here...
and the dot, the 10:00 dot...
will show exactly what
the camera sees on the back.
It's a magazine-loaded camera.
Super 8mm...
William P. Moran.
William P. Moran
of Detroit, Michigan.
House courtesy telephone,
please.
That's your automatic
recorder actuator.
It undetectably
starts the recorder...
when the phone is lifted...
and shuts it off
when the receiver is put back.
What?
It's real nice, you know.
It's not your old-fashioned
voice actuator...
you know,
always starting the recorder...
when nobody was talking...
or shutting it off
in the middle...
of an important conversation.
Is it like the Moran actuator?
The Moran E-27 is a copy.
I won't let him even
smell my equipment any more.
You in surveillance?
Yeah.
Law enforcement
or private operator?
Private.
You mind if I take
your name and address...
for our mailing list?
Harry Cau... Harry Caul?
I didn't recognize you.
Say, I wonder,
would you take a Model 510-A?
Free of charge. Just to test it.
You know, say, in return for...
that we could print
in our flier that you use it.
I build all my own equipment.
Thank you.
Maybe we could take a picture
of you by our booth.
It would be a great honour
for Spectre.
This is not helping crime.
It's helping justice...
That may be affixed to
the subject's automobile--
Slide.
and will transmit
a pulsating tone signal--
Slide.
which is highly detectable.
Harry, good to see you.
Beautiful suit.
You like it? It's French.
Oh.
Let's go get a drink and talk.
Requiring no knowledge
or skill in electronics.
Come on. It's a bore.
The TA-30 may be
installed and concealed...
under the dash
in a matter of seconds.
Hey, come on. There's somebody
I want you to meet...
a competitor of yours.
Hey, Bernie, old buddy.
Yeah, Paulie, what's up?
This is Harry Caul.
William P. Moran.
Harry Caul, my pleasure.
My friends call me Bernie.
I heard a lot about you.
Bernie just moved in
from Detroit.
He's the fella
that let Chrysler know...
Cadillac was
discontinuing its fins.
I heard.
You're a tough man
to get ahold of.
I've been wanting
to talk to you for a long time.
Take five. We'll get a drink.
Maybe in a couple minutes.
Honey, sweetheart,
show time, all right?
I'd appreciate if you stuck around
for the demonstration.
Um, ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
what we have here...
is the Moran S-15
harmonica tap.
This electronic marvel
can be installed...
in a matter of two minutes.
Notice here it has its own
nickel cadmium power source...
so it cannot be detected
on the line.
Once installed,
it can be phoned...
from any telephone
in the world...
Singapore, Karachi, even Moscow.
I say Moscow 'cause
you look Russian, sir...
with the beard.
Just dial the target's
phone number...
pause before the last digit...
blow the harmonica tone
into the phone...
press the last digit.
The phone will not ring
in the target's house.
Instead, the receiver...
will be turned into
an actual room microphone...
thus enabling surveillance
to take place.
And now, by way of
an actual demonstration...
we've installed one of these units
in my very own home.
I will now dial that number.
Thank you.
I pause before the last digit.
Harmonica.
I dial the last digit.
You will note the phone
does not ring.
Can we get away?
I don't know. Maybe I can.
Where's your husband?
He's out at a convention.
When will he be back?
Not until late.
April Fool.
Just a little joke, folks.
That shows you
the possibilities...
Larry Peterson Burns.
Telephone call.
Thank you. The demonstration
is concluded.
I'd like you to take some
literature on your way.
What did you think of that?
You like it?
That's a good item.
Good for
the catalogue suckers, huh?
Here you go, Harry.
Have a free pen.
You, too, Paulie.
I'd rather have a free drink.
Hey, me, too.
Stanley, do me a favour, huh?
Mind the booth, all right?
That's what I pay you for.
Just a couple of minutes
to get a drink.
Hi, Harry.
Hi, Stan.
That's right.
You two used to
work together, huh?
That son of a bitch
stole my latest idea.
A lot of nice ladies
are here tonight.
Forget it.
She's a part-time nun.
Hey, Harry, where you going?
Go on without me.
I'm going to talk to Stan.
We'll meet you at
the chrome-dome exhibit.
Don't be long, Harry.
Since when are you
working for Moran, Stanley?
Since yesterday.
Mm-hmm.
Listen, that wasn't serious.
That was just
a stupid argument.
That wasn't it, Harry.
It's just time I moved up.
I don't want you
telling him about my things.
It's not ethical.
There's not much you
ever let me in on.
Okay. I'll show you
some of the stuff.
You won't show me anything.
You'll keep it to yourself.
You know damn well you will.
No, really, Stan, wait a while.
Will you think about it?
Don't do this to me now.
Some guy's following me.
Who?
I don't know.
It has something to do
with the assignment last week.
I don't know what it's about,
but I don't like it.
Okay, all right.
Thanks, Stan.
This is junk.
You have reached
a disconnected number.
Will you please make sure you...
Information.
Number for
Amy Fredericks, please.
It's a new listing.
One moment, please.
Sir, I see no listing
for Amy Fredericks.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
Take it easy.
I'm just a messenger.
I brought you a drink.
Why are you following me?
I'm not following you.
I'm looking for you.
There's a big difference.
How'd you know I was here?
It's a convention
of wiretappers...
Oh, excuse me... surveillance
and security technicians.
It was a snap.
I'm not giving those tapes
to anybody but the director.
I know what you told me.
All right, what's the message?
We want you to deliver
the tapes on Sunday, 1:00.
The director will be there.
He'll accept the tapes
from you, in person.
You tell him
I'll think about it.
Hey, Paulie!
Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Lurleen and Millard,
get in the back there.
Stanley, get in front!
I'm trying to dress up
the boss, okay?
Take one out here.
Bernie, it's a
come-as-you-are party.
Wait a minute!
All the girls up front!
I think you take a right...
then a left...
Sons of bitches!
Those smart asses!
Who the hell they think
they're tangling with?
Easy, we're going
to have a party.
Millard, make them stop.
Relax, honey.
Paul's the best tail man
in the country.
Meredith, do you hear that?
Ha ha.
Make-4, 111.
I'm driving east on Lombard.
I'd like a rolling 10-28 on...
California 5-6-0...
Boy Adam Lincoln.
What are you calling
for a 10-28 for?
Thanks.
Hey, Willie Sanchez...
33654 14th Street...
162 pounds...
5' 10 1/2" shit head!
Want me to pick
that lock for you, Harry?
Hey, this'll be the bar.
It's freezing in here.
Oh, boy, Harry.
Okay.
All right, the bar is now open.
Stanley.
Yes, sir.
How about a little music?
The man wants a little music.
Harry, you got a nice shop here.
I was rereading Dear Abby
the other night.
There was a letter from a fella
called "Lonely and Anonymous."
I think it was Harry.
Hey!
Ahh.
Where's the club soda?
Let me tell you
something about Harry Caul.
There you go.
I know you heard this
a thousand times...
but let me say it again.
Here's to Harry...
the best, bar none.
I'll drink to that.
Best what?
The best bugger
on the West Coast.
Who's the best bugger
on the East Coast?
Me.
I'll drink to that, too.
I'll bet you will.
It's funny we never bumped
into each other in New York.
Why is that funny?
We're in the same
business, same city.
I figure we'd bump
into each other.
I didn't know
you came from New York.
Are you kidding?
Harry's famous in New York.
You know the only one
I couldn't figure out?
The welfare fund back in '68.
How'd you know about that?
Everybody in the biz knew.
Nobody knows how you did it.
Hmm?
How'd you do it, Harry?
Harry.
Hmm?
10 cents a dance.
Come on.
Ooh.
You all right?
You hurt yourself?
No. Don't worry about my head.
It happens all the time.
When I was a little baby...
I loved to love to bang my head
up against the wall.
Sometimes I still feel
like doing it. It's comforting.
I tapped my first telephone...
when I was 12 years old...
12 years old.
It was a hallway payphone
where I lived.
For six months,
they didn't know who it was.
My father, he was proud as hell.
He was beaming.
Yeah, boy.
"That Bernie's got a real brain,"
he said.
From then on,
it's been all uphill, Harry.
I got contacts you
wouldn't believe.
Here. Well, bring them over.
Take a cab over.
Nothing's sacred
with you, is it, Harry?
Sure. The more, the merrier.
We'll be here all night.
Oh! You son of a..
Ha ha ha ha!
What's the matter, Harry?
Can't you take a vacation?
When are you getting
a new scrambler, Harry?
This went out
with the Trojan War.
Come on.
I want to hear all about you.
Really obsolete, you know that?
Harry got himself a girlfriend.
Watch out, Harry.
Where are you from?
New York.
I used to live in New York.
First I worked
as a receptionist...
and then I got
promoted to secretary.
And then I was promoted
to gal Friday...
and special assistant
to the boss...
and then I married him.
Do you live far from here?
Harry?
Are you still married?
Oh, I don't know.
Probably.
I guess maybe I am.
Last time I heard...
Well, he was trying to
scrape up enough money...
to buy another hardware store.
Yeah.
And I ended up out here
in San Francisco, unemployed...
which is the entire story
of my life...
up until tonight.
Here's to you. Salute.
You don't like me
very much, do you?
You don't want to
talk to me or anything.
I didn't say that.
Something is on your mind.
I wish you'd tell me.
I really do.
I wish that you'd feel
that you could talk to me...
and that we could be friends.
I mean aside from
all of this junk.
Would you, um...
If you were a girl who'd
waited for someone...
You can trust me.
Well, you never really knew...
when he was going to
come to see you.
You just lived in a room alone...
and you knew nothing about him.
And if you loved him...
and were patient with him...
and even though
he didn't dare ever...
tell you anything
about himself personally...
Even though he may
have loved you...
would you...
Would I what?
Would you...
Would you go back to him?
Well, how would I know...
How would I know
that he loved me?
You'd have no way of knowing.
Hey, Harry!
Did you hear the one about
the broad who busted Vegas?
She wore a see-through blouse.
Where are you going?
Hey! Hey!
You know something, Harry?
12 years ago, I recorded
every telephone call...
made by the
presidential nominee...
of a major political party.
I don't want to say which party.
Everywhere he went,
that's where I was.
Coast to coast, I was listening.
I'm not saying I elected...
the president of
the United States...
but you can draw
your own conclusions.
I mean, he lost.
Harry, tell them
about the time...
you put the bug
in the parakeet.
Parakeet?
No kidding.
Harry one time actually
put a microphone...
in a little parakeet.
Is that right?
Parakeets don't happen
to be my thing...
but I sure would
like to know...
how you did
the teamster local back in '68.
What was that?
Don't you get papers
in Chicago, Millard?
Probably out on strike.
It was all over the front pages.
Harry was working
for the attorney general.
You didn't know I knew, did you?
The president of
this teamster local...
set up a phoney welfare fund.
I mean, you correct me
on the details, Harry.
I may be a little fuzzy.
Only two people seemed to know...
the president and his accountant.
They only talked about it
on fishing trips.
On a private boat...
That was the only place
they talked details.
That boat was bug-proof.
That's a fact.
They wouldn't strike up
a conversation...
if there was another boat
on the horizon.
That didn't stop Harry, did it?
No, he recorded everything.
Nobody knows
how you did it though.
Caused a hell of a scandal.
Why?
No reason.
Three people were murdered.
Harry's a bit too modest
to tell us how he did it.
It had nothing to do with me.
I just turned in the tapes.
The president thought
the accountant talked.
Nobody really knows for sure.
Three days later...
they found the accountant,
his wife, and kid...
naked and tied up in the house...
Hands and feet
tied up with rope...
all the hair on their bodies
shaved off.
The heads were found
in different places.
They killed them?
No. They gift-wrapped them.
This is ancient history now.
Harry, how'd you do it?
What they do with the tapes
is their business.
Next thing I knew,
you moved out of New York.
It had nothing to do with me.
Come on, show and tell.
How'd you do it?
For God's sake, tell him.
Turn it off, Stan.
What for?
Stan, turn it off.
They ought to hear this.
It's the best thing
you've ever done.
What was that, Stan?
Well, it's the assignment
that Harry did this week.
It'll make history.
Yeah?
There's no moment between
human beings that I cannot record...
and there's no method
that I cannot figure out.
I could figure out
any of Harry's schemes, right?
Come on, come on. Try me.
Let me give him
the assignment, Harry.
Yeah.
This is a quad
in the centre of the city.
These are steps,
benches all around.
It's 12:00 noon...
which means
that it's lunchtime...
for the people working
in these offices.
They're walking, talking,
having lunch...
and it's crowded.
Naturally. Come on, Stan.
Okay. Two people are constantly
moving in circles...
in and out of the crowd.
We don't know whether
they'll sit down or what.
They're convinced
they can't be recorded...
because they're in a crowd
and constantly moving.
Yet, they're the target.
The assignment is
to get everything they say.
How would you do it?
One system won't do it.
I could've told you that.
Why didn't you?
Go on, figure it out.
You get to their clothes first.
You pre-rig their clothes.
There's no way of telling...
what they're
going to be wearing.
Get somebody to bump into them.
Get a drunk to plant
a pin mike on them.
They've been bugged before.
It's too risky.
I got it.
You hire a lip-reader
with binoculars.
No. The client wants
their actual voice.
Why?
So he can believe it.
All right. I'll figure it out.
I don't know.
It must've been an expensive show.
Who was so interested?
Yeah, was it us?
Who's us?
Federal government.
Private party.
It would take
at least four passes.
I did it in three.
Three? That's very nice.
What did you use?
Three-stage directional
microphones...
with Mosfet amplifier
of my own design.
We got another 20% conventionally
just tailing them.
Paul did.
It was beautiful.
It really was.
It was a work of art.
You should have
seen it, though.
These new microphones
are just incredible.
I couldn't believe it myself.
We were 200 yards away.
It was absolutely readable.
I broke in a couple
of newsreel cameramen.
You should have
been there, Bernie.
What did they do?
They took the cross hairs
of the telescope...
and lined it up on the mouths...
No. The boy and the girl.
What did they do?
Oh, I don't know.
But it was beautiful,
something to see.
Yeah. Sounds very pretty.
I'd like to take
a look at that mike, too.
There it is.
Oh.
I always said
we should be partners, Harry.
You're the best, but you
and me together, that'd be tops.
I need a quick look at
your plans and devices.
I got all the
manufacturing plants.
We could make a fortune
selling to Uncle Sam.
Did you hear about
the fag wiretapper...
who could only tap
a Princess phone?
No.
Made that up yourself, huh?
It's pretty funny.
Can I cut in?
He's got a hell
of a sense of humour.
I'm talking about
making millions...
he's making with the jokes.
Come on!
Thanks a lot.
What do you say, Harry?
How about going
into a partnership?
I could use a partner,
so could you.
50-50, how about it?
I don't need anyone.
That's all right.
I do pretty good
on my own, anyway.
You got to give credit
where credit's due, right?
Abracadabra, Harry.
See, I'm number two, Harry.
I have to try harder.
Would you, um...
If you were a girl...
who'd waited for someone...
You can trust me.
Harry, that's you and me
when we were out there.
What? No shit. Ha ha ha.
It's the Moran Super P-7
pen mike and transmitter.
That's terrific!
The bugger got bugged, huh?
He got you, Harry.
And if you loved him
and were patient with him...
and even though
he didn't dare ever...
tell you anything about
himself personally...
Hey, touch, Harry.
That's wild.
When did you do that?
How do you like it?
What do you think?
Would you...
Would you go back to him?
I think you better
turn it off and get out.
Are you kidding? It's just
a joke, for Christ's sakes.
Bernie, Harry don't like you
to say "Christ's sakes."
Well, I'm sorry, Harry.
Are you crazy, too, Stanley?
What's wrong?
Let's have a party here.
Paul, it's getting late.
Come on, take it easy.
Come on.
Hey, Millard.
Know what these things cost?
This cost 1.500 beans.
On the house, from me to you.
Very nice to meet you.
It's only a joke.
Meredith?
He's got no sense of humour.
No. I'm going to stay here.
Paul!
Okay.
I forgot my bag.
Harry, I'm really sorry.
I didn't mean anything.
Come on, Stan.
See you Monday, Harry.
You want us to
put the lights out?
Night, Harry!
Yeah. Goodnight, Harry.
What do you think?
I don't know what
I'm going to get him...
for Christmas yet.
He's already got everything.
Harry, are you going to give me
a hard time tonight?
# When the red,
red robin #
Harry!
Come on. Come back.
Turn it off.
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# When the red, red robin #
# Wake up, wake up,
you sleepyhead #
She's frightened.
This is where she's frightened.
I don't know what
I'm going to get him...
for Christmas yet.
This is no ordinary conversation.
He doesn't need anything any more.
It makes me feel...
I haven't decided
what I'm going to get you yet.
Something.
Forget it, Harry.
It's only a trick.
What?
A job.
You're not supposed
to feel anything.
You're just supposed to do it.
That's all.
Relax, honey.
A lot of fun you are.
You're supposed to tease me...
give me hints, make me guess.
You know.
Does it bother you?
What?
Walking around in circles.
Oh, look, that's terrible.
He's not hurting anyone.
Neither are we.
Oh, God.
"Oh, God."
Listen to the way
she says "Oh, God."
Come here.
Every time I see
one of those old guys...
I always think the same thing.
What do you think?
I always think...
that he was once
somebody's baby boy.
Really. I... I do.
I think he was once
somebody's baby boy...
and he had a mother
and a father who loved him.
And now there he is,
half dead on a park bench...
and where are his
mother or his father...
all his uncles now?
Anyway, that's what
I always think.
I always think...
how, when they had
the newspaper strike...
in New York...
more of those old guys died.
50 of them froze
to death in one night.
Just because there were
no newspapers?
Really. Keeps them warm.
Well, that's terrible.
Who started this
conversation, anyhow?
You did.
Did not.
Yes, you did.
You just don't remember it.
Pretend like I just
told you a joke.
Where did you hear that?
That's my secret.
Later in the week.
Sunday, maybe.
Sunday, definitely.
The Jack Tar Hotel.
3:00. Room 773.
Look, Mark. Do you see him?
The man with the hearing aid
like Charles.
No. Where?
Right there,
with the shopping bag.
He's been following us
all around...
and he's following us close.
It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
# When the red, red robin #
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
Angel...
God, it will be so good...
to be finished with all this.
I love you.
It's all right, baby.
It's all right.
We're spending too much
time together here.
No. Let's stay
just a little longer.
"Kill us."
He'd kill them
if he had a chance.
He'd kill us if he got the chance.
Oh, God. What have I done?
I have to destroy the tapes.
I can't let it happen again.
I better get back.
It's almost 2:00.
Oh, please, don't go.
A family was murdered
because of me.
I know.
I know, Harry.
Everything will turn out.
Oh, God. There's no protection.
I follow them
wherever they're going.
And I can hear them.
Bye-bye.
Oh, wait, you have
something in your eye.
Yeah?
You really don't.
I just wanted to kiss you.
I forgive you.
I forgive you, darling.
Listen.
Listen. My name is Harry Caul.
Can you hear me?
Don't be afraid.
I... I know you don't
know who I am...
but I know you.
There isn't much
to say about myself.
I...
Sick when I was a boy.
I was very sick
when I was a boy.
I was paralyzed in my left arm
and my left leg.
I couldn't walk for six months.
One doctor said that
I'd probably never walk again.
My mother...
My mother used to
lower me into a hot bath.
It was therapy.
One time the doorbell rang...
and she went down to answer it.
I started sliding down.
I could feel the water.
It started coming up
to my chin, to my nose.
When I woke up...
my body was all greasy
from the holy oil...
she put on my body.
I remember being
disappointed I survived.
When I was 5...
my... my father introduced me
to a friend of his.
For no reason,
I hit him in the stomach.
He died a year later.
He'll kill you
if he gets a chance.
I'm not afraid of death.
I am afraid of murder.
Meredith?
Hey.
Bitch.
Good morning. May I help you?
Yes. Extension 765, please.
One moment, please.
Director's office.
I'd like to speak to
the director's assistant, please.
Mr Stett. Uh, Mr Martin Stett.
Mr Caul is on the line.
One moment, please.
I'm sorry. That's impossible now.
Can we get back to you?
No, I... I... I have
to talk to him.
Can we have your name again?
Caul.
Would you mind spelling that?
C-A-U-L. Caul.
I'm putting you on hold.
Mr Caul, we'll get
right back to you.
No. You don't have
my telephone number.
Hello?
Yes?
Mr Caul? This is Martin Stett.
How did you get this number?
We prepare dossiers
on everyone...
who comes in contact
with the director.
You know that means
we've been watching you.
We have the tapes.
They're perfectly safe.
The director was anxious
to hear them as soon as possible.
You seemed to be...
I don't know... disturbed.
I couldn't risk
you destroying our tapes.
You understand,
don't you, Mr Caul?
Our tapes have nothing
to do with you.
Why don't you come over now...
and bring the photographs?
The director's here...
and he's prepared
to pay you in full.
Every time I see
one of those old guys...
I think the same thing.
What do you think?
I always think that he
was once somebody's baby boy.
Really. I... I do.
He was once somebody's
baby boy...
and he had a mother
and father who loved him...
and now, there he is...
half dead on a park bench.
And where are his mother
or his father...
all his uncles now?
Anyway, that's what
I always think.
I always think...
how, when they had
the newspaper strike in New York...
more of those old guys died.
50 of them froze to death
in one night.
Just because there were
no newspapers?
Really. Keeps them warm.
Sounds terrible.
Who started this
conversation anyhow?
You did.
Did not.
Yes, you did.
You just don't remember it.
Oh, Mark, it's all right.
We can talk.
I can't stand it.
I can't stand it any more.
You're going to make me cry.
I know, honey, I know. Me, too.
No, don't.
Oh, God.
You want to hear that again?
You want it to be true!
No, I don't.
I just want you to know...
whatever you need to know.
That's all.
Your money's on the table.
Do you think we can do this?
I'm tired of drinking anyhow.
I'm tired of mostly everything.
Tired of me?
Tired of you...
but not today.
Later in the week.
Sunday, maybe.
Sunday, definitely.
The Jack Tar Hotel.
3:00.
Room 773.
Look, Mark, do you see him...
the man with the hearing aid
like Charles?
No. Where?
Right there, with
the shopping bag.
Please count your money outside.
He's been following us all around.
He was following us close.
It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
# When the red, red robin #
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
God, it will be so good...
to be finished with all this.
I love you.
These are the pictures
you asked for.
We're spending
too much time together here.
No. Let's stay
just a little longer.
What will you do to her?
...kill us if he got the chance.
I think he's been
recording my telephone.
Listen, I'd better get back.
It's almost 2:00.
No, please don't go back there.
Not just yet.
All right.
All right, honey. I won't.
15.000 bucks.
That's not bad for a day's work,
is it, Mr Caul?
What'll he do with them?
We'll see.
...kill us if he got the chance.
# When the red, red robin #
# Goes bob, bob, bobbin' along #
# Along #
Later in the week.
Sunday, maybe.
Sunday, definitely.
The Jack Tar Hotel.
3:00.
Room 773.
Uh...
I wonder if you could give me
room 773.
773?
That is occupied, sir.
The rooms are all
basically the same, however.
Well...
Do you have a room
that would be, uh...
adjoining, uh... close by?
Adjoining, just...
Yes, I do.
You do.
I'm tired of this lying,
all right?
I can't stand it.
I can't stand it any more.
You're going to make me cry.
I know. Me, too.
No, don't.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
No idea!
This is horrible...
I love you.
Aah!
It was stated that Nixon
would not deliver...
the State of the Union
message in person...
Will you cut that out?
How can you yell
at me like that?
And in my condition.
You're not fit to be
the father of my child.
Oh, what is this?
I'm trying to act like Wilma.
Well, you're overdoing it.
All right. Pull over.
What's the big rush?
I'm taking my wife
to the hospital.
She's having a baby.
I got to hand it to you.
You got intestinal fortitude.
Sit down, Fred.
You're wearing a groove
in the floor.
Look at Wilma out there.
How can she be so calm...
when she knows
what I'm going through?
How are you, Fred?
How do you think I am?
Betty, you go out there...
and tell Wilma if she doesn't...
Wait. Richard!
I want to see the director.
He's not in today.
I'm afraid you'll
have to leave now.
Let's clear an aisle.
Let these people through.
Come on, clear the way.
We'll answer your
questions upstairs.
Let these people through.
Just one question.
No, please.
Do you suspect foul play
in the accident?
What about your
corporate control?
Will your stock now give you...
controlling interest?
What kind of insurance
do you have?
That's an unfair question.
What do you think?
I don't know what
I'm getting him for Christmas.
He's already got everything.
Doesn't need anything any more.
Do you feel there's an enemy
within the company?
He's not hurting anybody.
Neither are we.
Oh, God.
...drunk driving?
I can't stand it.
I can't stand it any more.
Aah!
Take it!
Do you think we can do this?
Later in the week.
Sunday, maybe.
Sunday, definitely.
The Jack Tar Hotel.
3:00.
Room 773.
He'd kill us if he got the chance.
Hello.
We know that you know, Mr Caul.
For your own sake,
don't get involved any further.
We'll be listening to you.
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napisw <<<<<<<<