- What's your name again?
- Chrissy.
- Where are we goin'?
- Swimming.
Slow up. Slow down some.
I'm not drunk. Slow down.
Wait. I'm coming.
I'm coming.
I'm definitely coming.
Hold on.
I can swim.
I just can't walk or undress myself.
Come on in the water.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Help me!
I'm coming. I'm coming.
It hurts!
Oh, my God!
Please help!
How come the sun didn't
use to shine in here?
We bought the house in the fall,
and this is summer.
Somebody feed the dogs.
Right.
Do you see the kids?
They must be in the backyard.
In Amity you say "yard."
They're in the "yard",
not too "far" from the "car."
- How's that?
- Like you're from New York.
Mom, I got cut. I got hit by a vampire.
You were playin' on those swings,
weren't you?
Those swings are dangerous.
Stay off there. I haven't fixed them yet.
I think you're gonna live.
- It's not the prettiest thing I've ever seen.
- Hello.
- Yes.
- Can I go swimmin'?
Let me clean this thing off first.
What do they usually do?
Wash up or float up? Or what?
Keep 'em there. I'll be out in about...
...15, 20 minutes. All right?
- Dry you off. Go on, get a Band-Aid.
Got to go. Missing person.
Season hasn't started.
Nobody's even here yet.
Listen, Chief...
...be careful, will ya?
- In this town?
Hi, Dad.
Wait a minute. Let me get on.
- I want my cup back!
- You'll get it.
Wave goodbye. Bye.
Nobody saw her go into the water?
Somebody could've.
I was sort of passed out.
- You mean, she ran out on you?
- No, sir.
She must've drowned.
Look, I reported it to you, didn't I?
- You live here?
- No. Hartford.
I go to Trinity. My folks live in Greenwich.
- Your folks were born here, right?
- I'm an Islander.
They moved off when my dad retired.
- You an Islander?
- No. New York City.
You here for the summer?
Come on.
Hold it.
Oh, Jesus.
You're up awful early.
Is the Chief in there?
- Chief, what have you got on?
- Lf this new filing system is to work...
...you must keep that old stuff
off my desk. Just the pending.
Yes, Chief. We got a bunch
of calls about the Karate school.
It seems that the 9-year-olds
from the school have been...
...karate-ing the picket fences.
Chief Brody's office.
The Medical Inspector.
The Fire Chief wants you to go over...
I want a list of the water activities
that the city fathers...
...are planning for today.
Hendricks!
Where do we keep
the "Beach Closed" signs?
We never had any.
There's a truck with New Hampshire plates
in front of my store.
Just have him fill out the form.
Just fill it out.
Look what the kids did to my fence.
Eight and nine-year-olds...
- Glasses?
- Yeah, glasses.
I'll call you later in the afternoon.
I promise.
This stuff ain't gonna help me in August.
The summer ginks come
down here in June.
You haven't got one thing
on here I ordered.
Not a beach umbrella,
not a sun lounger, no beach balls.
If I can't get service...
Polly sent me to tell you
that there's a bunch...
...of Boy Scouts in Avril Bay,
doin' the mile swim for their Merit Badges.
I couldn't call them in,
there's no phones out there.
Come on, get out of there.
Take this stuff back to the office
and work on those signs.
"Beaches Closed. No Swimming.
By order of the Amity P.D."
Let Polly do the printing.
- What's the matter with my printing?
- Let Polly do the printing.
Chief Brody!
What have you got there?
We had a shark attack at South Beach
this morning, Mayor.
Fatal. I have to batten down the beach.
Albert, come on, you kook.
Keep your arms up.
Charlie, take me out to those kids, will ya?
You're gonna shut down
the beaches on your own authority?
- What other authority do I need?
- You need a civic ordinance...
...or a resolution by the board.
- That's going by the book.
We're really a little anxious that you're
rushing into something serious here.
This is your first summer, you know.
What does that mean?
I'm only trying to say
that Amity is a summer town.
We need summer dollars.
If they can't swim here, they'll be glad
to swim at the beaches of Cape Cod...
...the Hamptons, Long Island.
That doesn't mean we serve
them a smorgasbord.
But we've never had
that kind of trouble in these waters.
What else could've done that?
A boat propeller?
I think possibly yes, a boating accident.
That's not what you told me
over the phone.
I was wrong.
We'll have to amend our reports.
- And you'll stand by that?
- I'll stand by that.
A summer girl goes swimming,
swims out a little far.
- She tires, fishing boat comes along...
- It's happened before.
I don't think you appreciate
the reaction people have to these things.
I appreciate it.
I'm just reacting to what I was told.
It's all psychological.
You yell "Barracuda!"
and everybody says, "What?"
You yell, "Shark!"...
...we've got a panic on our hands
on the Fourth of July.
Okay. You can take us back now.
I'm gonna get my raft
and go back out in the water.
Let me see your fingers.
- Alex Kintner, they're beginning to prune.
- Just let me go out a little longer.
- Just 10 more minutes.
- Thanks.
All I want to know...
I just want to know one simple thing:
When do I get to become an Islander?
Ellen, never. Never.
You're not born here,
you're not an Islander. That's it.
Don't bother him. Come right back.
I know you got
a lot of problems downtown...
...but I've got a couple of problems
I wish you'd take care of.
One, I've got some cats parking
in front of the house, I can't get...
What I need is a red zone.
It's simple, you could take care of it.
Would you come here a minute, please?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Look, if the kids goin'
in the water is worrying you...
...they can play out here on the beach.
It's all right. Let them go.
It's cold.
We know all about you, Chief.
You don't go in the water at all, do you?
That's some bad hat, Harry.
Chief Brody, you are uptight.
Come on. That's it.
Tippet! Tippet!
Did you see that?
Blood!
Everybody out!
Get them out!
Michael, get out of the water!
Alex!
We don't even know
if there's a shark around here.
I can't argue with you. I can't talk to you.
I've got to talk to Mrs. Kintner.
This is turning into a contest.
It's not just the Gazette.
She's advertising in out of town papers.
I suggest we move to council chambers
where we'll have more room.
I'm responsible for public safety here.
Then go out tomorrow
and see that no one gets hurt.
It's a small story.
I'll bury it as deep as I can.
The ad is gonna run on the back
along with the grocery ads.
Right in here, please.
Move on in, please.
Why do you insist on playing the heavy?
I have a point of view and it speaks
for many of the people here.
Not only me, because I have the motel.
How do you feel about it?
Let's have some order.
Let's have some order, please.
Any special questions?
Is that $3,000 bounty on the shark
in cash or check?
I don't think that's funny.
I don't think that's funny at all.
All right, all right.
That's private business between
you fishermen and Mrs. Kintner.
Martin, would you please...
Chief Brody.
I just want to tell you
what we're planning so far.
What about the beaches, Chief?
We're gonna put on the extra
summer deputies as soon as possible.
And then we're gonna try
and use shark spotters on the beach.
Are you going to close the beaches?
Yes, we are.
We're also bringing in some experts
from the Oceanographic Institute.
Only 24 hours.
I didn't agree to that.
24 hours is like three weeks.
You all know me. Know how I earn a livin'.
I'll catch this bird for you.
It ain't gonna be easy. Bad fish.
Not like goin' down to the pond
and chasin' blue gills or tommy-cods.
This shark, swallow you whole.
Shakin', tenderizin'. Down you go.
And we got to do it quick.
Got to bring back the tourists that'll put
your businesses on a payin' basis.
But it's not gonna be pleasant.
I value my neck a lot more than $3,000.
I'll find him for $3,000,
but I'll catch him and kill him for $10,000.
You got to make up your minds.
Gonna stay alive and ante up...
...gonna play it cheap
and be on welfare the whole winter.
I don't want no volunteers.
I don't want no mates.
There's too many captains on this island.
$10,000, for me, by myself.
For that, you get the head,
the tail, the whole damn thing.
Thank you very much, Mr. Quint.
We'll take it under advisement.
Mr. Mayor, Chief...
...ladies and gentlemen.
Oh, God, you scared me.
People don't even know
how old sharks are.
If they live 2,000,
3,000 years they don't know.
Enough. You're not going to be able
to go to sleep tonight.
Here. Come on.
Thanks.
Want to get drunk and fool around?
Oh, yeah.
Mikey really loves his present.
Where is he?
Sitting in it.
Good God.
All right, Michael, out of the boat.
Tied up to the jetties, sittin' in the boat.
I'm helpin' Michael.
- Get out of that boat.
- Hi, Dad.
Just a little longer. Please?
- It's his birthday tomorrow.
- I don't want him on the ocean!
He's not on the ocean. He is in a boat.
He's not gonna go in the water.
I don't think he'll go in the water again,
after what happened yesterday.
Now don't say that.
I don't want that to happen,
you know that.
I want him to read the boating regulations,
the rules...
...before he goes out on his own.
Michael, did you hear your father?
Out of the water now!
I'm tired.
Let's stop before someone reports us.
The chief lives on the other side
of the island.
Am I comin' in straight?
Just keep rowin'.
We better catch something,
this is my wife's holiday roast.
Don't worry about it.
$3,000 buys an awful lot of roast.
Come and get it.
The tide's takin' it right out.
Can't we go home?
He's takin' it.
Go, go, go.
Charlie, take my word for it.
Don't look back. Swim, Charlie. Swim.
Come on, Charlie, swim to me!
Keep comin'.
- I can't get up.
- Give me your hand, Charlie.
- Help me!
- Get your feet out of the water!
Can we go home now?
So then Denherder and Charlie
sat there tryin' to catch their breath...
...and figure out how to tell Charlie's wife
what happened to her freezer full of meat.
That's not funny. That's not funny at all.
Mrs. Kintner must've put her ad
in Field and Stream.
Looks more like The National Enquirer.
All right, hold it, hold it.
Hold everything. I said, hold it!
- Hello.
- Hello, back, young feller. How are you?
Say, I hope you're not goin' out
with those nuts, are you?
The Weetock boat's gotta move out first.
You have to move out,
or he can't get out at all.
Don't raise sail, you're just gonna luff it.
You got a paddle on the boat?
Officer, wait a second. Wait a second.
How many guys are you gonna put
in that boat?
Whatever's safe, right?
- Yeah, well that ain't safe.
- Watch it, that's dynamite.
- Where are you goin' with that?
- I'm goin' on the boat.
- Help me get those guys out of the boat.
- Sure.
Gentlemen, the officer asked me to tell you
that you're overloading that boat.
Go on, get out of here.
- You ain't going. What do you care?
- Can you tell me...
...if there's a good restaurant
or hotel here?
Yeah, you walk straight ahead.
They're all gonna die.
Listen to me.
We've got some road block signs outside.
You've got to get somebody to help us.
Yeah, get those road block signs
out on the highway.
Because we've got more people
down here than we can handle.
What are you doing?
These are your people. Go talk to them.
They aren't mine. They're from all over.
You see the plates in the parking lot?
Connecticut, Rhode Island, New Jersey...
I'm all by myself out there.
What happened to the extra help?
That's not until the Fourth of July.
You know those guys
in that fan-tail launch out there?
None of them will get
out of the harbor alive.
That's what I'm saying. You know
their names. Talk to those clowns.
- Everyone seems to be having a good time.
- Tell me about it. I'll get back to you.
Could you tell me
how I could find Chief Brody?
Who are you?
Matt Hooper.
I'm from the Oceanographic Institute.
For Christ sakes. You're the guy we called.
I'm Brody.
- I'm glad to meet you.
- Me, too.
I know you got a lot
on your hands right now, but...
The best thing for me to do is
to see the remains of the first victim.
The girl on the beach.
- Just bear with me, will ya?
- Sure.
Wait'll we get them silly bastards
down in that rock pile.
There'll be some fun.
They'll wish their fathers
had never met their mothers...
...when they start diggin' the bottoms out
and slammin' into them rocks.
Get away from there, you goddamn fool!
What's the matter with you?
You want to swamp us,
you crazy son of a bitch?
What are these guys doin' out here?
- What are they doin' back there?
- They're chummin' right now.
- What is that?
- They're tracking the shark now.
$3,000 divided four ways is what?
Let's show Mr. Hooper our accident.
Victim identified as Christine Watkins,
female Caucasian.
- And here's the way we have it.
- Probable boating accident.
The height and weight of the victim can
only be estimated from the partial remains.
The torso has been severed in mid-thorax.
There are no major organs remaining.
May I have a glass of water?
The right arm has been severed
above the elbow with massive tissue loss...
...in the upper musculature.
Thank you, very much.
Partially denuded bone remaining.
This was no boat accident.
- Did you notify the Coast Guard about this?
- No. It was only local jurisdiction.
The left arm, head, the shoulders, sternum
and portions of the rib cage are intact.
Do not smoke in here.
Thank you very much.
This is what happens.
Indicates the non-frenzy feeding
of a large squalus, possibly longimanus...
...or isurus glaucus.
The amount of tissue loss
prevents any detailed analysis...
...however, the attacking squalus
must be larger...
...than any normal squalus
found in these waters.
Didn't you get a boat
and check these waters?
This is not a boat accident.
And it wasn't any propeller.
It wasn't any coral reef.
And it wasn't Jack the Ripper.
It was a shark.
I wanna go AP and UPI.
I wanna get on the state wire services.
See if Boston'll pick it up and go national.
Call Dave Axelrod in New York
and tell him he owes me a favor.
This is the shot I want
with everybody and the fish in it.
Guys, could we please get organized?
I want to get a picture for the paper.
- Ben Gardner get this?
- No, no. We caught it.
- That's swell.
- It's a beauty, eh?
I need a picture for the paper.
Clear out of the way, please.
Just the guys that caught the fish.
Open it up a little bit.
I want to get a picture
of the guy with the fish.
I need a picture for the paper.
Could we get the sign please?
Young fella,
could you step out of the picture?
We're ready.
- Can you get that, please.
- How's that?
Larry, you won't believe it.
- What kind of a shark is that?
- I don't know.
- I think it's a mako.
- It's got a deep throat, Frank.
- Yeah, but what kind? What kind of shark?
- Tiger shark.
A what?
We can start breathing again.
- Is Ben getting plenty of pictures?
- You bet he is.
What is this bite radius crap?
You stuff your friggin' head in there man,
and find out if it's a man-eater.
All I'm saying,
is that it may not be the shark.
I want you to meet Matt.
This is Larry Vaughn, our Mayor.
- Matt's from the Oceanographic Institute.
- Nice to meet you.
There are all kinds of sharks in the waters.
Hammerheads, white tips, blues, makos...
And the chances that these bozos got
the exact shark...
- There are no other sharks like this here.
- It's 100 to 1.
I'm not saying that this is not the shark.
It probably is, Martin.
It's a man-eater.
It's extremely rare for these waters.
The fact is,
the bite radius on this animal is different...
...than the wounds on the victim.
I want to be sure. You want to be sure.
We all want to be sure. Okay?
What I want to do is very simple.
The digestive system
of this animal is very, very slow.
Let's cut it open.
Whatever it's eaten in the last 24 hours...
...is bound to still be in there.
And then we'll be sure.
It may be the only way to confirm it.
Look, fellas let's be reasonable.
This is not the time or the place...
...to perform some kind
of a half-assed autopsy on a fish.
I am not going to stand here
and see that thing cut open...
...and see that little Kintner boy spill out
all over the dock.
I just found out...
...that a girl got killed here last week.
And you knew it.
You knew there was a shark out there.
You knew it was dangerous.
But you let people go swimming anyway.
You knew all those things...
...but still my boy is dead now.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
My boy is dead.
I wanted you to know that.
I'm sorry, Martin. She's wrong.
No, she's not.
All right, fellas...
...let's cut this ugly son of a bitch down
before it stinks up the island.
Harve, you and Carl take it out tomorrow
and dump it in the drink.
Come here.
Give us a kiss.
Why?
Because I need it.
Get out of here.
The door was open.
Mind if I come in? I'm Matt Hooper.
Oh, hi. Ellen Brody.
Your husband's home?
I'd really like to talk to him.
Yes, so would I.
Can I get you some coffee?
Wine. How nice.
How was your day?
Swell.
I got red and white.
I didn't know what you'd be serving.
That's nice.
Is anyone eating this?
My husband tells me you're in sharks.
Excuse me. Yes. I've never heard it
quite put that way. But yes, I am.
I love sharks.
- You love sharks?
- Yeah, I love them.
When I was 12 years old, my father got me
a boat, and I went fishing off of Cape Cod.
I hooked a scup and as I was reeling it in...
...I hooked a four and a half foot
baby thresher shark...
...who proceeded to eat my boat.
He ate my oar, hooks,
and my seat cushions.
He turned an inboard into an outboard.
Scared me to death...
...and I swam back to shore.
When I was on the beach...
...I turned around and I saw my boat
being taken apart.
Ever since then,
I have been studying sharks...
...and that's why I'm gonna go
to the Institute tomorrow...
...and tell them that you still have
a shark problem here.
- Why do you have to tell them that?
- I'm sorry, I thought that...
You told me the shark was caught.
I heard it on the news.
I heard it on the Cape station.
They caught a shark, not the shark.
Not the shark that killed Chrissy Watkins.
And probably not the shark
that killed the little boy.
Which I wanted to prove
by cutting the shark open...
You may want to let that breathe...
Nothing.
You'll be the only rational man
left on this island after I leave tomorrow.
Where are you going?
I am going on the Aurora.
- The Aurora? What is that?
- It's a floating asylum for shark addicts.
Pure research. Eighteen months at sea.
Martin hates boats. Martin hates water.
Martin sits in his car when we go
on the ferry to the mainland.
I guess it's a childhood thing.
There's a clinical name for it, isn't there?
Drowning.
Is it true that most people get attacked
by sharks in three feet of water...
...about 10 feet from the beach?
And before people started
to swim for recreation...
...I mean before sharks knew
what they were missing...
...that a lot of these attacks
weren't reported?
That's right.
Now this shark that swims alone,
what's it called?
- Rogue.
- Rogue, yeah.
Now, this guy...
...he keeps swimmin' around in a place
where the feeding is good...
...until the food supply is gone. Right?
- That's called territoriality.
It's just a theory
that I happen to agree with.
Then why don't we have one more drink
and go down and cut that shark open?
Can you do that?
I can do anything. I'm the Chief of Police.
We start in the alimentary canal...
...open the digestive tract.
- Just like I thought.
- What?
Came up from the Gulf Stream
from southern waters.
He didn't eat a car, did he?
Tiger shark's like a garbage can.
It'll eat anything.
Somebody probably threw that in the river.
That's it.
I've got to close the beach, call the Mayor.
You got a bigger problem than that.
You still got a hell of a fish out there...
...with a mouth about this big.
How do we confirm that by morning?
If he is a rogue, and there's any truth
to territoriality at all...
...we could spot him
between Cape Scott and South Beach.
- Where're you going?
- To find him. He's a night feeder.
- On the water!
- We're not gonna find him on the land.
I'm not drunk enough to go on a boat.
- Yes, you are.
- No, I'm not!
- I can't do that.
- Yes, you can.
I'm tellin' you,
the crime rate in New York'll kill ya.
There's so many problems, you never feel
like you're accomplishing anything.
Violence, rip-offs, muggings.
The kids can't leave the house.
You've got to walk them to school.
But in Amity,
one man can make a difference.
In 25 years, there's never been a shooting
or a murder in this town.
No kidding? Want a pretzel?
Where are we?
We're right in the stretch
where he's been feeding.
Can you get the Late Show on this thing?
No, it's a closed circuit TV system.
I have underwater cameras fore and aft.
Who pays for all this stuff?
The Government? The Institute?
This stuff cost a lot of money.
- I paid for this mostly myself, actually.
- You're kidding.
- You rich?
- Yeah.
How much?
Personally or the whole family?
Doesn't make any sense.
They pay a guy like you to watch sharks?
It doesn't make sense for a guy who hates
the water to live on an island, either.
It's only an island
if you look at it from the water.
That makes a lot of sense.
What is that thing doing?
It's a fish finder.
It's probably just a school of mackerel
or something, all clumped together.
Wait a minute.
- There's somethin' else out there.
- What is it?
About 100 yards, south, southwest.
- That's Ben Gardner's boat.
- You know him?
It's all banged up. Sure I know him.
He's a fisherman.
What happened?
I got to go down there and check their hull.
Wait. Why don't we just tow it in?
We will. I just got to check something out.
Keep the lights going.
Let's tow it in.
Don't worry, Martin.
Nothing's gonna happen.
What am I supposed to do
while you're gone?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
Don't touch any of the equipment.
I'll be back in two minutes.
This is a great white. A big one.
Any shark expert in the world
will tell you it's a killer. It's a man-eater.
A great white shark has staked a claim
in the waters off Amity Island.
He'll continue to feed here
as long as there's food in the water.
There's no limit to what he'll do.
We've had three incidents.
Two people killed in a week.
It'll happen again.
It happened before, the Jersey beach, 1916.
- Five people were killed...
- In one week.
Tell him about the swimmers.
A shark is attracted to the exact kind
of splashing and activity...
...that occurs whenever people swim.
You can't avoid it.
If you open the beaches
on the Fourth of July...
...it's like ringing the dinner bell,
for Christ sakes.
I pulled a tooth, the size of a shot glass,
out of a boat out there.
It was the tooth of a great white.
It was Gardner's boat all chewed up.
I helped tow it. You should've seen it.
Where is that tooth?
Did you see it, Brody?
I didn't see it.
- He dropped it on the way in.
- I had an accident.
And what did you say
the name of this shark is?
It's a carcharodon carcharias.
It's a great white.
You don't have the tooth?
We depend on the summer people
for our lives...
You are not gonna have a summer
unless you deal with this problem.
We have to close the beaches,
and hire somebody to kill the shark!
We have to tell the Coast Guard.
You'll have to contact
the Shark Research Panel.
You'll have to ring this entire harbor.
I don't think either one of you
are familiar with our problems.
I know that you are going to ignore...
...this problem until it swims up
and bites you on the ass!
Wait a second.
There are two ways to deal with this.
You're either gonna kill this animal,
or cut off it's food supply.
We have to close the beaches.
Sick vandalism.
That is a deliberate mutilation
of a public service message.
I want those little paint-happy
bastards caught...
...and hung up by their Buster-Browns.
- That's it. Goodbye.
I won't waste my time arguing with a man
who's lining up to be a hot lunch.
Don't do this.
What we are dealing with here,
is a perfect engine, an eating machine.
It's really a miracle of evolution.
All this machine does is swim...
...and eat, and make little sharks.
And that's all.
Now, why don't you take a long,
close look at this sign.
- Those proportions are correct.
- You'd love to prove that.
Get your name
into the National Geographic.
Larry, if we make an effort today,
we might be able to save August.
August? For Christ sake,
tomorrow's the Fourth of July.
And we will be open for business.
This will be the best summer
we've ever had.
If you are concerned about the beaches
do what you have to, to make them safe.
But those beaches will be open
for this weekend.
I want to know how many men
you're going to send.
I don't need to come to Brisbane...
...when I have a great white shark
right here.
We need men to patrol the swimming area.
We've got to have help.
Anybody with a gun or a boat.
Monday!
Is Chief Federal Officer Feldman there?
He's the little guy with a crew cut.
Operator, isn't there a phone on the island?
Could you connect me, please?
Brody to Gotcha, do you read me?
The guys from the TV station
on the mainland are here.
All right. I'll get to them later.
Brody to Scutbucket, please come in.
Brody to Daisy, do you read me?
Fascinating Rhythm, do you read me?
Come in, Hooper. What do you see?
Nothing, here, Martin.
And nothing on sonar.
Amity Island has long been known
for it's clean air, clear water...
...beautiful white sand beaches.
But in recent days...
...a cloud has appeared on the horizon
of this beautiful resort community.
A cloud in the shape of a killer shark.
- Hi, Larry.
- Why aren't you in the water?
I just put some sun tan lotion on,
and I'm trying to absorb some...
Nobody's going in.
Please, get in the water.
Do me a favor, will you?
You and the other guys take the boat
and put it in the pond instead.
The pond's for old ladies.
I know it's for the old ladies,
but just do it for the old man.
- All right.
- Thanks.
I've got Sean.
Michael, wait!
Michael, I don't like you no more.
Daisy, Daisy, this is Hendricks.
Anything? Thought I saw a shadow. Over.
False alarm. Must be this glare.
I'm pleased and happy to repeat the news
that we have...
...caught and killed a large predator
that supposedly injured some bathers.
As you see, it's a beautiful day.
The beaches are open,
and people are having a wonderful time.
"Amity," as you know, means "friendship."
My God!
Jesus Christ! Fin! Shark! 350!
Martin, get them the hell out of the water.
No whistles! No whistles!
Everybody please, get out of the water.
Everybody out of the water.
Give an answer, please.
What's going on out there?
He made me do it. He talked me into it.
Please, please, move back.
Please. Give these people some air.
Martin it's just a hoax.
There are two kids with a cardboard fin.
Everyone there okay?
Everyone get out of the water all right?
Shark! A shark!
- It's going into the pond! Shark in estuary!
- Now what?
Michael's in the pond.
Somebody do something! It's in the pond!
- Hurry up. Get that done.
- I can't do a damn thing.
Haul in your sheet. Make it fast.
You guys okay over there?
In the pond!
Somebody get a gun and shoot it!
Doesn't anybody have a gun?
- Is he dead?
- No, he's not. He's in shock.
Doctor says he's okay. Mild shock.
He can go home in the morning.
- How's my big kid?
- I'm all right.
You gonna miss me tonight?
You can watch television.
- Want anything from home?
- My cars.
- What about ice cream?
- Coffee.
Want to take him home?
Like to New York?
No. Home, here.
I'm sorry, I'm truly sorry.
You got a pen, Larry?
Yeah, pen, you know.
'Cause you're gonna do what you do best.
You're gonna sign this voucher
so I can hire a contractor.
- I don't know if I can do that without...
- I'm gonna hire Quint to kill the shark.
- August?
- What?
What are you talkin' about?
Summer's over.
You're the Mayor of Shark City.
These people think
you want the beaches open.
I was acting in the town's best interest.
You were acting
in the town's best interest.
That's why you're gonna do the right thing.
That's why you're gonna sign this, and
we're gonna pay that guy what he wants.
My kids were on that beach, too.
Sign it, Larry.
$10,000.
-$200 a day, whether I catch him or not.
-You've got it.
Get the Mayor off my back
so I don't have more zoning crap.
You've got that.
One case of apricot brandy,
and you buy the lunch.
Two cases.
And you get dinner when you get back.
Champagne, pt de foie gras,
Iranian caviar...
...and don't forget the color TV.
You try this. Made it myself.
Pretty good stuff.
Thanks.
Here's to swimmin'
with bow-legged women.
Excuse me, Chief.
Can't get a good man these days, under 60.
All gone at least 35 years.
Don't drink that.
You'll need an extra hand.
- This is Matt Hooper.
- I know.
- I've crewed three Trans Pacs.
- Transplants?
- He's from the Oceanographic Institute.
- And an America's Cup trial.
Mr. Hooper, I'm not talkin'
about pleasure boatin' or day sailin'.
I'm talkin' about workin' for a living.
I'm talkin' about sharkin'.
I'm not talkin' about hookin'
some poor dogfish or sand shark.
I'm talkin' about finding a great white.
Porkers? Talkin' about porkers?
Just tie me a sheepshank.
I haven't had to pass basic seamanship
in a long time.
You didn't say how short you wanted it.
How's that?
Gimme your hands.
Dogfish?
You got a $5,000 net
and you got $2,000 worth of fish in it.
Along comes Mr. Whitey,
by the time he's finished with that net...
...it looks like a kiddy's scissors class
has cut it up for a paper doll.
You got city hands, Mr. Hooper.
You been countin' money all your life.
I don't need this.
I don't need this working class hero crap.
You're not gonna do this
aboard the ship are you, Mr. Quint?
Maybe I should go alone.
It's my party. It's my charter.
Yeah, it's your charter, it's your party.
It's my vessel.
You're on board my vessel...
...l'm mate, master, pilot...
...and I'm captain.
I'll take him for ballast, Chief.
You got him.
Tail rope, eye splice, M-1, pliers, irons...
Sample bottles, dye marker,
flares, safety float...
...temperature gauge, spear guns, SMG...
What are you?
Some kind of half-assed astronaut?
Take that stuff down below
and you lash it secure.
Jesus H. Christ!
When I was a boy, every squirt wanted
to be a harpooner or a swordfisherman.
What have you got here?
A portable shower or a monkey cage?
- An anti-shark cage.
- Anti-shark cage?
You go inside the cage?
Cage goes in the water?
You go in the water? Shark's in the water.
Our shark.
"Farewell and adieu to you,
fair Spanish ladies
"Farewell and adieu, you ladies of Spain
"For we've received orders
for to sail back to Boston
"And so never more
shall we see you again"
- Did you take your Dramamine?
- Yes.
I put an extra pair of glasses
in your black socks...
...and there's the stuff for your nose,
the zinc oxide and Blistex is in the kit.
Goddamn women today,
they can't handle nothin'.
Young girls just ain't quite smart
like their grandmothers were.
That's got to be Quint.
Colorful, isn't he?
He scares me.
- Don't use the fireplace in the den.
- What am I gonna tell the kids?
Tell them I'm going fishing.
Break it up, will ya, Chief?
Daylight's wastin'.
Front: bow. Back: stern.
Better get it right, squirt...
...or I throw your ass out
the little round window on the side.
This isn't no Boy Scout picnic.
See you got your rubbers.
"Here lies the body of Mary Lee,
Died at the age of 103
"For 15 years she kept her virginity,
Not a bad record for this vicinity"
All right, Commissioner,
fasten your safety belt.
If you see a shark, Hooper, swallow.
Up periscope. Rig for depth charge.
How's the Missus, Chief?
If they don't like you goin' out,
they'll love you comin' in.
Keep that chum line goin'.
We got five good miles on it.
- Who's driving this boat?
- Nobody. The tide.
One time, I caught a 16-footer off Montauk.
Had to stick two barrels in him.
Two to wear him down and bring him up.
Nowadays, these kids,
they take out everything.
Radar, sonar, electric toothbrushes.
Jesus H. Christ.
Best drop another chum marker.
Damn it, Martin!
This is compressed air.
- What the hell kind of a knot was that?
- You pulled the wrong one.
You screw around with these tanks,
and they're gonna blow up.
Yeah, that's real fine,
expensive gear you've brought out here.
I don't know what
that bastard shark's gonna do with it.
Might eat it, I suppose.
Seen one eat a rockin' chair one time.
Next time,
you just ask me which line to pull, right?
Little brown eel comes out of the cave...
...swims into the hole...
...comes out of the hole,
back into the cave again.
It's not too good, is it?
Nothin's easy, is it? One more time.
I got it.
- What?
- Get behind me.
Hooper, reverse her!
Takin' a hell of a lot of line.
Get the scoop out of the bucket.
Wet the reel.
Reverse her!
Duck your head down.
We're swingin'. Get behind me again.
No more water.
I don't want you to drown me.
Hooper, you idiot, starboard!
Ain't you watchin' it!
Hooper, neutral.
Where'd he go now?
He ain't foolin' me.
What's he yankin' on now?
Go on, try it.
I don't know, Chief,
if he's very smart or very dumb.
Jesus...
He's gone under.
He's gone under the boat.
I think he's gone under the boat.
Yeah, it's too easy.
He is a smart, big fish.
He's gone under the boat.
Keep her steady, now.
I got somethin' very big.
I don't think so.
Chief, put your gloves on.
You put your gloves on, both of you.
Getting ready to run out again.
Quint, let it go.
You may be big in the lab,
but out here you're just cargo.
If you don't want to backstroke home,
you get down here.
You don't want to listen to me,
don't listen to me.
- It's not a shark.
- The wire's showing!
Unbuckle me.
- Get the other side.
- It's a tuna or swordfish.
Take this rod.
- Give the Chief a hand, will you?
- Right!
It's a marlin or a stingray...
...but it's definitely a game fish.
Gamin' fish?
Marlin, stingray bit
through this piano wire?
Don't you tell me my business again.
- You get back on the bridge.
- Quint, that doesn't prove a damn thing.
It proves one thing.
It proves that you wealthy college boys
don't have the education enough...
...to admit when you're wrong.
What's the point? Hooks and lines?
You lose one, you rig one.
Twelve minutes, south, southeast, now.
Full throttle.
Aye, aye, sir.
You see, what I do, Chief,
is I trick 'em to the surface.
And then jab at 'em.
I'm not gonna haul 'em up
like a lot of catfish.
Full throttle.
I don't have to take this abuse
much longer.
Your head's bleeding. First aid there.
Start that chum line again, will ya?
Let Hooper take a turn.
Hooper drives the boat.
Stop playin' with yourself, Hooper.
Slow ahead, if you please.
You heard him. Slow ahead.
Slow ahead.
I can go slow ahead. Come on down
and chum some of this shit.
You're gonna need a bigger boat.
Shut off that engine.
- That's a 20-footer.
- 25.
Three tons of him.
We're gonna need a bigger boat, right?
Gotta get to work.
How do we handle this?
Come up front, Martin. I need you.
He's circling the boat.
Amity Point Light Station to Orca.
This is Amity Point Light Station to Orca.
Come in, Orca.
- Orca. Come in.
- I have Mrs. Martin Brody here.
Put her on.
- Come on, Martin! Move!
- I'm not goin' out there!
Beyond the edge of the barrels.
Go to the end of the barrels, further out.
- Further out.
- Why?
- Go further out.
- What for?
Will you go to the end of the pulpit?
- What?
- Will you go to the end of the pulpit?
I need something
in the foreground to give it some scale.
Foreground my ass!
Your husband's okay. He's fishin'.
He just caught some stripers.
We'll bring 'em for dinner.
We won't be long.
We ain't seen anything yet. Over. Out.
- I'm not staying here!
- I'm begging you!
Goddamn it!
Come here, come here, darlin'.
I want you up on the bridge,
just take her forward, steady.
- I've never steered a boat in my life.
- Just watch my hand, take her steady.
Attach the end of this line to the first keg.
I've got to get a good shot
at that porker's head.
Get clear of the bow.
- Hurry up, will ya?
- Your turn, Quint.
Hooper, where are you?
Hurry it up now, tie it on.
He's comin' straight for us!
Don't screw up now.
Don't wait for me.
Come on, Hooper. Come on.
Hurry it up. Tie it on.
Now. Now.
Kill it!
Now!
Shoot!
Time.
What were you doin', anyway?
I didn't get a clean shot right in the head.
Let's see how long that barrel takes
to bring him up.
Free another barrel.
I'm comin' around again.
What do we do now? We're quittin', right?
We got one barrel on him.
We stay out here until we find him again.
We could radio in and get a bigger boat...
Don't you worry about it, Chief.
It won't be permanent.
You want to see something permanent?
You want to feel somethin' permanent?
Just put your hand underneath my cap.
You feel that little lump?
Knocko Nolans, St. Paddy's Day, Boston.
I got that beat.
It's a moray eel.
It bit right through my wet suit.
I don't know about that,
but I entered an arm wrestlin' contest...
...in an Oakie bar in San Francisco.
See this?
I can't extend that. You know why?
'Cause in the semi-final...
...celebrating my third wife's demise...
...big Chinese fella, he pulled me right over.
Look at that.
That's a bull shark.
He scraped me when I was takin' samples.
I got something for you.
There's a thresher.
You see that? A thresher's tail.
- Thresher?
- It's a shark.
- You want a drink? Drink to your leg?
- I'll drink to your leg.
So we drink to our legs.
I got the crme de la crme.
Right here. Hold on.
Here, you see that?
You're wearin' a sweater.
Right there. Mary Ellen Moffit.
She broke my heart.
What's that one?
- What?
- That one, there. On your arm.
A tattoo. I got that removed.
Don't tell me. Don't tell me, "Mother."
What is it?
That's the U.S.S. Indianapolis.
You were on the Indianapolis?
What happened?
Japanese submarine slammed
two torpedoes into her side, Chief.
I was comin' back
from the island of Tinian to Leyte...
...just delivered the bomb,
the Hiroshima bomb.
1,100 men went into the water.
Vessel went down in 12 minutes.
Didn't see the first shark
for about half an hour.
Tiger, 13-footer.
Know how you know that
when you're in the water?
You tell by lookin'
from the dorsal to the tail.
Well, we didn't know.
Because our bomb mission
had been so secret...
...no distress signal had been sent.
They didn't even list us overdue
for a week.
Very first light, sharks come cruisin'...
...so we formed ourselves
into tight groups.
Kinda like old squares in a battle
like you see on a calendar...
...like the Battle of Waterloo.
The idea was,
the shark comes to the nearest man...
...and he starts poundin'
hollerin' and screamin'.
Sometimes the shark would go away...
...but sometimes he wouldn't go away.
Sometimes that shark,
he looks right into you...
...right into your eyes.
You know, a thing about a shark, he's got...
...lifeless eyes.
Black eyes, like a doll's eyes.
When he comes at you,
he doesn't seem to be livin'...
...until he bites you.
Those little black eyes
roll over white and then...
...then you hear
that terrible high-pitched screamin'.
The ocean turns red...
...in spite of the poundin' and the hollerin',
they all come in.
They rip you to pieces.
You know, by the end of that first dawn...
...we lost 100 men.
I don't know how many sharks.
Maybe 1,000.
I don't know how many men,
they averaged six an hour.
On Thursday mornin',
I bumped into a friend of mine...
...Herbie Robinson, from Cleveland.
Baseball player, Bosun's mate.
I thought he was asleep.
Reached over to wake him up.
He bobbed up and down
in the water just like a kind of top.
Upended.
He'd been bitten in half, below the waist.
Noon the fifth day,
a Lockheed Ventura saw us.
He swung in low and he saw us.
He was a young pilot.
Younger than Mr. Hooper. He saw us...
...and he came in low,
and three hours later...
...a big fat PBY comes down
and starts to pick us up.
That was the time I was most frightened.
Waitin' for my turn.
I'll never put on a life jacket again.
So, 1,100 men went into the water...
...316 men come out.
The sharks took the rest
June the 29th, 1945.
Anyway, we delivered the bomb.
What's that?
It's a whale.
"Farewell and adieu to you,
fair Spanish ladies
"Farewell and adieu, you ladies of Spain"
"Show me the way to go home
"I'm tired and I want to go to bed
"I had a little drink about an hour ago
"And it's gone right to my head
"Wherever I may roam
"By land, or sea, or foam
"Show me the way to go home
"I'm tired and I want to go to bed
"I had a little drink about a hour ago
"And it's gone right to my head
"Wherever I may roam
"On land or sea or foam
"You can always hear me singing this..."
Start the engines.
Fire her up!
Put out the fire, will ya?
- Pump her out.
- Done.
- Everybody on deck.
- He ate the light.
- Terrific.
- Excuse me.
Quint, what are you doing?
Don't waste your time.
What's wrong with this?
Hooper, take the wheel.
Brody, follow that. Watch for him.
You okay?
More left rudder.
Pull your left hand down.
I can't. It'll only go about three inches.
All of our injectors got scored
from the salt water in the fuel.
Yeah, the housing's bent, you can hear it.
Try the left rudder again. More left.
Good. Once again now.
There it is.
What do you say, Chief?
The barrel is up, it's right in the stern.
I think he's right under the keg.
Grab the boat hook.
If we can get close enough...
...l've got things on board that'll kill it.
- Just want to goose him up. Come on.
When he runs, you drop that rope
or you'll lose your hands.
I've seen fingers torn out at the knuckles.
Whole sea's bones, full of 'em.
Give it to me a minute.
Haul in that line or it'll foul us.
Start the engine.
- Where are you goin'?
- I'm gonna make a phone call.
Hello, mayday, Orca. Coast Guard?
Coast Guard, this is the Orca.
Do you read me?
Coast Guard, this is the Orca. Do you...
Excuse me, Chief.
That's great. That's just great.
Now, where the hell are we?
You're certifiable, Quint.
You know that? You're certifiable.
- You're certifiable, but I'll tell you this!
- Boys.
I think he's come back for his noon feeding.
Hook me up another barrel.
Bring her around after him.
Full throttle.
Get me right up alongside of him.
I can't rev it up that high,
it's not gonna take it.
Five degrees port.
All right, hold your course.
Five degrees port now.
Hold your course.
- Fast fish.
- Watch my hand.
Be sure you watch my hand.
Follow me. Follow me.
Lad, you watch him now.
Starboard. Starboard.
Run him down.
Hard apart.
Watch him.
Starboard.
I can't believe it.
Two barrels and he's going down again.
It's incredible.
- They're up again!
- Now what?
Why don't we lead the shark into shore
instead of him leading us out to sea?
Grab a couple of poles.
Hang on now, we're going around.
Into starboard. Easy.
I'm gonna back her off now.
Keep a watch on it, boys. Watch him.
All right, gentlemen, snag them.
Now then tie them to the stern cleats.
Brody, bring your end around the cleat.
That's right, it'll lock itself off.
Give him room, Brody.
Stay clear of the line.
Watch it. Stand clear.
Stand away from those stern cleats.
Back home we got a taxidermy man.
He gonna have a heart attack
when he sees what I brought him.
Throttle back. You're losing the cleats.
My God, this one, too. They're both going.
- He's eating his way through that line.
- He's working his way right up to us.
Come on, Quint. Hurry!
Out of my way.
Watch it.
Untie this. He'll pull out the transom.
Make it fast.
I can't. It's trying to run.
Pull, you son of a bitch!
Go ahead. Pull your bloody heart out.
It's impossible!
We're breaking up! Cut it!
Watch your hands!
Cut it quick. I can't hold it!
He can't stay down
with three barrels on him.
Not with three barrels, he can't.
What about us?
Get the pump out of the locker
in front of you, will you?
We're gonna sink, aren't we?
Keep an eye on the barrels.
Pump it out, Chief.
Starting to go under.
He can't with three barrels on him.
Not with three he can't.
You ever have one do this before?
No.
He's chasin' us. I don't believe it.
I'm gonna draw him into the shallows.
Draw him into the shallow water.
I'm gonna draw him in and drown him.
- We're headin' in, Brody.
- Thank Christ!
- You ever had a great white do that?
- No.
How far do we have to go?
Don't put that much pressure on it.
- Goddamn it.
- Shut up. Get back there.
Hold on.
"Farewell and adieu to you,
fair Spanish ladies
"Farewell and adieu, you ladies of Spain
"For we received order
for to sail back to Boston"
You idiot, you burned out the bearings.
All right stop the boat. Stop the boat.
Stop it.
What exactly can you do
with these things of yours?
I think I can pump 20 ccm
of strychnine nitrate into him.
If I can get close enough.
Get this little needle through his skin?
No, I can't do that.
If I can get him close to the cage,
I can get him in the mouth.
- That shark'll rip that cage to pieces.
- You got any better suggestions?
Easy.
Up she goes.
Ain't got no spit.
Try and keep him off me until I'm lower.
Okay, okay, I'm ready.
Bring him up, goddamn it.
Bring him up now!
Pull it up. Pull it.
Come on, Quint, bring him in.
It's giving way.
Rig something!
Got it?
It's comin'.
Slower.
Show me the tank.
Blow up!
Smile, you son of a bitch!
Quint?
No.
Can we get in on those?
What day is this?
It's Wednesday. It's Tuesday, I think.
I think the tide's with us.
Keep kicking.
I used to hate the water.
I can't imagine why.
Subtitles by SubRip