You all right?
Shit's really hitting the fan.
FOSTER: [ON TV]:
What difference does it make?
-That's a different study.
BERMAN [ON TV]: But if we knew that-
FOSTER [ON TV]: We don't know that.
We don't know that.
We've gotta operate
on what we do know.
I'm still dreaming.
No, you're not.
FOSTER [ON TV]: It's human beings
whose lives we're trying to save.
My turn with the coat.
FOSTER [ON TV]:
I try to explain several times.
The guys on the crew are going crazy.
A couple of them
have flown the coop already.
I don't know how long
we're gonna stay on the air.
Who's on camera?
Who the hell's on camera?
Who the hell's on camera two,
a blind man?
Roll the rescue-
Roll the rescue stations.
We just got a report that half those
stations have been knocked out.
Get me another list.
Sure, I'll just pull it out of my ass, right?
-Believe the dead are returning to life?
-I'm not--
You believe the dead are returning
to life and attacking the living?
I'm not so sure what to believe, doctor.
All we get is what you people tell us,
it's hard enough to believe--
It's fact. It's fact.
It's hard enough to believe
without you coming in here-
You're not running a talk show here,
Mr. Berman.
You can forget pitching an audience
the moral bullshit they wanna hear.
BERMAN [ON TV]: You're talking about
abandoning human....
Frannie, get the list of rescue stations.
Charlie's receiving on the emergencies.
Rescue stations?
Half of those are inoperative as of now.
Charlie, these are rescue stations.
We can't send people
in inoperative rescue stations.
We've had old information on the air
for the last 12 hours.
-Kill those old ones.
-Givens wants them.
Kill them, Dick. Tell Givens to see me.
FOSTER:
You have not listened.
You have not listened in the situation
for three weeks.
What does it take?
What does it take to make people see?
People aren't willing to accept
your solutions, doctor.
And I, for one, don't blame them.
Every dead body that is not exterminated
becomes one of them.
It gets up and kills.
The people it kills get up and kill.
Operative rescue stations.
Dan!
Yeah, that's the one, kid. Type that up.
They're dropping like flies.
I think Foster's right. We're losing it.
We're blowing it ourselves.
The dead body must be exterminated
either by destroying the brain...
...or severing the brain
from the rest of the body.
The situation must be controlled...
before it is too late
too rapidly
What's going on?
Who killed those supers?
I didn't order to do that.
Garrett, who told you
to kill those supers?
Nobody, I killed them.
They're out of date.
-Do you know you're on the air?
-What is going on?
I want those supers on the air
all the time.
Without those rescue situations on-screen
every minute, people won't watch us.
They'll tune out.
You willing to murder people
by sending them to stations...
...that have closed down?
I want that list up on the screen
every minute that we're on the air.
LUCAS: Anybody need a ride?
-What the hell are you doing?
Get back here on this console.
What is this, the news show
or a football game?
Get that idiot off the air!
This is supposed to be a doggone
news television show!
Officer, stop those men.
Lucas, get back here on the console!
Damn.
Get somebody in here
who can run this thing.
Get that fucking idiot off the air!
Get someone. Triple pay!
We're staying on the air!
My God. Turn it off!
Dr. Foster, so what's the facts?
The public needs facts.
What do you have to give us?
They kill for one reason.
They kill for food.
They eat their victims.
Do you understand that, Mr. Berman?
That's what keeps them going.
If we'd listened, if we'd dealt
with this phenomenon properly...
...without emotion, without emotion,
it wouldn't have come to this.
There is a martial law state
in effect in Philadelphia...
...as in all other major cities
in the country,
Hold it, friend. Need a badge.
Hey, what's going on?
It's just crazy.
Here.
Should we be unable to check this threat...
beacuse of the emotional attitude of the citizens
Jim, you take it.
It is the order of the OEP by command
of the federal government...
...the president of the United States.
Citizens may no longer occupy
private residences...
...no matter how safely protected
or well-stocked.
Citizens will be moved in the central areas of the city.
The bodies of the dead
will be delivered over...
...to specially equipped squads
of the national guard......
Frannie, meet me on the roof at 9:00.
We're getting out.
-I don't believe this, what...?
-Get out in the chopper.
David, we can't, we've got.....
Is 9 p.m. all right?
-Stephen, we can't. We've got to-
-We've got to nothing, Fran.
We've got to survive.
Somebody's got to survive.
Now, you be upstairs at 9:00,
and don't make me come looking for you.
Go ahead. We'll be off the air
by midnight anyway.
The emergency networks
are taking over.
Our responsibility is finished.
POLICE CHIEF: Martinez.
You know we've got this building
surrounded.
Little bastard's got them moved
into one building. Dumb little bastard.
-Come on.
POLICE CHIEF: Martinez.
The people in this project
are your responsibility.
POLICE CHIEF:
We don't want any of them hurt.
neither you
I'm giving you 3 minutes Martinez
POLICE CHIEF: I'm giving you 3 minutes Martinez
POLICE CHIEF: Turn over your weapons and surrender
There is no charge against you
POLICE CHIEF: There were no charges
against you or any of your people.
Yet.
Come on, Martinez,
Yeah, Martinez,
show your greasy little Puerto Rican ass...
...so I can blow it right off.
Blow all their asses off,
lowlife bastards.
Blow all their lowlife little Puerto Rican
and nigger asses right off,
-You're Rod, right?
-Rod Tucker.
How the hell come we stick
these lowlife bastards...
...in these big ass fancy hotels anyway?
Shit, man. This is better than I got.
Hey, you ain't gonna talk them
out of here.
-You gotta blow them out.
-Just stay cool, okay?
When we go in there, don't pop off,
all right?
I'll be okay.
Come on, let's get on with it.
This is a waste of my time.
Let's go, let's go!
Jesus Christ.
POLICE CHIEF:
Move in. Move in.
Goddamn it.
Come on, you dumb bastards.
Come and get them.
Rico, look out!
Hold it.
Don't go out there!
MAN [ON RADIO]:
Gas. Gas.
Masks.
CHIEF: Masks for gas. Masks for gas.
POLICEMAN 1: Down there.
Come on, work yourselves down.
One floor at a time. Deep down here.
-Hands up.
-Damn.
Steve, don't go!
No, let me go!
Come on, you little bastards, ha, ha.
Wooley's gone ape shit, man.
-Woo ley!
-He-he-he-hey.
Give me a hand here, man.
Yah!
What the hell, man?! Leave me alone!
Give me a hand, somebody!
Don't do anything, man.
Goddamn it. Help me, he's crazy.
Step away from him.
Not that room. Not that room.
Do that again.
Come on.
Jesus Christ.
Come on, come on,
You don't want to see that.
Shoot it, man.
Shoot it in the head.
No! No!
Miguel.
Miguel. Miguelito.
Watch out for the girl.
For chrissakes, stand clear.
Oh, no, please. No, no, please.
MAN: You ain't just in here
by yourself, boy.
You was in Wooley's unit, wasn't you?
I didn't see nothing.
I didn't see how he died.
Man, there's a lot of people
who were running out.
I could run.
I could run right tonight.
Friend of mine's got this helicopter.
He asked me to come with him.
Think it's right to run?
Setters, please let me pass.
Let's get him to the medics.
No, no, please.
Just let me pass.
I go up to seventh floor to find my sister.
The people of 107 will do
what you wish now.
Many have died last week
on these streets.
In the basement of this building,
you'll find them.
I have given them the last rites.
Now, you do what you will.
You are stronger than us.
But soon, I think they be stronger
than you.
When the dead walk, senores,
we must stop the killing...
...or we lose the war,
Hurry, get up! Get it off!
Jesus Christ.
Hey, you okay down there?
Yeah.
This must be
where they dumped them in, huh?
-You need more men?
-No, it's all done, man.
It's all been done.
Jesus Christ.
Why did these people keep them here?
Because they still believe
there's respect in dying.
Come on I need you
I don't see Roger...
we'll give him 10 minutes
Steve
just wait right here
just like that...
line in a car
just hold it there..
...captain.
Moving on the top fl--
The line's not coming in at all.
Hello, HQ, this is police dock.
Operator dead. Post abandoned.
Stephen.
I hope that's Roger.
- What are you doing
- I'll be right there
Just stay cool
- Hello
- Come on Skipper
They got friends coming
We're with GON
No, wait a minute
We're just here to refuel
Those men were already dead
And you were here, you know that
GON traffic watch
no shit
How many will that thing hold
Hey man, I ain't going nowhere
That's true
We'd be stuck, stick with the boat
We gotta walk further in this bird
Hey that's a squad car
It's OK, we're pleased
Bullshit man
You and your friends are running in the GON traffic
What's the problem officer
You got your friends here stealing company gasoline
What do you mean by friends
You guys okay?
Who's he?
His name is Peter. He's all right.
Come on, let's hustle.
Hey, you guys,
you better get a move on.
There's a report at the dock's
being knocked out.
Right. The left squad.
Can we carry the extra weight?
A little harder on the fuel,
but we'll be okay.
Hey, you got any cigarettes?
Any of you guys got cigarettes?
No, sorry.
Where you headed?
Downriver.
We got an idea.
Maybe we can make it to the islands.
What islands?
Any island.
What about you? Where you headed?
Straight up.
Have you got any cigarettes?
I never had a cigarette.
Did any of you guys got cigarettes?
an ex-husband
an ex-wife
- You Peter?
- Some brothers
Those real brothers?
you know real brothers or street brothers
both
How many real ones?
- Two
- Two?
One is in jail
The other is a pro ball player
But we catch up each other once in a while
Is he your man?
Most of the time, yeah.
Just like to know who everybody is.
Yeah, me too.
Got any more water?
You know where we are?
Yeah, I know exactly where we are.
Harrisburg?
Passed it about an hour ago.
Jesus. It's everywhere.
We're still pretty close to Johnstown.
Those rednecks are probably enjoying
the whole thing.
What are you looking at?
Happy hunting.
MAN 1: I heard there about
ten or 12 down in the woods.
MAN 2:
I got at least 14 shells.....
MAN 3: I got a couple extra boxes
in case they come around later on.
Look out, behind you.
Get down, get down. Get out of the way!
There, by the old car.
Hit the gas tank.
Shit.
Ah.
Eh, got him.
Ah, missed.
Got the bitch.
Ah, shit, man, damn near empty.
I got this one.
There's a lot of private planes
in farm country like this.
I guess they all hit the pumps
and they took off,
Yeah, to where?
I got some here.
-Can you handle that?
-Yeah, I got it.
I'm gonna see what's left
in the hangars.
Bunch of junk.
Stephen?
Run! Run!
Run!
Oh.
Run.
Roger!
It's all right. It's okay. It's all right.
Peter!
[MURMURING]
Son of a bitch.
PETER:
You never aim a gun at anyone, mister.
FRANCINE:
Peter!
Scary, isn't it?
isn't it?
We gotta find fuel.
Maybe closer to Cleveland.
No, we gotta stay out of the big cities.
if it's like Philly,
we may never get out alive.
PETER: We may never get out
of any place alive.
We almost didn't get out of here.
ROGER:
We're getting out of here fine.
As long as there's not many
of those around, we can handle them.
Yeah, well, it wasn't those things
that nearly blew me away.
We gotta stay in the sticks.
I mean, there's bound to be more
private airports upstate.
There's the locks along the Allegheny.
Fuel stations there, state, private.
Those are probably still manned.
We don't need those hassles either.
-They're just out after scavengers, looters.
-You got papers for this limousine?
I got GON ID. So does Fran.
Right, and we're out
doing traffic reports.
Wake up, sucker.
We're thieves and we're bad guys.
That's exactly what we are.
We gotta find our own way.
We don't even know
where we're going.
We don't have food, we don't have water.
We don't even have a radio.
Stephen, you need to get some sleep.
STEPHEN:
What the hell is it?
ROGER: Looks like a shopping center,
one of those big indoor malls.
FRANCINE:
Oh, my God.
No chance. Let's get out of here.
-Wait a minute. They can't get up here.
STEPHEN: We can't go down there.
ROGER:
Let's check it out.
Most of the gates are down.
I don't think they can get into the stores.
I haven't seen any of them
up on the second floor.
The big department stores
usually use both floors.
If we can get in up top....
Okay.
Guess the power's not off in this area.
Could be nuclear.
What are they doing?
Why do they come here?
Some kind of instinct.
STEPHEN:
Memory of what they used to do.
This was an important place
in their lives.
Hey, look at this.
This doesn't go down into the mall.
What the hell is this?
How do we get down there?
STEPHEN:
Come down. Come on, drop.
There, let's go.
Looks like a free lunch.
"SPAM."
Did you bring a can opener?
No, I guess I didn't.
Then don't knock it. It's got its own key.
What do you think?
This is the only way up here.
[MOUTHING]
No, thanks.
You better get some sleep too, buddy.
There's an awful lot of stuff down there
that we could use.
-I know it.
-It's a big place.
But they're pretty spread out
down there.
I think we can outrun them.
-Hit and run?
-Hit and run.
You're crazy.
This place could be a gold mine.
We gotta at least check it out.
This is exactly what we're trying
to get away from. Look what....
-Stephen.
-Leave him be. We're going ourselves.
That's ready to shoot. Be careful.
The trigger squeezes real easy.
But the weapon will kick you good
when it fires. Be ready for that.
Anyone but us comes up them stairs,
you guys take off in the machine.
You'll probably hear some shooting.
Just don't panic, okay?
Here.
Keys to the kingdom.
Grab the walkie-talkies.
It's Christmas down there buddy
brother, how we're gonna work it?
We're getting in one of the apartment stores up here
they probably have their own escalaters inside
Let's check those keys
Fifteen upper and lower,
Right here.
How about a little music?
-What?
-Might cover the noise we make.
Hit them all. Might as well
have power in everything.
We might need it.
[MURMURING]
Jesus Christ.
Stephen? Stephen.
What do you think,
bag it or try for it?
-You game?
-I need lighter fluid.
You got it.
Jesus Christ. They're maniacs.
Wait.
All right.
Come on.
Stephen, don't go down there.
Why? What's the matter?
Won't open.
Not working.
-To the right.
-Let's go.
ROGER:
Come on.
Come on, don't give in.
Don't open the door, Come on, let up.
Let it go, Take care of the other one.
FRANCINE:
Stephen, for God's sake.
Let's get up to the roof.
We can't leave those guys down there.
ROGER: Well, we're in. Now how the hell
are we gonna get back?!
PETER: Who the hell cares?
Let's go shopping first!
PETER: Whoo!
ROGER: Ah!
ROGER:
Watches. Watches.
PETER: Hey, hey, hey,
let's get the stuff we need.
I'll get a television and a radio.
ROGER: Oh, lighter fluid,
and chocolates, chocolates.
PETER:
Okay.
ROGER: Whoo!
Oh, I'm gonna need a coat.
PETER: Why not? It's about time.
ROGER: Whoo!
Hey, man, we can't carry all that shit.
Oh, I see, we're gonna just wheel
right by them.
We gonna try, brother.
We ain't doing this for the exercise.
We might as well try to get what we can.
No way this is gonna happen.
Hey, Peter!
Whoa! Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
All right, let's go, brother.
The old okeydoke.
-Okay.
-All right.
Hey, hey, ugly.
Let's raise some hell. Hey, hey.
-Come here, chump. Come here.
-Come on.
ROGER:
Hey, hey.
PETER:
Hey, come on!
-Come on over here.
-Over here, that's right.
PETER:
Come on, come on, come on.
ROGER:
Come here.
ROGER: [LAUGHS] Come on.
Come here. Whoo, whoo, whoo.
-All right, come on.
-Hey, hey, hey.
Come on, over here.
Just give it time. Give it time.
Okay, they're coming.
Go on up. Stay out of sight.
Let me know when it's clear enough.
-Okay.
Come to papa. That's it, keep coming.
Keep coming.
[LOW VOICE]
Good, good, good.
-Peter, it's good. Let's do it.
-Is it clear?
Not altogether,
but they're spread out good.
I think we can move the wagon.
PETER [ON RADIO]:
I'm coming. [STATIC]
What the hell is that?
I don't know. Fuzz maybe?
-Maybe flyboy. Where's it coming from?
-Don't know. I can't tell.
Come on. Open up.
-Maybe I ought to go with you.
-Open up, I can get the wagon over.
If it's flyboy, let's get him on our side.
Okay.
Just cover me good, you hear?
You got it.
PETER:
Hold it, flyboy.
Don't go into the stairway.
Don't open that door, baby.
You'll lead them right up with you.
Run for it. Run this way.
That's it, come on. Run, run, run.
Come on. All right, all right, all right.
Now head for the department store. Go.
Come on, come on,
Okay, downstairs again, same trick.
Let's go.
STEPHEN: What do we do?
-Let them know we're here.
Come on, let's go. Over here.
You did all right this time, flyboy.
How about it?
Over here.
Come on.
MAN [ON PA SYSTEM]:
Now this is time to save shoppers...
...with our weekend sale-o-rama.
Chairs sold with sectional love seats
all reduced.
-This week's major offer...
-Jesus Christ.
...is a contemporary dining room set
with a 40-by-60 burlap tablecloth....
Why pay more
when the sales are often right here?
-We'll have a hell of a time getting back.
-We gotta wait before we move.
No. There's always a chance of some
of them staying up on the balcony.
ROGER:
We can handle that. Break through them.
If any of them see us or hear us,
they'll just follow us on up.
It's no good.
We sure in hell can outrun them. Load up
what we got and get the hell out of here.
I've been thinking...
...maybe we got
a good thing going here.
Maybe we shouldn't be
in such a hurry to leave.
Oh, man.
If we can get back up there,
without them catching on...
...we can hold up for a while.
At least long enough to catch a breath.
Check out the radio.
See what's happening.
There's some kind of passageway
over the tops of these stores.
I don't know if it's just heating ducts
or some kind of access.
I saw it on a map.
Upstairs. Let's go.
These are just lighting fixtures.
No, it's got to be in this area.
It's on the map.
Elevator shaft.
PETER:
Hold the doors.
It's here.
Get me a screwdriver and something
to stand on from down there.
Uh, I know where the tools are.
Why don't you grab that stool over there?
It's all right. We can get it off.
You found it, fly boy.
One-stop shopping. Everything you need
right at your fingertips.
PETER: Phillips.
-Here you go,
Stephen?
ROGER:
Sweet Jesus.
I've seen it. Come on.
Don't shoot.
They'll hear you downstairs.
Looks like we're gonna be okay.
You should see all the great stuff we got,
Frannie. All kinds of stuff.
This place is terrific.
It really is. It's perfect.
All kinds of things.
We really got it made here, Frannie.
What the hell time is it, anyway?
Not quite 9.
And nothing?
As long as we're getting the pattern,
that must mean they're sending the signal.
MAN [ON RADIO]: No longer
seek occupancy in private residences...
...no matter how safe
or well-protected they may be.
The president today
has sent to Congress,..
... a package of initiatives...
...aimed at what sources call
a most sweeping set....
PETER:
She all right? She looks blown.
-What do you expect?
-No, I mean she really looks sick.
-Physically.
-She's pregnant.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
That communications with Detroit...
...have been knocked out...
...along with Atlanta, Boston....
ROGER:
Well, how far along?
Three and a half, four months.
Jesus.
Maybe we should try to get moving.
We can deal with it.
Yeah, but maybe she needs
a doctor or something.
We can deal with it.
Doesn't change a thing.
MAN [ON RADIO] ...sections
of Philadelphia and New York City.
You wanna get rid of it?
Huh?
Do you want to abort it?
It's not too late. And I know how.
MAN [ON RADIO]: In other reports
now coming into our department....
-Foreign sources.....
-Let's get some sleep.
...power crises throughout Europe...
...and parts of Asia, where a state
of martial law will take effect...
.....in scattered areas this evening.
Citizens there have been asked
to understand...
...the dire, dire consequences
of this phenomenon.
The Southern Hotel
and Motel Association of America...
...today issued a strong denial
that troubles.....
All your decisions made?
Do you wanna abort it?
Do you?
Somebody better sit watch all the time.
-They'll never get through there.
-Enough of them will.
And it ain't just them things
we got to worry about.
That chopper up there
could give us away...
...if somebody comes messing around.
What are they gonna do?
Land another pilot to fly it out?
They're not gonna mess with a little bird
like that. They got enough on their hands.
So I guess we forget about Canada,
right?
Nobody cares about my vote, huh?
Oh, come on, Fran.
I thought you were sleeping.
Damn it, I'm afraid
You're hypnotised by this place, all of you
It's so bright and neat ...
You don't see that it's a prison too
Stephen, let's just take what we need and keep going
Do you know how many times we would have to land...
for fuel on our way up North?
Those thing out there are everywhere
The Authorities would give us
just as a hard at a time, maybe worse
Fran,...
you got everything we need right here
Let's get some sleep
You were the one that
wanted to setup a house
MAN [ONI TV]: The normal question,
the first question is always:
Are these cannibals?
No, they are not cannibals.
Cannibalism,
in the true sense of the word...
.....implies an intraspecies activity.
These creatures
cannot be considered human.
They prey on humans.
They do not prey on each other.
That's the difference.
They attack and they feed only
on warm human flesh.
Intelligence?
Seemingly little or no reasoning power.
What basic skills remain
are more remembered behaviors...
...from, uh, normal life.
There are reports
of these creatures using tools...
...but even these actions
are the most primitive.
The use of external articles
as bludgeons and so forth.
I might point out to you
that even animals will adopt...
...the basic use of tools in this manner.
These creatures are nothing
but pure motorized instinct.
We must not be lulled by the concept...
...that these are our family members
or our friends.
They are not.
They will not respond to such emotions.
MAN 2 [ON TV]: They are.
-They must be destroyed on sight.
That was Dr. Milliard Rausch
from the OEP
and later on hopefully today
we're not exactly sure yet,
I'm waiting for word on this from some people
uh, we expect to get in here for a live show
actual live interview
so we can discuss things within
MAN [ON TV:] They're working on
an analysis of this whole phenomenon...
...uh, from the point of view
of a viral disease.
They're doing various laboratory tests...
...to see if they can deal with it
in that way.
Perhaps come up with some kind
of a workable vaccine.
Hey, Fran.
MAN [ON TV]: According to this report,
the problem they've run into in Atlanta...
.....is that there are
no live specimens available.
Uh, in that area, there are in fact....
Uh, we've had a filmed report
shot in Atlanta.
But it has not arrived yet.
Contact has been....
I would've made you all
coffee and breakfast...
...but I don't have my pots and pans.
MAN [ONI TV]:
Also, uh.....
Wait a minute.
Uh, there's another report....
May I say something?
Sure.
Sorry you found out I'm pregnant...
...because I don't wanna be treated
any differently than you treat each other,
Oh, hey, Fran, come on.
And I'm not gonna be
den mother for you guys.
I wanna know what's going on.
And I wanna have something to say
about the plans.
There's four of us, okay?
STEPHEN:
Jesus, Fran.
Fair enough.
Okay. Now, what's going on?
We're going out.
And you're not coming with us.
And you won't come with us
until you learn how to handle yourself.
FRANCINE:
Something else.
I don't know about you two...
...but I wanna learn
how to fly that helicopter.
If anything happens to you,
we have to be able to fly out of here.
She's right, man.
Come on, let's go.
And I don't want you to leave me
without a gun again.
I just might be able to figure out
how to use it.
I'm sorry, Stephen.
It's all right. It's all right.
Stephen.
Yeah?
Be careful.
Yeah, we'll be all right.
MAN [ONI TV]: To at least keep
some of the chaos under control.
Bowling for Dollars at 6.
In spite of everything,
as you can hear...
...there are still people
with a sense of humor.
How about it?
Getting it.
I'm not too sure of this thing.
I'll just ride pick-up.
I grew up in one of these things.
Come on.
All right.
Hey, Too Tall Too Slow Two, come in.
You look my size
when you're sitting in a truck.
What I wanna know is how we both
got in the same force together...
...you being so large and all.
Well, they told me
it was a midget force.
They needed somebody to look up to.
Hey, Where's fly boy? Where's his 20?
He's probably up on the roof
with flygirl.
All right, full speed. Let's go, come on.
Come on, hotshot. Come on.
Come on. Come on, man.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Three more, baby. Three more!
Roger,
Come on. Look, man.
Look.
What?
PETER:
Get its head up.
Roger, get its head up, man.
Get down!
Get down and stay down. I've got it.
Roger, move!
You bastards.
Roger,
We got this, man.
We got this by the ass.
Roger,
Come on, man, get your head together.
We got a lot of work to do.
Let's go, baby. Number two.
You all right?
Perfect, baby. Perfect.
Come on, bring it up.
For chrissake, come on, man.
PETER:
Roger, look out.
Roger, come on. Come on, man.
PETER:
Come on, Roger. Come on.
Goddamn motherfucking
sons of bitches.
Oh, God. Oh, Jesus.
What?
My bag,
I left my goddamn bag in the other truck.
All right, trooper.
You better screw your head on.
Yeah, come on, come on. Let's go.
I mean it, man.
Now you're not just playing with your life,
you're playing with mine.
Now are you straight?
Yeah.
Go, Rog. Go, go, go.
Come on, Rog. Come on.
Shit.
Watch it, man.
Watch out. Come on.
Back up, man.
Roger! Roger, watch it!
Damn.
[GUNSHOT]
FRANCINE: Roger!
Oh, God.
They got him.
That's it, man.
-That's it.
-Oh, bullshit.
We gotta deal with that leg.
Mao, I'm dealing with it, man.
Don't you worry about it.
There's a lot to get done
before you can afford to lose me.
PETER: It all depends on how many
of them are still inside.
That's one hell of a run
we've gotta make.
STEPHEN:
If we had more flares.
Maybe some of those propane jobs.
Guns are first. Guns and ammunition.
I'm sorry.
You sure you gonna make it?
Just hurry up with that.
Whew.
How about this, huh?
Don't try to shoot through those gates.
Openings are too small.
Bullet will wind up
chasing us around in here.
Don't worry. They can't get through.
-Ain't it a crime?
-What?
The only person
who could ever miss with this gun...
...will be the sucker
with the bread to buy it.
PETER:
You just wait out there, sissies.
We're coming...
...and we're ready.
[WHISPERS]
Okay, let's go.
When the door opens, push.
[GUNSHOT]
STEPHEN: That's it, push. That's it.
Come on, let's go.
Hardware.
Look here, man, I, urn....
I know. Shut up, will you?
All right. The toughest part
will be getting by these right here.
Too far.
There's no backing out now.
We've gotta lock those main doors.
We'll never make all four entrances.
It's too risky.
STEPHEN:
We'll make it.
You just be ready to open up for us.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, the car.
-What?
-One of the cars.
Why don't you use
one of the cars over there?
You okay to start it?
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
Close the door. Close the door.
The keys, Stephen, the keys!
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Come on, man. Get out of there.
Goddamn it.
Keep them, Stephen. Just keep them.
Come on, just hang a minute.
Oh, man.
Just jump in the back.
-You all right?
-I got it.
You get the latches, I'll get the lock.
Got you.
PETER:
That's not a hundred percent.
But I don't think they'll get through.
Can't they smash the glass?
Safety stuff. Pretty indestructible.
They got no leverage under the truck.
I'm hoping they'll just go away
after they find they can't get in.
I'll get the alarm. Get in the car.
Go.
We're okay.
We got it made.
It's gonna work.
How many you figure are already here?
PETER:
Don't know. Not too many.
We'll get them easy.
We'll get it all locked up.
Then we're going on a hunt.
We put up a wall here:
This way,
we can still get to the plumbing.
Why don't we just board up
the stairway?
Sooner or later,
there might be a patrol through here.
Looters, maybe.
I don't want anybody to even know
that stairway exists.
I don't know what else to do.
You're doing fine.
His leg is awful.
The infection is spreading quickly.
Can't we do something?
Can't we take him to a med unit?
I've seen half a dozen guys
get bitten by those things.
None of them lasted
more than three days.
ROGER:
Peter, where are you?
Right here, trooper,
We did it, didn't we?
We whipped them, didn't we?
That's right, Rog.
Didn't we?
Didn't we whip them?
We sure did, buddy.
We whipped them.
Whipped them good.
We whipped them and we got it all!
Hey, Fran
-Frannie.
-Leave me alone.
It's all right. It's my problem.
Just get out of here.
I don't want you here.
I just don't want you to see me
like this, okay?
Stephen, get out, please.
PETER:
This place is gonna be rotten.
We gotta clean it up, brother.
You never know.
Money, money, money
PETER:
Look right.
What do you think?
They're still here.
They're after us.
They know were still in here.
They're after the place.
They don't know why,
they just remember.
Remember that they wanna be in here.
What the hell are they?
They're us, that's all.
-There's no more room in hell.
-What?
Something my granddaddy
used to tell us.
You know macumba?
Voodoo.
Granddad was a priest in Trinidad.
He used to tell us:
"When there's no more room in hell,
the dead will walk the earth."
Never mind, get up. Hurry up, come on.
Jesus, hurry up!
Go on.
I'll stay with him.
You'll take care of me,
won't you, Peter?
I mean...
...you'd take care of me when I go.
Just try to get some sleep, man.
Save your strength.
I..,.
I don't wanna be walking around
like that.
Peter,
-Peter!
-Yes, I'm here, man.
Don't do it till you're sure
I am conning back.
I'm gonna try...
...not to.
I'm gonna try not to come back.
I'm gonna try...
...not to.
MAN 1 [ON TV]: They use 5 percent
of the food available in the human body.
MAN 2 [ON TV]:
The kind of-
With that small amount...
...the body is usually intact enough
to be mobile when it revives,
What are you saying? I mean-
-Dummies, dummies, dummies!
-Are you suggesting that we hurt them?
Excuse me, listen. Quiet, quiet.
TV HOST: Shh.
-One wonders whether it's worth saving.
It's worth saving.
For all I know the brains are already dead,
and it's the idiots that are still alive.
[AUDIENCE CHATTERING]
Huh?
And I figured out how to stay alive too.
And I'm trying to help you, dummies.
In your calm helping way,
you do irritate
MAN [ON TV]: In my calm logic way-
TV HOST: To the illogical way-
MAN [ONI TV]:
Illogical hell!
Illogical hell.
I'm showing you a way...
...that we can up the food supply
20 times.
TV HOST:
The food supply for who?
For a whole specimen
that is walking around there...
...in increasing numbers-
-We should feed them?
-What else you gonna do with them?
-God.
-Give me an alternative.
Let's start a zoo.
I thought you scientists can come up
with an actual way to solve the problem...
...rather than feeding the opposition.
Doesn't make any sense.
MAN [ONI TV]:
I can think of one other alternative.
I can think of another alternative, yes.
Since they seem to congregate
in heavily populated areas...
...and since we haven't touched upon
our nuclear resources.
Why don't we drop bombs
on all the big cities?
-You're probably serious-
-I'm deadly serious.
-What choices?
WOMAN: They'll run out of food.
They won't run out of food, young lady.
That's the problem you see.
And they won't run out of food
while we're still alive.
These kind of thing is out,
the things that you're talking about here...
...sound like just a bunch of people
This is not political rhetoric.
We're not fighting.....
This is not the Republicans
versus the Democrats.
They've got us in the hole.
Economically, only we're in another war.
It's more crucial than that,
we are down to the line, folks.
We are down to the line.
-There are no divisions among-
-Please.
TV HOST:
Shh.
-At least let him finish.
-We've got to remain....
It's really all over, isn't it?
Unemotional
[GUNSHOT]
Quiet.
We've got to remain rational.
Logical.
-Ho, ho, ho.
-Logical.
Scientists always think
in those kind of terms.
It doesn't work that way.
That's not how people really are.
We've got to remain logical.
We've got to.
There's no choice. It has to be that.
It's got to be that.
-Here it comes.
-Ah.
-Oh, wow.
-Oh, nice.
Thanks.
-For the lady.
-Thank you.
There you are.
-Stephen.
-Thank you very much.
Mm-hm.
Peter, what about you?
Where are you going?
This is just for the two of you.
Enjoy.
[WHISPERING]
Thanks.
We can't, Stephen. Not now.
It wouldn't be real.
WOMAN ON PA SYSTEM:
Attention all shoppers.
If you have a sweet tooth,
we have a special treat for you.
If your purchases in the next half hour
amount to $5 or more...
...we'll give you a bag
of hard candies, free...
...to take home to the kiddies
or enjoy yourself.
So hurry and do your shopping.
There hasn't been a broadcast
for three days. Why don't you give it up?
They might come back on.
What have we done to ourselves?
Okay. Now, easy, easy.
Stabilize it, that's right.
Take it down. Down, down.
That's it, you got it.
Hon, you got it.
[LAUGHING]
I did it!
Hey.
-Wow.
-They must get in through the roof,
Son of a bitch.
They got trucks
blocking all the entrances.
Yeah, trucks.
No sweat.
What do you think?
Do we hit them now or tonight?
Tonight.
A comb?
We know you're up there.
We saw the whirlybird on the roof.
Hey, wanna see my whirlybird?
Will you guys can it? Can this shit.
Raiders.
Listen,
could you use some company up there?
-We're just riding by.
-We could use some company down here.
-They know we're here, maybe we-
-No chance.
-Oh, thanks very much, you wanna try it?
-Oh, it's a radio.....
All right, can it, can it. Can it.
Okay, listen, how many
have you got up there anyway?
Look, there's three of us.
-What if-
-Shh, quiet!
-I think we should-
- Jesus Christ, shut up and listen.
Hey, you in the mall, listen.
We don't like people who don't share.
You just fucked up real bad.
Let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Just three, huh?
Holy shit!
They'll get in. They'll move the trucks.
There's hundreds of those creatures
down there.
Come on, man.
That's a professional army.
Looks like they been surviving on the road
all through this thing.
Well, let's not make it easy for them.
Come on.
-What's happening?
-Fifteen or 20 of them.
-We'll shut the gates.
-Stephen!
We're just gonna shut the gates.
They'll never know we're here.
-Downstairs first.
-Okay.
-Got your talk box?
-Yeah.
Keep it handy.
-Watch out, Billy.
-Down there.
They're in, flyboy.
Be up in the loading docks.
When those bay doors open, there's
gonna be a thousand zombies in here.
That'll take the heat off us.
These guys
are gonna have their hands full.
Don't be looking for yourself.
Look for us, now let's go.
Hee-yah.
Hey, Nick.
Flyboy.
Fly boy.
Flyboy, where the hell are you?
-Come on, just throw it.
-Come on, man, let's get out of here.
It's ours.
We took it.
What the hell are you doing?
Someone's up there shooting at us.
Goddamn you, flyboy.
What the hell are you doing?
Just stay out of sight.
They're after the place,
they don't care about us.
All right, damn it.
Now we've got a war.
Say goodbye, creep.
What the hell are you gonna watch
on that thing?
I don't know, man.
Hey, Nick.
Upstairs, come on.
Nick, come on, you mother....
-The lights.
-The lights went off.
Hit the lights.
-Where did he go?
-Down there, come on.
I see you!
Peter! Peter!
Peter!
Rope, man.
-I know he's in here.
-Come on!
-Hey, come on down.
-Come on.
Give me a bike.
Son of a bitch.
-Peter, Peter.
-Where the hell are you?
In the elevator.
And those things,
they're all over the place.
Climb up top.
I'll get you out of the grid in the shaft.
I'm coming
Flyboy.
Damn it, flyboy.
He's dead?
I heard his gun. Maybe he's all right.
We'll just wait.
We'll just wait a while and see.
It's almost light. Let's go.
He hasn't answered the radio for hours.
For God's sake.
-What is it?
-Stephen.
They're coming up.
Go on. Get out of here.
-Peter.
-I said get out of here.
-Jesus Christ, Peter.
-I don't wanna go.
I really don't.
Get up.
Move, woman!
-How much fuel do we have?
-Not much.
All right.