Having reached the end
of my sinner's life...
my hair now white...
I prepare to leave
on this parchment my testimony...
as to the wondrous
and terrible events...
I witnessed in my youth...
at the end of the year of 1327.
May God grant me
the wisdom and grace...
to be the faithful chronicler
of the happenings that took place...
in a remote abbey
in the dark north of ltaly.
An abbey whose name
it may seem, even now...
bias andprudent to omit.
THE NAME OF THE ROSE
May my hand not tremble
now that I start...
to relieve the past and
revive the feelings of uneasiness...
that opressed my heart
as we entered the battlements.
Should we tell him?
No. He will look
in the wrong places.
But...
what if he learns it
of his own account?
You're overestimating
his talents.
There's only one authority
capable of investigating such matters.
The holly lnquisition.
What's your opinion,
venerable Jorge?
Dear brothers...
I leave such worldly
matters to younger men.
Adso?
-Yes, master.
-To command nature...
one must learn
to obey it, huh?
So, return to the court,
turn the building on your left...
enter the court on you right.
You'll find the place you're in need of...
behind the third arch.
But you told me you'd never
been to this abbey.
When we arrived, I saw a
brother making this way so hazily.
But he left more slowly,
with an air of content.
Thank you, master.
On behalf of the Benedict Order..
I'm honored to welcome you
and your Franciscan brothers...
to our abbey.
The other delegates
have arrived?
Ubertino de Casale has been
here for some weeks...
the others are due tomorrow.
You must be very tired
after your long journey.
Not particularly.
You're not in need
of anything?
No, thank you.
Well... then l...
I beech you peace.
I'm sorry to see that
one of your brothers...
has recently gone
to God.
Yes, a terrible loss.
Brother Adelmo was one
of our finest illuminates.
-Not, Adelmo of Otranto?
-You knew him?
No, but I knew and
admired his work.
His humor and comic
images were almost infamous.
But he was said to be very young.
Ah, yes! Very young indeed.
An accident, no doubt.
Yes, as you say, an accident.
Well... that is l...
Brother William...
may I speak to you candidly?
You seem anxious to do so.
When I heard you were coming
to our abbey...
I thought it was an answer
to my prayers.
I said: "He's a man who has the
knowledge both of the human spirit...
and of the wilds of the evil one."
Brother Adelmo's death
has caused much...
spiritual
uneasy upon my flock.
This is my novice, Adso.
The youngest son of the
Baron de Melk.
Please, do continue.
We found the body
after a heavy storm...
horribly mutilated...
cast against a rock in
front of the tower...
under a window that was...
How should I say this?
-which was...
-which was found closed.
-Somebody told you?
-lf it was opened...
You'd not have mentioned
spiritual uneasy.
-He'd have fallen.
-Brother William...
the window can't be opened...
nor was the glass shattered.
There's no access
through the roof above.
I see. As you can't
find a natural explanation...
the monks suspect the
presence of supernatural forces.
I need the help of an
acute man such as you.
Acute in uncovering and
prudent, if necessary...
in covering up before
the papal delegates arrive.
You know I no longer deal
in such matters.
I'm reluctant to burden
you with my dilemma, but...
unless I can tranquilize
my flock...
I have no alternative but
turn to the lnquisition.
That is Ubertino de Casale...
one of the greatest spiritual
leaders of our Order.
Come.
Many revere him
as a living saint...
but others would have him
burnt as a heretic.
His book on the poverty
of the clergy...
isn't favorite
reading in the papal palace.
So, now he lives
in hiding.
Dear Franciscans...
you must leave
this place at once.
The devil's roaming this abbey!
Ubertino, it's, William.
Willian of Baskerville.
William is dead.
William... my son...
forgive me.
We lost trace ofyou
for so long!
I tried hard to be forgotten.
When we heard of your
troubles...
I prayed to our Virgin
for a miracle.
Your prayers met with a
favorable response.
This is my young novice,
Adso de Melk.
His father has entrusted
me his education and wealth.
Let him out of here at once!
Haven't you heard the devil...
is hurling beautiful
boys out of windows?
There was something feminine...
something diabolical...
about the young one who died.
He had the eyes of a girl...
seeking into course
with the devil.
Beware of this place.
The beast is still
among us.
I can sense him...
now... here...
within these very walls.
I'm afraid, William.
For you, for me.
For the outcome of this debate...
My son!
The times we're living!
Let's not frighten
our young friend.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
When a female...
by nature so perverted...
becomes sublime by holiness...
then she can be the
noble vehicle of grace.
Beautiful are the breasts...
which feed only one baby.
-I don't like this place.
-Really?
I find it thrillingly.
Come.
We must not allow ourselves
to be influenced...
by irrational rumors
of the antichrist.
Let's instead exercise
our brains...
and try to solve this enigma.
May you receive more in Heaven...
for what you've given in Earth.
My master trusted
Aristotle, the Greek philosopher...
and in his remarkable
logic intelligence.
Unhappily, my fears
were not...
mere phantoms
of my youthful imagination.
A rather dark end for such
a brilliant illuminate.
Another generous donation
by the Church to the poor.
What if it wasn't that tower
he fell from...
but somewhere over there and
the body rolled all the way down here?
No devil needed anymore.
There's more blood here.
That's where he fell from.
He jumped.
-Are you paying attention?
-Yes, he jumped.
Jumped? You mean that
he committed suicide?
Why else would someone go up
there in the middle of a rainstorm?
Not to admire the landscape.
Perhaps someone murdered him.
And then towed all the
way up there with the body?
Much easier to get rid of it
through that small door.
My dear Adso.
It seems elementary.
Suicide?
Do you think this is a place
abandoned by God?
Have you ever known a place
where God would've felt at home?
We pray, oh, mighty God,
that there are no grounds...
for suspecting the presence
of an evil spirit among us...
either of this world or another.
We praise our Lord
that the debate...
we are so greatly honored to host...
may now proceed
without a shadow of fear.
We also praise oh mighty
for sending us brother William...
whose experience and
previous duties...
although onerous to him...
has been of such service to us here.
May serenity and
spiritual peace...
reign once more
in our hearts.
A monk must be quiet.
He mustn't speak
what he's thinking...
until he's asked.
A monk mustn't laugh.
That's what fools are for...
who raise their voices in laughter.
Master, if I may ask what...
onerous duties was
the abbot talking about?
Were you not always a monk?
Even monks have past, Adso.
Now, try to sleep.
Just...
Yes, master.
There's sadness in wisdom.
The one who increases his knowledge...
also increases his suffering.
A calamity!
It was a calamity!
Father! A tragedy in the pigpen!
Come! Come quickly!
This one, I admit, didn't
commit suicide.
Water!
Venancius, the Greek translator!
I'm to blame. Had I not been so eager
to believe your convenient explanation...
this second tragedy
might've been prevented.
I'm convinced brother Adelmo
took his own life.
Whether this death is connected
with it. I intend to find.
"After the heavy storm,
with the second trumpet..."
"the sea became blood."
-And hold... there's blood here!
-The prophecy of the Apocalypse.
"With the third trumpet,
a burning star..."
"will fall in fountains of water'
The devil is here!
Grated stem bistort
for treating diarrhea.
As for onions, administered
in small quantities...
warm and moist, they help to
prolong the male erection.
In those who haven't taken
our vows, naturally.
Do you apply arsenic in
many circumstances?
Yes, indeed.
This effective remedy for
nervous disorders.
If taken in small doses.
And what if not in so small doses?
Death.
What was his function here?
He was our finest translator
of Greek.
Entirely devoted to the works
of Aristotle.
Was he in friendly terms with
the handsome Adelmo?
Yes. They worked together in
the escritoire.
But in a brotherly way
understand? Not like...
I mean... flesh can be tempted
according to nature...
or against nature.
And they weren't allowed to
this position... you see!
Penitengiazite!
Watch out for Satan,
who comes to know your soul.
Death is supreme.
Contemplating my sanctuary?
There, we have the devil.
As ugly as Salvatore.
My little brother,
penitenziagite.
"Penitenziagite"?
I didn't say that.
You said "penitenziagite".
I heard.
Noble father, "magnifico"!
I don't have a good rhetoric.
I said "penitence".
I'm a monk. Saint Benedict!
Saint Benedict!
Salvatore, come here.
Master, what language was
he speaking?
All languages and none.
And what was the word you
both repeated?
"Penitenziagite"?
-What does it mean?
-That the hunchback, undoubtedly...
was once a herectic.
"Penitenziagite" was the rally
cry of Dolcinites.
Dolcinites? Who were they?
Those who believed
in the poverty of Christ.
So do we, Franciscans.
But they also declared everyone
must be poor.
So, they slaughtered the rich.
You see, Adso...
the step between ecstatic vision
and sinful frenzy...
is all too brief.
So, could he not have killed
the translator?
No. Fat bishops and wealthy priests...
were more to the taste
of the Dolcinites...
not a specialist of Aristotle.
But you're right, we must
keep the mind open.
We're fortunate to have such
a snowy ground here.
It's the parchment on which
the criminal, unwillingly...
writes his autograph.
What do you mean from these
footprints here?
They're twice as deep as the
others, Master.
Good! And thus we may conclude...
That the man was very heavy.
Precisely! And why was
he very heavy?
Because... he was very fat?
Or because he was carrying
another man.
Let's commit the autograph
of this sole to our memory.
But the footprints lead away
from the jar, in this direction.
Adso, you're discounting
the possibility...
that the man was walking
backwards, dragging the body...
into the furrows
created by the heels.
Where did the erudite
Greek translator...
meet the anonymous
author of his death?
Brother librarian...
perhaps you'd permit us to examine
the work of the two unfortunates...
who were so distressingly
gone to God.
-Your request's most unusual.
-As are the circumstances of their deaths.
Brother Adelmo sat there.
Eyeglasses in frames.
A donkey teaching the
Scriptures to the bishops.
The pope as a fox.
And the abbot as a monkey.
He had a daring talent
for comic images.
A monk must not laugh!
Only fools laugh for nothing!
I trust my words didn't
offend you brother William...
but I heard them laughing
at unlaughable things.
You, Franciscans, however,
belong to an Order...
where merriment is viewed
with indulges.
Yes, it's true. Saint Francis
was much disposed to laughter.
Laughter's a devil's squint
which deforms the face...
and makes men look
like monkeys.
Monkeys do not laugh.
Laughter's particular to man.
As a sin.
Christ never laughed.
Can you be so sure?
There's nothing in the
Scriptures to say that He did.
There's nothing there
to say He didn't.
Even the saints also
employed comedy...
to ridicule the enemies
of the faith.
For example, when the
pagans plunged Saint Maurus...
into the boiling water,
he complained...
that his bath was cold.
The Sultan put his hand in...
-and burnt himself.
-A saint...
immersed in boiling water
doesn't play childish tricks.
He restrains his cries
and suffers for the truth.
And yet, Aristotle devoted his second
book of poetics to comedy...
as an instrument of truth.
Have you read this work?
Of course not.
It's been lost for centuries.
No, it's not!
It was never written!
Because Providence doesn't
want futile things glorified.
-That I must contempt.
-Enough!
This abbey is overshadowed by grief.
Yet you would...
intrude on our sorrows
with idle banter!
Forgive me, Venerable Jorge.
My remarks were truly out of place.
Which was the Greek
translator's desk?
This one.
Come, Adso.
-What'd you deduce from that visit?
-That we're not meant to laugh in there.
But you noticed how few books
there were on the escritoire's shelves?
All those scriveners, copyists,
translators, researchers...
thinkers... Where are the books
needed for their work...
and for which this abbey
is famous?
Where are the books?
-Are you testing me?
-What do you mean?
With all due respect...
it seems that whenever you ask me a
question, you already have the answer.
Do you know where the books are?
No, but I've faith that that
tower contains something other than air.
Did you see the little door
the librarian closed as we came in?
That leads to the library?
Master! Quick! I have him!
-Stop! Enough.
-He tried to kill us.
Salvatore!
Please, don't talk to the abbot
about his past.
He's innocent of the deaths
in this abbey. I swear it.
Brother Remigio, my price is
some information.
I couldn't comprehend
why my master so quickly dismissed...
my suspicions for the
heretic hunchback...
and why it was so urgent
that we visited the tower.
I assumed he couldn't
resist the temptation...
to penetrate the library
and look at the books.
No lock. Just as I thought,
it must be bolted from inside.
How do we get in?
Obviously, there must be
another entrance.
Let's see what the moon-faced
assistant librarian...
was trying to conceal this morning.
Tiny Greek letters.
Perhaps written by an ant
with ink feet.
"Have fun with the defects
of vulgar people."
Written with lemon juice.
Sagittarius... Sun... Mercury...
Scorpion.
It's a zodiac code...
giving directions...
but to where?
Who's there?
-My magnifying glasses...
-They were in that book.
You go that way.
Come on out, you little bitch!
I know you're here.
I can smell you.
What's the matter with you?
Are you afraid of me?
I'll find you.
Who was she?
Who was this creature
that rose like the dawn...
bewitched as the moon,
radiant as the sun..
terrible as an army
poised for battle?
Good evening, Salvatore.
This is where you catch them?
Here they're "piu grassi",
bigger.
Do you eat them?
-Do you like?
-Thank you, no.
"lch bin" good catholic.
As you're a good Christian,
you must tell me.
So Adelmo gave the
parchment to Berengar?
No. To the trans... tran...
Translator! Venancius,
the black monk.
What happened then?
Master! Here, quick!
I found another one.
Where are your wits, boy?
Have you ever met anyone with a
rib cage large enough to accommodate...
a heart of those dimensions?
This is the heart of an ox.
One of the monks probably
gave it to that peasant girl...
in exchange for her favors.
A girl? What?
The one I saw out of here.
-He must've been a very ugly monk.
-Why ugly?
If he'd been young and beautiful,
she'd have blessed him...
with her carnal favors for nothing.
Whatever happened in this
dreadful kitchen...
has no bearing on
our investigations.
The hunchback's convinced
me that brother Berengar...
the assistant librarian,
is the key to the whole enigma.
-What did you say?
-Nothing, master.
Good.
Master?
There's something I must tell you.
I know.
Then, you'll hear my confession?
I'd rather you told me
first as a friend.
Master...
Have you ever been...
in love?
In love?
-Many times.
-You were?
Of course. Aristotle, Ovid,
Virgil...
No. I meant with a...
Are you not confusing love
with lust?
Am l?
I don't know.
I want to make her own good.
I want her to be happy.
I want to save her from poverty.
Oh, dear!
-Why "oh, dear"?
-You are in love.
Is that bad?
For a monk it presents
certain problems.
But doesn't St Thomas Aquinas
praise love above all the virtues?
Yes, the love of God, Adso.
Love of God!
And the love of... woman?
Of woman, Thomas Aquinas
knew very little.
The Scriptures are very clear.
Proverbs warns us.
Woman takes possession of a
man's precious soul.
Ecclesiastes tells us:
"More bitter than death is woman."
Yes, but what do you think, master?
Of course, I don't have the benefit
of your experience...
but I find it difficult
to convince myself that...
God'd have introduced such
a being into creation...
without endowing her
with some virtues.
How peaceful life'd be
without love, Adso.
How safe... how tranquil...
and how dull.
God, You've guided us to
this refuge...
of spiritual peace because
you wish for reconciliation...
as much as we, Franciscans.
Let's go, brothers!
Brother Berengar?
He's probably hiding
somewhere...
with the book and
my magnifying glasses.
Brother Berengar?
Master, look! The door!
Brother Malaquias!
I was looking for brother Berengar.
Is he here?
No.
I see. Do you know where
we might find him?
No.
Or is he perhaps upstairs,
in the library?
No.
I'm curious to see the library
for myself. May I do so?
No.
Why not?
It's strict order of the abbot.
No one's permitted
to enter the library...
other than myself and my assistant.
I see. Thank you again.
Maybe something's happened to him.
Maybe we'll find him in the water.
-What?
-The third trumpet...
as Ubertino said.
The book of Revelation.
That's not the book we're after.
Is it a chicken for you?
It's more like a sparrow.
Franciscans.
Welcome to our abbey,
brother Michele.
And your fellow Franciscan
delegates.
Get in the line like the others!
Salvatore, let him go!
This is Cuthbert of Winchester...
one of our most esteemed
Franciscan guests.
Come, your grace. We have a
very urgent matter to discuss.
The abbot and his colleagues
believe...
the devil's at work
within these walls.
He is!
The only evidence I see
of the devil...
is everyone's desire to see
him at work.
What if Ubertino's right and
you're wrong?
This debate's
crucial to us all.
we suspect the Pope
wants to crash our Order.
-And declare us heretics.
-Yes, and declare us heretics.
I only have one brother to
question and the matter's resolved.
William, we place our trust
in you.
I pray God that you don't
abuse it.
Brother William.
Did you find a book in Greek?
I was right.
So was the book of
Revelation.
-We must talk at once.
-lndeed, we must.
And I have much to tell.
Just as he and I've
examined this corpse.
Lime leaves in the bath
are used to alleviate pain.
He was left-handed?
Brother Berengar was
inverted in many ways.
Are there other left-handed
brothers at the abbey?
Not that I know.
Ink stains.
He didn't write with his
tongue, I presume.
-A few lines in Greek.
-Yes, written by Venancius.
Notes from the book he
was reading...
just before he died.
You see how the calligraphy changes?
From this point on, he was dying.
And what can we conclude from that?
A spot of blue paint.
yes, but a unique spot
of blue...
blended by your finest
illuminate, brother Adelmo...
who had this parchment
before Venancius.
How do we know that?
Because those notes overrun...
Adelmo's blue spots,
and not vice-versa.
Brother William...
this abbey is enshrouded
in a terrifying mystery.
Yet, I detect nothing,
in your obscure citation...
that sheds light upon it.
Adso, the light.
Someone was in great pains
to conceal a secret...
of the first magnitude.
The calligraphy's, without
question, left-handed.
The only left-handed member
ofyour community is... or rather was...
brother Berengar,
the assistant librarian.
What kind of secret knowledge
would he not have privilege?
-I feel you're about to tell me.
-Books. Restricted books.
Spiritually dangerous books.
Everyone here knew of
the assistant's passion...
for handsome boys.
When the beautiful Adelmo...
wanted to read such a
forbidden book...
Berengar offered him the
key to its whereabouts...
inside that parchment...
in exchange for unnatural caresses.
Enough, William!
Adelmo submitted to
Berengar's lustful advances.
But afterwards wracked,
by remorse he wandered desperate...
in the graveyard, where
he met the Greek translator.
-How do you know?
-There was a witness.
The hunchback...
he sawAdelmo giving
this parchment to Venancius...
and running towards
the small tower...
and hurling himself
out of the window.
the night of my arrival,
while Berengar punished his sinful flesh...
Venancius, following
the instructions on the parchment...
entered the forbidden library
and found the book.
He took it back to his desk
and began to read it.
After scribbling down
those mysterious quotations...
he died with a blackstain
on his finger.
The assistant discovered the body...
and dragged it down to the pigpen
to avertsuspicion on him.
But he left his autograph behind.
The book remained
on the translator's desk.
Berengar returned there
last night and read it.
Soon after, overcome
by some agonizing pain...
he tried to take a soothing bath
with lime leaves...
and drawned.
He too had a black finger.
All three died because
ofa book which kills...
or for which men will kill.
Therefore, I urge you to grant
me access to the library.
Brother William, your pride
blinds you.
By idolizing reason...
you failed to see what's obvious
to everyone in this abbey.
The papal delegation's arrived.
Bernardo Gui.
Thank you, brother William.
We're grateful
for your efforts...
but I now ask you...
to refrain from further
investigations.
Happily, there'll be someone
arriving with the papal delegation...
who is a well-versed
in the wilds of the evil one.
A man, I believe,
you know too well.
Bernardo Gui...
of the lnquisition.
Master, who's Bernardo Gui?
I've been searching the
entire abbey for you!
Michele wishes to speak
with you at once.
Alone.
-You know who's coming?
-I know. Bernardo Gui.
Ubertino must be moved to
a safe place.
The arrangements have been made.
It's you that concerns us.
You must put aside these
totally irrelevant investigations.
Erroneous conclusions.
It's the truth. I'm right.
William's right,
he's always right!
No matter what the
consequences...
for himself or anyone else...
William of Baskerville...
must always prove
himself right.
Wasn't your vanity,
your intellectual pride...
that brought you into conflict
with Bernardo Gui before?
Do not dare fate
twice, William.
Not even the Emperor will be able to
save you if you tangle with Bernardo.
My flesh'd forgotten the
sinful pleasure she'd...
given me. But my soul
couldn't forget her.
And now?
Now that I saw herin the
midst of her poverty and squatter...
I praised God that
I was a Franciscan.
I wanted her to know
that I didn't belong to...
this abbeybut to an
order dedicated to lifting...
her people out of
their physical destitution.
And spiritual depravation.
Farewell William.
You're mad and arrogant.
But I love you and I'll
never cease to pray for you.
Goodbye, dear child.
Try not to learn too many bad
examples from your master.
He thinks too much.
Relying always on the...
deductions of his head.
Instead of trusting in the
prophetic capacities...
of his heart.
Learn to mortify your...
intelligence. Weep over
the wounds of our Lord...
and do throw away
those books!
There's a side of Ubertino
I truly envy.
Remember, fear the last trumpet,
my friends.
The next'll fall from the sky.
And then will come a thousand...
-scorpions.
-Yes, we won't forget.
Which one frightens you most?
They all do.
Look closely.
-That one.
-My choice exactly.
After you.
Those are the foundations
of the tower.
But how to reach the library?
The rats love parchment
even more than scholars do.
Let's follow him.
166, bolted door, 167...
168, 169, 170...
I knew it.
Adso! I knew it!
You realize...
we're in one of the greatest
libraries in the whole Christendom?
-How are we gonna find the book?
-ln time.
"The Beatus of Liebana".
That's a masterpiece.
And this is the version anoted
by Umberto de Bologna!
How many more rooms?
How many more books?
No one should be forbidden
to consult these books.
Perhaps they're thought to be
too precious, too fragile.
It's not that, Adso.
They contain a wisdom that's
different from ours...
and ideas that could
make us doubt...
the infallibility
of the word of God.
Master?
And doubt, Adso,
is the enemy offaith.
Master?
Wait for me!
I'm waiting foryou.
But I can hear you walking.
I'm not walking.
I'm down here.
Is that you up there?
Where are you?
I'm lost!
Well, Adso, it'd appear we're
in a labyrinth.
Are you still there?
Yes.
How do we get out?
With some difficulty.
At least.
You see, Adso, that's the charm
of a labyrinth.
Adso, staycalm.
Open a book...
read it aloud.
Leave the room you're in...
keep turning left.
"Love's not originated as a
trouble but it transforms into it..."
when it becomes
obsessive cause."
"lt was lb Hazm who said
the love sick person..."
"doesn't want to be healed
and his amorous reverie..."
"cause irregularbreathing
and quick pulse."
"He identifies amorous
melancholy with lincantropy..."
"the disease that induces
woof-like behavior in humans."
"The external appearance..."
"begins to change."
"Soon the eyes fail,
his lips dry..."
"his face becomes postuled."
"Marks resembling bites of
the dog appear in his face..."
"he ends his days
by prowling in the graveyards..."
"at night, like a wolf."
Master?
I see a lantern.
Don't move.
Stay where you are.
I see a man.
He's stopped.
What's he doing?
He's raising his lantern.
How many times?
Three times.
It's l.
Raise your lantern.
Look!
You foolish boy!
It's just a mirror.
Master!
-Save the books.
-I'm trying to save you!
A trap door, a mirror...
We're almost there.
If I've deciphered the instructions
of the translator correctly...
You didn't think me
so foolish as to surrender...
the parchment to the abbot
without making a copy, right?
"With the hand above the idol..."
"press the 1st. and the 7th.
of four'
Very good.
What idol?
That's what we're here
to find out.
The 1st and the 7th of four what?
If I knew the answer of everything
I'd teach Theology in Paris.
And... again.
You hear that?
It's my teeth, master.
-What?
-My teeth.
Don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid,
I'm cold.
-Well... we should return.
-Don't leave for my account.
I confess It deludes me
for the moment
Well... Iet me see...
to find the way out of a labyrinth...
you come to a fork
mark it with an arrow...
-Master.
-Please! I'm thinking.
If there are arrows
at the forks, then...
Well done, boy!
Your classical education
serves us well!
Give it to me.
Give me!
Bernardo, sprinkle me
with the sperm.
Then, you have the love.
Spit it, please.
Spit it over there.
Thank you.
Lucifer, be at my service,
for a woman's love.
Leave me! Leave me!
It's burning!
Bernardo, look what we found.
Search the creature.
Mr. Abbot, you invited me to
investigate...
the presence of the evil one
in your abbey...
and I already found it.
How many times have I seen
these objects of devil worship?
The black cock and the black cat!
She did it for the food,
not for the devil!
William de Baskerville must
recall the trial...
in which a woman confessed
to have had intercourse...
with the demon in the form
of a black cat.
You don't have draw on
my past experiences...
to formulate your conclusions.
No indeed. Not in the face of
irrefutable evidences.
A witch! A seduced monk!
Satanic rite!
Tomorrow we shall learn
if these events...
are connected with the mystery
that afflicts your abbey.
Lock them up! So they'll sleep
safely tonight.
You said nothing!
I said nothing because there was
nothing to be said.
You're ready enough to speak
the truth...
when it comes to books
and ideas.
She's already burned flesh, Adso.
Bernardo Gui's spoken.
She's a witch.
It's not true and you know it!
I know.
I also know that anyone
who disputes the verdict...
of an inquisitor
is guilty of heresy.
You seem to know a lot about it.
Oh, yes.
Won't you tell me...
as a friend?
There's not much to tell.
I was an inquisitor, but
in the early days...
when the lnquisition struggled
to guide, no to punish.
Once, I had to preside the trial
of a man...
whose only crime was to
have translated a Greek book...
that conflicted with
the Holly Scriptures.
Bernardo Gui wanted to
condemn him as heretic.
I acquitted the man.
Gui accused me of heresy
for having defended him.
I appealed to the Pope.
I was brought to prison...
tortured...
and I recanted.
What happened then?
The man was burnt at stake...
and I'm still alive.
Brother Salvatore...
this torment causes me
as much pain as you.
You can end it before
we even begin.
Open the gates ofyour heart,
search the depths ofyour soul.
-Search!
-I'm searching, sir.
Then tell me...
who, among your brethren, is the
heretic responsible for these murders?
I don't know.
I don't know!
I know nothing!
Stupid. I don't know anything.
Did I lie awake that night,
suffering for the girl...
or for myself?
I did not know.
With the dawn, came
the emissaries of the Pope...
our adversaries of the debate.
But it meant so little
to me now.
Your Eminence,
venerable brothers...
at last we meet
for this long waiting debate!
We've all traveled
great distances...
to put an end to the dispute...
that has shaken the unity...
of our Holly Mother Church.
Good people throughout Christendom...
are directing their gazes
at these venerable walls...
anxiously awaiting our answer
to that question...
"Did Christ or did he not owe...
the clothes that He wore?"
Beloved brethren of
the Franciscan Order...
our Holly Father, the Pope,
has authorized me...
and these servants
to speak on his behalf.
The question's not whether
Christ was poor...
But whether the Church
should be poor!
You, Franciscans, wish to see...
the clergy renounce
its possessions...
and surrenderits richness.
The abbots dissipated
their sacred treasures...
and handed their fertile
land to the servs.
I found the book.
I found the book at the dispensary.
A book in Greek.
It's behind one of my jars.
Don't touch it.
Return, lock your self inside.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
...defying the Church on the resources
needed to combat the eager...
great flow of the infident.
You forget that even the
greatest monument to OurLord...
is a pale reflex of
His infinite Majesty and glory.
Brother, quick! Salvatore
confessed his heretic past...
and yours. You have little to
escape from the flames.
Thank you, brother.
I consider this an absurd!
I can'tstand it!
How dare you call the
Pope's brothel God's palace on Earth?
-Answer that, your Eminence!
-These murders are a sign.
-I don't believe it!
-Why not?
Gospel speaks categorically...
that Christ possessed
a purse!
It's a lie, and you know it!
Why did Our Lord tell
his disciples on seven occasions...
not to carry neither gold
nor silver?
You, please!
A matter's occurred of
utmost gravity.
Let me go! I swear
I didn't kill him!
I was in the barn
making the inventory.
I neverkilled anybody,
I swear it!
Then explain us
why you were escaping.
I wasn't.
I've already ordered your arrest
in another choice.
I see now that I was correct.
If someone hadn't chosen to look
in the wrong direction...
many men of God would
still be with us.
"Hand above the idol,
1 and 7 of four..."
"Use vulgar persons.
Take pleasure from the defects."
Please, dear boy,
I'm trying to think.
So am l, master.
Then use your head
instead ofyour heart.
And we can make some progress.
Are the books more important
than people to you?
Did I say they were?
You never seem to care
about anyone!
Can't you show a little pity?
Perhaps that's the style
of my pity.
But pity won't save her from
the fire.
I remind all present that,
they're bound by their vow of obedience...
and on pain of excommunication...
to aim the lnquisitor in his
struggle against heresy.
To sit with me
on this tribunal...
and to share the burden
of the verdict...
I'd require the counsel...
of two fellowjudges.
My lord Abbot...
and...
Brother William of Baskerville.
Salvatore...
Salvatore!
Would you repeat your confession
of last night...
that you and your accomplice,
Remigio de Varagine...
were members of the heretical
Dolcinites?
Enough!
Remigio de Varagine, do you deny
the confession ofyour accomplice?
No.
I don't deny it.
I'm proud of it!
For the twelve years I lived here...
I stuffed my belly...
shagged my weak...
and squeezed the hungry peasants
for dimes.
But now you've given me strength...
to remember what I once believed
in with all my heart.
And for that I thank you.
To remember that you once looted
and burnt the property of the Church?
Yes! To give it back to
the people you stole it from!
And did you not kill many
bishops and priests?
Yes! I'd burn your people...
if I had the chance!
Holly Mary, Mother of God,
Hear my humble prayer.
I know that my sin was
very great...
but I beg you to not let her
suffer for my wrongdoing.
Blessed Mother...
many years ago you granted
a miracle by saving my master.
Would you not do the same
for this girl?.
My master says that the
simple folk always pay for all.
But, please, Holly Mother,
do not let it be so.
Guilty is that witch...
who's seduced a monk...
and practiced his diabolical
rituals in this holly place.
Guilty is Salvatore...
who's confessed his
heretical past...
and was caught in flagrant
delito with a witch!
Guilty is Remigio de Varagine...
who's not regretted
his former heresies and was caught...
trying to escape after
murdering the herbalist Severinus.
That's a lie! I never killed
the herbalist...
or anyone else in this abbey!
I therefore, request you...
to confirm my
sentence, My lord abbot.
My heart is
full of sorrow...
but I can't find no
reason to contest...
the just sentence of
the Holly lnquisition.
And you, William of Baskerville?
Yes, he is guilty.
Guilty of having, in his youth...
misinterpreted the message
of the Gospels...
and he's guilty of having
confused...
the love of poverty with
the blind destruction...
of wealthy and property.
But, my lord abbot...
he's innocent of the crimes
that've bathed your abbey in blood.
For brother Remigio
cannot read Greek...
and this entire mystery
hinges on...
the theft and possession of a
book written in Greek...
and hidden in some secret
part of the library.
As the verdict of the
lnquisition was disputed by William...
we must extract the
prisoner's confession.
Take him to the forge
and show him the instruments.
I'll confess anything you
want, but don't torture me.
I can't go through a night
like Salvatore!
Very well.
Why did you kill them?
Why? I don't know why.
-Because you were inspired by the devil?
-Yes... that's it.
I was inspired by the devil.
I'm inspired by the devil!
Adralmech, Lucifer,
I call for you...
Lords of Hell.
The shepherd has done
his duty...
and the infected sheep must
now be consigned to the purifying flames!
You may burn brother Remigio...
but you won't put a stop for the
crimes being committed in this abbey!
Other monks will meet
death here...
and they'll also have
black fingers and black tongues!
Your Eminence, I beg you...
we, Franciscans, are disappointed
with brother William.
Once more we've seen that
your theories protect heretics...
and lead to murder.
The debate's concluded.
Brother William
has relaxed...
into the errors of which
he was formerly perjured.
Having sought yet again
to shield a heretic...
from just punishment by
the lnquisition...
He'll come with me
to Avignon for confirmation...
of my sentence by Pope John.
I'm right.
Ifonlyl could find the book
andprove that Gui was wrong!
But the Antichrist
was victorious once more...
and nothing seemed to be
able to hinder him.
Come on.
When the pyres are light
tonight...
Let the flames purify...
each of us
in his own heart.
Let's return to what was,
and ever should be...
the office of this abbey:
the preservation of
knowledge.
Preservation, I said.
Not search for...
because there's no progress
in the history of knowledge...
merely a continuous
and sublime recapitulation.
Let's now pray oh mighty...
that the blood-eyed antichrist...
has been removed from our
sacred precincts...
and our monastery
has returned to peace.
The fifth trumpet had
the power of a thousand scorpions...
-He told me.
-Who told you?
His tongue's black
and his finger's black...
as brother William foretold!
It's brother Malachia, father.
-Malachia?
-Yes, father.
Dear God! Not Malachia!
Will it never end?
William of Baskerville
was right. He said...
Yes! He knew!
Just as I'd have known,
if I'd been the murderer!
Find William
of Baskerville!
We can't open the mirror!
Perhaps pressing the 1a and the
7a letters of the word "four".
But "four" only has 4 letters.
In Latin, "quatuor". Remember
the inscription of the mirror?
We had to press above
the idol.
Not "idolum" as in Latin,
but "eidolon" as in Greek.
Meaning "image: or
"reflection". Our own reflection!
-This way, master!
-No, this way, Adso.
Here... Q and R.
Pray God we're
not mistaken.
Come.
Good evening, Venerable Jorge.
I've been expecting you
these several days past, William.
You must've flown
to this chamber to reach it ahead of us.
You've discovered many things...
since your arrival at
this abbey...
but the shortcut through
the labyrinth isn't among them.
So now, what's it that you want?
I want to see the book
in Greek you said was never written.
A book entirely devoted to comedy,
which you hate...
as much as you hate laughter.
I want to see what's probably
the only the surviving copy...
of the 2nd book of the
poetics ofAristotle.
William, what a magnificent
librarian you'd have been!
Here's your well done
reward.
Read it. Leaf its secrets.
You've won.
It's close now.
"We'll now discuss how comedy
stimulates the liking ridicule..."
"by using vulgar persons..."
"and taking pleasure from
their defects."
-Carry on, William. Read it!
-Master, we must hurry.
If the light is too deem
for you, give it to the boy...
I'm sure he can read it.
I don't want my pupil
to turn your poisoned pages...
not without the protection
of a glove, such as I'm wearing.
The door! Quick,
before it closes!
Venerable brother, there are many
books that speak of comedy.
Why does this one
fill you with such fear?
Because it's by Aristotle.
This way.
Do you, Salvatore, renounce
the devil and embrace Jesus Christ...
as your Lord and Savior?
Do you, Remigio de Veragine,
renounce the devil...
-and embrace Jesus...
-What for?
It's better die fast
than to spend...
the rest of life in prison.
The devil I renounce
is you, Bernardo Gui.
Do you renounce the devil
and embrace Jesus as your Savior?
But what's so alarming
about laughter?
Laughter kills fear...
and without fear
there can't be faith.
And without fear to the devil...
there's no more need to God.
But you won't eliminate laughter
by eliminating that book.
No, to be sure.
Laughter will remain
the common man's recreation...
but what'll happen if,
because of this book...
Iearned men work
to pronounce permissible...
to laugh of everything?
Can we laugh at God?
The world would
be back to chaos.
Therefore, I seal that
which is not to be said...
in the tomb I become.
He's there, behind the arch!
Save me!
Look!
Courage, brother!
Remember Dolcino!
Go out! I insist!
Go out! I insist!.
God, save him.
Stay back.
Burn the witch!
Do you dare to raise your
hands to the Church?
You won't leave!
It's all your wrong doing!
My master found out the murderer!
Help me!
Master...
I never regretted
my decision...
for I learned from my master
what's wise...
and good and true.
When at last we parted,
he presented me with his glasses.
I was too young, he said...
but one day they'd
serve me well.
In fact, I'm wearing them now
while I write these lines.
He embraced me like a father...
and sent me on my way.
I never saw him again, and knew
nothing of what have become of him...
but I always prayed that God
received his soul...
and forgave his little
vanities to which was driven...
by his intellectual pride.
And yet, now that I'm
an old, old man...
I must confess that all the
faces that appeared to me out of the past...
the one I see most clearly
is that of the girl...
whom I never ceased
to dream...
these many long years.
She was the only earthly
love in my life...
yet I never knew
not ever learned...
her name.
Keep the name first of the rose,
without which we won't exist.
English subtitle originally by: patronu83
Recut, resynced, and post-OCR fixed by
masken 2003-02-22, Athomic 2003-11-11