The thing I've
been asking myself is
what kind of sick individual
names a street Edgewood Way
and he put it half a mile away
from Edgewood Lane?
Huh?
It's crazy.
You got me out here in this creepy,
confusing ass suburb.
I'm serious, though.
I feel like a sore thumb out here.
All right, baby. All right,
I'll talk to you soon.
See you.
Okay,
so this is Rhine Ave.
It's like a fucking
hedge maze out here.
East...
Keep going straight and then
I think it said a left on...
What was that?
Peacock?
Go straight and a left on...
Okay.
All right,
just keep on walking, bruh.
Don't do nothin' stupid.
Just keep on...
Fuck this. I'mma fucking
go the other way I came.
Not today. Not me.
You know how they like to do
motherfuckers out here, man. I'm gone.
Yo... Come on, brother,
this is...
Yo! Yo! Hey!
Sid, Sid, Sid.
How's it goin' over there?
Good.
You got your toothbrush?
Check.
Do you have your deodorant?
Do you have your cozy clothes?
Got that.
Can you give me
a minute, Sid?
We gotta pry something
out of your dad.
What?
Do they know I'm black?
No.
Should they?
It seems like it's something
you might wanna, you know,
mention.
"Mom and Dad,
my black boyfriend
"will be coming
up this weekend
"and I just don't
want you to be shocked
"that he's a black man."
You said I was the first
black guy you ever dated.
Yeah, so what?
Yeah, so this is uncharted
territory for them.
You know, I don't wanna get chased
off the lawn with a shotgun.
You're not going to.
First of all,
my dad would've voted for Obama
a third time if he could've.
Like, the love is so real.
I'm only telling you
that 'cause he's definitely
gonna wanna talk
to you about that.
And it will definitely fucking suck.
But that's because he's a lame
dad more than anything else.
They are not racist.
All right.
I would've told you.
I wouldn't be
bringing you home to them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Think about that for, like, two seconds.
I'm thinkin'.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Good.
No, no, no.
Come on, I'm a grown man.
No way.
You broke my cigarette.
Seriously, you just
threw it out a window?
Just like a dollar. You basically
threw a dollar out the window. Great.
That was a dollar you decided
to spend on nicotine.
Yeah.
Tobacco.
Hold on, I gotta call Rod.
Oh, Rod.
Don't do that.
'Sup?
Yo, you at work?
Yeah, yeah,
I'm at work.
Look, Chris,
tell me this, okay?
How can I get in trouble
for patting down an old lady?
It's standard procedure.
Gary just think 'cause
an elderly bitch is elderly,
she can't hijack no
motherfucking plane.
C, wait, wait, wait.
I know you laughin'.
I'm serious, man.
The next 9/11
is gonna be on
some geriatric shit.
Straight up.
Look, man,
thanks for looking after Sid this weekend.
Remember, no human food.
He's got IBS.
Damn, C.
Give me some type of credit.
Okay, I don't forget shit.
You do.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right, all right.
No, I accept your apology.
It's all good.
How Little
Miss Rosie doin'?
She's good. She's driving.
Can I talk to him?
No.
I'd like to talk
to him, please.
Hold on, hold on.
- Hi, Rod!
- Now, look here.
You know you picked
the wrong guy, right?
Yeah, of course I know that.
This is all just a ploy to get to you.
It's not too late for us.
Okay, get your own girl.
Goddamn.
She's all mad at you 'cause
you never take my advice.
Like what?
Like don't go to
a white girl's parents' house.
What's she doin'?
Lickin' your balls or somethin'?
Yeah, bye.
You know what I'm sayin', Chris?
Chris.
Chri...
This motherfucker
hung up on me.
You're jealous.
I'm not jealous.
I made you jealous?
I'm not jealous of Rod.
It's Rod!
Fuck. Are you okay?
Yeah, that scared
the shit outta me.
You?
Yeah, I'm okay.
All right.
Oh, my God.
Fuck.
Stay here.
What?
What are you doing?
I don't know.
Well, maybe he's gone,
you know?
Chris.
So, in the future, the number to
call is Animal Control Services.
Yes. Sorry about that.
I was just disoriented.
So you guys
coming up from the city?
Yeah, yeah. My parents are
from the Lake Pontaco area.
We're just heading up there
for the weekend. Hmm.
Sir, can I see
your license, please?
Wait, why?
Yeah.
I have state ID.
No, no, no.
He wasn't driving.
I didn't ask who was driving.
I asked to see his ID.
Yeah, why? That doesn't
make any sense. Here.
No, no, no. Fuck that. You
don't have to give him your ID
'cause you haven't
done anything wrong.
Baby, baby, it's okay.
Come on.
Any time there is an incident,
we have every right to ask...
That's bullshit.
Ma'am...
Everything all right, Ryan?
Yeah, I'm good.
Get that headlight fixed.
And that mirror.
Thank you, Officer.
What?
That was hot.
Well, I'm not gonna
let anyone fuck with my man.
I see that.
Okay.
We're here.
It's the groundskeeper.
Are you ready?
Hi!
My little girl!
Come here!
How are you? I love you too.
I missed you.
This is my dad, Dean.
This is Chris.
Call me Mr. Armitage.
Of course.
How you doin'?
I'm kiddin'! You call me Dean.
And you hug me, my man.
How are ya?
I'm good. How are you?
We're huggers.
Yes.
This is my mom.
This is Chris.
Hi, welcome.
Nice to meet you.
Your father gets
really excited, but...
Anyway, yeah.
I'm Missy.
Yes. Come on in.
Please, welcome. Inside.
So how was your drive in?
It was fine.
We actually hit a deer.
What?
Oh, no.
Is it dead?
Yeah.
That's horrible.
Are you guys all right?
Yeah.
It just fruck us out.
It did?
Yeah. It came outta nowhere.
We got it pretty good.
Yeah, it must have
frucked you out, big time.
Frucking weird. Well, you
know what I say?
I say one down, a couple
hundred thousand to go.
Dean.
Dad.
No, I don't mean to get on my
high horse, but I'm telling ya,
I do not like the deer. I'm sick of it.
They're taking over.
They're like rats.
They're destroying the ecosystem.
I see a dead deer on the side
of the road, I think to myself,
"That's a start."
I don't even
understand that.
I'm sorry.
I'm just sayin'.
You know what, I am grateful
for what you've done today.
I don't like 'em.
We got that.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right, you guys
look so wiped out.
Yeah, a little.
Yeah.
So how long has this
been going on? This...
This thang?
How long?
Four months.
Four months?
Mmm.
Five months, actually.
She's right, I'm wrong.
Attaboy. Better get
used to saying that.
Please, I'm so sorry.
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry.
She's right, I'm wrong.
See?
Does he have an off button?
This is exhausting.
I know.
I wanna give you a tour.
They just got...
Can we unpack first?
You wanna unpack?
Before the tour?
This is Missy's office.
She takes appointments in there.
She's a therapist,
right?
Psychiatrist, yeah.
Turns out people up here
are just as messed up in the
head as they are in the city.
This is Jeremy.
That's Rose's little brother.
There he is.
I've heard stories.
Yeah, I bet you have.
He's studying medicine now.
Wants to be just like his old man.
You'll meet him.
All right. Cool.
I picked these up in Bali.
It's pretty eclectic.
I'm a traveler and I can't help it.
I keep bringing
souvenirs back.
It's such
a privilege to be able
to experience
another person's culture.
You know what I'm saying?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, you're gonna
love this.
My dad's claim to fame.
He was beat by Jesse Owens
in the qualifying round for
the Berlin Olympics in 1936.
Those are the ones where...
Owens won in front of Hitler.
Yeah, what a moment.
What a moment.
I mean, Hitler's up there with all
his perfect Aryan race bullshit.
This black dude
comes along,
proves him wrong in front
of the entire world.
Amazing.
Tough break for
your dad though.
Yeah.
He almost got over it.
That's the basement.
We had to seal it up.
We got some black
mold down there.
My mother loved her kitchen,
so we keep a piece of her in here.
Georgina, this is Chris.
This is Rose's boyfriend.
Hi.
Hello.
The garbage goes
under the sink,
and now for the
pièce de résistance,
the field of play.
I love it.
The nearest house
is across the lake.
It's total privacy.
I know what
you're thinking.
What?
Come on, I get it.
White family,
black servants.
It's a total cliché.
I wasn't gonna
take it there.
Well, you didn't have to.
Believe me.
No.
We hired Georgina and Walter
to help care for my parents.
When they died,
I couldn't bear to
let them go. I mean...
But, boy, I hate
the way it looks.
Yeah, I know
what you mean.
By the way, I would have voted for
Obama for a third term if I could.
Best president in my lifetime.
Hands down.
I agree.
Yeah.
So what do your
parents do, Chris?
Uh...
My dad wasn't
really in the picture.
My mom passed
away when I was 11.
Oh, I'm sorry.
How did she die?
A hit and run.
That's awful.
Yeah, I'm sorry to hear that.
You were young.
Actually, I don't remember a
lot from that time, so...
Well, that's okay. We don't
have to talk about that.
You smoke, Chris?
Mmm-hmm.
You jonesing
a little bit over there, huh?
I'm quitting.
Dad, this is why I don't bring
people to the house anymore.
That's okay.
We're not judging. We're not.
That's a nasty habit,
though.
You should have Missy take
care of that for you.
How?
Hypnosis.
She developed a method, and I'm
telling you, it works like a charm.
Wow, um...
Some people
don't want strangers
messing around in
their heads, guys.
Listen, Chris, I thought
it was total bullshit.
I smoked cigarettes
for 15 years.
I loved every
goddamn puff I took.
She puts me under once...
The sight of a cigarette
makes me want to vomit.
Okay, fall back, Dean.
It's a service we provide.
I'm good, actually.
Yes.
Thank you, though.
Well, smoker or not,
we're thrilled to have you up here
for the big get-together.
Yeah.
Wait, holy shit.
That's this weekend?
Yes, this weekend.
What get-together?
Oh, my God.
Thanks, George.
It's Rose's grandfather's party.
My dad would throw
a shindig once a year.
Get all his friends together,
bocce ball, badminton...
Wait, why didn't you
guys tell me about this?
Well, it's the same day
every year, sweetheart.
- No, it's not.
- Um...
It is.
Actually, it is.
Is it really?
- Yeah, that's where you'd be wrong.
- Yeah.
We just kept it up because after
they died, it felt like...
We keep them close to us.
Yeah, they're still with us.
I just wanted to
have a chill weekend.
Sounds like fun, actually.
Oh, Georgina.
I'm so sorry.
That's okay.
Why don't you go lay down?
Just get some rest.
Yes, I think I will.
Good.
My God, it must be very...
'Sup, fam!
Hey, Jer-Bear.
Hi, darling.
Hey, buddy.
Nobody answers
the door around here?
Hey, Rosie.
Why would I lie, huh?
I love it!
Did she tell you about
her toenail collection?
What?
Oh, my God!
She used to bite 'em off, suck on 'em,
and save 'em in a jewelry box.
No, I didn't. I don't know
what you're talking about.
That is so disgusting.
I fucking hate you.
Okay, here's a good one.
Uh, let me set the scene.
It was our junior year.
Rose has a crush on this guy,
Conner Garfield.
No. Mom?
No, Jeremy, stop.
No, no, these are good.
I want to hear them.
Yeah, Rose,
where are your manners?
Our guest wants to
hear the stories, please.
Thank you.
So Conner's from my lacrosse team, right?
Huge kid, like 6'3".
And he's pretty dumb, right?
So we threw this party.
You threw a party.
I think my parents
were in Greece or something.
We raided their liquor cabinet
and we're all shit-faced.
Like 15 of us.
Oh, my God. Tell me
this isn't true, Rose.
Yeah.
I filled the liquor
bottles with water...
And let me finish?
Uh-huh. Go ahead.
I'm curious.
So I'm upstairs hooking up with the
hottest girl in class, Jean Deely.
Oh, God.
You realize you're
coming off as, like,
the world's
biggest douchebag, right?
So Conner starts banging
on the bathroom door, right?
I open it
and blood's gushing from his mouth.
And he's screaming,
"Your sister
bit my fucking tongue off!"
- You bit him?
- What?
Okay, to be fair,
it was my first kiss
and he slipped some tongue
and I was not expecting it.
It was a reflex.
I'm sorry.
A reflex that I have
since gotten rid of.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you better be careful.
Yeah, I'm very careful now.
I'm gonna go get dessert. And, Dean,
maybe clean it up just a little bit?
So, Chris, what's your sport?
Football? Baseball?
Basketball, mostly, I guess.
You an MMA fan?
Dude.
"Dude" what?
What?
Hey, Jeremy, why don't we let someone
else have the floor for a second?
You're dating
my sister, right?
He's dating my sister.
You had your chance.
I can't get to know
the guy?
You mean like UFC?
Yes.
Nah, too brutal for me.
You ever get into
street fights as a kid?
I did judo after school,
first grade.
Aw...
You should've seen me.
Judo?
'Cause with your frame
and your genetic makeup,
if you really
pushed your body,
and I mean really train,
you know?
No pussyfooting around.
You'd be a fucking beast.
Carrot cake!
Ooh!
Hi.
Carrot cake.
What did I miss?
A whole bunch of nothing.
Just talking about sports.
Right?
Yeah.
That sounds good.
So the thing
about jiu-jitsu is
strength doesn't matter, right?
It's all about this.
It's a strategic game
like chess.
It's all about being two,
three, four moves ahead.
Cool.
Stand up.
Jeremy, no karate
at the dinner table.
It's not karate, Ma.
Yo, I got a rule.
No play-fighting with drunk dudes.
I don't play,
I'm just...
Jeremy.
I wasn't gonna hurt him.
He was gonna put you
in a fucking headlock.
What is his problem?
He has never treated
any of my boyfriends that way.
Ever, ever, ever.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, my God. And then my dad
with the "my man" stuff.
"My man, my man."
I don't think he's ever heard that
or said it. And now he just...
It's all he says.
Yup.
Oh, and my mom being
rude to Georgina?
What the fuck was that about?
That was so crazy.
I mean...
How are they different
than that cop?
That's the fucking
bummer of it all.
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm-hmm?
Anything more
you'd like to add?
I told you so, like...
I didn't want to say it.
I didn't want to say that.
I don't like being wrong.
I've noticed that.
But I am sorry.
No, no, no.
Wait. Come here. Come here.
I'm sorry.
This sucks.
What? Why you saying "sorry"?
'Cause I brought you here and
I'm related to all of them.
No, it's fine.
It's fine.
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
How are you so calm?
Honestly, it's nothing.
I like you on your
racial flow, though.
Is this a racial flow?
Racial flow.
Am I feeling
a racial flow?
Yeah, you're
feeling racially flowy.
Oh, fuck. The party.
How bad can it be?
They are so white.
Like, so white!
It's all good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You know,
with my genetic makeup,
shit gonna go down.
I'm a beast.
I'm a beast!
Do you realize how
dangerous smoking is?
Yeah.
Come in and sit with me.
Please?
Just for a little while.
Please.
Thank you.
So you're
comfortable enough, right?
It's perfect. Thanks.
Sure.
You wanna know
how it works?
You just dangle a pocket watch in
front of people's faces? Is that it?
You watch a lot of TV.
When I was a kid.
Uh...
Now you're
feeling very sleepy.
We do use focal
points sometimes
to guide someone into a state
of heightened suggestibility.
"Heightened suggestibility."
That's right.
Do you smoke in front
of my daughter?
I'm gonna quit.
I promise.
That's my kid.
That is my kid.
You understand?
What about your mother?
What about her?
Wait, are we...
Where were you when she died?
I don't want to
think about that.
Home. Watching TV.
Do you hear the TV?
What do you hear?
Rain.
Rain. It was raining.
Hmm.
You hear the rain?
Mmm-hmm...
You hear it? Find it.
Tell me when you've found it.
Come here, Chris.
Look at me.
I found it.
Where was your mom?
She was coming home
and she wasn't home.
From work?
Hmm.
And what do you do?
Nothing.
I just sat there.
You didn't call anyone?
No.
Why not?
I don't know.
I just thought that if I did,
it would make it real.
Hmm.
You're so scared.
You think it was your fault.
How do you feel now?
I can't move.
You can't move.
Why can't I move?
You're paralyzed.
Just like that day
when you did nothing.
You did nothing.
Now,
sink into the floor.
Wait, wait, wait.
Sink.
Now you're in
the Sunken Place.
'Sup, man?
They're workin' you
good out here, huh?
Nothing I don't want
to be doing.
Yeah.
I didn't get to meet you,
actually, up close. I'm Chris.
I know who you are.
She is lovely, isn't she?
Rose?
Yeah, she is.
One of a kind.
Top of the line.
A real doggone keeper.
Right.
Sorry about last night.
What?
My exercise.
I didn't mean to scare you.
Yeah. Yeah.
And did it work?
Did what work?
You were in Mrs. Armitage's
office for quite some time.
Oh, yeah.
Hmm?
I guess I had too much
of that wine last night.
Can't really remember. Sorry.
Well, I should get back to
work and mind my own business.
I think your mom hypnotized
me last night.
What?
When?
I went out for some air last night,
and I run into her.
And I can barely
remember anything,
but now the thought of a cigarette
makes me wanna throw up.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry. I can't believe
she did that to you.
And I had some
fucked-up dreams.
What'd you dream?
I was in a hole or something.
And I couldn't move. It was like...
Oh, God. That sounds terrible.
I'm sorry.
Hey, uh, what's Walter's deal?
What do you mean "his deal"?
I just talked to him.
Dude's whole vibe is hostile.
Did he say something?
It's not what he says.
It's how he says it, you know?
Hmm.
Maybe he likes you.
Maybe he's jealous
or something. I don't...
Are you fucking with me?
No.
So you think I've got
a chance with him?
All right, you got jokes.
Put in a good word?
Great. No, funny.
I'm gonna talk to my dad about that.
That's not...
No, don't talk to your dad.
It's not cool.
It's fine, it's not a big deal.
It's not a big deal.
Forget about it. It's done.
Okay.
Oh, boy.
Oh, man.
It begins.
Are you ready for this?
Yeah, I am.
I'm not.
There they are.
Oh!
So nice.
How are you?
Just smile.
Smile? All right.
How do you do that again?
Yeah, just smile
the whole time.
Yeah, there you go.
There it is.
Oh, look,
it's the Greenes.
Gordon and Emily,
this is Chris.
Chris, this is Gordon
and Emily Greene.
Chris. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, Chris.
Nice to meet you indeed.
Oh, that's quite a grip.
Thank you. You too, man.
You, uh, ever play golf?
Mmm, once, a few years ago.
I wasn't very good.
Gordon was a professional
golfer for years.
Oh, you kiddin'?
Well, I can't quite swing the
hips like I used to, though.
But, uh, I do know Tiger.
Oh.
Oh, that's great.
Super.
Gordon loves Tiger.
Oh, the best I've ever seen.
Ever. Hands down.
So, Chris, uh,
let's see your form.
This is Nelson and Lisa.
Hey, how you doin'?
So, how handsome is he?
I don't know, are you handsome?
Okay.
Oh!
Not bad. Eh, Nelson?
So, is it true?
Is it better?
Oh, wow.
Wow.
Fairer skin has been in favor for the
past, what, couple of hundreds of years?
But now the pendulum
has swung back.
Black is in fashion.
Pardon me, I'm gonna
take some pictures.
Sure thing.
- There he is.
- Oh!
Good to see another
brother around here.
Hi. Yes, of course it is.
Something wrong?
There you are.
Do something with this.
Ah, yes, yes.
Oh, hello. I'm Philomena.
And you are?
Chris. Rose's boyfriend.
Fantastic.
You two make a lovely couple.
Thanks.
Oh, where are my manners?
Logan. Logan King.
Chris was just telling me
how he felt
much more comfortable
with my being here.
That's nice.
Logan, I hate to tear you
away, dear, but
the Wincotts were
asking about you.
Ah, mmm.
Well, it was nice to
meet you, Chris.
Goodbye.
What the fuck?
Ignorance.
Who?
All of 'em.
They mean well but they have no
idea what real people go through.
Jim Hudson.
Chris.
I know who you are.
I am an admirer of your work.
You have a great eye.
Wait, Jim Hudson?
Hudson Galleries?
Believe me, the irony of being a
blind art dealer isn't lost on me.
How'd you do it?
My assistant describes the
work to me in great detail.
You've got something.
The images you capture.
So brutal, so melancholic.
It's powerful stuff, I think.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Used to dabble myself,
wilderness mostly.
I submitted to Nat Geo 14 times before
realizing I didn't have the eye.
I began dealing.
Then, of course, my vision went to shit.
Damn.
I know. Life can be
a sick joke.
One day, you're developing
prints in the darkroom.
The next day,
you wake up in the dark.
Genetic disease.
Shit ain't fair, man.
Oh, you got that right.
Shit ain't fair.
Hey.
Come here, come here.
What the fuck?
You left me out there.
Look at this.
She unplugged my phone.
Who?
Georgina. I came here to talk
to Rod, and I got no juice.
So you think she
did that because...
Maybe she doesn't like
the fact that I'm with you.
Really?
It's a thing.
So you are so sexy that people
are just unpluggin' your phone?
Forget it. Never mind.
No, no, no. Stop, don't...
Don't do that.
Don't...
Okay, okay, I'm sorry.
It's all good, all right?
They got you on
display now, huh?
It's weird, man.
And it's the people here, too.
It's like they haven't met a black
person that doesn't work for 'em.
Yep, you're in it.
Also, shit...
I don't even wanna tell you.
What?
I got hypnotized last night.
Nigga, get the fuck
outta here.
No. Yo, yo.
Yeah, to quit smoking.
But it's Rose's mom's
a psychiatrist, so...
Bruh, I don't care if the bitch
is Iyanla Vanzant, okay?
She can't fix my motherfuckin' life.
You ain't gettin' in my head.
I know. She caught me
off guard, right?
But it's cool because
I'm cured. It worked.
Bruh, how are you
not scared of this, man?
Look, they could've made you
do all types of stupid shit.
They'd have you fuckin'
barking like a dog,
flying around
like you're a fuckin' pigeon,
lookin' ridiculous, okay?
Or, I don't know
if you know this,
white people love makin'
people sex slaves and shit.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure they're
not a kinky sex family, dawg.
Look, Jeffrey Dahmer was eating the
shit outta niggas' heads. Okay?
But that was after
he fucked the heads.
Do you think they
saw that shit comin'?
Hell no.
Okay? They was comin'
over there like,
"I'mma just suck a little dick,
maybe jiggle some balls and shit."
No. They didn't get
a chance to jiggle shit
because their head
was off their fuckin' body.
Yeah, they still sucked a dick,
but without their heads.
It was fuckin' weird,
detached head shit.
You know, that's
Jeffrey Dahmer's business.
And thanks for that
image right there, man.
Hey, man, I ain't makin' this shit up.
I saw on A&E, man.
It's real life.
Yo, and it's the black people
out here, too.
It's like all of them
missed the movement.
'Cause they
probably hypnotized.
Look, bruh, all I'm doin'
is connecting the dots.
I'm taking what you
presented to me, okay?
I'mma tell you this.
I think that mom
is puttin' everybody
in a trance,
and she's fuckin'
the shit out of 'em.
Thanks, Rod, bye.
Hello.
Fuck. Hi.
I owe you an apology.
How rude of me to have touched
your belongings without asking.
Oh...
No, it's cool.
I was just confused.
Well, I can assure you,
there was no funny business.
Allow me to explain.
I lifted your cellular phone
to wipe down the dresser,
and it accidentally
came undone.
Yeah, I told... Rather than
meddle with it further,
I left it that way.
How foolish of me.
It's fine.
I wasn't trying to snitch.
Snitch?
Rat you out.
Tattletale.
Yeah.
Oh, don't you
worry about that.
I can assure you,
I don't answer to anyone.
Right.
All I know is sometimes
if there's too many white people,
I get nervous, you know?
Oh. Oh!
No. No. No.
No, no, no, no.
Aren't you something?
That's not my experience.
Not at all.
The Armitages are
so good to us.
They treat us like family.
This bitch is crazy.
The bitch is crazy.
Oh, hey, hang on. Chris.
Chris, I wanna introduce you
to some friends.
This is David
and Marcia Wincott,
Ronald and Celia Jeffries,
Hiroki Tanaka,
and Jessika and
Fredrich Walden.
Too many names
to remember, but hi.
Do you find that
being African-American
has more advantage or
disadvantage in the modern world?
Whoa!
It's a tough one.
Yeah, um, I don't know, man.
Hey.
Yo, my man.
They were askin' me about the
African-American experience.
Maybe you could take this one.
Oh.
Well, well, I find that the
African-American experience
for me has been,
for the most part, very good.
Although I find it difficult
to go into detail
as I haven't had much of a desire
to leave the house in a while.
We've become such homebodies.
Yes, yes.
But even when you go into the city,
I've just had no interest.
The chores have become
my sanctuary.
Fucking shit.
Get out.
Sorry, man.
Logan.
Get out!
Yo!
Yo, chill, man.
Get out!
Get outta here! Get outta here!
Chill! Chill, man! Chill!
Get the fuck outta here!
Chill!
Seizures create anxiety
which can trigger aggression.
Yeah, but randomly
attacking other people?
It's not random.
You know, it was your flash.
That's what set him off.
Hey.
Well...
How's he doing?
He's much better.
I imagine that I owe
you all an apology.
No, no, no.
We're just very happy
that you're yourself again.
Yes. Yes, I am.
Hmm.
And I thank God
for you for calming me down.
I know that I must've
frightened you all quite a bit.
Especially you, Chris.
No. I'm sorry.
The flash. I didn't know.
Of course not.
How could you have?
And you shouldn't
have been drinking, either.
Yes.
Well, I'll have to
let you all get on
the rest of the night without
the aid of my marvelous wit.
The whole ordeal has made me
quite a bit exhausted.
Logan, you just
get some rest.
It was nice
meeting you, Chris.
Yeah.
Something to lighten the mood?
Yes! Yeah, let's get this
party back on track.
How about sparklers
and Bingo?
We're gonna go on a walk.
You sure?
Shall we?
My cousin's epileptic.
That wasn't a seizure, right?
My dad's a neurosurgeon.
And that's what he said it was.
I'm inclined to trust...
That wasn't a seizure.
What was it then?
How long have you
known that guy?
I met him today. Why?
Man, this is gonna
sound weird,
but when he came at me,
it felt like I knew him.
Like you've met Logan before?
No, I don't know Logan.
I knew the guy that come at me.
I think your mom got in my head, all right?
I think she got in my head.
Yeah, and it worked,
I thought...
No, it did not.
It didn't work.
She got in my head,
and now I'm thinking all this fucked-up
shit that I don't want to think about.
Like what?
I just need to go.
You wanna go?
Mmm-hmm.
Without me?
Whatever you want.
I told you about that
night my mom died.
When I didn't call 911,
didn't go out looking for her.
Yeah.
One hour went by,
then two, then three,
and I just sat there.
I was just watching TV.
There's nothing
you could've done.
I found out later
that, uh,
she had survived
the initial hit.
She laid there bleeding
by the side of the road,
cold and alone.
That's how she died in the
early morning, cold and alone.
And I was watching TV.
There was time. There was time.
You were just a little kid.
There was time.
There was time, if somebody
was looking for her.
There was time, but nobody,
nobody was looking.
You're all I got.
I'm not gonna leave here without you.
I'm not gonna abandon you, okay?
You're not?
No, no, I'm not.
Oh, my God.
You scared me.
Let's go home.
What?
Let's go home. This sucks.
This sucks. Let's go home.
I'll make something up.
I love you.
I love you too, baby.
Good night.
Thank you.
Come on, sweetie.
Good night, Chris!
It was great to meet you.
Asshole.
Yo!
That's Dre.
Dre?
Andre Hayworth. He used
to kick it with Veronica.
Veronica from what?
Teresa's sister, that worked at
the movie theater on Eighth!
Yes, that is him!
That is him! But wait...
This is so fucking crazy!
Yo, he's different.
No shit. Why's he
dressed like that?
It's not that,
it's everything.
He came to the party with a white
woman 30 years older than him.
Sex slave! Oh, shit!
Chris, you gotta get the
fuck up outta there, man!
You in some Eyes Wide Shut situation.
Leave, motherfucker.
Hello?
You gonna be a...
Hello? Chris?
Oh, shit. His battery
must've fuckin' died.
Hey, handsome.
Are you packing?
Rose, we gotta go.
We gotta go now.
Okay.
Is everything okay?
I'll tell you in the car.
But we gotta go right now.
Is that okay?
Okay, yeah.
Uh, let me go get my bag.
Okay.
Shit.
Hey, you ready?
Yeah, I'm just looking
for my camera.
Uh...
It's right here.
Have you got the keys? I'm gonna put
the bags in the trunk real quick.
Okay.
Uh, yeah.
They are in here somewhere.
It's just a matter of finding them.
Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
Might take me a second.
Hey, uh...
What, you can't
find those keys?
No. I can never find them.
Let's do this on the move.
Yeah.
Chris?
Just get the keys.
Yo.
Yo, man.
Where you going?
The party was just getting started.
Just putting the bags
in the car, man.
Would anyone like tea?
Nah, I'm good.
We leavin', actually.
Really? Why?
Is something wrong?
Rose?
His dog got really sick.
So he has to be at the vet
first thing in the morning.
Sick.
Yeah.
Oh, how terrible.
- Rose, the keys.
- Looking.
Rose?
What is your
purpose, Chris?
What?
In life, what is your purpose?
Right now,
it's finding those keys.
Fire.
It's a reflection
of our own mortality.
We're born, we breathe,
and we die.
Rose?
I'm looking.
Even the sun will die someday.
But we are divine.
We are the gods
trapped in cocoons.
Rose...
I don't know where they are.
Rose?
Rose!
Rose, give me those keys!
Rose, give me...
Give me those keys.
Rose, now! Now, the keys!
Be careful, bro.
What the fuck?
I didn't do anything.
What the fuck
is going on?
Where are those keys, Rose?
You know I can't give you
the keys, right, babe?
Come on.
Oh, shit.
Is he hurt?
Did you see him drop?
Yes, I did.
Jeremy, grab his legs, please.
Take him downstairs.
Dean, help him.
I can get him alone.
No, you can't.
You've already
damaged him enough.
Okay, fine.
Okay.
Ready?
Mind his head. Please.
Easy.
You're gonna drop him.
No, I'm not.
You're not gonna give me
a little credit?
Okay, that was my fault.
You were
one of my favorites.
You hear that, Chris?
Huh?
You're one of her favorites. Chris?
Hey, it's Chris.
I'm either away from the phone or I
just don't wanna talk to you. Peace.
Chris!
Hey, it's Chris.
I'm either away from the phone or I
just don't wanna talk to you. Peace.
Yeah.
Me too.
...College Fund.
A mind is a terrible
thing to waste.
Millions of Americans
feel the effects of aging.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Is there anything
more beautiful than a sunrise?
Hi. I'm Roman Armitage.
And if you're watching this, you're
probably wondering what's going on.
There's no need to worry.
Let's take a walk.
You have been chosen because
of the physical advantages
you've enjoyed
your entire lifetime.
With your natural gifts
and our determination,
we could both be
part of something greater.
Something perfect.
The Coagula procedure
is a man-made miracle.
Our order has been developing
it for many, many years,
and it wasn't until
recently it was perfected
by my own flesh and blood.
My family and I are honored to offer it
as a service to members of our group.
Don't waste your strength,
don't try to fight it.
You can't stop the inevitable.
And who knows?
Maybe one day, you'll enjoy
being members of the family.
Behold,
the Coagula.
What the fuck?
Hello, Mr...
Uh, Williams. Rod Williams.
From the TSA?
Yes, ma'am.
You know all TSA issues should be brought
up with your authorizing officer.
Yes, ma'am, but this
is not TSA business.
Okay, don't call me "ma'am."
Otherwise we're not gonna get along.
How can I help you,
Rod Williams from the TSA?
All right, here it is.
Mmm.
My boy, Chris, has been
missing for two days.
Your son is missing?
Oh, no. Not my son,
my friend. He's 26.
His name is Chris Washington.
He left on Friday with
his girlfriend, Rose Armitage.
She's white.
All right. Go on.
Look, Chris was supposed
to come back on Sunday, right?
And I've been watching his dog, Sid.
That's Sid.
Cute, right?
So Chris sent this to me from his
girlfriend's parents' house.
See, that's Andre Hayworth.
Okay? Somebody we knew
from back in the day.
Apparently, he's been missing for
six months in some affluent suburb.
Well, he don't look
so missing to me.
That's 'cause we
found him, right?
But Chris said
he's acting real different.
Different how?
This dude is from Brooklyn.
Huh? He didn't dress
like this.
I didn't use to
dress like this.
Plus he's married to a
white woman twice his age.
And that would explain
the clothes. All right.
Oh, Lord! Rod Williams
from the TSA.
I know, I know, I know.
Okay, I'm trying to
work towards this.
Look, what I'm about to
tell you gonna sound crazy.
You ready?
All right.
Try me.
I believe they've been
abducting black people,
brainwashing 'em, making 'em work
for 'em as sex slaves and shit.
Oh, sorry about the "shit."
Sorry.
Hold on a second.
Then he sent me some
weird picture and I'm like,
"Oh, man,
that's Andre Hayworth."
This dude been missing
for six months, right?
So I do all my research,
you know, 'cause as a TSA agent...
You guys are detectives?
I got the same training, you know?
We might know more
than y'all sometimes.
'Cause we dealin' with
some terrorist shit, so...
But that's a
totally different story.
So, look, I go do
my detective work, right?
And I start putting
pieces together.
And, see, this is
what I came up with.
They're probably abducting black people,
brainwashing 'em and making 'em slaves.
Or sex slaves. Not just regular slaves,
but sex slaves and shit.
See, I don't know if it's the hypnosis
that's making 'em slaves or whatnot,
but all I know is they already
got two brothers we know,
and there could be a whole bunch
of brothers they got already.
What's the next move?
And don't ever, ever say that
I don't do nothin' for you.
Oh! White girls.
Oh, they get you every time.
Oh!
Magic ain't real.
None of this shit makes sense.
Hello?
Chris?
Yo, um...
Hey, what up?
Rose, it's me, Rod.
Hi.
Where's Chris?
He left two days ago.
He left?
Yeah. He got all paranoid,
and then he freaked out on me.
And then he just got
in a cab and left his phone.
Wait. You haven't seen him?
No, he never came back here.
Oh, my God.
Look, look, I've been calling
his phone a bunch of times.
Matter of fact,
I went to the police.
What did you say?
I just said he was missing.
Oh, good. Uh...
Let me ask you somethin'.
What cab company
did he, uh, use to leave?
Oh, gosh.
I don't know. I guess
maybe a local one.
Or I guess he could've
called an Uber?
Um, wait. I'm so confused.
Oh, you confused? Okay.
You know somethin'? Me too.
Could you hold on one second?
Okay.
Okay. Hold on.
You lyin' bitch. She is lyin' like
a motherfucker. I know that...
Ooh, that TSA shit tingles.
This motherfucker's lying.
Okay, I got you.
I'm gonna record your ass.
I'mma record
the shit outta you.
You talk too goddamn much.
You're gonna say somethin'.
Hold on. Record.
Speaker.
Unmute.
Uh, Rose?
Uh-huh?
Um...
So last time I talked to Chris,
he told me your mama hypnotized him.
Rod, just stop.
Huh?
I know why you're calling.
Why is that?
It's kind of obvious,
don't you think?
What?
That there's something
between us.
No. What you talkin' about, girl?
I called you about Chris.
No, Rod, whenever we'd go out,
I remember you looking at me.
What the fuck you...
No! Chris is my best friend.
Look, if you did
somethin' to him...
I know you think about
fucking me, Rod.
Ain't nobody thought about fucking you.
Why would you say some stupid shit?
What the... You ass! Fuck you!
I didn't wanna...
Fuck you! Bye!
Shit!
God! She's so...
She's a fuckin'... She's a...
She's a genius.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hey, Chris.
How's it going, buddy?
You can answer.
There's an intercom in the room.
Where's Rose?
Oh, you dirty dog.
You're one of the lucky ones,
trust me.
Jeremy's wrangling method
sounds way less pleasant.
I'm supposed to answer
any outstanding questions,
concerns you may have so far.
Apparently, our common
understanding of the process
has a positive impact on the
success rate of the procedure.
You could give a shit,
right? Okay.
Let me just tell you
what it is.
Phase one was the hypnotism.
That's how they sedate you.
Phase two is this.
Mental preparation.
It's basically psychological pre-op.
Pre-op?
For phase three.
The transplantation.
Well, partial, actually.
The piece of your brain connected
to your nervous system
needs to stay put, keeping those
intricate connections intact.
So you won't be gone,
not completely.
A sliver of you will still be in there,
somewhere, limited consciousness.
You'll be able to see and hear
what your body is doing,
but your existence
will be as a passenger.
An audience. You'll live in...
The Sunken Place.
Now you're in the Sunken Place.
Yeah. That's what
she calls it.
Now, I'll control the motor
functions, so I'll be...
Me.
You'll be me.
Good, good.
You got it quick. Good on you.
Why us, huh?
Why black people?
Who knows?
People want a change.
Some people wanna be stronger,
faster, cooler.
Black is in fashion.
But please don't lump me in with that.
I could give a shit what color you are.
No. What I want is deeper.
I want your eye, man.
I want those things
you see through.
This is crazy.
Okay, I'm done.
No, no, no, no.
Jeremy?
You fuck!
You fuck.
Fuck you!
Come on! Come on!
One Mississippi.
Two Mississippi.
Three Mississippi.
Four Mississippi.
911. What's your emergency?
I'm at the Armitage house.
My name is Chris.
I'm sorry, sir,
can you repeat that?
I'm at the Armitage...
No, no, no.
Don't do it, don't do it.
Don't do it. Just fuckin' go.
Grandma.
You ruined my house!
Get him, Grandpa.
Damn you!
Let me do it.
Chris, I'm so sorry.
It's me.
And I love you.
I love you.
Help. Help.
Help. Help me.
Oh, shit!
Chris!
I mean, I told you
not to go in that house.
I mean...
How'd you find me?
I'm T-S-motherfuckin'-A.
We handle shit.
That's what we do.
Consider this situation
fuckin' handled.