It's like everything
changed in the blink of an eye.
One moment we were fine,
then everything turned to shit.
My little one...
I'm going to miss you all.
Look at me.
We'll write to each other.
You have my address,
don't you?
Then everything's fine.
Off you go.
We'll all miss you, Teacher Dilek.
- Good luck in Istanbul.
- Give your mother my best.
Have a good holiday, Miss.
You're all sad.
Come here.
Selma,
the sun's out, let's walk.
Lale!
Don't splash me!
Ready?
Stop it!
We win!
What?
- My turn again!
- No way.
I want another go.
No way!
You cheated.
No, we didn't.
It's not fair.
- You cheated!
- No, we never!
Give her another go.
Everyone gets just one go.
Take your turn!
Let me go!
I can't reach.
I was going to help you.
Look, they've grown all of a sudden!
Show me your boobs.
What are you doing in my garden!
Clear off!
We've only taken a few apples.
Get out of my garden!
- OK, we're going.
- Calm down.
Sonay,
as you're the eldest,
I'll start with you.
Grandma!
Sonay!
Grandma, open the door!
Grandma?
Sonay, are you OK?
Your turn now.
Selma!
Open the door!
Grandma, open up!
Grandma, open the door!
- Get out!
- What's this all about?
- Ece, come here.
- What did we do?
It was just a few apples.
Everyone's talking
about your obscene behaviour.
What?
Rubbing up against boys' necks.
On the beach.
Rubbing your parts on boys' necks!
We were on their shoulders,
it was a game...
There's no such game!
Who told you this?
- Ece, come here.
- Who told you?
Come here!
Mrs Petek called me
to tell me what you were up to.
How could she?
My granddaughters,
pleasuring themselves on boys' necks!
What?
You're depraved!
Come here!
Get out!
I can't watch you all day long.
You're disgusting!
Get back!
Grandma, stop it!
Nur, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
These chairs touched our arseholes!
That's disgusting!
Have you gone mad?
Come here!
Come back!
Mrs Petek!
Girls!
Mrs Petek's at the market.
Lale!
Mrs Petek!
Do your shit-coloured clothes
make you everyone's moral judge?
What are you doing?
I did it for your own good.
No.
Yes.
I'm sorry, Mrs Petek.
Please forgive them.
Straight home!
Now!
What am I going to do with you?
That's enough, Mum.
Enough!
You've been saying that for years.
"Give them their freedom,
they're just children."
- It's true.
- What's true?
Their parents have been dead
a decade now.
- Be more understanding...
- About what?
They've grown up.
Can't you see?
You know what people are saying?
Don't listen to gossip.
Do you know what they do?
You think you're helping them?
How can you talk like this
to your own mother?
I'll show them!
Where are they?
Watch your language.
Lale, Nur, out!
Out!
Calm down.
Which one is it?
- Calm down.
- Or is it all of you?
- Which one?
- Calm down.
Which one acts like a whore?
Or is it all of you?
Teasing the boys, eh?
Is it you?
Mum!
- They've done nothing wrong!
- How do you know?
- I know.
- How can you be so sure?
They're my granddaughters.
If they're sullied, it's your fault.
I'll prove it to you.
Calm down.
They've always done just what they want.
- How can you fix that?
- Do you think it's easy?
I lost my sons.
I understand.
But it was a long time ago now.
Pull yourself together.
I've raised them
by myself for years.
I understand.
But Erol is right.
He has every reason to be angry.
It's come to this
because you didn't do your job right.
What are you looking at?
Spit out that gum!
Ece, Sonay, Selma, come with me.
Selma.
- What did they do?
- A virginity report.
What's that?
- Did you strip naked for the doctor?
- Yes.
He said I had nothing
he hadn't seen before.
It's true.
We're all made the same.
No. You've got one boob
bigger than the other!
We didn't need to go to the doctor's.
We told you.
If there was the slightest doubt,
you'd never be able to get married.
After that, the doors to the house
were always locked.
Anything likely to pervert us
was banned.
What?
Which road?
All right.
The bastards!
Mum, will you take these girls in hand,
or do I have to?
Sonay, you're mine
Welcome!
- Jump...
- I'm going to fall!
You won't fall.
She's falling.
My baby's born!
Move your feet!
Your order is here.
Your toe dessert from foot world!
- I didn't order anything.
- It's your order!
There's been a mistake.
A mistake?
Put a vine leaf on your plate...
The house became a wife factory,
that we never came out of.
Watch...
If you overstuff them, they go soft,
which isn't good.
No one likes a soft dolma.
Don't burst the peppers.
It has to be nice and round.
Watch carefully.
Yes, you're doing it well.
That's very good.
There's nothing you can't do.
Keep turning it.
You watched me do it, right?
There, that'll be perfectly round.
Well done.
Shall we show the others?
Straight towards you.
You'll all learn how to do this.
Careful with the knife.
Ece, it's your turn.
Well done, girls.
Spread it out evenly.
Come here.
Now it was our turn to wear
shapeless, shit-coloured dresses.
A few basic principles about soup.
Made from a proper broth,
it has more taste.
You can also improve the flavour
and nutritional value
with certain preparations.
In front of my house!
I'll kill him!
"Sonay, you're mine"?
Lale!
That's enough! Get out!
What are you doing here?
Once the milk
takes on this consistency,
add the sugar and the gum.
A measure of salep...
Pour it into these moulds,
put it in the fridge,
and once it's cooled
you'll have chewing-gum!
I'm going to faint!
Help, I'm stuck!
Hang on...
Watch it!
How are we going
to get the dress back?
Did it fly out?
What's that?
Chewing-gum.
Really? Where did you get it?
- We made it.
- How?
The best chewing-gum ever!
It's a bit sticky.
You know what?
We can improve these dresses.
That's better.
- Nice.
- Tear it a bit more.
All the way up.
Wear it like that.
- Strike a pose!
- Like this?
Ouch, my ear!
Where did you go?
The beach.
What were you doing at the beach?
Mind your own business.
Go and put some clothes on!
It's only us here.
What if your uncles saw you?
They're out. Let me breathe!
Come here!
I'll kill you!
You think it's funny?
Nick my stuff again,
I'll rip your head off!
Take it off!
He lost the third trial
and he wants to appeal again.
What do you want?
To ask you a favour, Uncle.
Yes?
It's the Super League quarter finals
on Friday.
So?
Can I come to the match with you?
Do the others want to come too?
They don't like football.
You can't be among all those men.
I asked Grandma.
She didn't say no.
- What did she say?
- That it's up to you.
That it's up to me?
She knows I've followed
all the matches,
that I know all the teams
and the players.
It'll be my last season.
What does she say about the men
who invaded the pitch on Saturday?
And all the fighting?
It's out of the question.
Shame on him.
Shame on him!
Is that how a man behaves?
Don't get all worked up.
Think of your blood pressure.
Drink some water.
Did you know about his wickedness?
Suzanne, answer me.
Did you know what your son was doing?
No.
Goal!
Following the pitch invasion
which caused the match to be suspended,
the Turkish Football Federation
has announced
that Trabzonspor's match on Friday
will be off-limits to men.
Trabzonspor will be the next team
to play to a solely female crowd.
Women only for the home match
against Galatasaray.
Women know how to support their team
and make plenty of noise...
We have to go to that match!
In your dreams!
The most devoted supporters
are already queuing for their tickets.
I was here at dawn.
- You waited for 4 hours?
- Yes.
I'm grateful to the men!
What's going on?
Coming to the match?
- Are you going?
- All the girls in the village are.
They've organised a bus to take us.
Where does it go from?
In front of the café, at 4.
We'll say we're sick.
They'll think we're in bed.
I'm in!
When did you start liking football?
I don't care about the match,
I want to get the hell out.
We can make heads
to put under the covers.
It hasn't even got any hair!
Quiet!
We can't go that way
in broad daylight.
And it's a long way down.
You're mad! They'll skin us alive.
At least something will happen.
- I'm stuck!
- What do you mean, stuck?
- It hurts!
- Push yourself.
- I can't!
- Why can't you?
- Get out!
- I can't!
Get out!
Lale's got no boobs
so she can get through.
It's not your boobs,
it's your fat bum jammed in there!
Be quiet!
Up here.
Give us a hand.
- Hurry up!
- I've got you.
Can you give me a hand?
Go on, Ece.
- Nur won't get up with her fat bum!
- Shut up, shorty!
Pancake chest!
Don't push!
Come on, Selma, hurry up!
Wait for us!
Stop!
It's all your fault!
If you hadn't been scared
of a fly...
It was a great big wasp!
You can't even walk properly!
Stop it, Lale! She fell.
What are you doing
in the middle of the road?
We missed the bus
for the match in Trabzon.
Help us catch it up.
Are you mad? No!
- Take us!
- No way!
- Please!
- No.
Stop!
Thank you so much.
Erol, the cable's too short.
Are we going to miss the match
because of a cable?
What's the matter?
What the hell?
There's light at Durmus Emmi's.
We'll drink here after.
I only found out later
what Aunt Emine did for us.
Quiet!
The fallout from our escape
wasn't what we expected.
Stand up straight.
Put your sleeves down.
Show your face.
That's good.
Your hair needs fixing.
Done it?
Ready?
We're going out for lemonade.
Don't drag your feet.
We'll sit here.
Come here a second.
Wait...
Walk over to the fountain
and back again.
What for?
Just go and walk
while I order the lemonade.
She wants us to drink here?
It's a foot fountain!
Grandma started by showing us off.
A few days later some workers came.
Press down hard on the rug.
Lale, do you hear me?
Couldn't you have talked to me
about it first?
You're not always here.
I called the workers.
They're raising the walls a bit.
Now the house
really did look like a prison.
Get this ball out of here!
Play somewhere else!
Grandma, we've got visitors.
Visitors?
Do your hair.
And go get dressed.
Sonay? Selma?
Look how you're dressed!
Put some clothes on!
Bare feet too!
Hurry, Lale,
you come and get dressed too.
Quick, quick, quick!
It's so hard to raise children nowadays.
That's true.
Here she is.
God bless her, she's beautiful!
She's one of a kind!
Sonay, will you serve the tea?
Grandma, I want a word.
Excuse me, please.
I love Ekin.
If you try to marry me off
to anyone else, I'll scream.
What?
All right!
All right, all right.
But if you want to see him again,
he'll have to ask for your hand.
Finally Selma will serve the tea.
A beautiful girl too.
You like her?
Yes, God bless her.
She's one of a kind too.
Go on, serve the tea.
Osman, the lady's son,
has just done his military service.
I'd love all my granddaughters
to be married
while I'm still alive.
What is the young man doing now?
Welcome, Osman.
Thank you.
Come and sit here.
Do you know each other?
By sight.
How are you?
Good, thanks. And you?
Very well, thank you.
Do you like her, Osman?
They're still so young and shy.
But they'll grow fond of one another.
With time, God willing.
Shall we ask the men to join us?
To settle the matter.
Right now?
Why not?
The children seem to like each other.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Go and fetch some more chairs.
I understand the children
have taken a liking to each other.
The women are agreed.
I ask, with God's blessing
and the word of the Prophet,
for your daughter's hand
for our son.
Very well. It's agreed.
It's agreed.
Osman, your ring.
Congratulations!
At least that was settled.
And while we were at it...
We could watch some matches together.
Who do you support?
The national team!
Do you drink alcohol?
No.
I ask, with God's blessing
and the word of the Prophet,
for the hand of your daughter
for our son,
with your full consent.
If God wills it,
we have nothing to say.
Two down.
Lale, I have to take
your measurements too.
- Grandma...
- Yes, my child?
Where do I put these?
In Sonay's chest.
Those are Selma's.
We'll keep these for Ece's wedding.
- Ece's wedding?
- Of course.
All About Sex
Do I really have to sleep with Osman?
Straight away?
Why are you so worried?
You're not a virgin?
Of course I am!
You can tell me.
No, honestly.
Listen...
Me and Ekin make love
but I'm still a virgin.
How?
We do it the back way.
The back way?
So I stay a virgin
and no chance I'll get pregnant.
If my mother had a boat,
she'd sail it to me
If my father had a horse,
he'd ride it to me
If my brothers and sisters
knew where I am
They'd come looking for me...
They're coming!
Come on, girls!
They're here!
Get ready.
Where are the veils?
Sonay!
- Where are you?
- I'm here.
Put your veil on, they're here.
Where's the veil?
Hurry up!
Hanife!
Put her veil on, quick!
Erol?
Are you coming?
- Welcome.
- Wait a minute!
Wait.
At a wedding,
the girl's family plays hard to get.
Sit on those chests, girls.
Don't give yourselves up too easily.
Now we're playing hard to get?
My love!
What's the matter?
If you don't want to marry Osman,
run away.
How?
Just get in a car and go.
Where?
To Istanbul, like everyone.
It's 1000 km away.
And I can't drive.
Goodbye.
Stop it, you'll make me cry.
It was the last time
we were all together.
- Did it hurt?
- Yes.
- What was it like?
- Bumpy.
Aunt Emine said it'd be hard at first,
but that I'd get used to it.
Did you bleed a lot?
Not at all.
Osman, my son, we're waiting.
Osman, are you going
to show us the sheet?
Coming!
I swear I'm a virgin.
- So where's the blood?
- I don't know.
Show us the sheet.
Just a minute!
What do I tell them?
Where is it?
Good evening.
We just married our son
and the girl didn't bleed.
Your husband doesn't seem very romantic.
I don't know him that well.
You weren't a virgin, then?
That'll stay between us.
I slept with the entire world.
Are you sure?
- About what?
- Sleeping with the entire world.
I must have slept with someone
and forgotten.
- Your hymen's right here.
- How?
It happens.
It's just the way you're made.
It'll break sometime.
With your husband, or giving birth.
But I can see it there.
It wouldn't have resisted
"the entire world"!
Why do you say things like that?
I don't know.
It's late.
I'm tired.
When I say I'm a virgin,
no one believes me.
Why won't you all leave me alone?
What's going on?
They've come to ask for Ece's hand.
Tell them,
"You want coffee? Get it yourself!"
Then slam the door and go.
Open this.
Did they bring it?
Lale, what are you doing?
I'll slap you! Get out!
Don't walk on the biscuits!
Put that salt down!
Be quiet!
Don't push me.
Ece is one of a kind.
She's so helpful.
Thank you.
Elegant...
When it was Ece's turn,
at first she went along with it.
Then she started behaving dangerously.
Another match?
Where are you going?
I'm leaving.
Going where?
Istanbul.
On foot?
Get in, I'll take you home.
No way.
You're right.
It'll only take you
about nine or ten days.
And you're in luck.
Muddy slippers
are all the rage in Istanbul.
Open up!
Maybe it was the fresh air, but it felt
like returning to the nut-house.
I used to kiss
the soles of my mum's feet.
She made a fuss about it.
I said,
"Mum, don't pull your feet away.
"That's the fragrance of paradise."
Sometimes she cried.
That's how mothers are.
Coming for a swim?
Easy! You'll end up
a fat cow at your wedding!
Some will understand, others won't.
Feminists won't.
They refuse motherhood.
One,
two, three!
I'm going to dive under the water.
Don't spit at me!
I'm down really deep.
Lale, where are you?
I'm coming to find you.
Look, I found a seashell.
Listen.
Not in front of my door!
You've put bars everywhere.
Aren't you coming back to school?
I'm going to the bank. Stay here.
What's that?
- Shall I beat those boys up?
- No.
Hang them up by their feet?
No, don't bother.
Where are you going?
Across the street.
Güven Travel
Istanbul, Ankara, Samsun
Warn me when Erol comes back.
Why are you out of the car?
Now we're here,
can we have an ice-cream?
We don't have time.
Later.
I leave you two minutes
and everybody's out.
And why did you close the windows?
Ece?
I want you!
Is that you, Ece?
It's the guy who got in the car.
I've been talking to my mates
about you all night.
Come into my arms, Ece!
I want you!
Idiot!
Did he follow us?
How does he know where we live?
I told him.
Erol, do you hear that?
There are people in the garden.
Go and see.
Are you mad?
Get the hell out of here!
Girls?
Stop!
Teach me how to drive a car.
I've tried loads of times.
I press down, the engine revs
but it doesn't move.
Show me how to do it.
I could get in big trouble
hanging about with you.
And me?
You think I should be here with you?
Turn the wheel...
Nice and gently.
Come off the brake.
Well done.
Don't let the clutch out suddenly.
Do it gradually.
Accelerate a bit.
Not all at once!
That's it.
What's this?
The horn.
Watch it!
Accelerate. More!
Very nice.
Huge progress with your shoes, at least.
Women must be chaste and pure,
know their limits,
and mustn't laugh openly in public,
or be provocative with every move.
Women must guard their chastity!
Where are the girls who blush
when you look at them?
What's this?
A bunch of these!
Can you read between the lines?
What's going on?
Leave the table.
Go away!
All right.
Finish your meal.
Seref, get the girls away from here!
Darling, we're going.
Selma, your husband's waiting too.
Lale...
Thank you.
Don't you want to leave?
Where to?
We could go to Istanbul.
Istanbul...
I want to get out of here.
If we get caught, they'll murder us.
We'll do it right.
No one will know we're gone
until we're far away.
What have you done to your hair?
It's hot.
Get up and take the girls out.
They're hot.
What were you doing?
I asked you a question!
Stop that! Stop it right now!
Not sleeping?
I was thirsty.
Yes, I am.
It's nice to see you
working hard like this.
You do it really well.
You're a woman now.
It'll soon be time for you to marry.
- What?
- You're a young woman now.
I got married when I was your age.
There were special circumstances too.
Married?
Me?
- Yes, you.
- Marry who?
There'll be plenty of suitors
once you're ready.
I didn't know my husband at all.
But I grew to love him.
It'll be the same for you.
You'll fall in love.
You fall in love easily at your age.
You're joking, right?
No.
Your son has a very good job.
Nur, sit next to Bülent.
Bülent will be in the army
for a year and a half.
When you're married,
you'll live with his parents.
They'll be
like a mother and father to you.
She won't need that.
She can use this one.
All ready.
Welcome.
What are you doing?
Open the door!
We're playing hard to get!
Girls!
- What are you doing?
- You want to marry him?
No.
Then help me move this.
Open the door!
Maybe they have a surprise for us.
They should have followed us out.
Where are you?
Everything's fine, don't worry.
Let's make ourselves comfortable.
They'll join us later.
It's all the excitement.
It happens sometimes.
They'll be out soon, don't worry.
She's been so looking forward to it.
I'm not marrying that guy!
What did you say?
You didn't have to say it like that!
Keep calm.
Come here.
Closer.
Let's have some music.
Do what I tell you.
Open the door now.
Pull yourself together.
All right, Mum.
Let's go and sit over there.
Let's sit down.
Open the door!
Come here!
Open it!
He's looking for a way in.
Nur, be reasonable.
Take this.
Leave me alone.
Come down.
I know it's a special day for you.
No way am I doing stuff like that
with that guy!
I've never been so humiliated.
The wedding's off!
Now we agree!
Be reasonable, Nur.
There's your dowry!
I have loads of salesmen.
His name's Yasin, he has long hair.
I don't have any queer salesmen.
Nur, I can see you!
I'll call the police, you bastard,
and tell them everything!
Yasin?
Yes?
It's Lale.
You have to come and help me.
We're locked in the house.
They want to kill us.
Yasin?
I'll kill you!
Shit!
They've cut the phone line.
Do they have their guns?
I've got Uncle Erol's car keys.
Show yourselves!
Where are you?
I'll get you!
- Leave them.
- Let me go!
They're getting away!
Leave it to me!
Erol, don't go.
Stay there!
Hurry up!
Quick!
If he heard me, he'll come.
Hide!
He's not going to come.
Wait!
Stop him! That's him!
Stop, Yasin!
Big sister.
Do you know this address?
Hello?
I'm looking for my teacher, Miss Dilek.
Dilek!
Lale?
Sweetheart.