(Chirping of insects)
(Chirping birds)
(Radiohead You and
Whose Army sings)
(Sigh)
- I'm glad to see you.
(Kisses)
(Sigh)
Please.
Testament of Dr. Nawal Marwan.
Opening of the will to
her two children,
Marwan Marwan and Jeanne Simon.
In accordance with the will,
regulations and rights
Nawal Marwan,
the lawyer, Jean Lebel,
executor is established.
Hmm ... I must tell you here
it is the decision
of your mother.
I was personally against
it, but she insisted.
You know ...
(Sigh)
... your mother was more
than I used to.
My late wife and me
you felt like our family, so ...
I could not refuse.
Hum!
''All my assets will be
shared between twins,
Jeanne Simon''and Marwan.
''The money will be left fairly
My furniture''and distributed according
to their desire and agreement.''
Burial''.''
(Sigh)
In''notary Jean Lebel
''Bury me without
a coffin, naked
And''without prayers,
''Faces turned towards the ground,
face first against the world.''
(Sigh)
''Peter and epitaph.
''No stone will be
placed on my grave
''And my name engraved nowhere.
''No epitaph for those who do
not keep their promises.
In''Jane and Simon
Child''is a knife in the throat.
''We do not remove easily.
''Jeanne, notaries Lebel will
hand you an envelope.
(Sigh)
''This envelope is
for your father.
Meet the''
''And hand him the envelope.
''Simon, the lawyer will
hand you an envelope.''
- I've heard enough.
- Oh ...
It's not finished, there.
- Continue.
-''Simon, the lawyer will
hand you an envelope.
''This envelope is
for your brother.
Retrieve it''and hand
him the envelope.
''When these envelopes
have been handed
''Their addressees, a
letter will be given.
''The silence is broken,
a promise kept
'', A stone may be placed
on my grave,
''And my name engraved on
the stone in the sun.''
(Sigh)
I admit it's a bit special.
- Is there stuff to sign?
- No, not today.
- OK.
Thank you, John.
Shall we?
- Wait.
(Sigh)
You know, the history
of our father.
You know, we have no brother.
Why you left off writing this?
(Sigh)
- I understand your surprise.
It's ... it's very surprising.
- Stop doing the innocent!
We know that we speak, there is
nothing surprising in this.
- It does not invent
these things, Simon
not in a will.
There's that too.
(Sigh)
Well, your mother this morning
gives us something rather ...
We'll sleep on it, then ...
We'll meet again, huh?
- I'll wait outside.
Thank you, John.
- Sit down, Simon there.
- Look, John ...
your secretary, she loved
working for you.
It has done this well in his
life, congratulations.
But your secretary, it
was also my mother.
Then his mother's job,
that's another story.
- Simon ...
- Your secretary, you can
bury the edge you want.
My mother, myself, I want to
bury it in the normal way
for once in your fucking life
make it something normal.
This is not negotiable.
(Door)
(Sigh)
(Closed Door)
- Take your time.
And come see me when Simon
will be calmed.
(Sigh)
I know it's very
unusual, but ...
(Sigh)
... Your mother was
not crazy, Jeanne.
(Chirping birds and
man's voice off)
- We have a large
family, astheure.
She spoke of a dog?
A big family, it's always a dog.
Will he have to also
find the dog?
Fucking crazy!
I'll fix that with John.
- Arrange what?
- We'll give him a
normal funeral.
We'll take care of her, then
I'll take care of you.
Where you going?
- You bury the bin as you like!
- Oh, stop!
You feel guilty because
you were not there
when she died.
You feel guilty because
you were there
when she had her accident.
We need to stop you feeling
guilty for everything!
I am not guilty of
anything, myself.
- Do you realize you realize
what he just read?
- Well, she's gone!
It's over, fucking,
you have the peace!
I have the fucking peace!
(Sigh)
I'm at peace now.
- Yes, I see it.
(Sigh)
- Mathematics as you
have known so far
have aimed to achieve a stringent
response and final
starting problems strict
and definitive.
Now, you enter an entirely
different adventure.
The subject will be
intractable problems
you will always lead
to other problems just
as intractable.
People around you
will repeatedly
it is picking what
you do not need.
You'll have no argument
to defend yourself,
for they shall be an exhausting
complexity.
Welcome to pure mathematics,
the land of loneliness.
This is my assistant,
Miss Jeanne Marwan.
- Hello!
We will start with the conjecture
of Syracuse.
- What is your intuition
telling you?
Your intuition is always right.
That's why you got potential
becoming a real mathematician.
But here, you'll need help.
Have you any family there?
Contacts?
- It's ridiculous, Niv.
- You come to learn that
A, your father is alive;
and B, you have another brother.
This is ridiculous
is that you are questioning
what is inevitable.
You need to know.
Otherwise, your spirit
will never be peace.
And no peace of mind, not
of pure mathematics.
It takes you a starting point.
- My father died during
the war, Daresh.
- That's the unknown variable
in the equation.
It never starts with the
unknown variable.
- My mother, she comes
from a village
Der called Om, Fouad.
She studied the teaching
of French
at the University of Daresh.
- If she has studied,
there is hope.
Said Haidar.
You'll go knock on the
door Said Haidar
an old friend of mine who
teaches at Daresh.
You can trust him.
(Sigh)
- What are you doing?
Mom! Okay?
- Well, Madam, is
my towel, please.
- Mom?
Mom!
What happened?
Where's Jeanne?
Mom?
(Panting)
- Is she suffers from migraines?
- No.
- Memory loss?
- Loss of balance?
- No.
- The temporary absence?
- It is absent in general.
- No, she was never absent.
(Squeal of cicadas)
(Arabic)
(Panting)
(Arabic): Wahab, come.
(Whistle)
(Panting)
(Chirping birds)
(Arabic)
- Just get out of my sister.
Son of refugees, where
will you like that?
- Nicolas, stop!
- Go back to your country.
- Wahab!
- We will give you the skin
in your camps, believe me.
- Donne.
- I want to kill her.
- It's mine to do.
You have sullied the
family honor.
- Enough!
Go home!
(Panting)
Outside.
(Sobs)
What have you done!
Thou hast afflicted us!
You have sullied the
name of our family!
Why my God you plunge
us in the dark?
(Crying)
My God, what have you done?
Why did you do that?
What will I do with you!
You want me to kill you?
- I'm pregnant, grandmother.
- My God, everything is black.
Why?
Why hast thou done this?
Do I have to kill you?
What will I do with you?
(Crying Nawal)
(Cris Nawal)
(Uproar off)
(Chirping of insects
and birds chirping)
Mange.
Eat if you want your
child is safe.
Listen to me.
There's nothing here for you.
I'll help after birth.
I want you to go from here.
You'll go to the city at
your uncle Charbel.
There, you'll go to school.
To learn to read, think.
Out of this misery.
Promise me you'll help etje.
Promise me you'll go to school.
(Sniff)
- I promise you, grandmother.
I promise.
(Sigh)
(Squeal of cicadas)
(Sing)
(Chirping birds)
(Breath jerky)
(Sigh)
(Wail)
(Runoff)
(Arabic)
(Cry Baby)
(Sing)
(Crying)
- Shh.
(Sing)
(Repetition of crying)
Shh.
(Sigh)
Look carefully at your mother.
You'll recognize it.
- I'll find you one day.
I promise you my heart.
(Sobs)
- Be careful.
- Do not worry.
(Chirping birds)
(Call to prayer in the distance)
(Chirping of insects)
- Come on, it is time
for you to go.
I feel that something terrible
is coming ...
One day I'll find you, my son.
(Horns and sirens
in the distance)
(Arabic)
(Panting)
(Klaxons)
- I received the message
from my friend Niv Cohen
but I can not help you
because at the time,
I taught
history of mathematics
in Paris XI.
Specifically, the period
where Euler had
succeeded, blind,
to give first
formal mathematical resolution
the problem of seven bridges
of Konigsberg, yes.
It would have defied
the Court Diderot
with running like this:
Gentlemen ...''
''I-ft plus
''Equals zero.
''So, God exists!''
- Niv, Niv, Niv ...
Hello! Do you speak French?
- Yes, of course!
Can I help you?
- Uh, yes, I looking for someone
who would have known this woman.
She studied here there
are maybe 35 years.
(Laughter)
- Are you kidding me?
I was not even born.
Well, you're in the wrong
place, you'll ...
- I do not care about you.
I'm sure you know someone
who can help me.
I just too far.
Please.
Her name is Nawal Marwan.
You are nice.
- I'm not nice, I want
to get rid of you.
(Arabic): Najat is me.
You have time to waste?
- That tells me something.
It may have worked in the
student newspaper.
It's been a long time.
People who left have
changed identity.
It is striking nonetheless.
(Arabic)
Your mother was photographed
in Kfar Ryat.
Look here.
This is a sign of Kfar Ryat.
It is a prison in the south.
You do not know Kfar Ryat?
- No.
- You're definitely
not here you.
You know not the South.
(Clicking typewriter)
(Arabic): If the in
ernational community
does not now
Refugees
in overcrowded camps
in the border ...
- It has arrived.
- OK.
We the students, we oppose
the Nationalist Party
trying to evict refugees
outside the borders.
- The National Party supports
militias of the Christian right,
who make open threats
to refugees.
- In the South, refugees
are now armed.
Et .. and they support
of much of the Muslim population
of the country.
- But you ...
but you're Christian.
- We, we are for peace.
Religion has nothing
to do with it.
(Humming)
(Cree)
- Nawal!
(Arabic): Put the radio!
They come to close
the University!
The Nationalists have
closed the campus!
- Nawal back.
Stay here.
- Uncle Charbel, the Nationalists
are closing the campus!
- There will be clashes.
Stay with me.
(A woman speaks Arabic
on the radio)
(Shots)
(Shouts off)
- There is shooting outside ...
- The table, girls!
- Mom, they attack
the university!
- It's not a reason not to eat!
- Aiou?
(Arabic)
Christian villages were attacked
in the South this morning.
- May God protect us!
- That's why they closed
the university.
In short time, it will
explode here as well.
We'll go to the mountain
until it calms down.
- For how long?
- We start tomorrow.
The rest of the family
is already there.
- And the school?
- Anyway, the school will close.
God alone saitjusqu' when.
- And lejournal?
- Do not be afraid.
Lejournal can survive without
us for a while.
- But ideas survive if someone
is there to defend them!
- Exactly, Rafqa.
Exactly.
(Barking)
- There are only two orphanages
in the region.
I will join you soon.
- You will not go there now!
Had promised to Grandma
to finish your studies.
- You heard your father.
It's going to explode across the country
if they attack the camps.
The study is finished.
(Sigh)
I think of him every day.
That's my child.
(Sigh)
I want to find him alive.
(Arabic)
(Horn)
(Arabic): I'm going to fetch
water from Shadia.
- Hurry, Nawal.
(Whistle)
(Chirping birds)
(Arabic)
- Your name?
- Nawal.
- Nawal what?
- Nawal Marwan.
- Where are you?
- South.
- Why?
- To meet my husband.
(Uproar)
(Chirping of insects)
(Chirping birds)
Wahab.
(Cries of children)
(Arabic)
You still have only daughters?
- The boys are in Kfar
Kout past three years.
You should go with us.
Kfar Kout was attacked
yesterday.
(Panting)
(Grinding metal)
(Buzzing Fly)
- Looking for the orphanage.
You know where is it?
- There.
- Children?
Where are the children?
- Should speak to those
who were there.
Muslim villagers fled
to the camp Deressa.
They fear reprisals will come.
Children may be with them.
Chamseddine and his men killed all the
Christians to avenge the refugees.
Children are perhaps Deressa.
(Sobs)
(Chirping birds)
- You go to camp Deressa?
(Arabic)
(Sigh)
(Cree)
(Buzzing Fly)
(Kiss)
(Sobs)
(Panting)
(Arabic)
(Sniffles and groans)
(Clap sheet)
(Panting)
(Sobs)
I am a Christian.
My daughter! My daughter!
(Cree girl)
- Mom!
(Sobs)
(Muffled Shots)
(Chirps)
(Radiohead You and
Whose Army sings)
(Chirping birds)
- Hi, Simon, that's me!
I am in the village of Mama,
it then I wish you were here.
Listen.
(Chirping of insects)
(Arabic)
Oh, sorry, I do not understand.
(Arabic): I told you to do
plusjamais come here!
(Laughter)
- Hello!
Suha?
- Ahmed love you!
Ahmed loves you!
- I told you not to say that!
- Hello.
Can I help you?
Does anyone speak French
or English?
- Where's Sami?
- Marhaba!
- (In chorus): Marhaba!
- Hello!
(Arabic)
Uh, Jeanne.
Jeanne.
(Arabic)
Uh ...
(Laughter)
(Arabic): Thank you.
- You speak French?
- Yes, hello!
- Hello.
My name is Samia.
- Me, Marwan is Jeanne.
Thank you for helping me.
- Marwan?
There are many Marwan here.
- Really?
Ben, me, I'm from Canada.
I'm looking Suha.
- Suha, is she.
It is my great-grandmother.
- Oh! Marhaba!
- Marhaba.
(Arabic)
- It's the corner shop who
told me to come see you.
(Arabic)
I am looking for my father.
His name is Wahab.
(Arabic)
Uh ...
My mother's name
is Nawal Marwan.
(Arabic)
She was born here.
- We do not know.
- But if known.
(Shouts in Arabic)
- Her mother is a disgrace.
(Arabic)
- Marwan's family was
struck with shame.
The war came.
- Uh, I'm looking Wahab.
(Arabic)
- She does not know Wahab.
- I can not help you.
Sorry, I'm tired.
(Arabic)
- If you're the girl
Nawal Marwan,
you're not welcome here.
Go home.
(Arabic): Looking
for your father,
but you do not know
who is your mother.
(Explosions in the distance)
(Shots)
(Blast Off)
(Explosions and gunfire)
(A woman sings in
foreign language)
- I arrived at the end of the massacre
in the refugee camp of Deressa.
Everything was burning.
I looked for my son amid
waves of blood.
I do not want this console
quej'ai seen and heard.
- You say to be against
our enemy.
It does not make you our friend.
Chamseddine Why would
he trust you?
- The father of my son was
a refugee from Deressa.
My son has been swallowed
by the war.
I have nothing to lose.
My hatred is great toward
the Nationalists.
- This is not what you wrote
in the journal Charbel.
- My uncle thought Charbel encourage
peace with words and books.
I believed.
Life has taught me
something else.
- What do you do now?
- Teach to the enemy what
life has taught me.
(Arabic)
(Chirping birds)
(Sigh)
- Okay. Very good.
You've just forgotten it. There.
(Twitter and bird chirps)
(Arabic): So the French?
- I ... I am much better, Dad.
- They say''a lot''or''best''
but never both at the same
time, my darling.
(Arabic): I want my son speaks
several languages.
I want him to understand the other
without an intermediary.
(Phone)
- How are you, Nawal?
It Nouchine.
- Good evening, Nouchine.
How's your mother?
- My mother is going very well.
10 o'clock tomorrow.
- Tomorrow.
(Sigh)
Marhaba.
(Chirping birds)
- Hello, beautiful.
- Good morning.
- Then you go out
with nousjeudi?
- No.
- Friday?
- Saturday?
- No.
- We are patient, we!
- Me too.
(Laughter guards)
(Sigh)
Never forget:
''Always''is always''S''.
(Arabic)
(Panting)
(Shouts in Arabic)
- Bitch.
(Breath jerky)
(Blast Off)
(Panting)
- The prison of Kfar
Ryat was sentenced
several reports by Amnesty
International.
Here is the women's section.
The cells are larger.
Some prisoners remained
there until 15.
- It has existed since when?
- At the time of the killings.
Just after the war began.
They have 600 political
prisoners jailed.
You can come in, eh?
I'll take a picture.
- You know this woman?
- No.
- It was taken here.
- I do not know.
It's really long, you know?
Me ...
- Maybe you know someone
who worked here.
(Chirping of insects)
(Arabic)
(Chirping birds)
(Arabic): Hello.
- Hello.
- Looking Harrsa Fahim.
- I am a school janitor.
- Yes, but before?
- Before, hum!
That was before I was
school janitor.
It's been a long time I'm
caretaker of the school.
- You know this woman?
She was in Kfar Ryat.
- I am a school janitor.
Bess! That's it.
(Deep breath)
- I am looking for someone
who knew her.
Someone who could
tell me about it.
This is my mother.
- This is the woman who sings.
Number 72.
It was she who murdered
militia leader
the Christian Right.
They made him pay dearly.
Very, very expensive.
Fifteen years.
(Arabic)
It was called the
Woman who sings
because she sings all the time.
- Han, you are sure it is?
- I spent 13 years
at the monitor.
(Arabic)
You've already spent 13 years
overseeing someone, you?
(Sigh)
They did everything
to make it bend.
In the end, it was
still standing,
She looked ...
Ah! Never seen it.
She never bent.
It was infuriating.
(Inspiration)
(Arabic)
And he sent Abu Tarek.
- Who's that?
(Chirping birds)
- Tarek Abou ...
(Sigh)
You know, sometimes it
is better perhaps
do not know everything.
- Sir, I live with anyway.
Continue.
- Tarek Abou ...
(Sigh)
Abu Tarek was a specialist
in torture.
He raped her repeatedly
to break it before it emerges,
for she stops singing.
For strength, she
became pregnant.
It was like that.
Never forget.
72 pregnant by Abu Tarek.
They waited ...
she gives birth in prison
then they let her go.
(Sigh)
- The child?
Did you see the child?
- There was a doctor
who sometimes came.
I think it's crazy.
Others say he has a restaurant
in Tel Aviv ...
(Arabic)
That's bullshit.
He went mad when he died.
The nurse her, I know.
She lives in Daresh.
- At Daresh.
Listen, Simon, Calisse!
I Calisse, there, shut up, OK?
Shut your mouth!
Mom, she was in prison.
Simon, mom, she ...
(Sobs)
Mom, she was raped.
Our brother, she was in prison.
I need you there.
(Voice of a man who
spoke in Arabic)
(Chirping birds)
(Panting)
(Roars of distant woman)
(Sing)
(Screams)
(Arab Song)
(Sings Radiohead Like
Spinning Plates)
- It, Simon, it contracts
the notary Amyotte
from 1868 to 1892.
His son took over, Edward,
until 1925.
All contracts written by hand.
My grandfather, Charles,
my father, Henry.
And me.
Yeah, well, it stops there
because as you know,
I am the last of the Lebel.
I'll show you the
will of a man ...
(Sigh)
... which took several lives.
His heirs have discovered
he had three wives
at the same time.
One here, one in Miami,
and another in Honduras,
where he did business.
There, there ...
you've lost three children
in the file there.
There are eight.
That is sport, my man.
Look. Hum!
Death is never the
end of a story.
There are still traces.
If you want to find
your brother,
he will have to go back into
the past of your mother.
- John, I'll fetch my
sister, that's all.
- I mind that.
Two, three small business
to take care,
then it will take no time.
Well, prepare your business
we should go in ...
My passport ...
-''We''?
Do not you worry that you already
done enough like this?
- Exactly, that's not the
time to let you down.
Am a man of you, Simon.
I know that you need me.
- We'll get it, then come back.
- Promised.
Then, promise, Mr. Marwan,
a notary is on the order
of the sacred.
(Breathing hard)
(Inaudible)
(Rail)
(Singing in Arabic)
(Arabic): Sing now.
(Panting)
(Sobs)
(Cree)
(Arabic)
(Sobs)
(Groans)
(Shout)
- Gently, gently.
He leaves.
We see the head.
Grows.
Go, girl.
(Cree and effort)
(Sigh)
The first came out.
(Groans)
(Wail)
Rest now ...
I'm proud of you.
Get ready for the second.
(Chirps)
(Runoff)
Stop.
Donne.
- What are you doing?
- Thou asjets in the
river as usual.
- It's dangerous.
- No.
You've done your duty.:
Thou asjets in river.
I want to take care of them.
These are the children of
the woman who sings.
- Oh, this country is a war
zone to another, eh!
It's not complicated.
If the notary had existed
at the time of Noah,
we would not be there.
We need only find the
original contracts.
That's up to you, that's up to you.
And a right of passage there.
And we do talk more.
Everyone would be happy.
- The Notary has existed
only 1000 years, Simon.
- That's the problem.
It should have been
there at first.
- Thank you again for your
help, Me Maddadi.
- The pleasure is all
mine, my dear fellow.
I search result
that you have requested
via email.
Simon is my towel on
the seat beside you.
Could you give it to
me Lebel, please?
- You are very nice, but the
lag and everything ...
I think I'll wait until later.
- But I'll summarize.
For the father, it is
rather difficult
because I can not find
the death certificate.
For Brother ...
- Excuse me, but what
are we talking here?
- I asked for help, Simon.
Maddadi me kindly give us a hand
to speed things up.
- I told you, John,
we came for Jeanne.
- Your sister is the person
in your family
easiest to find.
(Deep breath)
- I'm so glad you're here.
- Me too.
(Sigh)
- OK, that's the name
of the nurse
which helped to give birth
mother in prison.
We can go today.
- Jeanne, that's enough.
- Here, you shut up,
then you follow me.
It's your job to find our
brother is not mine!
Then, if you do not
for her or for you,
ben crunches, do it for me!
It is at the American hospital.
(Door)
I'm glad you're here, John.
- Me too, my owl, too.
- If she sleeps, he must return.
Ms. Maika?
(Arabic)
- ...
Lebel, Joan Marwan,
Marwan Simon.
- Bonjour, Madame!
Thank you for having us.
We seek someone you know.
Nawal Marwan you know?
(Arabic)
(Panting)
You worked in the prison
of Kfar Ryat as a nurse?
(Arabic)
(Sobs)
- She says she knows your mom.
- You helped our mother to
give birth in prison?
(Arabic)
- Yes.
- Madame, the child seeks Nawal
Marwan was in prison.
Can you help us?
(Arabic)
- She worked in the prison
of Kfar Ryat.
She accompanied her
during childbirth.
She gathered the children.
Then she was given back
to the woman who sings
when leaving prison.
Nawal Marwan gave
birth to twins.
Hush, hush, hush.
(Deep breath)
(Panting)
(Chirping birds)
(Arabic)
(Panting)
(Gunshot)
(Arabic)
(Call to prayer)
(Klaxons)
- You really know the
woman who sings?
You do not know what
it means to me.
- Nawal Marwan worked for me
for 18 years as secretary.
My wife and I, we had
taken a liking
for herself and her children.
But I confess that I find
I knew it not really the end.
(Sigh)
Ready?
- Ready.
- Hmm ...
I Maddadi conducted research
at my request
to find traces of your brother
and your father.
- For the father, Abu Tarek,
I still have not found
a death certificate.
The country has a lot missing.
It may be moved abroad.
That's what happened with
this kind of characters.
They are dead or gone.
You have to see.
- Maybe it's better that way.
- For the brother ...
your client, Ms. Nawal Marwan,
comes from the village
of Der Om.
She handed the child to a midwife
who is named Elham
who herself has returned to
the orphanage in Kfar Kout
in May 1970.
The main work was to
trace the records.
Many documents have been
lost in the war.
But I found the records
which were recovered and given
by the Sisters of Charity
at the National Archives.
In May 1970, the midwife
Der Om, Elham
file a male child for adoption.
This is the only boy in the
orphanage filed this month.
Look.
It was registered under
the name Nihad.
Dates match.
That's him.
- Ha! It's your brother! Nihad.
(Sigh)
- Orphanage Kfar Kout,
Nihad May.
It is his name for the records.
Nihad month of May.
It gave a temporary name
with the month of arrival.
There was no adoption
during this period.
It was the beginning of the war.
The orphanage was destroyed
four years later.
We must ask that destroyed
the orphanage in Kfar Kout
to know what happened
with the children.
Between you and me, with what
happened in the region ...
there is not much hope.
- It is probably also dead.
- I'm not saying he is dead.
I say we lost track of him.
- They are both dead.
We open the envelopes,
then that's it.
- That I will not, Simon.
This kind of thing is sacred.
(Me Maddadi): This commit rape.
- Luckily, I have a history.
Excuse me.
- We still worth exploring.
But it is a little radical.
Warlord
which demolished the orphanage
at that time still alive.
And he may know what happened
Nihad these children belonged.
- It's been an eternity.
- You must understand
that this period is a
series of reprisals
which fit one another in
an inexorable logic,
as additions.
A warlord is exactly
the type of man who
has a long memory.
And he remembers it, believe me.
Wallat Chamseddine,
is his name.
- It is found where it?
- We find it. He finds you.
But we can try something.
Do you like tea, Mr. Marwan?
- It's your turn.
(Klaxons off)
(Me Maddadi): You will go
in the refugee camp Deressa.
You will come to tea
anywhere in the camp
with the person you invite.
And you say you are the son
of the woman who sings
and are looking Nihad May.
You can not go there alone.
I'll find someone
to accompany you.
- Welcome to Deressa.
(Chirping birds and hubbub)
(Arabic)
- Ha!
Ha! You know where you
are going, Simon?
- I know.
(Arabic)
(Kisses)
(Arabic): How are you?
- Name of God, you've grown!
- I finished my e
gineering studies.
I do not find work, alorsje
am the taxi driver.
- What brings you here?
- I am with foreign visitors, who
asked me to bring them here.
- Welcome, come.
- No, thank you, you're
in a hurry.
- Please, come.
- He invites us to tea.
- Oh, good!
(Drone of aircraft)
(Arabic)
- Uh, I wonder why you
come to Deressa.
- I am looking for someone
named Nihad May.
(Arabic)
- He does not know Nihad May.
He asks me what are your names.
- My mother comes from the village
of Der Om, in the South.
(Arabic)
My mother is the
woman who sings.
Yes, that's fine. Done.
Wait what?
- Sarwan Marwan?
- Yes.
- We are here to offer help.
You will be back in an hour.
- I can tell my sister?
- No, you come back in
an hour, I promise.
- I put a shirt, a second.
- He will call.
- It's going to go.
- Ever!
Do not worry, you can follow.
Ah, I told you: the South,
a spark and it exploded.
Oh, okay.
(Alarm)
(Chirping birds)
(Sigh)
(Arabic): You have greatly helped
us, we'll help our turn.
You'll leave the country.
It'll be easier.
We will find you a
house and a job.
I want your life to be better.
We have many contacts
in America.
You gotta go with your children.
I know they are alive.
Take them with you.
Children will help
you, you'll see.
(Swallowing)
- You can not ask me.
- Your children are our
children, Nawal.
Your family is our family.
Trust me.
I'll help you.
I'm here for you and
your children.
(Slam latch)
Hello, Sarwan.
Excuse my introduction, but
it is for your protection.
They call me Wallat Chamseddine.
Tell me, what can I do to
help, Sarwan Marwan?
- You knew my mother.
- Let it worked for me.
What can I do to help?
- I am looking for a
man named Nihad May.
- Why you are looking Nihad May?
- It's my brother.
My mother asked me to find him.
- And how can you say
Nihad May is the son
of Nawal Marwan?
- My brother has been
placed for adoption
orphanage in Kfar Kout.
We found the registry with
the original link.
The dates ... Everything fits.
Nihad May is my brother.
(Sigh)
(Inaudible)
- Me and my friends, we attacked
Christian village Kfar Kout ...
In response to attacks
that our brothers, refugees
were victims.
There was an orphanage
in Kfar Kout.
I saved the children.
I took them with us.
And Nihad was among them.
We have trained and prepared
for they are fighting
alongside us.
Nihad, he had a gift.
He was at hand.
And soon it became a
formidable fencer.
But he wanted to
find her mother.
He has sought for months.
Nihad, I do not know what
he saw or heard.
He became ...
a crazy war.
He came to see me, he
wanted to be a martyr
so that his mother should see
her picture everywhere
on the walls of the country.
But I refused.
He went back to Daresh.
He became a maverick,
the most dangerous region.
A real machine.
He pulls on everyone.
And then there was the
enemy invasion.
And one morning ...
They captured Nihad.
He killed seven gunmen.
They have not killed.
They formed
and sent to the prison
of Kfar Ryat.
- It has been in prison?
- Yes.
As executioner.
(Sigh)
- He worked with my father?
- No, it did not work
with Abu Tarek, your father.
(Uproar distant)
(Hits at the door)
- Are you okay?
- One plus one ...
that makes two.
- What?
- One plus one makes two.
It can not make one.
- Hey, you have a fever.
- Jeanne?
One plus one, does it make one?
(Inspiration)
(Sobs)
- There are empty seats, there.
- Oh, go ahead if you want.
(Panting)
(Men who speak in Arabic)
- Is it can help you, ma'am?
- Excuse me.
(Sobs)
(W. Chamseddine): By
becoming a hangman
your brother has changed
its name.
He became Abu Tarek.
Nihad Abu Tarek is from May.
We know now that he
lives in Canada
under a new identity.
Nihad Harmanni.
(Horn)
- Mr. Harmanni?
- Yes?
(Shout gull)
- It's for you.
(Chirping birds)
(Horn)
(Voice of Nawal): I am
writing trembling.
I recognized you.
You have not acknowledged.
It's a wonderful miracle.
I'm your number 72.
This letter will be delivered
by our children.
You will not recognize them
because they are beautiful,
but they know who you are.
(Chirping birds)
Through them, I want to tell you
you're still alive.
But soon, you'll be quiet.
I know.
Because silence is
all to the truth.
Signed.: The whore 72.
I spoke to the son.
I do not talk to
the executioner.
Whatever happens, I will
always love you.
That's the promise I made you
at your birth, my son.
Whatever happens, I will
always love you.
I've searched my whole life.
I found you.
You, you could not recognize me.
You have your tattoo
on his right heel.
I've seen.
I recognized you.
(Panting)
Etje found you beautiful.
I'll blow all the sweetness
of the world, my love.
Console yourself because nothing
is more beautiful
than being together.
You were born of love.
Your brother and your sister
are also born of love.
Nothing is more beautiful
than to be together.
Your mother, Nawal Marwan ...
prisoner number 72.
(Panting)
(Me Lebel):''When these envelopes
have been handed
''To the addressee,
''A letter will be given.
''The silence is broken,
''A promise kept,
'', A stone may be placed
on my grave,
''And my name engraved on
the stone in the sun.''
(Sigh)
(Voice of Nawal): My love ...
Where does your story?
In your birth?
Then she starts in horror.
(Sigh)
At the birth of your father?
Then she begins a
great love story.
I say that your story
begins with a promise
that break the thread of anger.
Thanks to you, today I finally
managed to keep it.
The wire is broken.
Etje can finally take
the time to rock ...
(Sobs)
you sing softly a lullaby
to comfort you.
Nothing is more beautiful
than to be together.
I love you.
Your mother, Nawal.
(Sniffle)
(Sigh)
(Chirping birds)
(Woman sings)
(Chirping of insects)
DVD subtitle: CNST, Montreal