Subrip
CHRISOSFP
Robin Williger.
He is a 1 5-year-old freshman
from Raci ne, Wisconsin.
He enjoys studying history.
He's on the debate team.
Robin's future looked
very, very bright,
but recently he was
diagnosed with cancer,
a very tough kind of cancer.
Robin tells me he has
quit smoking, though,
and he no longer thinks
that cigarettes are cool.
( applause )
Whoo!.
And our final guest today
is Nick Naylor.
Mr. Naylor is the vice president
ofthe Academy ofTobacco Studies.
Now, they are the tobacco
industry's main lobby
in Washington, D.C.
and Mr. Naylor is
their chiefspokesman.
( audience murmuring )
( booing, hissing )
NICK:
Fewpeople on this planet know
what it is to be truly despised.
Can you blame them?
I earn a living
fronting an organization
that kills 1,200 human beings a day.
1,200 people.
We 're talking
two jumbo jet plane loads
ofmen, women and children.
I mean, there 's Attila,
Genghis,
and me,
Nick Naylor,
the face ofcigarettes...
the Colonel Sanders ofnicotine.
This is where I work,
the Academy of Tobacco Studies.
It was established
by seven gentlemen
you may recognize from C-SPAN.
These guys realized quick
ifthey were going to claim
that cigarettes were not addictive,
they better have proof.
This is the man they rely on,
Erhardt Von Grupten Mundt.
They found him in Germany.
I won 't go into the details.
He 's been testing the link
between nicotine
and lung cancer
for 30 years and hasn 't found
any conclusive results.
The man 's a genius.
He could disprove gravity.
Then we 've got our sharks.
We draft them out
oflvy League law schools
and give them time-shares
and sports cars.
It's just like
a John Grisham novel-
you know, without all the espionage.
Most importantly,
we 've got spin control.
That's where I come in.
I get paid to talk.
I don 't have an MD or law degree.
( shutter clicking )
( machine gun firing )
I have a bachelor's in
kicking ass and taking names.
You know that guy
who can pick up any girl?
I'm him
on crack.
( cheers, applause )
This is obviously a heated issue
and we do have a lot
that we want to cover today.
Nick, do you have a question?.
Joan,
how on earth would
Big Tobacco profit
off ofthe loss ofthis young man?.
Now, I hate to think
in such callous terms,
but, ifanything,
we'd be losing a customer.
It's not only our hope,
it's in our best interest
to keep Robin alive and smoking.
- That's ludicrous.
- Let me tell you something,
Joan, and please,
let me share something
with the fine, concerned
people in the audience today.
The Ron Goodes ofthis world...
want the Robin Willigers to die.
- What?.
- NAYLOR: You know why?.
So that their budgets will go up.
This is nothing less than
trafficking in human misery,
and you, sir, ought
to be ashamed ofyourself.
I ought to be ashamed of myself?.
As a matter offact,
we're about to launch...
a $50 million campaign
aimed at persuading kids
not to smoke.
Because I think
that we can all agree
that there is nothing
more important
than America's children.
LUNDEN: All right, now,
that's something that
we're going towant
to know more about.
but I have to take a short break.
Hang on, a lot more coming.
( applause )
$50 million??!. Areyou
out ofyour fucking mind??!.
Everyone has a boss.
BRjust happens
to be mine.
He came from the vending
machine world.
This made him tough.
The name BR came
from his tour in Vietnam.
The people who know
its meaning are all dead.
The deal was five m i I l ion!
$ 5 m i I l ion wi I l get you
a couple of subway posters.
I t's not going to impress anyone.
That's the idea, Nick.
You'll be thanking me soon.
This'll probably getyou great press.
I gotta call the captain
and see ifthis is gonna fly.
Getyour ass back to D.C.
( applause nearby)
( door opening )
Thankyou so much for coming.
Mr. Naylor?.
It's your turn.
Ah.
Joey is such a bright young man.
We all look forward
to his coming out
ofhis shell a little.
He's a bit shy.
Yeah, he gets that from his mother.
( whisper): Hey,Joey.
Please don't ruin my childhood.
Come on,Joey. Trust me.
How many ofyou want to be
lawyers when you grow up?.
Right.
How about...
movie stars?.
( laughing )
How about lobbyists?.
What's that?.
It's kind oflike being a movie star.
It's what I do.
I talk for a living.
What doyou talk about?.
I speak on behalf of cigarettes.
My mom used to smoke.
She says that cigarettes kill.
Really?. Now, is your mommy a doctor?.
No.
A scientific researcher of some kind?.
Well, she doesn't exactly sound
Iike a credible expert,
now, does she?.
Don't feel bad.
It's okay to listen toyour mom.
I mean, it's good to listen
toyour parents...Joey.
All I'm suggesting
is that there will always
be people trying to tell you
what to do and what to think.
There probably already are
people doing that.
Am I right?.
KI DS: Yes.
I'm here to say
that when someone tries to act
like some sort of an expert,
you can respond, "Who says??"
So, cigarettes are good foryou?.
- No!
- No, that's not...
That's not what I'm getting at.
My point is that you have
to think foryourself.
You have to challenge authority.
Ifyour parents told you
that chocolate was dangerous,
would you just take theirword for it?.
KI DS: No.
Exactly.
So perhaps instead of acting
like sheep
when it comes to cigarettes,
you should find out foryourself.
Okay, then.
Thankyou, Mr. Naylor,
forjoining us.
( light applause )
NICK:
Everyweek we meet here at Bert's.
Together, we represent
the chiefspokespeople
for the tobacco, alcohol and
firearms industries.
We call ourselves the MD Squad.
Al I ri ght.
M--D, Merchants ofDeath.
So, my day's rui ned.
Why?.
Dateline's doi ng a segment
on fetal alcohol syndrome.
Thank you.
Polly works
for the Moderation Council.
A casual drinker
by the age of 14,
Polly quickly developed
a tolerance usually reserved
for lrish dockworkers.
In our world, she 's the woman
that got the pope
to endorse red wine.
We' re gonna get creamed.
Any ideas?.
I don't know.
Deformed kids are tough.
I 'm lucky my product only makes
them bald before it kills them.
You could hug the kids.
They're not going
to let me hug the kids.
Who's doing the segment,
Donaldson or Sawyer?.
Sawyer, probably.
You're fucked.
Why?.
Cause she's gonna hug them.
Look, ifyou see her going in
for a hug,
maybe just box her out,
get in there before she does.
NICK:
BobbyJayworks forSAFETY,
- ( ricochet )
- the Societyforthe Advancement ofFirearms
and Effective Training for Youth.
You want me to smile?.
After watching the footage
ofthe Kent State shootings,
BobbyJay, then 1 7, signed up
for the National Guard
so he, too, could shoot
college students.
But the National Guard
recruiter was out to lunch,
so BobbyJay ended up
shooting Panamanians instead,
which was almost as good
as college students.
( gunshot )
nly they shoot back.
You know, you can beat
a Breathalyzer
- by sucki ng on activated charcoal tablets?.
- Really?.
Maybe we should change
our campaign to
"IfYou Must Drink and Drive,
Suck Charcoal."
Yeah, but don't the police wonder
whyyou're sucking on charcoal?.
There's no law against charcoal.
- Yet.
Dad, why is the American
government the best government?.
Because of our
endless appeals system.
Joe, you're not writing down
what I just said areyou?.
Mm-hmm.
Joey, stop for a second.
What is the subject ofyour essay?.
Why is American government
the best government in the world.
Your teacher crafted that question?.
Yeah. Why?.
Well... I'll look past
the obvious problems
in syntax for a moment,
and I'll focus more on the core
ofthe question.
I mean, "A,"
does America have
the best government in the world?.
And "B," what constitutes
a "best government"?.
Is it crime, is it poverty, literacy?.
Hmm?.
And America- definitely not best.
Perhaps not even better than most.
We do have a very
entertaining government...
Dad.
I'm sorry.
Are you familiarwith the term "B.S."?.
Bullshit.
Yes, exactly.
B.S., if I may, is what
questions like the one
your teacher posed are made for.
Because even if America
had the best government,
there'd be no way to prove it.
And how many pages are you writing?.
Two pages.
Two pages...
Definitely not in two pages.
So what am I supposed to write?.
You can write whateveryou want.
Okay.
Write about...
write about America's
amazing ability
to make profit by breaking down
trading tariffs
and bringing American jobs
to Third World countries.
Or how good we are
at executing felons.
They're all correct answers.
I can do that?.
See,Joey, that's the beauty
of argument.
'Cause ifyou argue correctly,
you're neverwrong.
Dad, if I finish
this essaywithin an hour,
can we stay up all night?.
That's a negotiation,
not an argument.
( over TV):
Well, Conway, seeyou made it.
Yeah, I guess that little
voice was wrong.
I feel better.
I feel a lot better, too.
As a matter offact, I never
felt so good in my life.
How about a cigarette?.
( gunshot )
( dramatic music playing )
( gunfire )
MAN 1 : Is he...?.
MAN 2: Yeah.
Hey.
Nick, you still own a watch, don't you?.
J ill, I can't help feeling
Joey's getting the wrong idea
about his dad.
It would be great ifl could spend
a little more timewith him,
you know?.
To give him a fair
and balanced perspective.
Nick, you had plenty
oftime forthat.
Nowyou're his weekend guardian.
Besides, he has Brad.
He still needs his father.
Nick.
You have a second?.
Sure, Brad.
Nick, yourjob
and everything aside,
I hopeyou understand
that secondhand smoke's
a real killer.
What areyou talking about?.
I just hopeyou're providing
a smoke-free environment
forJoey, that's all I'm saying.
Brad, I'm his father.
You're the guy fucking his mom.
That was unnecessary.
Thankyou all.
Thankyou all for coming.
Tobacco is winning thewar.
Thewar against our children.
They like to use cartoons
and symbols to hook our kids.
Well, nowwe have
a symbol of our own.
Doctor.
It is my hope that
within theyear
every cigarette package
sold in America
will carry this symbol.
Perhaps then, cigarettes
will finally be labeled
appropriately as poison.
I will be holding
a congressional hearing
to discuss the inclusion
ofthe skull and crossbones
in the next two weeks.
As usual, I extend
an open invitation
to big tobacco.
Perhaps this time theywill
grace us with their presence.
And their answers.
Thankyou very much.
( reporters clamoring )
People, what is going on out there?.
I look down this table,
all I see are white flags.
Our numbers are down
all across the board.
Teen smoking-
our bread and butter,
is falling like a shit from heaven.
We don't sell TicTacs,
for Christ's sake.
We sell cigarettes.
And they're cool and available
and addictive.
The job is almost done for us.
This environmentalist
is challenging us.
We have to have an answer.
I'm asking you,
when this cocksucker puts
Captain Hook on our products,
what the fuck are we going to do?.
- BR.
- Yeah, Nick.
Ifl may.
In 1 91 0,
the U.S. was producing
ten billion cigarettes a year.
By 1 930,
we were up to 1 23 billion.
What happened in between?.
Three things.
Aworld war,
dieting... and movies.
Movies?.
1 927- talking pictures are born.
Suddenly, directors need to give
their actors
something to do
while they're talking.
Cary Grant, Carole Lombard
are lighting up.
Bette Davis- a chimney.
And Bogart-
remember the first picture
with him and Lauren Bacall?.
Well, yea... not specifically.
Oh, she sort
of shimmies in
through the doorway,
1 9 years old.
Pure sex.
She says,
"Anyone got a match??"
And Bogie throws
the matches at her...
and she catches them.
Greatest romance ofthe century.
How'd it start?.
Lighting a cigarette.
These days when someone
smokes in the movies,
they're either a psychopath
or a European.
The message Hollywood
needs to send out
is smoking is cool.
We need the cast of Willand Grace
smoking in their living room.
Forrest Gump puffing away
between his box of chocolates.
Hugh Grant earning back
the love ofJulia Roberts
by buying her favorite brand-
herVirginia Slims.
Most ofthe actors smoke already.
Ifthey start doing it on-screen,
we can put the sex
back into cigarettes.
Well, it's a thought.
I was hoping for something
a little more inspiring,
but at leastyou're thinking.
Rest ofyou people,
slam yourfucking brains
againstyour desks
until something useful comes out.
Thatwas awesome.
Thankyou.
Nick, you've been summoned.
Captain wants to seeyou.
He saw the Joan show.
What'd he think?.
Getyour ass on the next flight
to Winston-Salem.
Mostpeople have this image
in theirheads
oftobacco executives
jet-setting around the world
on private planes,
eating foie gras
as they count their money.
Not me.
I like to ride with the people.
Knowyour clients.
My people cram themselves
into a tiny seat,
pop a Xanax and dream
ofthe moment
they can stufftheir face
with fresh tobacco.
Ifl can convince just one of
these kids to pick up smoking,
I've paid for my flight- round-trip.
The Captain is the last great
man oftobacco.
He introduced filters
when cigarettes first got
slammed by Reader's Di gest.
Later, he founded
the Academy ofTobacco Studies.
The club was founded
by the tobacco barons in 1 890
so they'd have a place
to get away from their wives.
Here, the Captain is a legend-
a self-made man who started
from nothing,
and ended up with everything...
except, evidently, a son.
N ick, my boy.
You're just i n ti me for m ud.
Thank you.
Sit down there. Yeah.
Yeah.
You know the secret
to a really good julep?.
No, sir.
Well, you crush the mint
down onto the ice with your thumb
and you grind it in, see?.
And it releases the menthol.
Hmm.
Nowyou know who taught me that?.
No, sir. Who?.
Fidel Castro.
Doyou remember 1 952?.
Well, sir, I wasn't alive in 1 952.
Good Lord, I was in Korea
shooting Chinese in 1 952.
Really?.
Todaythey're our best customer.
Next timewewon't have to shoot
so many ofthem, will we?.
- ( chuckles )
- No, sir.
1 952 was theyear
Reader's Digest
nailed us with
the whole health aspect.
As Churchill said,
that was perhaps the end
of our beginning.
Tell me,
doyou enjoyyour current work, Nick?.
Yes, sir.
It's challenging...
Ifyou can do tobacco,
you can do anything.
Yes, sir, I like that.
You know, Nick, you remind me
just a little bit
of myselfwhen I was your age.
Well, thankyou, sir.
Like thatJoan Lunden showyou did.
You could have given up,
cried, apologized,
butyou didn't.
You stayed loyal.
And you gave it
to that son ofa bitch good.
- ( chuckles )
- My pleasure.
Now, BR's come under the idea
that we should start bribing
producers in Hollywood
to make the actors smoke on screen.
You know, like in the old days.
Say, that's, uh...
that's a great idea.
Mm-hmm.
Smart man, that BR.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
And loyal.
Yes, sir?.
Have a seat, Ron.
You, see, Ron, I can't be
everywhere I'm needed.
That's why I send
people likeyou
to speak on my behalf.
When you're there,
you're not Ron Goode,
the guyyour friends probably like,
you're Senator Finistirre's aide,
and your name really doesn't matter.
So, when
Ron Goode acts
like a complete asshole
on the Joan Lunden Show,
I am being an asshole
on the Joan Lunden Show.
Senator, sir, he sprang on me like...
Where in the hell
did you find cancer boy?.
He was supposed to be quite reliable.
The Pulmonary Council
was one ofhis references.
Fucking nonprofits.
When you're looking
for a cancer kid,
he should be hopeless.
He should have a wheelchair.
He should have trouble talking.
He should have
a little pet goldfish
he carries around
in a ziplock bag-
hopeless.
I apologize, sir, but ifitwasn't
- for Nick Naylor...
- Nick Naylor?.
Don'tyou even think
of using him as an excuse.
The man shills bullshit for a living.
You work for a fucking senator.
A senatorwho is supposed
to be tough on tobacco.
Have a little... pride,
for God's sake.
It won't happen again, sir,
I promise.
All right, you're excused.
Sometimes I feel like
a Colombian drug dealer.
( chuckles )
The other day, my own granddaughter,
flesh of flesh of my own loins,
asked me, "Granddaddy, is it true
cigarettes are bad foryou??"
We got to do something, Nick.
I thinkyou're our man.
Thankyou, sir.
I wantyou to work
on this Hollywood project.
Get out there the next
few weeks, stir things up
and report directly to me.
Sir, about the,
the $50 million.
Anti teen-smoking advertising.
Well, shit, I sure hope
it's not too persuasive.
( laughs )
I hope.
Nick,
you're family now.
Tobacco takes care of its own, eh?.
Thankyou, sir.
Mr. Naylor?.
Hi.
Hi. Welcome to Tobacco One.
Thankyou.
The captain told me to take
extra special care ofyou today.
So ifthere is anything
at all I can do
to makeyour flight
more pleasant,
you be sure and let me know now.
BR.
Pleasant flight?.
Oh! You could say that.
Came up on the Captain's plane.
Oh, it's quite the way to travel.
I wouldn't know.
No?. You never been on Tobacco One
with those seats, that kitchen,
that stewardess, Tiffany?.
Haven't had the chance yet.
Oh, well, you really must try it.
It's the onlyway to travel.
What'd he think ofyour $50 million
anti-smoking campaign?.
Oh, the $50 million
anti teen-smoking campaign?.
Yeah.
Yeah, he gave that the go-ahead.
Oh, and he loved your idea
to put cigarettes back into movies.
- That was your idea.
- Oh, yeah?.
- He must have gotten confused.
- Hmm.
Yeah. Well, eitherway,
he was pretty blown away.
Right. Well, get a flight to L.A.
I'll getyou a meeting
with Jeff Megall.
Who?.
Hollywood super agent.
Runs the agency EGO:
Entertainment Global Offices.
This guy is the entertainment business.
And you are cigarettes, BR.
Whatever.
Yeah, but it's not a vacation,
it's a learning experience.
And California is one
ofthe fastest-growing
states, it's got
the largest number of electoral
votes in the country.
I mean, this could be
a very good trip forJoey.
You know what?.
Don't smooth-talk me.
You're not going to
take him sightseeing.
You're probably going
to take him
to some lung cancer symposium
where a guywith an electronic
voice box will tell him
that his father is the devil.
That's unfair.
Unfair?. What about Virginia?.
And what about Virginia?.
You took him to a cigarette factory.
No, I took him to a tobacco farm.
That's hardly the same thing.
This conversation's over.
( sighs ): Oh, fuck.
Last weekwe had another
disgruntled postman.
Of course,
an hour later the Washington Post
is calling me on the phone-
godless swine.
I said to 'em, I says,
"Now if a plane crashes
on account of pilot error,
do you blame the Boeing Corporation??"
Nice.
- That's a good one.
- Thankyou.
If some booze-besotten drunk
runs someone down,
do you go banging on the doors
at General Motors?.
Tell meyou didn't say that.
Mm-hmm.
Have either ofyou heard of a
reporter named Heather Holloway?.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Irish type.
Brown hair, big blue eyes.
Nice skin.
Amazing tits.
Tits?. Why are tits relevant?.
Hmm, let's see.
World-class tits on a reporter
interviewing a man
with privileged information
are relevant.
How about it, Nick?.
Areyou a tit man?.
Don't answer that.
That's a trap.
Depends whose tits.
Look,just don't get screwed,
all right?.
Bobby, I think I can handle
a good-looking girl reporter.
Thankyou.
Heather Holloway.
Nick Naylor, big tobacco.
Is this kosher?.
Only ifl can call you "Heather."
By all means.
So, Mr. Naylor...
- Nick.
Let's start with...
An '82 Margaux.
Okay. Is it good?.
Good?. It'll makeyou believe in God.
So what is the focus ofyour piece?.
- You.
- Really?.
You want to know how I live
with myself.
No. I don't imagine
that's much of a problem.
I want to know howyou seeyourself.
I'm...
a mediator between two sects
of society
that are trying
to reach an accommodation.
Interesting.
My other interviews have pinned
you as a mass murderer,
bloodsucker, pimp,
profiteer, child killer,
and my personal favorite
"yuppie Mephistopheles."
Wow, that sounds
like a balanced article.
Who else should I talk to?.
55 million American smokers,
for starters
or perhaps
the American tobacco farmer
who is constantly being treated
like a drug smuggler.
I actually do plan on speaking
to a tobacco farmer.
Good.
They're fine people,
salt ofthe earth.
Nick, why doyou do this?.
What motivates you?.
You reallywant to know?.
Mm-hmm.
Really?.
( whispers ): Population control.
( chuckles )
You're bad.
Everyone's got a mortgage to pay.
NICK: Theyuppie Nuremberg defense.
So is a mortgage that much
of a life goal?.
Well, 99%%% of everything done
in the world, good or bad,
is done to pay a mortgage,
so perhaps the world
would be a better place
if everyone rented.
Then why don't you rent?.
Mm. Well, I rent as well.
- Really?.
- Yeah.
My son and his mother
and her boyfriend
Iive in my house.
I live in my apartment.
What does Nick Naylor's
apartment look like?.
I don't know.
It's nothing impressive.
It wouldn't make
the real estate section.
( chuckles )
Can I see it?.
You want to see my apartment?.
I'd like to see
where the devil sleeps.
NICK: I know what
you're probablythinking.
This is a bad idea, right?
I mean, come on.
It's not that bad ofan idea.
( sizzling )
( pots clattering )
Mom, why can't I go
to Cal ifornia?.
Because California's
just not a... safe place.
And besides,
I'm not sure it's appropriate
foryour father to bring you
on a business trip.
Appropriate forwho?.
What?.
Mom, is it possible that
you're taking the frustration
ofyour failed marriage out on me?.
Excuse me?.
This California trip seems like
a great learning opportunity
and a chance for me
to get to know my father.
But ifyou think it's more important
to use me to channel your frustration
against the man you no longer love,
I'll understand.
How'd you convince her?.
It was an argument,
not a negotiation.
That's my boy.
( soft music playing )
Nick?.
Nick,Jack,Jeff's assistant. Hey.
How was your flight?.
Areyou jet-lagged at all?.
It's, like, 2:00 in D.C.
right now.
You know what?.
Take some vitamin B.
Jeffswears by it- in fact,
I'm gonna hookyou up
with an injection.
Who's this with you?.
How areyou, dude?. What's going on?.
You guys ever been to L.A. before?.
You want to head back
toJeff's office?.
In fact, we probably should-
He's a punctual being.
We actually had some problems at first
with the exterior mirrored glass.
The reflection ofthe sun was causing
head-on collisions on Wilshire.
Oh, is everybody all right?.
Yeah, they got three-picture deals
at Paramount- I'm sure they'll live.
- It's a nice building.
- Yeah?.
Hey, tell Jeffyou think so, okay?.
'Cause he just put a lot
ofhimselfinto this building.
And you know something?.
It really shows.
What's up, Hiroshi?.
Keep going-that sand's
not gonna rake itself.
All right, come here,
this is my favorite part.
That one right there?.
It's $7,000.
- $7,000 for a fish?.
- ( laughs ): Yep.
Kind of makes you want
to stop eating sushi,
but I guess you kind ofhave to.
Hey, you see that
big white one right there?.
Swear toyou- $1 2,000,
gift from Oprah.
It's a Chamberlain- office-warming gift
from Matthew McConaughey.
Generous gift.
( laughs ): Yeah. Right!
Don't get me wrong, Matthew is
a tremendously talented individual
and an extremely decent human being,
however, beforeJeff
took him on, he was a face.
Now he's a name.
( elevatorbell dings )
Do you hear that?.
No.
Exactly.
( bell dings )
Hey, Neal.
Neal, I'm gonna impale
your mom on a spike,
and I'm gonna feed her dead body
to my dog with syphilis.
( laughs ): Aw,Jack, you got me!
NEAL: That guy!
It's an inside joke.
( sighs ):
So, as you can see,
Jeff just really loves Asian shit.
Uh, Candace, is he ready?.
- Mm-hmm.
- Fantastic.
( quietly): Okay,Joey,
I'm gonna bring your dad in now.
Is there anything I can get
you whileyou're waiting,
Iike an orange juice
or a coffee or a Red Bull?.
- No, thanks.
- Okay.
Wow, it's a great office.
Yeah.Jeffbasically designed
the whole thing.
The architect just made the drawings.
Jack, stop it.
Nextyou're gonna be telling him
what position I played
for the Bruins.
( quietly): Quarterback.
Jeff Megall.
Nick Naylor.
Mr. Naylor's here to see
ifwe can't get cigarettes
- into the hands of somebody
other than the usual RAVs.
- Sure.
- RAVs?.
- Russians, Arabs and Villains.
Oh, well, then yes, I guess
that is why I'm here.
Good. I thinkwe can help.
Jeffinvented product placement.
NICK: I feel I have to ask, uh...
Areyou concerned at
all about the, um...
about the health element?.
I'm not a doctor, I'm a facilitator.
I bring creative people together.
Whatever information there is,
exists, it's out there.
People will decide for themselves.
They should. It's not
my role to decide for them.
It'd be morally presumptuous.
NICK: I couldlearn a lot
from this man.
Now, what we need is
a smoking role model,
a real winner.
Indiana Jones meets Jerry Maguire.
Right, on two packs a day.
Only he can't live
in contemporary society.
Why not?.
The health issue's way too prevalent.
People would constantly
be asking the character
why he's smoking-
and that should go unsaid.
How doyou feel about the future?.
The future?.
Yeah, after the health thing's
blown over.
A world
where smokers and nonsmokers
Iive together in perfect harmony.
Sony has a futuristic sci-fi movie
they're looking to make.
Message From SectorSix.
All takes place in a space station.
They're actively looking
for some cofinancing.
So cigarettes in space?.
It's the final frontier, Nick.
But wouldn't they blow up
in an all-oxygen environment?.
Probably.
But it's an easy fix-
one line of dialogue:
"Thank God we invented the..."
you know,
whatever device.
Brad Pitt.
Catherine Zeta-Jones.
They've just finished ravishing
each other's bodies
for the first time.
They lie naked, suspended in air
underneath the heavens.
Pitt lights up.
He starts blowing smoke rings
all around
Catherine's naked, flawless body,
as the galaxies go whizzing
by over the glass-domed ceiling.
Now, tell me that
doesn't work foryou.
I'd see that movie.
I'd buy the goddamn DVD.
You know, ifthe academy
didn't send them to me for free.
You know,
you guys ought to think
about designing a cigarette
to be released simultaneously
with the movie.
Sector Sixes.
No one's ever done it
with a cigarette.
Wow.
Well, where do we go from here?.
You enjoy the rest ofyour day
in L.A. with your son
while I find out
the answers to these questions.
Hey, where can I get
a bite to eat with my son?.
You ought to try Nobu's new place.
- He only serves food that's white.
- Oh, great.
JOEY: So,you go to an office,
thenyou go on TV
and talk about cigarettes.
Thenyou fly out to L.A.
to talk to some guy who
works with movie stars.
- What is that?.
- That's my job;, I'm a lobbyist.
I know, but did you study to do that?.
No. No, I just kind offigured it out.
Then can't anyone just do that?.
No, it, uh, requires a...
a moral flexibility
that goes beyond most people.
Do I have flexible morals?.
Well, let's say
you became a lawyer, right?.
And you were asked
to defend a murderer.
Worse than that- a child murderer.
Now,
the law states that every person
deserves a fair trial.
Would you defend them?.
I don't know.
I guess every person
- deserves a fair defense.
- Yeah, well,
so do multinational corporations.
So, what happens when you're wrong?.
( chuckles ):
Well,Joey, I'm neverwrong.
Butyou can't always be right.
Well, ifit's yourjob to be right,
then you're neverwrong.
But what ifyou are wrong?.
Okay, let's say that
you're defending chocolate
and I'm defending vanilla.
Now, ifl were to say toyou,
"Vanilla's the best flavor
ice cream," you'd say...?.
- "No, chocolate is."
- Exactly.
But you can't win that argument.
So, I'll askyou-
So you think chocolate
is the end-all and be-all
ofice cream, doyou?.
It's the best ice cream;
I wouldn't order any other.
Oh. So it's all chocolate
foryou, is it?.
Yes, chocolate is all I need.
Well, I need more than chocolate.
And for that matter,
I need more than vanilla.
I believe that we need
freedom and choice
when it comes to our ice cream,
and that,Joey Naylor,
that is the definition ofliberty.
But that's not what
we're talking about.
Ah, but that's what
I'm talking about.
- But... you didn't prove that vanilla's the best.
- I didn't have to.
I proved thatyou're wrong-
and ifyou're wrong, I'm right.
Butyou still didn't
convince me.
'Cause I'm not afteryou.
I'm after them.
( phone ringing )
Hello?.
Thought I'd giveyou a little update.
Jeff. You still at the office?.
Doyou know what time it is
in Tokyo right now?.
- No.
- 4:00 p.m. tomorrow.
It's the future, Nick.
Anyway, for Pitt to smoke,
it's $1 0 million;
for the pair, it's 25.
25??!. Usuallywhen I buy two
ofsomething, I get a discount.
What's the extra five for?.
Synergy.
These are not stupid people;
they got it right away.
Pitt and Zeta-Jones lighting up
after some cosmic fucking
in the bubble suite's
gonna sell a lot of cigarettes.
Well, for that kind of money,
my people will expect
some very serious smoking.
Can Brad blow smoke rings?.
I don't have that information.
Well, for $25 million,
we'd want smoke rings.
Oh, one other thing-
you'll be cofinancing
the picture
with the Sultan ofGlutan.
The Sultan ofGlutan?.
The onewho massacred
and enslaved his own people?.
Aren't they calling him
the Hitler ofthe South Pacific?.
No, I can't speak to that-
All my dealings with him,
he's been a very reasonable
and sensitive guy.
He's fun. You'll like him.
I better run it by my people.
No problem.
- ( beep )
- Oh, that's London calling.
7;:00 a.m. in the Old Empire.
Jeff, when doyou sleep?.
Sunday.
( line hangs up )
( laughs softly)
( groans )
( line ringing )
- Operator.
- Yeah, my light is blinking.
- There's a package downstairs foryou.
- Okay, send it up.
Captain, I'm sitting in front
of an open briefcase.
I don't suppose this is a raise.
Now, Nick, doyou know
who Lorne Lutch is?.
Yeah, of course.
He's the original Marlboro Man.
He's dying.
He was on Sally last week.
Not exactly our biggest fan.
Well, the money's for him.
Now, he has a ranch
out there in California.
I wantyou to bring it to him.
He's a cowboy, sir,
and cowboys don't like bribes.
It's not a bribe. No, sir.
You're going out there
on wings ofangels, son.
You mean we're just going
to give him the money?.
Well, I think Christ himself
would say,
"That's mightywhite ofyou boys."
No gag agreement?.
Hopefully, he'll be so damn
overcome with gratitude
he'll... he'll have to shut up.
Hey, kiddo, I got to go do
a little bit more work
this afternoon, all right?.
Can I come?.
No. Not this time.
But I want to see whatyou do.
You stay here, okay?.
What the fuck areyou doing here?.
Uh... uh...
Doyou have a minute?.
What doyou want?.
Dad!
Joey, get back in the car.
Just want to talk.
All right.
Let's talk.
Pearl, we got company.
Mister, you got a lot of nerve
walking in here after...
Honey, why don't you show
this young man some iced tea?.
I'll be right back, tiger.
( hissing )
Saw you on...
Weren't you on that TV show?.
Yeah. Yeah, that was me.
You're luckyyou made it
out ofthere alive.
Yeah. Tobacco used to be
all over the television.
Now TV is leading the witch hunt.
Strange business.
Lastyear, after I was diagnosed,
flew east to attend the
annual stockholders' convention.
Stood up and told them
I thought
they ought to cut back
on their advertising.
You know whatyour boss said to me?.
He said, "We're certainly sorry
"to hear aboutyour medical problem.
"However, without
knowing more
"ofyour medical history,
we can't comment further."
But then they tried to pretend
I neverworked for 'em.
Yeah, I got the pay stubs.
But, hell,
I was on the damn billboards.
I never
even smoked
Marlboro.
I smoked Kools.
You look like a nice-enough fella.
What areyou doing
working for these assholes?.
I'm good at it.
Better at doing this
than I everwas
at doing anything else.
Aw, hell, son.
I was good at shooting VC.
I didn't make it my career.
I suppose we all
got to pay the mortgage.
Your dad always bring
you along like this?.
No. I live with my mom.
He tell you why he's here today?.
He said thatyour husband
was the Marlboro Man.
( phone rings )
Yeah, well, not anymore.
Hello.
Yeah. Hey, can you hold on a second?.
You need anything else,
grab it out ofthe fridge.
So I'm standing here
minding my own business,
filling up pill bottles...
Soyou're here to talk me
into shutting up?.
Thatwhat's in that case ofyours?.
Yeah, basically.
No, not basically.
That's... that's exactly it.
My dignity ain't for sale.
It's not an offer.
It's a gift.
Taxes have all been paid.
You get to keep it
no matterwhatyou do.
The idea is that, somehow,
your guilt will preventyou
from bad-mouthing us.
Areyou supposed to be
telling me all that?.
No, sir.Just apologize,
giveyou the money, and leave.
Why are you telling me this?.
Because, this way,
you'll take the money.
Whywould I do that?.
Becauseyou're mad.
Damn straight I am.
The first thing you'll do,
is you'll call the L.A. Times,
and CNN...
- Huh?.
- and insist on Bonnie Carlton.
She does really good
controlled outrage.
Tell them, "No Bonnie, no story."
Watch it on MSNBC.
- Okay.
- When they get here,
you open up the case...
and you pour all the cash
out onto the floor.
- Why?.
- Trust me.
It'll look more effective that way.
Don't forget to shake
every last bundle out.
Ifyou can, you know,
give a cough or two.
Once it's all
out on the floor,
tell them what you're
going to do with it.
What am I going to do with it?.
You're going to donate it.
Yeah. Start the Lorne Lutch
Cancer Foundation.
You're going to have
a ranch and a fair
and a 5K.
A 5K is a must. Television...
Wait a minute.
What about my family?.
But, Lorne, you can't keep the money.
Why the hell not?.
What doyou mean?.
Denounce us,
and then keep the blood money?.
I mean, look at it.
I got to think this over.
Lorne, whoa.
News doesn't work that way.
You can't denounce us next week.
I don't suppose I can
denounce you for half of it.
No, Lorne. Eitheryou keep
all the money,
oryou... you give it all away.
Dad, how did you know
he would take the money?.
You'd have to be crazy
to turn down all that money.
When I saw he wasn't crazy,
I knew he'd take it.
Would you have taken it?.
If I were him?. Sure.
So would I.
I don't thinkyou understand, sir.
He's like a wild animal.
You'll have to be
on your guard at all times.
He has this trick.
Ron, shut up.
I've tangoed with presidents,
lawyers and Indian chiefs.
I think I can handle Mr. Nick Naylor.
( clears throat )
DENNIS MI LLER:
All right, welcome back, kids.
We've got two guests
on the show tonight.
First,joining us
from ourWashington studio...
I must have that tie clip!
...is the senator from
the great state ofVermont.
Please welcome Ortolan Finistirre.
Welcome, Senator.
Good to be here, Dennis.
And,joining us here
in our Los Angeles studio,
he is the chiefspokesperson
for the Academy ofTobacco Studies.
Quite an august chamber, might I add?.
- Nick Naylor. Nick, welcome.
- Pleasure to be here.
All right, I understand you were
on Joan Lunden's show recently.
Didn't make a lot
offriends over there, did you?.
I will say that I don't think
I'll be getting
my annual invitation
to the Finistirre Labor Day Barbecue.
Well, I continue to offer
an open invitation to Mr. Naylor
to join us in Congress
to talk about the inclusion
of our new poison label which,
ifl might say...
Nick, ready to trek up
the Hill and testify
before Congress?.
Well, I'd love to, Dennis,
but not as long as the senator
is calling for me to be fired.
It's not exactly
a welcome invitation.
Yeah. Bit ofa mixed message,
Senator.
Well, not as mixed as the stance
that Big Tobacco has taken
about the dangers
of smoking cigarettes.
- Oh, no.
- Now what areyou laughing...?.
You're a wind-up artist.
Give the man his due.
He's got a bit of a point there,
doesn't he?.
Sorry. I just can't
help myself, Dennis.
I... I... I'm just tickled by the idea
ofthe gentleman from Vermont
calling me a hypocrite
when, uh... this same man,
in one day, held a press
conference where he called
for the American tobacco fields
to be slashed and burned,
then he jumped on a private jet
and flew down to Farm Aid
where he rode a tractor onstage
- Oh, come on.
- as he bemoaned the downfall
ofthe American farmer.
Care to comment, Senator?.
He... I... No.
Eloquent in its brevity.
Emotional issue.
Let's take some phone calls now.
Herndon, Virginia.
Go ahead. You're on the show.
MAN: Dennis, has anyone ever
announced that they're going
to kill someone live on your show?.
My demo's been called quirky
but, no, at this point,
we're not skewing
to the emotionally unstable.
Then it's your lucky day.
Because I'm here to tell
you that, within a week,
we're going to dispatch
Mr. Naylor from this planet
for all the pain and suffering
he's caused in the world.
( click )
As I said, emotional issue.
We're going to break now.
I got to fire a call screener.
Let's go.
( chuckling )
( moans )
This is Nick Naylor
telling you kids,
"Don't do drugs, smoke cigarettes."
That's really great.
It's like I'm looking in a mirror.
New idea:
cigarettes for the homeless.
We'll call them "hobos."
( chuckling )
Uh, that's awful.
Any better than "Sector Sixes"?.
Right.
Oh, my God, Nick, you're on TV.
( TVplaying )
"Lobbyist on the lookout."
You got to be kidding me.
I want to fuckyou
while I watch you on TV.
And they call me sick.
Hurry.
Before your segment ends.
All right.
Tell me more about Los Angeles, baby.
Huh?.
NICK: He says he wants
to trail me everywhere,
I said, "Who's paying for it??"
He says the tobacco company's
paying for it.
I said, "I don't need a bodyguard."
I'm a man of the people.
Rock on, Kennedy.
Listen, we're all going to
need bodyguards soon enough.
Did you see the coverage
the fetal alcohol people
got themselves over this weekend?.
They made it seem like
we were encouraging
pregnant women to drink.
I'm surprised I didn't get kidnapped
on myway to work this morning.
I don't think people from
the alcoholic beverage industry
need to worry about
being kidnapped justyet.
Pardon me?.
Look, I mean,
nothing personal,
but tobacco generates
a little more heat than alcohol.
Oh, this is news.
My product puts away 475,000 a year.
Oh, okay, now 475 is a legit number.
Okay, 435,000.
That's 1,200 a day.
How many alcohol-related deaths
a year?.
- Well, does that...
- 1 00,000 tops?.
That's, what, 270 a day?.
Wowee.
270 people, a tragedy.
Excuse me ifl don't exactly see
terrorists getting excited
about kidnapping anyone
from the alcohol industry.
- Well, you haven't even
- Okay,
- taken into account the number of deaths
- let's just
- breathe.
- How many gun deaths a year in the U.S.?.
1 1,000.
1 1,000, areyou kidding me?.
30 a day.
That's less than passenger car
mortalities.
No terrorist would bother
with either ofyou.
Okay, look...
stupid argument.
I'll say.
I'm sure both ofyou warrant
vigilante justice.
Thankyou.
( motorrevs )
( tires screech )
( grunting, groaning )
( engine racing,
overlapping voices )
Hey... please.
Stop... hey.
Who are you guys?.
( tires screeching )
GI RL: And freedom means
that we can do what we want.
And that's really important.
Because otherwise,
we couldn't be free.
And that's why America is
the best government in the world.
Whoa, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, no need for that,
no need for that.
Whoa, whoa, hey.
Hey, wait.
Can we get a dialogue going here?.
Nick, we want you
to stop killing people.
So many people.
Half a million people a year
in the U.S.
That, there's no data
to support that.
Nick... you're not on TV anymore.
Okay,Joey, it's your turn.
Hey!
Nick, how much doyou smoke a day?.
Hey, what are you doing?.
According to the box,
each one ofthose patches
contains 21 milligrams of nicotine.
That's, like, what?.
One pack?.
Our industry has been working
hand in hand with...
Nick! Just listen, all right?.
What makes America
the best government?.
The passion that doesn't exist
anywhere in the world.
Says here there are
many adverse reactions
from those things.
Let's see, "arrhythmia,
"constipation, dyspepsia,
- "nausea...
- My industry does $48 billion in revenue.
pharyngitis, sinusitis..."
Sureyou can call it capitalism,
a free market,
a celebration oftariffbreakdowns...
"dysmenorrhea..."
I don't even want to know
what that means.
Hey, look, I guess you could
start by, you know,
asking for five million,
working yourway up from there.
But I don't want any money, Nick.
Well, what doyou want?.
I mean, I'm all ears here.
I have anotherword for it-
Iove.
What does any man want?.
The love of a woman,
crisp bacon...
an average life span over 80 years.
Oh, Nick...
( filteredapplause )
...you don't look so good.
WOMAN:
lfyou shouldsmellsmoke,
please dialzero for the operator.
Before leaving the room,
check the door for heat.
Findyour nearest
emergency exit,
then soak a washcloth
and coveryour nose and mouth.
Do not remove your washcloth.
Try at all times to avoid
breathing in the smoke.
Ifnecessary, crawl on
your hands and knees
to avoid the inhalation ofsmoke.
Do not be alarmed.
There are still
no conclusive studies
that link smoking to emphysema.
( machine beeping )
( monotone ) : You woke up.
N I CK:
Perhaps a bad choice ofinflection.
Is she implying that l
could've just as easily not?
I was so scared.
Hey, J oey.
( sighs heavily )
What happened?.
No nonsmoker
could've ever withstood
the amount of nicotine
you had in your bloodstream.
Hate to say it, but...
cigarettes saved your life.
Can I quoteyou on that, doc?.
You're a real trooper, my boy.
Hey, Captain,
where are you?.
Winston-Salem General.
Damn heart failing me again.
I thought we could be roommates.
Nick, before
we get sidetracked,
there is one thing.
All right, don't get
all dramatic on me, doc.
You can't smoke.
That's no problem.
I've quit before.
I did during the pregnancy.
How long, you think?.
I don't thinkyou understand.
It's a miracleyou came
out ofthis alive.
Any smoking-one cigarette-
could putyou right back
into a paralytic state.
Your bodyjust can't handle it.
Nick, I don't want to put
any more pressure on you,
but we got a camera crew
waiting out there.
Ifwe want to make
the evening news...
You want to unhook me here?.
This just goes to prove what
I've been saying for so long.
These nicotine patches
are just deadly.
Smoking saved my life.
Considering your condition,
will you still be able to appear
before Senator Finistirre's
subcommittee hearing
on the usage of poison labels
on cigarette packaging?.
Oh, I think now more than ever
it is imperative that I be there.
Nothing will keep me from testifying.
Fucking kidnapping.
I don't understand, sir.
Aren't we considering
the kidnapping a good thing?.
Well, he didn't die.
Hewas almost killed, sir.
That's the point.
Now he looks like a victim,
lucky bastard.
Theway I heard it,
D.C. police found you naked
Iaying in Lincoln's crotch
coveredin nicotine patches
with a sign acrossyour chest
- that said...
- He doesn't need to hear the details.
It was some pretty fucked up shit.
Shh!
How are you feeling?.
I don't know.
First time I'm thinking these
cigarettes are pretty dangerous.
You might be right about that.
What areyou doing?.
It may be small,
but it'll do the trick.
One shot, bam.
Listen, Nick is not
going to shoot anyone.
Cool.
Yeah, huh?.
I mean, uh...
guns are to be treated with
respect, you understand that?.
You'll make a great father.
Thanks.
( applause )
Hey, there he is!
Hey, he's back!
Hey!
Welcome back.
- You okay?.
- Great.
Good, 'cause you're booked on
all the Sunday talk shows.
For once we got public sympathy
on our side.
We can start our own little
celebrityvictim tour.
I mean, we couldn't have planned
this thing better ourselves.
Oh, maybe next time
I can lose a lung.
Oh. Uh, I heard the, uh...
Heather Holloway article
is coming out tomorrow.
Really?.
Yeah, anything I should be
worried about?.
Uh, yeah, the Cancer Association.
Apparently, they have it in for us.
Fuckers.
What?.
I got a call from the paper.
Really?.
What'd theywant?.
Theywanted the correct spelling
of my name and job title.
You didn't tell her
about us, did you?.
Who?.
Heather?.
No.
I mean, maybe in passing, I...
In passing.
Oh, God, he fucked her.
I tried to warn you.
Hey, he didn't fuck her.
You didn't fuck her, did you?.
When?.
In passing.
Look, she's a really nice girl.
Oh, God.
We're really fucked.
NICK: "Nick Naylor,
leadspokesman forbig tobacco,
"would haveyou believe he
thinks cigarettes are harmless.
"But really, he's doing it
for the mortgage.
BAI LEY: The MD squad- meaning,
ofcourse, merchants ofdeath-
is comprised ofPolly Bailey
ofthe Moderation Council
and BobbyJay Bliss
ofthe gun business's
own advisory group, SAFETY.
BLI SS: As explained by Naylor,
the sole purpose oftheir meetings
is to compete for
the highest death toll
as they compare strategies
on how to dupe the American people.
M EGALL:
The film, Message from Sector Six,
would emphasize the sex appeal
ofcigarettes
in a way that only floating, nude,
copulating Hollywood stars could.
LUTCH: This did not stop Nick
from bribing the dying man
with a suitcase ofcash
to keep quiet on the subject
ofhis recent lung cancer diagnosis.
J I LL: Nick's own son,Joey Naylor,
seems to be being groomed
for the job as he joins his father
on the majority ofhis trips.
( beep )
RECEPTI ON I ST:
I have Heather Hol loway on I i ne one.
Heather.
Hey, Nick, what did you think?.
Heather, uh... I...
I mean, there's a lot
of information in here, Heather,
that is offthe record.
You never said anything
about offthe record.
I presumed anything said while
I was insideyou was privileged.
Nick...
Ifyou wanted to talk on a plane
or at a movie or over dinner,
that would have been fine.
Butyou wanted to fuck.
That's fine by me.
You used me.
Oh, Nick, come on.
Now we're being children.
Look, we both love ourjobs.
I'm just a reporter,
and you're just a lobbyist.
How can you do this to me?.
For the mortgage.
Bitch.
Whore.
You should have been
more careful, Nick.
You've destroyed all the good
will created byyour kidnapping.
Well, we'll work up a rebuttal.
Heather Holloway isn't
the only reporter in town.
No, there isn't going
to be any rebuttal.
What doyou mean?.
Don't talk to anyone.
We're pulling you
from the congressional hearing.
No, no, no. You can't pull me
All you'll be doing is giving
credence to her article.
I'm readyto testify.
Look, Nick, half of myjob
is damage control.
Today, that consists
of distancing ourselves
from you entirely-
Ietting you take
all the heat on this article.
Yourjob relied on your ability
to keep secrets
and spin the truth.
I just cannot imagine a way
in which you could have fucked
up more.
There's just no way I could
possibly keepyou on staff.
Then I assumeyou've run this
by the captain.
Captain died this morning.
( mellow,jazzyintro plays )
( man singingslowly)
( singing ends )
( beep )
( overanswering machine ): Mr. Naylor,
this is Pete in Security from the Academy.
Your things are waiting foryou
at the information kiosk
in the lobby.
Look, ifyou don 't pick your
stuffup by Friday,
we 're instructed to throw it out.
( beep )
Mr. Naylor, this is Special
AgentJohnson with the FBl.
Having not found any leads in
your kidnapping investigation,
we 're going to be
handing over the case
to the local D. C. police,
so please refer to them
in the future
for any updates and questions.
( beep )
Nick,Jack in JeffMegall's office.
Jeffreally enjoyed
meetingyou the other day
and he 's just... he 's torn up
about the fact
thatyou two couldn't find
a project to work on.
He's reallyjust... I don't know.
So, listen,
but we should hang, at least,
so you drop me a line
wheneveryou're in town.
Uh... my e-mail is, uh...
[ Man Si ngi ng ]
( knocking on door )
( pounding on door )
Who is it?.
J I LL: I t's me, N ick.
J ill, this is a bad time.
Let me in.
( sighs softly )
No.
I brought someone
who needs to talk to you.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, Dad.
Coke in the fridge.
So, this Heather Holloway,
she must have been pretty hot.
Yes. She's pretty hot.
Don't take it so hard.
A few flaws can be appealing.
Makes you human.
Who wants to be human?.
Well, I know one person
who still thinks you're a God.
Why did you tell that reporter
all your secrets?.
You're tooyoung to understand.
Mom says it's because
you have dependency issues
and it was all just
a matter oftime
beforeyou threw it all away
on some tramp.
Well, that's one theory.
Why areyou hiding from everyone?.
It has something to do with
being generally hated right now.
But it's yourjob to be
generally hated.
It's more complicated
than that,Joey.
You're just making it
more complicated
so thatyou can feel
sorry foryourself.
Likeyou always said,
"Ifyou want an easyjob,
go work for the Red Cross."
You're a lobbyist.
Yourjob is to be right, and
you're the best at whatyou do.
You're the sultan of spin.
"Sultan ofspin"?.
Mom subscribes to Newsweek.
Who cares what the Brads
ofthe world think?.
He's not my dad.
You are.
NICK: Andright there,
looking intoJoey's eyes,
it all came back in a rush.
Why I do what I do-
defending the defenseless,
protecting the disenfranchised
corporations
that have been abandoned
by their very own consumers-
the logger...
the sweatshop foreman...
the oil driller...
the land mine developer...
the baby seal poacher...
Baby seal poacher?.
Even I thi nk that's kind of cruel.
All right, you're missing the point.
I must be, because I thought
you were apologizing.
I'm getting to that.
When?.
Look.
The two ofyou, you're
basically my only friends,
and the last thing that
I would everwant to do
would be to hurtyou.
And, I can only imagine...
Why areyou smiling?.
Why is he smiling?.
Hewon a hundred bucks off ofyou.
I bet Pollyyou'd spill the beans
to that reporter.
That goes against everything
that we stand for.
Oh, please! You've ratted us out
to some reporterwith tits!
Glorious tits.
Only afteryou created a betting
pool testing my incompetence?.
Do you have any idea the beating
I'm taking at Moderation?.
Well, look, I'm sure both of
you are under a lot of scrutiny.
You know what?.
You can stop using the plural.
The guys at Safety actually liked
the name "Merchants of Death."
They're gonna have
some bumper stickers made up.
I'll make sureyou get one.
Thankyou.
That is disgusting.
It's American.
Can I have a bite?.
Mmm.
So I guess this means
you won't be appearing
at Finistirre's subcommittee.
Hmm. I was kind oflooking
forward to it, too.
It's kind of cool in
a JimmyStewart sort ofway.
More like an Ollie North sort ofway.
Finistirre would have
torn you a new asshole
in a House of Parliament, no less.
I could have taken him.
- Yeah.
- Oh, yeah?. What would you have said?.
I don't know.
I'd just like him to feel
immeasurable pain,
humiliation.
Yeah, well, thatwould be
kind oftough.
I mean, he's already a Senator.
( chuckles )
I mean, howwould you get
back in even ifyou wanted to?.
Uh-oh.
You're not gonna like this.
( reporters clamoring )
Hello.
Thanks very much for coming.
First of all, I'd like to say
a few words
to all the people who
are mentioned
in the recent newspaper article.
Please take comfort in knowing
that I will not rest until
your names are cleared.
This experience has taught me
an important lesson-
having sexual affairs
with members ofthe press
is just unfair.
It's not unfair to me, mind you,
but to all the people in my life
whose only crime is knowing me.
It was your names, not mine,
that suffered
from a meaningless affair
with a seductress
in the form ofa young
brunette Washington reporter
whose name I won't mention
because I have dignity.
( reporters clamoring )
Mr. Naylor!
Are you still planning
on testifying
at tomorrow's subcommittee
hearing on tobacco?.
I'm glad you asked that question.
There have been wide accusations of me
dropping out oftomorrow's hearing.
Let it be known
that unless Senator Finistirre
has withdrawn my invitation
- to speak, it is my plan
- It's called a subpoena.
to be in Congress tomorrow
to share my knowledge
ofbig tobacco and all those
who enjoy its products.
Thankyou very much.
I'll seeyou tomorrow.
( all clamoring )
( TVshuts off)
( phone rings )
( cacophony ofphones ringing )
( indistinct, distorted
roaring and shutters clicking )
Sti I l feel I i ke J i m my Stewart?.
Good.
( beeping )
( electronic squealing )
Why don't you al I go ahead?.
This could be a while.
( electronic squealing
continues )
Ifwe could, um... ifwe could
take our seats, please.
( clears throat )
Gentlemen, ladies.
If I may call this meeting to order.
We'll do everything we can to
keep things brief and concise
so that we can all
get out ofhere on time.
The skull and crossbones
means one thing:
Poison.
Thus, the message is quite clear.
Like any other product
that carries the branding,
ifyou take it, you will die.
Yes, but isn't this overkill?.
Why don't we just use words,
as we currently do?.
Something that describes the
dangers of cigarette smoking.
Well, the American public
is not affected
by masthead anymore.
They need images.
We've done studies
which show that consumers react
up to 80%%% more to imagery
rather than words.
The stats are there.
It's just sad
that the Academy ofTobacco
Studies did not release
this type ofinformation earlier.
When you say
the Academy ofTobacco Studies,
you're referring to...
Yes.
to the coalition...
Yes, the coalition.
The big... big tobacco...
...that is represented by...
By, um...
And specifically
Mr...
Um...
Mr., uh, Nick Naylor.
Nick Naylor?.
Thankyou very much.
WITNESS:
The current use
ofwords instead of imagery
is an obvious move against
the non-English-speaking population
ofthe United States.
The skull and crossbones
speak loudly in all languages.
By not using it,
they're saying
theywant those who can't
read English to die.
Hmm. Senor Herrera,
could you clarify "they"?.
NICK:
Let it be known,
the public beating
has not gone out ofstyle.
Nick Naylor, please step forward.
You go sit with him.
Please state your name,
address and current occupation.
My name is Nick Naylor.
I live at 6000
Massachusetts Avenue
and I am currently unemployed,
but until recently,
I was the vice president
ofthe Academy ofTobacco Studies.
Mr. Naylor,
as vice president
ofthe Academy
ofTobacco Studies,
what was required ofyou?.
What did you do?.
I informed the public
of all the research performed
in the investigation
on the effects oftobacco.
Mm-hmm,
and what,
so far,
has the Academy concluded
in their investigation
into the effects oftobacco?.
Well, many things, actually.
Why,just the other day
they uncovered evidence
that smoking can offset
Parkinson's disease.
( amusedbuzz )
I'm sure the health
community
is thrilled.
Mr. Naylor, who provides
the financial backing
for the Academy ofTobacco Studies?.
Uh... Conglomerated Tobacco.
That's the cigarette companies.
For the most part, yes.
Doyou think that...
might affect their priorities?.
No,just as I'm sure
campaign contributions
don't affectyours.
Ohh.
( alllaughing )
Senators, Mr. Naylor is not here
to testify on the goings-on
ofthe Academy ofTobacco Studies.
We're here to examine
the possibility
of a warning logo on cigarettes.
Now, Mr. Naylor,
I have to askyou,
out offormality,
doyou believe that smoking
cigarettes, over time,
can lead to lung cancer and
other respiratory conditions
such as emphysema?.
Yes.
In fact, I thinkyou'd be
hard-pressed
to find someone
who really believes
that cigarettes are not
potentially harmful.
I mean, show ofhands,
who out here thinks
- that cigarettes aren't dangerous...
- Mr. Naylor.
There's no need for theatrics.
Sir, I just don't see the point in a warning
label for something people already know.
The warning symbol
is a reminder, a reminder ofthe
dangers ofsmoking cigarettes.
Well, ifwewant to remind
people of danger,
why don'twe slap
a skull and crossbones
on all Boeing airplanes,
Senator Lothridge?.
And all Fords, Senator Dupree?.
That is ridiculous.
The death toll from airline
and automobile accidents
doesn't even skim the surface
of cigarettes.
They don't even compare.
Oh, this from a senator
who calls Vermont home.
I don't followyou, Mr. Naylor.
Well, the real
demonstrated number one killer
in America is cholesterol,
and here comes
Senator Finistirre,
whose fine state is,
I regret to say,
clogging the nation's arteries
with Vermont cheddar cheese.
( audience murmuring )
Ifwe want to talk numbers,
how about the millions of people
dying ofheart attacks.
Perhaps Vermont cheddar
should come
with a skull and crossbones.
That is lud...
The great state ofVermont
will not apologize for its cheese.
Mr. Naylor,
we are here to discuss cigarettes.
Not planes, not cars- cigarettes.
Now, as we discussed earlier,
these warning labels
are not for those who know, but
rather for those who don't know.
( sighs )
What about the children?.
Gentlemen...
it's called education.
It doesn't come offthe side
of a cigarette carton.
It comes from our teachers,
and more importantly, our parents.
It is the job
of every parent
to warn their children of all
the dangers ofthe world,
including cigarettes, so that
one day, when they get older,
they can choose for themselves.
I look at my... son
who...
was kind enough
to come with me today,
and I can't help but think
that I am responsible
for his growth
and his development.
And I'm proud ofthat.
Well, having
said that,
would you condone him smoking?.
Well, of course not.
He's not 1 8.
That would be illegal.
( chuckling )
Yes, I-I heard you deliver
that line on 20-20,
but enough dancing.
What areyou going to do
when he turns 1 8?.
Come on, Mr. Naylor.
On his 1 8th birthday, will
you share a cigarette with him?.
Will you spend
a lovely afternoon,
Iike one ofyour ludicrous
cigarette advertisements?.
You seem to have a lot to say
about how we
should raise our children.
What ofyour own?.
What areyou
going to do
when he turns 1 8?.
Ifhe reallywants a cigarette,
I'll buy him his first pack.
( audience mutters softly)
Thankyou foryour testimony,
Mr. Naylor. You're excused.
I'll meetyou outside, okay?.
Great.
Well done, my boy.
Were you in the same room as me?.
The whole personal choice thing?.
They ate that shit up.
( laughing ):
Just checked the whip count.
That bill is going down in flames.
Your speech was unorthodox,
butyou did it, boy.
You crushed the fucker.
That's good news foryou guys.
Oh. Whoa, whoa.
We're still a team, right?.
What about damage control?.
Look, Nick.
Winston-Salem is ready
to do whatever it takes
to keepyou onboard.
( crowdclamoring )
Nick, will you continue
fighting for cigarettes?.
Of course he will.
This man here is our general.
We're not just gonna let him retire.
REPORTER:
Is that correct, Nick?.
You're sticking with tobacco?.
NICK: Now, I know what
you're probablythinking.
What a great opportunityfor me
to teachJoey
how to use leverage against
a backstabbing boss.
But I actually meant what
I said about responsibility.
Some things
are just more important
than paying a mortgage.
So I did the only responsible
thing I could.
I turned down the job.
And my timing
couldn 't have been better.
Within a few months,
the cigarette companies
settled
with the American smoker
to the tune of$246 billion.
And the Academy
ofTobacco Studies
was permanently dismantled.
For the first time in decades,
BR found himselfout ofwork.
therwise, not much has changed.
The MD squad still meets every week.
N ice.
We even added a few new members.
The thi ngs I could learn
from you, Bobby J ay.
POLLY: Right.
BOBBY JAY:
Stick around. Stick around.
Senator Finistirre is still
fighting forhis causes.
What do you say
to the people who claim
you are destroying cinema classics?.
Mmm, no. All
we're doing
is using
digital technology
to tastefully update
movies ofthe past...
by removing cigarettes.
I believe that ifthese
stars were alive today,
they would agree that
we're doing the right thing.
But, in essence, aren't
you changing history?.
No, I think we're improving history.
Even Heatheris still reporting.
The whole town has been evacuated.
They're calling this
the storm of the century.
Not much changes at all.
And this year's Foggy Bottom
Debating Society Champion is...
Joey Naylor.
- Yay!
NICK: Joey!
POLLY:Joey!
NICK: Joey,Joey!
That's my boy.
Hold it up. Hold it up.
( Pollywhooping )
Andme?
Well, there's still a place
forguys like me.
So, be straight with me.
Is it true?.
- It could be.
- Come on.
We know ofvery few cases.
There's no scientific proof at all.
There was an unfortunate
incident out in Iowa...
It's really a complicated situation.
NICK:
Gentlemen,
practice these words
in front ofthe mirror.
"Although we are constantly
exploring the subject,
"currently,
there is no direct evidence
"that links cell phone usage
to brain cancer."
( relievedsigh )
MichaelJordan plays ball.
Charles Manson kills people.
I talk.
Everyone has a talent.
Subrip
CHRISOSFP