Hey... Hey... Hey... Hey...
Hey... Hey... Hey...
l need to reverse my car
Where are you going
lrrr.... lrrr friend?...
you park the car like this?
What do you said?
Hey... l'm going to kill you.
Stop the car
No
What happen?... are
you getting in or out
Get in
What are you doing?
What are you doing in air?
You are trying to get in...
...are you trying to steal the radio?
Help me!
Please... Listen to me
Why are you asking for help...?
are we trying to rape you?
are you going to shout for the police?
Do you know? Who am l...
We don't know... Who are you?
G.S Gay today...
Deputy Chief Engineer...
Maha Nagar Palika
What is this municipality?
your status can't allow
you to argue for a radio
Hey... Hey... What is
this...? Who are you people?
What do you need?
What...? ....can l seal your shop?
... l'm going to cancel
you driving license.
There is only one bullet in it...
l'll pull the trigger as many times
you ask the questions... Now Talk...
But... Where are you taking me?
l'm enjoying? ask me...?
Where to go Bhai (Brother)...?
Why you ask the
question...? Are you mad...?
Ask...? Understand...?
Alam... move towards
the Lucky Singh's office
This... This is correct.
Hey... Photo studio...
Write it down that Mr. Lucky
Singh President Mumbai Builder...
...association in serious talking
with George. Bush President of America.
You never visit America... Sir.
do one thing... replace white
house with our farm house
Your mother can't taught
you any common sense:::
Sir... Circuit's here...
Circuit... My Dear...
Some times people face
the betrayal in this world
you're not attending
my calls now these days
Right now he's going to pick up
Circuit! we're rocking
Get a side... Koko
Look... l'm unable
to give you any favour
Why...
you got the permission
of 8 story building....
last time and you build
a 1 1 story building...
lt has been completed by the time and
my counting is very poor since childhood
l'm going to lose my job
Leave this 10,000 job
- Do you hear about Parana Builders
-Yes
My daughter engaged over there
- Koko show him that map
- Yes
They purchased the Property that...
...is behind the Varsua Pump House
But only this yellow
house is not for sale
l Said, l'm going to buy it
Just count it as a wedding gift
This Bungalow is on liaison
for 99 years
- Next month lt's expires
- lt's going to renewed
Don't send the renewal paper's
Default it
No... No.... lt can't be done...
lt's a question of reputation
l already committed it
l need this bungalow
Now it's over you
You choose the difference
between this valet and bullet
Ask for the price?
Ten
Ten... Just ten... you take twenty
Koko give him twenty thousand
New notes... Happy...
No... No... One million...
30 thousand
Nine hundred thousand
Thirty one
l m leaving
Leaving
l'm kidnapped you
Pistol is in my hand and that one
is sitting brake few bones in a day
Brake it... Brake it...
You must've some fear
Look Lucky Bhai.... Midway...
- Five hundred thousand
- That's right
Now your's not mine....
midway... 2,50,000
The deal is done
- Offer him sweets
- Yes
With best complements
Circuit.... Give Munna good news
A bungalow evacuation
order... Where is he...
Bhai (Brother) can't work
till 9:00am to 12:00pm
is he rise late...
He can't sleep now these days
He is low... Low...
On the river bank all the day
lt's very cheap... flags
are empty... use it...
lt's not like that... He's
listening radio over there
Radio... What's special on radio
Our Madam is on the radio
Good Morning Mumbai
This is Janvi on worried famous radio
My today's message before leaving
For all of them are running in the city
What to do in the race of the city
lf that's the life then what is death
The reason being late for
the train in first rain
knowing everything about
the serial characters...
but don't have time to
care about your mother...
Now... Can't walk on the beach sand...
...108 channels are on without enjoyment
Connected to the Global
village with internet...
but can't know who's in our neighbors...
Life's full with Mobile and
Land line but don't have...
...that line that connects
you with your best friend
Remember last time
when you see the sunset
and remember when the evening is over
So Friends... why you
wants to run in the race
Wow... Janvi
lf this is life then what is death
So Good bye Mumbai now it's time to go
Bye bye Janvi
See you soon tomorrow
100% right here right now
Friends till then don't
worry be happy sayonara
Remember this tomorrow is 2nd October...
...and we're having the Mahatma Quiz
Who ever wins be my special guest
Yes, l'm going to invite him
for an interview in my studio.
So bye bye and don't forget
to tune in tomorrow at 9:00
- Bhai
- Circuit
What happened on 2nd October
lt's dry day
Do l purchase the stock
Dry day why?
lt's holiday
l'll find out don't take any tension
Birthday Bhai
2nd October is the
happy birthday of Bapu
Who's Bapu
Bapu Means Mahatma Gandhi
The Person on the bill...
correct he is the one...
What else do you know about him
He don't have any muscular body but he
was very daring l only know that much
- Bhai he over ruled English men
- What
Everybody escapes do to his fear...
He gives us freedom
ls he in army?
Bhai, l can't see his
Photograph in uniform
And his close-up is on the note
Look... A quiz on Bapu
is on radio tomorrow
l can meet Janvi lf l win
Madam... Bhai, it should be done
Circuit... What shirt l'll wear
Bhai, don't take any
kind of wearing tension
Nobody can see your shirt on radio
Correct
Concentrate on you voice Bhai
You voice should be prominent
Are you going to impress her?
Concentrate Bhai and l'll
going to take care of everything
Janvi Ji, l'm Murli Persad Sharma
l'm fine and how's about you
Don't be afraid it's very simple
On radio she's going to ask
the question's about Bapu
You answer them
Right...
Collect the prizes for the right answers
Look... that's not fair
l' m late for the college
Professor... these people
go to your home to...
...say hello to you wife
if you go to the college
- We can take what we want
- Yes, Answer perfectly
and take what ever...
you want, that mixer,
that gasket, that stove
Janvi Ji, Your voice make me mad
Bhai, they really think that we are...
... vagrants if you use
this king of language
Do as they professor do
Hey... Take out the Phone
make it on redial
As she ask question push the button
Nobody can able to call her
Tersu... what're you doing Come here
Marriage... Not till yet
Truth is that l'm interested in no one
Bhai, Come on
Alam, rise the volume
Till that time l ask the question
from each caller till he'll wrong
And anybody who'll answers the 10
question correctly will be our winner
Everybody is ready on his
phone and our number is 22666888
My first question
Gandhi called by which name
in south Africa by his fellows?
- lt's on Bhai
- Give it to me
First call has been received
before the question ends
- Hello
The network is busy
write now please try later
- Hello... Hello
- Yours.....
- Hello...
- This one Bhai...
Why showing it give it to me
- Hello
Who's this?
l'm... l'm Murli Parsad Sharma
So Murli what's the right answer?
- Bhai?
- yes
- Bhai... Bhai
- Yes speak
- Bhai... Bhai...
- l'll give a slap
Gandhi's fellows honored him by
the name of Bhai in South Africa
Murli you do have only 10 seconds
- Are you sure
- Think before answer
- Yes
- Either these Bhai's can't leave you
100 percent sure
- Hello
ln South Africa Gandhi Ji....
- ...Honored
-...Honored ... Honored by the name of Bhai
Well that's the right
answer, congratulations!
Now l'm going to ask you the question
till that time your answer is wrong
No chance Janvi ji
2nd Question, How many offspring's
Gandhi Ji have and their names?
- Rajeev Gandhi and lndraa Gandhi.
- Wow
Eldest Son name was Hari Lal
Hari Lal, Mani Lal, Ram Das, Devdas
Bhai... Bhai... Bhai l need the cooker.
- Hari Lal, Mani Lal
- Ram Das
- Devdas
- And Devdas
Wow! that's absolutely right.
Thank you... Thank you
Now third question
What was the difference among
the weapons of Gandhi and Hitler?
- lron
- lron, are you sure?
Justice and peace
Give me the lron
Well done Murli
What was the age of
Gandhi when he got married?
- 13 years
Thirteen years
Hey Keep this Madam
Kastoor was also thirteen
Bhai (Brother), Bhabhi
(Madam) was 13 years old
When they got married
See the tragedy of life
Why? Bhai, still a bachelor
What kind of noise is this?
They're my family members
They are little bit angry...
They said that you'll get marry because
Bhai was being married at thirteen
All that's on is wrong
- Quite you
- l'm going to call police
l'll can't let this happen
- Go
- l'll can't let this happen
- What's your name notebook?
- Office Ranta Shawati Kurti.
Look Woti Kuti, Help
each other in the life
...You've all the
information regarding Bapu
and we don't have it,
that's why l need it...
Right or not?
lf you need the information
of Shakeel Haira, Dagro...
...Dada, Afzal Tonda then
ask us we'll not refuse you
...Swear
Why are you hiding the knowledge?
... instead of spreading it
That's wrong and l'm
not let you to do that
l'm going to call the police
- Your cloth's are wet...
- That's wrong
- Forget it
Dry clean, Keep him dry... ...Bhai wins
This year our first caller Murli
Parsad Sharma win this contest
Janvi Ji, l'm the biggest
fan of Bapu (Gandhi)
Then Mulri whish you best of
luck for tomorrow at studio
l'm dying to meet you
Me too.
- Good bye Mr. Sharma
- Good Bye Janvi
Bhai wins
Bhai, How she looks like?
But how can he's able to see her
- lf she's tall or short
- Heavy or slim in size
Bhai you're taking the risk
you're going to mad
Hey lnquiry where is
Bhabi Ji (Brother's wife)
- Bhabi Ji (Brother's wife)
- Janvi Ji
My self Murli Parsad
Sharma contest winner
He stands first... First...
She is waiting for you over there
Good morning
Hello
l can't here your voice
Who's speaking
l'm Murli Pardas Sharma
Can't here you from
where are you talking
l'm talking from outside
l'm Jainpur
So Ok! what song you
would like to listen
To see a boy then
Alright my friend from
Jainpur your song is...
...coming up right after
this commercial break
Circuit... Move from here
What happens Bhai?
l'm not willing to meet her
But why Bhai?
My first impression is very bad
l say hello... hello in the air
in front of that sound proof glass
l'm an idiot she's thinking that
Bhai don't speak Mamoon (ldiot),
today's you said Bapu (Gandhi)
Tinchu Lequage, Go from here... Go...
Go outside, do anything you want to do
An emergency meeting is on... Go...
- l'm failed
- What happened Bhai?
lsn't she good looking?
No... She's pretty
Artistic eyes
What do you say that
hair fall on your cheek?
- Shandy (Hair)
- No
- Curl... curl... curl...
- curl...
That one curl moving on her cheek
Pat her cheek with love
Then... then... then... then...
Then she arrange her curl
with her finger behind her ear
l lost my heart
You're a jam Bhai
lf you hit somebody then
he's also loose his heart
Don't take any kind of tension
Full confidence
Talk with politeness
and with full confidence
Who's he?
ln means polite in Hindi
Professor Tell me that.
He said that, Bapu (Gandhi) do
so many works with politeness
Can you stop for a while
But
l'm requesting you with
full politeness that...
...wait for a while why
are you spoiling our meeting
We also do politeness
l know that with politeness
work has been done
- Carry On
- Use your words precisely
Like this our country is ruined
You can say that our
country is insolvent
Bhai use some profound words
Like, revolutionize
self-esteem
- Like this
- More words
And talk less regarding Bapu (Gandhi)
We don't know sufficient about Bapu
we'll be ruined
We'll be embarrassed
- So regarding Bapu
- Your's...
Who are you?
Are you Murli Parsad Sharma?
l'm Polite
Then who is Murli Parsad Sharma?
l'm
Then who is polite?
- What do you want?... Because Janvi
Madam is looking for Murli Parsaad Sharma
Then Get a side...
What are you talking?
- Hey... Turn on the radio
- Come outside
Good morning Mumbai
Welcome back to you
favorite show today...
we're with Mulri Parsad
Sharma in our studio...
How can you know that
much about Gandhi Ji?
You can say that, l'm
a very big fan of Bapu
What kind of man he is, alone
he get rid over english men
Means he ruined them
Not ruin... insolvent... insolvent
What a man!
- What sir?
- ls this our Munna?
- Yes
- Rise the volume
What do you think that people
are forgetting them now a days?
Absolutely not...
Due to his honor we celebrate
Dry day on 2nd October
l can't drink if that's not a dry day
No jokes apart, are
you following his way?
Yes l do... every day
l walk three kilometers
on Mahatma Gandhi Road
l means to say that, are you
following his set of laws?
Total... l'm a true follower
You mean that you're a Gandhi devotee
Total and you?
Me, not really
But l like some of his rules
Like?
Like l never lie
Then we're thinking on the same lines
We'll meet regularly
You never lie?
Once in 1992
A kid lost his 50 paisa and he is crying
l gave him mine 50 paisa
and said that's your
Mark my words he's
heading towards politics
What do you do?
l'm a professor
Professor
l'm teaching history
l mean your language?
What can l do the language
of the country is ruin...
.... means insolvent
Nobody can understand the real Hindi
He can say that every thing is changed
lt seems that one could
bare a heart attack
You means that intentionally
you use that kind of...
...language which is easily
understandable by the students
Correct
That's every one stood
first in his class
No one stood 2nd
Well from today l'm also
following the same style, what...
...kind of song you would like
to dedicate to your students?
Any kind of rocking song.
Fantastic Show really professor!
Hope, my kids listen that
- Your children
- Yes l have six children
Bhai... Bhai... we got to go
l'm Sarkeshwar
l'm a student
Alright! Pull-up the chair, be seated
Sit down... Sit down
Meet My Children
are they cute?
- Look... Look
- They are really cute
They are expert like
you in Gandhi devotee
- Who're these people?
- My grandpa's college friends?
They've difference among their
families so grandpa invite them at home
They live at your place?
2nd innings home named by grandpa
He Said that, this is the last over of
the life so play it on the front foot
Correct!
Your grandpa is great!
l wants to meet him?
Actually can you give him
a lecture on Gandhi Ji?
- Lecture on Gandhi Ji
- Yes they love it
- How about Friday?
- Day for the college
- Then Saturday...? -
Yes - There's a tension
Sunday is done.
That's great
So l'll see on Sunday
l've to rush now my 7th
child is coming today
- Ok bye! See you! see you then!
- Thank you... Thank you
Dad! l hope you understand
lf you stay alone that is
better for you and Bindu
Don't worry about myself
All of them are my friends
We'll enjoy together
You'll take care of your wife
you spend your life with her
How much l'll live?
Then what? can l come in?
No... No... l can do it by myself
Dad... Dad... l getting very late ok.
Son lf you get some
time then remember me
l brought up four children
in single room house
And now they don't have a single room
in there four houses for there father
You spend two hours for telling this
What's new in it?
lt a same story of every home
How is he crying?
Like a girl
The water problem of the country will...
...solve if all the aged
are going to cry like you
Give him the corner room
he is going to disturb us
l'm serious...
...and you think that l'm kidding
The serious talks are
restricted in 2nd innings house
- 2nd innings house
- Look Atma Ram
We played our 1st innings
in search of food and shelter
Now in our 2nd innings die trying...
... or find a way for life
l'll travel by an aero plane just once
l'll pay a visit to Lahore
before passing away...
l'll like to see my home and my streets
l want to be a singer
l wish to see my photograph on a
cassette cover before passing away
l wish to marry again
before l'm passing away
Marry... are you able
to bat in this age?
l practiced Atma Ram
Grandpa, l arrange a professor
for your friends on Sunday
Very good... very good
He'll deliver you a lecture on Gandhi Ji
You all need it.
Bhai, don't get tense
Professor's will make the
key and putting it in...
...your pocket and pasting in you
leg and drop it in you underwear
Put it in my underwear?
They ask questions and
l put my hand in my...
...underwear and take out
the key and answer them
You're talking nonsense.
Ajeet why are putting you hand
in you underwear frequently
We use the phone
They ask the question
and you said l'll be back
Call us from the washroom
- Professor's will answer the questions
- How many times l go to the washroom?
That is not operated by the phone
Bhai then there is only one way
And there is no other way
The other radio station...
over there is an item Anphwa Choppra...
You meet her
She talk about the
Shahrukhan all day long
Granted her children are
the fan of Dalip Kumar
You can take care of them
Stop this nonsense.
Let me think
Bhai we don't have any other way
We only have five day study
as much you can about Bapu
Ok! l'm leaving
Ok! Bhai...
What are you doing Bhai?
Concentrate on you studies
Bhai, l'll take care of business
- Don't take tension
- Come here
Bhai! you can go.
Hello!
Anybody around
Namshkar (hello)... l'm Harri Ram
May l help you?
Can l'm able to find
some information on Bapu?
What happens
After so many years some
one come here l' m very happy
You can find every book written
on Gandhi Ji, feel free for reading
l send tea for you
All the old books are over here
Munna
Who is it? Mohan Das Karamchand Gandhi
Look Uncle l'm up from three nights
- Don't waste my mind
- The what else do you do?
Unique just because of your age
Let me study either...
Moreover, you beat me up?
lf you slap me on my right cheek
then present my left cheek, professor.
Who tell you about that professor thing?
-Tea
- Serve it to the fancy dress
and ask him to be quite...
- To whom?
- That duplicate of Bapu
Where?
There you can't see him
Everyone crazy come over here
Who are you?
You can call me Bapu
Don't touch me
Don't be afraid, l never
harm anybody till that day
Boss, here is some problem
Are you not a soul?
You can call me spirit instead of Soul
- l'm unable to understand Baap (Father)
- Not Baap (Father), lt's Bapu (Gandhi)
You love to much with Janvi
You'll going to her home on Sunday
How can you know?
- Hari Ram
- Don't be afraid Son
- l come to help you
- Hari Ram
l'll leave because you're afraid
Whenever you need me call me
from the depth of your heart
- l'll come
- Hari Ram
What happens?
There some one over there
Who's it?
lllusion, what is this?
May times you hear voices due to the...
...mental tiredness and
the chemical imbalance
See that kind of things that's
not real... that's illumination
Mahatma Gandhi was there
l saw him over there
He's the soul of Bapu
lf there's a sprit then why
only you're able to see him
lt depends upon the mood of the sprit
From past three nights
you are researching...
...on Gandhi without
having rest and food
That's why a restless
mind show you Gandhi Ji.
What do you mean to say? that l'm Mad...
Don't worry, take this medicine
- Just a minute... Look...
Bapu said that lf l call
him from heart... he show up
l'll try
How're you Murli Parsad
Don't touch me Don't touch me
Don't be afraid son l hear to help you
Look... look over there Bapu
Now what do you think l'm mad
Nobody is over there Mr. Sharma
l see him clearly
lt's in your mind
Circuit, do you see him?
Hello Bapu... Last time
you showed up amazingly
He's scared
He's brave and he reorder so many guys
Circuit, He's over here
l'm offering him water
Bapu, would you like to have
cold rink, tea or anything?
What is this?
Don't reinforces hallucination
l'm going to slap you
Bhai Says it there it means that over...
...there, now l show
you the stars in day time
Not really but they are
you can say that Hallucination
Come here... Come here...
Bhai you may sit with Bapu
l'll take care of him
You mental hospital
What're you saying?
l know that there is no Bapu
and why are you spoiling his mind
are you making him mad?
Give me the medicine
l'll give him the doze
- Circuit...
- Bhai...
Why Bapu only shows in front you and me?
Because of you will power
he came out from the book
Just like Aladdin's lamp
l went also along with you
lt's Gandhi... that's
why he says hello to us
Don't take any kind of tension
He spent two or there
days over here and after...
...seeing the state of
our country he returns back
Don't take any tension
Why to spoil while thinking?
He said, he's going to help us
May l directed him towards
the Lucky's job of that house
Take the medicine
Murli Parsad... What favour
can Mohan Das do for you
Bapu...
- Like that Bapu
- Where's the bottle
l need your help...
l can't kill and kidnap any one
l'm weak in these kind ofjobs
No Bapu... l can do that...
Tomorrow you accompany
me at Janvi's place...
Just like that...
invisible
Like Mr. lndia
They ask about your self
you'll answer me in my ear
My history is weak
l do that favour for then
you must do a favour for me
l'll do 10 favors for you
But do this favour for me
Listen my job
Bapu promise... what ever
you said l'll do it...
l'm giving you oath
My job is not easy
Bapu, Nothing is
impossible in Mumbai for me
You work has to be done
Ok! l've to go...
l'll be there...
Circuit... No more worries
Now Grandpa ask what ever he wants
to because the history is with me
Thank you... Thank you...
l've a question Professor Saab (Mr.)
Just a minute, just a minute...
before any question we recall Bapu
Bapu... Thank you... thank you...
Take care of myself
lt's done... lt's done
Now leave it... leave it
Ask any question...
Son yesterday a youngster
through a stone in front of me...
....on the sculpture of
Bapu and break his hand...
... and he's laughing
l can't understand how can l teach him?
lt's simple...
....go to his home
and take him from there
and stand him in front
of Bapu's sculpture
And...
And give him a stone and ask
him to brake my whole sculpture
What're you saying Bapu?
Say what l said...
Are you sure?
Give him a stone and ask him
to brake his whole sculpture
Lay down every sculpture
of mine in this country
lay down all the sculpture
of Bapu in the country
Take off my all picture from the walls
Take off all the pictures
of Bapu from the walls
Remove my name from every building,
every roundabout, every road
Remove his name from every
building, every note, every road
l you want to keep me then
keep me in your hearts...
lf you want to keep him
then keep him in your hearts
Understand...
Over here... ln you heart...
He do so many things for us...
He's go to Jail, do fastening and
visit the whole country in one cloth
He do a lot for us
and what we do for him
put his portrait on the wall
and beneath it we take bribe easily
He think we made our country stronger...
just like developing countries
and we ruined this country
Son, that's not so bad
Country is developing now these days
What kind of development?
Tap without water
electric bulbs without electricity
Roads with less
vehicles and more gullies
You can't walk on the
footpath because of the shops
Names are on the
waiting list of the train
Train will be cancel
if the ticket is confirm
Hospitals are without beds
lf the bed is available
then there is no one for care
Nobody going to solve your complaints
Ask the minister and
he recommends Bapu....
and Bapu is busy in meeting
Call him at home and
he is in the bathroom
When he'll meet you he
ask for an application...
that will be in duplicate form
and then that application
will in the process
Round and round.... Round and round...
lf Bapu is present today...
then he said that, country is ours...
but the people are departed
Thank you... Thank you.... Thank you...
Thank you... Thank you....
Hey Professor?
are you in love with her
What? l can see it in you eyes...
How can that possible?
Don't lie
You don't have control on your eyes
Eyes see towards her side and
your head faces on the other
l've problem with my eyes
are you afraid to tell her?
Right...
Me too...
- What?
Look this...
This is Tina...
She is my college fellow
l'm willing to marry her
My Papa Says, lf you marry with a...
...Non-Parse then
l'll Kick out from home
Then l married with Ferozah
l meet Tina after 50 years
Her husband and Ferozah are no more
Then marry her
Children says, Dad don't embarrass us
Listen to your father
first then children
l do have my so l left
my home and come here
Then what's the tension
How can l say her that l love you
- l don't understand
- lsn't she says you that she loves you?
l think so
Look it... lt's 50 year's old
That's the same car
Yes, lt's raining like
dogs and cats that day
lt's to dark and on the back
seat of that car l kissed Tina
- She ran off
- You...
Ask for the keys if you ever need it
lsn't this a lovely car Murly
Ask why we name it kissing car?
lf you want to go for a drive then go
Any song might be the
reason to call Bapu
- Look over there
- you sing love songs over here
And Janvi fallen in
love with some one else
To whom Bapu
- There's a professor
- Who's he Bapu?
- Some professor
- Tell me the name? l'm going to hit him
Professor Murli Parsad Sharma
What Bapu? are you kidding with me
That true my son she's fallen in
love with that professor not you
Tell her the truth tomorrow, she'll
leaves you one day if you'll lie
lf l tell her the truth
then she'll leave me tomorrow
You promise me that
you do a favour for me
What kind ofjob is this?
tell me some otherjob
That's my job, walk on the line of truth
Circuit! Show him the way of his home
Bapu... Hey Bapu...
Lets go Bapu... Lets go
lt's not right to walk
alone in Mumbai... Let go
- Circuit
- Where're you looking at?...
- Bapu is over here
- Son, speak truth
and live with honor
Bapu, why are you
wandering here and their
if we miss the last local
train then we go by taxi
Circuit... you are drunk
Take his hand and go
l can't see him then how
can l'm able see his hand
l find Bapu... Let's go
Bapu, wandering at late
night must effect your health
and make dark circle beneath you eyes
Sit down... Ok... bye bye....
Drop him...
- Whom l'll drop
- l don't know
The path you choose brings
trouble for you one day
That day call me l'll come
- Hello
- Yes Janvi
- Hey Murli, where are you?
- ln college
- yes
- l'm taking class
- Guess what
l'm in your college
- But why?
- To meet with principal
- Why?
- First meet me then l'll let you know
Look, l'm coming don't
meet with principal
Why?
Look... wait for me in the
canteen l'll be there in 10 minutes
Ok... Please
Ok... Relax... l'm waiting you over here
Circuit... lt emergency... Move
- Hello Janvi
- Hi Murli
Look don't trust on this principal
he's very talkative, sometimes
he's going to unbearable
- ln my class, he asked who are you?
- Relax
- Why are you so exited?
- Excuse me
Just a minute l'm busy
unmannered... you come to
college once in three months
And you sit in the canteen all the day
- Go... - Who's he? - Go
in... - He... He's a professor
- Who's he
- Must be his father
But why you meet with principal
Tomorrow is the birthday Atama Ram
Ji and l through a surprise party
Atma Ram... dropped by
his son in front of home
Humm... Hari
Hey barber shop... Go...
He miss him a lot
Continuously he dial his
phone and he don't respond
and don't call him back
- Good morning Sir
- Good morning... Good morning
- Bye bye sir...
- Bye bye... Bye bye
- Do you know that principal...
- Good morning professor
- Good morning...
- Good morning... Good morning
Wow... Professor your style of teaching
He's going to spoil the whole scene
l'm little bit busy Dobay Ji
You will be the principal... Principal
Do you see the principal?
ls he look like a principal
He's a fool, do you see his
wearing he's look like a laundryman
- We all are laundrymen in front of him
- Mr. Dobay
Madam Phatkehli is calling you
Thank you Bye....
- Who's she Madam Phatkay
- l'm going to slap you
25 paisa Chicken and 75 paisa powder
That much over acting move from here
- Good morning sir
- Good morning
- Do you know what to do?
- Yes Bhai
Hello
l talk with Harri, He said he can't come
Atma Ram ji is really low
l really wants to cheer him up
- Ask principal to call the police
- Police
Without any reason he can't leave me
But what's the principal
connection with this story
Principal and Atma
Ram ji are old friends
l'm going to invite him
l think that all the
friends enjoy together
That principal is a very depressing
person, he attempt suicide three times
Take less food instead of sleeping pills
Tino... l'm Shyam
Look towards you glasses
you're confused due to black shirt
Hey... Where is he...
Do you see him? Call the police...
Call the police... Call the police...
- Call the police...
- Look at him...
Student don't done his home
work and he's calling police
Right now he's over
here right now he ran off
- He's the principal
- Bhai Let's go
- Sir should we start the class
- Sir should we move
Now l've to go because
the 2nd class is on
Don't get tense, l'll bring a...
...surprise which
makes Atma Ram Ji happy
- Hey You
- l'm coming sir... coming
Hey Full moon will like to race
Let's Go... Come...
You get prepared for the
birthday you need smile...
...on Atma Ram's Ji face
its my problem now its done
hey Taxi...
Where is he...?
- l'm looking for Harri Desai
- Your name?
- l'm Murli Parsad Sharma
- What kind of work?
lt's private
He's in a meeting if you have
any message then give it to me
Tell him that the work has been done...
...that dead body is in the trunk
of the car behind the bungalow
l'm here for the payment
Where are the office?
don't take tension
Ok Fine, we'll meet in theater
on Sunday, remember 3 to 6
Make it 6 to 9
5'o clock is you father's birthday
You bring the cake and write
on it happy birthday Papa
Ok, See you on Sunday... bye...
You... How can you come in?
From the door, are you
coming from the window?
Ok leave this... what kind
of a gift you bring for him
Look, please don't interfere,
it's my family matter
- Ok
- Don't show your anger on birthday
How many birthdays of
your father celebrated...
...for you just come for half an
hour and say happy birthday to him
Smile will be on his face all day long
- Please Come with...
- Yes... Go.... Go...
Tank you very much... After
you... Good bye... Get out...
- What do you mean by get out?
- Out
You didn't want to understand that...
You want to fight me...
You want to fight me... C'mon...
You know l was used
to be a boxing champion
lf you're a boxing champion
then l'm a slapping champion
Little bit up... little bit left...
That's Uncle fault, if he slaps you
six and seven times your childhood...
... then today's not come.
Hello... Hello... Bindu
- What...?
- How are you honey?
- where are you?
- l'm outside from my office.
Do one thing... Order a birthday cake
and happy birthday Dad will write on it
... and beneath it write
Haari you beloved son
Darling... lsn't it necessary?
Honey try to understand he's my father
But darling
Just shut up do what l say organize...
...a birthday party
and buy an expensive...
...gift and send the
carpenter at my office l...
...need to fix some grills
into my balcony Urgent...
- Now take it off
- Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday dear Atma Ram
Happy birthday to you...
You're the best dad ever
We forget you never
Happy birthday to you dearest dad
Happy birthday to you...
How can you do that?
l go to his office and
teach him with politeness
and he understand
He fought if l was not there
He's going to slap him and hang him
upside down from a 12 story building
- Then he can't come
- This is really unbelievable
- Thank you so much Murli
l've another surprise for you?
Can you accompany me
for an hour, tomorrow?
Where?
Bobby Uncle, can l have your car keys
Lucky l hear this, that in every
2 seconds a child is born in lndia
Might be then?
That means in each second
some one going to marry
Then?
Then in every half second a boy
tells his heart feeling to a girl
lt's up to 2 months and
l don't have guts to talk
What to talk?
- That
- l mean that...
- What that....
That... That l like you very much
Will you be my wife?
Do that work which suites you
...evacuate the bungalow, break the bones
and l'll talk to her father for your marriage
Her father died, she lived with
some six or seven aged peoples
Where she live?
We don't know where she lives
He don't take us over
their, he went alone
That's the address and that will
be the house which will be evacuated
Give it to me... Sir Ji if they don't
have the address then how come they find it
Like you born in this
worried without any address
Ask you mother you born
with a map in your hand
Munna you leave this
work, you need to relax
Do one thing, take her and move to Goa
Goa!
lt's a very romantic
place, Sea waves, on them...
...a motorboat and both
of you are in that boat
All alone...
Girls are very emotional
Take her far away to the sunset and
ask her marry me or leave the boat
lt's my boat, she's not
die alone in the water
Why she go alone with us?
No... No... No... Not alone
Take all the aged along with you
Koko my dear, arrange the Goa air
tickets and hotel l'll pay the dues
lf You consider me as friend
don't think go to Goa and...
...don't come back without
give her the engagement ring
l'll evacuate the house
Ok
- Done
- No and yours
l call her and she's out Saroon says
Why she's left with a smiling face
What you think it's a joke
What...? You're just bamboozle
You go to tell her a joke in the car
- Give me the keys
- lt's in the car
Careless bugger, you left the
keys in the car idiot... stupid...
Hurry up, pack your bags
we're leaving for Goa
- Goa... Goa... Goa...
- But why...?
A wedding ceremony
Wedding... Who's wedding?
You tell them l can't
All of you favour that or not?
No... No... but we want to
know who's wedding is this
- Listen... Listen...
- No... No...
Who's marriage tell us?
- l can't tell
- Where you people going?
Tell us, we'll not say anything
Tell us what's the matter it is?
Why you can't tell me
who's wedding is this?
- who is he?
- Surprise gift
- Bobby's Tina
- Yes
- Janvi
- Hi Murli
l wants to tell some important thing
Come down please
What?
What're you looking for?
Something important
This ring?
How can you find this ring?
- will you give it to some one?
- lt's a ladies ring it
means l'll give it to some one
That means you like a girl in Goa
Yes
- Her name starts from 'M'
- My name starts from 'M'
Then it's starts from
'J', l'm so jealous
- Don't take tension
- Lucky girl
lf l like some one
that means she is lucky
Off course Murli
Janvi l've to tell you
a very important thing
First give this to that 'J'
then tell me your important thing
lt's very important to tell
her before giving her the ring
Then tell her?
Janvi, don't say no
lf the answer is No
then about turn and go
But don't say No
l don't say No
Janvi, from my heart l'm...
- Take it... take it
- Sorry
Hello.... What...
When...
Who can do this?
Murli someone enter in
the home and evacuating it
Hello... call the police right now
Which builder from where...?
- Hello Bhai, where are you Bhai...
- someone entered in janvi's home
l'm going to kill him
He can't enter his own home
you just give me the address
- Look... That Versowa
- l'm in Versowa, don't take tension
- Which road?
- Jetty road...
Jetty road... l'm on Jetty road...
Ram Bhova take out the vehicle
Plot no. 22 yellow bungalow
Which.... Which plot Bhai?
Plot no. 22, hurry up?
- We're evacuating this house
- Are you going mad
What can we do Bhai, Lucky
Singh ask as to do that
Enough... paste film stars
in these kind of poses
paste our leaders and
politicians in these kind of poses
And l want one with Queens of U.K.
Like this pose only as it is pack
Go...
Why are you so happy?
- Yes
- l got the 2nd innings house
How can you get it...? Khorana
Ji is trying for it since 2 years
He do business with consultation
of his fortune teller
l tell him don't put
this project over here
But No, He said Maharaj says that
it'll be here then what can l do?
He purchased 7 billion
rupees land around this house
lf he unable to buy this house
then these 7 billion will be wasted
Sir Ji, Khurana here? What timing...
Look his smiley face
when l'll show him the key
2nd innings house is yours
Consider it a wedding gift
Lucky Sing Ji, this
wedding can't be done
What're you saying?
l make the horoscope of
your daughter she's unlucky
- Then...?
- lt means if that wedding is on then...
- Sunny will be destroyed
- My daughter will turn any home into heaven
and make all the family decease
lt's very clear in the horoscope
that if this wedding will happens
Sunny can't live more then a year
That's confirm...
- Khorana Ji... ln this century
- l can't ignore his fortunetelling
What ever we are today it's
just because of Battook Maharaj
We lost our factories
He said, put one more 'K' in Khorana
Look... today where're we
lf your daughter born after few
hours then the fate will be different
Bad timing Ji...
lf you gave birth to simran after
5 minutes then the date was changed
How can date been changed
Simran was born at 1 1 :55 correct
- Yes
lf you hold on for five more minutes
then 7 April changed in to 8th April
- Understand my words?
- One minute... One minute
Your daughter was born
at 1 1 :55am in morning
No... No... at 1 1 :55 pm
- lt was night
- No... No... you tell me... Look...
Look that...
lsn't it written over here
Subramanian Chacha
Subramanian
Our typist now he's def
He's lip-read the dictation
am, pm shows same in lip-read am, pm
lt's a big problem
He writes lawyer as liar and
risky business as whiskey business
Once l tell him that wrote down the
cement Supplier ''send us an email''
He wrote, Send us a female
and he sends because of the order
Very embarrassing situation in office
Koko buy a big machine
for Subramaniyum's ear
Who's Subramaniyum?
Buy two machine for both ears,
its doesn't makes any difference
lf l whisper, he can
get me loud and clear
Thank Koko... Thanks...
lt's a pleasure that Simran is unlucky
Aunty... What a time of
her birth... Well done...
- Now take the keys
- No... No... wait a minute
Key will be taken on
wedding day at 10:27 pm
Ok... Offer them sweets...
Offer them sweets...
Congrats... Congrats....
Final... Final...
That's it deal it done...
- You know that
- What?
That Janvi lives in that bungalow
You cheat me and send me to Goa
Tomorrow if l'll enter in you
house and says that's mine then
Look... Look Madam, property
liaison paper are on his name
He's having the possession
You must serve a notice
before transferring the liaison
Look BMC must serve you a notice
you check it from the post office
Oye Munna, house has
been evacuated peacefully
lt's don't look nice to
have a fight with aged
Look... l'll give you a flat in Vevar
Fresh air... Good for Health flat
Give it to her from your side
- She'll be happy
- You don't help us
Look Madam we can't do
anything, go and hire a lawyer
Go
Give me the bungalow keys
Look Munna.... Listen...
l give my words to Khurana
lt's the matter of my Simran's wedding
Don't shatter it
Look Lucky if you need this then l'll
evacuate the bungalow of chief minister for you
But please leave this bungalow for me
You leave that girl for me
l'll arrange your marriage
with some Miss. lndia... Happy
Don't put Janvi in it... Lucky
Yes or No
Your love at one side and
my business at the other
- Don't mix it
- You mix it Lucky
Now l'll take over that bungalow
Today l takeover the bungalow
What ever you wants to do, do it?
Who take them to Goa?
You... Who evacuate the
house...? Your friend...
Professor Saab should l
tell her about your subjects
- Hello
- Hello...
Hello... Baloo is there
- Wrong Number
- Sorry wrong number
Now you can go and do
what ever you wants to do
Take a side
Just chill Chill... Just chill...
Just Chill chill... Just Chill...
Sorry Bhai, we done a mistake
l'll call you but l think
that l going disturb you
lt's a small job and
l here as a care taker
Bhai why are you spoiling your mood
Leave it now...
Bhai, l'll going to explain
her, don't get tension
Don't get any tension
What're you going to explain...?
That l'm a gangster,
that's what you explain
Not single job can be done correctly
How are you?
Take to much time to call me
Look Bapu first time in
my life l'm stuck like this
Save me right now with
the help of any idea
- There is only one solution
- what?
Kidnap Lucky's daughter
and then bargain with him
l rejected this idea yesterday
Then fire four bullets
in the chest of Lucky
Bapu do you've any problem with me
Why you gave me all the false ideas?
They're not mine there're your's ideas
You can do as same till today
You can't follow my path
...there is no need to ask you
Ok... Ok Bapu, lets carry on
tell me about your way
l can try this
- You can't do that
- Why not Bapu?
l'm very much daring
My way is not easy but
it's confirms success
- can l get the bungalow
- l'll give you my words
- Janvi will not leave me
- She moves with honor besides you
You do have that much confidence
then ask me what to do?
- Ask for forgiveness
- Forgiveness
To whom?
lt's necessary to ask for forgiveness
l wants to see your courage
What?
lt's easy to slap but it's need
courage to ask for forgiveness
This not the rite job for looser
Go son...
- What are you doing over here?
- Nothing Bhai
Since morning l'm Missing
mom so that's why l'm here
l've to say something to you
- Yes Bhai... Say it
- Don't think that l'm drunk
- What happen Bhai?
- Turn this side
Don't see in my eyes
l want to say sorry
l can't sleep at night all the past
memories are revolving in my mind
Remember that, when l was
hit by a bullet in my bally
l can't sleep at night
l said to you that l missing Mom
You take care of my emotions
and l slapped you
l'm also mad
l wish to eat Chinese
at 3 o'clock midnight
And you kidnapped the
Chinese from a five star hotel
He cooked very delouses noodles
and l Slapped you
Forgive me friend
Don't speak like that
l'm sorry
Bapu... Thank you Bapu...
My heart is light now
Now what do to do next?
- Lucky will be handled politely
- This job is really hard
Don't take tension, Bapu is here
Look... Lakhbair Singh
do something erroneous
- What can we do know?
- Madam we're here
First we file the suit
lllegal possession of property,
we show him our strength
But how much time it'll
take to get back our house
At least 15 years
No... No Madam not more then six months
- Why we are here
- Give me grantee
- More or less 2 or 4 months
- 2 or 4
More or less
Look... this is a matter
of court and law...
Sometimes mishaps happens like
transfer of Judge, dates, we're not sure
- Give me a total
- 4 to 5 years
Ok take six years but write it down
No... No lawyer can write this on paper
You ask for six months and can't
give the grantee of six years
- Go... Move from here
- Where
- l arranged a lawyer
- What lawyer?
He's a great lawyer, he studied in
London and practiced in South Africa
He said, don't use harm
ways be a Gandhi devotee
That Ghuju Swine.... Taking
over my clients from the gate
- lf enemy gives you harm then give him a smile
- Ghuju Said this?
Hey Said that, lf someone slaps you on your
left cheek then give him your right cheek
lf you do that, it controls
his anger and raze your respect
He also said, if you try win's your enemy
heart then there is no need of lawyers
Who said this? Who said that?
Move...
Murli, what are you doing
- Gandhi fellowship
- Means
opposite of bully
Lucky thinks we going to fight
with him but we do the opposite
l'll send him the flowers
Good Morning Pops
Junior Khorana sends red roses for you
Sunny send this, that impossible
Why? do you have a fight with him
With Sunny... Never...
Then?
Batook Maharaja tells khoranas
that roses are unlucky for them
Khorana uncle, cut all
the roses of his home
and he changed the name of her
sectary from ross to chambali
How can sunny bare his father
because his father is a good man
He's a little bit
superstitious, but its ok
Little bit... without any fortune
decision he can't go to washroom
Already he placed two ''KK''
before his name now l don't...
...understand should l call
him Khorana or K...Khorana
lf behave like him will bare me
You also expose your self all day
Like this... Like that.... Like this
Then sometimes with
Ashwerya, Bush and Queen
But l still love you
Because you are a good man
Come here... Come here...
One Minute
- Then who send these flowers?
- Might be you beloved sectary send them
- Don't be ashamed
- Mom
Dad that's for you a get well soon card
What happens to your health?
l've a gastric problem
in my stomach that's all
Now she's sending the get well soon card
along with flowers for your gastric problem
Munna Send these
Don't touch.... Don't touch...
might be he placed a bomb in it
Every get down... Duck....
Stop it POP, something is written in it
My lawyer said that, fraud is a disease
You don't know how much that infects you
l'm going to cure you till
that time you'll be alright
look from you window... Munna
Talk.... Talk...
That hard night will be over
and Lucky you going to loose it
- What kind of drama it this Munna?
- That's the right way
- We're not going to fight you till that time
- Till when...
that you're doing wrong
One should be present in front of your home
if one slips down the other will fill his place
We'll pray for your cure
Get well soon Lucky
Go... and get our home keys
- Come here
- Yes sir
- Hello
- Beat them all
- No... No...
Bapu says, if enemy hits you on you
right cheek then present him the left one
Here it is... Look nothing is happens
Bhai he done it
When slapped on both
cheeks then what to do?
That's not addressed by the Bapu
Munna, let them do...
But you don't fight them
That changes the mood of your enemy
His odium decreases and
increases you respect
Show him that we can't hit him
Neither we're going to leave our path
Go Munna and ask him for forgiveness
We'll take back the house
with peace, if you do...
...some thing wrong then we
going to give you a bamboo
- Say sorry to him
- But why Bhai?
Look... Bapu says if l do this then it'll
decrease there odium and increase our respect
- Say sorry to him
- Bapu going to shatter our business
- l'm sorry
- Now get up we're sorry
Get up or l'm going to hit you
- Bhai
- Yes
We take over 1 15 houses
52 Kidnappings
More of less we broke 250 bones
but never sentence to jail
First time... First time...
We say sorry to some one
and sentence to jail
Public going to laugh at us
Our reputation is ended
lf you sentenced to jail after murdering
some one then it'll increases your respect?
But the must charged us in kidnapping
Do you know that...?
Bapu only made the salt
and he sentence to jail directly
- What about his reputation
- No...
His reputation increases buy
the which he spent in the jail
because he's right
lf we sentence to jail after
doing right things then...
Then our sculpture will
place in the park after death
Our photo will on each note
Roads named after us
Our stories publish in the text books
Chapter Six, Munna and Circuit
Leader's quote us
Munna and Circuit will
remebere till Armageddon
- On our birthday...
- Bank holiday
All the country celebrate dry day
- No... No...
- No... No... dry day
You are free to go now, you're bailed
Thank you...
You bailed us
No Murli, Thank you...
You jailed because of us
Emotional movements
One night is enough or you
need the sentence for whole life
- Then a city will named after us
- Yes
Naag Pur... Kan Pur... Munna Pur
Ahmedabad... Hyderabad... Circuitabad...
Jam Nagaar... Ullas
Nagaar... Munna Nagaar...
- Why are you worried
- you underestimate our strength
l've police, power and
money, what do you have?
l've Bapu Uncle...
and l've the radio
Well Come.... Mumbai, welcome
to our new show Bapu's Magic
Before 100 year a noble
man was came in our country
Mohan Das Karam Chand Gandhi
Bapu taught us the right way of living
Today we all are forget this
Consider this that Bapu
is with me in the studio
lf you've any problem in your life then
ask me l'm going to solve it like he do
ln return we need your support
- Our one friend is very sick
- He is in l.C.U
But he's not ready for treatment
lf you all tries then he'll understand
- Then give us a call
- Bapu that's live
Please understand...
Wow... Our first call
- Dropped
- No... Dropped intentionally
- Dial this number again
- Ok
- Hello
- why you disconnected?
What's the problem?
- What can you do?
- Try it my friend
- l need 7 hundred thousand rupees
- But Why?
All waste my fathers
money in share's business
My friend Says, They going to be doubled
He was saving the money to buy a home
From where l can find the money
- lt's very easy
- Simple
- How?
- Spend less and work hard
Save each penne and return them back
Look... work hard, and save the money
That's not a solution
it's takes ten years
What can l'd right now
First dare to speak the
truth in front your father
Look... dare to speak the
truth in front of your father
- lt's better that l'll suicide under a train
- Are you mad?
You do the mistake and
your father will suffer
He will be happy when
he'll see your body?
The shoulder used for your enjoyment you
want that should lead you to sanctuary
He don't believe that
you're gone for six months
He'll dial your number frequently
thinking this that
you'll receives his call
You're in no men land
Then, What can l do?
- What is your name?
- Victor
Victor D'suza
Look Victor... He's your father
Don't hide anything from
him, he's your father
One morning l wake up and l
see that my father was gone
l've a lots of thing to share with him
But l'm unable to share it
- Where is he
- ln his room
- What's he doing?
- l don't know
- Door is closed
- Open the door and get in and say...
- But
- l told you open the door and get in
Don't think... get in
Get in Victor
l told you that Open the door and get in
What happened now...? Now
you do some thing wrong again
Why are you standing like
this...? Tell me what happened
Talk
ls there any radio in the room
- Yes
- You're talking with whom
Switch on the radio
Mr. D'suza your son wants
to tell you something
All the Mumbai city is
on... Now tell him Victor
Talk...
Daddy... l wished that l can able
to tell you each and everything
Don't look sideways Victor
tell him the bottom line
Talk...
Daddy... l lost your 7 hundred
thousand rupees in share's business
Mr. D'suza don't beat him lf you slap him
he'll be afraid to speak truth in his all life
Daddy l'll quit this share's business
l'll do any job
l'll throw the newspapers, taking
Tuition so l can able to return your money
Mr. D'suza l know what're you thinking
How can he able to earn 7,00,000 while
throwing news paper's in the morning
But think that Mr. D'suza
that's your Son come back
He's going to suicide on railway track
Now you see his life
is right on the track
Dad, Uncle Frances own three cabs
everyday he needs a driver
will you recommend me
You're not feel awkward
dad if l drive a cab
- l can't drive it near by home
- Now stop this...
- You want me to cry
- Go in
Give me the phone
Hello... l don't know who are you
and l don't know what you said to my son
l only know that, my son is mature today
God bless you
Bhai he's our brother
lf you like our show then
send flowers to our sick friend
And write ''Get well soon'' on the card
- Write down the address
- 41 ....
- Hello
- What're we listening on radio?
Munna he's a gangster and he's
trying to extract some money from me
Look... lf this house is
illegal then we don't need it
l've the legal paper of that house
According to stars the house
is alright for you, so keep it
They launched a protest
in front of your house
Don't worry this protest
will ends tomorrow
Be careful... don't spoil the reputation
- Ok... Bye
Pops, are you doing everything right?
You're a good man
- Hello
- Hello Munna
Look... You're my friends that's
why this is my last and final offer
First stop this radio nonsense
and lay off the protest
ln return l've a 4 point package for you
One... for them l've a bungalow of
same size and same color but in Pune
Two... for you and her l
offered you a flat in Mumbai
Tars Flat
Three... One car with
drive in white uniform
And Four... Admission in an
english medium school for children
They learn A.B.C and going to be
real professor's.... Just think
Exact at 7:00 in morning
l'll come on the window...
lf you don't change the
geography of the road...
Then l'll tell Janvi
abut your entire history
You've all the night for thinking
Munna... and your time starts now
- What can l do Bapu....?
- Will you do what l say?
Then Janvi can't give
the importance to Lucky
Then tell me Bapu... Hurry up
You tell her the truth before Lucky do
What Bapu? Who ever
tells her l'll lost her
She leave me
But you'll fear less
to fight for her house
You'll see one day she'll come back
How can l tell her it's need courage
When l was 15 year old.. l
lift some gold of my brother
You steal Bapu
God... Then
Heat was broken and l can't sleep
l decided to speak truth to
my father then l got peace
But l was unable to dare it
Then l wrote him a letter
l admit my fault and
asked for forgiveness
Promise that l'll never
do anything wrong again
Then your father beat you up
No... he cried
and then he tear the
letter and go to sleep
Go to sleep
l was crying all the night beside him
All the life l remembered that night
Then your father forgive you Bapu?
lt took time but he forgive me
Then it's done Bapu
l'm also write a letter to her and give
it to her at 6 o'clock early morning
Why right now?
Tonight l wants to see
her with depth of my heart
Tomorrow she'll leave
At least tonight memories
be with me till she come back
Please Bapu
Don't forget at 6 o'clock in morning
Promise
What are you writing?
- Letter
- To whom?
l'm here you go and sleep
No.. Tonight l can't sleep
Do you know what Grandpa said
Child when you're sad
then close your eyes and...
...recall your happy
memories and enjoy them
then smile come back on you face
Now close your eyes
What you see?
- Radio
When you say good
morning Mumbai on radio...
Sarkehwar Says, then a
happy smile comes on my face
Say just once?
Over here... No...
- Please
- Not here Murli No Way
Good Morning........ Mumbai
Welcome to our late night show
Tonight, on this deserted street under
the dim light of sparkling stars,...
...a little bit surprised, a little bit
worried professor Mulri Parsad Sharma
Breaking news, ln his
pocket there's a love letter
Let me take a guess, whom
the professor has written to
May be to me
May be he wants to say something to
me and he's thinking how can he say
l know what he wants to say
- You don't know
- Then say it...
Not Now...
Tomorrow at 6 o'clock
l know what you say...
But l want to see how can you say it
Say it like way it'll be
remember through the life
l'll wait till 6 o'clock
Rocky...
Security... Send Munna in
Well played Munna, You
stumped all of them in one ball
Now Flat, Car and driver
Munna life is set Munna
l say marry to day
Send these flowers
You're wrong lucky l told her the truth
Now my heart is light
l've no fear of you
are you telling me the truth?
l'm thinking how can l able to
stump you and you're head wicket
Match is still on Lucky till the
time hand over me the bungalow
Alone... Your team left you
Still l've a solid player... no
googli of yours can get him out
Which Player?
Bapu
Who's FATHER?
The nation's father
Mahatma Gandhi
as the Bapu possessed you
Bapu can't walk now these days
Not on these days to
Remember this, he was
shot dead by some one
Who wins... that one who shot
him or that one who take them
Correct.... To whom dry day may observed
who give up or who take it
Correct... whom sculpture is in the park
Correct... Whom photo is on the Note
To whom you're talking to
Lucky Just a minute...
Look... l'm telling
you a top secret thing
l can see Mahatma Gandhi
What ?
Look... He's sitting beside you
How's he looking towards you
Who's looking?
Mohan Das Karamchand Gandhi
- Can you here him...
- No
- Bapu once more
- Mohan Das Karamchand Gandhi
- Can you here him...
- No
Look.... Look... Look...
lf you can't be truthful
then Bapu can't move from here
Look Munna.... you're
in the state of shock
Go home and have some rest
Lucky give me the bungalow
Why are you meddle with Bapu?
Get out.... Get out...
Tell him whatever he can do
l can't give you the house
l can break your 206 bones
and take over the house
But no... Now you can
see my Gandhi fellowship
l don't slap you neither l do bad
But l'll take it back
You'll give me the keys with smiley face
Spare some space you'll
receive too many flowers
Go... Go... Mohan Das Karam Chand Gandhi
Good Morning.... Mumbai
My friend is in coma
He can't understand what's
right and what's wrong
Look Janvi... The show must go on
lt's a big hit
Unbelievable
- Hello what's your problem?
Dad, took a boy for me
from newspaper matrimonial
He says, meet him once and decide
But how can l judge him in one meeting
He behave good in first meeting
lf you wants to judge a man then see how
can he behave with lower society people
- From where you're talking
- From restaurant
- Right now he's coming to see me
- That's very good
lf he call a waiter like....
..... this then leave him
You must be Priya
- Rahul
- Priya
- Hey
- Pleasure to meet you
What can l get for you ?
- Tea
- Sure
- Yes sir
- One coffee for me and a tea for the lady
Lady...
Where is she ?
Thanks a lot Murli, lf l spent my
whole life with then l'll passes away
People of Mumbai, wherever you see
Lucky Singh give him the flowers
and tell him to do right...
he going to get well soon
Come here...
Have them... Take it Uncle
For you it's free....
Get well soon Lucky
He lives over my flat and everyday
he come down while chewing pan...
....and when came in front of
my door he spit and then leave
lt's my desire to kill him
Do opposite.... opposite....
Let him spit...
ln return give him a smile
Then clean his spit in front of him
From three days l'm
cleaning his Spitting
he can't understand
Bapu says... have patience
One day he can admit it
Sorry...
Long live Gandhisum
Why you hand the flower's? Remove them
Do you know everything
Get well soon.... you
say get well soon to me
You get well soon
l'm a retired teacher all my life l taught
children that bribing each other is wrong
Now today, An officer ask me for 5000
He was not starting
my pension for 2 years
Now l'm... in deep trouble
Pension is your right
- His father can pay it...
- What can l do...
- You tell me ?
- Disgrace him..
Tell the peoples what he's doing
l'm giving you an idea
Hello (Namste)
This is 12 hundred
Nothing can happen in 12 hundred
why you come to mess with me
Have patience l'm giving you more
This spectacle worth five hundred rupees
This watch worth eight hundred
Diabetic tablets worth eighteen rupees
- What's this master?
- Wait... wait...
One minute
What're you doing?
Shirt worth two hundred
- Master Ji that's enough
- One minute
Master Ji
- This under west
- Worth 25 rupees
Belt worth 100 rupees
Shoes worth 300 rupees
What're you doing?
That's enough Master Ji
Please forgive me
Please forgive me,
l'm giving you the file
- Please don't do this
- Pant worth 300 rupees
l'm signing it
Moilay give him his pension
Long live Gandhisum
- Hello
- Do you listen his programme
Don't take any tension
just switch off the radio
We switch off the radio
but can't stop his voice
All the city quotes his words
Yesterday My driver spit on the road...
...and four guys came and cleaning
his spitting with smiley face
He's mentally unstable he's mad
You say's that he's a gangster
- Yes he is
- ls he gangster or mad...?
He's a mad gangster
l don't think he's mad or a gangster
All the city is supporting him
- Tomorrow he'll leave the city
- You told me this before
- Give me 24 hours
- l'll prove that he's mad
- Hey KoKo
- Yes sir
- Arrange a press conference
- Press conference
lnvite Munna to...
Tell him, l'm going to give
him the 2nd innings house
Look... l've the papers of that house
l've the possession
Legally speaking that house is mine
- Be seated
- Thanks... Thanks...
When it's came to my knowledge that
Mahatma Gandhi Ji was also interested
Then l said take the keys
That much big personality
requesting how can l refuse
Munna... Tell them you can
able to see Mahatma Gandhi Ji
That's true l'm not lying
They are like good friends
- Murli Look
- You tell them about my secret
Ladies and Gentleman he's right
l can see him in reality
l learn so much from Bapu
l'm going to beat him
But Bapu says... No...
Deal him with politeness
Win his heart
and he'll fine
Now he's fine today
Love you.... Love you
ls this a joke?
What're you saying am l talk
like this in front of him
You mean Bapu is here
Behind me with all of his due support
Silence... Silence...
Silence... Please sit down
l'll find out what is
the truth in 2 minutes
Mr. Murli Bapu will
answer my 4 questions
He knows the answers
you tell us his answers
lf he's right then we've
no option to believe you
Ok! Go ask me
- Question one... Bapu your first name?
- Mohan Das
Mohan Das
Your fathers name?
Karam Chand
Your mothers name?
You don't know the name of your mother
Tell me Bapu
Who gave you title name of Mahatma?
What is the name of your
house in South Africa?
Tell me Bapu
l'm loosing my reputation
l still have 55 seconds left
Mr. Murli Parsad Sharma is very sick
Due to a mind chemical
imbalance he's seeing Gandhi
l deal with so many cases like him
When my patience complain
they often see the dead
parents, wife or there children
lf Gandhi Ji is a reality
Then he must tell Mr.
Sharma the name of his mother
l know you read a lot about him
But you don't read every thing
He'll only answer the
questions which you know about
Your Bapu doesn't what you don't know
Now you please come here
Go Munna... Go...
There're the answers
Take it...
Read once and ask the same
questions again from Bapu
and l'm sure he'll answer
Try it out
- Mother's name
- Putaly Bai
- Title name...
- Rabinder Nath Teagure
- South Africa house...
- Tallesti Farm
Get well soon Munna
- Circuit
- Yes Bhai
Circuit do you see him?
Yes Bhai
Right now you see him
can you see him?
Look... there're going there
Hello Bapu how're you?
You lied
Why you lies? Tell me...
- What can l say Bhai?
- That l'm mad
That doctor was right that l
have mental chemical disbalance
- No Bhai
- l was mad to walk in his footsteps
- l'm mad
- No... No... Bhai
Circuit, there's no Bapu
lt's chemical disbalance
- l'm mad...mad
- No... No.. Bhai
Bhai everything will be fine you go home
l don't want to live here
l want to go to my village
Right Now...
Greeting... Greeting
- To you to...
Tell me what will you in the village?
You don't know how to reap
Bhai l do everything
then what will bull do?
Bhai... Bhai... l've an idea
We're going to become a
professor in the village
Teaching history Bhai
We don't know about the history
The villagers don't know either
- Circuit
- Yes Bhai
l'm missing Janvi very much
- Bhai May l turn the car around
- Yes turn around
- Listen.... Listen to me...
- What?
Simran is not in her room
- Let's Go
- Where?
Any where
- Get a side
- Hello Uncle Ji
- Hello
don't like him
Under west should l call your mother
You wish to marry with somebody else
Stop the car
l say stop it
Listen... l don't tell her
Greetings... Greetings...
Get a side
- What you say?
- Well l said..
- What?
- lf somebody going to ask about you
...birth time then tell
him that it's am not pm
- Tell her everything
- Yes
Go... Jump in front of the train
You came for that
Your mother will cry a lot
She selected this dress
Yes
She selected it
Papa ruining all that
What can you do?
What's the problem
Say something
What can you do?
l've a friend who can do everything
Janvi
Talk with him just once
Local passes after every 2 minutes
What the rush to die
Look... l just want
to talk to Janvi once
- Then good bye Mumbai
- She's gone for the day
You call her from you phone, please...
She don't talk with you
Then l'll talk to her on radio
Get a side
- Get a side...
- Murli... Murli... Murli... Wait...
l tell you that he is
going to talk on radio
- So guys have a blast
- Hey Uncle come out
l wants to talk with Janvi
Hey you get out
Today's no politeness
lf somebody moves l'm going
to make a hole in his head
Hey watchman stay over there
Good Morning.... Mumbai
Ladies and Gentlemen
this is my last show
But only for Janvi
Now turn of your radios
l wants to talk with Janvi in private
- Private
- Janvi
l leaving for the village
permanently after retirement
Before leaving l wants to meet you
Please
- Hello Janvi
- Hello Murli
- Who's this
- l'm Victor... Victor D'suza
Hey... Hey victor my friend...
Look... you call me after 2 minutes
l'm in a private meeting with Janvi
lt's an emergency Murli
You again spent the money
Sir Ji, switch on the radio
Simran is on air
l can't lie and marry
l'll laid my demands
This necessary for them to know
lf something go wrong with
him after the marriage then
l won't able to forgive myself
Take a tour of the city you
see so many cursed peoples
Wife's tired to serve
them but they're still on
Look... don't believe on this mess
l don't believe but they do
Papa should tell them the truth
l hate my father
Don't talk like this
He's you father
lf l'm going to you his name
you'll say the same thing
Don't haul up your
father name in the public
l Know who is he?
He's sick
Help him...
Don't leave him like this
He do all this for your happiness
He was my hero
l never think that he lie to me
My father is a cheat
l'll never go back
Quite...
ln your childhood when you
lied then he ran off in a cab
- No...
He's trying to teach you
Punish You
But always he'll be with you
Just like a solid person
Go... Back
l'll go back then
there'll be a demonstration
lf don't go then there'll
be double demonstration
and alone your father will bare it
ln the time of hardship if somebody
leave you l know how it seems
But l don't lie and marry
Go back and tell them the truth
Your work will be finish
Let me think what to do with them
Uncle will not understand
Tell me one thing
Did he loves you, that much you love him
l think so
Then l'll take the grantee
This marriage will go on
Hey Victor take her back
Uncle... l wants to say something
What it is?
l'll lay down my demand
- But that horoscope...
- That's wrong...
Why you telling this right now
l don't lie and marry
Now what do you think?
Now you tells the truth and marry
- l love him uncle
- Get out
Get out before l slap you
Let's go...
What happens Victor?
Guest are leaving Murli
How can they leave?
Don't go any where l'm coming
till that time hear this song....
Hey uncle
You're doing a big mistake
You can never able to find
a girl like her for your son
Which girl going to dare this
in front of that much public?
lf she born at 1 1 :55pm
then its not her mistake
lt's common sense, why are
you involving the fortune in it
What do you want Mr.?
After knowing that should
we leave our child for death
Who are you boss?
l'm an astrologer
Batook Maharaj
So you're the one
Bhai our aged men house
was gone just because of him
He come up with a new story
that if this marriage will
go on then the boy will die
How can you know?
Because l saw their horoscopes
Might be your knowledge
show the wrong side
Not till today
Bhai he's a god
Do one thing, you choose
the lndian cricket team
Select them who've a
century in their horoscopes
We never lost
On hundred not out
You're mocking on my knowledge
When tsunami came,
earthquake came, Mumbai...
...was underwater then
where is your knowledge?
Listen to me l'm not
a weather forecaster
l tell them there future
You don't know about your future
then how can you tell others
Who say that l don't
know about my future
lf you know then tell us
What'll happen with
you in next 2 minutes
- What'll happen
- We don't know
You're the astrologer you tells
us about your problematic future
Bad time... why problematic time come?
Circuit take out you gun
Problem
Circuit start the game
l counts till ten after
ten fire the bullet
Look you're not doing it right
- Bathook
- Yes
You've full confidence on your horoscope
- Don't move
- No...
l'm not a joke listen to me
- Listen to me
- Ladies and Gentlemen don't be afraid
l'm a very peaceful man
But l'm sure that bullet
is going to through his head
What are you talking?
But he face no damages
Batook bullet will
go through and through
What are you doing?
- One
- Take it off
- No listen to me...
- Two... - Stop it
- Three
- Are you listening me or not?
- Get a side
- Four
Take it off
- Five
- Listen to me
- Six
- Why you all people are doing nothing
- Seven
- Nobody can do like this
- Khoorana Saab do some this... Look
- Eight
- Nine
- Enough
Don't speak Ten
He's fainted Bhai
Come over here l wants to say sorry
Uncle
That person who are not sure about his
future then how come he tell others future
Don't stop this marriage
l'm requesting you
Somebody try to explain him
Somebody tell him anything
l'm a mad person
But l can see it clear that
something is happening wrong
You smart peoples can't
understand this thing...
Circuit it's better that
Bapu is not in reality
lf today he's here, then he'll
cry after seeing this scary nation
He died saying this that speak the truth
But today if somebody speaks the
truth then people are going to bust him
That girl dare to do
it.... then guests returns
Go Circuit
Go...
Take me in
l don't live among these smart people
Go...
Where is Sunny?
Sunny... Go...
Dad...
lf l'll marry Simran
then may be l'll die...
But if not then l must die
Sorry Dad...
- Bhai
- Yes
Bhai are you sure that
after paying visit...
...daily over here that
increases our reputation
Write a letter
To whom Bhai?
l'm sorry that l came into your life
But what can l do?
When you say ''Good Morning Mumbai''
Then sunlight came to my life
and when you left after
saying ''Good Night Mumbai''
Then l'll remember you all the night
This life is wasted
But after reborn l'll
be a real professor
And win the quiz without
cheating and come into your studio
But Janvi... Don't change your self
Who saw the next life Munna?
l wants to live this life with you
l'm going to see you from studios window
Then you remove your curl with help of
your finger and place it behind your ear
Like this
Well next time lf l'll go to Goa
Then l'll give you the
ring in full confidence
How can you do that?
l've it
Circuit l've a very big
mental chemical disbalance
Can you able to see Janvi
Yes Bhai
Hey Janvi Tell me where is she?
She's there Bhai
Behind your back
On my back
Yes... behind your back
Why you lied?
Why you said that you're not a professor
You're the best professor ever met Murli
l saw too many professors
teaching Gandhi history
Follower of Gandhisum Just one
- Third one from the left
- Which one
- Third one, 1 ... 2... 3...
- 1 ... 2... 3...
- Congratulations Bhai... Congratulations
- Thanks you Circuit... Thanks you
We're going to hit him over here
Already we are in the jail
Friend
Thanks it done
Take this
Then what else they've there home
Munna and Janvi get married
Now both of them do Gandhisum on radio
Bobby and Tina wants a son
lt's very difficult but they own Circuit
They think they'll change him
They changed but not Circuit
Mr. D'suza live with honor
Today his son buy a
new cab from his earning
Sunny married simran for 5 years
Sunny is alive and very happy
After seeing all this
Khorana understands
One day he lay of Batook from
his work and 'K' from his name
You think that what happens with me
l was assassinated long time ago
But my teaching can't
die from three bullets
Time will change
But my teaching will cause chemical
disbalances to somebody's mind
Now its up to you
lf you want to hang me
as photograph on the wall
or follow my teachings
Now l've to go
Somebody is waiting for me
- Lucky Singh
- Who?
Mohan Das Karam Chand Gandhi
Bapu... lt's amazing... lt's amazing
Make my life Bapu... Make my life....
But before study... One photo Bapu
Oye photo studio...
Come on... Hurry up...
Expose it perfectly