- You're looking good, Dutch.
- It's been a long time, General.
Come on inside.
18 hours ago, we lost a chopper...
carrying a cabinet minister and his aide
from this charming little country.
We've got a transponder fixed
on their position... about here.
This cabinet minister, does he always travel
on the wrong side of the border?
Apparently, they strayed off course.
We're fairly certain they're in guerrilla hands.
So why don't you use the regular army?
What do you need us for?
Cos some damn fool
accused you of being the best.
Dillon.
You son of a bitch.
What's the matter? The CIA got you
pushing too many pencils?
- Had enough?
- Make it easy on yourself, Dutch.
- Never did know when to quit.
- Damn good to see you, Dutch.
- What is this fucking tie business?
- Forget about my tie.
I heard about that job you pulled off in Berlin.
Very nice, Dutch.
- Good old days.
- Yeah, like the good old days.
- Then how come you passed on Libya?
- That wasn't my style.
You got no style, Dutch. You know that.
Come on. Why'd you pass?
We're a rescue team, not assassins.
Now, what we gotta do?
That cabinet minister
is important to our scope of operations.
A couple of our friends are about to
get squeezed and we can't let that happen.
We need the best. That's why you're here.
- Go on.
- Simple setup. One-day operation.
We pick up their trail at the chopper,
grab those hostages, and bounce back.
- What do you mean, "we"?
- I'm goin' in with you, Dutch.
General, my team always works alone.
You know that.
I'm afraid we all have our orders, Major.
Once you reach your objective, Dillon will
evaluate the situation and take charge.
Delta One-Zero to Two Leader.
Rendezvous points and radio freqs
are indicated and fixed.
- AWACS contact on four-hour intervals.
- Who's our backup?
No such thing. This is a one-way ticket.
Once we cross that border, we're on our own.
This is getting better by the minute.
Billy!
Billy! The other day
I went up to my girlfriend. I said,
"You know, I'd like a little pussy."
She said, "Me, too. Mine's as big as a house."
You see, she wanted
a littler one cos hers was...
big as a house.
Get that stinkin' shit out of my face.
Bunch of slack-jawed faggots around here.
This stuff'll make you
a goddamn sexual tyrannosaurus,
just like me.
Strap this on your sore ass, Blain.
That was in '72. Me and Dutch both got one.
That's a real nasty habit you got there.
You got it, Leader.
Never knew how much I missed this, Dutch.
You never were that smart.
Hawkins, you're up.
Lines away.
The pilots have been shot in the head.
Whoever hit it stripped the shit out of it.
- Took 'em out with a heat seeker.
- There's something else, Major.
This is no ordinary army taxi.
It looks more like a surveillance bird to me.
- Pick up the trail yet?
- Billy's on it.
Heat seeker, Dillon. Pretty sophisticated
for a bunch of half-assed mountain boys.
I guess they're getting
better equipped every day.
There were 12 guerrillas.
They took the two men from the helicopter,
but there's something else.
- What do you mean?
- Six men wearing US-issued army boots.
They came in from the north,
and then they followed the guerrillas.
Mean anything to you?
Probably just another rebel patrol.
They operate in here all the time.
Get ahead and see what you can find.
What's he got?
Same business. Guerrillas hauling
two guys from the chopper,
followed by men with American equipment.
Do you remember Afghanistan?
Trying to forget it. Come on.
Holy mother of God.
Jim Hopper.
Mac, cut 'em down.
I knew these men.
Green Berets out of Fort Bragg.
What the hell were they doing here?
I don't know, Dutch. This is inhuman.
Nobody told me
there was an operation in this area.
- They shouldn't have been here.
- Somebody sent them.
The guerrillas skinned them?
Why did they skin them?
Ain't no way for no soldier to die.
- What happened here, Billy?
- Strange, Major.
There was a firefight.
They were shooting in all directions.
I can't believe Hopper
walked into an ambush.
I don't believe he did.
I can't find a single track.
- It just doesn't make sense.
- What about the rest of Hopper's men?
There's no sign, sir.
They never left here.
It's like they just disappeared.
Stick with the guerrilla trail.
Let's get the hostages.
We move, five-metre spread. No sound.
It's time to let old painless out the bag.
Payback time.
You're ghostin' us, motherfucker.
I don't care who you are back in the world.
You give our position one more time,
I'll bleed you, real quiet, and leave you here.
Got that?
Fuck you.
He killed one of the hostages. We move.
Mac, Blain - the nest.
Billy, Poncho - the guard.
Hawkins, Dillon - backup.
As soon as they're set, I hit the fuel dump.
One down.
What the hell's he doin'?
What the fuck...?
Showtime, kid.
Target's the centre of the palapa.
Dutch, on your nine.
Get that mother.
Stick around.
Hostages inside.
Knock, knock.
I got 'em.
Hawkins, call in position and situation.
Get Con Op on the hook.
You got it, Major.
Shit.
Mac. Any sign of the other hostage?
Found the other guy - he's dead, too -
and the gear from the chopper.
But if they're Central American,
I'm a goddamn Chinaman.
From the looks of it, our cabinet minister was
CIA. Another thing, Major. We were lucky.
Other guys they waxed...
were Russian military advisers.
Something pretty big
was gonna happen here.
Good work, Mac. Clear the area. No traces.
Get the men ready to move.
Son of a bitch is dug in like an Alabama tick.
- You're hit. You're bleedin', man.
- I ain't got time to bleed.
You got time to duck?
This is goddamn beautiful.
Goddamn jackpot.
This is more than we ever thought we'd get.
We got those bastards.
- We got 'em.
- I think this is what you're looking for.
You set us up. It's all bullshit. All of it.
The cabinet minister, the whole business.
Got us in here to do your dirty work.
We stopped a major invasion.
In three days they'd have crossed the border.
- Why us?
- Because nobody else could've pulled it off.
- You're pissed about the cover story.
- So, what story did you hand to Hopper?
We've been looking for this place for months.
My men were in that chopper when it got hit.
- Hopper went in and he disappeared.
- He didn't disappear. He was skinned alive.
I had to get somebody
who could crack these bastards.
So you cooked up a story
and dropped the six of us in a meat grinder.
What happened to you, Dillon?
You used to be somebody I could trust.
I woke up.
Why don't you?
You're an asset,
an expendable asset,
and I used you to get the job done. Got it?
My men are not expendable.
And I don't do this kind of work.
Major, we stepped into some real shit here.
We've got guerrillas all over the place.
Can't be more than one, two miles away.
- How much time?
- Half an hour, maybe less.
- Tell Mac we move in five.
- She goes with us. She's too valuable.
She'll give away our position
any chance she gets. No deal.
You're still under orders, Major.
Now, you wanna make that call or should I?
She's your baggage.
You fall behind and you're on your own.
This place is too hot for a pickup. They won't
touch us till we get over the border.
Billy. Give me a way out of this hole.
Aerial says we are cut off.
The only way outta here
is that valley that leads to the east.
I wouldn't waste that on a broke-dick dog.
Not much choice.
Poncho, take lead. Double-time it.
Dillon.
Over here.
- Turn around.
- Why?
Thanks.
Any time.
Billy.
The other day
I was goin' down on my girlfriend.
I said to her, "Jeez, you've got a big pussy.
Jeez, you've got a big pussy."
She said, "Why did you say that twice?"
I said, "I didn't."
See, it was cos of the echo.
Over here.
Turn around.
Turn around. Over here.
Any time.
Goddamn.
Buddy, buddy, buddy, buddy.
I've seen some bad-ass bush before, man,
but nothin' like this.
I hear you. This shit's somethin'.
Makes Cambodia look like Kansas.
Hey, a little taste of home.
You lose it here, you're in a world of hurt.
Come on. Stop sandbaggin' it. Now, get up.
Come on, get up. Would you get up?
Maybe you'd better
put her on a leash, agent man.
Try it again... please.
What's got Billy so spooked?
Can't say, Major.
Been acting squirrely all morning.
That damn nose of his... it's weird.
What is it?
Billy...
What the hell is wrong with you?
There's something in those trees.
Do you see anything?
Up there.
Nothing.
What do you think?
I guess it's nothing, Major.
Please.
Billy, break left.
Mac, right.
- What the...? This isn't her blood.
- What the hell'd you do to him?
Major... you'd better take a look at this.
Did you find Hawkins?
I...
I can't tell.
What in God's name...?
I think it's Hawkins.
- Where the hell is his body?
- There's no sign of it.
Ask her what happened.
She says the jungle...
it just came alive and took him.
Bullshit. That's not what she said.
- It doesn't make sense.
- Those sappers have followed us...
They've been in front of us. This woman...
Hold it.
Hold it. Why didn't they take
his radio or his weapon?
Why didn't she escape?
- Hopper.
- What?
They did the same thing to Jim Hopper.
I want Hawkins' body found. Sweep pattern.
Double back. 50 metres. Let's go.
Come on in, you fuckers.
Come on in.
Old painless is waitin'.
Sergeant.
Motherfucker.
- What happened?
- I saw it.
- You saw what?
Blain.
No powder burns, no shrapnel.
The wound's all fused, cauterised.
What the hell could have done this to a man?
Mac.
Mac, look at me.
- Who did this?
- I don't know, goddamn it.
I saw something.
Not a thing. Not a fuckin' trace.
No blood, no bodies. We hit nothing.
Dillon, better get on the radio.
Mac.
- Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
I want a defensive position above that ridge
mined with everything we've got.
- Put him in his poncho. Take him with us.
- I got him.
Major, I set up flares, frags and claymores.
Nothing's coming near this place
without tripping on somethin'.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Mac.
He was a good soldier.
He was...
my friend.
Goodbye, bro.
Blazer One, I repeat, extraction necessary.
Say again, Blazer One. Say again.
Request for extraction denied.
Area is still compromised.
Proceed to sector 3,000 for prisoner
extraction. Priority, out. Next contact 0930.
Roger, Blazer One. 1030 hours.
Damn bastards.
They say we're still in too far.
They can't risk coming in.
We're assets, Dillon. Expendable assets.
It comes with the job. I can accept it.
Bullshit. You're just like the rest of us.
Shitload of good a chopper's
gonna do us in here anyhow.
Sergeant?
Sergeant. Who hit us today?
I don't know.
I only saw one of them camouflaged.
He was there.
Those eyes disappeared.
What was that?
Those eyes, they...
they disappeared.
I know one thing, Major.
I drew and fired straight at it.
Capped off 200 rounds
in the Minigun... Full pack.
Nothing... nothing on this earth
could have lived.
Not at that range.
Mac, you take first watch,
then you get some rest.
Ask her. Ask her what she saw.
Ask her what happened to Hawkins.
Go ahead. Ask her.
She says the same fuckin' thing.
The jungle, it came alive and took him.
Billy... you know something. What is it?
- I'm scared, Poncho.
- Bullshit. You ain't afraid of no man.
There's something out there waiting for us,
and it ain't no man.
We're all gonna die.
He's losing his cool. There's a couple of
guys out there and we gotta take 'em down.
You still don't understand, Dillon, do you?
Whatever it is out there, it killed Hopper,
and now it wants us.
Here we are again, bro,
just you and me.
Same kind of moon and same kind ofjungle.
Real number 10 night, remember?
Whole platoon, 32 men chopped into meat,
and we walk out, just you and me.
Nobody else. Right on top, bro.
Not a scratch. Not a fuckin' scratch.
You know, whoever got you,
he'll come back again, and when he does,
I'm gonna cut your name right into him.
I'm gonna cut your name into him.
Mac.
- This way.
- Where the hell are you?
Where are you?
Mac, where are you?
Jesus.
I got you, motherfucker.
I killed you, you fuck.
Jesus. You killed a pig.
Do you think you could have found
something bigger?
Fuck you, Poncho. Fuck you.
- Where's the girl?
- Shit.
Why wasn't anybody watching her?
Why didn't she try to get away?
Look at her. She's scared out of her mind.
Major, you better take a look at this.
Blain's body, it's gone.
It came in through the tripwires.
Took it right out from under our noses.
That boar had to set off the trip flare, Major,
cos there ain't no other tracks.
How could anyone get through this
and carry out Blain without us knowing it?
And why didn't he try and kill one of us?
He came in to get the body.
He's killing us one at a time.
Like a hunter.
He's using the trees.
Yesterday, what did you see?
- You're wasting your time.
- No more games.
I don't know what it was.
- It...
- Go on.
It changed colours like the chameleon.
It uses the jungle.
Are you sayin' Blain and Hawkins were killed
by a fuckin' lizard?
That's a bullshit psych job. There's two
or three men at the most. Fucking lizard.
- What's your name?
- Anna.
Anna, this thing is hunting us. All of us.
You know that.
- What the hell are you doing?
- We need everyone.
- I'm taking her back. We're out of here.
- We're not going yet.
The rendezvous is 10 miles away.
You think the chopper'll wait?
Dillon, we make a stand now, or there will be
nobody left to go to the chopper.
There is something else.
When the big man was killed,
you must have wounded it.
Its blood was on the leaves.
If it bleeds, we can kill it.
Look out.
You really think
this boy-scout bullshit's gonna work.
It can see our tripwires.
Maybe it can't see this.
Instead of complaining,
maybe you should help.
What makes you think
he'll come in through here?
There are tripwires on every tree for 50 yards.
This is the only way in.
When I was little, we found a man.
He looked like,
like, butchered.
The old women in the village
crossed themselves
and whispered crazy things,
said strange things.
Only in the hottest years this happens.
And this year it grows hot.
We begin finding our men.
We found them sometimes without their skin,
and sometimes much, much worse.
"El que hace trofeos de los hombres" means
"the demon who makes trophies of man."
So, what you gonna try next? Cheese?
Hey, Dutch!
Shit.
Got you, motherfucker. I got you.
I'm coming.
Mac. Mac. Get Ramirez on his feet
and get to the chopper.
- Hold it. I'm going after Mac.
- That's not your style, Dillon.
I picked up some bad habits from you.
Get your people the hell outta here.
You can't win this, Dillon.
Maybe I can get even.
Dillon.
Just hold on to that damn chopper.
He's busted up pretty bad, Major.
- I can make it. I can make it.
- Get the radio. Forget the rest.
Come on, Poncho.
Long tall Sally
She's built sweet
She got everything that Uncle John need
Oh, baby
Baby
I'm gonna have me some fun
Turn around.
Over here.
Mac?
Out there. Past them trees.
You see it?
I see you.
I see it.
You know, we can get this thing, Mac.
You work your way down there toward him.
I'll get in back of him, flush him toward you.
When I flush that son of a bitch, you nail him.
I got a score to settle.
We've both got scores to settle.
Come on. Quickly. Hurry up.
Don't. Leave it.
It didn't kill you because you weren't armed.
No sport.
Mac.
Any time.
Let's go.
Billy.
Billy, let's go.
Give me the weapon.
No.
Run.
Go.
Get to the chopper.
Oh, shit.
He couldn't see me.
Bleed, bastard.
You're one ugly motherfucker.
Bad idea.
Come on.
Come on. Do it.
Do it.
Come on. Come on.
Kill me. I'm here. Kill me.
I'm here. Kill me.
Come on. Kill me. I'm here.
Come on. Do it now. Kill me.
What the hell are you?
What the...?
My God.
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH