You don't like flying, do you?
What gives you that idea?
You want to know the secret
to surviving air travel?
After you get where you're going,
take off your shoes and socks.
Then you walk around on the rug barefoot
and make fists with your toes.
Fists with your toes?
I know. It sounds crazy.
Trust me.
I've been doing it for nine years.
Yes, sir! Better than a shower
and a hot cup of coffee.
OK.
It's OK. I'm a cop.
Trust me.
I've been doing this for 11 years.
On behalf
of the captain and the crew,...
..l'd like to welcome you
to Los Angeles.
Have a very merry Christmas.
Flight247 to Tucson
now boarding at gate 14.
Flight 247 to Tucson
How do you do?
Ladies and gentlemen,...
Ladies and gentlemen!
I want to congratulate
each and every one of you...
..for making this
one of the greatest years...
..in the history
of the Nakatomi Corporation.
On behalf of the Chief
Executive Officer, Mr Ozu,...
..and the Board of Directors,...
..we thank you one and all...
..and wish you a merry Christmas
and a happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
Hey, Holly.
What about dinner tonight?
Harry, it's Christmas Eve.
Families, stockings,...
Chestnuts?
Rudolph and Frosty?
Any of these things ring a bell?
Actually, I was thinking more of...
..mulled wine, a nice aged Brie...
..and a roaring fireplace.
You know what I'm saying?
Ginny, it's 5.40. Go join the party.
Have some champagne.
You're making me feel
like Ebenezer Scrooge.
Thanks. Do you think the baby
can handle a little sip?
That baby's ready to tend bar.
Last chance.
Bye.
McClane residence.
Lucy McClane speaking.
Hello, Lucy McClane.
This is your mother speaking.
Mommy!
When are you coming home?
Pretty soon.
You'll be in bed
when I get there, though.
Let me talk to Paulina, OK, hon?
And no snooping around the house
looking for presents.
Is Daddy coming home with you?
Well, we'll see what...
..Santa and Mommy can do, OK?
Put Paulina on. Bye, honey.
Paulina!
Hola, Mrs Holly.
Um, did Mr McClane call?
No, Mrs Holly. No telefono.
He probably didn't have time
before his flight.
It might be a good idea
to make up the spare bedroom...
..just in case.
Si, Mrs Holly. I do that already.
What would I do without you, Paulina?
California!
Hey, I'm John McClane.
Argyle.
I'm your limo driver.
Nice bear.
OK... Argyle.
What do we do now?
I was, uh, hoping you could tell me.
It's my first time driving a limo.
That's OK.
It's my first time riding in one.
We got everything in this mug, man.
Look at this... CD, CB, TV,...
..telephone, full bar, VHS.
If your friend's hot to trot,...
..l know a few mama bears
we can hook up with.
Or is he married?
He's married.
OK.
Sorry about that.
It's the girl's day off.
I didn't know
you were gonna sit up front.
Your lady live out here?
About the past six months.
Meaning you still live in New York?
You always ask
this many questions, Argyle?
Sorry. I used to drive a cab
and people would expect a little chitchat.
- So, you divorced?
- Just drive the car, man.
Hey, come on. You divorced?
You separated? She beat you up!?
She had a good job.
It turned into a great career.
- That meant she had to move here.
- You're very fast, Argyle.
So, why didn't you come?
Why didn't you come with her?
Because I'm a New York cop.
I got a backlog of New York scumbags
I'm still trying to put behind bars.
I can'tjust go that easy.
You thought she wasn't
gonna make it out here...
..and she'd come crawling back to you
so why bother to pack, right?
Like I said, you're very fast, Argyle.
Mind ifwe hear some tunes?
Hey, that'll work.
Don't you got any Christmas music?
This is Christmas music.
So your lady sees you,
you run into each other's arms,...
..the music comes up
and you live happily ever after, right?
I can live with that.
So, if it doesn't work out,
you got a place to stay?
I'll find a place.
I tell you what...
I'll wait in the parking garage. You score,
give me a call on the car phone.
I'll take your bags to the desk.
You strike out, I'll get you a hotel.
- You're all right, Argyle.
- Remember that when you sign for the tip.
- Hi.
- Good evening.
I'm here to see Holly McClane.
Just type it in there.
Cute toy.
Yeah, if you have to take a leak,
it'll even help you find your zipper.
Christ.
- Thirtieth floor?
- The party.
They're the only ones
left in the building.
Take the express elevator.
Get off where you hear the noise.
Thanks.
- Champagne, sir?
- Yeah, thanks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey! Merry Christmas!
Jesus.
Fuckin' California!
I couldn't agree with you more.
Why don't I talk to him right now?
Hi. I'm looking for...
- Holly Gennero.
- Yeah.
Then you must be John McClane.
Joe Takagi.
How was your ride in?
Nice. I have you to thank for that?
Seemed the least we could do.
- Quite a place you have here.
- It will be ifwe ever get it finished.
Still several floors under construction.
Holly went to fax some documents.
She should be back any minute.
In the meanwhile,
her office is back here.
Ellis?
I was just making a call.
This was the nearest phone.
I want you to meet John McClane,...
..Holly's husband.
Holly's policeman.
Ellis is in charge
of international development.
Heard a lot about you.
You missed some.
Can I get you anything?
Food? Cake?
Some watered-down champagne?
No, thank you. I'm fine.
You throw quite a party.
I didn't realise they celebrated
Christmas in Japan.
We're flexible.
Pearl Harbor didn't work out,
so we got you with tape decks.
It's sort of a double celebration.
We closed a pretty big deal today...
..and a lot of it was due
to Holly. Right, Joe?
I'll be out
in a couple of minutes.
John.
Have you met everyone?
We've been sticking him with spears.
Of course he has.
She was made for the business.
Tough as nails.
I was hoping you made that flight.
Show him the watch.
Later.
Show him. Are you embarrassed?
It's just a small token of appreciation...
..for all her hard work. It's a Rolex.
I'm sure I'll see it later.
Is there a place
where I could wash up?
Sure.
You have to forgive Ellis.
He gets very depressed
this time ofyear.
He thought he was
God's greatest gift, you know?
I know the type.
I think he's got his eye on you.
That's OK. I have my eye
on his private bathroom.
Where are you staying?
Things happened so fast...
..l didn't get a chance
to ask you on the phone.
Cappy Roberts retired out here.
Oh, yeah?
He said I could bunk with him.
Cappy retired, huh?
Where's he live?
- Romona.
- Ha! Pomona.
- Huh?
- Pomona.
- Yeah.
You'll be in the car halfthe time.
Why don't we make it easy?
I have a spare bedroom.
It's not huge or anything, but...
..the kids would love to have you
at the house.
They would, huh?
I would, too.
Ha ha! Ooh!
Sorry.
I missed you.
Didn't miss my name, though, huh?
Except maybe
when you're signing cheques?
Since when did you start using
Ms Gennero?
This is a Japanese company.
They figure a married woman's...
You are a married woman.
This conversation again?
We did this in July.
We never finished this conversation.
I had an opportunity. I had to take it.
No matter what it did to our marriage.
It only changed your idea
of our marriage.
You have no clue what my idea...
I know exactly what your idea
of our marriage should be.
Ms Gennero, l...
Excuse me.
Hi.
Um, Mr Takagi is looking for you.
He wants you to say something
to the troops.
Thank you.
Speech time.
Be back in a few minutes.
That was great, John.
Good job. Very mature.
So Kareem rebounds.
Feeds Worthy on the break,
over to AC, to Magic,...
..then back to Worthy.
Boom! Two points.
We're in.
Links...
..rechts...
..und wieder links.
Son of a bitch.
Ha ha!
Fists with your toes.
Yeah, Argyle?
How's it going?
All right. Where are you?
Down at the garage.
What's with you and your lady?
The vote's not in yet.
- Hey, Bruder.
- Moment.
Nein! Nein! Nein!
Argyle?
Mac, you there? Hello?
You know the number. Use it.
Stay calm.
Everything's going to be fine.
Shit!
Think.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Due to the Nakatomi Corporation's
legacy of greed around the globe...
..they're about to be taught a lesson
in the real use of power.
You will be witnesses.
Now...
..where is Mr Takagi?
Joseph Yashinobo Takagi,...
..born Kyoto, 1937...
Family emigrated to San Pedro,
California, 1939,...
..interned at Manzanar, 1942 to '43,...
..scholarship student,
University of California,...
..1955.
Law degree, Stanford, 1962.
MBA, Harvard, 1970.
President, Nakatomi Trading.
Vice Chairman,
Nakatomi lnvestment Group...
Enough.
And father...
..of five.
I am Takagi.
How do you do?
It's a pleasure to meet you.
OK, 32... construction,
33... computers.
Nice suit.
John Phillips, London.
I have two myself.
Rumour has it
Arafat buys his there.
- This way?
- On the left.
And when Alexander saw
the breadth of his domain...
..he wept, for there were
no more worlds to conquer.
The benefits of a classical education.
Ohh, that's beautiful.
I always enjoyed to make models
when I was a boy.
The exactness, the attention
to every conceivable detail.
It's beautiful.
Is this what this is all about?
Our project in lndonesia?
Contrary to what you people may think,...
..we're going to develop
that region, not exploit it.
I believe you.
I read the article in Forbes.
Mr Takagi...
I could talk about industrialisation
and men's fashions all day...
..but I'm afraid work must intrude...
..and my associate here
has some questions for you.
Sort offill-in-the-blanks questions,
actually.
I don't have that code.
You broke in here
to access our computer?
Any information you could get...
..when they wake up in Tokyo,
they'll change it.
You won't be able to blackmail
our executives...
Sit... down!
Mr Takagi, I'm really not
interested in your computer.
But I need the code key...
..because I am interested
in the $640 million...
..in negotiable bearer bonds
that you have locked in your vault...
..and the computer
controls the vault.
You want money?
What kind ofterrorists are you?
Who said we were terrorists?
The bonds represent, at most...
..10 days' operating capital
for your parent organisation.
It's really no more
than a temporary inconvenience.
Now...
..the code, please.
It's useless to you.
There are seven safeguards on our vault
and the code key's only one of them.
You'll never get it open.
Then there's no reason
not to tell it to us.
- I told you.
- It's not over yet.
It's a very nice suit, Mr Takagi.
It would be a shame to ruin it.
I'm going to count to three.
There will not be a four.
Give me the code.
One,...
..two,...
- ..three,...
- I don't know it.
Get on ajet to Tokyo
and ask the chairman.
You're just gonna have to kill me.
OK.
We do it the hard way.
Tony, see ifyou can dispose ofthat.
Karl, you better check on Heinrich's work
up on the machine floor.
[bumps head]
Nothing.
See to Heinrich.
Now...
..you can break the code?
You didn't bring me
for my charming personality.
Argyle, tell me you heard the shots.
You're calling the police right now.
Of course I'm still coming by later.
Sweetheart, have I ever lied to you?
My boss? He thinks
I'm on my way to Vegas.
Uli, get up on the pipes.
Marco, you go through here.
I'll throw you the cord.
Hans, we're on the roof.
Here.
Uli.
30 minutes to break the code,...
..two hours, two and a half hours
for the five mechanicals, at the minimum.
The 7th lock, however,
is out of my hands.
I'm sorry?
The 7th lock...
the electromagnetic seal.
You do understand the circuits
cannot be cut locally?
Trust me.
Why the fuck
didn't you stop him, John?
'Cause then you'd be dead, too,
asshole.
Think, goddamn it! Think!
We've got a fire alarm.
Call 911.
Give them the guard's name
and cancel the alarm.
Then disable the sys...
Eddie, on what floor
did the alarm go off?
Shall we go?
Nein.
Yes.
Hello, baby.
Come to Papa. Come on.
Ah ha ha ha!
Come on, baby.
Come on, baby. Come to Papa.
I'll kiss your fuckin' Dalmatian.
You stupid motherfuckers!
No! No!
Turn the fuckin' truck around!
The fire has been called off, my friend.
No-one is coming to help you.
You might as well come out
and join the others.
I promise I won't hurt you.
Drop it, dickhead. It's the police.
You won't hurt me.
Yeah? Why not?
Because you're a policeman.
There are rules for policemen.
Yeah, that's what my captain
keeps telling me.
Bet your ass I wish to proceed.
Nine million terrorists in the world...
..and I got to kill one with feet
smaller than my sister.
I wanted this to be professional,...
..efficient, adult, cooperative.
Not a lot to ask.
Alas, your Mr Takagi
did not see it that way...
..so he won't be joining us
for the rest of his life.
We can go any way you want it.
You can walk out of here
or be carried out...
..but have no illusions...
we are in charge.
So... decide now, each ofyou...
..and please remember...
..we have left nothing to chance.
It's Tony!
Get them back!
Now lhave a machine gun.
Ho... ho... ho.
A security guard we missed?
They're usually tired old policemen.
No, this is something else.
We have to do something, Hans.
Yes, we do.
Tell Karl his brother is dead.
Tell him to come down.
Karl... komm sofort.
Franco, Fritz,
take the body upstairs...
..and out of sight.
I don't want the hostages
to think too much.
Komm sofort. Schnell.
I want blood!
You'll have it, but let
Heinrich plant the detonators...
..and Theo prepare the vault.
After we call the police,...
..you can tear the building apart
looking for this man...
..but until then,
do not alter the plan!
And if he alters it?
What do you think?
Something's wrong.
Cops?
- John.
- John?
He can fuck
this whole thing up.
What does he think he's doing?
His job.
Bullshit.
His job's 3,000 miles away.
Without him, we still have
a chance to get out of here.
Tell that to Takagi.
Mayday, Mayday,
anyone copying channel nine.
Terrorists have seized
the Nakatomibuilding...
..and are holding
at least 30 people hostage.
I repeat.
Unknown number ofterrorists...
..six or more
armed with automatic weapons...
..at Nakatomi Plaza,...
..Century City.
Where's the best place to transmit?
The roof!
Go! Go!
It's the same address
as that fire signal.
I'll handle it.
Attention, whoever you are,...
..this channel is reserved
for emergency calls only.
No fucking shit, lady!
Do lsoundlike I'm ordering a pizza?
No-one kills him but me.
They have already killed one hostage.
They are fortifying their positions
while you're jerkin' me off on the radio!
Sir, I've already told you.
This is a reserved channel.
If this is an emergency call,
dial 911 on your telephone.
Otherwise, I'll report this
as an FCC violation.
Fine! Report me!
Come the fuck down here and arrest me!
Just send the police now!
See if a black and white can drive by.
Thought you guys just ate doughnuts.
- They're for my wife.
- Yeah.
- She's pregnant.
Bag it.
Big time.
Thanks.
Dispatch to 8-Lincoln-30. Over.
This is 8-Lincoln-30.
Investigate a code two
at NakatomiPlaza, Century City.
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch.
I'm on my way.
Girls.
Shit! Where the fuck is it?
Oh, my God.
He's in the elevator shaft.
Perfect.
The elevators are locked off.
He can't escape.
Just shut him in
and come back down.
Oh, fuck.
Karl, the police are probably
on their way...
..already.
Karl?
Christ.
I can stall them,
but not ifthey hear gunshots.
If you lock him in,
he'll be neutralised...
"Come out to the coast!"
"We'll get together,
have a few laughs."
Now I know
what a TV dinner feels like.
Such!
Karl, komm! Die polizei!
Karl, die polizei!
Well, it's about time.
No signs of disturbance, Dispatch.
Roger. Possible crank call.
Check the area again and confirm.
Who's driving this car,
Stevie Wonder?
I do see a guard inside.
I'm gonna go in for a closer look.
Use caution.
Eddie?
I had a feelin' you'd be calling.
Evenin', officer.
What can I do for you?
We had that false alarm.
You ask me, that goddamn
computer sent you...
..on another wild-goose chase.
They been chasing bugs in this system
ever since they installed it.
..Notre Dame on top ofUSC.
Aw, shit!
I got 50 bucks bet on them assholes.
Come on, come on,
where's the fucking cavalry?
..was goodfor52 yards.
Mind if I look around?
Help yourself.
27 seconds left in this first period.
Seven to nothing, Notre Dame.
The lrish driving 74yards
in eightplays...
I'll put this fuckin'...
Freeze, motherfucker! Drop it!
Don't shoot!
- Put the gun down!
- OK! Don't shoot!
Drop that fuckin' gun!
Marco, down!
Ah, to hell with this!
You are done!
No more table!
Where are you going, pal?
Next time you have a chance
to kill someone,...
..don't hesitate.
Thanks for the advice.
- Sorry to waste your time.
- No problem at all.
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas to you.
Oh, for the love...
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch.
Go ahead.
A wild-goose chase
over here at Nakatomi Plaza.
Everything here's OK. Over.
Shit!
Goddamn it! Jesus H Christ!
Welcome to the party, pal!
Goddamn it!
Get someone here now,
goddamn it!
Policeman under automatic
rifle fire at Nakatomi!
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddamn it! Now!
Monica, I can get us a table.
Wolfgang and I
are very close friends.
I interviewed him, for God's sake.
..Nakatomi.
Repeat.
Officer needs assistance at...
I'm at Nakatomi Plaza.
They're turning my car
into Swiss cheese!
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddamn it! Now!
Never thought
I'd love to hear that sound.
All of you relax.
This is a matter
of inconvenient timing, that's all.
Police action was inevitable...
..and, as it happens, necessary.
So, let them fumble about outside
and stay calm.
This is simply the beginning.
I told you all I wanted
radio silence until...
I'm very sorry, Hans.
I didn't get that message.
Maybe you shouldhave putit
on the bulletin board.
I figured since I waxed Tony
and Marco and his friend here,...
..l figured you and Karl
and Franco might be lonely...
..so I wanted to give you a call.
How does he know
so much about us?
That's very kind ofyou.
I assume you are
our mysterious party crasher.
You are most troublesome...
..for a security guard.
Eeeh! Sorry, Hans. Wrong guess.
Would you like to go for doublejeopardy
where the scores can really change?
Mm, these are very bad for you.
Who are you, then?
Just the fly in the ointment, Hans.
The monkey in the wrench,...
..the pain in the ass.
Whoa!
Check on all the others.
Don't use the radio.
See if he's lying about Marco...
..and find out
if anyone else is missing.
Mr Mystery Guest,...
..are you still there?
Yeah, I'm still here...
..unless you want to open
the front door for me.
No, I'm afraidnot...
..but you have me at a loss.
You know my name, but who are you?
Just another American
who saw too many movies as a child?
Another orphan
of a bankrupt culture...
..who thinks he's John Wayne,
Rambo, Marshal Dillon?
I was always partial
to Roy Rogers, actually.
I liked those sequined shirts.
Do you really think you have
a chance against us, Mr Cowboy?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
I'll beat everyone if I get a remote.
Sam, I don't have the new pages.
Harvey, keep your pants on.
Sam, I'm begging you.
Simon's with the remote.
I'll tell him to swing by.
I won't sit on this!
This is my story!
I'm going out there!
Look, Sam. Tell you what.
You don't give me a truck,
I'll steal a truck.
Give us a break, Thornburg.
Eat it, Harvey!
..four, three, two,...
..one.
Harvey, we're on the air.
Good evening.
This is Harvey Johnson.
And I'm Gail Wallens.
This is Nightline News at 10.00.
Our top stories
on this Christmas Eve...
Take truck number five.
Get out of here.
He wasn't lying about Marco.
He's down on the street.
The other man was Heinrich...
..and his bag is missing.
He had the detonator.
Theo.
Yo!
We mayhave some problems.
How's ourschedule?
Three down, four to go.
Then don't waste time...
..talking to me.
This is SergeantAIPowell...
..of the Los Angeles
Police Department.
If the person who radioed for help...
..can hearme on this channel,...
..acknowledge this transmission.
I say again,...
..if the person who radioed
for help can hear me,...
..acknowledge this transmission!
I read you, pal.
You the guy in the car?
What's left of him.
Can you identify yourself?.
Not now. Maybe later.
Listen fast. This is a party line.
The neighbours got itchy trigger fingers.
All right, here's the deal.
You got 30 or so hostages
on the 30th floor.
The leader's name is Hans.
We have to find him and shut him up.
He's telling them everything!
Let him. I'm waiting for the FBl.
He can waste
as much time as he likes...
..but we must find the bag, Fritz.
They have a freakin'arsenalhere.
We must have the detonators.
They got missiles, automatic weapons,...
..and enough plastic explosives
to orbit Arnold Schwarzenegger.
They're down to nine now,
counting the skydiver you met.
These guys are mostly European...
..judging by their clothing labels and...
..cigarettes.
They're well-financed and very slick.
How do you know that?
I've seen enough phoney IDs in my time...
..to recognise the ones they got
must have cost a fortune.
Add all that up. I don't know
what the fuck it means...
..but you got
some bad-ass perpetrators...
..and they're here to stay.
I hear you, partner.
LA's finest are on it,...
..so light 'em if you got 'em.
Way ahead of you, partner.
So what do I call you?
Call me...
..Roy.
Listen up, Roy,
if you think of anything else...
..don't be shy, OK?
In the meantime, find a safe place
and let us do our job.
They're all yours, Al.
Who's talking to 'em?
I am, sir.
Sergeant Powell. AI Powell.
Dwayne Robinson. What's the deal?
What do these pricks want?
If you mean the terrorists,...
..we haven't heard a peep from them.
Who have you been talking to?
We don't know.
He won't give us his name.
But he appears to be
the one who phoned.
He's killed one terrorist for sure
and claims he capped off two others.
He claims?
Powell, has it occurred to you...
..he could be
one ofthe terrorists pulling your chain...
..or some nutcase in there?
I don't think so.
In fact, I think he's a cop,...
..maybe not LAPD,
But he's definitely a badge.
- How do you know that?
- A hunch... things he said...
..like being able to spot a phoney ID.
Jesus Christ, Powell!
He could be a fucking bartender
for all we know!
TV's here.
Oh, shit.
I have a request.
What idiot put you in charge?
You did...
..when you murdered my boss.
Now everybody's looking to me.
Personally, I'd pass on the job.
I don't enjoy being this close to you.
Go on.
We have a pregnant woman.
Relax. She's not due
for a couple weeks...
..but sitting on that rock
isn't doing her back any good.
So I'd like permission to move her
to an office with a sofa.
No, but I'll have a sofa
brought out. Good enough?
Good enough.
And unless you like it messy,...
..start bringing us
in groups to the bathroom.
Yes. You're right.
It will be done.
Was there something else?
No, thank you.
Mr Takagi
chose his people well, Mrs...?
Gennero.
Ms Gennero.
We interrupt this programme
for a special news bulletin.
This is Richard Thornburg
live from Century City.
Tonight, Los Angeles hasjoined
the sadand worldwide
fraternity ofcities
whose only membership requirement
is to suffer the anguish
of international terrorism.
Approximately two hours ago,
an unidentified group of men
seized control
of the Nakatomi building,
sealing off all entrances and exits.
All telephone lines have been cut
and the only communication
now possible
has been through the use
of CB communicators
which the group
apparently brought with them.
According to official sources,
the perpetrators of this building siege...
Unit five,
hold your position in the main entrance.
We got Charlie unit in position
by the parking structure.
Let me ask you something.
Does this stairway
go up to the escalator?
Yeah.
Tell them to go ahead.
What's going on?
What's it look like? We're going in.
Going in? Man, that's crazy!
There could be over 30 hostages
in there for all we know.
We don't know shit, Powell.
If there's hostages, how come
there were no ransom demands?
If there's terrorists in there,
where's their list of demands?
All we know is that
somebody shot your car up.
It's probably the same silly son of a bitch
you've been talking to on that radio.
Excuse me, sir,
but what about the body
that fell out the window?
Probably some stockbroker
got depressed.
We're ready, Chief.
- Light 'em up. Let's go.
- Hit your lights.
- Blue units, go.
- Lights on!
Powell?
Powell, you still with me, babe?
What's going on?
Yo, Al.
I'm here, Roy,
but I'm kind of busy right now.
I'll talk to you later.
Al, what's wrong?
If you are what I think you are,
you'll know when to listen,
shut up, and
and when to pray.
Jesus Christ!
You're coming in, right?
Christ, Powell,
I told you what kind of people
you're dealing with here.
Let's load them up.
They'll be coming.
Everyone get ready.
Theo, you are the eyes now.
- Rivers.
- Yo.
Begin your reconnoitre.
Let's go.
Shit!
Come on. Let's go.
Ow! Jesus!
All right, spread out.
Shut up.
Let's go.
You macho assholes. No! No!
Ahem... all right. Listen up, guys.
'Twas the night before Christmas
and all through the house
not a creature was stirring, except
the four assholes
coming in the rear in standard
two-by-two cover formation.
We're all set.
We're ready.
Kick ass.
Go!
Right. Let's do it.
Take cover!
They're shooting at 'em.
It's panic fire.
They can't see anything.
They're shooting at the lights.
They're going after the lights.
Call them back.
It's not happening.
Mike, burn it.
Don't be impatient.
Just wound them.
Get them back.
They're sitting ducks without lights.
They're almost in.
Send in the car.
Jesus Christ!
Rivers, Rodriguez, report.
Wait a minute.
What have we here, gentlemen?
The police have themselves an RV.
Southeast corner.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Get back! Get the fuck back!
Get over there.
Schnell! Schnell!
Mach schnell!
Weiter! Weiter! Weiter!
Mach schnell! Mach schnell!
Weiter!
Mach los! Mach los!
I see him!
- Fire!
- Clear!
Oh, my God!
The quarterback is toast!
Hang on, Rivers. That's an order.
Hit it again.
All right, you motherfucker,
you made your point!
Let them pull back!
Thank you, Mr Cowboy.
I'll take it under advisement.
Hit it
again.
Fire.
Fuck me.
Get them out of the car! They're burning!
Fuck it.
Mach schnell! Mach los!
Let's see you take this
under advisement, jerkweed.
Geronimo, motherfucker.
Oh, shit!
They're using artillery on us!
You idiot, it's not the police.
It's him.
Holy shit.
My God!
- Tell me you got that.
- I got it.
Eat your heart out, Channel Five.
We've had an update
on the terrorist take over
of the Nakatomi building.
Sources say
the terroristleader, Hans,
may be this man... Hans Gruber.
A member ofthe radical
West German Volksfreimovement.
Strangely, the Volksfrei leadership
issued a communiqu an hour ago
stating that Gruber had been
expelled from that organisation.
Al, do you copy?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
W-what was that?
Remember that plastic
explosive I told you about?
There you go.
Is the building on fire?
No, but it's gonna need a paint job
and a shitload of screen doors.
Our spotter said you got two
with that blast.
- Is that him?
- Yes, sir.
I don't know who you think you are
but you just destroyed a building.
We do not want your help.
Is that clear?
We don't want your help.
I've got 100 people down here,
and they're covered with glass.
Glass? Who gives a shit about glass?
Who the fuck is this?
This is Deputy Chief of Police
Dwayne T Robinson
and I am in charge of this situation.
Oh, you're in charge?
I got some bad news for you, Dwayne.
From up here it doesn'tlook
like you're in charge ofshit.
Listen to me, you little asshole...
Asshole?
I'm not the one
who just got butt fucked
on national TV, Dwayne.
Ah ha ha!
Listen to me,jerk-off,
if you're not part of the solution,
you're part of the problem.
Quit being part of the problem
and put the other guy back on!
Hey, Roy, how you feeling?
Pretty fucking unappreciated, Al.
Hey, look. I love you.
So do a lot of the otherguys.
So hang in there, man, you hear me?
You hang in there.
Yeah, thanks, partner.
What are you doing?
I'm tired of sitting here
waiting to see
who gets us killed first,
them or your husband.
What are you going to do?
Hey, babe,
I negotiate million-dollar deals
for breakfast.
I think I can handle this Eurotrash.
Hey, sprechen sie talk, huh?
If you'd listened to me,
he would be neutralised already.
I don't want neutral. I want dead.
Hope I'm not interrupting.
What does he want?
It's not what I want.
It's what I can give you.
Look, let's be straight, OK?
It's obvious you're not
some dumb schmuck
up here to snatch a few purses.
You're very perceptive.
I watch 60 Minutes.
I say to myself,
these guys are professional,
they're motivated, they're happening,
they want something.
I couldn't care less
about your politics.
Maybe you're pissed off
at the camel jockeys.
Maybe it's the Hebes,
Northern lreland.
It's none of my business.
I figure you're here
to negotiate, am I right?
You're amazing.
You figured this all out already?
Hey, business is business.
You use a gun,
I use a fountain pen.
What's the difference?
Let's put it in my terms.
You're here on a hostile takeover.
You grab us for some green
but you didn't expect some poison pill
was gonna be running around the building.
Am I right?
Hans,
bubbie...
I'm your white knight.
I must have missed 60 Minutes.
What are you saying?
The guy upstairs
who's fucking things up, huh?
I can give him to you.
Oh, God...
Roy? Roy, you all right?
Just trying to fire down
a 1,000-year-old Twinkie.
What do they put in these things,
anyway?
Sugar, enriched flour,
partially hydrogenated
vegetable oil,
polysorbate 60,
and yellow dye number five.
Just everything
a growing boyneeds.
How many kids you got, Al?
As a matter of fact,
my wife is working on our first.
How about you, cowboy?
You got any kids
back on your ranch?
Yeah.
Two.
Sure hope I can see them
swinging on ajungle gym
with AI Jnr someday.
Well, now, that's a date
but you bring the ice cream.
Touching, cowboy. Touching.
Or shouldl call you
Mr McClane?
Mr Officer John McClane
of the New York
Police Department?
Get on the phone to Harry in New York.
You better get a hold of somebody
at Dispatch.
Sister Theresa called me
Mr McClane in the third grade.
My friends call me John
and you're neither, shithead.
I have someone
who wants to talk to you.
A very special friend
who was with you
at the party tonight.
Hey, John boy.
Ellis?
Yeah.
Listen, John, they're giving me
a few minutes to talk sense into you.
I know you think you're doing yourjob
and I can appreciate that
but you'rejust dragging
this thing out.
Look, no-one gets out of here
until these guys
can talk to the LA Police.
That won't happen until you stop
messing up the works. Capisce?
Ellis, what have you told them?
I told them we were old friends
and you were my guest
at the party.
Ellis, you shouldn't be doing this.
Tell me about it.
All right, John, listen.
They want you to tell them
where the detonators are.
They know people are listening.
They want the detonators,
or they're gonna kill me.
John, didn't you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
John, get with the programme.
The police are here now.
It's their problem.
Tell these guys where the detonators are
so no-one else gets hurt!
I'm putting my life
on the line for you, pal!
Ellis, listen to me carefully.
John...
Shut up, Ellis!
Just shut your mouth!
Put Hans back on the line.
Hans, this shithead doesn'tknow
what kind of man you are but l do.
Good. Then you'll
give us what we want
and save your friend's life.
You're not part ofthis equation.
Hey, what am l, a method actor?
Babe, putaway the gun.
This is radio, not television.
Hans, this asshole is not my friend!
I just met him tonight!
I don't know him!
Jesus Christ, Ellis!
These people will kill you!
Tell them you don't know me!
How can you say that
after all these years?
John? John?
Do you hear that?
Talk to me!
Where are my detonators?
Where are they,
or shall I shoot another one?
Sooner or later
I mightget to someone
you do care about.
Go fuck yourself, Hans.
He just let the guy die.
He just gave him up.
Give me that headset.
That's like pulling the trigger yourself.
Can't you see what's happening?
Can't you read between the lines?
He did everything he could
to save him.
If he gave himself up,
they'd both be dead right now!
No way, man. They'd be talking to us.
You tell this partner of yours
to stay out of this from now on.
Because if he doesn't,
I'm really going to nail his ass.
The man is hurting.
He is alone, tired,
and he hasn't seen diddly-squat
from anybody here!
You're gonna tell me he'll give a damn
about what you do to him
if he makes it out ofthere alive?
Why don't you wake up
and smell what you're shovelling?
You listen to me, sergeant.
Any time you want to go home,
you consider yourself dismissed.
No, sir.
You couldn't drag me away.
Attention, police.
- This is Sergeant AI Powell...
- Give me that.
This is Deputy Chief Dwayne Robinson.
Who is this?
This is Hans Gruber.
I assume you realise the futility
of direct action against me.
We have no wish
for further loss of life.
What is it you do wish for?
I have comrades in arms
around the world languishing in prison.
The American State Department
enjoys rattling its sabre for its own ends.
Now it can rattle it for me.
The following people
are to be released from their captors.
In Northern lreland the seven members
of the New Provo Front.
In Canada, the five imprisonedleaders
ofLibert de Quebec.
In Sri Lanka, the nine members
of the Asian Dawn.
What the fuck?
Asian Dawn?
I read about them in Time magazine.
When these revolutionary
brothers and sisters are free,
the hostages in this building
will be taken to the roof
and they will accompany us
in helicopters
to the Los Angeles
lnternational Airport
where they will be given
further instructions.
You have two hours to comply.
Wait a minute. Uh, Mr. Gruber.
This is crazy.
I don't have the authority.
Two hours is not enough.
Hello? Hello!
Did you get all that?
We got to make some calls.
Do you think they'll even try?
Who cares?
Theo, are we on schedule?
One more to go, then it's up to you.
You better be right
because the last one will take a miracle.
It's Christmas, Theo.
It's the time of miracles,
so be of good cheer
and call me
when you hit the last lock.
Karl,
hunt that little shit down
and get those detonators.
Fritz is checking the explosives.
I'll check the explosives.
You just get the detonators.
Hey, Powell, you out there?
I'm here, John. I'm here.
You gotta believe me.
There was nothing I could do.
Well, it's gonna be
both our asses ifyou're wrong.
I hear you.
Did you catch that bullshit
Hans was running?
It doesn'tmake sense, man.
Hey, don't ask me, man.
I'm just a deskjockey
who was on my way home when you rang.
The way you drove that car
I figured you for the street, Al.
In my youth. In my youth.
..author of "Hostage Terrorist,
Terrorist Hostage,
A Study in Duality. "
Dr Hasseldorf,
what can we expect
in the next few hours?
Well, Gail,
by this time,
the hostages should be going through
the early stages
of the Helsinki Syndrome.
As in Helsinki, Sweden.
Finland.
Basically, it's when the hostages
and the terrorists
go through a sort of
psychological transference
and a projection of dependency.
A strange sort oftrust
and bond develops.
We've hadsituations
where the hostages
have embraced their captors
after release
and even corresponded with them
in prison.
No, no, darling. Asian Dawn. Dawn.
D-A-W-N.
- Sir?
- Yeah?
Sir, the FBI is here.
- The FBI is here now?
- Yes, sir. Right over there.
Hold this.
Want a breath mint?
Hey, how you doing, man?
I'm Agent Johnson.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
- Oh, how you doing?
- No relation.
I'm, uh...
I'm Dwayne Robinson, LAPD.
I'm in charge here.
Not any more.
Hi, there. How you doing?
Ohh...
Please, God. No.
You're one ofthem, aren't you?
You're one ofthem.
No! Don't kill me! Please!
Don't kill me, please!
Please, please, please.
Whoa. Relax.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt you!
Oh, God.
What the fuck
are you doing up here?
What were you looking for?
I managed to get out ofthere and
I was just trying
to get up on the roof
and see if I could signal for help.
It's just over here.
Why don't you come and help?
Hold it. Forget the roof.
I said forget the roof.
They got people all over it.
You want to stay alive,
you stay with me.
The best we can figure it,
we've got maybe
30 or 35 hostages up there
probably on the 30th floor
and maybe seven or eight
terrorists up there.
Sounds like an A-7 scenario.
Thank you.
We'll handle it from here.
When we commandeer your men,
we'll try and let you know.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Such as?
What about John McClane?
He's the reason
we have any information.
He's also the reason
you're facing seven terrorists, not twelve.
He's inside? Who is he?
He might be a cop.
We're checking on that.
- One ofyours?
- No, no way.
You smoke?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You don't work for Nakatomi.
And ifyou're not one ofthem...
I'm a cop from New York.
New York?
Yeah.
Got invited to
the Christmas party by mistake.
Who knew?
Better than being caught
with your pants down, huh?
I'm John McClane.
You're, uh...
Clay.
Bill Clay.
Know how to use a handgun, Bill?
I spent a weekend at a combat ranch.
That game with the guns
that shoot red paint.
Probably seems kind of stupid to you.
Nope.
Time for the real thing, Bill.
All you got to do
is pull the trigger.
Come on.
Put down the gun
and give me my detonators.
Well, well, well...
Hans.
Put it down now.
That's pretty tricky
with that accent.
You oughta be on fucking TV
But what do you want
with the detonators?
I already used all the explosives.
Or did l?
I'm going to count to three.
Yeah. Like you did with Takagi?
Oops.
No bullets.
What do you think...
I'm fucking stupid, Hans?
You were saying?
Karl.
SchieB dem Fenster.
Shoot the glass!
Jesus Christ!
Smile, Karl.
We're back in business.
..is the lastresort ofdiplomacy,
then couldn't wejustas well say
that terrorism has an equal claim
on being that, too?
Tell me you got something.
McClane's name, badge number,
employment record, vital statistics,
and his family's home address
right here in LA.
Whoo!
Go to work.
Got it.
God, that man looks really pissed.
He's still alive.
What?
Only John can drive
somebody that crazy.
Hans, you better heat up that miracle
because we just broke through
on number six
and the electromagnetic
came down like a fucking anvil.
Have a look at what our friends
outside are doing and I'll be right up.
Hey, John.
John McClane, you still with us?
Yeah.
But all things being equal,
I'd rather be in Philadelphia.
Chalk up two more bad guys.
The boys down here
will be glad to hear that.
We gota poolgoing on you.
What kind of odds am I getting?
You don't want to know.
Put me down for 20.
I'm good for it.
Hey, pal, you gotflatfeet?
What the hell
are you talking about, man?
Something had
to get you offthe street.
What's the matter?
You don't thinkjockeyingpapers
across a desk is a noble effortfora cop?
No.
I had an accident.
The wayyou drive, I can see why.
What'd you do ?
Run over your captain's foot
with the car?
I shot a kid.
He was 13 years old.
Oh, it was dark. I couldn'tsee him.
He hada raygun, lookedreal enough.
When you're a rookie, they teach you
everything about being a cop
except how to live with a mistake.
Anyway, ljust couldn'tbring myself
to drawmygun on anybody again.
Sorry, man.
Hey, man, how could you know?
I feel like shit anyway.
Well, then, this won't matter.
The LAPD is not calling the shots
down here any more.
The Feds?
You got it.
Those are the city engineers.
Wait.
They're going into the street circuits.
Those guys in the suits,
I don't know who they are.
That's the FBl.
They're ordering the others
to cut the building's power.
Regular as clockwork.
Or a time lock.
Precisely.
The circuits that cannot be cut
are cut automatically
in response to a terrorist incident.
You asked for miracles, Theo.
I give you the F-B-l.
I want the building shut down.
I got a problem. I got a switch...
I don't care
about your switch. I want it out. Dark!
You can't do it from here.
- Yeah, you could.
- It can't be done from here.
I could just... I got the radio...
You can't do it from here.
It's got to be done from downtown.
They've gotta take out
a whole city grid.
We're talking 10 square blocks.
Ten blocks? Johnson, that's crazy.
It's Christmas Eve.
There's thousands of people.
You have to go wider.
- I need authorisation.
- How about the United States government?
Lose the grid, or you lose yourjob.
- Yeah, Central?
- Yeah?
This is Walt down at Nakatomi.
Would it be possible for you
to turn off grid 212?
Are you crazy?!
Maybe I should call the Mayor.
No shit it's my ass.
I got a big problem here.
Shut it down now.
Emergency lighting activated.
Al, talk to me. What's going on here?
Ask the FBl.
They got the universal
terrorist playbook
and they're running it step by step.
It's gonna go. It's gonna go!
Yes!
Merry Christmas.
They must be pissing in their pants.
The Mayor is gonna have my ass.
Whoo!
What are we gonna do now ?
Arrest them for not paying
their electric bill?
We've shut them down.
We let them sweat for a while,
then we give them helicopters.
Right up the ass.
This is Agent Johnson.
No, the other one.
I want that air support ready
to lift off in five minutes.
Damn right. Fully armed.
We're on the way.
Oh, yes!
I wish to talk to the FBl.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
The State Departmenthas arranged
for the return ofyour comrades.
Helicopters are en route
as you requested.
I hearyou. We'll be ready.
By the time he figures out
what hit him, he'll be in a body bag.
When they touch down,
we'll blow the roof.
They'll spend a month
sifting through the rubble.
By the time they figure out
what went wrong,
we'll be sitting on a beach earning 20%.
Ah! Jeez!
Powell?
Yo, Powell, you got a minute?
I'm here, John.
Listen, I'm starting to get
a bad feeling up here.
I want you to do something for me.
Um... ahem...
I want you to find my wife.
Don't ask me how.
By then you'll know how.
Uh, I want you
to tell her something.
I want you to tell her that...
Tell her it took me
a while to figure out
what ajerk I've been
but, um...
that...
that when things started
to pan out for her
I should have been more supportive.
And, uh...
Ijustshouldhave been
behind hermore.
Oh, shit.
Tell her that, um
that she's the best thing
that ever happened to a bum like me.
She's heard me say "l love you"
a thousand times.
She never heard me say I'm sorry.
I want you to tell her that, Al.
Tell her that John said that he was sorry.
OK?
You got that, man?
Yeah, lgotit, John.
But you can tell her that yourself.
You just watch your ass
and you'll make it out. You hear me?
I guess that's up to the man upstairs.
John?
What the fuck
were you doing upstairs, Hans?
John?
No, Al, listen.
Just lay offfor a while.
I gotta go check on something.
One minute, that's all I'm asking.
One minute to speak to them.
All right. Get back. Get back.
All right, look.
You let me in right now,
or I call the INS, comprende?
This is the last time
these kids are gonna have
to speak to their parents.
All right?
All right. Come on. Come on.
What were you doing, Hans?
What were you doing?
Jesus, Mary, mother of God.
Al, listen to me!
It's a double-cross!
The roof is wired to...
John?
John!
John, come in!
Did you get that?
Something about a double-cross.
Tell me about it.
We are both professionals.
This is personal.
Aww...
They're coming!
Choppers are coming.
Time to gather your flock,
Miss Gennero.
Your mom and dad
are veryimportantpeople.
They're verybrave people.
Is there somethingyou'dlike
to say to them, ifthey're watching?
Come home.
Mrs McClane.
How nice to make your acquaintance.
On your feet, everyone! To the roof!
Lock them up there
and come right back.
You should have heard
your brother squeal
when I broke his fucking neck!
What do you figure the breakage?
I figure we take out the terrorists,
Iose 20, 25% ofthe hostages, tops.
I can live with that.
Get this thing on the deck.
They're expecting transports,
not gun ships.
Move it! Come on! Move!
Come on! Come on!
Move it!
Go! Move!
Theo.
A little bonus for us.
Please, sit down. Sit down!
A policeman's wife
might come in handy.
McClane, I have some news for you.
McClane?
Move!
Come on!
Motherfucker! I'll kill you!
Armed.
- The truck?
- The truck.
After all your posturing,
all your little speeches,
you're nothing but a common thief.
I am an exceptional thief,
Mrs McClane.
And since I'm moving up
to kidnapping,
you should be more polite.
You motherfucker,
I'm gonna kill you!
I'm gonna fuckin' cook you,
and I'm gonna fuckin' eat you!
I don't like this, Sarge.
Yee-hah!
Just like fucking Saigon, eh, Slick?
I was in Junior High, dickhead.
Where's Holly?
Where's Holly Gennero?
Holly Gennero? Where's Holly?
Where's Holly? Where is she?
- They took her!
- Where?
The vault!
- Where is the vault?
- The 30th floor!
They just took her!
Get downstairs!
The whole fucking roof
is wired to blow!
Get down!
Get the fuck downstairs!
They made us, Bureau.
Terrorist shooting hostages.
Break left!
Nail that sucker!
I'm on your side, you assholes!
Swing around again!
I'll bag this little bastard.
What the fuck...
Oh, John,
what the fuck are you doing?
How the fuck
did you get into this shit?
There's something wrong!
They're coming back down!
- Blow the roof.
- But Karl's up there!
Blow the roof!
I promise I will never even think
about going up
in a tall building again.
Oh, God, please don't let me die!
Holy Christ!
We're gonna need
some more FBI guys, I guess.
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fuck!
What the fuck is going on?
What are you gonna do?
Sit here while the building falls down?
Shit!
All right!
Hey! Hey!
Hang on, baby.
Hang on, honey.
Oh, God.
Hans!
Jesus.
Hi, honey.
So that's what this is all about?
A fucking robbery?
Put down the gun.
Why'd you have to nuke
the whole building, Hans?
Well, when you steal $600,
you can just disappear.
When you steal 600 million,
they will find you
unless they think
you're already dead.
Put down the gun.
Nein. This is mine.
You got me.
Still the cowboy, Mr McClane.
Americans... all alike.
This time, John Wayne does not walk off
into the sunset with Grace Kelly.
That was Gary Cooper, asshole.
Enough jokes.
You'd have made a pretty
good cowboy yourself, Hans.
Oh, yes. What was it
you said to me before?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
Holly!
Happy trails, Hans.
- Aah!
- Holly.
I hope that's not a hostage.
Gimme water hook-ups
for engine companies 5, 3, 9, 6.
Over here. It's a better angle.
Let's give them a hand.
Keep it going, now. Keep it going.
- Come on. We're going to miss it!
- OK. Hand me my notes!
What was it like in there?
How did they treat you?
Al, this is my wife Holly.
Holly Gennero.
Holly McClane.
Hello, Holly.
You got yourself a good man.
You take good care of him.
McClane!
McClane, I want a debriefing!
You got some things
to answer for, mister.
Ellis' murder, for one thing.
Property damage,
interfering with police business.
Two ofyou go inside
and see ifthere's anybody else!
No. This one's with me.
Mr McClane, Mr McClane!
Now that it's all over,
after this incredible ordeal,
what are your feelings?
Well, well, well.
- Merry Christmas, Argyle.
- Merry Christmas.
Did you get that?
Let me through.
If this is their idea of Christmas,
I gotta be here for New Year's.
Yo, Al.
I'm here, Roy,
but I'm kind of busy right now.
I'll talk to you later.
Al, what's wrong?
If you are what I think you are,
you'll know when to listen,
shut up, and
and when to pray.
Jesus Christ!
You're coming in, right?
Christ, Powell,
I told you what kind of people
you're dealing with here.
Let's load them up.
They'll be coming.
Everyone get ready.
Theo, you are the eyes now.
- Rivers.
- Yo.
Begin your reconnoitre.
Let's go.
Shit!
Come on. Let's go.
Ow! Jesus!
All right, spread out.
Shut up.
Let's go.
You macho assholes. No! No!
Ahem... all right. Listen up, guys.
'Twas the night before Christmas
and all through the house
not a creature was stirring, except
the four assholes
coming in the rear in standard
two-by-two cover formation.
We're all set.
We're ready.
Kick ass.
Go!
Right. Let's do it.
Take cover!
They're shooting at 'em.
It's panic fire.
They can't see anything.
They're shooting at the lights.
They're going after the lights.
Call them back.
It's not happening.
Mike, burn it.
Don't be impatient.
Just wound them.
Get them back.
They're sitting ducks without lights.
They're almost in.
Send in the car.
Jesus Christ!
Rivers, Rodriguez, report.
Wait a minute.
What have we here, gentlemen?
The police have themselves an RV.
Southeast corner.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Get back! Get the fuck back!
Get over there.
Schnell! Schnell!
Mach schnell!
Weiter! Weiter! Weiter!
Mach schnell! Mach schnell!
Weiter!
Mach los! Mach los!
I see him!
- Fire!
- Clear!
Oh, my God!
The quarterback is toast!
Hang on, Rivers. That's an order.
Hit it again.
All right, you motherfucker,
you made your point!
Let them pull back!
Thank you, Mr Cowboy.
I'll take it under advisement.
Hit it
again.
Fire.
Fuck me.
Get them out of the car! They're burning!
Fuck it.
Mach schnell! Mach los!
Let's see you take this
under advisement, jerkweed.
Geronimo, motherfucker.
Oh, shit!
They're using artillery on us!
You idiot, it's not the police.
It's him.
Holy shit.
My God!
- Tell me you got that.
- I got it.
Eat your heart out, Channel Five.
We've had an update
on the terrorist take over
of the Nakatomi building.
Sources say
the terroristleader, Hans,
may be this man... Hans Gruber.
A member ofthe radical
West German Volksfreimovement.
Strangely, the Volksfrei leadership
issued a communiqu an hour ago
stating that Gruber had been
expelled from that organisation.
Al, do you copy?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
W-what was that?
Remember that plastic
explosive I told you about?
There you go.
Is the building on fire?
No, but it's gonna need a paint job
and a shitload of screen doors.
Our spotter said you got two
with that blast.
- Is that him?
- Yes, sir.
I don't know who you think you are
but you just destroyed a building.
We do not want your help.
Is that clear?
We don't want your help.
I've got 100 people down here,
and they're covered with glass.
Glass? Who gives a shit about glass?
Who the fuck is this?
This is Deputy Chief of Police
Dwayne T Robinson
and I am in charge of this situation.
Oh, you're in charge?
I got some bad news for you, Dwayne.
From up here it doesn'tlook
like you're in charge ofshit.
Listen to me, you little asshole...
Asshole?
I'm not the one
who just got butt fucked
on national TV, Dwayne.
Ah ha ha!
Listen to me,jerk-off,
if you're not part of the solution,
you're part of the problem.
Quit being part of the problem
and put the other guy back on!
Hey, Roy, how you feeling?
Pretty fucking unappreciated, Al.
Hey, look. I love you.
So do a lot of the otherguys.
So hang in there, man, you hear me?
You hang in there.
Yeah, thanks, partner.
What are you doing?
I'm tired of sitting here
waiting to see
who gets us killed first,
them or your husband.
What are you going to do?
Hey, babe,
I negotiate million-dollar deals
for breakfast.
I think I can handle this Eurotrash.
Hey, sprechen sie talk, huh?
If you'd listened to me,
he would be neutralised already.
I don't want neutral. I want dead.
Hope I'm not interrupting.
What does he want?
It's not what I want.
It's what I can give you.
Look, let's be straight, OK?
It's obvious you're not
some dumb schmuck
up here to snatch a few purses.
You're very perceptive.
I watch 60 Minutes.
I say to myself,
these guys are professional,
they're motivated, they're happening,
they want something.
I couldn't care less
about your politics.
Maybe you're pissed off
at the camel jockeys.
Maybe it's the Hebes,
Northern lreland.
It's none of my business.
I figure you're here
to negotiate, am I right?
You're amazing.
You figured this all out already?
Hey, business is business.
You use a gun,
I use a fountain pen.
What's the difference?
Let's put it in my terms.
You're here on a hostile takeover.
You grab us for some green
but you didn't expect some poison pill
was gonna be running around the building.
Am I right?
Hans,
bubbie...
I'm your white knight.
I must have missed 60 Minutes.
What are you saying?
The guy upstairs
who's fucking things up, huh?
I can give him to you.
Oh, God...
Roy? Roy, you all right?
Just trying to fire down
a 1,000-year-old Twinkie.
What do they put in these things,
anyway?
Sugar, enriched flour,
partially hydrogenated
vegetable oil,
polysorbate 60,
and yellow dye number five.
Just everything
a growing boyneeds.
How many kids you got, Al?
As a matter of fact,
my wife is working on our first.
How about you, cowboy?
You got any kids
back on your ranch?
Yeah.
Two.
Sure hope I can see them
swinging on ajungle gym
with AI Jnr someday.
Well, now, that's a date
but you bring the ice cream.
Touching, cowboy. Touching.
Or shouldl call you
Mr McClane?
Mr Officer John McClane
of the New York
Police Department?
Get on the phone to Harry in New York.
You better get a hold of somebody
at Dispatch.
Sister Theresa called me
Mr McClane in the third grade.
My friends call me John
and you're neither, shithead.
I have someone
who wants to talk to you.
A very special friend
who was with you
at the party tonight.
Hey, John boy.
Ellis?
Yeah.
Listen, John, they're giving me
a few minutes to talk sense into you.
I know you think you're doing yourjob
and I can appreciate that
but you'rejust dragging
this thing out.
Look, no-one gets out of here
until these guys
can talk to the LA Police.
That won't happen until you stop
messing up the works. Capisce?
Ellis, what have you told them?
I told them we were old friends
and you were my guest
at the party.
Ellis, you shouldn't be doing this.
Tell me about it.
All right, John, listen.
They want you to tell them
where the detonators are.
They know people are listening.
They want the detonators,
or they're gonna kill me.
John, didn't you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
John, get with the programme.
The police are here now.
It's their problem.
Tell these guys where the detonators are
so no-one else gets hurt!
I'm putting my life
on the line for you, pal!
Ellis, listen to me carefully.
John...
Shut up, Ellis!
Just shut your mouth!
Put Hans back on the line.
Hans, this shithead doesn'tknow
what kind of man you are but l do.
Good. Then you'll
give us what we want
and save your friend's life.
You're not part ofthis equation.
Hey, what am l, a method actor?
Babe, putaway the gun.
This is radio, not television.
Hans, this asshole is not my friend!
I just met him tonight!
I don't know him!
Jesus Christ, Ellis!
These people will kill you!
Tell them you don't know me!
How can you say that
after all these years?
John? John?
Do you hear that?
Talk to me!
Where are my detonators?
Where are they,
or shall I shoot another one?
Sooner or later
I mightget to someone
you do care about.
Go fuck yourself, Hans.
He just let the guy die.
He just gave him up.
Give me that headset.
That's like pulling the trigger yourself.
Can't you see what's happening?
Can't you read between the lines?
He did everything he could
to save him.
If he gave himself up,
they'd both be dead right now!
No way, man. They'd be talking to us.
You tell this partner of yours
to stay out of this from now on.
Because if he doesn't,
I'm really going to nail his ass.
The man is hurting.
He is alone, tired,
and he hasn't seen diddly-squat
from anybody here!
You're gonna tell me he'll give a damn
about what you do to him
if he makes it out ofthere alive?
Why don't you wake up
and smell what you're shovelling?
You listen to me, sergeant.
Any time you want to go home,
you consider yourself dismissed.
No, sir.
You couldn't drag me away.
Attention, police.
- This is Sergeant AI Powell...
- Give me that.
This is Deputy Chief Dwayne Robinson.
Who is this?
This is Hans Gruber.
I assume you realise the futility
of direct action against me.
We have no wish
for further loss of life.
What is it you do wish for?
I have comrades in arms
around the world languishing in prison.
The American State Department
enjoys rattling its sabre for its own ends.
Now it can rattle it for me.
The following people
are to be released from their captors.
In Northern lreland the seven members
of the New Provo Front.
In Canada, the five imprisonedleaders
ofLibert de Quebec.
In Sri Lanka, the nine members
of the Asian Dawn.
What the fuck?
Asian Dawn?
I read about them in Time magazine.
When these revolutionary
brothers and sisters are free,
the hostages in this building
will be taken to the roof
and they will accompany us
in helicopters
to the Los Angeles
lnternational Airport
where they will be given
further instructions.
You have two hours to comply.
Wait a minute. Uh, Mr. Gruber.
This is crazy.
I don't have the authority.
Two hours is not enough.
Hello? Hello!
Did you get all that?
We got to make some calls.
Do you think they'll even try?
Who cares?
Theo, are we on schedule?
One more to go, then it's up to you.
You better be right
because the last one will take a miracle.
It's Christmas, Theo.
It's the time of miracles,
so be of good cheer
and call me
when you hit the last lock.
Karl,
hunt that little shit down
and get those detonators.
Fritz is checking the explosives.
I'll check the explosives.
You just get the detonators.
Hey, Powell, you out there?
I'm here, John. I'm here.
You gotta believe me.
There was nothing I could do.
Well, it's gonna be
both our asses ifyou're wrong.
I hear you.
Did you catch that bullshit
Hans was running?
It doesn'tmake sense, man.
Hey, don't ask me, man.
I'm just a deskjockey
who was on my way home when you rang.
The way you drove that car
I figured you for the street, Al.
In my youth. In my youth.
..author of "Hostage Terrorist,
Terrorist Hostage,
A Study in Duality. "
Dr Hasseldorf,
what can we expect
in the next few hours?
Well, Gail,
by this time,
the hostages should be going through
the early stages
of the Helsinki Syndrome.
As in Helsinki, Sweden.
Finland.
Basically, it's when the hostages
and the terrorists
go through a sort of
psychological transference
and a projection of dependency.
A strange sort oftrust
and bond develops.
We've hadsituations
where the hostages
have embraced their captors
after release
and even corresponded with them
in prison.
No, no, darling. Asian Dawn. Dawn.
D-A-W-N.
- Sir?
- Yeah?
Sir, the FBI is here.
- The FBI is here now?
- Yes, sir. Right over there.
Hold this.
Want a breath mint?
Hey, how you doing, man?
I'm Agent Johnson.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
- Oh, how you doing?
- No relation.
I'm, uh...
I'm Dwayne Robinson, LAPD.
I'm in charge here.
Not any more.
Hi, there. How you doing?
Ohh...
Please, God. No.
You're one ofthem, aren't you?
You're one ofthem.
No! Don't kill me! Please!
Don't kill me, please!
Please, please, please.
Whoa. Relax.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt you!
Oh, God.
What the fuck
are you doing up here?
What were you looking for?
I managed to get out ofthere and
I was just trying
to get up on the roof
and see if I could signal for help.
It's just over here.
Why don't you come and help?
Hold it. Forget the roof.
I said forget the roof.
They got people all over it.
You want to stay alive,
you stay with me.
The best we can figure it,
we've got maybe
30 or 35 hostages up there
probably on the 30th floor
and maybe seven or eight
terrorists up there.
Sounds like an A-7 scenario.
Thank you.
We'll handle it from here.
When we commandeer your men,
we'll try and let you know.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Such as?
What about John McClane?
He's the reason
we have any information.
He's also the reason
you're facing seven terrorists, not twelve.
He's inside? Who is he?
He might be a cop.
We're checking on that.
- One ofyours?
- No, no way.
You smoke?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You don't work for Nakatomi.
And ifyou're not one ofthem...
I'm a cop from New York.
New York?
Yeah.
Got invited to
the Christmas party by mistake.
Who knew?
Better than being caught
with your pants down, huh?
I'm John McClane.
You're, uh...
Clay.
Bill Clay.
Know how to use a handgun, Bill?
I spent a weekend at a combat ranch.
That game with the guns
that shoot red paint.
Probably seems kind of stupid to you.
Nope.
Time for the real thing, Bill.
All you got to do
is pull the trigger.
Come on.
Put down the gun
and give me my detonators.
Well, well, well...
Hans.
Put it down now.
That's pretty tricky
with that accent.
You oughta be on fucking TV
But what do you want
with the detonators?
I already used all the explosives.
Or did l?
I'm going to count to three.
Yeah. Like you did with Takagi?
Oops.
No bullets.
What do you think...
I'm fucking stupid, Hans?
You were saying?
Karl.
SchieB dem Fenster.
Shoot the glass!
Jesus Christ!
Smile, Karl.
We're back in business.
..is the lastresort ofdiplomacy,
then couldn't wejustas well say
that terrorism has an equal claim
on being that, too?
Tell me you got something.
McClane's name, badge number,
employment record, vital statistics,
and his family's home address
right here in LA.
Whoo!
Go to work.
Got it.
God, that man looks really pissed.
He's still alive.
What?
Only John can drive
somebody that crazy.
Hans, you better heat up that miracle
because we just broke through
on number six
and the electromagnetic
came down like a fucking anvil.
Have a look at what our friends
outside are doing and I'll be right up.
Hey, John.
John McClane, you still with us?
Yeah.
But all things being equal,
I'd rather be in Philadelphia.
Chalk up two more bad guys.
The boys down here
will be glad to hear that.
We gota poolgoing on you.
What kind of odds am I getting?
You don't want to know.
Put me down for 20.
I'm good for it.
Hey, pal, you gotflatfeet?
What the hell
are you talking about, man?
Something had
to get you offthe street.
What's the matter?
You don't thinkjockeyingpapers
across a desk is a noble effortfora cop?
No.
I had an accident.
The wayyou drive, I can see why.
What'd you do ?
Run over your captain's foot
with the car?
I shot a kid.
He was 13 years old.
Oh, it was dark. I couldn'tsee him.
He hada raygun, lookedreal enough.
When you're a rookie, they teach you
everything about being a cop
except how to live with a mistake.
Anyway, ljust couldn'tbring myself
to drawmygun on anybody again.
Sorry, man.
Hey, man, how could you know?
I feel like shit anyway.
Well, then, this won't matter.
The LAPD is not calling the shots
down here any more.
The Feds?
You got it.
Those are the city engineers.
Wait.
They're going into the street circuits.
Those guys in the suits,
I don't know who they are.
That's the FBl.
They're ordering the others
to cut the building's power.
Regular as clockwork.
Or a time lock.
Precisely.
The circuits that cannot be cut
are cut automatically
in response to a terrorist incident.
You asked for miracles, Theo.
I give you the F-B-l.
I want the building shut down.
I got a problem. I got a switch...
I don't care
about your switch. I want it out. Dark!
You can't do it from here.
- Yeah, you could.
- It can't be done from here.
I could just... I got the radio...
You can't do it from here.
It's got to be done from downtown.
They've gotta take out
a whole city grid.
We're talking 10 square blocks.
Ten blocks? Johnson, that's crazy.
It's Christmas Eve.
There's thousands of people.
You have to go wider.
- I need authorisation.
- How about the United States government?
Lose the grid, or you lose yourjob.
- Yeah, Central?
- Yeah?
This is Walt down at Nakatomi.
Would it be possible for you
to turn off grid 212?
Are you crazy?!
Maybe I should call the Mayor.
No shit it's my ass.
I got a big problem here.
Shut it down now.
Emergency lighting activated.
Al, talk to me. What's going on here?
Ask the FBl.
They got the universal
terrorist playbook
and they're running it step by step.
It's gonna go. It's gonna go!
Yes!
Merry Christmas.
They must be pissing in their pants.
The Mayor is gonna have my ass.
Whoo!
What are we gonna do now ?
Arrest them for not paying
their electric bill?
We've shut them down.
We let them sweat for a while,
then we give them helicopters.
Right up the ass.
This is Agent Johnson.
No, the other one.
I want that air support ready
to lift off in five minutes.
Damn right. Fully armed.
We're on the way.
Oh, yes!
I wish to talk to the FBl.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
The State Departmenthas arranged
for the return ofyour comrades.
Helicopters are en route
as you requested.
I hearyou. We'll be ready.
By the time he figures out
what hit him, he'll be in a body bag.
When they touch down,
we'll blow the roof.
They'll spend a month
sifting through the rubble.
By the time they figure out
what went wrong,
we'll be sitting on a beach earning 20%.
Ah! Jeez!
Powell?
Yo, Powell, you got a minute?
I'm here, John.
Listen, I'm starting to get
a bad feeling up here.
I want you to do something for me.
Um... ahem...
I want you to find my wife.
Don't ask me how.
By then you'll know how.
Uh, I want you
to tell her something.
I want you to tell her that...
Tell her it took me
a while to figure out
what ajerk I've been
but, um...
that...
that when things started
to pan out for her
I should have been more supportive.
And, uh...
Ijustshouldhave been
behind hermore.
Oh, shit.
Tell her that, um
that she's the best thing
that ever happened to a bum like me.
She's heard me say "l love you"
a thousand times.
She never heard me say I'm sorry.
I want you to tell her that, Al.
Tell her that John said that he was sorry.
OK?
You got that, man?
Yeah, lgotit, John.
But you can tell her that yourself.
You just watch your ass
and you'll make it out. You hear me?
I guess that's up to the man upstairs.
John?
What the fuck
were you doing upstairs, Hans?
John?
No, Al, listen.
Just lay offfor a while.
I gotta go check on something.
One minute, that's all I'm asking.
One minute to speak to them.
All right. Get back. Get back.
All right, look.
You let me in right now,
or I call the INS, comprende?
This is the last time
these kids are gonna have
to speak to their parents.
All right?
All right. Come on. Come on.
What were you doing, Hans?
What were you doing?
Jesus, Mary, mother of God.
Al, listen to me!
It's a double-cross!
The roof is wired to...
John?
John!
John, come in!
Did you get that?
Something about a double-cross.
Tell me about it.
We are both professionals.
This is personal.
Aww...
They're coming!
Choppers are coming.
Time to gather your flock,
Miss Gennero.
Your mom and dad
are veryimportantpeople.
They're verybrave people.
Is there somethingyou'dlike
to say to them, ifthey're watching?
Come home.
Mrs McClane.
How nice to make your acquaintance.
On your feet, everyone! To the roof!
Lock them up there
and come right back.
You should have heard
your brother squeal
when I broke his fucking neck!
What do you figure the breakage?
I figure we take out the terrorists,
Iose 20, 25% ofthe hostages, tops.
I can live with that.
Get this thing on the deck.
They're expecting transports,
not gun ships.
Move it! Come on! Move!
Come on! Come on!
Move it!
Go! Move!
Theo.
A little bonus for us.
Please, sit down. Sit down!
A policeman's wife
might come in handy.
McClane, I have some news for you.
McClane?
Move!
Come on!
Motherfucker! I'll kill you!
Armed.
- The truck?
- The truck.
After all your posturing,
all your little speeches,
you're nothing but a common thief.
I am an exceptional thief,
Mrs McClane.
And since I'm moving up
to kidnapping,
you should be more polite.
You motherfucker,
I'm gonna kill you!
I'm gonna fuckin' cook you,
and I'm gonna fuckin' eat you!
I don't like this, Sarge.
Yee-hah!
Just like fucking Saigon, eh, Slick?
I was in Junior High, dickhead.
Where's Holly?
Where's Holly Gennero?
Holly Gennero? Where's Holly?
Where's Holly? Where is she?
- They took her!
- Where?
The vault!
- Where is the vault?
- The 30th floor!
They just took her!
Get downstairs!
The whole fucking roof
is wired to blow!
Get down!
Get the fuck downstairs!
They made us, Bureau.
Terrorist shooting hostages.
Break left!
Nail that sucker!
I'm on your side, you assholes!
Swing around again!
I'll bag this little bastard.
What the fuck...
Oh, John,
what the fuck are you doing?
How the fuck
did you get into this shit?
There's something wrong!
They're coming back down!
- Blow the roof.
- But Karl's up there!
Blow the roof!
I promise I will never even think
about going up
in a tall building again.
Oh, God, please don't let me die!
Holy Christ!
We're gonna need
some more FBI guys, I guess.
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fuck!
What the fuck is going on?
What are you gonna do?
Sit here while the building falls down?
Shit!
All right!
Hey! Hey!
Hang on, baby.
Hang on, honey.
Oh, God.
Hans!
Jesus.
Hi, honey.
So that's what this is all about?
A fucking robbery?
Put down the gun.
Why'd you have to nuke
the whole building, Hans?
Well, when you steal $600,
you can just disappear.
When you steal 600 million,
they will find you
unless they think
you're already dead.
Put down the gun.
Nein. This is mine.
You got me.
Still the cowboy, Mr McClane.
Americans... all alike.
This time, John Wayne does not walk off
into the sunset with Grace Kelly.
That was Gary Cooper, asshole.
Enough jokes.
You'd have made a pretty
good cowboy yourself, Hans.
Oh, yes. What was it
you said to me before?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
Holly!
Happy trails, Hans.
- Aah!
- Holly.
I hope that's not a hostage.
Gimme water hook-ups
for engine companies 5, 3, 9, 6.
Over here. It's a better angle.
Let's give them a hand.
Keep it going, now. Keep it going.
- Come on. We're going to miss it!
- OK. Hand me my notes!
What was it like in there?
How did they treat you?
Al, this is my wife Holly.
Holly Gennero.
Holly McClane.
Hello, Holly.
You got yourself a good man.
You take good care of him.
McClane!
McClane, I want a debriefing!
You got some things
to answer for, mister.
Ellis' murder, for one thing.
Property damage,
interfering with police business.
Two ofyou go inside
and see ifthere's anybody else!
No. This one's with me.
Mr McClane, Mr McClane!
Now that it's all over,
after this incredible ordeal,
what are your feelings?
Well, well, well.
- Merry Christmas, Argyle.
- Merry Christmas.
Did you get that?
Let me through.
If this is their idea of Christmas,
I gotta be here for New Year's.