- [Rustling]
- [Man On Radio] We've been receiving...
so many calls, asking
about this marvelous airship...
the Spirit of Freedom...
which, uh, may or may not
be passing over our area soon.
I'll let you know as soon as we have
more information available.
But, fiirst, here's the weather forecast.
Skies are clearing up,
thanks to a high-pressure front
moving in from the mountains.
Mild winds will be blowing in from the west...
- pushing the clouds out by this evening.
- [Bee Buzzing]
There'll be a beautiful
full moon lighting up the skies...
so, if you've been
planning something special,
tonight might be the night.
Tomorrow also looks good
with clear skies and sun.
[Clicks Off Radio]
- Mornin'!
- Hi!
[Bird Chirps]
- Jiji, wake up.! Tonight's the night.
- Hmm?
Hey, Mom! Oh.
Hi, Miss Dora. Hey, Mom, it's gonna
be clear tonight.
And, guess what.
The radio says there'll be a full moon!
Did you borrow your father's radio
again without asking?
Don't worry. He doesn't mind.
Please excuse me, Miss Dora.
Mom, it's a perfect midnight
for me to leave home.
You mean tonight?
Next month is what you told me.
Yeah, but the next
full moon might be on a cloudy night.
And, I want to leave
on the perfect midnight.
Huh? But, Kiki... Wait!
Ohh...
[Gasps]
Uhh...
[Sighs]
My, oh, my. What's this all about?
It's one of our oldest customs
that when a witch turns 13...
she has to leave home for a year
to begin her training.
- Your little baby is 13?
- [Sighs]
My goodness, but time flies so quickly.
I know. She seems so young
to be leaving home now.
I remember very well
the exact day you arrived in this town.
A little girl flew down from the sky
on her broomstick.
And, I was certain
she was much too young
to hold such an importantjob...
as resident witch.
- [Chuckles]
- Yes, but I could fly. Kiki
barely knows how to do that.
And, I have had no time
to teach her how to mix potions like me.
Hmm. Young people are all the same.
They all want to do something different.
But, I hope, you at least get to teach her...
- the potion that cures my rheumatism.
- [Laughs]
Hurry up! We always said
we'd leave on the perfect night, didn't we?
Uh-uh. Our plan was that
we would stick around for
another month and play it safe.
I liked that plan.
And, if we put it off for a
month, and I find some wonderful
boyfriend, then what'll we do?
- Uh-oh!
- Come on, Jiji.!
I'm gonna put my paws together
and pray you're not serious.
Of course, I am.
You know ever since I turned 13,
I've been excited about making this trip.
- [Car Approaching]
- There. Dad!
Dad! Guess what!
I've decided to leave tonight!
- You're... You're going away?
- Yeah, there's a full moon!
Well, yeah, but what happened
to the camping trip...
we were supposed
to take this weekend?
Sorry, Dad!
Aah, oh... Uh, Kiki, wait!
I need... Whoa! Ya... Ow!
Ahh... Ohh...
Ye... Yeah,
I'll expect you then. Thanks.
Hi, Mom, it's me.
I wanted to make sure you knew
that Kiki is leaving tonight.
Yes, midnight.
- Very pretty.
- Lilac would look prettier on me.
- Or, white.
- Witches have worn this color
for a very long time, Kiki.
Oh, Mom, I look really dumb.
It's not really important
what color your dress is.
What matters is the heart inside.
Well, I'm gonna be the very
best witch that I can be, Mom.
And, I know having
a good heart is important.
- Just follow your heart and keep smiling.
- Yeah.
- And, be sure to write home
as soon as you're settled.
- Okay.
Dad! Oh. Can I please take the radio?
- Mom, didn't you say I could have the radio?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yea.!
- All right. It's yours already.
- Thank you.!
- Well, now. You certainly
look very grown up.
- My little princess.
- [Giggles]
#Ta-da ##
You look just like your mother,
when she was young.
I'm glad about that.
Dad, can you lift me up high,
like when I was little?
Well...
- Uhh... Uh... I don't know.
[Grunts]
- Oh...
- Here we go!
- [Laughs]
- Oh.
How come you never
told me you were growin' up so fast?
If things don't work out, you can
always come home.
And come back a failure? Ooh-aghh!
[Laughing]
Will you write us if you have the time?
Mm-hmm. Oh, I love you, Dad.
[Woman] After all, she is a baby.
[Man] I won't disagree with you there.
It's beautiful.
But aren't you worried about
Kiki living in the big city all alone?
Of course they are, but Kiki'll be just fine.
- You're gonna find a city by the ocean?
- Or maybe a town?
Uh-huh. That's what I'm hoping, anyway.
- Wow. You're gonna have such a good time.
- Wow, I'm so jealous.
- You'll have so much fun!
- But I'm not going just for a good time.
In order to be a good witch,
I have to train a year away from home.
Yeah. Be sure to tell that to the boys.
- [Girls Giggling]
- Kiki, it's time.
- 'Kay!
- Oh.
That's the broom you're going
to be leaving on?
Yep! I just made it
this morning all by myself.
Honey, it's too small to be really safe.
I'd rather you took my broom.
I know it better.
But, Mom, that one's so old!
And, that's why it's good.
You can rely on it time after time
in any kind of weather.
Now, Kiki, do this for me, please.
But I put so much work into this one.
Right, Jiji?
- Your broom is nice, but
let's take your mother's.
- You're no help!
Now, Kiki, can't you make
yourself another fine broom
when you get settled down?
Mm-hmm.
- Umm-hmm.
- Be careful.
- You be strong, okay?
- I will!
- Bye!
- Bye, Kiki!
- [Girl] Fly safely.!
- [Girl] Go get 'em.! Good-bye.!
Oh, dear!
Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki!
Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki! Go!
[Gasps] Uhh! Uhh!
- [Parents Gasp]
- [Jiji] Bear right!
- [Jiji] Go left! Go left! Go left!
- [Kiki] Okay!
- [Bells Ringing]
- [Jiji] Oww.!
Aim your broomstick!
[Kiki] Good-bye, everybody.!
I'll miss you.!
She's okay.
May our little baby be well and have
a safe trip.
I'm going to miss the wonderful sound
of those bells.
Mm-hmm.
- [Wind Howling]
- Where are we going?
I'm headed south to see the ocean.
Jiji, climb up and turn on the radio.
I don't think I can handle it.
Can you do it?
Oh, great!
- Now, I'm suddenly the flight attendant.
- [Clicks]
- ## [Up-tempo]
- Uhh-ah...
- Uhh-uhh...
[Laughing]
[Woman]
##My heart is ready to beat ##
##I can feel the wind
underneath my feet ##
##I'm gonna jump
over the moon ##
##Hands in the air
waving up like a balloon ##
##I'm free as a bird ##
##Lost in the stars
and waving down to Earth ##
##Don't know where
I'm gonna land ##
##But ya gotta wobble
before you stand ##
##I'm soaring ##
##All alone and on my own ##
##And I know my heart
will lead me home ##
##Just look in my eyes ##
## Can't you see I'm not
the same today ##
##I can see farther now ##
##Stepped off the edge
I'm making my own way ##
##Don't know where
I'm gonna land ##
##But ya gotta wobble
before you stand ##
##I'm soaring ##
##All alone and on my own ##
##And I know my heart
will lead me home ####
[Skipped item nr. 162]
- Hey. Good evening!
- It was.!
- You're new, aren't you?
- Yep! How'd ya guess?
- I just left home tonight.
- Uh-huh. Would you mind
turning off that radio?
I prefer to fly without being distracted.
- Oh! Yeah, sure!
- [Clicks]
Could you tell me?
Is it really hard to get settled
into a brand-new city?
Oh, yes. A lot can go wrong.
But since my skill is fortune-telling,
I can handle anything.
- Fortune-telling?
- Yes. I tell fortunes about love.
- Wow!
- And, what exactly is your skill?
Um... Well, I haven't
really decided that yet.
Ah. Well, I'm nearly finished with
my training period.
I'm going home soon
to show off my new skills.
- That's my town down there.
- It's so big.!
Yes. To you, I'm sure it looks big.
- I hope you don't have too tough a time.
- Thanks!
Ciao!
Jeez, what a snob!
And did you see that cat?
[Blows Raspberry]
What's my skill?
[Thunder Crash]
- [Kiki Screams]
- [Jiji] Whooaa!
What are we gonna do? We can't stay up!
- Hold on!
- Whoa!
[Jiji] All right.
First, don't panic! Second, don't panic!
And, third...
Did I mention not to panic?
- [Jiji Grunts]
- Hold on tight!
- Ohh!
- Huh? Mmm-mmm!
Kiki, that opening is extremely small.!
- 'Kay! Nice landing.
- Uh... [Grunts]
- [Shudders]
- We better rest here until it's dry.
- Won't we get in trouble?
- Not if nobody finds us.
Oh, dear.
This is perfect.
- Oh... I'm soaked through down to the bone.
- Hello?
Uhh... uh!
Ahh! Mmm! This smells great!
And, it's warm too! Let's get some sleep.
- Kiki, I get the feeling we're not alone.
- Night, Jiji.
[Horn Blowing]
[Engine Idling]
[Horn Blares]
[Train Wheels Clattering Rhythmically]
[Cows Mooing]
- [Screams]
- Yeoww!
Ahh! Ah!
[Laughing]
Aha! Aha-ha-ha.
[Grunts]
I think I hear cows!
I think I smell cows.
Oops! Sorry. We didn't mean to fall
asleep in your breakfast.
Wow!
Jiji, you've gotta come see the ocean.
It's beautiful!
- Big deal. It's just a big puddle of water.
- Look! Up ahead!
Mm-hmm... And this would
be interesting because?
It's a city, floating on waves.!
Isn't it wonderful.!
It's all right. I guess.
How lovely!
- I wonder if they have a witch there.
- Oh, great.
[Train Horn Blares]
Ready. Set. Go-o-o!
- Hold on! Ah!
- Oh!
[Laughing]
- [Groans]
- You okay back there?
- Fine.
- Wow!
This is just the kind
of place I've always imagined.
Look out below!
Whoo-whoo!
[Laughing]
Whoo! Hi there!
Whoo.!
[Laughing]
- Hello!
- [Man On Boat] 'Lo!
[Bell Tolling In The Distance]
Wow.! A clock tower.
Look at this city! A place like this
would be great to live in.
But there may be
some witches living here already.
And, there may not be.
- Steady. Careful. Careful.
- Where are we going now, Kiki?
The clock tower. I bet
you can see the whole city from there.
There're so many beautiful buildings!
There are a lot of buildings... Yes.
[Gasps]
Ahh...
Jiji, look at all the cars.!
Yes.
Lots and lots of cars.
- And, the market.! Oh...
- With much hustling and bustling... Yes.
Oh, Jiji, it's so amazing.!
And... Andjust look.!
Look at how many people there are!
Too many, if ya ask me!
Bless my hourglass.
It's a real, live witch.!
- Good morning.!
- Morning!
- Do any witches live in this town?
- Why, uh...
Nobody's seen one
around here in a long time.
That's great! Our trip is over.
We're staying right here.
- Thanks, mister! Bye!
- Uh, no problem.!
- Tell me we're not landing down there.
- Well, of course we are!
- Hey, check that out!
- Oh, my!
- Woo-o-o!
- Ooh!
- Wow!
- Well, we're not too conspicuous.
- Hey, up there. Way to go!
- They're looking at us.
- I know. Smile, so we make a good impression.
- Hee-hee.
- Wow!
- Look. She's got a cat.!
- Good day. Hello.
You'd think they'd never
seen a girl and a cat on a broomstick before.
- Kiki. Bus!
- [Kiki Screams]
[Gasps]
Uhh... Whoa!
- [Tires Screeching]
- [Screams] Oww! Ohh...
- [Crowd Gasps]
- Whoa-a-a-a!
- Hey, watch out!
- Wow... Whoa!
[Kiki Gasping]
Smooth. Very smooth.
You definitely know how
to make a good first impression.
- Huh?
Um, hi! My name's Kiki, and I'm a witch.
And this is Jiji. He's my black cat.
And we'd be honored
if we could live here.
[Murmuring]
Your city is so amazing.
And what a beautiful clock tower.
Oh-h-h... Really. That's very nice,
dear. Bye.
Uh... Uhh...
- [Man] Taxi? Taxi?
- [Whistle Blows]
- [Footsteps Running]
- Hey, you kid!
Who do you think you are, jumping out
into the street like that?
You were almost responsible for
a big accident, zooming around
on your broom back there.
But I'm a new witch, sir.
We're supposed to fly around.
You're supposed to obey
the law. I'm gonna have to write you up.
Now give me your name and address.
- Will you tell my parents?
- Of course I'm going to tell your parents!
- I have to do that with every minor.
- [Boy] Thief.! Thief.!
- Hmm? Huh? Hey!
- [Boy] Somebody, call
the cops.! He's gettin'away.!
- Now you stay right there!
- [Man] Did he say thief?
[Woman]
My goodness.! What happened?
[Jiji] Kiki, he said to stay here. No!
He told us to stay there!
We don't want to get in trouble, Kiki.
- Uh, Kiki?
- [Boy] Hello?
- [Horn Beeps]
- Huh?
Miss! Wait up!
I sure fooled that cop, huh?
Hey, that was me yellin' "thief."
You'll be okay now.
Worked out pretty good, huh?
You gotta be a real witch,
the way you can fly that broom.
Do you think, maybe,
you can teach me how to fly it?
Hey, Tombo.! Maybe you can sweep her
offher feet with that broom.
- [Laughing]
- Hey, shut up, all right? Who-o-a! Hey...
You know, miss, I love flying too.
Could I see your broom?
- Hey, wait!
- Thank you for getting me out of trouble.
But I really shouldn't
be talking to you,
and you wanna know why?
It's very rude to talk to a girl
before you've been introduced
and before you know her name.
- Hmph!
- [Stammers]
Hmm.
You're kind of old-fashioned,
aren't ya? You sound like my grandmother.
Just go away and leave me alone!
Hey! Don't go. Come back. Wait up, huh?
Ohh! Oh...
Hmm. What a cool witch.
[Clicks Tongue] Come on.
Stay here tonight? I'm afraid
I don't understand.
Your parents are here
with you, aren't they?
No, sir, I'm alone.
I've come to this town because
I'm a new witch in training.
Do you have some identification?
Oh, never mind.
- [Children Chattering]
- Hey, hey, come on over here.
Kiki, aren't you going to eat that?
No, you can have it, Jiji.
Where are we going to stay tonight?
- [Siren Approaching]
- Huh?
Let's go.
Why don't we go find another town?
I'll bet there are bigger
and better ones. Ones that
are friendlier than this.
Just a thought.
Oh, dear.
Oh, my goodness.!
Hey there! Your pacifier!
Ma'am, you forgot your baby's pacifiier.!
Oh! Poor baby.
Without this, the baby'll wake
up and cry all the way home.
I better go give it to her myself.
I'm sorry, folks. But could
you wait just a minute? I'll be right back.
- [Man] Uh-huh.
- [Woman] Certainly.
- Excuse me. But would you like
me to deliver it for you?
- What?
The woman with the baby carriage
who just went around the corner.
- I could reach her in no time.
- Really? You'd do that?
- Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
- Let's go, Jiji!
- Excuse me, young lady!
[Gasps]
Oh! Oh, my goodness!
Oh...
[Laughs]
Wow!
Uh, Kiki, is this really
any of our business?
Kiki? No, I thought not.
- Wow!
- [Gasps] Oh!
Sorry to surprise you, but
the lady in the bakery asked me
to return this pacifier.
Oh!
Here you go.
[Both Laughing]
- Here ya go.
- Eh, I'd like one of those.
Yes, sir. Oh, hi there. Come in
and wait a minute, will you?
- Excuse me.
- Mmm. These are nice and fresh.
Just out of the oven.
- There you are.
- All right. Thank you very much.
- Here you go. See you tomorrow. Bye.
- Mm-hmm.
That'll be all for you?
All right. Thank you.
- Now come back again!
- Thanks.
But of course.
When I saw you fly off,
I thought for a second I was dreaming!
The baby's mother told me
to give you this message.
Hmm?
"Thanks for returning the
pacifier. Your new delivery
girl is really quite special."
- Well, I'll be on my way.
- Wait!
Wait a minute. I really must do something
to show you my thanks.
Huh?
Follow me. Bakery's downstairs,
upstairs is home.
- Sit down and relax. Would
you like some hot chocolate?
- Okay.
## [Humming]
- There you go.
- Thank you very much, ma'am.
And, this is for you, little guy.
So, tell me if I'm right.
- I'm guessing you're a witch in training.
- You're right.!
And I really love it here,
but people don't seem to like
witches in this town.
Depends on the people.
Now, take me, for instance.
I just met you and I know I like you.
- [Meows]
- So, tell me, whereabouts
are you two staying?
- Uhh...
- Oh, I see.
Why didn't you tell me you have
no place to stay? We have
a spare room in the attic.
- You can use that.
- You'd really let me stay with you?
[Laughs]
Why, of course! But we haven't
introduced ourselves.
- My name's Osono.
- And I'm Kiki, ma'am. And Jiji
here is my very best friend.
It's right up here, Kiki.
It may need a little dusting...
but I think you'll like it.
Oh, my. It's a little bit
dustier than I remember.
- If I weren't about to have
a baby, I'd help you clean.
- That's okay!
All right, then. Water
and bathroom are downstairs.
- Give a shout if you need anything.
- Thank you.
- This is... quaint.
- Jiji.
This isn't dust on the floor,
you know. It's flour.
- [Kiki Coughs]
- Hmph.
If you wake up tomorrow
and find a white cat, it's me.
[Man Chattering]
[Sighs]
Oh-h-h... Jiji, we can see
the ocean from here!
[Sighs]
Can we look for a new town?
[Groans] Mmm!
Well, well, well.!
- Hello, kitty.!
- [Meows] Hmph!
Huh! Pardon me, Miss Snooty Cat!
[Bell Tolling]
[Siren Wailing]
[Man On Radio] I think
the excitement is building for
the moment when the big blimp...
appears in our skies.
So, we're gonna go to Scott...
live... as he reports in
from Freedom Base One.
Jiji, I've decided
not to leave this town.
- Maybe I can stay and find some
other nice people like Osono,
- You know, Jack, I think...
- who will like me and accept me for who I am.
- Our audience would agree...
Spectacular if the ship made
some kind oflanding so everyone
could get a closer look.
- [Clicks]
- [Sighs]
[Foghorn Blares]
- [Groans] More sleep, thank you.
- Oh.
[Sighs]
[Murmurs, Sighs]
[Grunts]
[Toilet Flushing]
[Gasps]
####[Whistling]
[Grunts]
[Gasps]
[Man On Radio]
But the amazing thing is there's
never been a dirigible...
this large and this safe before.
How much do you think it would
cost to get a phone here?
- A phone?
- Yep. We're gonna need a phone.
And I personally think that what
money you have should be spent
on getting us back home.
Or, at least, on buying me
some decent cat food. And
another thing...
- Morning, everyone!
- Well, look who's up!
- Did you sleep well?
- Yes. Oh, that smells good!
- Can I help out?
- Sure can.!
Osono, I have something
I want to talk to you about.
Whoa!
- Ooh, a delivery business, huh?
- Well, I really only have
one skill and that's flying.
So I thought a delivery service
wouldn't be a bad idea.
It's a great idea...
Kiki's Flying Delivery Service.
And, since you're
staying right here, I can
be your very fiirst account.
You mean it! Oh, that's great!
[Laughs]
I was planning on putting
a phone upstairs.
- But a phone is so expensive.
- I have a little saved up already.
Don't waste your money.!
What I think you should do
is use our phone.
You know it will take some time
to get regular customers.
I'll make you a deal.
Since I'm expecting a baby,
I could use help.
If you mind the store,
once in a while, I'll let you
have the room and the phone.
And, I'll throw in a free breakfast, okay?
Yeah! We've got a deal!
I'm gonna work very hard for you.
Yo... [Laughs]
Osono, you're the greatest!
Oh...
[Laughs]
Huh? Uhh...
- [Man] It's gonna be a beautiful day.
- [Woman] Good morning, Martha.
- ####[Man Humming]
- [Woman Laughing]
[Man On Radio]
But here at the headquarters for
Spirit of Freedom operations...
the flight plan
is no unscheduled stops
between here and the coast.
The weather right now
is very favorable...
Jiji! Come on! I'm all through!
- We're gonna go shopping. Come on!
- Great!
- One can of cat food is all I ask.
- Okay, we'll see.
- [Man] Watch out.!
- [Kiki Screams]
[Gasps]
Kiki, in the city, you can't
just run out into the street.
I'm sorry. We're still alive, aren't we?
- [Girl] Look, you know how boys are.
- [Giggling]
[Girl] He's so cute. I hope he's still
invited to her birthday party.
- Don't you? [Laughing]
- Yeah!
[Laughing]
I wish I had something pretty to wear.
My dress is so ugly.
[Man]
Yes, ma'am, canned peas are
right over there on aisle two.
[Man] $ 1. 1 9 a pound.
Oh, wow! This cost so much!
Kiki, look! It's me!
[Cash Register Clattering]
- [Bell Chimes]
- Thank you. Here's your change.
- Any money left, Kiki?
- Not much.
Looks like all we can afford
to eat now is pancakes.
I hope I can keep my trim waist.
I wouldn't want that
girl cat next door to think
I'm turning into... Kiki!
Kiki?
They're so expensive.!
But look, Jiji. Aren't they beautiful!
- [Youths Laughing]
- Whoa! Whoa...
- [Laughing]
- Oh! Huh...
- Hey! Pull over!
- Hey! Come on. Get off!
- There she is!
- Hey there! Miss Witch!
Do you remember me?
How come you're not flying today?
- Ahh...
- It's me! Do you remember? Tombo.
- Eww, Tombo.!
- Oh-oh.!
You can tell she's a witch
'cause she always wears a dark dress.
Hey, wait! Come back, please.
I didn't mean to insult you!
- Yeah!
- Better luck next time, Tombo!
- Come on, you guys.!
- Nice dress.! [Laughter]
Kiki, sometimes you just
have to be who you are...
and not care what people think.
Oh, Kiki, perfect timing!
There's a lady here
who wants you to make a delivery.!
- She's your fiirst customer.
- Customer! Oh, my. I'll be right back!
- [Footsteps Running]
- [Panting] Ohh-h-h! Uh...
Now, where's that map?
[Panting]
- She sounds wonderful.
- [Panting] Aah... Uh.
Ah!
Dear, this lady is a customer
of ours, and we were talking
about your new delivery service.
What a charming girl!
- My name's Kiki, ma'am.
- Osono's told me great things about you.
Do you think you can
deliver this by tonight?
Yeah! I can.
It's a birthday gift for my nephew.
But something came up
at work, and I can't make it
to the party on time.
I can get it there for you, guaranteed.
- Show me on the map
where you want it delivered.
- Huh? But that's me.
Are you sure it won't be too far?
I can fly there straight from here.
- Great, how much will it cost?
- Oh. Well, I haven't really
thought about a price.
Aha! How about this much then?
I hope it'll be enough.
What do you think?
[Gasps] This much for me?
That's great! Thank you!
- [Brakes Squeaking]
- Huh?
Yeah! I gotta see this!
[Panting]
- [Gasps]
- She's the most amazing girl!
- She sure is!
Hey, what can you tell me about her?
[Jiji] It's beautiful flying weather, and...
gee, but we're flying awfully high.
You're getting very good at your flying.
Yes. You're just able to fly higher and higher
and higher, aren't you?
Kiki, how high do you intend to go?
This is my first job,
and I do not want to be stopped
by that traffic cop.
Hmm... Well, don't look now,
but that's an airplane flying under us.
This is as high as we'll go,
'fraidy cat. I just want to check the map.
Now, let's see. Yep! It's just past the cape.
- Here we go! Whee-e-e-e...
- Whoa, boy!
- I'm getting to like this town more and more.
- I'm getting sick to my stomach.
I can't wait to write Mom
and Dad about my new business.
- [Birds Calling]
- [Gasps]
Wow!
Look who's behind us. Wild geese!
And they're coming with us!
[Sighs] Aah... Ha.
- [Geese Calling]
- Hi-i-i-i! [Laughs]
- They seem awfully upset.
- They say they're going to fly higher.
- Huh?
- They say a gust of wind's coming.
Oh!
[Wind Howling]
- [Screams]
- Hold on, Kiki!
- Uh-oh-h-h-h...
- Kiki! The cage!
[Kiki Panting]
- [Jiji] Whoa... Whoa!
- [Kiki Grunts]
[Jiji] Whoa-a-a-a-a-a...
[Kiki Grunts, Groans]
[Bird Squawks]
- [Squawking Continues]
- [Kiki Sighs]
Ahh! A nest!
- Oh, I'm sorry! Ow! Oh!
- [Squawking Continues]
[Kiki] Leave me alone!
I wasn't trying to steal your
eggs! Really.! Uh... Uh...
Go away.! Go away.! Ugh.!
What was the matter with them?
Oh, my goodness!
That was your fault.
The geese were kind enough
to warn us of that wind.
- But would you listen?
- Oh, be quiet!
Look at them.! Up so high.
- That gust of wind took them all the way up.
- Kiki, we've got a problem.!
- The toy fell out!
- We've gotta go back!
[Grunts] Ahh...
- Back to where?
- Where we fell.!
- Come on, Jiji!
- [Birds Squawking]
[Gasps] Oh!
What are they saying now, Jiji?
They're calling you
an egg stealer. And you don't
wanna know what else.
- If I were you, I wouldn't
go back down there... again.
- We have to! Hold on!
Oh, no.! Kiki, brace yourself.!
[Screaming]
[Screams]
Kiki, look.! Look.!
- Hey! Stop that! Go away! Oh...
- [Screams]
Leave us alone! Stop it!
Maybe we better rethink our plan.
Frankly, I think this is a major insult.
Crows used to serve witches
and do what you told them.
Hey, that was a long time ago, okay?
How about if we go in after dark?
Go in. Get it. Get out.
We won't be able to make it in time.
Unless we buy ourselves some time.
You gotta be kidding!
You can just pretend to be the doll until
I find the real one.
Why don't you pretend
to be stuffed, and I'll go
get the stupid doll?
- Uh-oh!
- Don't worry. Hold still.
- Can I breathe?
- No! No breathing.
[Jiji Whimpers]
- [Whispers] Act stuffed.
- [Doorbell Buzzes]
- Oh, dear.
- Be quiet!
It must be my present from Auntie.!
- Yea! Give it to me! Ha!
- Oh!
This is dumb!
[Laughs]
You're a bit late! After
my sister telephoned, we were
wondering where you were.
Uh, I'm sorry. Uh...
Ah... Um. Could I please have
your signature, ma'am?
- Mom, can I put the canary in here?
- Uh-huh.
- But you be sure not to let it fly away, Ket.
- 'Kay. [Laughs]
Ahh... Um...
I've gotta run! Bye!
Oh...
Thank you! Enjoy your present!
Well! Woo...
Come on, you stupid bird.!
I got a brand-new home for you.
[Grunts]
[Whimpers] Please hurry, Kiki.
[Groans]
I know you fell close by, so
you've got to be here somewhere.
[Gasps]
There you are!
Hello! Anyone home?
Is anybody here? Anybody? Hello!
- Anybody here?
- Yes.! Stop shouting.! I'm on
the roof.! What do you want?
Why don't you come up?
Good, birdie. Hold it right there.
- [Gasps]
- [Crow Caws]
[Caws]
- What do you want?
- Oh, well, you have a black cat...
in your cabin window,
and, you see, it's mine and I need it back.
You're a good birdie, aren't you?
I'm sorry, but, uh, I'm kind of in a hurry.
So, why was it alone in the forest, huh?
That's where I dropped it.
Um, may I have it back, please?
I really need to finish this.
That's my girl!
- You're just about through, okay?
- [Crow Caws]
[Sighs]
Well, why didn't you tell me
sooner why you needed it
in such a hurry?
He keeps me company.
I've gotten sort of fond ofhim, you know?
Thank you.
[Gasps]
Oh...
Oh, no!
His head's falling off.
Ooh, it must have been
the crows. They were making
such a big fuss over him.
This is terrible. I can't deliver it like this.
Hm. Hey!
- I know. How about we work out a deal?
- Huh?
So, you're on your own at 13.
That's pretty exciting.
To be completely independent
and a witch!
- Impressive!
- How's it going?
Trust me. He'll be good as new.
Huh... Almost done.
- [Woman] Ket, dear, turn off the TV.!
- [TV Character Growls]
Your birthday guests are gonna be here soon.!
Ket, did you hear me?
- [Shouting] Ket, turn off the TV.!
- Okay! Okay!
That's right. You just keep sleeping.
[Gasps]
Nice doggy.
Good dog. Stay. Stay!
All right. Don't stay.
[Whimpering]
Uhh-h-h... Yuck!
- [Groans]
- Uhh...
- I'm done!
- Thank you very much!
- Better go getJiji before it's too late.
- But I haven't finished yet.
Don't worry. You've done enough.
Now, go on and get him!
[Panting] Thanks!
Hmm.
[Skipped item nr. 659]
[Laughter]
- Jeff likes my present more than me!
- [Laughing]
Jeff's such a funny dog. He
simply adores that stuffed cat.
He won't leave it alone.!
[Man]
I'll bet he thinks it's a puppy.!
[Older Woman]
He'll be upset when Ket wants
to take it and play with it.
- Sure will.!
- He sure will.!
- That's okay. He can have it.
Just don't forget to send
your aunt a thank-you note.
- [Ket] Okay.
- Ket...
- Okay.!
- Well, I'm glad to seeJeff
excited about something.
He's getting to be such an old dog.
- Yeah. All he does is sleep all day.
- [Laughs] All day.!
Ket, dear, go open the door.
Jeff wants to go out.
- Jeff, shut the door when you're done. Okay?
- [Groans]
- [Jeff Groans]
- Thanks!
- [Gasps] There you are!
- What took you so long?
- I'm sorry!
- My friend, Jeff, helped me escape.
Kiki, if we ask him,
I bet he'll take the stuffed one back inside.
He'll do it. He's a good dog!
- Could you take this in, please?
- [Murmurs]
See. What did I tell ya.!
Isn't he the greatest?
Thanks, Jeff, you're a real pal.!
I owe you one.!
- How are ya? Hungry?
- No, I'm tired!
Yeah, me too. I'm very tired.
We're both gonna sleep well tonight!
By the way, that painter
who found the stuffed cat...
told me she wants to do
a drawing with me in it.
- Naked?
- Jiji!
- [Girl] Mommy.!
- [Woman] Hurry up.! Hurry up.!
Over here.!
- Thank you. I'll be right back with your order.
- No garlic, sir.
[Sighs]
Boring.
Hey!
Message for sleepyhead!
Wake up! You're supposed
to be minding the store!
I am, but today this place is boring.
But it always gets busy about this time.
I know that. That's not what I mean.
I mean, my customers.
Jiji, if nobody comes in,
I'm gonna have to eat pancakes forever...
and be fat, fat, fat!
And what am I supposed
to do about that?
- Well, I like pancakes,
provided they're not burned.
- [Groans]
Look, fur ball, when you get
as fat and round as a pancake,
you see if I care.
[Gasps]
Hi! Oh.
Beautiful, isn't she?
They tell me she's a clothes designer.
Her designs may be fabulous,
but her cat's still a snob.
[Rings]
[Gasps]
Oh...
Hello! Good Cooking Pan Bakery.
What? Pardon? Uh, yes, ma'am.
'Bout time we got a customer, huh?
Uh, yes, ma'am, 4:30 will be a perfect time
to pick it up.
- If you'll just...
- Oh-h-h... Gee.
Uh-huh. And the address?
Yes. The blue roof. Right.
Yeah. I'm pretty sure I have it all.
- And thank you very much, ma'am.
- [Door Opens]
- Hi!
- Hmph!
I'll take this, please. Okay?
Thank you very much. Good afternoon.
Aw, come on.
You're not still mad at me, are you?
Listen. We're gonna
have a huge party at the club tonight.
It's called the Aviation Club.
And we'd really like for you to come.
Here's your invitation.
It's a serious club for kids who are into
flying and aircraft and stuff.
And you know everybody would
be really excited if you came.
- Yes. May I help you, sir?
- They tell me you have a delivery service.
Oh... Oh, I'm sorry. Yes,
of course, we can handle it.
It's very urgent this package arrive
as soon as possible.
- That's no problem. Oh...
- Oh...
- Uh, are you all right?
- [Kiki Grunts]
- [Straining] I do this every day.
- Can I help you?
[Grunting]
[Grunting] Uh. Oh-h-h...
Uhh...
[Sighs]
Well, I hope you make up
your mind by 6:00, 'cause that's
when I'll be by to pick ya up.
- See ya! Uh-ah... Uh.
- How much will that be?
Will that be inside
or outside city limits, sir?
- I wrote the address on the box!
- Oh... Oh, the box! Oh, I'm sorry.
Osono.! Osono.!
I've got a big problem.!
I got an invitation to go to a party
at Tombo's flying club!
I'm sure it'll be a great party, Kiki.
No! But my problem is,
what am I going to wear?
Kiki, you haven't got a problem.
You look fine in that.
- Besides, it makes you look
beautiful and mysterious.
- Really?
- How's work?
- [Gasps] I almost forgot about that!
It's already 4:00! Oh, no!
Can you watch the store
until I get back, Osono?
Jiji?
[Laughs]
[Grunts]
You were so mad at that boy.
I don't understand why
you're going to his party.
Please don't talk.
I'm tryin' to fly this broom, okay?
[Grunting]
[Grunting Continues]
- [Grunts, Pants]
- Whoa!
[Strains]
Thank you very much. Bye. Come on, Jiji!
Aren't we just going a tad too fast?
- We can't keep our
next appointment waiting.
- [Whimpers]
There's the blue roof.
Here we are.
[Door Lock Rattles]
My name's Kiki, and someone
telephoned for a delivery
service, so here I am.
Right this way, dear.
[Ticking]
- You are right on time.
- Thank you.
Oh, madam, the delivery girl is here.
My, delivery time already?
Come in, dear. Please make yourself
right at home.
- Please do.
- Thanks.
May I take that for you?
Thank you.
Oh? A black cat.
Broom and a black cat.
Well, it's just as
my great-grandmother told me.
My name's Kiki, and I'm a witch.
Mm-hmm. Oh, my,
what a pretty witch you are.
I'm so sorry, but that
special treat you were supposed
to deliver... isn't ready yet.
[Clicking]
I think there's something wrong with it.
It's got a mind of its own,
and it doesn't want to heat up.
It's old. Like me, it's seen better days.
I was hoping you'd be
able to deliver a dish to my
granddaughter's birthday party.
It's my speciality...
herring and pumpkin potpie.
But I must admit defeat.
I'll have to phone her and tell her I'm sorry.
- I feel just awful having
you come here for nothing.
- [Woman Imitating Wind Howling]
- Barsa! Barsa!
- Hmm?
- [Clears Throat]
- Would you get Kiki's money, please?
Certainly, madam.
- All of it. Pay her what we agreed on.
- Oh, no, I couldn't.
Please accept it. This was all my fault.
Yes, but...
Ma'am, since I don't have any
other jobs, maybe I can help.
How about we use that old oven over there?
Well, maybe?
It used to bake beautiful bread, but
I haven't baked in it lately.
Well, if it burns firewood,
I can help you.
I used to help my mom bake all the time.
But it's such a big job to build a fire.
A great idea, ma'am.
I never liked that electric thing.
- I think her plan is perfect.
- Ma'am, it'll work, really.
You think so?
All right then. Let's try it.
Kiki! Kiki! Kiki! This is crazy!
Don't blame me if you're late
for your party.
I can't take her money
and not help out.
- Come on, Kiki!
- Okay, Jiji, let's go.
Madam, here. Look what I found.
You're a very clever girl, my dear.
Your mother must be proud.
[Gasps]
Ah.
Oh, well, this is exciting.
Mm-hmm. Yes, this is much better.
[Sighs]
[Clicks]
It should be about time.
Yes, the fire's almost ready.
- Ah!
- Thanks.
- Now we wait.
- You think 40 minutes should be about right?
Exactly right.
So why don't we take a little break?
Maybe I can help around the house
while the pie is baking.
Oh, how nice of you to offer.
- [Squeaking]
- What a wonderful witch.
There we go.
You're never gonna
make the party on time.
Stop worrying. It'll only take me 15 minutes
if I fly there fast.
Would you like some hot tea?
It's no trouble.
[Gasps]
Dear. What did you say to me
was the time of your party?
It's at 6:00, but
it's only 15 minutes away.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm afraid my clock runs
about ten minutes slow.
[Gasps]
I'm gonna be late!
- Check the potpie and see if it's ready.
- [Whimpers]
Help! Barsa, come!
Quickly. We have to hurry.
Kiki's running very late.
[Bubbling]
Is the pie baked? Is it ready?
- It seems fine. Now, you'd better hurry.
- Uh-huh.
[Panting]
I got the broom. We're ready! Come on!
- Okay!
- Let me pay you for your time.
But that's much too much.
- Not for all of your help.
- Hurry up.
- Hurry up!
- Bye!
- Have a good time now.
- Here you go.
- Fly carefully.
- Bye-bye!
[Skipped item nr. 85]
Kiki, I don't think we should
be flying into those clouds.
We can beat the rain
if we just fly a little faster.
Not according to my whiskers.
Come on, Jiji! Think positive.
[Jiji]
What was that again
about beating the rain?
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Jiji] Could we get out
of the rain, please?
I'm begging you!
We can't! That'll make us
even later, and the food
will get cold if we stop.
[Tolling]
[Tolling Continues]
[Shudders, Sighs]
####[Up-tempo]
[Doorbell Chiming]
- [Sighs]
- [Door Opening]
- [Chattering]
- Yes? What do you want?
- I have a delivery.
- But it is soaking wet.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
It began to rain on the way.
But don't worry.
The food came through all right.
Oh, no, I told Grandma
I didn't want that.
[Girl]
Hey, what'd you get?
Oh, Grandma sent me another one of her
crummy herring pies again.
[Girl]
Mmm.! Yummy.! Herring pie.!
Um, will you please sign this receipt for me?
I hate Grandma's stupid pies.
I cannot believe they're related.
[Blows Raspberry]
Maybe we still have time.
Kiki, there he is!
Come on! We can catch him!
Kiki? We were all so worried about you.
And that poor boy waited such a long time.
It doesn't matter anyway.
I can't go in these wet clothes.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Kiki, what's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
[Skipped item nr. 121]
Maybe we should eat something, okay?
[Coughs]
You eat.
[Kiki Sniffles]
[Birds Chirping]
- [Scraping]
- Wake up, Kiki!
- [Scraping Continues]
- [Jiji Meowing]
[Meowing]
- Hmm?
- [Scraping Continues]
[Knocking]
[Meows]
Not feeling very well, huh?
Uh-uh.
- You have quite a fever.
- Uh-huh. My head's hurting so much.
Well, you flew in that weather
and you never really dried off.
Do you think I'm going to die, Osono?
Huh?
[Laughing]
No, you're not. I'll bring
some medicine right up...
and maybe you should have some potpie.
[Groans] Not that.
Well, then, I'll just
make something else for you.
How about some nice
hot oatmeal with honey in it?
You want some too?
[Meows]
This oatmeal will pick ya right up.
There ya go. Here.
Oof! Now, don't burn your tongue.
- Ow!
- You should come and eat your
meal while it's still warm.
- Here it is.
- Do I have to eat it?
Only if you want to get well.
Oh! You know that boy stopped
by to see you again today.
- Huh?
- That's right.
When I told him you were sick...
he asked me how a witch could
catch cold in the first place.
Oh, and he said he wanted
to visit you a little later.
Oh, my gosh! No!
Well, I thought you
might feel that way,
so I turned him down politely.
You must be tired.
You try to get some sleep.
Now, I'll just open up the window
so you'll have some fresh air.
- [Window Opens]
- [Traffiic Passing]
- Osono!
- Hmm?
- Um, never mind.
- All right.
[Birds Chirping]
[Sighs]
[Gasps]
Oh!
Breakfast!
Jiji.!
What? Hmm?
Hmm?
[Gulps]
Wow!
Good morning.
Perhaps we got off on the wrong paw.
Allow me to introduce myself.
The name's Jiji.
Where are you?
- [Door Opens]
- [Osono] Kiki?
- Are you feeling better?
- A lot better. Thank you.
I'm sorry I didn't realize I'd overslept.
That's okay. Come down later.
I have a favor to ask you.
- All right?
- Okay.
- The name is "Koppori"?
- Uh-huh. Now, take this money.
Oh, no, ma'am. No money. It's on me.
Impossible. Work is work,
and make sure you deliver it in person.
- [Jiji] The country's nice,
but I'm more of a city cat.
- Jiji!
- What is it?
- We've got a delivery.
- Hey, who's your friend there?
- Lily's her name. Be right there.
Stay there. I'll be right back.
He's all yours. Bye-bye.
- [Meows]
- Mmm!
- [Wind Blowing]
- Oh! Ah!
[Seagulls Screeching]
It's so pretty... and warm.
Mmm!
Ooh. Wow.
- Hey. Hey there, Miss Witch!
- [Gasps]
- Huh?
- Takin' a walk?
Uh... Uh-uh. I'm looking for someone
named, uh, Koppori.
Hey, that's my name. That's me.
[Gasps]
- If you go around that way,
I'll be right with you, okay?
- Okay.
Osono, how could you do this to me?
Hi.
Gee, thanks a lot.
Um, about the other night?
I'm sorry I didn't show up.
Huh? Mmm. I'm sorry you had
to end up so sick like that.
Hey, come over to my place.
There's somethin' I wanna show ya.
Oh, you gotta see it.
[Grunting]
The party was to celebrate
the completion of this thing.
What do ya think?
This is the engine of a man-propelled plane.
Watch this.
We're going to assemble
the wings and the frame
at somebody else's house.
I'm plannin' on flyin'
this thing during most
of my summer vacation.
[Imitating Propeller Whirring]
[Giggles]
Miss Witch, I got a great idea.
Why don't we go down
to the beach where that
dirigible landed yesterday?
- Dirigible?
- Don't tell me you didn't hear about it?
- I was sick.
- Then we gotta see it! Let's do it!
- We're going on this?
- Why not?
I have to practice all the time anyway.
Gotta build up my legs.
'Kay. Ready?
Um, mm-hmm.
This is my first time on a bike.
Oh, boy. Just hold on.
Brace the bike with your foot
until I get her revved up.
- Let's go!
- [Gasps]
- Okay!
- [Grunting]
Kick off... now! Good!
Ooh!
- [Grunting]
- Should I get off?
No!
Huh?
[Laughs]
[Kiki] Ooh!
[Car Horn Honking]
- [Child] Hey, look at that.! Whoa.!
- [Child Giggles]
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Hey! Over here!
- Hi!
Hi!
Lean your body to the inside when
we go around the curve!
- Why?
- Because, otherwise, we're
gonna have trouble turning.
Now!
Great! You're doin' fine.
Now put your weight
into it again. That's it.!
We're quite a team.!
All right! We're doin' great!
Wow!
- That's the dirigible, right?
- Right!
- [Both Screaming]
- [Horn Honking]
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa! That was close.
[Grunts]
- We're flying!
- [Laughs]
- [Horn Honking]
- Oh, my gosh!
- [Screams]
- Hold on!
[Gasps] Oh, boy!
[Screaming]
Hey! Watch it!
Whoa! Whoa! Aah!
Whoa!
- [Groans]
- What happened, Tombo? Are you okay?
- Yeah. Are you?
- I'm okay.
[Giggles]
What are you laughin'at?
- Hmm?
- Your face.!
[Laughing Continues]
- Oh, oh!
- Hmm?
Do I really look that funny?
I'm sorry, but when we flew up...
I was so scared.
Yeah, me too.
Was it your magic that made us stay up?
I'm not sure. Anything's possible.
[Gasps]
- Your bike's a real mess.
- [Gasps]
My propeller.!
I have to go get it, Kiki.
- Will you keep an eye on my bike for me?
- Uh-huh.
- What went wrong?
- I think I pedaled too hard.
That's why it busted.
You wait here. I'll be right back.
How great would it be
to go around the world
in a dirigible like that.
Of course, you were flying since
you were very young, huh?
Well, yes, since I was a baby.
My mother used to take me
with her. She taught me
never to be scared.
Gosh. You're so lucky, Kiki.
I wish I could fly.
People like you can just
fly away on a broomstick.
But me?
[Imitates Propeller Whirring]
That's all I can do.
Flying used to be fun
until I started doing it for a living.
Hey, wait. You can't not
enjoy flying. You're a witch!
I know. I still feel that way though.
But I'm very glad I came with you today.
I feel much better sitting by the beach.
Why don't I bring you here
whenever you want and train
myself at the same time?
- [Grunts]
- You're a very nice person.
- Huh? You just found that out?
- Sorry, but at first I thought
you were such a clown.
You know, my mom says the same thing.
"Don't be such a clown.
Quit looking up at the sky
and get back to your books."
- Ha!
- [Both Laughing]
- Look! It's Tombo!
- Hey, stop.
- Hey.! Tombo.!
- Huh?
- Guess what's up, Tombo!
- What?
Something really great! You're gonna love it!
- Come on over.!
- I'll be back in a sec, okay?
[Man On Radio]
So hold on tight
because we've got blimp fever...
and that means you could win big.
- We're all gonna get to go
for a ride in the blimp.
- Hi.!
Really? Wow! That's great!
- Hey, who's your friend?
- That's Kiki. I'll get her to come over.
Hey, come over and meet the gang, Kiki.
We're all goin' for a tour inside
the Spirit of Freedom.
Thanks, but I don't want to.
Oh, why not? It'll be fun.
She made a delivery
to my house on my birthday.
- You mean, she's working at her age?
- Well, I'll be.
Come on. I'll introduce you
to everybody.
- No thanks. See ya later.
- What's the matter?
Hey!
What are you so mad about?
I'm not mad at all, Tombo.
I have a lot on my mind.
So, please, just leave me alone.
Huh? Huh?
Forget her, Tombo! Come on!
- Hey, be nice.
- Yeah, I think we hurt her feelings.
[Birds Chirping]
- [Clicks]
- [Man On Radio] Don't forget
that this summer the hit music...
[Clicks]
[Bird Chirps]
[Meows]
Jiji, I think something's wrong with me.
I meet a lot of people,
and at first everything
seems to be going okay.
But then I start feeling
like such an outsider.
You should have seen
how Tombo's friends looked at me.
Hey?
Where ya goin'?
Oh. Some friend you are.
[Grunts]
[Bell Tolling]
Hey! You know, you can't be
late for every meal just because
you have a new girlfriend.
And you can wash your plate yourself!
- [Meows]
- Meow! Why are you talking like a cat?
[Meows]
Huh?
Oh, my!
Oh, no! Talk to me, Jiji!
You mean you can't speak anymore?
Jiji?
What's going on with him?
I can't understand anything he's trying to say.
[Gasps] What if it means...
Oh, my goodness!
[Whimpers]
Oh!
[Groans]
Oh.
[Grunts]
[Gasps, Sighs]
I'm losing my witch's powers.
[Panting]
Aah! Whoa! Ooh!
[Crickets Chirping]
Oh!
[Panting]
[Crashing]
[Groaning, Gasping]
Huh? Oh!
What do you mean?
You haven't lost your magic, have you?
It's become very weak, so l...
Well, I think I've got to take
a break from my delivery work.
But I promise I'll be really good
with my work in the bakery...
so please let me stay
in the room upstairs!
Well, that's no problem.
I'll bet your powers come back
after you've had some rest.
I really don't know.
Maybe if I make a new broom.
[Panting]
- Hey! Look at that!
- [Engine Approaching]
[Kiki]
Hello. Bakery.
Hi, Kiki? It's me, Tombo.
Did you see me today?
I was wavin' at ya
from the dirigible, 'cause
the captain let me come...
into the control cabin
during the test run.
Boy, did I have a cool time!
Hello? Kiki? Are you there?
- Please don't call me anymore.
- What did ya say?
I can barely hear ya.
You know what the captain said?
He'd like to meet ya...
What? Kiki? She hung up.
[Girl] One of each.
What's the matter, dear?
Is there anything I can do for you?
I'm still in training to become a witch.
If I lose my magic,
that means I've lost absolutely everything.
Kiki.!
[Crying]
[Horn Honks]
[Girl] Hey! It's mine!
Uh-huh. It's right over
there across the street.
Kiki! Kiki!
- Hey!
- [Kiki Gasps]
Hi!
Hi! Well, since you didn't
come and visit me, I thought
I'd come here and visit you.
I'm sorry.
Well, that's sort of a white lie.
I need to do some shopping too.
Come on in, 'cause I'm done now, and
I can take a break, okay?
- You better believe I will.
- [Both Laughing]
[Sighs] Nice place you have.
Help yourself to some of these, and
I'll go make us some tea.
- No tea, thanks, but
some milk if you have any.
- Sure.
Hey there. Unbelievable.
You're the spitting image of that stuffed cat.
I bet your name's Jiji, right?
Comin' through.
So how's the delivery biz?
You makin' any money?
- [Milk Pours]
- That bad, huh?
I'm not working much now.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm. I kind of thought
you looked unhappy.
I didn't know things
like that happened to witches.
Hey! Why don't you come
and stay at my cabin?
Huh?
It'll probably make you
feel better. Your boss
would let you have a break.
How about it, kitty cat?
Wanna come?
Hmm?
[Giggles]
Rather be with your girlfriend,
huh? Come on, girl.
Why not? We'll leave now.
Uh-huh.
[Meows]
Come on!
Pretty day.
- Hurry! Hurry!
- [Horn Honks]
The bus is leaving!
Kiki?
- [Gum Pops]
- Oh, thank you. Oh. Ooh!
Ahh!
- Oh!
- [Both Laughing]
- Okay, now I'm officially exhausted.
- [Laughs]
It's beautiful here.
[Inhales] Mmm!
- Kiki?
- Huh? Coming.
[Car Approaching]
[Man]
Get outta the road.!
What's the matter with you?
Must have been blinded by two
beautiful girls in front of him.
Hey!
[Coughs]
[Both Coughing]
[Man] Ursula? Is that you?
- Yea!
- Hop in.!
I know this guy. Come on.
You know, when I first saw you,
I didn't recognize you.
I thought you were a boy.
Huh? You... You really
thought I was a boy?
Well, it's the way
you're dressed and all.
[Groans] Tell me. What kind of a boy
has these legs, mister?
Bye, ladies! Take care now!
- You get along with the crows.
- Yep, we've become real close friends.
Wow!
- Hello, everybody. I'm home again.
- [Cawing]
- Good afternoon. Um, I wanna say I'm sorry.
I'm not an egg stealer, and I didn't mean to
cause you any problems.
Why don't you go inside,
and I'll go get some water?
Okay.
[Gasps]
Oh.
- Like it?
- Yes.
I have to say I became inspired after
the first time we met.
But... I really haven't got the face right.
I've been waiting for you to come back
so I can try again.
- You mean that's me?
- Sure is.
You know, you'd make
my life a lot easier if you'd model for me.
But I'm not very beautiful.
What do you want me to do that for?
[Laughing]
Come on, Kiki. You have got a great face.
You're very pretty.
Now, don't you be nervous.
Sit down over here.
Raise your chin up a little.
Look straight ahead. Now, don't move.
Painting and magical powers
seem very much the same.
Sometimes I'm unable to paint a thing.
You mean it?
Then what? What happens?
Kiki, please don't move.
It's hard to draw a moving target.
Without even thinking about it,
I used to be able to fly.
Now I'm trying to look inside
myself to find out how I did it.
- But I just can't fiigure it out.
- You know, could be you're
working at it too hard.
Maybe you shouldjust take a break.
Yeah, but still, if I can't fly...
Then stop trying.
Take long walks. Look at the scenery.
Doze off at noon.
Don't even think about flying.
And then, pretty soon,
you'll be flying again.
- You think my problems will...
- Go away? That's right.
It's gonna be fine. I promise.
When I was your age,
I'd already decided to become an artist.
I loved to paint so much.
I'd paint all day until
I fell asleep right at my easel.
And then one day,
for some reason, I just
couldn't paint anymore.
I tried and tried,
but nothing I did seemed any good.
They were copies of paintings
I'd seen somewhere before...
and not very good copies either.
I just felt like I'd lost my ability.
That sounds like me.
It's exactly the same,
but then I found the answer.
You see, I hadn't
fiigured out what or why
I wanted to paint.
- I had to discover my own style.
- Mm-hmm.
When you fly, you rely on what's
inside of you, don't you?
Uh-huh. We fly with our spirit.
Trusting your spirit!
Yes, yes! That's exactly
what I'm talkin' about.
That same spirit
is what makes me paint
and makes your friend bake.
But we each need to find
our own inspiration, Kiki.
Sometimes it's not easy.
I guess I never gave much thought to why
I wanted to do this.
I got so caught up
in all the training and stuff.
Maybe I have to find my own inspiration.
But am I ever gonna find it?
And is it worth all the trouble?
Well, for example,
there were quite a few times...
when I thought of painting something
over that painting.
- [Kiki] But it ended up being so great.
- So I guess it's worth it.
Today when I saw you
I thought, I wanna paint!
- You've got such a great face.
- That's why I came?
[Laughing]
Hey, well, it's better than
you cleaning my floor again.
- Let's turn out the lights and go to sleep.
- Okay.
Sorry about taking your bed from you.
Aw, no problem.
- So you really think I'll fly again?
- Sure.
You'll just have to wait
for the right inspiration to come along.
- You understand?
- Uh-huh.
Mmm!
[Man On TV] And there it is, folks,
the Spirit of Freedom...
- recently downed in
a spectacular forced landing...
- [Phone Ringing]
Due to torrential rains
just outside the city limits.
- Well, it's been repaired.
It is now in fiinal preparation...
- [Osono] Yes?
Good Cooking Pan Bakery.
- Kiki! How are you?
- I'm okay. Thanks.
Well, you take plenty of time coming home.
Oh, and by the way...
- that older woman you made a delivery for?
- Uh-huh?
She has another delivery
for you. I said I wasn't sure you could do it.
- She was really very insistent.
What do you think, Kiki?
- Okay.
Great! Stop there on your way back. Bye.
Thank you so much for everything.
Bye.!
[Birds Chirping]
[Bell Dinging]
- Afternoon, ma'am.
- Well, well, we've been expecting you.
Thanks.
[Man On TV] There are less than five
minutes to takeoff now.
Um, it's very nice
to see you again, ma'am.
I'm glad you came.
Please excuse me for not standing.
My legs are bothering me more than usual.
Barsa, bring the package now.
Gosh, I hope it hasn't taken off.
Not yet. Barsa is absolutely mad about
lighter-than-air travel.
I'm the adventuresome type. Mm-hmm.
[Man On TV]
The local fiire department
and the Coast Guard stand ready.
- Could you turn it down, please?
- Certainly.
Would you do me a favor and open the box?
Yep.
[Gasps] I don't get it.
Would you please bring this
to a young delivery girl?
She was kind to me and a very big help.
It's my way of saying thank you.
Ah, yes, and can you find out
when her next birthday is?
Then I can bake her another one.
Will you handle this very
special delivery, Kiki?
[Crying]
Don't cry.
[Sniffling]
Of course I will! And maybe
the young girl will want
to know the lady's birthday...
because she'll be able to give
her a present to repay her!
- You've got a deal.
- [Both Laughing]
- Oh! Oh, my!
- [People Screaming On TV]
[Screaming]
[Gasps]
- [Screaming]
- [Static]
- What happened?
- Oh, there's been a terrible accident.
- [Giggles]
- Oh, my!
[Screaming]
- [Screaming]
- [Static]
Oh, darn this old thing!
And just when it was getting good!
Midsummer is always
when these winds come.
- They'll be hitting us any minute.
- Oh!
Goodness.! It's a strong one.!
It'll pass quickly. Don't worry.
- [People Screaming On TV]
- [Barsa] Oh, goody.!
- It's back on. Look!
- [Screaming]
Oh, look at that.
It's completely upside down.
Freak winds blowing in from the sea!
- It has broken loose from its mooring ropes.
- My, my. How terrible.
A desperate last-ditch
effort is being made to tie
the dirigible to the ground...
and keep it from drifting into the air.
But it's extremely doubtful
whether or not this can actually be done.
- Oh!
- Oh, no, no.! It's useless.!
The tremendous lifting power
of the helium balloon is lifting
the police patrol car...
- That's Tombo! That's
my friend hanging on that rope.
- Huh?
It's being lifted as though it were a toy!
Oh, no, there's a young boy
hanging onto the cable!
He's being lifted away
together with the police car!
L-I don't believe what
I'm seeing. The dirigible
is being blown towards town!
I'm told our remote crew
has escaped injury...
- Are you sure it's your friend, my dear?
- I have to go!
- Oh, dear!
- Be careful!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh!
[Panting]
- Come on! Over here!
- Over here!
- Look! There he is!
- Look! It's a man up there!
Hold on there, son!
Just hold your grip steady!
Release the helium
from the tail! Quick!
[Straining, Grunting]
[Screaming, Grunting]
Oh!
- [Screaming]
- [Man] Comin' down!
- Hmph!
- Gotta see this!
- [Panting]
- [Siren Wailing]
What's going on?
- [Man On Megaphone]
All citizens are kindly...
- Sorry!
Requested to remain calm.!
- He's up there!
- Do not panic.!
Tombo! Sir, is there
any word about the boy?
All I know is that the radio
said that the police car
dropped into a pool.
The helium inside the dirigible
will not explode.!
He's still up there!
- It's awfully close to those buildings.
- Where did it take off from?
- It was around the corner, and then...
- [Woman] It's frightening.
[Man] Move.!
[Man On Megaphone]
Stay out of the street.!
Get on the sidewalks.!
You there.! Young lady.!
Don't block the street.!
Clear the area.!
Do not block the street.!
- Are you all right, young lady?
- Huh?
- [Woman] What happened?
- [Man] Snapped it right off.
Please, sir, may I use
your broom for a minute?
- What?
- Please! I promise I'll bring it right back!
- Huh? I'm not gonna give you my broom...
- Thank you very much!
- Hey!
- [Siren Wailing]
Fly.
[Crowd Gasps]
- Watch out!
- Whoa!
[Grunts]
[Screaming, Groaning]
[Groaning, Screaming]
- [Crowd Gasping]
- [Screaming]
- Did you see that?
- Unbelievable! Flew up in the air!
Come on, broom. Fly for me.
- [Screaming]
- [Siren Wailing]
[Screaming Continues]
Ladies and gentlemen, it appears
that the blimp is heading
directly for the clock tower!
And, look, the young boy
is safe, but he's clutching
that rope for dear life.!
If the wind doesn't shift,
the Spirit of Freedom
will smash into the tower.!
We gotta get up higher or else
we'll hit the tower, Captain!
There's not enough helium.
Jump onto the tower before we hit!
Aye, aye, Captain!
Hey there! Over here! Come on!
Get outta the way!
The blimp's gonna crash!
Grab a hold of this!
- [Grunting]
- Huh?
[Straining, Grunting]
[Screaming]
- Go!
- [Tombo Screaming]
- [Screaming Continues]
- Hurry up!
[Gasps, Screams]
- [Siren Wailing]
- Hey!
[Gas Hissing]
We are listening to the sound
of a helium gas leak!
The condition of the boy
is unknown, but from where
I'm standing... Oh, no!
- [Man] Oh.!
- [Man] Oh, no.! Oh, no.!
It's falling!
Too much gas has escaped.
It's coming down!
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- It's snagged on the building
across the street where it's...
- Hey, look! Over there!
It's a miracle! The young boy
has somehow managed to keep
his hold on the rope!
- But how can anyone rescue him now?
- [Screams]
That brave young boy
is hanging on for dear life!
He can't... Something just flew by!
It's a bird? No, it's not a bird.
It's a young girl.
No.! It's a young witch
soaring through the sky, and she's riding...
- Go, Kiki!
- Oh, my!
- She can fly again!
- Get 'im, Kiki!
- Tombo!
- Kiki!
- Oh! Tombo!
- [Screams]
Come on now! Be a good broom!
Hold on, Tombo!
Hang in there, my good lad!
Oh, no!
Oh! Oh!
- Kiki!
- Tombo.!
[Both Straining]
- Whoa!
And she's trying to reach the boy!
- You can do it! Yes!
- Don't give up now, sonny!
- Come on!
- [Crowd Chanting] Don't give up.!
Don't give up.! Don't give up.!
Don't give up.!
- Don't give up.!
- [Screaming]
She got him! She saved the youngster!
I've never seen anything so amazing!
[Cheering]
Congratulations, young lady!
[Woman] Oh.! Let me see.!
Let me see.!
- Yea!
- Now she's bringing him
down to land, safe and sound.
She actually caught
the boy in midair.!
- And you saw it all live
as she saved his life.
- Well done, young lady!
That broom she used was mine.
That was my broom, you know!
- Oh, Barsa! Oh, my!
- Yippee!
- What a girl!
- Kiki was so brave.
- She really saved the day.
- Mmm!
- Uh-oh! Uh, better call the hospital, honey!
- Oh? Oh?
- I think it's time now!
- Oh! Oh, my!
Ooh!
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
- Kiki, can you hear me?
- And I thought I was a goner for sure.
- But my friend Kiki saved me!
- Jiji!
- She's the greatest friend a
person could have. That's all.
- Meow!
- Hey, let me tell you about
when she first came to town.
- You live around these parts?
[Skipped item nr. 685]
[Woman]
## One day ##
## The whole world looks ##
##Like an open page ##
##And you've been dancing
as fast as you can ##
## With a smile on your ##
##Face ##
##And then the earth and the sky ##
## They all fiit together ##
##And carry me away
as light as a feather ##
## Chase the clouds from the ground ##
##In the big blue sky ##
##Don't wanna watch it all go by ##
##So I'm gonna fly ##
##Higher than ##
##I ever could ##
##Feel the wind blow through my hair ##
##Feel the sun dance with the moon ##
##And my feet can't stay ##
## On the ground any longer ##
## With every leap of faith ##
##I feel a little stronger ##
## Wanna swing from a star ##
##In the big blue sky ##
##Don't wanna watch it all go by ##
##So I'm gonna fly ##
##And see for myself what it looks like ##
##From up there ##
##And taste the stardust in my mouth ##
## Chase the clouds ##
## Until they disappear ##
##And if I can make ##
##Just one life better ##
##Bring a smile to
your face when you're
under the weather ##
##And I'm feelin'like I've fiinally
found my home ##
##I'll plant the seeds
and watch them grow ##
##And I'm gonna ##
##Fly ##
##Higher than I ever ##
##Ever could ##
##I'm gonna fly ##
##Higher than I ever ever could ##