Totoro
Go! Go! Go!
Energetic!
I like walking most.
Walk straight
Up the hills
Big tunnels
Grasslands
Long bridges
The lively road
Look at the spider nets
Down the hills
Go! Go! Go!
Energetic!
I like walking most
Walk straight
wolves
foxes
come here
deep to the forest
enjoy the adventure
Many many friends
Make me live happily
Father, caramel.
Oh, thanks.
Are you tired?
It's just a little further.
Mei! Hide!
It wasn't a policeman.
Is someone there from this house?
Oh, thanks.
I'm Kusakabe.
We've arrived. Welcome!
Sorry for bothering
Thanks for your help
Thanks a lot.
Well, we've arrived.
Wait!
Mei, there's a bridge.
Fish.
See, it flashed again
Well, do you like it?
Father, it's beautiful!
A tunnel of trees.
Ah, that house?
Hurry
Yes!
It's like a haunted house!
It's rotten.
Mei, look!
There... Isn't it big?
Father, a huge tree!
Right, it's a camphor tree.
Oh, a camphor tree.
A nut.
Let me see.
Another one.
Woo...
Here it is
Hey, hey.
We've got to open up
the storm shutters.
Nuts!
They fell from above.
Squirrels?
Or maybe acorn-
mice?
No, squirrels are better.
Where do you want this?
Ah, just a minute.
I'll open up over here.
Satsuki,
would you open the back door?
You should be able to find it.
Come on!
Wait!
Hurry up!
I'm going in.
The bath...
Nobody's here
It's a bath
Father,
there's something in here.
Squirrels? I don't know.
Not cockroaches, not mice...
Black. There were a wholebunch!
Hmmmmm. Hmmmmm...
It must be Mak-kuro Kurosuke
Mak-kuro Kurosuke?
Like the ones in the picture book?
It must be... Ghosts
wouldn't be out on a beautiful day like this.
When you suddenly enter a dark place
from bright sunlight,
black spots appear in front of your eyes.
So that's it!
MAK-KURO KUROSUKE, COME ON OUT!
IF YOU DON'T, WE'LL PULL
YOU OUT BY YOUR EYEBALLS!!!
Okay, back to work.
Where are the stairs to the second floor?
Let's find the stairs
and open the upstairs windows.
Okay!
Toilet!
Not Here!
Mei, I found it...
It's pitch black.
Mak-kuro Kurosuke!
...A nut!
MAK-KURO KUROSUKE, COME OUT!
Mister Mak-kuro Kurosuke,
are you here?
Father,
there's something
in this house after all!
That's great!
Since I was a boy,
I've wanted to live in a haunted house!
Ooops!
I got one!! Sis!!
What energy!
This is the neighbor-lady
who watches over this house.
She came to help us move in.
I'm Satsuki and this is my sister, Mei.
How do you do?
What nice children.
If there had been time
I could have cleaned up the house.
You've done plenty.
We're so busy
in the fields right now,
but I cleaned a little,
every so often.
Mei, your hands are black!
What happened?
Mak-kuro Kurosuke escaped!
Oh, Mei, your feet...
Oh, mine are black too!
Oh, Oh. It looks like the 'susu-atari'
have come out.
Susu-atari?
Are susu-atari like this,
and move like this?
Yes,
they live in old, empty houses
and make dust here and there.
I could see them too, when I was young.
So, you also saw them...
Are they ghosts?
Nothing that scary.
If you're good,
they won't do anything bad.
Then before you know it,
they're gone.
They're probably up
in the ceiling right now,
discussing whether to move out.
Mei, they're going to leave.
I don't like that.
But what would you do
if they came out at once?
Mei not scared.
Okay then.
I won't go with you to the toilet at night.
Say, would you go to the creek
and bring up some water?
The creek? Mei go too.
Mei,
you better stay and here and wait.
Have you caught the fish!
Granny!
Keep pumping,
until the water runs cold.
Oh, it's you.
What can I do for you?
From Mother, for Granny.
What is it?
Wait! What is this?
Is that Kanta?
YAH-H-H!! YOUR HOUSE IS HAUNTED!!!
KANTA!
Ha, ha, ha!
Reminds me of when I was a boy.
I hate boys!
But I love Granny's sweet rice cake.
Eat all you like.
Thank you for all your help.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye!
Father,
this old house will fall down.
Ha, ha! What a problem,
since we just moved in.
HA HA HA HA HA! Everyone laugh!
So your fears will all run away.
Mei not scared,
Mei not scared.
One, two,
one, two...
Okay, laundry is finished.
Off we go!
Granny!
How are you!
Don't work too hard!
Where are you going?
To the hospital to visit mother!
That's nice!
Say hello for me!
Okay!
This way, this way!
Good day. Welcome.
Oh, MOTHER!
Mei, it's good to see you!
Father took the wrong road.
Really? Welcome.
Today is the Harvest Holiday.
Father's talking with the doctor.
I'm so happy you all came.
How's the new house?
Are you settled in?
What? A haunted house?
Mother, do you like haunted houses?
Of course.
I've got to hurry and get well.
I'd like to meet a ghost.
That's good. Right, Mei?
We were worried.
If you were scared,
We wouldn't know what to do.
What about you two? We like it!!
Mei not scared!
Is Satsuki doing Mei's hair?
Your good at it.
Isn't that nice, Mei?
Unn, but Satsuki gets real mad.
That's because you never stay still.
Satsuki,
come here. Isn't it too short?
Satsuki, I like it this way.
Mei too, Mei too!
Unruly, just like always, isn't it.
Exactly like mine when I was your age.
When I grow up,
will my hair be just like Mother's?
Probably,
since you're just like I used to be.
Mother's looking good, isn't she?
Yes.
The doctor was saying
she'll be able to leave the hospital soon.
Soon? Tomorrow?
There she goes again with 'tomorrow'.
Tomorrow is probably too soon, though.
Mother says she wants to sleep together
with Mei again.
But you're a big girl now.
Weren't you going to sleep by yourself?
With mother is okay.
Father,
it's morning!
Hey, WAKE UP!!
Starting today,
I'm taking lunch (to school).
Darn, I completely forgot.
It's okay. I'll make everyone's.
It's burning!
This one is Mei's.
Mei's?
Want meal
Here. Wrap it yourself, okay?
Satsuki-chan!
Oh, no!
OKAY!!
You made a friend already?
She called you 'Satsuki-chan'.
I've had enough.
I'll be going.
Have a nice day.
Morning.
Hurry, let's go.
Father,
does Mei look like Sis?
Yes. Where are you going
with your lunch basket?
Just over there.
Father, is it time for lunch?
What, already?
Father is a florist, okay?
Tadpoles!
Ah, bottom's gone.
Found one!
Who are you?
Mak-Kuro Kurosuke?
To To Ro.
Totoro... Your name is Totoro, right?
So... it's Totoro, after all... Totoro.
See you later.
I'm home.
Welcome. Oh, is it that time already?
Where's Mei?
I'm going over to Mit-chan's house.
We haven't had lunch yet.
Isn't she playing in the garden?
Mei!
MEI!!!
Father, I found Mei's hat.
Mei, Mei!!
...MEI! Wake up
You can't sleep in a place like this!
Where's Totoro? Totoro?
Huh? Huh?
Were you dreaming?
Totoro was here.
Totoro? You mean Tororo
that was in the picture book?
Unn. He said he was Totoro.
With fur,
and a mouth like this.
One like this,
and one about like this.
There you are, there you are.
Hey, how great.
Just like a secret hideaway.
Father! Mei, says she met Totoro here.
Totoro?
Over here!
Hey, wait!
Here?
Uh-uh.
Before he was by the big tree.
But there was only one pathway...
Mei,
let's go home. I said, Mei!
It's true!
There really was Totoro!
Not a lie.
Mei...
It not lie.
Uh, Father and Satsuki
don't think you're a liar.
You must have met the keeper of the forest.
That means good fortune is with you.
But you can't see him all the time.
Sayy, we haven't offered
a prope greeting yet.
Greeting?
Tsukamori! Let's go!
Mei's gotten so heavy.
Father, that camphor tree.
Isn't it huge?
There it is!
Father, hurry. Hurry!
The hole is gone.
Was this really the place?
She says the hole is gone.
Well, you can't see him all the time.
We'll see him again?
I want to meet him too.
Well, if good fortune is with you.
Isn't this a beautiful tree?
It's been here since long, long ago.
Back then,
man and trees were friends.
Father saw this tree
and fell in love with that house.
I'm sure Mother will like it too.
Well, let's offer our greetings
and get back home.
We have to eat our lunch.
Oh yeah.
I was supposed to go to Mit-chan's.
Mei go too.
Thank you for taking care of Mei.
From this moment on,
'Onegai itashimasu'.
Onegai itashimasu.
A race to the house!
Wait!
Hurry!
Today I have wonderful news.
Mei met the spirit, Totoro.
I'm thinking it would be wonderful
to meet him too.
Kanta! If you don't hurry,
you'll be late!
Attention!
Oh, it's Mei...
Teacher?
Yes, Satsuki?
My younger sister...
Granny, Mei...
Well, she says she wants to go where you are,
and she won't listen.
But Mei, today's Father's day
at the university
and you promised to be a good girl
and stay with Granny.
I have two more hours,
And Granny's busy too.
She was a good girl all day,
right?
Sigh... Granny,
I'll go and speak with the teacher.
Satsuki's Mother is in the hospital
and it's rather difficult right now.
Class, we'll do all we can to help, right?
Right!
What's that?
It's Totoro.
Shhhhh. You have to be quiet.
Okay!
Tell them I'm going to skip the club today.
Okay, I'll tell the teacher.
See you later.
Mei, let's hurry!
It looks like rain.
Mei won't cry. Is she a big girl?
Yes, but what a problem.
Please let us share your roof
for a little while.
But...
Good thing. Right, Sis?
It's got holes.
Father didn't take an umbrella.
Mei go to meet him too.
And that's why I forgot it!
What dummy would forget
his umbrella when it's raining?
That hurts!
You were probably swinging it
around and broke it.
I didn't!
Excuse me.
Oh, Satsuki. And little Mei, too.
Granny!
Thank you for today.
You're welcome. It wasn't much.
Oh, Kanta lent us his umbrella.
Really? That kid?
It's such a beat up old umbrella.
Mei was with me,
so it really saved us.
But Kanta got all wet.
Thank you. That's all right.
He's always so dirty anyway;
he must have gotten a little bit cleaner.
Are you going to meet your father?
Yes.
Mei-chan, bye bye.
Who came?
I don't know.
There it comes.
Are you getting on?
All right, driver.
Father wasn't on it.
It'll be the next bus for sure.
Does Mei want to wait at Granny's house?
What's wrong?
Mei,
are you sleepy?
That's why I told you...
Want to go to Granny's house now?
Hold on, it's just a little longer...
The bus is sure late... Here.
Totoro?
Ah, just a minute.
I'll lend you this...
Hurry,
Mei will fall.
Use it like this.
The bus is coming!
Totoro took father's umbrella...
Ah, sorry, sorry.
The train was late and I missed the bus.
Were you worried?
It came! Father,
it came! It came! A cat, a cat bus!
Really huge! With eyes like this!
It was wonderful!
We met him, we met him! We met Totoro!
It was fantastic!
Mother,
it feels like my heart is still racing.
Today is a scary day,
but is also a joyful day!
What's more? Totoro's gift!
I was a fantastic, too.
It was a bamboo-leaf package,
wied with a dragon's whisker.
When we got home, we opened it
and inside were nuts.
If our garden became a forest,
it would be beautiful, so we planted them.
But they just won't grow.
Every day, Mei says
'Still nothing, there's still nothing'.
She's just like
the crab of the monkey-crab fable.
It will soon be summer vacation.
Please hurry and get well.
Satsuki.
Okay, okay.
I'm going to turn it off. Wait.
Father,
I wonder if they'll come up tomorrow?
I wonder. Totoro would probably know.
Good night.
Mei,
that's where we planted the seeds.
Hooray! We did it, we did it!
Mei, we're the wind!
The tree is gone.
We did it, we did it!
It was a dream but it wasn't a dream!
We did it!
Mr. Kusakabe,
telegram.
it's a telegram.
Nobody home?
Granny!
Over here.
This one's ready to eat.
Granny, how about this one?
It's ripe.
Granny's garden is like a treasure-hill.
Say, let's take a little rest...
They're nice and cold.
Start
It's delicious.
Is it? They've gotten a lot of Mr. Sun,
so they're also good for you.
For Mother's sickness, too?
Of course.
If you eat Granny's vegetables,
you'll get real healthy fast.
Mother's coming home this Saturday.
She will sleep with Mei.
So she's finally
leaving the hospital.
Un-uh. It's not for good.
She'll return to the hospital
on Monday.
It seems they're going
to release her gradually.
Is that right?
Then we're going to have
to get her to eat more and more.
The corn Mei picked, Mei will give to Mother.
That will make her so happy.
A telegram.
Nobody was home
so we accepted it for you.
For our house?
Granny,
Father won't be home until evening.
Open it. It might be an emergency.
P-l-e-a-s-e re-ply,
shi-koku-yama... Shikokuyama
Hospital!
It's form Mother's Hospital!
Something's happened!
Granny, what shall I do?
We have to answer! Calm down,
calm down.
Do you know where your father is?
I know the telephone number
of the research department,
but we don't have a phone.
Kanta,
take her to your uncle's.
Let her use the phone.
Mei, you stay with Granny!
Hello, long distance please.
Tokyo 31-1382. Yes.
Isn't she cute, Kanta?
Hello,
yes... Hello,
is this the Kokogaku Research Department?
Father, I mean,
Mr. Kusakabe please.
This is Satsuki Kusakabe.
All right...
Oh Father, it's Satsuki.
Yes, what is it?
Uh-huh... from the hospital?
I understand.
I'll call the hospital right away.
Did something happen with Mother?
What shall I do? Father?
Don't worry.
As soon as I find out what it's all about,
I'll call you.
Ask them to let you wait there.
I'm going to hang up now.
Granny, may I wait here?
Father will call back.
Of course. Rest awhile.
Sis!
No way!
This corn is for Mother.
I said, no way!
It seems Mother's not feeling well,
so they're delaying her home visit.
No!
It can't be helped.
If she rushes it and gets worse,
what'll we do?
No!
It's just a short postponement.
Then it's all right if Mother dies,
is that right?
NO!
You dummy!
I'm not talking to you anymore!
Let's go.
Sis is a meany!
Let's put away the laundry.
Don't be so sad.
Granny's come to help, so perk up.
Isn't your Father at the hospital?
They say it's just a cold.
She'll be home next Saturday.
It was just like this last time.
Just a short stay at the hospital.
A little cold.
What will we do if Mother dies?
But, Satsuki...
Maybe she'll...
It's okay, it's okay.
Who would die and leave such nice children?
Don't cry,
don't cry.
Granny will be here
till your father comes home.
Mei-chan!
Mei!
Did Mei come home?
You didn't see her at the bus stop?
Funny,
where could she have gone?
A little while ago, we had a fight.
Because Mei's a...
That kid.
I wonder if she went to Mother's hospital?
The Shinkokuyama Hospital?
It would even take an adult
at least three hours to walk there.
I'm going to look.
Kanta!
Hurry and call your father!
Mei's disappeared!
Darn Mei! She's always getting lost.
MEI!
Excuse me, Mister.
Did a little girl pass by on this road?
My little sister.
Hmmmm... a little girl?
I would remember if I saw someone...
I wonder if it was another road?
Are you sure she came this way?
I don't know.
Mei!
Stop, please!
You fool! That's dangerous!
Your little sister?
I think she's on her way to
the Shikokuyama Hospital.
Four years old, a little girl.
Ryoko, did you see anyone?
Uh-uh. We came from Shikokuyama,
But we didn't see anyone like that.
Oh. Thank you.
Where did you come from?
From Matsu-go.
Matsu-go?
Isn't there some mistake?
Well, bye.
Satsuki!
Kan-chan!
Find her?
No. How about you?
Right now
Dad and the others are searching.
I'll go to Shkokuyama for you.
You go home.
Mei tried to get to the hospital
and got lost on the way. I'm sure.
A while ago, they found a sandal in the pond.
We don't know for sure if it belongs to Mei!
Did you find her?
Nami Amida Buddha,
Nami Amida Buddha...
The mud's deeper over there!
Try there first!
Hey, got another pole?
Granny, Satsuki's coming.
Granny!
This... this is it.
It's not Mei's.
Thank heaven.
I thought for sure it was Mei's.
What, Granny junped to conclusions?
Hey, it was a mistake!
Where could she have gone?
We'll have to start over again.
We'll have to hurry. It'll be dark soon.
Thanks everyone.
Let's divide up and search some more.
We we've found...
Please let me through to Totoro's den.
Mei's lost.
It'll be dark soon,
and that kid, she's lost somewhere.
Totoro!
Totoro! Mei's lost!
I've searched all over,
but I can't find her.
Please, find Mei.
I'm sure she's crying somewhere right now.
I don't know what to do!
Everyone can't see it!
Mei-chan!
The trees are leaning out of the way!
Mei!
Sis!
You dummy!
I'm sorry!
You wanted to bring that corn to Mother?
You'll take us to the hospital?
Thank you!
I'm sorry.
It's just a little cold
and the hospital
had to go and send a telegram.
The kids are sure to be worried.
Poor kids.
Well, the kids
will be relieved when they hear.
Our good times are just put off for a little while,
that's all.
Those kids have to put up with so much.
Satsuki's such a sensitive child,
I feel sorry for her.
You're right.
When I get home I plan to really spoil them.
Mother's laughing.
She looks okay.
Ah, I've got to hurry and get well.
Who could it be?
What's the matter?
Just now, in the pine tree,
I thought I saw Mei and Satsuki laughing...
It could be.
Look!
This is for you! (Mother)
Totoro, totoro.
Someone quietly
Sow the rice hull in the path
When they grow up,
They turn the secret path
Into forest.
A wonderful adventure will soon start,
Totoro in the next door, totoro,
Totoro, totoro.
They used to live in the forest.
Totoro in the next door, totoro,
Totoro, totoro.
They only show themselves
In front of kids.
What a wonderful meeting.
In rainy days,
a fat monster suddenly appear
at the bus stop sign.
It is holding an umbrella for her
This is the passport to the forest.
Magic door will open for this.
Totoro in the next door, totoro,
Totoro, totoro.
It lovely appear in the hillock.
Totoro in the next door, totoro,
Totoro, totoro.
When you meet her by luck,
Happiness will befall.
~The end~