Only a white man would make a fire
for eeryone to see.
Maybe there's more than one.
There might be three or four.
I know three or four...
...who will not be making the trip back home.
We have nothing to show for this trail.
We have no rifles.
White men are sure to have rifles.
It's hard to say how many might be down there.
We should forget this and go home.
Then go.
I would rather die...
...than argue about a single line of smoke
in my own country.
He will not quit until we are all dead.
Kicking Bird has been keeping to himself
these last few days.
I do not like to see our medicine man
walking so alone.
What does his wife say?
She says that he is keeping to himself.
That's not what I asked you.
Well, what did you ask me?
What did she say?
She said that he is keeping
to himself these days.
That's what she says.
Make sure that my meat is soft.
My teeth hurt.
May I come in?
No, let him sit with me.
Our country seems good this summer...
...but I have not been out to see it.
But the buffalo are late.
And I always worry
about the bellies of our children.
I was thinking of a dance.
Yes. A dance is always a good idea.
It would be good to have a strong sign.
There's a funny thing about signs.
We know when they are bad or good.
Sometimes they are strange
and it's hard to understand them.
A smart man will think on these things.
If he is still confused, he will tell somebody.
For instance, he might tell you or me.
A smart man always does this.
I have seen such a sign.
Really?
I saw a man.
A naked, white man.
Are you sure it was a man?
I saw his sex.
Did you speak to him?
No.
He might be a god.
Or a white chief with special abilities.
That is why we should talk with him.
I do not care for this talk about this white man.
Whatever he is, he is not a Sioux,
and that makes him less.
When I hear that more whites are coming,
I want to laugh.
We took a hundred horses from these people.
There was no honor in it.
They don't ride well. They don't shoot well.
They're dirty.
Those soldiers could not even make it
through one winter here.
And these people are said to flourish?
I think they will all be dead soon.
I think this fool is probably lost.
Wind In His Hair's words are strong
and I have heard them.
It's true the whites are a poor race
and hard to understand.
But make no mistake. The whites are coming.
Even our enemies agree on this.
So when I see one man alone
without fear in our country...
...I do not think he is lost.
I think he may have medicine.
I see someone who might speak...
...for all the white people who are coming.
I think this is a person
with which treaties might be struck.
Kicking Bird is always looking ahead
and that is good.
But this man cannot cover our lodges
or feed our children.
He is nothing to us.
I will take some men.
We will shoot some arrows into this white man.
If he truly has medicine, he will not be hurt.
If he has no medicine, he will be dead.
No man can tell another what to do.
But killing a white man is a delicate matter.
If you kill one, more are sure to come.
It's easy to become confused
by these questions.
It's hard to know what to do.
We should talk about this some more.
That is all I have to say.
What's the matter, now?
We don't think this is such a good idea.
If we take the horse of a white god...
...they will make up songs about us.
Maybe.
They will ask us to go on raids.
Who gets the horse?
I do.
I do, but we share. Now who can say
this is not a great plan?
It's always the same.
Every time.
We'll be heroes.
They'll write songs about us.
What happened?
I don't know. My arm doesn't work.
You shouldn't have fallen off.
Now we'll get in trouble.
It was your idea.
My idea was only to take the horse,
not fall down.
Otter hurt himself.
What are you looking at?
I'm the one who's hurt.
I will be when my father finds out.
His bow will be across my back.
I am Wind In His Hair.
Do you see that I am not afraid of you?
Do you see?
The party that went against the Utes
is coming back.
There are many hearts on the ground.