They cut the bloody rations!
-Don't worry. I'll get yours.
-You're just like your father.
They cut our rations in half!
I'll get ours. You sit down.
You cut the bloody rations!
You cut them!
I've got yours, Mr. Maxton.
I've got some! I've got some!
Hello, everybody.
-Sit there.
-Eat it up, please.
The rations have been cut.
They're like animals.
82, 83, 84....
87 weevils today, Mr. Victor.
That's above average,
but the trend is down.
-Must you, Jim?
-Sorry.
Some of us will die just before we're
saved, so use everything.
-You'll miss this camp after the war.
-Will I?
I'll locate my parents when the people
in the camps come out.
-I'll tell my dad you looked after me.
-Think I'll get the reward?
-What reward?
-You told everyone.
I was much younger then.
Why'd the Japanese close the school?
To punish the grownups.
I wonder how you'll take to school
in England.
It might be a bit strange.
The best teacher's the university
of life.
For heaven's--
Could we finish our meal? We know your
views on the university of life.
-We should eat the weevils.
-I know. Dr. Rawlins told you.
-He said we need the protein.
-Yes, he's right.
We should eat all the weevils.
Do you believe in vitamins?
Strange child.
Perhaps it's time you moved into
the men's dormitory.
You're not 1 2 anymore.
The Americans are over Nantao again.
They're bombing the Shanghai docks!
Coney lsland pilots.
-What was that?
-A 29 going down.
-A 200-pounder.
-That was close.
-Too close for Nagata.
-He won't go like that.
What's happening, doctor?
Reprisals, and damned silly it is too.
-Keep the patients from the windows.
-Yes, doctor.
Get away! This is British food!
Leave it alone!
This is our food. Get away!
Guards!
Mines. That was a mine. I told you.
Somebody lobbed a grenade.
Say, Basie, I bet he hits a mine.
I bet you there are no mines.
You can walk right through.
You got a bet.
So far so good.
He's seen something.
Jim's a black cat.
That's a dead boy, Basie.
I'll give you odds.
My harmonica...
...and my next meal
against your wristwatch.
You're on, my friend.
I double my bet. My next two meals.
-You'll lose a lot of weight.
-What else you betting?
-My Life.
-Who's on the cover?
-Two cigarettes on the kid!
-Sunglasses on Nagata!
Keep going, sarge!
-The lucky kid.
-Cleaned me out.
-Hello, Jim.
-Hello, Nina.
-Would you like a Hershey bar?
-Yes.
So would I, kid. You got one?
Don't let me down, kid.
You're an American now.
How you doing, Frank?
The river's east. You can go
up the bank or up the middle...
...or go north of east,
but you gotta go across canals.
It doesn't say if it's
buildings or what.
Where'd you get a map?
It's a cork and needle?
-A compass that actually works.
-Put it down.
-ls it time?
-No, I'll tell you when.
-You won't forget?
-Fat chance.
-I almost feel human.
-Without me, you'd have no compass.
No, without you
I wouldn't have the needle.
The best way is across the river.
Jim, the curtain.
Jim, come here.
You're in charge of my stuff.
You see this mosquito net?
See?
What does that tell you?
Rawlins is on the take.
-You're so clever, Basie.
-Yeah.
Only cost me two batteries.
How are you feeling?
I've had worse.
I was beaten by a stoker once.
Were you a stoker?
Ship's steward. Shanghai-Frisco line.
Why did he beat you?
Shanghai-Frisco will be
the trip now. Huh, Jim?
Basie, where do you live?
Here.
No, I mean after the war.
Somewhere else.
Until you find a place,
you could live at Amherst Avenue.
I'd like you to come
and meet my parents.
We could fill up the pool...
...and we'll eat three times a day.
You're not feeling
sorry for me, are you?
-No one feels sorry for you, Basie.
-That's right.
-And you always eat first.
-You said it, kid.
I've been thinking about
going upriver.
I know.
Listen--
The plan is,
we're going to get a sampan.
Take it up the Yangtze estuary.
Rendezvous with some Hakka friends.
Are they proper pirates, you mean?
Let's just call them gentlemen
of fortune, shall we?
Did you ever see...
-...the Hell Drivers in Shanghai?
-Yes. On the news reels.
I saw them crash
through a burning wall.
That's what I'm going to call
our little outfit.
With 250 calibers...
...we are going to be
the lords of the Yangtze.
Actually, that may be a better name.
It's at the beginning and end of war
that we have to watch out.
In between, it's like a country club.
But you gotta know how to stay
balanced and make the right friends.
Because this war
is definitely winding down.
And after that?
After that...
...I retire in luxury,
start a barber college....
What are you doing here?
I told you to look out for my stuff.
They were bigger than me.
-Look who's here.
-Heard they had you under the net.
Stay with me, Johnny!
-Get everybody inside, quick!
-Stay away from the building!
Oh, God. Please, no!
My husband's in there.
Go! P-51 , Cadillac of the sky!
P-51 , Cadillac of the sky!
Jim, get off the roof!
Horsepower!
Get down, Jim. Go on, get down!
P-51 ! Aren't they beautiful?
-Get down!
-I touched them!
I felt their heat! I can taste them.
Oil and cordite.
Come back to the hospital.
Remember how we helped
to build the runway?
lf we died like the others,
our bones would be in the runway.
-In a way, it's our runway.
-No, it's their runway, Jim.
Try not to think so much.
Try not to think so much!
I can't remember
what my parents look like.
I used to play bridge
with my mother in her bedroom.
She used to comb her hair.
I'd watch her.
She had dark hair.
What's happening? What's happening?
The guards are leaving!
They're taking us upcountry.
They're moving us to Nantao!
The Japanese say there's food there.
One suitcase! We leave in one hour!
One suitcase!
They've got our rations at Nantao.
He's gone.
Him and Dainty.
He's gone?
He's escaped!
He can't have. He promised me!
He knew it was time.
-Where am I gonna go?
-We'll all have to leave now.
He knew it was time.
Boy.
Difficult boy.
Just look...
...later here for escort!
Jim, where's my husband?
Where's Mr. Victor?
We are civilians. Listen to me.
I am a British doctor.
They are my responsibility!
No, we must have rest and food.
We're going upcountry, Jim.
Will there be food there?
There's none here.
Mrs. Victor, we're going upcountry.
Come on, Jim.
Don't go. It's better here.
You'll die here.
Don't worry, Mr. Maxton.
Pretend you're dead, Mrs. Victor.
Surrender reached the Japanese
in a broadcast by Hirohito.
He said Japan will endure the
unendurable and suffer greatly.
The war minister and others
committed suicide outside the palace.
Japan is devastated,
destroyed in spirit. ..
...as Hiroshima and Nagasakihave
been destroyed.
More than 100,000 people
were killed in two...
...single-bomb explosions, which
ended the Pacifiic War.
The Russian declaration of war...
...has sent a million
soldiers into Manchuria.
Tokyo was hit with a dawn-to-dusk
raid by 1500 B-29 bombers.
But Japan's war was lost.
Her goal to create...
...a new empire incinerated
in a flash...
...hotter than the sun.
Everyone stands in awe of
the new super-weapon.
Only a few scientists knew the power
in splitting the uranium atom.
It reached us in a shock wave...
...and a white light: the atom bomb.
Each of the two bombs...
...had the power of
20,000 tons of explosives.
Nagasakiis
Japan's gateway to China...
...just 500 miles from Shanghai.
I saw that! I saw that! I saw that!
The white light.
I thought it was Mrs. Victor's
soul going to heaven.
Bastard!
He gave me a mango.
I'll give you
a whole fruit salad!
There's Frigidaires
falling from the sky!
-He was my friend!
-He was a Jap!
The war's over!
You walked all the way
here from Nantao Stadium?
What did you see? Rich pickings?
Crystal chandeliers, cocktail bars...
...white pianos?
I learned a new word today.
Atom bomb.
It was like a white light
in the sky.
Like God taking a photograph.
I saw it.
I can bring everyone back.
Everyone.
-Didn't I teach you anything?
-Yes!
You taught me people will do
anything for a potato.
Three years with him?
Come on. I'll take you
back to your dad.
You can retire
and eat three meals a day.
Kid, you want a Hershey bar?
Yes, please, Basie.
I surrender.
Come along. Off you go.
Gather in, children. Come along.
Mum.
Ju-- Julie!
Jamie?
Jamie.