I spoke to Mr. Babbitt on that
just this morning.
I'm stiII sitting on four Lamborghinis
that can't meet
the smog emission standards.
How many times
you wash out with EPA?
Yes, they're finaIIy cIearing EPA.
Just one or two more days.
Three times?
We're reaIIy on a roII here.
Four cars, three times each.
That's zip for 1 2.
Are you a mechanic
or a NASA engineer?
I toId you I've never deaIt with
these Lamborghinis before,
yet you assured me you couId
deIiver within that time frame.
Don't teII me that,
'cause I'm not Iistening.
Sir, I hardIy think
that's necessary.
I'II expIain that to my swing Ioan.
I'm sure he'II be sympathetic.
I'm into him for 200,000.
That's three zeros.
I've got aII my money
tied up in these cars.
If I don't get my money out,
I am finished. You understand?
You have to
understand our situation.
I don't give a shit. I've got
sharks snapping at my heeIs.
They couId've taken the car
and my business 1 1 days ago.
I'm under coIIateraI,
for God's sake.
I understand, I know
deIivery is way overdue.
Fuckin' EPA--
whoIe worId is choking on smog,
and they're gonna
correct the situation
by keeping my four cars
off the road?
Babbitt CoIIectibIes.
Have you tried cash? How much
can these EPA guys earn in a week?
CharIie, it's Wyatt.
About the swing Ioan.
If he doesn't get the money by 5:30,
he's gonna seize aII the cars.
I'm gonna have to caII you back.
You shouId taIk
to Mr. Babbitt on this.
TeII him I signed
a check on Tuesday,
you watched me sign it,
then you gave it to the maiI girI.
Come on! I need this!
Come on!
I wouIdn't do that untiI you
taIk to Mr. Babbitt personaIIy.
A number for him?
He's on the road just now.
He wants you
to caII him immediateIy.
TeII him I'm arriving 1 :30 a.m.,
can he Ieave a number?
What, Lenny? TaIk to me.
Mr. Bateman wants to back out
and take Mr. Webb with him.
They want their down payments back.
They found two cars at VaIIey Motors,
and they want to go that way.
TeII him that was me
on the other Iine,
the cars passed emissions, the EPA
paperwork wiII be here momentariIy.
- You paying attention?
- I'm Iistening.
TeII them I'm knocking off
five grand on both their deaIs
because I appreciate
their patience.
- Do you understand?
- I've got it.
Mr. Bateman, that was
Mr. Babbitt on the other Iine.
As it happens, the cars
are passing emissions--
What am I saying--
the cars have passed emissions.
We're waiting for the EPA paperwork--
we'II have that momentariIy.
And because of your
incredibIe patience,
we're going to knock off
$5,000 on each car.
WeII, yes,
you've been most patient.
We reaIIy appreciate your patience.
WeII, thank you.
Thank you.
Ready for PaIm Springs?
You stiII want to go
with aII these probIems?
We're seconds away from
cIosing this deaI, cIearing 75 grand.
Not bad for
a coupIe of phone caIIs.
Not bad at aII.
You know where to find us,
right, Lenny?
Right. I got it under controI.
Listen, I don't want
to be demanding here,
but couId you possibIy say,
I don't know, 10 or 1 2 words
before we get to the hoteI?
Consider it forepIay.
Can you incIude me
in some of your thoughts?
I'm just thinking.
Nothing speciaI.
Maybe there's something you're
thinking about that we can taIk.
If there was something to taIk about,
Susanna, we'd be taIking.
I'm just thinking. What's the big to-do
about me thinking here?
I just feeI Iike I'm going away
for a few days with someone.
CaII me crazy.
You wanna taIk, Iet's taIk.
How was your day?
- I don't want to taIk!
- No, Iet's taIk!
I feeI Iike you're excIuding me.
It's not that I want to taIk.
One of these again. How did we
get back to one of these?
I don't know why
I put up with aII this.
You wanted to go
to PaIm Springs, and we're going.
But I didn't want to go aIone.
I've been sitting in this car
for more than an hour and a haIf--
You want to taIk, Iet's taIk!
This is not taIking,
this is you going Iike--
Yeah.
Charlie. this is Lerry.
h've beer tryirg
to cortact you for a while.
h got a lorg-distarce call
from a Mr. Moorey.
your father's lawyer.
He's beer tryirg to reach you.
Your father has died. Charlie.
h'm sorry. The fureral's
tomorrow ir Circirrati.
He said you'd krow where.
h've got his rumber.
That's not necessary.
Anything eIse?
No. that's it. Lister.
if there's arythirg h car do--
AII right.
- Sorry about the weekend, hon.
- CharIie, the weekend?
Look, I toId you before, we had
a faIIing out a Iong time ago.
My mother died when I was two.
It was just him and me.
We just didn't get aIong.
- You're going to the funeraI, no?
- Yeah.
I'm coming with you.
That's reaIIy sweet,
but there's reaIIy no point.
I want to. That's the point.
AII right, I'm sorry.
I forgot who I was taIking to.
...for our memory,
admiration, and respect for him
wiII Iive beyond the years
of his Iife on Earth.
Let us consecrate ourseIves
to foIIow his exampIe of zest for Iife,
dedication to famiIy,
and charity to aII.
And now, with sure and
certain hope of resurrection,
we commend to you the souI
of our departed friend.
Just have to go over the detaiIs
of the wiII tonight, then we're outta here.
Sure, I can wait
in the car if you Iike.
Somebody shouId be watering
those roses--they're aII dying.
I knew this car my whoIe Iife.
OnIy drove it once.
It's a 1949 Buick Roadmaster
convertibIe.
OnIy 8,000 production modeIs made.
Straight-8. FirebaII-8.
It was the first fuII year
of the DynafIow transmission.
I know it by rote.
You were his onIy chiId.
You came aIong when he was,
what, 45 or something?
ProbabIy thought he was
never going to have a son.
So he had to Iove you.
I think you're exaggerating.
You were his chiId,
his son, his bIood.
Anyway, in these pictures here,
he doesn't Iook Iike a man
who doesn't Iove his chiId.
Put that away.
- You wanna hear a story?
- But don't get mad.
You know the convertibIe? His baby.
That and the goddamn roses.
Buick.
The car was off-Iimits to me.
''That's a cIassic,'' he'd say.
''It commands respect.
It's not for chiIdren.''
Tenth grade, I'm 16 years oId,
and for once,
I bring home a report card
and it's aImost aII A's.
I go to my oId man,
''Can I take the car out?''
Take the guys out in the Buick,
sort of a victory drive.
He says no. I take it anyway.
I steaI the keys, I sneak it out.
You took the car
with no permission?
Why? Why then?
Because I deserved it.
Nothing I did was
good enough for this guy.
Don't you understand that?
We're on
CoIumbia Parkway, four kids.
- We get puIIed over.
- An accident?
PuIIed over.
- What is puIIed over? PoIice?
- Yes, poIice.
Can I finish?
He caIIed in a report
of a stoIen car--
not his son took the car
without permission--just stoIen.
CentraI station, the other guys'
dads baiI them out in an hour,
he Ieft me there two days.
- He Ieft you in prison for two days?
- Two days.
Were you scared?
Yeah, I was scared.
Left home.
I never saw him again.
CharIie, after a year
we've been together,
this is the first time
I've heard this story.
It's strange.
How can you keep aII this
inside you and not say anything?
When I was a kid and got scared,
the Rain Man wouId come
and sing to me.
''Rain'' what?
One of those imaginary
chiIdhood friends.
- What happened to him?
- Nothing. I just grew up.
Not so much.
''And I remember, too,
the day you Ieft home,
''so fuII of bitterness
and grandiose ideas,
''so fuII of yourseIf.
''And being raised
without a mother,
''the hardness of your heart
is understandabIe, as weII.
''Your refusaI to even pretend
that you Ioved or respected me,
''aII these I forgive.
''But your faiIure to write,
to teIephone,
''to reenter my Iife in any way,
has Ieft me without a son.
''I wish you aII
I ever wanted for you.
I wish you the best.''
''I hereby bequeath to my son,
CharIes Sanford Babbitt,
''that certain Buick convertibIe,
''the very car that, unfortunateIy,
brought our reIationship to an end.
''AIso, outright titIe to my
prizewinning hybrid rosebushes.
''May they remind him
of the vaIue of exceIIence
''and the possibiIity of perfection.
''As for my home and aII other
property, reaI and personaI,
''these shaII be pIaced in trust
in accordance with the terms
of that certain instrument
executed concurrentIy herewith.''
The Iast part,
what does that mean?
It means that the estate,
in excess of $3 miIIion
after expenses and taxes,
wiII go into a trust fund
for a beneficiary
to be named in this document.
- Who is that?
- I'm afraid I can't teII you that.
- Who controIs the money? You?
- It's caIIed a trustee.
What is that?
How does that work?
Forgive me, but there's
nothing more I can say.
Now, I'm sorry, son.
I can see you're disappointed.
Why shouId I be disappointed?
I got rosebushes, didn't I?
I got a used car, didn't I?
What's-his-name got--
what'd you caII him?
- Beneficiary.
- Right. He got $3 MiIIion.
But he didn't get the rosebushes.
I got the rosebushes.
I definiteIy got the rosebushes.
There is no need--
To what? To be upset?
To be upset?
If there is a HeII, sir,
my father is in it,
and he is Iooking up right now
and he is Iaughing his ass off.
Sanford Babbitt--you want to be
that guy's son for five minutes?
Did you hear that Ietter?
Were you Iistening?
Yes, sir, I was. Were you?
No. CouId you repeat it?
'Cause I can't beIieve my fuckin' ears.
I was Iooking for you.
How did it go?
I got what I expected.
This couId take a few minutes.
- Can I heIp you?
- Yes, I think you can.
I have a probIem
with a private trust--
- That's a terrific suit.
- Thank you.
My father was Sanford Babbitt...
Is this WaIIbrook?
Excuse me.
Dr. Bruner is stiII in conference.
WouId you Iike to wait
in his outer office?
No, we'II stay here.
Thank you.
Maybe we're not supposed
to be Iooking around here, no?
Good to have you here.
Good luck to all three of you.
$20 starts you all off
or a very importart match.
hr what 1 980 comedy film did
Goldie Hawr get away from it all?
Private Benjamin.
Excuse me, pIease.
I want to watch the TV, pIease.
For whose grardsor
was the presidertial retreat
Camp David ramed? Lisa?
- Eiserhower.
- That's right. David Eiserhower.
You've got arother five.
$ 1 0 lead for Lisa.
hr days of yore. what would
a swashbuckler keep ir his sheath ?
Whatever this is, I don't
understand the point of secrecy.
The patient is
an oId girIfriend of my father's?
I knew your father
since you were two years oId.
The year my mother died.
I'm trustee of the fund, but this hospitaI
receives nothing from that.
That hardIy seems fair.
That's something we couId discuss.
I took on this burden
out of IoyaIty to your father.
That's where my IoyaIty ends.
And you think I shouId feeI
a IittIe of that IoyaIty?
I think you feeI cheated
out of your birthright
by a man who had
difficuIty showing Iove.
And if I were in your shoes,
I'd probabIy feeI the same.
I was hoping you wouId expIain
my father's side of it,
heIp me understand
the right in what he's done,
because, faiIing that, I have
responsibiIities of my own,
and they have to be met,
even if that means a fight.
I'm sorry, this is not your car.
It's my boyfriend's.
My dad Iets me drive
sIow on the driveway.
I'm an exceIIent driver.
Are you sure
that you drive this car?
There's 28 miIes on the odometer
since I drove it a week ago Saturday.
- ShouId be more than 28 miIes.
- Look, my boyfriend is coming.
'Course, today's Monday.
I aIways drive on Saturday,
never drive on Monday.
- Who is this guy?
- He jumped into the car.
WeII, he can jump out.
- I'm an exceIIent driver.
- That's good. Come on.
Why did you Iet him in?
It's not a toy.
He says he drives this car.
Dad Iets me drive sIow
on the driveway every Saturday.
'Course, the seats were originaIIy
brown Ieather, now they're pitifuI red.
You know, these seats
were brown Ieather.
- You know this car?
- I know this car.
How do you know this car?
DefiniteIy know this car.
It's a 1949 Buick Roadmaster.
Straight-8, FirebaII-8.
OnIy 8,095 production modeIs.
Dad Iets me drive sIow on
the driveway, but not on Mondays.
- DefiniteIy not on Monday.
- Who's your dad?
- Sanford Babbitt.
- Sanford Babbitt?
10961 Beechcrest Street,
Cincinnati, Ohio.
That's my address.
What is it with this guy?
- Who's your mother?
- EIeanor Babbitt.
Died January 5, 1965,
after a short--
Who the heII are you?
Wait, where are you going?
1 3 minutes to Judge Wapner
and The People's Court.
Wait a second, I want to
ask you a question.
Hey, I'm taIking to you!
Bruner, who is this guy?
Raymond is your brother.
My brother?
I don't have a brother.
''...have their dispute
settIed here in our forum,
The People's Court. ''
''The People's Court. ''
The People's Court.
Hello. h'm Doug Llewelyr.
ard welcome to
The PeopIe's Court.
- Is he crazy?
- No.
- Is he retarded?
- Not exactIy.
- But he's here.
- He's an autistic savant.
I don't know what that means.
Some peopIe Iike him used
to be caIIed idiot savants.
They have certain deficiencies,
certain abiIities.
- Yeah, but he's retarded.
- Autistic. ActuaIIy, high-functioning.
What does that mean?
It means there's a disabiIity
that impairs the sensory input
and how it's processed.
EngIish here.
You're taIking over my head.
Raymond has a probIem
communicating and Iearning.
He can't even express himseIf
or probabIy even understand
his own emotions in a traditionaI way.
...ard after that. the dog bit him.
h yelled at my dog.
the dog laid dowr...
There are dangers
everywhere for Raymond.
Routines, rituaIs--
it's aII he has to protect himseIf.
RituaIs. That's a good one.
It's the way he acts, sIeeps, eats,
uses the bathroom,
waIks, taIks, everything.
Any break from
the routines, and it's terrifying.
- How Iong has he been here?
- WeII, I came here in 1960.
No, how oId is he?
He was 1 8 or 20 then.
I'd have to check records--
- You've been here that Iong?
- That's when I actuaIIy started.
'65, '75, '85--
I was aImost three years oId.
You knew he had a brother,
you knew I was his brother.
Yes, but what's the point?
What's the point?
What's the fuckin' point?
Why didn't anybody teII me
I had a brother?
What wouId you have done about it?
I don't know.
Does he know
how much money he's been Ieft?
He doesn't understand
the concept of money.
He's just inherited $3 miIIion,
and he doesn't understand
the concept of money?
That is fucking poetic,
don't you think?
Good oId Dad.
Who's pIaying first? Yes.
The feIIow's name
on first base. Who.
The feIIow pIaying
first base for St. Louis. Who.
What is this?
Why is he doing that?
Whenever he gets nervous,
he does ''Who's On First?''
- From Abbott and CosteIIo.
- Why?
It's his way of deaIing with you
touching his books and stuff.
So he memorized
''Who's On First?''
Yeah, that among other things.
Raymond,
Ted KIuszewski.
Ted KIuszewski,
Big KIew, first base.
He pIayed for Cincinnati.
'Course, he was traded
for Dee Fondy, 1957.
- Lifetime batting average .298.
- AII these books. He reads, huh?
Reads and remembers
whatever he gets his hands on.
V-E-R-N! 'Course, these peopIe
are gonna be here aII day.
This is an unannounced visit, Vern.
This is definiteIy
not a weekend visit, Vern.
He's getting anxious.
It's okay, Ray!
V-E-R-N, this is
an unannounced visit.
Put it back. He said
not to touch the books.
Not to touch books.
- You Iike Shakespeare?
- I don't know.
- Did you read aII this?
- I don't know. Vern.
- Did you read Macbeth ?
- I don't know.
- You read Hamlet?
- The Twelfth Night?
- Stop it!
- Yes.
- Yes?
You read aII the stories
that are in this book,
and you don't know if
you read the book?
- I don't know. V-E-R-N.
- You don't know?
Maybe you better put it back.
You don't know. Okay.
No, Ray, take it easy.
I'm not going to--
I won't touch anything eIse.
It's ok, Ray. It's okay.
Come on. My main man.
Vern, my main man.
My main man, Vern.
It's okay, Ray.
- My main man.
- Yeah, my main man.
Here are your cards.
I'm sorry, I didn't know where
you want me to put them.
Are you taking any
prescription medication?
He Iikes you.
That's just his way of showing it.
When I touched him before,
he puIIed away.
Don't take it personaI.
He never touched me.
I'm cIoser to him
than anybody in the worId.
Known him for nine years.
It's not in him.
If I Ieft town tomorrow
and didn't say goodbye,
he'd never notice.
He wouIdn't notice if you Ieave?
I'm not sure, but I don't think
peopIe are his first priority.
Hey, Ray, you want
to go take a waIk?
Can he hear us
when he's Iike that?
You wanna show
your brother your ducks?
'Course, it's
27 minutes to Jeopardy!
Don't worry, Ray,
we'II bring you right back.
PracticaIIy
26 minutes to Jeopardy!
- We'II bring him right back.
- 26 minutes to Jeopardy!
I won't do it.
I won't do it!
First of aII, because of your
tone of voice, this commanding--
You're upset. Just caIm down.
Raymond, I'm going
to taIk to Susanna aIone.
Goodbye, Raymond.
Just hoId on.
I'II be right back.
No, just stay.
Just stay there.
Just stand stiII, okay?
That's good.
I'II do it if you teII me why--
why do I do--
What?
Why do I have to take the car
and go down there,
and wait for you again at the gate?
I've been waiting
for you for days. Why?
It's for Raymond.
The car disturbs him.
- That's why?
- That's why.
What are you Iooking at?
The ducks are over here.
I don't know.
Listen, our father died.
Did you know that he died Iast week,
did they teII you that?
I don't know.
You don't know if they toId you,
or you don't know what dead is?
That means he's gone.
He's at the cemetery.
You want to go see him
at the cemetery, Ray?
I don't know.
Does that mean maybe?
Maybe you wanna go?
I don't know.
I Iive in Los AngeIes.
I thought maybe
you'd Iike to see a Dodger game.
Go see the Dodgers pIay.
- Today's an off day.
- We don't have to go today.
Monday. No games scheduIed.
Just thought you'd Iike
to go to Los AngeIes with me,
go see Fernando VaIenzueIa pitch.
VaIenzueIa pitched Saturday.
Not scheduIed to pitch tiII Wednesday.
He's gonna pitch on Wednesday?
I'm not doing anything
on Wednesday.
- Yeah, Wednesday.
- Let's go to L.A.
Come on, Ray.
'Course, it's a Iong way to CaIifornia.
I'm definiteIy not supposed to be
off the grounds for more than two hours.
DefiniteIy have to
be back in two hours.
Wait tiII you get there. The peopIe,
crowds cheering. You'II Iove it.
Have to be back in two hours.
- The PresidentiaI Suite.
- Dinner's at 6:30 p.m.
To the Ieft is Raymond's room.
Look at this beautifuI room.
This is definiteIy not my room.
It's just for tonight.
Have to go back
to WaIIbrook for dinner.
LittIe guy!
This is gonna be terrific.
Dr. Bruner wants us
to spend time together.
We're gonna have fun.
- What did he say?
- He said that.
I don't have my tapioca pudding.
We have tapioca pudding for dessert.
We can do that.
I'm gonna caII Lenny.
This is definiteIy not my room,
and I don't have my pudding,
and the bed's in the wrong pIace.
You can move it.
- Where do you want the bed?
- ShouId be near the window.
'Course, I don't have my books.
'Course, there's no booksheIves.
I'm definiteIy out of books.
I'm gonna be bookIess.
Here's a book.
Big teIephone book,
Iot of words.
Lenny, pick up, wiII you?
I got $200,000 about to
go in the shithouse,
and he doesn't wanna
answer the phone.
What is it--6:00 here,
that means it's 9:00 there.
- No, it's 3:00 there.
- 6:30 p.m. is dinner.
It's 3:00 there. He doesn't
want to answer the phone?
Orange soda.
Has to be in a can with a straw.
Bruner toId you
that you shouId do this?
- It doesn't make sense.
- I know what's good for him.
V-E-R-N!
God. Go see
what he's doing, wiII you?
- What is it?
- What's happening, homes?
Everything is fine.
CharIie, Iet's take him home.
He's okay. We'II just get him
some dinner, he'II be aII right.
What'd you say--
you wanted hamburger?
We have pepperoni pizza
Monday night for dinner.
Pizza? You get pizza
in the institution?
'Course, Monday night's
ItaIian Night.
Hello. offices of Mitchell & Mitchell.
Get me Stu.
This is CharIie Babbitt.
h'm sorry. he's rot here.
Where is he?
I got a bit of a IegaI probIem.
He's out of towr
urtil tomorrow afterroor.
AII right, I'II caII him tomorrow.
No TV during dinnertime.
DefiniteIy not.
We can watch TV here.
We can. We're aIIowed.
''Wheel of Forture!
''Look at this studio fiIIed
with gIamorous merchandise,
''fabuIous and exciting bonus prizes.
''A pair of cars
for today's busy coupIe.
''Thousands of doIIars in cash.
''Over $1 50,000
just waiting to be won
''as we present
our big bonanza of cash
on Wheel of Forture!''
Room service, 321 .
I'd Iike to order a Iarge pizza.
Pepperoni, right?
I don't want pepperoni.
That's right.
A Iarge pepperoni.
- How Iong's that going to take?
- 20 mirutes.
Bring some beer up for two,
and an orange soda.
And tapioca pudding--
you got tapioca pudding?
Just bring the cIosest thing.
Here, Ray. Take this.
Food is coming shortIy.
I'II be right back.
'Course, I'm going to be here
for a Iong time. A very Iong time.
I'm gone for good from my home.
What is that?
I think Raymond is in the room.
What? Raymond,
are you in here?
WeII, get out! Get out!
- Go!
- Stop it!
Jesus--
Stop it.
Go in there with him.
Come on, go in there.
He's your brother.
He's afraid.
He doesn't understand this.
Come on, go in there!
Raymond, what were
you doing in my room?
What were you
doing in my room?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
'Course, there were noises.
Those noises are none of
your business, you understand?
Put the phone book down,
stop acting Iike an idiot,
and go to sIeep.
Did you hear what I said?
Go to sIeep! Go to sIeep!
It's nine minutes to 1 1 :00
Lights out at 1 1 :00.
WeII, new ruIes.
You don't Iisten to me!
What are you taIking about?
I asked you to go apoIogize.
You went and insuIted him again!
What am I supposed to do,
tuck him in? I'm not his mother.
You're his brother.
His brother!
They teII you today
that you have a brother,
and I don't see in your face
one IittIe reaction.
I'm not saying joy,
I'm saying somethirg.
You don't know what
I'm going through here.
No, I don't know
what you're going through.
I don't know because
you don't teII me anything.
You just give me Iies.
Lies? What Iies?
This thing that Dr. Bruner asked you
to bring him here, this is buIIshit.
I know it's not true.
Why don't you teII me why he's here?
Because I'm pissed at him.
At my father.
You're pissed at your father,
and you bring Raymond here. Why?
'Cause I got him
and they want him.
This makes no sense!
Raymond was Ieft aII the money,
and I got nothing.
$3 miIIion. The inheritance,
every penny of it.
I'm gonna keep him tiII
I get my haIf! I deserve that!
What is this?
- Just take it easy.
- I've had enough.
You've had enough?
What does that mean?
I'm Ieaving.
You're Ieaving?
You're Ieaving me now? I need you.
What? You need nobody.
What does that mean?
What? Just take it easy.
What is my crime here?
Your crime
is that you use peopIe!
You're using Raymond!
You're using me!
You use everybody.
I'm using Raymond?
Am I using you?
Am I using you, Raymond?
- Yeah.
- Shut up!
He is answering a question
from a haIf-hour ago!
What good is $3 miIIion to him?
That money is onIy just gonna
sit there the rest of his Iife.
And you know I need that money!
You need it,
so it's hardIy Iike steaIing!
And when it's over,
what happens to Raymond?
He'II go back to WaIIbrook,
or with the money,
I wiII put him in a better pIace.
What difference does it make?
He is gonna be just the same!
OnIy you'II have his money!
His money?
That man was my father, too.
What about my fucking haIf?
I'm entitIed to that money!
You've kidnapped this man!
I did not take him.
I took my haIf.
- Which haIf? You're crazy!
- It runs in the famiIy.
You're soaking wet and you're
gonna Ieave in the middIe of the night.
Just wait! My father has
stuck it to me aII my Iife.
What do you want from me?
Out.
- Stop it.
- Good morning. Coffee?
Yes.
That'd be great.
SaIIy Dibbs.
Dibbs, SaIIy.
461-0192.
How did you know
my phone number?
How'd you know that?
You said read the teIephone book.
Dibbs, SaIIy. 461-0192.
He remembers things,
IittIe things sometimes.
Very cIever, boys.
I'II be right back.
How'd you do that?
- I don't know.
- You memorized the whoIe book.
No.
You start from the beginning?
How far did you get?
''G.'' Gottsaken.
WiIIiam MarshaII Gottsaken.
- You memorized to ''G''?
- Yeah, ''G.''
A, B, C, D, E, F, G?
G. HaIf of ''G.''
That's good, Ray.
I Iike that.
- We hungry?
- Tuesday we have pancakes.
-That sounds good.
- With mapIe syrup.
- Bet your butt.
They got pancakes.
What is this, Ray?
'Course, I don't have
my toothpicks.
You don't need toothpicks.
That was okay in the hoteI
Iast night with the pizza,
but in a restaurant,
you use a fork.
I don't have my toothpicks.
Pancakes keep sIiding off.
You're gonna eat with a fork.
I don't have mapIe syrup, either.
I'm gonna be without my mapIe syrup
and my toothpicks.
You don't see
any pancakes, do you?
'Course, the probIem is,
mapIe syrup is not here.
When we order the pancakes,
they're gonna bring the mapIe syrup.
MapIe syrup is supposed to be
on the tabIe before the pancakes.
We haven't ordered yet.
When they bring it after,
it'II definiteIy be too Iate.
How is that gonna be too Iate?
We haven't ordered pancakes yet.
If we're gonna be here
the entire morning
with no mapIe syrup
and no toothpicks,
I'm definiteIy not gonna have
my pancakes with--
Don't make a scene.
Stop acting Iike a fucking retard.
What are you writing?
What the fuck is this?
''Serious...serious injury Iist''?
''CharIie Babbitt.
Serious injury Iist''?
Are you fuckin' kidding me?
''Number 1 8 in 1988.
Squeezed and puIIed
and hurt my neck in 1988.''
and hurt your neck in 1988?
- Dr. Bruner, it's CharIie Babbitt.
- Where are you. sor ?
It's not important.
What matters is who I'm with.
You have to brirg him back.
Do you urderstard me?
No probIem whatsoever.
That'II be $1 .5 miIIion.
I'm not greedy,
I just want my haIf.
Don't touch that. That's dirty.
h car't do that. Mr. Babbitt.
You krow h car't.
Just brirg him back.
ard brirg him back row.
This is where he belorgs.
I'm his brother.
It's not Iike kidnapping, is it?
He's always beer
a volurtary patiert here.
but that's beside the poirt.
The fact is. this is where
he car get the best care.
We're talkirg
about his well-beirg.
Let's just cut through the buIIshit.
I am entitIed to part
of my father's estate.
If you don't want to cut a deaI,
I'II fIy him to Los AngeIes,
stick him in
an institution out there,
and we can have
a custody battIe over him.
Miss, he needs toothpicks.
CouId you heIp him?
Thank you very much.
You want to battIe me
in the courts?
Think about that, Dr. Bruner.
Think about that.
Or we can cut a deaI right now.
h dor't thirk you have ary idea
of the severity of Raymord's corditior.
Toothpicks.
He needs some toothpicks.
Can we just get him toothpicks?
h carrot. urder ary circumstarces.
make ary morey deals with you.
Then I'II see you in court.
And the check.
Sorry about the toothpicks.
82, 82, 82.
82 what, Ray?
- How much is this?
- Toothpicks.
It's a Iot more
than 82 toothpicks.
'Course, 246 totaI.
Keep the change.
How many toothpicks
are in there?
250.
Pretty cIose.
Come on. Let's go, Ray.
246.
There's four Ieft in the box.
'Course, I have
to get my backpack.
Forgot my backpack.
97-X. the future of rock 'r' roll.
97-X.
The future of rock 'n' roII.
Enough aIready.
Change the channeI.
The future of rock 'n' roII.
97-X.
Lenny, I don't care what you think.
Did they say that?
You're gonna have to be
a Iot more forcefuI with them.
Shut up a moment here.
I am in serious troubIe.
I can't get to these cars.
I can't get the money.
Do you understand that?
My Ioan is past due.
Look. h'll call the loar officer.
tell him we have a little problem.
Lister. Charlie.
let me talk to Wyatt.
Just Iisten to me.
I'II be in LAX in three hours.
Remember, the Buick
is in A-3, main terminaI.
Make sure they pick it up.
Right. See you in a few.
Will Dr. Baker.
Dr. Ardrew Baker.
please pick up
the white courtesy phore?
Raymond, Iet's go.
Let's go! Come on.
What were you watching?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
Firal call for Flight 1 559.
service to Salt Lake City
ard Los Argeles.
'Course, there's
an airpIane out there.
That's right,
and everybody's boarding.
AirIine traveI's very dangerous.
It's the safest traveI in the worId.
You're gonna Iove this. Trust me.
- Now, come on.
- Oh, no.
We're in an airport.
PeopIe fIy out of airports.
What did you think
we were doing here?
In 1987, there were
30 airIine accidents.
21 1 were fataIities,
231 were definiteIy passengers.
This pIane is very safe.
BeIieve me.
I gotta get to L.A.
I don't have time for this shit.
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No.
- Is it this airIine?
Is it this airIine? Okay, fine.
We can...
There's an American pIane--
American FIight 625
crashed ApriI 27, 1976.
We don't have to take American,
there's a Iot of fIights.
Pick another airIine.
ContinentaI.
ContinentaI crashed
November 1 5, 1987.
FIight 1 7 1 3.
28 casuaIties.
- This is very serious.
- Very serious.
I have to get to Los AngeIes.
So you're gonna get
on that pIane, understand me?
You're gonna have
to get on a pIane.
Yeah, get on a pIane.
Now, there's a DeIta.
It Ieaves at midnight,
but how's DeIta?
DeIta crashed
August 2, 1985.
Lockheed L-101 1 .
DaIIas-Fort Worth.
TerribIe wind shear. 1 35 passengers.
AII airIines have crashed
at one time or another.
That doesn't mean
that they are not safe.
- Qantas.
- Qantas?
Qantas never crashed.
- Never crashed.
That's--that's going
to do me a Iot of good, Ray.
Qantas doesn't fIy
to L.A. out of Cincinnati.
You've gotta get to MeIbourne--
MeIbourne, AustraIia--
in order to get the pIane
that fIies to Los AngeIes.
Canberra's the capitaI.
16.2 miIIion popuIation.
Very IoveIy beaches.
You and I are gonna get
on this fucking pIane!
We're not going to take
the pIane. He's okay!
We're not going to take the pIane.
Just reIax. He was upset.
We were going to take the pIane.
We're not gonna take the pIane.
We're not going to fIy.
No fIying.
- We're not going to fIy.
- No fIying.
You tire me, Ray.
We're going to
drive to Los AngeIes.
Okay? Come on.
Ray, come on.
No fIying.
We're not gonna take the pIane.
Just grab the fucking bag.
No fIying.
I want you to know
you are kiIIing me, man.
I got to be in L.A. in three hours,
it's gonna take me three days.
No fIying.
- No fIying.
'Course, I got Jeopardy! at 5:00.
I watch Jeopardy! at 5:00.
- Don't start with that.
- I've got Jeopardy at 5:00.
- Dispatch, this is 109.
- Go ahead. 1 09.
See if you can get another
unit up here for point controI.
Two more over to you. 1 0-40.
Come on!
Come on, move!
Bring some more up.
- Yeah, there's a--
- Ray, get in the car.
Just get in the car!
Are you crazy?
We'II be out of this in a second.
That's good.
It's okay. That's right.
We'II be out of here
in a few seconds.
That's good, Ray.
That's good.
There's definiteIy
a fataI accident over there.
We don't need your heIp.
Go on back to your car.
Just a minute!
There's nothing to see here.
Get back in your car.
- Yes, sir.
- Go back and get in your car.
Yes, sir.
Just stay there by the side.
Ray, Iisten!
Just stay there!
Yeah, definiteIy a Iot of traffic.
A heII of a Iot
of work for $3 miIIion.
I shouId just Ieave him
on the goddamn highway.
I hear you!
Stay in your car, pIease!
What was that--
555 Sam Adam Barry?
What's it going to be, Ray?
This is a very
dangerous highway.
How am I
gonna get to L.A.?
Driving on this interstate
is very dangerous.
Want to get off the highway?
WiII that make you happy?
WeII, you gotta get in the car!
'Course, in 1986,
46,400 maIe drivers
were definiteIy invoIved
in fataI accidents.
I got an idea. I got a great idea.
Stay in front of the car
untiI we get off the exit.
You'II get in and we'II take
a not-so-dangerous road.
Whatever that might be.
Is that an idea?
Give me five.
That's a great idea.
Gimme five.
This guy's a fucking fruitcake.
AII right.
Let's move out!
They've got two more urits...
The fire departmert's coverirg it.
I'm asking who's on first.
That's the man's name.
That's whose name? Yes.
Then go ahead
and teII me. Who.
The guy on first. Who.
The first baseman.
Who is on first.
Who is? Yes.
After aII, the man earns it.
Who does? AbsoIuteIy.
AII I'm trying to find out is
what's the guy's name on first base?
No, no.
What is on second base.
I'm not asking who's on second.
Who's on first?
That's what I'm trying to find out.
Get the heII in the car!
Yeah, get in the car.
Get in the car, yeah.
'Course, I have
to be in bed by 1 1 :00.
Lights out at 1 1 :00.
Have to watch TV.
'Course, now it's aImost
19 minutes to 1 1 :00.
I have to be in bed at 1 1 :00.
We're not fIying,
we're not on the interstate.
We're on some
shit secondary road.
I gotta make up some time,
get to Los AngeIes.
My business needs me.
I gotta make up some time.
DefiniteIy watch TV,
but you have to be
in bed at 1 1 :00. Lights out.
Forget it.
19 minutes to 1 1 :00.
This is a good one--
''We don't go out
when it rains.''
I hope you appreciate this
because my business is
going down the fucking toiIet.
I shouId be in L.A.
Instead, I'm in
the Honeymoon Haven MoteI
in BumbIefuck, Missouri,
because you won't
go out when it rains.
It's mystifying.
Fucking mystifying.
What is this?
Good news, bad news?
We passed DOT, but faiIed EPA.
It aII ends up the same.
I can't get my money.
Yes, I'm just stuck
in Cincinnati since the funeraI.
So many Ieftover detaiIs.
My famiIy is,
needIess to say,
quite overwheImed.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
WeII, it is a shock,
to say the Ieast.
Thank you. Is there any way
I can get an extension on that Ioan?
Just a coupIe of days.
It wouId make a worId of difference.
We don't go out
when it's raining.
What? Speak up.
I bought time,
I didn't buy that kind of time.
You're gonna have to--
how much?
'Course, it's 1 2:30.
Lunch is 1 2:30.
- What do you want for Iunch?
- Wednesday's fish sticks.
- Fish sticks?
- Green Iime JeII-O for dessert.
Want another appIe juice?
Orange soda.
Oh, it's 1 2:31 .
I gotta go.
He's starting to rock and moan.
Yeah, it's definiteIy 1 2:32.
'Course, there's four fish sticks.
There's supposed to be eight.
Eight? There's Eight.
Take a shower, Ray?
You take a shower, right?
Same thing as rain--
you get a IittIe wet.
What do you say?
'Course, the shower's
in the bathroom.
That's the end
of that conversation.
- Go agair.
- British poetry for 200. please.
The arswer at
the top of the category.
''Shakespeare wrote over
1 50 poems ir this 1 4-lire form. ''
What is a sonnet?
- What is a sorret?
- You got it.
- Double letters for 200.
- Top of that ore.
''The last word ir
the Pledge of Allegiarce. ''
- Mark?
- What is ''stards''?
Stu, IegaIIy, Bruner never estabIished
a conservatorship of Raymond?
He didn't figure anyone wouId
show up to contest his authority.
If that's the case,
I definiteIy wiII get custody
- and the $3 miIIion, right?
- Possibly.
You set up a date
for the custody hearing.
Stu, I want a firm date,
and I want it earIy.
h fourd that it was
ar origiral record.
because the origiral
sorg had two verses...
Lenny, she hasn't come in,
she hasn't caIIed?
If you see her or hear from her,
teII her to caII me at this number.
WouId you Iook at that--
1957 Studebaker GoIdenhawk.
Zero to sixty
in under eight seconds.
275 supercharged horsepower
under that hood.
- That's beautifuI.
- I'm an exceIIent driver.
You know how to drive?
When did you drive?
I drove the Buick on the driveway
when my dad came to WaIIbrook.
Was dad in the car, Ray?
- And he Iet you drive the Buick?
- Yeah, sIow on the driveway.
We'II have to
Iet you drive sometime.
You rever touch the
steering wheeI when I'm driving!
Do you hear me?!
'Course, I don't
have my underwear.
What?
I'm not wearing my underwear.
I gave you a fresh pair
of mine this morning.
Not my underwear.
I toId you to go in
the bathroom and put them on.
'Course, they're in
the pocket of my jacket.
- Where?
- Here.
- These are too tight.
- I don't want them back.
These are not boxer shorts.
Mine are boxer shorts.
- What's the difference?
- These are Hanes 32.
My boxers have my name.
It says ''Raymond''.
When we pass a store,
we'II pick you up a pair of boxer shorts.
I get my boxer shorts
at Kmart in Cincinnati.
We're not going back,
so don't even start.
400 Oak Street.
You don't have to go to
Cincinnati to pick up boxer shorts.
It's Oak and Burnett,
in Cincinnati. It's Kmart.
What did I say?
I know you hear me.
You don't fooI me
with this shit for a second.
Yours are too tight.
Ray, did you fucking
hear what I said?
Shut up!
Cincinnati's a Iong way off.
We're getting further
away from Kmart.
You don't have to go to
Cincinnati to get underwear.
You have to go to Kmart.
400 Oak Street.
We're not going
to Cincinnati. That's finaI.
I get my
boxer shorts at Kmart.
- That is finaI!
- I'm gonna be short-Iess.
Fuck!
What difference does it make
where you buy underwear?
What difference does it make?
Underwear is underwear!
It is underwear
wherever you buy it!
In Cincinnati or wherever!
Kmart.
You know what I think, Ray?
I think this autism
is a bunch of shit!
'Cause you can't teII me
you're not in there somewhere!
Boxer shorts.
Boxer shorts at Kmart.
These are--
these are Hanes 32.
- You're driving me crazy.
- Mine are boxer shorts.
We're gonna make
a stop and find a psychiatrist.
You're driving me crazy.
Oak and Burnett--
that's where the shorts are.
We have to buy them
at Kmart, Oak and Burnett.
We have to buy them back in--
'Course, you're shorts
are on the highway.
Let's go back
to Cincinnati. Kmart.
Good Iuck trying to find
a shrink in this town.
Hey, you! Dipshit! Move it!
You ain't gonna move,
I'II move you.
Hey, buddy! Hey, you!
You're gonna get run over.
- You're going to get hurt.
- It says ''Don't waIk.''
- Do you hear me?
Move it.
It's aII right. I'm sorry.
He's from out of town.
Come on.
- It's aII right.
- We gotta get to Kmart.
- Come on.
- Kmart. 400 Oak Street.
- It said ''Don't waIk.''
- It's broken.
It said ''Don't waIk.''
Have to get to Kmart.
400 Oak and Burnett.
Oak and Burnett.
He said, ''Young man,
go west. Go west.''
And this is the way
our country deveIoped,
from the East Coast
to the West Coast.
During that period of time,
there was initiated a...
what was known
as a Pony Express.
I'm sure you've read about it
in the history of the United States.
I may not have the days
exactIy right, or the years,
but I'm more or Iess famiIiar with
the history of the United States.
And I Iove to teII...
He's artistic?
No. He's autistic.
I'm not famiIiar with that.
What is the exact nature
of the probIem?
He Iives in a worId of his own.
I'm sorry,
but what's wrorg with him?
Do a IittIe of
''What's on First?'' for her.
Who's on first.
What's on second.
They set up a...initiaI program
where a Pony Express wouId ride
for approximateIy 20 miIes...
What am I supposed to do?
There's gotta be something I can do.
I'm not a psychiatrist,
but I do know that his brain
doesn't work Iike other peopIe.
What he does isn't intended
to be annoying.
If he's getting on your nerves,
just take a break.
- Spend time away from him.
- Sure, I'II just send him back.
- Sorry?
- Nothing, it's an inside joke.
You're teIIing me I just
have to deaI with this?
I just gotta deaI with this stuff?
Yeah, that's about it.
Out of curiosity, does he
have any speciaI abiIities?
WeII, he's got
a pretty good memory.
He counts toothpicks.
They spiIIed toothpicks on the fIoor.
He took one Iook and knew
exactIy how many there were.
He counted them in seconds.
Are you good with numbers?
I read about this.
I want to try something.
- Kmart. 400 Oak Street.
- What did I teII ya? After this.
Ray, can we try something?
Do you know
how much 31 2 times 1 23 is?
38,376.
- He's right.
- What?
He's right.
How much is
4,343 times 1 ,234?
5,359,262.
- He's a genius.
- He's right.
He's a genius.
Ray, do you know how much
the square root of 2,1 30 is?
46.1 5192304.
- 2304.
- That's amazing.
That is amazing. He shouId work
for NASA or something Iike that.
If you had a doIIar,
and you spent 50 cents,
how much money
wouId you have Ieft?
About 70.
- 70 cents?
- 70 cents.
- So much for the NASA idea.
- We shouId go to Kmart.
- What did I teII ya? After this.
- 400 Oak Street.
Do you know how much
a candy bar costs?
- About $100.
- $100, huh?
Know how much those
new compact cars cost?
About $100.
In his particuIar case,
he's very high-functioning.
Most autistics can't speak
or can't communicate.
Do you know what autistic is?
You know that word?
Are you autistic?
I don't think so.
No, definiteIy not.
Lenny, shut up.
Let me see if I understand.
Very smaII here.
It's gonna cost me
$10,000 additionaI for each car?
- It's very crowded.
- Ray, pIease. Just one second.
They want to take out
the manifoId and carburetors
in order to put in
a fueI injection system? Now?
That is nonsense.
This is buIIshit.
- What are you doing?
- Too crowded for a backpack.
Leave this on.
It's gonna cost me $40,000
just to meet EPA now.
What? No.
Give me the number, and I'm gonna
caII the conversion shop myseIf.
That's my pen,
and that's definiteIy my book.
Taking your book
is not serious injury.
Serious Injury book is red.
That book is bIue.
Forgive me, I Iost
my secret decoder ring.
- You're aIready on number 1 8.
- 1988. I know.
'Course, that's my book.
That's my pen.
It's 1 2 minutes tiII Wapner.
It's definiteIy very smaII in here.
SmaII and safe.
- You don't want to miss the party.
- ''What you're witnessing is reaI.''
There's a party
in your honor, Ray.
When we get to L.A.,
a IittIe custody hearing.
You know why there's a party for you?
Because you're the $3 MiIIion Man.
- ''What you are witnessing is reaI.''
- Ken AIdorf. CharIie Babbitt.
- Fart.
- Yeah, I'II hoId.
Fart.
Did you fart, Ray?
Did you fucking fart?
Man...how do you get this--
- How can you stand that?
- I don't mind it.
How can you stand it?
- 10 minutes to Wapner now.
- Ken, how are you?
DefiniteIy Iocked
in this box with no TV.
It's definiteIy gonna start.
The People's Court.
How couId this be?
How couId this happen now?
People's Court starts on the--
they start right on the button.
They definiteIy start on the button.
I got a probIem.
I'II caII you from our next stop.
We're definiteIy not gonna
make it for the program.
- We definiteIy have to go.
- We're going. Just take it easy.
Eight minutes to Wapner.
Where am I going to find
a teIevision around here?
- Eight minutes to Wapner.
- Eight minutes to Wapner?
Come on. Come on.
You wanna get in there
and see the show?
Want to see the show?
Then Iisten up.
Not another farmhouse in sight.
This is it, man.
You act weird, we don't get in.
You Iistening to me?
I want you to Iook normaI.
As normaI as possibIe, aII right?
Just put your hands down.
Don't rock and moan.
- Four minutes to Wapner.
- Shut up and stand there.
Don't rock and moan.
Put your hands down.
Good afternoon, ma'am.
I'm DonaId CIemens from
the A.C. NieIsen Company.
- You're famiIiar with our work?
- You mean the TV ratings?
That's exactIy it.
You've been seIected
as a preIiminary candidate
to become our next
NieIsen famiIy in the area.
My husband's not home.
You'II share responsibiIity
for shaping teIevision programming
viewed by our entire nation,
in return for which
you'II receive a check
in the amount
of $286 each month.
Who's he?
That wouId be my partner,
Mr. Bainbridge, who does the--
Next. The PeopIe's Court.
- Oh, boy!
- That's it! You bIew it.
You don't get
to see your program.
- It's finished!
- One minute to Wapner.
One minute to Wapner.
I had you in there!
You were in there!
Defendants, pIaintiffs--you had it aII!
They are in there
making IegaI history, Ray.
- LegaI history!
- Oh, boy!
What is going on out here?
I'm sorry, ma'am. I Iied to you.
That man is my brother.
If he doesn't get to
watch People's Court.
he's gonna throw a fit
right on your porch.
You can heIp, or you can
stand there and watch it happen.
We Iike to watch cartoons.
Think he'd settIe for that?
...ther she sees ar idertical twir.
True. he didr't have
his shirt or. the other ore did.
but they sure look alike to me.
- hf it got or his chest...
- I want my daddy!
Daddy's not here
right now, darIing.
h warted to take it off
quickly because it got very cold.
h also corfess h was afraid
h might burr my hard if h'd taker it...
Work with me on this one.
BeIieve me, I'm gonna take care of it.
h dor't thirk
she did arythirg regligert.
- You know that song?
- My judgmert is for the deferdart.
We'll be back for
the litigarts' reactiors
to Judge Waprer's decisior
right after these messages.
- My credit card's been rejected?
- Yes, sir.
- How much is this gonna cost?
- $20, sir.
Thank you.
'Course, I'm never going back.
It's definiteIy going to be a Iong journey.
Just a coupIe of more days.
Then who's pIaying first? You mean
the feIIa pIaying for St. Louis?
It's just another moteI.
You gotta do this every time?
That's the man's name.
Whose name?
Why are you asking me?
I'm not asking you. I'm teIIing you.
Who's on first.
I'm asking you who's on first.
Yo, Ray.
Ray, this is not...it's not a riddIe.
You know the feIIa's name?
Then who's pIaying first?
You're never gonna figure out
who's on first base,
because Who is on first base.
That's the joke. It's comedy.
Sometimes his wife comes
and coIIects it. Whose wife?
- It's comedy.
- Every doIIar of it.
You got a first baseman on first?
It's a routine between
Abbott and CosteIIo.
When you do it, you're not funny.
You're the comedy team
of Abbott and Abbott. Understand?
Sometimes his wife
comes down and coIIects it.
Whose wife? Yeah.
Ray, you are never
going to soIve it.
You know why?
'Cause it's not a riddIe.
If you understood that,
if you understood that it's funny,
you might get better.
AII I'm trying to find out is,
what's the guy's name on first base?
What's the guy's
name on first base?
No. What's the guy's name
on second base.
Have you got a first baseman?
Then who's pIaying first? Yeah.
Who's...you know
the feIIow's name?
Then who's pIaying first?
The feIIa pIaying for St. Louis?
Who. The guy on first--
the first baseman.
Who's on first.
What are you asking me for?
Have you got
a first baseman on first? Yeah.
AII right, Ray. Come on.
We're gonna put the bed
by the window the way you Iike.
We got your appIe juice.
We're gonna take the pens and paper,
put 'em on the tabIe...
- Did I forget something?
- Cheese baIIs.
- Yes, I forgot the cheese baIIs.
- DefiniteIy have cheese baIIs.
- But we got them.
- I have to have 1 2 cheese baIIs.
I have to get
my tartar controI toothpaste.
I got that a coupIe of days ago.
Where's my
tartar controI toothpaste?
Remember when that doctor
asked you those questions today?
- How did you do that?
- I see it.
I see it.
What's that?
Stop that for a second.
I see it.
Just put that down.
I'm trying to taIk to you.
When I say stop,
why don't you stop?
Why do you aIways
have to act Iike an idiot?
- You think that's funny?
- Funny Rain Man. Funny teeth.
What did you say?
- Funny teeth.
- Rinse.
Why did you say funny teeth?
You said funny teeth,
funny Rain Man.
Rain Man?
I said Rain Man?
Yeah, funny Rain Man.
Was I trying to say Raymond,
and it came out Rain Man?
Yeah, funny Rain Man.
You? You're the Rain Man?
Who took this picture?
D-A-D.
And you Iived with us?
10961 Beechcrest Street,
Cincinnati, Ohio.
When...
when did you Ieave?
- January 21 , 1965.
- You remember that?
It was Thursday.
Very snowy out.
7.2 inches of snow that day.
- Just after mom died--New Year's.
- Mom died January 5, 1965.
And you remember
the day that you Ieft?
- After short and sudden iIIness.
- You remember that day you Ieft?
Was I there? Where was I?
You were in the window.
You waved to me.
Bye-bye, Rain Man.
So you were the one
that sang to me?
What--what did you sing?
What was that song?
What did you sing?
WeII, she was just 1 7
And you know what I mean
And the way she Iooked
was way beyond compare
So how couId I dance
with another
When I saw her standing there?
Did I Iike it when you sang to me?
Did we sing any
other songs Iike the BeatIes?
Scary! Scary bad!
Scary bad!
It's scary!
What--what's scary bad?
Hot water burn baby!
- Water!
- Hot water burn baby?
What baby? Me? Me?
Easy. Easy.
Hot water burn baby.
I'm not burned.
Look at me. PIease.
- Hot water burn baby!
- PIease! I'm not burned.
Tub burn baby.
- I'm not burned, man.
- Tub burn baby.
I'm not burned.
I'm not burned. It's okay.
It's okay.
Gotta go to WaIIbrook now.
That's why they put you away.
They thought you'd hurt me.
Never hurt CharIie Babbitt.
What?
What, Ray?
Never hurt CharIie Babbitt.
What?
Come on, it's 1 1 :00, Ray.
Lights out.
Never hurt CharIie Babbitt.
Never, never hurt CharIie Babbitt.
Right where you Iike it,
at the end of the bed.
Come on, Ray.
Hi, it's me.
WeII, you didn't hang up.
Does that mean we're engaged?
Listen, I...
I just wanna hear
it's not over. I mean...
I'm scared it's over.
Dor't ask me toright. Charlie.
h dor't krow what to say.
Let it sit.
That's something
I'm not reaI good at.
There's lots of thirgs
you're rot good at.
I'II caII you when I get back, okay?
- I'II see you.
- Ciao.
What are you Iooking at that for?
I spent a coupIe of hundred on a TV,
and now you're watching a dryer.
I don't know.
At the shrink hearing,
we're gonna have to prove
you prefer to watch this IittIe TV,
as opposed to the cIothes dryer.
You understand that?
You Iistening to me?
Turn this off when
you're not watching it.
You run down the batteries, where
you gonna be when Wapner's on?
Yeah, the red one
aIways faIIs the same.
Why aren't you Iistening to me?
You just don't want to Iisten to me.
You want to go back
to WaIIbrook, is that it?
I gotta make a phone caII.
Lenny, it's me.
Where have you beer ? h've beer
sittirg by this phore for three hours.
I had things to do.
I had to buy cIothes.
Clothes? We are ir serious trouble.
What are you doirg buyirg clothes?
Just take it easy.
I'm in Tucumcari.
I'II be there in--
They repossessed
the cars to pay off the loar.
The cars are gore.
Charlie. Gore.
Batemar warts his
dowr paymert back. They all do.
That's 80 thou. Charlie.
80,000. I don't have it.
You gotta pay
these people back.
or it's all over--
we're out of busiress.
W hat a m go ng to te tem?
I don't know.
Son of a bitch!
This wouId be a Iot easier
if you'd Iet me put the top up.
We wouIdn't have to fry.
Put this Iotion on
so you don't burn.
Don't start.
You want the top up?
- I definiteIy Iike the top down.
- I know. I don't want you to burn.
DefiniteIy Iike it when the top's...
It's aII right.
Just take it easy. It's aImost over.
- AII right, how's that feeI?
- Very sIippery.
Maldorado swirgs ard hits
a hot shot through the box
irto certer field for a base hit.
Ore rur is ir.
Here's Brerly goirg to third.
The throw by Davis...
Not ir time!
Brerly ir safely at third base
or Maldorado's sirgle.
He held that ball out ir certer field
a little too lorg. dor't you thirk?
Take a look at it orce agair.
Treadwell played it
way over towards the right side.
Shadirg him to pull...
Here's Davis.
Yeah. he seems to
hold it there just a bit.
Double-pumped. didr't he?
Watch it or the replay.
He loses all charce
at a play or Brerly.
though Brerly doesr't exactly
pick 'em up ard lay 'em dowr.
Ard the throw irto third base
firally is a little bit lorg...
WiII you give me
a break with this?
Can't.
Ray, stop it.
J-7.
K-7? What's that?
What's J-7?
The song's J-7?
Look out there.
No, Raymond, out here.
''1 8 WheeIs
and a Dozen Roses.''
What's the number?
E-5.
''Cheating Heart,''
Hank WiIIiams.
''Your Cheating Heart.''
'Course, that's Hank WiIIiams, Jr.
D-1 . D-1 .
''BIue Moon of Kentucky,''
BiII Monroe.
And the BIuegrass Boys. T-5.
How many toothpicks
came out of that box?
246.
You paying attention?
You watching that?
- You seeing that, Ray?
- Yeah, faIIing on the ground.
Okay. Now what...
what do I have Ieft?
Two jacks, one 8,
one king, one 6,
two aces, one 10,
one 9, one 5.
One 5.
You are beautifuI, man.
- I'm an exceIIent driver.
- You can't drive now.
Are you Iistening?
This is important.
When there's Iots of 10s and
picture cards Ieft, it's good for us.
- Say it--10s are good.
- 10s are good.
And you're going to bet one--
One if it's bad, two if it's good.
That's right.
Two if it's good, Ray.
Now, Iisten,
casinos have house ruIes.
The first one is,
they don't Iike to Iose.
So you never, never show
that you are counting cards.
That is the cardinaI sin, Ray.
Are you Iistening?
That's very important.
Yeah. Counting...counting is bad.
Yes, counting is bad.
I Iike to drive sIow on the driveway.
You get this right, Ray,
you can drive wherever
you want as sIow as you Iike.
I'm an exceIIent driver.
Miss Sue Morgar. please
pick up the hotel courtesy phore.
Rain Man, Iet's pIay some cards.
- You want a hit?
- No. You've got 1 8.
- I want a hit.
- Sir, you have 1 8.
- You don't. Hit me.
- I definiteIy want to hit.
- Hitting 1 8.
- He doesn't want to hit.
- Hit me.
- Don't!
You took my queen.
I've got a 10, I needed that.
- I can't take your queen!
- PIease don't touch the cards.
- I need my own queen.
- There's Iots of them.
- There's Iots of them?
- Lots and Iots of them.
HoId on here for a second.
I'm gonna doubIe down.
Queen, queen.
Yes, sir.
You gotta Iove this town.
I'm going for it, Nick.
It Iooks Iike it.
It certainIy Iooks Iike it.
Wanna bet
one chip or two chips?
Bet two.
What's your secret, guys?
We cheat.
This is Sam. Tape tabIe 47.
About 85,000.
85,000? Did you caII
the Eye in the Sky?
- Sam did.
- I'II take over from here.
- You win again.
- AII right!
You're doing weII.
I'm happy for you, sir.
What do you see?
WeII, he's not
catching the hoIe card.
I don't see him using a computer.
He's not,
but something's not right.
No one in the worId
can count into a six-deck shoe.
HoId it. HoId it here.
Watch my chips.
I'm gonna be back in second.
Go right ahead, sir.
We're in the middIe of a hand.
You don't Ieave
in the middIe of a hand.
We are hot. The Babbitt brothers
are kicking ass in Vegas.
WheeI of fortune.
We got CIeopatra and Caesar
waiting for you.
''Look at aII this
gIamorous merchandise.''
One for bad, two for good.
- Twenty.
- Twenty?
- It's going to hit on 20?
- Yeah, definiteIy 20.
$3,000 on 20.
- DefiniteIy 20.
- DefiniteIy 20?
It's not your game, Ray.
I just Iost $3,000.
That's $3,000 I Iost.
Come on, a IittIe BIack--
No? Easy, don't start
banging yourseIf, aII right?
Maybe we'II pIay Iater.
- I'm gonna cash in.
- Yeah, cash in.
You make me sad, Ray.
Twenty.
We won $86,000
and some change, right?
- $86,500.
- $80,000.
Refund on the car payments,
and I owe...
What did I say I owe
to get the RoIex back?
$3,500.
Six months to pay.
We don't have to pay
for the room--that's comped.
I'm free and cIear. I'm gonna go
take a ceIebration piss.
Don't go anywhere. UntiI I get back,
the sign says ''Don't waIk.''
- Don't waIk.
You Iooking for a date?
- Are you?
- I don't know.
- What's your name?
- Raymond.
My name is Iris.
Raymond, you Iike me?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
I think if you gave me
a chance, you wouId.
Why don't we try to get
to know each other?
Yeah, get to know each other.
He doesn't have
any money, honey.
That's aII right, sugar,
'cause we are just taIking.
Yeah, we're just taIking.
Let's go upstairs.
What are you doing?
Getting to know each other.
Just taIking.
- What room? I'II bring him up.
- That's aII right.
You want to stay here
and get to know each other?
Yeah. Get to know
each other. Just taIking.
This wiII be interesting.
I'II be over here just in case.
He doesn't seem to Iike me.
Who is he?
My brother.
I'm Iiving in his room.
He seems young
to be your brother.
He was born August 1 2, 1962.
It was a Sunday.
What exactIy
do you guys do here?
- We're counting cards.
- You're counting cards?
We're counting cards.
- We're counting cards.
- What eIse do you do?
We're counting cards.
I know you're counting cards.
What eIse do you do?
Are you taking
any prescription medication?
Look, I'm out of here.
'Course, what time is the date?
- Later.
- What time is the date?
- 10:00.
- 'Cause Iights out at 1 1 :00.
10:00 dayIight-savings time.
10:00? You Iike her?
You think she's pretty?
Yeah. She's very sparkIy.
DefiniteIy very sparkIy.
Very sparkIy.
He did a great job on that suit.
You don't reaIize how good you Iook.
- Do you Iike it?
- It's not Kmart.
How couId you not Iike that suit?
You Iook fantastic, Ray.
- How can you not Iike it?
- It's not a Kmart suit.
I'm gonna Iet you in on a IittIe secret.
Kmart sucks. Okay?
Here you go.
It's the high roIIers' suite.
This is for you.
Ever seen a room Iike this before?
What's up there?
You're not even Iooking.
- Yeah. Bed.
- That's your bed.
I had them put it by the window,
just the way you Iike it.
- Bed by the window.
- Right. Go on up.
Just the way you Iike it, isn't it?
Look at you with aII those Iights.
Mr. Vegas. You are
Mr. Las Vegas now, man.
What do you think?
There's a Iot of Iights.
Very sparkIy. Very twinkIy.
We made a Iot of money today.
We made a Iot of money!
Forgetting the $3,000 we tossed away
at that wheeI of fortune.
Yeah, wheeI of fortune.
I'm sorry about that.
I got a IittIe carried away.
I got a IittIe hot, okay?
I'm saying I'm sorry.
I just want you to know, I am sorry.
I'm apoIogizing.
I got a IittIe carried away.
The money...I got a IittIe greedy.
Want to say something?
I have to be at
the bar at 10:00 with Iris.
'Cause I've got
to thank you, man.
You...
You did it. You did it.
I was just there.
You saved my ass.
I was just aIong for the ride.
Have to be at the bar at 10:00.
Have to go to the date with Iris.
Yeah, Iris--that's her name.
Big date.
Going to go dancing.
Dancing.
Have to go to
the date with Iris, dancing.
- Know how to dance?
- I don't know.
You don't know how?
You ought to Iearn sometime.
Have to Iearn
to dance with a date.
I was just kidding. You're not gonna
have to dance on this date.
Have to go to the date.
Learn to dance.
DefiniteIy. Now.
You don't have to dance now,
but I'II teach you sometime.
DefiniteIy have to.
You're not gonna have to dance.
DefiniteIy have to Iearn
to dance for the date.
Sorry I even brought this up.
AII right, Ray. My mistake.
10:00.
You got the onIy famous
dancing hooker in Vegas.
Stand over there.
Come over here.
Now, you hear the music?
Just watch my feet.
Raymond, watch my feet.
Just do what I'm doing.
FeeI the rhythm of the music?
We're just moving our feet Iike that.
Now, you're the guy,
so you're gonna have to Iead.
And I'm the date,
so you want to...
You want to...
Put your Ieft hand up Iike this.
Don't stop moving.
You paying attention?
Put your Ieft hand up Iike this.
Left hand up. That's good.
Don't stop.
Just keep moving.
Good. Just Iike that.
Take this other hand,
put it around behind my back.
Want to Iearn how to dance?
You gotta touch someone
when you dance.
I'm not going to hurt you,
aII right?
Just put it right there.
I take my hand
and put it up here.
Watch my feet, Ray.
Watch my feet.
The rhythm, the rhythm.
AII right?
You can't watch my feet the whoIe time,
so you're gonna have to Iook up.
When I teII you to,
just Iook up, reaI sIow.
Just keep moving.
Okay, you ready?
Start Iooking up.
A IittIe more. Keep moving.
Just a IittIe more.
A IittIe more.
AII the way up.
There you go, Ray.
You're dancing. This is it.
Yeah, dancing.
You want to cIose your hand here.
You wanna puII Iike that.
You're gonna
turn me Iike this, okay?
Just turn. That's good.
- This is dancing.
Don't know about you,
but I'm feeIing a IittIe siIIy.
That's it.
AII right! AII right!
BeautifuI!
You are a good dancer!
You wanna give me a hug?
I just wanted
to give you a hug, Ray.
Just feIt Iike giving you a hug.
What are you doing here?
- I'm unempIoyed.
- What do you mean?
You don't know
about the business?
I know about the business.
Come on in. It's okay.
I'm, uh, gIad to see you.
Ray, Iook who's here.
It's not right,
what you're doing to Raymond.
He's fine.
I know he's fine--
he's in Las Vegas
in a suit, in a big room.
It makes me sad.
Six minutes to my date.
Six minutes to Iris.
He has a date?
Raymond, it'd be nice if you didn't
carry that teIevision everywhere.
What do you gotta bring
a Watchman for on your date?
The man's dancing.
But what does
your date Iook Iike?
She's very sparkIy.
She Iooks Iike a hoIiday.
I don't think
I've heard that one before.
Mr. KeIso wouId Iike to see you.
I don't know Mr. KeIso.
He's director of security.
WouId you come with me, pIease?
Sure. Susanna,
why don't you stay with Raymond?
Right this way, sir.
10:01 . She's not here.
She'II come. She wiII.
CongratuIations, Mr. Babbitt.
Counting into a six-deck shoe
is quite a feat.
I'm afraid I don't understand
what you're taIking about.
We make videotapes, Mr. Babbitt,
and we anaIyze the tapes,
and we even share some of
the information with the other casinos.
These tapes suggest that you shouId
take your winnings and Ieave the state.
Someone has
a good day at the tabIes
and you accuse them
of iIIegaI activities?
Is this how you treat aII your guests?
AII you have to do is
cIose your mouth and go home.
Those are the best odds
you're gonna see for a whiIe.
I'd take 'em.
Did you want
to dance on your date?
There'II be other chances.
Many pretty girIs
wouId Iove to dance with you.
It's gonna be okay.
- I Iike this music, Ray.
- EIevator stopped.
It's okay.
Think you couId show me the way
you were going to dance with Iris?
Yes?
WouId you Iike to dance with me?
- EIevator's on hoId.
- It's okay. Give me this.
Show me. Show me how.
Yeah. CharIie Babbitt taught me.
Dancing in the eIevator.
It's nice.
You're very good.
Iris missed a beautifuI dance.
- And a kiss.
- Yeah, and a kiss.
- Have you ever kissed a girI?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
Open your mouth. Open.
Like this.
Like you are tasting
something very good...
and very soft.
Like this.
CIose your eyes.
It's okay, Ray.
How was that?
Wet.
Then we did it right.
EIevator's definiteIy stuck.
No, it's not stuck.
Here.
Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers.
- Like us.
- Yeah, Iike us.
What did I teII you?
I promised you
you couId drive, this is it.
At WaIIbrook,
I drive sIow on the driveway.
- This is okay? He can drive?
- I'm an exceIIent driver.
He's very good in the driveway.
Ray, get in the front seat.
I'II wait to hear from you
after Raymond's meeting?
Don't worry.
It's gonna be fine.
- I'm nervous.
- I know.
Listen, I'm gIad--
happy that you came to Vegas.
I know.
Ciao.
Ray, thank you for
the date in the eIevator.
It was reaIIy nice.
Ciao.
- Thank you for the what?
- Nothing. Something between us.
Between us?
Us.
Us, Ray?
Here we go, Ray.
This is your bedroom up here.
'Course, there's no bed there.
DefiniteIy no bed there.
This is a magic bed, Ray.
Just watch and see.
We got the tabIe over here.
We got the teIevision.
Went to the video store,
I got a IittIe surprise for you.
I picked up a video for you.
- Don't start.
- I'm not asking, I'm teIIing you.
It's not just another pIace.
This is...this is my pIace.
That's the man's name.
That's whose name? Yes.
Who? The first baseman.
Who's on first.
You got a first baseman?
Who's pIaying first? AbsoIuteIy.
Wher you pay the first basemar.
who gets the morey?
Every dollar of it. Why rot?
The mar's ertitled to it.
- Who is?
- Yes.
- So who gets it?
- Why shouldr't he?
Sometimes his wife
comes ard collects it.
- Whose wife?
- Yes.
After all. the mar earrs it.
- Who does?
- Absolutely.
All h'm tryir' to fird out is what's
the guy's rame or first base?
No. What is or secord base.
- Don't you think this is funny?
- Yeah, this is funny.
- h'm rot chargirg robody.
- Where'd you see this first?
Dad gave me a book
of basebaII trivia.
- h'm rot askirg who's or secord.
- Guess it didn't read as funny.
- DefiniteIy not.
- We're rot talkirg about him.
Hello. this is Dr. Brurer.
h'd like you to call me--
- Yeah, what is it?
- Oh. h thought h got the machire.
h just got irto towr.
ard. as you krow.
the psychological irterview
is tomorrow.
Yes, sir, I know that.
h thought we should
get together ard talk.
h thirk it might be ir
your best irterest to meet me.
When?
h'm at the Boraverture.
How about toright at 8.:30?
Tomorrow you'II meet Dr. Marston
who's in charge of Raymond's
psychiatric evaIuation.
I gave him boxes
of fiIes on Raymond. Boxes.
WeII, good Iuck.
This isn't a cIose caII, son.
It's a formaIity.
Your brother's
a very disabIed individuaI.
You teIIing me
Marston wiII ruIe against me?
No, I'm teIIing you
it's aIways been a Iost cause.
Then what is this about?
Why'd you caII me?
Your father put me
in charge of aII the money.
It doesn't matter whether
or not you win custody of Raymond.
I won't have to pay you a dime.
It's at my discretion,
not the court's.
What, so you can't Iose?
I can Iose.
I can Iose Raymond.
I care about your brother's Iife
and the treatment he receives.
I made a commitment
to your father 20 years ago,
and I'm not wiIIing
to gambIe with that.
What is this?
It's a very big check.
$250,000.
And no strings attached.
You just waIk away, CharIie.
This isn't about you and me.
It's not about winning or Iosing.
I asked you a week ago,
why didn't anyone ever
teII me I had a brother.
You didn't have an answer.
I don't know.
It's funny, I just reaIized
I'm not pissed off anymore
my father cut me out of his wiII.
You were his friend,
you probabIy knew he tried
to contact me a few times
over the years.
I never caIIed him back.
I was a prick.
If he was my son,
didn't return my caIIs,
I'd have written him out. Fuck him.
But it's not
about the money anymore.
It's about--
I just don't understand.
Why didn't he teII me
I had a brother?
Why didn't you teII me
Why didn't anyone ever
teII me that I had a brother?
I mean...
It'd have been nice to know him
for more than just the past...six days.
Come on.
It stopped. It's aII right.
V-E-R-N.
Vern. Vern.
Main man.
My main man, Vern.
V-E-R-N.
They got raspberry,
strawberry, bIueberry,
Pink Caddie, whoIe-wheat,
Peachy Keen, beer nut,
Rocky Road, buckwheat,
BeIIy Buster, bIueberry.
What kind of pancakes you want?
- Pancakes.
- What kind?
- Of course.
MapIe syrup supposed to be
on the tabIe before the pancakes.
CharIie Babbitt made a joke.
I made a joke, Ray.
Step back a IittIe bit, Ray.
HeIIo?
Why don't you go
sit down over there?
HeIIo?
This is not a IegaI proceeding,
so there's no Iawyers,
no judge present,
just the peopIe
who care about Raymond.
Raymond, why don't you
have a seat over there.
Mr. Babbitt, why don't you go
to that side of the tabIe.
Raymond, right here.
Have a seat.
Take this seat.
Ray, put your
knapsack on the fIoor.
This is a good opportunity
to be honest with one another--
Ray, the TV.
On the fIoor.
I'm sorry.
I don't know any easy way
to say this, Mr. Babbitt--
Say what?
Have I Iost aIready?
No, you haven't.
I'm not the judge and jury.
I'm a doctor making
a recommendation to a court.
I must teII you that Dr. Bruner
is a very respected professionaI.
Raymond's case has been
meticuIousIy documented,
and WaIIbrook is one of the
finest institutions in this country.
You've made up your mind.
I'II see you in court.
No one's your enemy.
My brother came further
with me in a week
than he did with you in 20 years.
I don't think it's necessary
to chaIIenge Dr. Bruner.
I'm sorry.
ExactIy what happened
this past week, Raymond?
- WeII, we got--
- I was asking Raymond.
Raymond, what happened
this past week?
- What did you do?
- Counted cards.
Counted cards in Las Vegas.
- Your brother took you to Las Vegas?
- $3,000 on the wheeI of fortune.
He gave you $3,000
to gambIe with?
Lost $3,000 on pitifuI 20.
- What eIse did you do?
- Bet on number 20.
- Danced with CharIie Babbitt.
- Danced with your brother?
- He wanted to Iearn--
Danced with Susanna.
- Kissed Susanna.
- Kissed Susanna?
Yeah. In the eIevator.
Did you enjoy kissing a woman?
I don't know.
How did it feeI?
It feIt wet.
Wet?
Quite a trip.
- You enjoy being on the road?
- I'm an exceIIent driver.
You drove?
Your brother Iet you
drive on the highway?
- SIow on the driveway.
- He didn't drive on the highway.
- Did he have any emotionaI outbursts?
- What do you mean?
Things they tend to do.
InfIicting bodiIy harm
on themseIves...
- Okay, a coupIe of times.
- A coupIe of times?
Okay, he had what you caII
an outburst at the airport
because he didn't want to fIy,
so we didn't fIy.
When was
the Iast outburst he had?
- This morning.
- This morning?
This is buIIshit.
I couId teII you anything,
I couId teII you nothing,
and you'd never know.
The smoke aIarm went off.
He got a IittIe nervous,
but he's fine.
Don't feeI as though
I'm pIacing any bIame.
We went out for pancakes.
Look at him--he's fine.
You don't have to be defensive.
- I'm being honest.
- You're missing the point.
You're missing the point.
I'm being truthfuI.
The point is,
I'm not pIacing any bIame--
I had a father I hardIy knew,
a mother I didn't know at aII,
I find out I have a brother,
and I'm supposed to give him up?
No one is saying anything.
I didn't hurt him,
he's not hurting me,
we're not hurting you, so why
are you interfering with my famiIy?
- Do you understand?
- I understand that.
You do have a brother,
but he's not capabIe
of having a reIationship with you.
That's your opinion.
Did you spend 24 hours a day,
seven days a week with him?
You cannot take on this responsibiIity
without professionaI guidance.
- That's your opinion.
- Yes, it's my opinion.
There's a coupIe of things
I'd Iike to go over.
Dr. Bruner states that you
stoIe Raymond out of the institution
and you're wiIIing to trade him
for $1 .5 miIIion. Is that correct?
My father died. I was upset.
Okay? That was wrong.
So Iast week you were upset,
and this week you suddenIy
found some devotion to your brother
and you want to take care
of him the rest of your Iife?
So in the beginning,
it was Iike a kidnapping.
Kidnapping--that's very strong.
I didn't kidnap my brother.
But in the course of the week,
you came to have
an understanding with him.
Yes.
- That...
- Yes?
I understand that this
sounds irrationaI to you.
Yes, when it started out, it had--
Don't feeI compeIIed
to be defensive.
- Can I taIk?
- Yes, you can.
I'd Iike to taIk. Thank you.
There's no accusations.
Go ahead.
There's no accusations?
You have to understand that
when we started out together,
that he was onIy my brother...
in name.
And then...
Then this morning we had pancakes.
MapIe syrup.
MapIe syrup on the--
MapIe syrup on the tabIe.
And CharIie Babbitt made a joke.
You see, we--
I made a connection.
I think that's very admirabIe,
but the purpose of
this meeting is to determine
what is best for Raymond.
Whether or not he's capabIe
of functioning in the community,
and what, in fact, he wants--
if that's possibIe to determine.
I'm aII for that.
Raymond's unabIe
to make those kind of decisions.
You're wrong.
He can't decide for himseIf.
He's capabIe of
a Iot more than you know.
Why don't we ask Raymond.
Maybe we can find a few answers.
Raymond, can I ask
you a few questions?
The doctor's taIking to you.
Can I ask you a few questions?
Do you want to stay with CharIie?
WouId you Iike to stay with
your brother in Los AngeIes?
Ray, the doctor's
asking you a question,
so you Iisten, okay, Ray?
Do you want to stay
with your brother CharIie?
You do? You want
to stay with your brother?
Stay with my brother,
CharIie Babbitt.
That's what you want?
You want to stay
with your brother?
Can I ask you something eIse?
Do you want to go
back to WaIIbrook?
Can you make a distinction between
your brother and WaIIbrook?
Do you want to stay with your
brother CharIie here in Los AngeIes?
Or go back to WaIIbrook?
Two separate things--stay with
your brother, or go back to WaIIbrook.
It's not one thing.
This is your brother.
Make a choice.
Back to WaIIbrook,
stay with CharIie.
Can you make that choice?
One or the other.
- AII right.
- Stay back at WaIIbrook.
HoId on. Just hoId on!
Stay back at WaIIbrook.
AII right.
You made your point.
Okay? You don't have
to humiIiate him.
Ray, it's okay. It's over.
Stay back at WaIIbrook
with CharIie Babbitt.
- Stay back at WaIIbrook.
- It's over.
Dr. Bruner,
can I taIk to you a minute?
Excuse me.
You okay, Ray?
You don't want
any more questions, do you?
I don't know.
You don't want
any more questions, do you?
No more questions.
Don't worry. There's not gonna be
any more questions, okay?
No more questions.
I'II make sure of that.
Yeah. Main man.
- What?
- My main man.
Listen...
I don't know if I'm gonna have
a chance to taIk to you again.
Because you see, these...
Dr. Bruner reaIIy Iikes you,
and he's probabIy gonna want
to take you back with him.
You know?
But I want you to know
that what I said about being
on the road with you, I meant.
Connecting.
I Iike having you for my brother.
I'm an exceIIent driver.
Yes, you are.
I Iike having you for my big brother.
C-H-A-R-L-I-E.
Main man.
May h have
your attertior. please.
Amtrak trair rumber 36.
the Desert Wind eastbourd.
row boardirg.
track rumber three.
Fullertor. Sar Berrardiro.
Barstow. Las Vegas.
Salt Lake City. Derver.
Omaha. Chicago.
ard other poirts betweer.
Ticketed passergers orly
may board the trair.
HeIIo, CharIie.
HeIIo, Raymond.
WouIdn't you feeI a IittIe more reIaxed
in your Kmart cIothes?
- TeII him, Ray.
- Kmart sucks.
I see.
I have the tickets, and I'II
be on this car here to the right.
Why don't you take
a coupIe of minutes.
See you, CharIie.
You made a joke, Ray.
I guess I better give this to you.
You're gonna have to
carry this now, it's--
It's got your cheese baIIs,
your appIe juice,
notebooks, pens, and...
''Who's on First?'' video that you Iike.
''Who's on First?''
Very funny.
I toId you it's funny.
Board!
- Better get going.
- Yeah. Very shiny train.
Yeah, it sure is.
Listen, Ray, Dr. Bruner
onIy has custody of you.
That doesn't mean I can't visit.
Now, I'm coming
to see you in two weeks.
How many days is that
before we're together?
1 4 days from today.
Today's Wednesday.
- Hours?
- 336 hours.
Mystifying.
'Course, that's 20,160 minutes.
1 ,209,600...
600 seconds.
I'II see you soon.
Yeah. One for bad,
two for good.
Bet two for good.
'Course,
three minutes to Wapner.
You'II make it.