Subtitle by :
d3xt3r (www.addic7ed.com)
THE HOBBIT
Old Bilbo: My dear Frodo,
you asked me once if I had told you everything
there was to know about my adventures.
And well, I can honestly say
I've told you the truth...
I may not have told you all of it.
I am old now, Frodo.
I am not the same hobbit I once was.
I think...It is time for you to know.
What really happened.
It began long ago.
In a land far away to the east.
The like of which,
You'll not find in the world..today.
There was a city of Dale.
It's market known far and wide.
Full with the bounties of fine and veil..
Peaceful and Prosperous.
For this city lay before the doors..
...of the greatest kingdom in middle earth.
Erebor. Stronghold of Thrr.
King under the mountain,
mightiest of the dwarf lords.
Thrr ruled with utter surety.
Never doubting his house would endure.
For his line lays secure
in the lifes of his son...and grandson.
Ahh..Frodo..Erebor!
Built deep within the mountainance-
the beauty of this fortress city was fetching.
It's wealth lay in the earth..
In precious gems humed from rock.
nd in great seams of gold...
running like river through stone.
The skill of the dwarfs was unequaled.
Fashioning objects of great beauty.
Out of diamond, emerald,
ruby and sapphire.
Ever they delve deeper down into the dark...
and that is where they found it.
The heart of the mountain...
The Arkenstone!
Thrr named it 'The King's Jewel'.
He took it as a sign,
A sign that his right to rule was divine.
All would pay homage to him.
Even the Elvenking..Thranduil.
But the years of peace and plenty
were not to last.
Slowly the days turn sour.
And the watchful eyes closed in.
Thrr's love of gold
has grown too fierce.
A sickness had begun to grow within him.
It was a sickness of the mind.
And where sickness thrive,
Bad things would follow.
the first they heard was a noise like a
hurricane  coming down from the North.
the pines on the mountain creaked and crocked
in the hot dry wind.
Balin, sound the alarm.
Do it now.
-What is it?
Dragon.
Dragon!!!
it was a fire drake from the North.
Smaug...had come.
Such wanton death was dealth that day,
This city of men was nothing to Smaug.
His eyes.. were set on another price.
The Dragons covet gold,
with a dark and fierce desire.
Erebor, was lost.
The Dragon would guard his plunder,
as long as he lives.
Run for your lives.
-Help us.
Thranduil would not risk the lives of his kin
against the wrath of the Dragon.
No help came from the Elfs that day..
nor any day since.
Robbed of their homeland,
the dwarves of Erebor wandered the wilderness.
A once mighty people,
brought low.
The young dwarf Prince took work
where he could find it. Labouring in the villages of men.
but always he remembered,
the mountains smoked beneath the moon..
The trees, like torches blazing bright.
For, he had seen the dragon's fire in the sky,
and city turned to ash.
But he never forgave and he never forgot.
That, my dear Frodo,
Is where I come in.
For quiet by chance and the will of a wizard...
fate decided,
I would become part of the tale.
It began..well it began
as you might've expect.
In a hole in the ground,
there lived a hobbit.
Not a nasty, dirty, wethole..
full of warm and oozie smells.
This was a Hobbit-hole.
That means, good food -
a warm heart
...and all the comforts of home.
Thank You.
What's this?
-That is private. Keep your sticky paws off.
It's not ready yet.
Not ready for what?
- Reading.
What on earth are these?
- Replies to your party invitations.
Good gracious!
Is it today?
They all said they're coming, except for the Sackville-Baggins
who are demanding you ask them in person.
Are they indeed?
Over my dead body.
Probably, they'd find quite agreeable.
They seem to think their tunnel overflowing...
It was one small chest.
Hardly over flowing.
And it still smells of troll.
-What on earth are you doing?
Taking precautions.
You know.. I caught her making off
with our silverware once?
-Who?
Lobelia, bag old-Baggins.
All my spoons..stuffed in her pocket.
Huh! Dreadful woman.
Make sure you keep an eye on her. After, I'm...?
When I'm...
When you're what?
It's Nothing.
Nothing.
You know, some people are beginning to
wonder about you, uncle.
They think you're becoming 'odd'.
- odd?
Unsociable.
-Unsociable? Me? Nonsense!
Be a good lad and put that on the gate.
NO ADMITTENCE,
'except for party affairs'.
Do you think he'll come?
- Who?
Gandalff.
He would not miss a chance
to lit of his wish boppers.
He'll give us quite a show.
You'll see.
I'm off.
- Off to where?
East Farthing Woods.
I'm going to surprise him.
Well, go on then.
You don't wanna be late.
He doesn't approve of being late.
Not that I ever was.
In those days, I was always on time.
I was entirely respectable.
And nothing unexpected...
ever happened.
An Unexpected Journey
60 Years Earlier...
Good Morning.
- What do you mean?
Wil je mij een goede morgen wensen, of is het
een goede morgen of ik dat nu wil of niet?
Or perhaps, you mean to say that,
you feel good on this perticular morning?
Or are you simply stating that
this is a morning to be good?
All of them or one...
I suppose.
Can I help you?
-That remains to be seen.
I'm looking for someone
to share in an adventure.
An adventure?
No, I don't imagine anyone West of Bree,
would have much interest in an adventures.
Nasty, disturbing..uncomforable thing.
I'm getting late for dinner.
Good morning.
Do you think I should've lived to bit ' good morning '
by Belladonna Toek's son ...
as if i'm selling buttons up the door?
- I beg your pardon?
You've changed.
And not entirely for better, Bilbo Baggins.
Im sorry, Do I know you?
-You know my name,
although you don't remember,
where i belong with.
I am Gandalf.
and Gandalf means ...
Me.
Not Gandalf, the wandering wizard..
who make such excellent fireworks?
Old toke who we use to have them
on midsummer eve.
I had no idea, you're still in business.
-And where else should I be?
Well, I'm pleased to find
you remember something about me.
Even if it's only my Fireworks.
Well, that's decided!
It will be very good for you.
And most amusing for me.
I shall inform the others.
Inform the who?
What? No...no.
We do not want any adventures here.
Thank you...Not today ...
I suggest you try.. over the Hill
or across the water.
Good morning.
Dwalin...
At your service.
Bilbo Baggins.
Do we know each other?
-No.
Which way, laddy?
It Is down here?
-Is what..down where?
Supper.
He said that there would be food.
Lots of it.
-He said? Who said?
Very good this. I
s there any more?
-What?
Ohh..yes..yes, huh.
Help yourself.
It's just that...umm..
I wasn't expecting...company.
That'll be the door.
Balin. At your service.
-Good Evening.
Yes, yes. It is.
Though, i think that it'll rain later.
Am I late?
-late, for what?
Evening, brother.
By my beard! You're shorter and wider than
last we met.
- Wider..not shorter.
Sharp enough for both of us.
Excuse me. Sorry, I hate to interrupt.
But the thing is...
Have you eaten?
- It's not that i don't like visiters.
I llike visitors, as much as the next hobbit.
But I do like to know them,
before they come..visiting.
What is this?
-I don't know. I just thought it'be cheese.
It's gone blue.
-It's riddled with mold.
Not in the slightest.
I don't mean to be blunt...
but I have to speak my mind.
I'm sorry.
Apology accepted.
Oh now fill it up, brother. Just don't stand.
Fili and Kili, At your service.
-You must be Mr. Baggins.
No. You can't come in..
you've come to the wrong House.
Has it been cancelled?
-No one told us.
Nothing has been canceled.
-That is a relief.
Be careful with this,
I just had them sharpened.
It's nice. Did you do it yourself?
-No, it's been in the family for years.
That's my mother's jewellery box.
Can you please don't do that.
Fili and Kili. C'mon give us a hand,
-Mr. Dwalin.
Better shove this in the hole, otherwise
we'll never get anyone in.
Anyone? How many more are there?
-How many more of it?
Oh no. There is nobody home!
Go away and bother somebody else!
There's far too many dwarfs in my dining room.
This is some...budhead idea of a joke. ...
I'm becoming insane.
It is embarassing and no taste.
Gandalf.
Excuse me...Not my wine.
-Put that back. Put that back!
Not the jam, please. Excuse me...
Tad excessive.. Isn't it? Have you got a cheese knive?
Cheese knive? He eats it by the block.
-No, that's grandpa Mungo's Chair.
Take it back. Take it back This is antique.
Not for sitting.
Excuse me, Mr. Gandalf,
Can I tempt you with a cup of Camomille?
Oh, No thank you Dori.
A little red wine, for me. I think.
Where are the tomatoes?
-Fili...Kili
Oin, Gloin, Dwalin, Balin.
Bifur, Bofur, Bombur.
Dori, Nori...
-Ori.
Yes, you're quite right, Bifur.
We appear to be one dwarf short.
-He is late. Is all.
He traveled North.
To a meeting of our kin. He will come.
Mr. Gandalf, a little glass of red wine
as requested.
It got a fruity bouquet.
-Cheers.
Catch.
Who wants an ale?
That is a doelli not a dish cloth.
But it's full of holes.
- yeah, it's suppose to look like that.It's crochet.
Must i get these dwarfs!!!
-My dear Bilbo, what the haste is the matter?
What's the matter?
I'm surrounded by dwarfs.What are they doing here?
Oh they're quite a merry gathering,
You must get used to them.
I don't want to get use to them!
the state of my kitchen, there's mud..troiling the carpet.
They've pillaged the pantry.
I'm not gonna tell you what they've done to the bathroom.
They've all but destroyed the plumming.
I don't know what they're doing in my house?
'cuse me, i'm sorry to interrupt,
but what should i do with my plate?
There you go Ori, give it to me.
Excuse me! That is my mothers crockery.
It is more than 100 years old.
Can you not do that.
You'd blunt them.
OOo didn't you hear that lads?
He says we'd blunt 'em.
Bend the knives, bend the forks
Smash the bottles, burn the corks...
He is here.
Gandalf,
I thought, you said
this place would be easy to find.
I lost my way, twice.
I wouldn't 've found it at all.
Had it not been that mark on the door.
Mark? There is no mark on that door.
It was painted a week ago.
There is a marker.
I put it there, myself.
Bilbo Baggings, allow me to introduce
the leader of our company...
Thorin Oakenshield
So, this is the Hobbit.
Tell me, Mr.Baggins..
have you done much fighting?
Pardon me?
-Axe or sword?
What's your weapon of choice?
Well, I do have some skills at conquers.
If you must know.
But i fail to see,
why that's relevant.
I thought that much.
He looks more like a grocer than a burgler.
What news of the meeting in Ered Luin?
Will they all come?
Aye, All dwarfs of all seven kingdoms.
What's the dwarves of the Iron Hills Say?
Is they in with us?
They will not come.
They say, this quest is ours,
and ours alone.
We're still on the quest?
Bilbo, my dear fella,
Let us have a little more light?
Far to the East,
over ranges and rivers ...
beyond woodlands and wastelands ...
lies a single solitary peak.
The Lonely Mountain.
Aye, Oin has read the portends,
and the portends say, it is time.
Ravens has been seen flying back to the mountain,
as it was foretold.
When the birds Beorn
return to Erebor ...
The reign of the beast, will end.
What beast?
-Well, that'd be a reference to Smaug- the terrible.
Chiefest and greatest calamity of our age.
Airborne fire breather. Teeth like razors
claws like meat hooks.
Extremely fond of precious metals.
-Yes, I know what a dragon is.
I'm not afraid. I'm up for it,
I'll give em a taste of dwafist iron right up their jackses.
Sit down.
-The task'd be difficult enough with an army behind us.
But we number just thirteen.
not thirteen of the best ...
Nor brightest.
-What you said?
We may be few in number!
but we are fighters. All of us!
To the last dwarfs.
-And you forget, we've a wizard in our company..
Gandalf would've killed
hundreds of dragons in his time.
No, I wouldn't say.
-How many then?
What?
-How many dragons you have killed?
Go on, give us the number.
Enough.
If we have read these signs,
Do you not think, others would've read em too?
Rumors have began to spread.
The dragon Smaug, hasn't been seen in 60 years.
Eyes look East of the mountains.
Acessing..wondering...weight the risk-
Perhaps the vast wealth of our people
now lies unprotected.
Do we sit back,
while others claim what's rightfully our?
Or do we seize this chance
to take back Erebor ?
You forget the front gate is sealed.
There is no way into the mountain.
-That my dear Balin, is not entirely true.
How came you by this?
-It was given to me by your father.
Thrin..for safe keeping.
It is yours.
If there is a key, there must be a door.
This ruins speak of a hidden passage
to the lower hall .
There's another way in.
-But if we can find it
the dwarf doors are invisible and closed.
The answer lies hidden somewhere in this map.
I do not have the skill to find em.
There are others in Middle-Earth
who can.
The task I have in mind, will require
a great deal of stealth and no small amount of courage.
But, if we are careful and clever,
I believe, It can be done.
That is why we need a burglar.
-Hmmm, and a good one.
An expert, I'd imagine.
-And are you?
Am i what?
-He said he is an expert. He hey,
Me? No, I'm not a burglar.
I have never stole a thing in my life.
I'm afraid i have to agree with Mr. Baggins.
He is hardly a burgler material.
Aye, the wild is no place for gentle folk,
who can neither fight or fend themselves.
Enough! If i say Bilbo Baggin is a burgler.
And a burgler he is.
Hobbits are remarkably light on their feet.
In fact, they can past unseen by most if they choose.
And while the Dragon
is accustomed to the smell of dwarves ...
the scent of hobbit is all but unknown him,
which gives us a distinct advantage.
You asked me
to find the 14th member of this company,
And I have chosen Mr. Baggins.
There's a lot more to him then appearance 've suggest.
And he's got a great deal to offer,
than any of you know.
Including himself.
You must trust me on this.
Very well,
we'll do it your way.
No..no.
-Give him the contract.
It's just the usual.
Summery about pocket expenses.
Time required.
Remuneration, funeral arrangements..so forth.
-Funeral arrangements?
I can not guarantee his safety.
-Understood.
Nor will I be responsible for his fate.
Agreed.
Total cash on delivery. Upto but not exceeding
one 14th total profit, if any.
Seems fair...
Incineration?
-Oh aye, they'd bite flesh off your bone
in a blink of an eye.
You're alright, laddy?
- Yeah, okay...
I fear that i might faint.
-Think  furnace with wings.
I need air.
-A Flash of light. Sheering pain and poof!
You're nothing more than a pile of ash.
I'll be alright, just let me sit quitely for a moment.
-You've been sitting quitely for far too long.
Tell me, when did doilys of
your mother's dishes become so important to you?
I remember a young hobbit,
who was always running in search of elves in the Woods.
stay out late and come home after dark,
trailing with muds and dweep and fireflies.
A young hobbit who would've liked nothing better than to
find out what was beyond the border of the Shire.
The world is not
in your books and maps.
It's out there.
I can't just go running off into the blue!
I am a Baggins, of Bag End!
You are also a Took.
Did you know that your great-great-great, great-uncle
"Bullroarer" Took was so large...
he could ride a real horse?
In the Battle of Greenfields, he charged the goblin
ranks - he swung his club so hard...
It knocked the goblin king's head clean off
and it sailed a hundred yards...
through the air,
and went down the rabbit hole.
And thus, the battle was won
and the game of golf invented at the same time.
I do believe you made that up.
-Well, all good stories deserve embellishment.
You'll have a tale or two to tell
of your own, when you come back.
Can you promise that I will come back?
No. And if you do,
you will not be the same.
That's what i thought.
Sorry, Gandalf.
I can't sign this.
You've got the wrong hobbit.
It appears,
we have lost our burgler.
Probably for the best.
The odds were always against us.
After all..What are we?
Merchants, miners,
tinkers and toy makers.
Hardly the stuff of legend.
-There are a few warrior amongst us.
Old warrior.
I 'll take each and everyone of these dwarves
over an army of the iron hills .
For when i call upon 'em, they answered.
Loyalty, honor
and a willing heart.
I cannot ask more than that?
You don't have to do this.
You have a choice.
You have done honourably,
by our people.
You have build a new life for us
in the blue mountains.
A life of peace and plenty.
A life that is worth more
than all the gold in Erebor.
From my father to my granfather,
This, has come to me.
They dreamt of the day when the dwarves of Erebor
will reclaim their homeland.
There is no choice, Balin.
Not for me.
Then, we are with you, laddie.
We will see it done.
Far over the misty mountains cold.
To dungeons deep,
and caverns old.
We must away, ere break of day,
To find our long forgotten gold.
The pines were roaring
on the height,
The winds were moaning
in the night.
The fire was red,
it flaming spread;
The trees like torches
blazed with light.
Subtitle by :
d3xt3r (www.addic7ed.com)
Hallo?
Mr. Bilbo, Where are you off to?
-Can't stop I'm already late.
Late, for what?
- I am going on an adventure.
-Wait.
I signed it.
Everything appears to be in order.
Welcome, Master Baggins,
to the company of Thorin Oakenshield.
Give him a pony.
-No..no...no. That won't be necessary.
I'm sure I can keep up, on foot.
I've done my share of walking holidays.
C'mon, Nori. Pay up.
- Thanks much.
What's that about?
Oh, they took wagers.
On whether or not you'd turn up.
Most of them bet
that you wouldn't.
And what did you think?
My dear fella,
I never doubted you for a second.
Horsehair, I'm having a reaction.
Wait.Wait.
Stop!
We have to turn around.
-What on Earth is the matter?
I forgot my handkerchief.
-Here, use this.
Move on.
You'd have to manage
without pocket handkerchiefs ...
and a good many other things,
Bilbo Baggins.
You are born to the rolling hills
and the little rivers of the Shire.
But home, is now behind you.
The world is ahead.
Hello girl...
who's a good girl?
This is our little secret, Myrtle.
Tell no one.
Wat was that?
- Orks.
Orks?
- Throat cutters, there'd be dozens of 'em out there.
The low lands are crawling with them.
-They strike on wee small hours, when everyone is asleep.
Quick and quite. No screams,
just lots of blood.
You think that is funny?
You think,
a night raids by Orks is a joke?
We didn't mean anything by it.
No, you did't.
You know nothing of the world.
Don't mind him, laddie.
Thorin has more cause than most,
to hate Orcs.
After the Dragon took the Lonely Mountain ...
King Thrr tried to reclaim
the ancient dwarf kingdom of Moria.
But our enemy had got there first.
Moria had been taken by legions of Orcs ...
lead by the most vile of all their race.
Azog - the Defiler.
The giant Gundabad Orc
had sworn ...
To wipe out,
the line of Durin.
He began by beheading the king.
Thrin, Thorins father,
was driven mad by grief.
He went missing, taken prisoner or killed.
We did not know.
We were leader less.
Defeat and death,
were upon us.
That is when, I saw him.
A young dwarfs Prince
facing down the pale ork.
He stood alone
against this terrible foe.
His armor wrenth,
wielding nothing but an oaken branch as a shield.
Azog the Defiler learned that day...
that the line of Durin will
not so easily broken.
Our forces rallied
and drove the orcs back.
Our enemy,
had been defeated.
But there was no feast.
No song.. that night.
Our dead were beyond the count of grief.
A few had survived.
And I thought to myself then...
There is one who I could follow.
There is one,
I could call ' King '.
And the pale ork ...
What's happened to him?
-He slugged back into the hole, whence he came.
That filth died of his wounds long ago.
Mr. Gandalf, can't you do something
about this deluge?
It's raining, master dwarf.
And it will continue to rain, until the rain is done.
If you wish to change the weather of the world,
You should find yourself another wizard.
Are there any?
-What?
Other wizards?
There were five of us.
The greatest of our order
is Saruman the white.
Then there are the two druidses.
And the other
i quite forgotten their names.
And who is the fifth?
- That would be, Radagast the Brown.
Is he a great wizard
or Is he...more like you?
I think he is a very great wizard.
In his own way.
He is a gentle soul, who prefers
the company of animals to others.
He keeps a watchful eye
over the vast forest land, to the East.
And a good thing too, for always evil
will look to find foothold in this world.
Not good.
Not at all good.
No, Sebastian.
Good gracious.
Move back.
Give him some air! For goodness sake...
I don't understand why it's not working.
As if it's witchcraft.
Witchcraft ...
Oh, but it is.
A dark and powerful magic.
Where on this good earth
did does foul creatures come from?
The old forest?
Show me.
We camp here for the night.
Fili.. Kili, look after the ponies.
Make sure you stay with them.
Farmer and his family
must've lived here.
Oin, Gloin, get a fire going.
I think it would be wiser,
to move on.
We could make to the hidden Valley drive.
I told you, already.
I will not go near that place.
Why not? The Elves can help us.
We could get food, rest... advice.
I do not need their advice.
We have a map, that we cannot read.
Lord Elrond could help us.
Help?
When the Dragons attacked, Erebor
what help came from the Elves?
Orcs plundered Moria
and desecrated our Sacred halls.
The Elves looked on and did nothing.
You ask me to seek out the very people
who betrayed my granfather, betrayed my father?
You're neither of them.
I did not give you that map and key
for you, to hold on to the past.
I did not know, nobody ought to keep.
Everything alright?
Gandalf, where are you going?
To seek the company of the only one around here
who's got any sense.
And who is that?
-Myself, Mr. Baggins.
I've had enough of dwarfs for one day.
C'mon, Bombur. We are hunger.
-Is he coming back?
He'd been a long time..Gandalf.
- He's a wizard. He does what he chooses.
Here, do us a favor.
Take this to the lads.
What's the matter?
- We're suppose to be looking after the ponies.
Only we've encountered a slight problem.
-We had 16.
Now there is.. 14.
Daisy and Bungo are missing.
-Well, that is not good.
And that is not good at all.
-Shouldn'd we tell Thorin?
Ahh no, let's not worry him.
As our official burglar
we thought,
you might want to look into it.
Well, look something big
uprooted these trees.
That was our thinking.
-Something very big and possibly quite dangerous.
Hey, There is a light.
Over Here.
Stay down.
What is it?
- Trolls.
We have to do something.
-Yes, you should.
Mountain trolls are slow and stupid,
and you're so small they will never see you.
It is perfectly safe.
We'll be right behind you.
If you run into trouble, hoot twice like a bowl owl..
and once like a brawl owl.
Twice like a bowl owl..once like a brawl owl..
Are you sure this is a good idea?
Mutton yesterday.
Mutton today..and like.
And it all look like mutton again tomorrow.
-quit your groaning.
These ain't sheep.
These's fresh maine.
I don't like horses. I never have...
not enough fat on 'em.
But better than that livery old farmer.
All skin and bone he was.
I'm still thinkin' he's bit in me teeth.
That's lovely taste..a floater.
-Oh, does improve the flavour.
Oh, more where that came from.
-Oh, no you don't.
Sit down.
You haven't kept these nags.
-But I like the stinky parts.
I said, Sit down.
I'm starving.
Are we gonna eat that horse or not?
Shut your Cakcom.
You eat what i give ya.
Bert is the Cook
Everything tastes the same.
Everything tastes like chicken.
-Except the chicken. That taste like fish.
I'm just saying
a little appreciatio would be nice.
' Thank you Very much Bert'
' Lovely stew, Bert '. How hard is that?
Just need a sprinkle of squirrel there .
That's my grog.
Sorry.
That is beautifully balanced.
That is.
Let me know if it need any else.
Good, in'it?
That's how I cook.
Me gags are rumbling.
I've got to snack something.
Flesh, I need flesh.
Bert..Look what's come outta me otter.
It 's got arms and legs and everything.
-What is it?
I don't know,
but i don't like the way it's wriggling.
What are you then?
An oversized squirrel?
I'm a burglar. A Hobbit.
-A burglar hobbit?
Can we cook him?
-We can try.
He might be more than a mouthful,
not only skin and bone.
There's more hobbit in this part.
More than enough for a pie.
Get him.
- Its too quick.
Oh you little,..
Gotcha.
Are there anymore of you little fellas hiding
where you shouldn't?
No.
He is lying.
-I'm not.
Hold his toes over  the fire,
Make him squeel.
Drop him!
-You want...what?
I said, Drop him!
Get 'em in their stand.
Bilbo.
-No.
Lay down your arms,
or we will rip his off.
Don't bother cooking 'em?
Let's just sit on him
and squas him into jelly.
They must be sautd and grilled
with a sprigkle of Sage.
That does sound quite nice.
Never mind the seasoning.
We ain't got all night.
Dawn ain't far away, let's get a move on.
I don't fancy being turned to stone.
Wait, you are making a terrible mistake!
You can't reason with them. They are half-wits.
-Half-wits? What does that make us?
I meant with the...seasoning.
What about the seasoning?
-Well, Have you smelled them?
You're gonna need something stronger than Sage
before you plate this one up.
Traitor.
-What do you know about cooking dwarfs?
Shut up.
Let the flagger burglar hobbit talk.
The secret to cooking dwarfs...
C'mon...
-The secret is ...
To skin them first.
Tom, get me filleting knife.
-I will get you for this...
I won't forget that.
-What a lot of rubbish.
I've eaten plenty wood man with skins on.
Scoffer marks with boots and all.
He is right.
There is nothing wrong with bit of raw dwarfs.
Nice and crunchy.
-Not that one. He is infected.
He what?
-He's got worms, in his tubes.
In fact, they all have. They're infested with parasites.
It's a terrible business.
I would don't risk it. I really wouldn't.
-Parasites...did he said parasites?
We have no parasites.
We are riddled.
What would you have us do then?
Let them all go?
You think i don't know what you're upto?
These little ferret
Is taking us for a fool.
Ferrets?
-Fools?
The dawn will take you all!
Who is that?
-No idea, can we eat him too?
Get your foot out of my mouth.
Where did you go to, if i may ask?
-to look ahead.
What brought you back?
-Looking behind.
Nasty business.
-Still they're all in one piece.
No thanks to your burgler.
He had to mask.
To bade for time.
They must've come down from Etinwoods.
Since when did the mountain trolls
venture down far South?
They have not ages.
Not since the darker power
ruled this land.
They couldn't have moved in daylight.
There must be a cave nearby.
What a stench.
-It's a trollenhol.
Be careful what you touch.
Seems ashame, just to let 'em lay around.
Anyone could take it.
-Agreed. Nori.
Get a shovel.
This sword are not made by any troll.
Nor they're made by smiths among men.
These are forged in Gondorlet,
by the High Elves in the first age.
You could not wish for a finer blade.
We are making a long term deposit.
-Let's get out of this foul place.
Come on, let's go.
Here. This is about your size.
I can't take this.
-The blade is of Elves make.
Which means, It glow blue
when Orcs and Goblins are near by.
I've never used a sword in my life.
-And hope you never have to.
But if you do, remember this:
True courage is about knowing
when not to take a life ...
but when to spare one.
Something's coming!
-Stay together.
Hurry there.
Arm you.
Thieves. Fire.
Murder.
Radagast.
Radagast the Brown.
What on earth are you doing here?
-I was looking for you, Gandalf. Something's wrong.
Something's...terribly wrong.
-Yes?
Just give me a minute.
Oh, I had a thought, now i've lost it.
It's right there, on the tip of my tongue.
It's not a thought all.
It is a little ...
Stick Insect.
The Green Wood is sick, Gandalf.
A darkness has fallen over it.
Nothing grows anymore,
at least nothing good.
The air is foul decay,
but the worst are the webs.
Webs? What do you mean?
-Spiders, Gandalf.
Giant ones.
Some kind of spawn of... Ungoliant.
But, I'm not a wizard.
I followed their trail...
They came from Dol Guldur.
Dol Guldur?
But the old fort is abandoned?
No, Gandalf.
It is not.
A dark power dwells in there.
Such that I've never felt before.
It is the shadow of an ancient horror.
One that can summon the spirits...
of the dead.
I saw him, Gandalf.
Out of the darkness...
A Necromancer has come.
Quickly.
Wait for me.
Sorry.
-Try this low tribute.
It helps settle the nerves.
Breathe out.
Now... A necromancer?
Are you sure?
That is not from the world of the living.
Was that a wolf? Are wolves out there?
-Wolfs, No, that is not a wolf.
Wargs Orcs. Which means Orc pack is not
far behind.
Orc Pack?
Who did you tell about your quest,
beyond your kin?
-No one.
Who did you tell?
-No one, I swear.
What in the name of Durin is going on?
-We are being hunted.
We have to get out of here.
We can't, we have no ponies.
They bolted.
I'll draw them off.
These are Gundabad-Wargs.
They'll out run you.
These are Rhosgobel rabbits.
I would like to see them try.
Come and get me.
Come on.
Stay together.
Ori, No. Go back.
Come on, quick.
Where are you leading us?
Move...
-Run!!!!
There they are.
This way.
Quickly.
There is more coming.
-Kili?
We are surrounded.
Where is Gandalf?
-He has abandoned us.
Hold your ground.
Kili.
This way you fools.
-Come on, move.
Quickly, all of you.
Go..go...go.
Nine, ten ...
Kili.
Elves.
I can't see where the path leads.
Do we follow it or not?
Follow, of course.
I think that would be wise.
The Valley of Imladris.
In common tongue
it's known by another name.
-Rivendell.
Here lies the last Holy House,
East of the sea.
It was your plan, all along?
To seek refuge at our enemies.
You have no enemies here,
Thorin Oakenshield.
The only ill will to be found in this Valley,
Is that you bring to your self.
Do you think the Elves,
will give our quest their blessing?
They will try to stop us.
Of course, they will. But we have questions
that need to be answered.
If we are to be successful,
This'll need to be handled with tact and respect.
And no small degree of charm.
Which is why, you'll leave
the talking..to me.
Mithrandir.
-Ahh, Lindir.
Watch out.
I must speak with Lord Elrond.
My Lord Elrond is not there.
-Not here?
Where is he?
In formation. Connect the rows.
Gandalf.
-Lord Elrond.
Strange, for Orcs to come
so close to our borders.
Something or Someone,
has drawn them near.
That may have been us.
Welcome, Thorin, son of Thrain.
I do not believe, we have met.
-You have your Grandfather's bearing.
I knew Thror, when he ruled under the mountain.
-Indeed, he made no mention of you.
What is he saying?
Does he offer us insults?
No, master Gloin.
He's offering you food.
Ah well, like this, lead on.
Try it. Just a mouthful.
-I don't like green food.
Where is the meat?
-Have they got any chips?
Kind of you to invite us.
i'd have dressed for dinner.
-Oh, you're never.
This is Orcrist, the Goblin Cleaver.
A famous blade,
forged by the High Elves from the West.
My King.
May it serve you well.
And this is Glamdring.
A ' foe -hammer '.
Sword of the King of Gondolin.
I wouldn't bother, laddie.
Swords are named for the great deeds
they do in war.
What do say,
my sword doesn't seen battle?
I'm not actually sure, It Is a sword?
More of a letter opener really.
How did you come by these?
We found them in a trollenhol,
at the great Eastern road.
Shortly before we were ambushed by Orcs.
And what were you doing
on the great Eastern road?
Our business is no for Elves.
For goodness sake, Thorin show him the map.
-It is the legacy of my people.
It's mine to protect
as are it's secrets.
Save me from the stubbornness of dwarves.
Your pride will be your downfall.
You stand here in the presence of one
of the few in Middle-Earth who can read that map.
Show it to Lord Elrond.
No, Thorin.
Erebor.
What is your interest in this map?
It's mainly academic.
As you know, this sort of artifacts
sometime contains hidden texts.
You still read ancient dwergs,
Do you not?
Minas Ithil.
Moon Runes.
-of course.
An easy thing to miss.
In this case that is true.
Moon runes can only be read ...
by the light of a moon of
the same shape and season ...
the day on which they were written.
Can you read them?
These runes are written
on a midsummer eve ...
by the light of a cresent moon,
nearly 200 years ago.
It would seem that
you're meant to come to Rivendell.
Fate is with you, Thorin Oakenshield.
The same moon shines upon us tonight.
' Stand by the grey stone,
When the thrush knocks ...
and the setting sun with the last
light of Durin's day ...
will shine on the keyhole '.
-Durin's day?
Which is the start of the dwarves
New year.
When the last Moon of
Autumn in the first Sun of the winter ...
appear in the sky together.
This is of news.
Summer is passing.
Durin's day will soon be upon us.
We still have time.
-Time for what?
To find the entrance.
We have to be standing at exactly
the right spot exactly the right time.
Then and only then,
can the door be opened.
So this is your purpose, to enter the mountain?
-What of it?
There are some,
who would not deem it wise.
What do you mean?
You're not the only guardian to stand
watch on Middle-Earth.
Bombur.
With or without our help,
these dwarves will march on the mountain.
They are determined
to reclaim their homeland.
I do not believe, Thorin
Oakenshield feels...
that he is answerable to anyone.
No, for that matter, am I.
-It is not me you must answer to.
Lady Galadriel.
-Mithrandir.
I had no idea
Lord Elrond has send for you.
He didn't, I did.
Saruman.
-You've been busy of late, my friend.
Tell me, Gandalf ...
Did you think, these plans and
schemes of yours would go unnoticed?
Unnoticed?
No.I'm simply doing
what i feel to be right.
The Dragon is long been your mind.
That is true, My lady.
Smaug owes no allegiance to no one.
But if he should side with the enemy,
A dragon can be used to terrible effect.
What enemy?
Gandalf, The enemy is defeated.
Sauron is vanquished.
He can never regain his full strength.
Gandalf.
For 400 years, we've lived in peace.
A hard-won watchful peace.
Are we at peace?
Trolls have come down from the mountains
they are raiding villages and destroying farms.
Orcs have attacked us along the way.
-Hardly a prelude to war.
That is we wouldn't meddle.
Looking for trouble when none exist.
Let him speak.
There is something at work
beyond the evil of Smaug.
Something far more powerful.
We can remain blind to it,
but it will not be ignoring us.
A sickness rise among the green woods.
The woodsman who lives there now call it Mirkwood.
And they say ...
Well, don't stop now.
Tell us what the woodsman say.
They speak of a necromancer ?
Dol Guldur.
summoned the dead.
-That is absurd.
There is no such power exists
in this world.
This necromancer
is nothing more than a mortal than a mortal man.
A conjurer, dabbling in black magic.
-And so I thought too.
But Radagast has seen him.
-Radagast.
Do not speak to me about Radagast the Brown.
He is a foolish fellow.
He's odd, i grant you.
Lives a solitary life.
Not that, it is his excessive
consumption of mushrooms.
It addled his brain and yellowed his teeth...
I warned You.
It is unbefitting ...
You carry something.
It came to you from Radagast.
He found it in Dol Guldur.
-Yes.
Show me.
What is that?
A relic of Mordor.
A Morgul blade.
Made for the Witch-King of Angmar.
And buried with him.
When Angmar fell ...
names the men of 't North
took his body ...
and sealed in
the high mountains of Rhudaur.
Deep within rock they buried him.
In a tomb so dark
it would never to light.
This is not possible.
A powerful spells lies upon those tombs,
they cannot be opened.
What proof do we have,this weapon
came from Angmars grave?
I have none.
-Because there is none.
Let's examine what we know.
A single Orcs pack, dared
to cross the Breowning.
A dagger from the bygone age
has been found.
And a human sorcerer,
who calls himself necromancer ...
has taken residence
in a ruined fortress.
It is not very much afterall.
But the question of these dwarfs
company however, troubles me deeply.
I am not convinced, Gandalf.
I don't feel like condoning such a quest.
If they'd come to me,
I might've spared them the disappoinments.
They're leaving?
Yes.
-You knew?
Er is niets anders te zeggen.
My Lord Elrond.
the dwarves, they're gone.
Be on your guard.
We're about to set on the edge of the wild .
Balin. You know this path, lead on.
-okay.
Master Baggins.
I suggest that you keep up.
You will follow them?
-Yes.
You're right to
help Thorin Oakenshield.
But I fear, this quest has set in motion forces
we do not yet.. understand.
The riddle of Morgul blade
must be answered.
Something moves in the shadows, unseen;
hidden from our sight. It'll not show itself...
Not yet.
But everyday, it grows in strength.
You must to be careful.
Mithrandir.
Why the halfling?
-I do not know.
Saruman believes that it is only great power..
that can hold the rule in check .
But that's not what I found.
I found that, it is the small things.
Every day deeds of ordinary folk,
that keeps the darkness at bay.
Simple acts of kindness and love.
Why Bilbo Baggins?
Perhaps, it's because I'm afraid.
It gives me courage.
Do not be afraid, Mithrandir.
You're not alone.
We must find shelter.
-Watchout!
This is not a thunderstorm.
This is Thunder Battle.
Move!
Oh, blast me. The legends are true.
Giants.
Stone Giants.
Fili grab my hand.
No.
No. Fili.
We're still alive!
Where is Bilbo?
-Where is the Hobbit?
There.
Grab my hand. Bilbo
I thought,
we have lost our burgler.
He's been lost,
ever since he left home.
He should never have come.
He has no place amongst us.
Dwalin.
It looks safe enought.
Search in the back.
There is nothing here.
Alright then. Let's get a fire started.
-No, no fire, not in this place.
Get some sleep.
We start at first light.
We were to wait in the mountains
until Gandalf joins us.
That was the plan.
-The plan has changed.
Bofur,
Take the first watch
Where do you think you are going?
Back to Rivendell.
-No, you can't go back now.
You're part of the company,
You are one of us.
Not now, am I?
Thorin said I should never have come.
He was right.
You're a took' and i am a Baggins.
I don't know what i was thinking.
I  never ran out my door.
-you are homesick..I understand.
No, you don't. You don't understand.
None of you do.
You are dwarfs.
You're used to tick to this life.
Never sticking in one place,
Not belonging anywhere.
I'm sorry, I don't ...
You are right.
We don't belong anywhere.
I wish you all the luck in the world.
I really do.
What's that?
Wake up.
Take my hand.
Get off me.
Who would be so bold,
to come armed into my Kingdom?
Spies? Thieves? Assasins?
Dwarfs, your malenevolence.
-Dwarfs?
We found them at the front torpish.
- Well, don't just stare 'em. Search them!
Every crack, every crevice.
What are you doing here, indeed?
Speak!
Very well, if they wouldn't talk,
Let's make them squak.
Bring up the mandler.
Bring up the bones breaker.
Start with the youngest.
-Wait.
Well, well..well,
Look who that is.
Thorin, son of Thrain,
son of Thror.
King under the mountain.
But I'm forgetting, you dont have a
Mountain, and you're not a King.
Which makes you.. ' nobody '.
Really.
I know someone,
who would pay a pretty price for your head.
Just the head.
Nothing attached.
Perhaps, you know of whom i speak.
An old enemy of yours.
A pale ork, that rides a white Warg.
Azog The Defiler, was destroyed.
He was slayed in battle, long ago.
So you think his defiling days are done.
Do you?
Send word to the pale orc.
Tell him, I have found his price.
Gollem.
Goblinses.
Better than the old bones, Precious.
Better than nothing.
Too many of bones, precious.
Not enough flesh.
Shut up. Cut the skin off.
Start with the head.
Rocks and stones are like old bones.
No flesh and meat.
Cold as death and without precious,
good to eat.
Blessed, splashes.
Precious, that's a meaty mouthful.
Gollem.
Back up, stay back.
I'm warning you
Don't come any closer.
He's got an Elfish blade,
but it is not an elf.
No, No elfs small.
What is it, precious.
What is it?
My name is Bilbo Baggins.
-Bagingses?
What is a Bagingses, precious?
I am a hobbit from the Shire.
We like Goblinses, bats
and fishes..but i haven't tried Hobbits before.
Is it soft, is it juicy?
- Stop.
Keep your distance.
I'll use this, if I have to.
I don't want any trouble.
Do you understand?
Show me the way to get out of here,
and i'll be on my way.
Why? Is he lost?
Yes, and I want to get 'unlost'
as soon as possible.
We know safe passage for Hobbitses.
Safe path in the dark.
Shut up.
- I didn't say anything.
I wasn't talking to you.
I don't know what your game is, but ...
-Games!
We love games, doesn't we, precious?
Does it like games?
Does it like to play?
Maybe...
What has roots has nobody sees?
Is taller than trees...
Up, up up it goes.
And yet, never grows?
The mountain.
Let's have another one, huh.
Yeah, do it, do it...Ask us.
No, no more riddles.
Finish him off, finish him now.
No, I want to play.
I want to play.
I can see, you are very good at this.
So, Why we don't we game up riddles.
Just you and me.
Just, just us.
Yes, and if i win...
then you show me the way out.
And  if it loses?
What then?
If it loses, precious,
then we eat it.
If Baggins loses
we eat it all.
Fair enough.
But Baggins first.
30 white horses on a Red Hill.
First they chant, then they stomp,
and then they stand still.
Teeth?
That's my precious.
But we, we have nine.
Our turn.
Voiceless, it cries.
Wingless, fat less
Toothless, bites.
Mouth missed, mutters.
Just a minute,
We loose, we loose,
Shut up.
It's Wind.
Of course it is.
Very clever, hobbins is.
Very clever.
A box without hinges, key or lid...
Yet, golden treasure
inside is hidden.
No...
Key. Money. Box.
-Well?
It's nasty.
Give up?
--Give us a chance, precious. Give us a chance.
Eggsess.
Fun, taught us to suck this. Yes!
We have a one for you.
All things, it devours.
Birds, bees,  trees, flowers.
Not iron, but still ...
grinds hard stones to mule.
Answer us.
-Give me a moment, please. I gave up a long while.
Please?
I don't know this one.
Is it tasty?
Is it scrumtious?
Is it crunchy?
-Let me think.
It's stuck.
Bagginses it's stuck.
Times up.
Time...time.
The answer is ' time '.
Actually, it wasn't that hard.
- Last question.
Last chance.
Ask us.
Ask us..
- Yes, yes. Alright.
What do I got in my Pocket?
That is not fair.
It is against the rules.
Ask us another one.
-No, no..no. You said, ask me a question.
That is my question.
What do I've got in my Pocket?
Must get gueses, must give us three.
Three gueses, very well.
Guess away.
Handses.
- -Wrong. Guess again.
Fish. Goblintanden?
Missed my chances, rat wings.
Knife. Oh shut Up.
-Wrong again. Last guess.
String or nothing.
Two guesses at once,
Wrong both times.
No...
I've won the game.
You promised to show me the way out.
If we say so, Precious.
If we say so.
What has you got in it's pockets?
That's no concern of yours.
You've lost.
Lost?
Lost.
Where is it?
No.
Lost.
Lost it, precious.
My precious is lost.
What have you lost?
-Most of precious,
Gollem.
What has it got...
in it's nasty, little pockets?
He stole it.
I know that sword.
It is the Goblincleaver.
The Biter. The blade that sliced
a thousand necks.
Blast them. Beat them.
Kill them all.
Cut off his head.
Take up arms.
Fight.
Follow me, quick.
Run.
Give it to us.
It's ours.
Thief!
Baggins...
Cut the rope.
Quickly.
Go on.
You thought you could escape me?
What are you going to do now, Wizard?
That will do it.
That could've been worst.
You've got to be joking.
Gandalf.
There's too many, we can't fight 'em.
- Only one thing will save us, the lights.
Run. Here, on your feet.
Wait, my precious...
Wait.
Gollem.
Baggingses. Thiefs.
Curse it and crash it.
We hate it forever.
Five, six, seven, eight ...
Bifur and Bofur. That is ten.
And Fili and Kili. That is twelve.
And Bombur. That makes thirteen.
Where is Bilbo?
Where is our Hobbit?
Curse the halfling.
I thought he was with Dori.
-Don't blame me.
Where did you last see him?
-I think i saw him slip away,
What happened exactly? Tell me.
-I'll tell you what happened.
Master Baggins saw his chance
and he took it.
He's thought nothing but his soft bed
and warm house...
Since he first step out his door.
We will not be seeing our Hobbit again.
He is long gone.
No, he isn't.
Bilbo Baggins, I've never been so glad
to see anyone in my life.
Bilbo, we've given you up .
-How in hell did you get past the goblins?
How indeed?
What does it matter?
He is back.
It matters.
I want to know.
Why did you come back?
I know you doubt me.
I know you always have.
And you're right, I often think of bag end.
I miss my books.
And my armchair and my garden.
See, that's where I belong.
That's home.
That is why I came back.
Cos, you don't have one.
A Home.
It was taken from you.
But I will help you
take it back if I can.
Out of the frying pan...
-And into the fire...run!
Quick to the trees. All of you.
Climb up, Bilbo. Climb!
They are coming!
Azog.
Fili.
Mr Gandalf. Help.
No.
Thorin.
Thorin?
The halfling?
-It's alright. Bilbo is here.
He is quite safe.
You.
What were you doing?
You know you could've got killed.
Did i not say that
you'd be a burden...
And you will not survive
in the wild...
And you have no place amongst us?
And I have never been so wrong.
All my life.
I'm sorry that I doubted you.
-No, I would've doubted me too.
I'm not a hero or a Warrior.
Or even a burgler.
Is that what i think it is?
Erebor.
The lonely Mountain.
The last of the great dwarf kingdoms
of Middle-earth.
Our Home.
A raven.
The birds are returning to the mountain.
That, my dear Oin, is a thrush.
We will take it as a sign..
a good omen;
You are right.
I do believe, that the worst is behind us.
Subtitle by :
d3xt3r (www.addic7ed.com)
- Happy New Year -