Jean Dujardin
Berenice Bejo
THE ARTIST
James Cromwell
Penelope Ann Miller
Malcolm McDowell
Missi Pyle
Beth Grant, Ed Lauter
Joel Murray, Ken Davitian
and John Goodman
Produced by
Thomas Langmann
Written & Directed by
Michel Hazanavicius
"I won't talk!
I won't say a word!!!"
"Speak!"
"SPEAK !"
Please, be silent
behind the screen
" Long live free Georgia !!! "
" I will get you for this. "
"A Russian Affair"
George Valentin
That's the question on
everyone's lips. Who indeed?
VARIETY:
WHO'S THAT GIRL?
KINOGRAPH STUDIOS
"Listen up! Three girls
who can dance !"
"The name's Miller.
Peppy Miller !"
"Clifton, go to the jewelry store. Get something
nice for my wife. To make it up to her."
"With all your nonsense, they don't
mention our movie until page 5 !"
"Where are you going, Miss?
We have a picture to shot."
"If you want to be an actress, you
need to have something the others don't."
And Peppy Miller
as Miss Isadora
"I have something to
show you."
"May I have my chair?!"
"Hey, you're not Napoleon.
You're just an extra!"
SOUND TEST
Constance Gray
in Romeo & Juliet
"Don't laugh, George!
That's the future."
"If that's the future,
you can have it!"
Kinograph Studios Stop All Silent Productions
To Work Exclusively On Talkies
"You and I belong to another era,
George. The world is talking now."
"People want new faces,
talking faces.'
"I wish it wasn't like this, but the public wants
fresh meat and the public is never wrong."
"I'm the one people come to see.
They never needed to hear me!"
"Make your talking movies. I'll make a great
movie. And it's not like I need you for that!"
THE NEW FACES
of KINOGRAPH
Peppy Miller
"Fresh meat..."
"What a coincidence, I was just thinking
about you. I signed with Kinograph!"
"Maybe now we'll do
another picture together!"
"Toys!"
"I'm not a puppet, I'm an artist!"
"Talkies are not serious"
for George Valentin
"We have to talk, George."
"Why do you refuse to talk?"
"I'm unhappy, George."
"So are millions of us."
"Your movie doesn't come out
until tomorrow and you're,
already Hollywood's new sweetheart!
How do you explain that?"
"I don't know. Maybe because I talk
and the audience can hear me."
"People are tired of old actors mugging
at the camera to be understood."
"Out with the old, in with the new.
Make way for the young!"
"That's the life!"
"I've made way for you."
STOCK MARKET
CRASH
"It looks like we've gone bust."
"Unless the movie is a big hit..."
"Hello. I wanted to
talk to you. I..."
"I just saw Tears of Love."
"And now want a refund?"
"Not too much mugging?"
"No. I'm sorry about last night.
I didn't mean what I said..."
"But you were right.
Make way for the young..."
"It's an honor to meet you.
My father is a big fan."
"Ok. We're going now.
I'll call you soon."
"Take me home.
I want to be alone."
"How long has it been
since I last paid you, Clifton?"
"One year, sir."
"You're fired."
"I'm not kidding, Clifton.
You're fired."
"Keep the car. And find
yourself another job."
"I don't want another job."
TO-NIGHT AUCTION SALE
Famed Hollywood Actor: George Valentin
"Congratulations! It's all sold,
you've got nothing left!"
"Excuse me, may
I trouble you one moment?"
"If anly he could talk!"
"Look what's become of you..."
"You've been stupid!
You've been proud!"
"GET BACK HERE,
YOU LOSER!!!"
"Oh my God! That's
George Valentin!"
"I'll get my car!"
"I'll say one thing, he
owes his life to that dog!"
"We're ready. Go get
Miss Miller."
"He's out of danger.
He needs rest now."
"He was clutching this. It was
hard to get it away from him."
"You think he could
rest at my house?"
"I have to be on the set at nine o'clock.
We're shooting a very important scene."
"Just think of it! *Sparkle of Love*,
starring George Valentin and Peppy Miller!"
"George is a silent movie
actor. He's a nobody now."
"What are you doing?"
"I won't work anymore.
It's either him or me."
"What I mean is, it's him AND
me! Or it's neither of us!"
"Hey, I'm blackmailing
you! Get it?"
"All right, send him
the damn screenplay."
"I work for Miss Miller now."
"Once again, she's
looking out for you."
"Beware of your pride, if I may say so sir.
Miss Miller is a good person, believe me."
"CLIFTON!"
"BANG!"
"I feel so bad. I only wanted to
help you, take care of you..."
"If only you would let
me help you, George Valentin."
"It's impossible, Peppy. I'm washed up.
No one wants to see me speak."
"There is one thing we
could try. Trust me."
Subtitles by
JimmyBG28