Check, please.
Look, Daddy,
a volcano.
It's very pretty.
Now drink up your volcano.
All right. We're going.
Mommy's waiting.
Daddy, please.
Just one more minute.
No. We're going.
Until I ended up
flatlining at the hospital.
But I survived. And instead
of letting that scare me,
I kept on going.
Until...
my first daughter
was born.
And now,
I look at my girls...
and my husband,
who has been standing
by me for so long.
Think which one
you're gonna pull out.
I always think, man.
No, you don't.
They didn't lock you up this time
'cause you're not 18 yet.
Next time, they're gonna
lock you up, brother.
Come on.
Well, you're not thinkin'.
Stealing might get you money,
you can tap
some cheerleader's ass,
you can show off riding
in some pickle-colored Thunderbird,
but tell me what's gonna happen if you
shoot a pregnant woman or an old man?
You know what'll happen?
The guilt will suck you
down to the bone.
Stealing ain't worth it.
Going to church,
reading the Bible...
and believing in Jesus, brother,
that's your ticket.
You think it's a fantasy, right?
Come here, man.
Get up. Come here.
See that truck? Beauty, isn't it?
I won it at a friend's raffle.
No shit. You know what?
It wasn't luck. It was Jesus
who wanted me to have that truck.
That's bullshit.
I bet you stole it.
Jesus gave me that truck.
And as He who gives
and He who takes away.
Right. He doesn't
give a shit about us.
Come back.
Take off the hat.
God even knows when a single
hair moves on your head.
You're wrong, Nick.
So, this is death's waiting room.
These ridiculous tubes.
These needles swelling my arms.
What am I doing
in this pre-corpse club?
What do I have to
do with them?
I don't know when
anything began anymore...
or when it's gonna end.
Who will be the first
to lose his life?
He, in the coma?
Or me?
All right.
You can get dressed now.
Your Fallopian tubes
are severely damaged.
It looks like you had
some kind of an infection...
that wasn't taken
care of properly.
We can try surgery, but I
have to tell you, I think,
the probabilities
are pretty slim.
Look.
Excuse me for asking this, but it's
important that you tell me the truth.
Have you ever
had an abortion?
Yes.
Any reason?
I had already separated from
my husband when I got pregnant,
and I...
No. I meant a medical reason.
My husband's dying.
I'm sorry?
Paul, my husband,
he's dying,
and I want to have his baby.
We can operate then and hope you get pregnant
within three or four months.
He's got one month left,
at most.
How'd it go?
Not good, Reverend.
In one ear,
out the other.
Be patient. All it takes is one
sheep in a thousand, Jack. Come on.
Afternoon, Reverend. Hey, Wolf, you still
having that birthday party Wednesday?
My place, brother.
Cool.
I may be late, Jack.
I have Bible class on Wednesday.
What the fuck
is wrong with you, man?
- I will hurt you, boy.
- Paul. Paul!
Back off.
I told you to think.
Fuck you!
Hit me!
Come on!
Leave it, Jack.
He's a kid, Jack.
- He's a punk, Reverend.
- No, he's a kid.
You think, Jack.
Those who are making decisions
that affect our life,
we must call out to God
to give them His wisdom.
Daddy's home.
I'll see you tomorrow, Tam.
I'll pick the boys up after school
if you want me to.
How's my queen?
And Hercules.
You don't have a queen.
Freddy, help me out.
I got the cooler from the
religious center. Good.
- Dad, are we gonna go buy a dog now?
- Help me out.
Freddy, we agreed no dogs.
Grab the other handle. Lift it up.
You said if I got good grades,
you'd buy me one.
Your sister has allergies,
and dog hair is bad for her.
Bad for her, not me.
Get me a dog.
Freddy, leave it alone. Well,
at least get me a hamster.
Well, we'll see.
We'll see.
You always say
you promise.
You back, motherfucker?
Lock down six!
Six down!
I win.
Age before beauty.
You're such
a sore loser.
Do you wanna go to the
Jacuzzi for a while? Shit.
No, I can't. Michael and the
girls are waiting for me already.
Well, call me later.
I'll call ya.
Cristina?
And you get away from leading
your family like a man of God...
ought to lead his family
in prayer...
and reading the word of God
and the things of God...
and bringing them to the
house of God,  Amen.
Then you're opening the door for the
devil to come in and slay your family.
Amen.
Jesus is our light.
Jesus is our hope.
Jesus is our forgiveness.
Jesus is the water
that quenches my thirst.
If you're saved
and you know it, say "Amen. "
Amen.
Everybody up on your feet.
Jesus is our light.
Hey, honey, I'm home.
Jesus, you scared me.
How are you feeling?
I feel great.
Have you been
smoking again?
For fuck's sake, Paul.
You know if they find out you're smoking,
they'll take you off the transplant list.
If I don't smoke,
I'll go fuckin'nuts.
Better nuts than dead.
Is that necessary?
I don't know
how the hell you get them.
Call an ambulance!
Baby!
Call a fucking ambulance!
Goddamn it!
Please, do something.
Come on, please.
Al, you want a Coke?
Jack, boss wants to talk to you.
He wants to see you now.
Come on. We both know
I'm not a caddie yet,
but I'm working at it.
And I'm learning, Brown.
Man, I swear to God,
I'm not going to let you down.
No, Jack, that's not the
problem. What's the problem?
The problem is some members have
started complaining about your tattoos.
I got a long-sleeved shirt. No, man...
No long-sleeved shirt...
You can't see it. Is gonna cover
that one on your neck right there.
You're gonna
start wearing a scarf.
Look, Jack. This club is for
people different from me and you.
No. You know, I don't drink.
I don't steal.
I'm clean.
Tell me, why me?
Look, I know you're clean.
That's why I hired you.
But this decision
comes from the administration.
If I don't follow through,
they're gonna fuck me too.
Look, I cut you
a hefty severance check,
and you can pick it up
on the way to the cashier's.
Try to understand.
Good.
So, is there any pain?
My head hurts a little bit.
That's normal. That's because
of the blood pressure medicine.
We'll get you something else
to make you feel better.
Thank you.
I brought...
...what you asked for.
Is that my heart?
The culprit.
Which one is he?
That's him
with the brown vest.
He's putting the bag
up on top right now.
You okay?
Come here.
I wanna kill him.
We have to kill him.
Thank you, Lord,
for keeping us together,
for filling us with love
and for giving us this meal.
Amen.
I got fired
from the club today.
'Cause of your
good pal Brown, right?
He had nothing to do with it.
It's mine!
- Believe that, Jack?
- Yes, I do.
Freddy, stop it.
Mommy, Freddy hit me in
the arm. Which arm, baby?
This one.
Jack, don't start.
Hold out your other arm
and let your brother hit you.
- Give me it!
- Jack, no!
Hold it out.
Whoever slaps you on the right
cheek, turn the other to him also.
Hit her.
Don't be afraid.
-  Jack, no! -
- Hit her!
Isn't that great. Wonderful.
Great parenting, Jack.
Good job.
It's okay.
He didn't hurt her.
There's no hitting
in this house.
Understand?
Get in the corner!
Do I put the chocolate chips
in now, Mommy?
That's right, honey,
and then stir.
Stir really quick.
Laura, put that back.
Come on.
When is Daddy coming? Soon. Now
let's get this finished, honey.
None for you.
No, Laura, stop it now.
Next Friday, ask Lupe
to stay the night.
I can't stay, 'cause I invited the
company managers over for dinner.
I fired her.
What, you fired her?
Why?
She made me feel
like a cripple.
Goddamn it, Paul.
So, now who's going
to cook for you?
Who's going to clean up after you?
Who's going to take care of you?
Who?
I can do it for myself.
You can do it
by yourself.
I can't do it anymore, Paul.
Really, I can't.
What are you doing?
I'm just... What?
What does it feel like I'm doing?
Don't. Don't.
You might hurt yourself.
I'm not gonna hurt myself.
Besides, I need you to...
I went to a fertility clinic.
Good, more doctors. Mary, I
can't have this discussion again.
No, this is a...
this is a specialist.
He said that with surgery,
I might get pregnant.
You need to donate sperm and then...
Mary, no.
I could take care of him.
But I can't.
So what's the point?
This is what I most want
in the world.
Do it for me, please.
This'll be $58.95.
Thank you.
Find everything you need, sir?
I'll have...
You know what?
I left my wallet.
Gonna be hot.
Great.
When does my brother
plan to show up?
He said he'll be back
by 6:00.
One hundred percent
pure golden lager.
You outta your mind?
Pretty much.
It's warm.
Well, if you wanna drink
lemonade all night...
Just give it here.
Give me...
Katie? Laura?
Where are you guys?
Hi, sweetheart, it's Dad. I was hoping
we could have lunch one day next week.
Give me a call.
Hi, honey.
I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything along the way...
Look, Daddy, a pigeon!
Girls, no, don't touch.
Laura, stop it.
Gimme a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
To send a message, press...
Hello.
Speaking.
What?
Where?
Stay here.
I'll be right back.
Now, Mary, you understand that even if the operation
is successful,
artificial insemination
doesn't always work.
It doesn't matter.
We want to try.
Paul?
Now, Paul
this is about
having a child.
And with your condition,
you know you probably
won't ever meet him.
Well, life goes on, right?
I'd like you to put on one of these
gloves to avoid contaminating the sample.
And try to make it
all land in the receptacle.
When you're done,
just leave it in here.
In case you need
a little inspiration.
Big boy, what are you doing?
You ready to party?
I'm here now.
There you go!
Good, come on. Come on!
Dr. Swann, call the operator.
Excuse me. My husband and
daughters were in an accident,
and I was told to come
here. What were their names?
Michael, Catherine
and Laura Peck.
Excuse me for a minute.
Cris.
What happened, sweetheart?
I don't know. They haven't
told me anything yet.
It's gonna be all right.
Everything will be okay. Don't worry.
Okay, what is the most important question
for safe sex?
What time does
your husband get home?
That's good?
His Highness has arrived.
Let's see
what he comes up with.
Serve up that chili.
It's 7:00. What are you gonna
make up this time... traffic?
You preaching the word? The entire
congregation has been waiting for you.
It's your party, remember?
What's wrong?
Have you been drinking?
No. You didn't drink again, did you?
I just ran over
a man and two girls.
You're lying, right?
I was driving home.
Took a turn...
a little too quickly.
I didn't see them crossing.
Can't you go any faster?
Baby, hold on.
I love you.
Deep breath.
Good.
- Your lungs are clear.
- I got a question for you.
Whose heart do I have?
I can't tell you.
It's hospital regulations.
Just like the donor's family
doesn't know your name either.
- But you know.
Yes.
This is your heart now. That's
all that should matter to you.
- I wanna know who saved my life.
- If you want, you can write...
an anonymous letter to the family
through the donor's association.
Personally, I think it's better
that you don't know.
Mrs. Peck?
I'm Dr. Jones.
What happened to my
family? Please, sit down.
No, I'm okay.
What happened?
Well, your husband and your
daughters were hit by a car,
and we had to perform
emergency surgery on your husband.
Your husband suffered
multiple skull fractures,
and we had to remove blood clots
from around the brain.
He's in critical condition, and we're
concerned that he's showing low brain activity.
What?
Is he gonna be all right?
We're doing the best we can.
And what about
my daughters?
Your youngest daughter
was brought in with severe bleeding.
She just wasn't able
to get here in time.
I'm very sorry.
They both died in the accident.
Where are they?
Mrs. Peck, your girls are here, and
you can see them if you like, but...
I wanna see them.
Mrs. Peck, I wouldn't recommend it.
I'm very sorry.
If you'll excuse us,
we have to get back
to Mr. Peck.
I'm very sorry.
We want dinner!
Marianne, we'd like
some dinner in here!
Tell Reverend John to stay.
Make sure no one notices and get everyone to leave.
What happened?
Trish, just do what I tell ya!
It's gonna be okay.
Come on.
Start the truck up.
Start the truck up. Pull
it in. Come on, baby.
Hey, Jack.
What are you
doing here, man?
Just came to pick up
my things, Brown.
Why don't you let me
buy you a couple of beers?
I don't drink, Brown.
How about a Diet Coke?
You know, I've been talking to a buddy
of mine about hooking you up with a job.
Been telling him
all about you.
So, what do you say? I've been
feeling shitty about what went down.
Come on.
I understand.
So, what do you say?
As you know, the doctors did everything
they could to save your husband's life,
but he has shown
no brain activity.
We're here to help you with some of the
final decisions that need to be made.
We have a patient...
who is gravely ill.
I'm here to give you some
information on organ donation.
Are you willing for your
husband to donate his heart?
- Can we discuss this another time?
- I'm afraid not.
I can give you time to discuss it, but this
is a decision that needs to be made soon.
Paul?
Paul, the beeper.
It's the hospital.
I think they've
got a heart.
Hello? Yes, I'm calling on
behalf of Mr. Paul Rivers.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Where do I
have to take him?
Good luck, my love.
Hello.
Does your shoulder
bother you?
Why? Because I was
watching you swim before,
and you have a wide stroke.
If you bring it in tighter,
you get a better glide.
Thanks for the advice.
Do you mind
if I join you?
- Actually, I was just leaving.
- Here you go.
Maybe just until you finish?
No. Maybe next time.
Did you know that eating alone can
cause kidney damage? And that's bad.
Well...
Okay, sorry.
Hello?
Hello, is Ana there?
What?
Is Ana there?
Hang on a sec.
Telephone.
Who was that?
Hi, honey, I'm on my way home. If you need me
to pick up anything along the way, let me know.
Look, Daddy, a pigeon!
Girls, no, don't touch!
Laura, stop it.
Gimme a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit.
Bye.
Did you go?
Are they dead?
I'm gonna turn myself in.
John says nobody saw you.
Nobody.
They don't know the license plate or what kind
of car. Some asshole even swears it was a cab.
Marianne, what would you do if
these were our children? Tell me.
But they're not.
It didn't happen to us.
No, it didn't happen to us.
It happened to me.
What the fuck do you gain
by turning yourself in?
It's my duty, Marianne.
No, Jack, your duty
is here with us.
With your family.
My duty's to God.
Please.
Marianne,
get outta my way.
Jack.
Buddy, right there! Yes!
My turn.
I think I better
go back to the hospital.
Hey, he deserves it.
I thought your doctor you're not supposed to eat that.
I'm making up
for lost time.
Lost time, not lost pounds.
We're gonna have to
send you back for liposuction.
Well, here's to all those
who didn't think I was going to die.
Hear!
To the first day of my new life.
Congratulations.
Cheers. It's good to have you home, man.
I knew you'd make it.
I told you.
I also have
an announcement to make.
I wanted to tell you that Paul
and I are going to be parents.
That's great.
There's a scary thought... Paul being a parent.
- You kept this real quiet.
- Have you told your parents yet?
We're going to be parents.
We just don't know when yet.
I'm going to have an operation, and then
we're going to try artificial insemination.
Terrific. Terrific.
Artificial insemination?
Professor, do your female students know
you no longer have lead in your pencil?
Come on!
Play nice!
Let's have more cake.
Let's pass the cake around.
Mr. Donneaud?
Mr. Rivers?
Thanks for coming.
Sorry I couldn't cancel this appointment, but
the way I'm bowling today, probably should have.
Have a seat here.
Park it right there.
Can I bring you
something to eat?
I'm not hungry. Honey,
you need to eat something.
I'm fine, Dad.
When your mother died,
I thought I wasn't going to make it.
I felt the world was falling on me
and that I was never going to get up.
But, sweetie,
life goes on.
You know what I thought
when Mom died?
I couldn't understand
how you could talk to people again.
How you could laugh... again.
I couldn't understand
how you could play with us.
And no...
no, that's a lie.
Life does not just go on.
Louise is getting fat,
don't you think?
She's done nothing but eat
since Robert left her.
What?
She looks okay to you?
Why did you tell everybody
we're having a baby?
I wanted to share
our plans with them.
That's what I mean,
they're our plans.
Why does everyone have to
know our private life?
Why the fuss?
They're our best friends.
But we haven't
even talked about it.
We haven't? I thought
this was more than settled.
Things change, Mary.
Something we have to
think about.
I don't have anything
to think about.
I've already
made my decision.
Would you help me
with the glasses?
So young.
You want me to stay
with you tonight?
I'm okay. Thanks.
I just wanna be alone.
Cris,
the police called.
They said you need to
go and press charges.
I'll go with you
if you want.
I'm not going to do anything.
This guy was...
was some ex-con.
Are you really gonna let him
just walk the streets?
What do you want me to do?
Well, he ran over
Michael and your daughters.
Nothing I can do
is going to bring them back.
Do you get that?
How you doin'?
You found it okay?
I did.
The donor's name was Michael
Peck. He was 37 years old.
An architect
and married.
This is the authorization for transplant
signed by his wife, Cristina Williams Peck.
I have a copy of the medical
report if you care to see it.
And I also have the widow's phone number
and address just in case you're interested.
How did Michael Peck die?
You might have seen it
in the newspaper.
This guy named Jack Jordan ran over
Mr. Peck and his two little girls...
October 10
at 6:50 p. m.
This Jack Jordan's a piece of work. He's
been in and out of jail since he was 16.
Car thief,
small-time crook, drugs,
bad checks, alcoholism.
Last time he was in jail
has only been a few years ago.
You feeling okay, Mr. Rivers?
This is what you wanted,
isn't it?
I just...
You want some water?
He was an architect.
What's the point
in getting involved?
Mary, I wanna know
who I am now.
I don't think
that's the way to do it.
What is then?
Look for it with me.
Let's look ahead together,
not behind.
Damn it, Jack, it's your birthday and
you didn't even have one drink with me.
Why don't you come over to my place?
I'm having a party.
I bet they're all
as boring as you are.
You'd be surprised.
No, man, I'll pass.
Listen, I'll call you later
about that job, okay?
All right, man.
All right.
Thank you.
Brown, you should.
I will.
Okay, now, we can schedule
the surgery
I could get you in
as early as Monday.
9:00 a. m?
What's the percentage chance
that Mary will get pregnant?
Well, I can't offer you
a real number on that.
You know, there's the
damage from the abortion...
that wasn't handled properly...
the blockage...
What abortion?
What abortion, Mary?
I can explain.
Explain what?
There is an explanation.
All that drama
about artificial insemination.
Kids' names.
You got pictures of our friends'
babies all over the place.
Why?
So you can flush it
down the fuckin' toilet?
We've been a fraud
for a long time, Mary.
Why didn't you tell
me that when you were sick?
Or did you expect one of your
girlfriends to come and take care of you?
You came back because you wanted
to. Don't blame me for that.
I came back to take care of you
because I love you.
Or because
you were feeling lonely.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I can't keep going like this.
The insemination,
the child.
It's like we're trying to put a Band-Aid
on something that's just been bled dry.
It's finished.
But it isn't finished if we
give it a chance and have this baby.
When we could have,
you didn't want to.
We were separated, goddamn it!
It's different now!
Yes, it's different.
We gonna go? You only know
how to think about yourself.
Close six!
Well, thanks
for finally seeing me.
They tell me
you don't want to eat.
I'm not hungry.
Jack, Jesus didn't come
to free us from pain.
He came to give us
the strength to bear it.
Maybe He wanted
this pain for me.
No, He had nothing to do with this.
It was an accident.
No, it wasn't an accident.
Jesus chose me for this.
Jack,
ask for the mercy
of Jesus Christ.
If it was an accident,
why do I have to ask
for His mercy?
"I will have mercy
on whom I will have mercy.
"I will have compassion
on whom I will have compassion.
- Don't be so prideful. That's a sin.
- "And the fearful and unbelieving.
"And the abominable, the murderers, the
warmongers,  Jack, listen to me.
"The sorcerers and the idolaters
and all liars...
Jesus came to save us, not to damn us.
"Shall have their part...
in the lake which burneth
with fire and brimstone. "
Revelation 21:8.
Jesus, loves you.
But He also knows how to punish
arrogant sinners like you.
"As many as I love, I rebuke
and chaste. " Revelation 3:19.
- Jesus betrayed me.
- Stop this shit, or you're going straight to hell!
Hell?
This is hell.
Right here!
You're damning your soul!
You shut up now...
and ask Christ to forgive you!
Forgive me?
I did everything He
asked me to do! I changed!
I gave Him my life,
and He betrayed me.
He put that fucking truck in my hand
so I could carry out His will.
Made me kill that man
and those girls.
He didn't give me the
strength to stay and save them.
Don't blaspheme, you bastard!
Christ had nothing to do with this!
God even knows when a single
hair moves on your head.
And you taught me that.
We're gonna pray
for you, Jack.
Good evening, sir.
Excuse me.
Using discrepancy, lyric weaponry
lessens your chances of testing me
Stop and freeze M.C.'s
I block atrocities
Philosophies from the lips
of black Socrates
The pocket-penciler
in your peninsula
Killing Dracula M.C. 's
who bit from my vernacular
I can back it
The ill scene we occupy
No lullaby, got you high
when I rock a fly
Verse, for my people
let me breathe slow
Give a heave-ho
and stimulate your cerebral
System, cut chemist grip the fader
Tuna the group debater
Just like old times?
How the hell
have you been?
Did you end up marrying that hunk
you brought around here last time?
Is he a good lay?
How they make us suffer?
It's all right.
I got some great candy for you.
I got Special "K,"angel dust.
I got your all-time favorite.
And I got the newest
of the new... R-2.
This shit is all the rage.
You take two of these,
- you go straight to heaven.
- I'm not into chemicals.
Cristi, you're not
a cuddly little kitty now, are you?
Look, if you don't like 'em,
you don't pay for 'em.
That's my girl.
It's busy.
Go easy on the booze
tonight, right?
What the fuck?
What the fuck
are you doing?
Would you get my car keys? Sure.
- What do you care, asshole?
- I can get you a cab.
- I don't need a fuckin' taxi.
- Just give me the glass, ma'am.
Here's your fuckin' glass.
You okay?
Stupid fucking asshole, move your car!
I'm fine. Get away from my car!
There's no damage. I'm
fine. Get away from my car.
There's no damage.
Excuse me, I know her. I can drive her home.
Is this any of your business? I'm
your friend Paul from the sports club.
Remember?
Well, can you tell these
assholes to get away from me?
I'll drive her home.
It's not a big deal, okay?
Okay. All right?
You can't drive like this.
What do you care?
You're gonna get arrested.
Let me drive you.
Please?
Damn it.
I sold the truck
to pay for the lawyer.
I didn't ask for a lawyer.
You want your children to spend
another two years without you?
Is that what you want?
This is God's will.
So be it.
Two years ago,
you didn't believe in anything.
Now everything
has to do with God.
I think I preferred you
the way you were before.
I was a fucking pig before.
Is that what you prefer?
At least it was you.
Now I don't have the slightest
fucking idea who you are.
Life has to go on, Jack,
with or without God.
How you doin'?
How are you?
Fine. Were you able
to find anything out?
Jack Jordan's living in a cheap motel
lost out in the middle of nowhere.
Phone records.
One of his prison fishy pals
is from there.
- That was quick.
- Just a matter of checking the calls.
Phone number and address
for the motel he's living in.
Here's a pretty recent photo
of Jordan.
It was taken the last time
he was in jail.
Were you able to get that other
thing that I asked about?
This is a clean gun, no record.
They call this an "orphan. "
It is loaded.
Careful there, Hoss.
You don't have to cock it. Just pull the
trigger to shoot it. This releases the cylinder.
I think we're set to go.
That's all I want to know.
Thank you.
Good luck to you.
Ma'am, it's been an hour
since I called.
Forty-six St. Vincent Street.
Thank you.
Some rain.
Do you not have your car? No, but
my taxi will be here in a minute.
I'm right over here.
I'll give you a lift if you like.
No. Thanks.
I'm the guy who drove
your car home last week.
I'm sorry.
I don't remember.
I left my jacket with you.
I'm sorry.
I'll bring it by tomorrow.
Sure I can't give you a ride?
I'm right here.
Or do you want to swim?
Hello.
Thanks.
You're very welcome.
Let me just give you my cell
phone number so you can have it.
Would you have
lunch with me tomorrow?
What for?
You're gonna have to eat at some point,
and I'm very worried about those kidneys.
Come on. Lawrence's, 2:00.
It's very nearby.
Please. Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
Great.
... report we have construction on the ramp
coming from southbound 240 at Summer.
That ramp is closed until 6:00 p. m.
Use Arlington Pike as an alternate.
Forty at the new bridge,
they have the center lane closed.
Use southbound I-20 as an alternate.
Safe Driving believes so strongly in minimum coverage.
They're easy, fast, affordable and reliable.
They're serious about minimum coverage.
1- 800-SAFE-DRIVING.
Minimum coverage is the best option...
Look, Daddy, a pigeon!
Daddy, look!
Girls, no, don't. Don't touch it.
Laura, stop it.
Gimme a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
Good night, Mr. Peck.
Lucio, don't forget to do my garden
on Saturday. No, sir, I won't forget.
Son of a bitch.
Leave it to me, Marianne.
Sometimes it happens, sometimes it
doesn't. Everybody reacts differently.
That's why you've been
vomiting so much.
So, what are you saying,
I've got to change medication?
I'm gonna be
frank with you, Paul.
The heart that you're carrying
is gonna give out soon.
I need you to stay in the hospital
until I can find you another heart.
You want me to wait for a new heart.
We don't have another choice.
I can't do that. I can't wait for someone
else to die, locked up in a fucking room.
I can't do it.
- You're dangerously close to heart failure, Paul.
You might die a lot sooner
than you think.
Let me ask you something, and I want
you to be really honest with me, okay?
If I stay...
will I be saved?
I can't guarantee it.
But if you don't
come back to the hospital,
you're condemning yourself
to a terrible death.
Your heart won't work anymore.
You'll die, asphyxiated.
It's an awful death, Paul.
You can't imagine it.
At least here we could help you to...
You can help me die better.
That's what you're saying.
Well, I'm not gonna do that, okay?
I'd rather die outside.
I'm not gonna do it again.
How much did the lawyer charge?
Marianne, how much did the fucking
lawyer charge?  Enough.
How much is enough,
Marianne?
Enough so your children can
remember your fucking face.
You keep asking stupid questions,
I'm getting out at the next corner.
Hi, guys. We're home.
Daddy! Daddy!
What'd you bring us?
I brought you a kiss.
You didn't bring me a
present? No, just a kiss.
We made you a cake.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Freddy put the icing on it.
Freddy, are you gonna
say hello to your father?
Freddy drew those for you.
I drew those ones.
Mommy made the cake.
Come here.
Come look at the cake, Daddy.
She did?
Come on, Daddy.
There is a number hidden in every act
of life, in every aspect of the universe.
Fractals, matter... that there's a
number screaming to tell us something.
Am I boring you?
I'm sorry.
I guess I try to tell them
that numbers are a door...
to understanding a mystery
that's bigger than us.
How two people, strangers,
come to meet.
There's a poem by
a Venezuelan writer that begins...
"The earth turned
to bring us closer.
"It turned on itself and in us...
until it finally brought us
together in this dream. "
That's beautiful.
There's so many things that have to
happen for two people to meet and...
Anyway, that's...
that's what mathematics are.
How long have you been swimming?
For years.
It doesn't bore you? No. It's
what makes me feel normal.
If I didn't swim or walk or do
something, I think I'd go crazy.
Thanks for lunch.
Do you want to come in?
No.
Thanks...
Yes, I do want to come in.
Can I ask you...
I have a gun.
Don't look at me. Don't look at me.
Don't look at me. I'll shoot...
- I don't have any money.
- Turn around. I'll shoot you. Just turn around. Go.
- I don't have any...
- Walk!
Put 'em up! Put your hands up!
Why?
- Wait.
-  Just walk. Go!
We're gonna go down that path right there.
Do what I say and then you won't get hurt.
- I don't have any...
- Go!
I'm not looking. Come on. Keep
walking. Go right down here.
Just keep walking. Keep walk... I said
don't look at me. I'll shoot you in the head.
Keep your hands up!
Walk! Over here.
Over here.
Come on, don't look at me.
Keep going!
Right
Turn around. But keep your hands on your head.
Get... Take your shoes
off and get down on your knees.
Take off your shoes.
No, not that... not that one.
- Just get down on your knees! Get down on your knees!
Sir, please.
You shouldn't have done it.
Done what?
You shouldn't have done it!
Close your goddamn eyes!
She looked me in the eyes.
What are you talking about?
One of the girls that I killed,
she looked me in the eye.
She wanted to tell me something.
I just... I left her there.
I ran away.
You sticking with red?
Sure.
Are you okay?
Sorry. Dizzy.
Can I get you a glass of water
or something?
I think I should go home.
I'm sorry. I just...
I like you a lot, Cristina.
It's been a long time since
I liked someone so much.
Can I see you again?
I'm a married woman.
I figured.
Thanks.
Good-bye.
I've got peace like a river
-   I've got peace like a river in my soul
- Everybody!
I've got love like an ocean
in my soul
I've got joy like a fountain...
I've got joy like a fountain
in my soul
- Look, Daddy. These are the zebras, these are the lions.
- Very pretty, Gina.
How could you draw a zoo if you've
never been to one? I've seen them in...
Stop fighting.
The lawyer called to remind you
you have to go sign on Monday.
If you want, I'll go with you to the church again.
Daddy, in school they said...
you killed two girls
and their daddy.
Is that true?
Yes.
- No.
- Yes.
- He killed them.
- It was an accident, sweetie.
You understand?
Jesus, every time
I look at my children...
Who is this?
Did I wake you?
Hang on a second.
No, that's okay.
Could you come
to my house?
Is something wrong?
No, I just...
I just want you to come
if you can.
Or if you want to.
I'll be right there.
Thanks.
It's 2:00 in the morning.
Who are you talking to?
I won't be long.
Where are you going?
I said I won't be long. Exactly
where and with who are you going?
I thought you'd change
after the transplants.
And I thought you'd change
if I did. Neither of us changed.
What's wrong?
He's been shot in the chest.
-  Come on.
- Shot in the chest.
He's been shot in the chest.
Come on.
- How long's he been like that?
- He's dying, okay? We need a...
I'll go get a stretcher.
- Ma'am, he'll be right back.
- It's okay.
Hang in there, baby.
I shot him.
-  You did what?
- I shot him.
Patrol, I need you
to call the police.
It's an emergency, yes.
I'm right out front.
Are you okay?
Cristina?
You kept me thinking all day.
You see, I haven't spoken
to anyone in months,
and I barely know you...
and I already
need to talk to you.
And...
there's something the more I
think about, the less I understand.
Why the hell did you tell me
that you liked me?
Answer me, because I didn't
like you saying that at all.
You can't just walk up to a woman you
barely know and tell her you like her.
You-You can't.
You can't do that.
You don't know
what she's going through.
Or what she's feeling.
I'm not married.
Come here.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
No.
Cristina, wait.
I have to tell you something.
Please, kiss me.
Wait. Cristina.
I have Michael's heart.
What...
You understand what I'm saying?
It was transplanted into me at
St. Francis Hospital on October 11.
No. No.
I tried to tell you. I just
didn't know how to tell you.
How dare you! Cristina...
How fucking dare you!
I'm here for a reason.
Get out of my house!
Don't touch me!
Get out of my house now!
You make me sick!
I had a reason.
Can't you see that?
You get out of my fucking...
Get the fuck out of my house!
You make me sick!
Get out!
Good morning.
Why did you look for me?
Because I needed to.
I don't want your fucking pity.
That wasn't it.
I was sick, Cristina.
I was very sick.
I was dying when Michael
gave me his heart.
He saved my life.
I tried in every way that
I knew how to find out...
who had given me this heart.
And that's how I found out how
he and your daughters had died.
And it's very painful for me
to know how I got this heart.
And I couldn't sleep.
I just... I wanted to thank you.
I wanted to help in some way.
I just want to
thank you for...
But I couldn't find you.
And then I saw you...
that day.
And now I can't
be away from you.
I can't.
You don't have to be afraid.
I've got a good heart.
I'm scared too.
Why did you leave us, Jack? Why?
I am where I have to be.
Gina got really sick because of the hamster.
Jack, we need you... The past is like the Atlantic Ocean.
Back when I was mean,
about the decisions I make,
that's my mirror.
Just come back, please.
That's my mirror.
Jack, it doesn't matter.
And I have to live with them alone.
Alone. Just come back to us, Jack.
And I can't erase it. No one can
erase it. Your family needs you.
We need to stabilize him before
we can get him to the hospital.
But right now what we really need
are units of B-positive blood.
I'm O-positive.
Will that work?
Open and close your fist
several times.
Unit 35, go ahead.
Pal, you're free to go
for lack of evidence.
Your story doesn't check out
and contradicts our investigation...
and the statements made by
Mrs. Peck and Mr. Rivers.
I just need you to sign here.
What if I really am guilty?
Well, it happens.
Won't be the first time,
won't be the last.
What are you doing?
You've been lost for too many days,
don't you think, you prick?
Mary, I don't want to fight.
I want this to end well.
You think ending well means
disappearing for a few days?
You just waited till you got better
to tell me to fuck off.
I'm going back to London.
We can't keep doing this.
Really?
I'll have surgery and I'll be inseminated
with your child, with or without you.
Mary, what for? Why?
Because I want to.
Well, I won't authorize
that. No.
Well, you already have.
I have a signed copy of your authorization
to use your semen.
Would you excuse me? I get what I want.
What do you gain? What do you gain?
You decide if you come
looking for me or not.
Hi, honey.
I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything along the way, let me...
Girls, no! Don't touch!
Laura, stop, it.
Gimme a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit.
Bye.
To repeat the message, press one.
To delete, press two.
Hi, honey.
I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything along the way, let me...
Girls, no! Don't touch!
Laura, stop, it.
Gimme a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
I'm grilling some chicken.
You want anything to eat?
No. Thanks.
I can make you a sandwich if you...
Listen to me.
You don't need that shit.
You don't need it.
Don't tell me what I need.
Katie could have lived.
What?
She'd be alive right now,
but that bastard left her there...
lying in the street.
He left the three of them
like animals. He didn't care.
At least she could
be here with me.
That son of a bitch is walking the streets,
and I can't even go into their room.
What do you mean
he's walking the street?
I want to kill him.
You want to kill him?
I'm gonna kill Jack Jordan.
I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
Slow down. Wait.
Just slow down.
Slow down? Slow down while
I what? While I what?
Take it easy.
My husband and my little girls are dead
and I'm supposed to take it fucking easy?
I can't just go on
with my life!
I am paralyzed here! I am a
fucking amputee, do you see that?
Who are you?
You owe it to Michael...
No, you've got his heart.
You're in his house fucking his wife
and sitting in his chair!
We have to kill him! No, we...
Not like this. Not like this.
Then how?
Tell me how!
Katie died
with red shoelaces on.
She hated red shoelaces.
And she kept asking me
to get her some blue ones,
and I never got her
the blue ones.
She was wearing those fucking
red shoelaces when she was killed.
You shouldn't have done it!
Close your goddamn eyes!
You... murderer.
You just let them
lie there on the street.
Those two little girls,
you just let them die like dogs.
I should have killed you.
Now you disappear. Don't even go
back to the motel and get your things.
Just disappear.
Mrs. Peck.
How is he?
We weren't able to use
your blood for his transfusion.
We found very high levels of illegal substances
in your blood. You're taking very high risks here.
Well, that's my problem. In your state,
I suggest you stop using these substances.
What are you talking about?
You're pregnant, Mrs. Peck.
You sure? You really need to start
taking care of yourself, Mrs. Peck.
We'll let you know when
Mr. Rivers is out of the O.R.
Where were you?
Did you kill him?
Did you?
Why didn't you wake me up?
Where's the body?
Nobody will ever
find the body.
I'm sorry.
We're gonna go home now.
Let's just get
out of here, okay?
You okay?
It's okay, baby.
Just lie down.
Need rest. I need rest. I know.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
Wake up.
There's somebody outside.
You want to kill me?
What's he doing here?
Here I am.
Shoot me.
Go ahead. Kill him. Paul.
Do something!
Call an ambulance.
Call a fucking ambulance!
How many lives do we live?
How many times do we die?
They say we all lose 21 grams...
at the exact moment of our death.
Everyone.
And how much fits
into 21 grams?
How much is lost?
When do we lose 21 grams?
How much goes with them?
How much is gained?
Twenty-one grams.
The weight
of a stack of five nickels.
The weight of a hummingbird.
A chocolate bar.
How much did 21 grams weigh?
One last kiss
One only
Then I'll let you go
Hard for you
I've fallen
But you can't break my fall
I'm broken
Don't break me
When I hit the ground
Some devil
Some angel
Has got me to the bones
You said always and forever
Now I believe you, baby
Is such a long
and lonely time
Too drunk and still drinking
It's just the way I feel
It's all right
Is what you told me
'Cause what we had
was so beautiful
But I feel heavy
Like floating
At the bottom of the sea
You said always and forever
Now I believe you, baby
Is such a long
and lonely time
Some devil is
stuck inside of me
I cannot set it free
I wish, I wish I was dead
And you were grieving
Just so that you could know
Some angel is
stuck inside of me
But I cannot set you free
You said always and forever
Now I believe you, baby
Such a long, lonely time
Stuck inside of me