Pan Singh has killed 9 people
He took his brother's vengeance and
police can't do anything
What police will do?
Give the cigarette
Hold it!
How did you get this attitude?
You looks so angry
You haven't seen my attitude
Read tomorrow's newspaper
If I my photo didn't pubish
then feed me with a dog
You have joined Pan Singh Group
How do you know that?
Don't tell anyone
He is journalist
Yes!
You didn't tell anyone?
No!
He is a solider
He is very panctual
Till the job done your kid will
stay with us
You stay here with your uncle
I will be back in few minutes,
I will get you some sweets
You show them a picture
Take care of her
Keep it
My kid will be fine
It depends on your intentions
Journalist is here
I am taking out my copy
You were putting your hand in the
pocket like you will take out the bomb
I am sitting downstairs
Sit here!
You have any problem to sit
on the floor
You are younger than me
You are Major Chauhan's nephew
He is my uncle
Why you didn'tjoin the army
I like to writing
If I will have your blessing then
one day
I will become a famous journalist
It's not a hard working job that's
why you are so fat
From tomorrow take a run of 4 k.m.
Say properly from tomorrow
From tomorrow
Shall we start?
How did you become dacoit?
You have become complete journalist
or you are on training
You are from this area and
you didn't know
Only Rebels are in Bihar
Dacoits are in Parliment
It's over
I am sorry
When did you pick up the gun for
the first time
English people leave this country
After that
Pandit Jee became a Prime Minsiter
And along with Free India I have
started my carrier
He is my son
He joined the army
That's why I am telling you I didn't
forgot anyone
You should have think about
your wife
Shall I get something to eat or
you will just asking questions to me
Let me help you
Leave it
I am addicted to live alone
Don't spoil my habit
If you're addicted so I'll go back
Go! Here you will go and I will
jump into the wall
You are sitting here
You run so fast
like a cock
Show me your face
You also thought that I am dead
Why you are saying like that?
I have showed your fortune
Priest said that you are not gonna
stay a single place longer
I knew that...
Whatever it takes but you will
must come back to me
It's Army not a government office that
you will join anytime
How did you came late 2 days?
My mom was sick
I had to get marry
Army first then family
And what about you?
My fields were prepared
How could I leave that
So I won't let you stand
Get your bags and take 10 rounds
10 Rounds are over
You think I am a fool
I ran little fast and I have no
problem to run
I will see,
Take another 10 Rounds
With or without luggage
Your name Rakesh!
Who is he?
He is new recruit Pan Singh Tomar
I can see for the first time that
someone is enjoying his punishment
It's 37 rupees
How would you spend a month
in 2 rupees
Military is looking after me
My wife got a daughter
Congratulations!
Now I will have to look after her
You live for eating or you eat
for living
We have food for living
and poison for eating
Want some?
It's Betallion not a wedding
Meal is fixed you will
kill everyone with hunger
What should I do if I my diet is
like that
Join Sports they have no problem
for food
British left two good things for us
Discipline
and Second Ice cream
I have ordered for you
Ice cream will be melt down when
I will reach home
Take me in sports
I've heard they have food problem
What do you play?
I can play anything in fact
I run so fast
What is that?
Take this icecream to his house
without melting down
and you will be in sports,
Give me the address
Major has send it
You can check it's not
melted down
what's the time?
It's 9
Tell him that you have got
it in 4 minutes
Not to read mantras but I shoot
to run
He was the man who brought
icecream in 4 minutes
Congratulation!
You are on second position
But he says he wants to join sports
for food
He is not such interested in sports
My dad fought with british and he
sent me here to join Military
to serve my country
I can't use the gun
Why you can't fire a bullet
Hold it on your shoulder close
your one eye
Take aim pull the trigger and
bullet is fired
What's going on here?
He is new in army and I am
teaching him firing
He is new and you were
born here
I have old relationship
with the gun
Then show me your aim
Get up!
Where you from?
Chambal!
Dacoit's Area
Not dacoit but rebel
My uncle is a rebel
He have respect
Police couldn't arrest him till yet
You have told that your uncle
is a dacoit
Not dacoit he is a rebel
He is a nice person
Only Answer the question
It's not in records
But have you ever been imprisoned
for some crime
Nor me nor my uncle
Police couldn't arrest him
What did I said?
Only answer the question
Do you believe in Government
Government is a theif
that's why I joined the army
In this country except army everyone
is a thief
Can you sacrify your life
for the country?
Yes and I can take life
Country is like our mom
and if somebody will try to hert my
mom so I won't sit quite
Army means discipline
You will have to obey your
senior's orders
Will you obey any order?
I am fourth standard failed
I have read man more than books
Now an officer like you will
give the order
then I will put my life
Few officers are bettallion are useless
Now if they will give me the orders
then I will have to think about it
Sir!
I will talk to him
I still have doubt
Did I say something wrong
You wait outside
Have you seen his attitude
His uncle is a Rebel
Army officers are useless
I have an idea
We will send him to Army Physical
Training Centre
He will run over there
And his entire anger will come
out to the land
We should use his hot temper
You haven't seen him running
Did you take bath?
Did you finish your Warm-up?
I will do it
Let's start the race
You will always be illetrate
You didn't learn anything in city
Breaking records mean...
First position in race
How do I know?
Leave me!
What are you doing?
Now they are sending me to foriegn
Tokyo Japan
And Asia's famous Athletes are
coming there
What should I bring you
from tokyo
You are going abroad
When you run in shorts
I really don't like that
All women looks at you
But they won't allow me to run
in pents
And what if I will bring a lady
then where will you jump down
because there is no well here
I will lay down on railway track
What if I will kill you
Is it necessary to wear?
Yes it is...
Long iron rods are under these shoes
how would I run?
These are called spikes
India's Athletes will run
without spikes
Then why you didn't gave on
practice time
Now you are telling me wear them and
run in competition
So what World will say that India
doesn't have shoes for it's Athletes
Look at other countries athletes
What should I see?
They got lot of food to eat
They got all the facilities
You gave me two eggs and said
bring the medal
What are you trying to say?
I have said less but assume it more
Don't try to be a leader
Wear these shoes
take God's name and get ready
You will must win
And that day I lost that race
I still have regret for that
It always will be
My shoes took my respect
I don't understand anything
You deal with her
What's your name?
She loves you
He brought lot of dirty clothes
He didn't bring the medal
Once I felt I should stay there
then what stopped you?
Your breads...
I don't know what she will feed me
You just missed my breads...
They are not going anywhere
Both of you sit here
I am telling you they are
not going anywhere
Don't be hurry to give your
measurements take your time
I have put my kids on job
You really decide to bring that
Japanese girl here
You don't like my races but she
loved me racing
What are you doing?
Time has come
to show your courage
and to sacrify on your country what
any soldier waiting for
Which body we have made steel
time has come to use it
They have started the war but
we will win this war
And we took swear of this land
Before giving our lives
We will take ten enemies lives and
we will become a martyr
What happen?
Why are you shouting this morning?
What's this?
Soils are ours and how did
you get it
It's stealing
Since when you have become
a police officer
Nor soils are your nor fields
It's mine
Take any legal action
Look! Don't talk about legal actions
that's not good for anyone
That's my field give it
back to me
I am the owner of that land
I gave money to Matha Deen
He sold his own fields
So he sold his own fields
that's my fields
We had a partition in fields
Go to the Munciple office and find out
who is the owner
Call any court
If I will get angry then I will kill
you here and decide it
What will you decide?
Tell me what will you decide?
Don't show me your guns I have
seen many guns
I am Pan Singh speaking
Nothing is good
I am in trouble
Me relatives snatched my soils
It's been two years
Your brother is a collector tell
him to make a call
He is lying
Land is on my name
He was a labour on that land
It's written on papers that
who is lying
Matha Deen must sold his land
but I didn't
He gave money to munciple officer
and he transferred the entire
land on his name
Entire land is mine
But you and Bhanwar Singh
are relatives
We are cousins
that's why he is still breathing
You are also still breathing for
that reason
Bhanwar Singh's problem
didn't solved yet
That's why he came here
He will solve this case right now
You are a soldier
Country needs you
You shouldn't die for nothing
Collector is sitting here
Show some respect to him
After checking Pan Singh's papers
it seems that land is his property
And you have so many lands
Why are you fighting for small land?
Finish this matter...
They have seven licensed guns and
my family is in danger
Until the judgement didn't come take
the custody of his guns
I came here for Masam's call
You solve this issue by your self
You can do it
They are becoming brave with guns
You're a soldier and afraid from guns
Fight with me hand to hand
It's Chmaba's blood
Your dad never went to war
If you like to fight a war
We have a huge family and if we
all pee together
then you will sink down
Why are you breaking your own hands
to beat him
Shoot him and the matter is over
Leave him!
If his father will do something
What will he do?
He will go to police station
His father knows only one thing
Running!
If he would have courage
then he wouldn't carry a gun
in these years
Tomorrow we will kill Pan Singh
in his own house
Entire village should know...
Stay here!
Your blood has become water
How long it will run
If you don't want then I will
teach him lesson today
Drop your gun here
Nothing will happen with this gun
My son's blood won't come back
What about our respect
We won't kill anyone
Army assume us country's saviour
Police will listen to us
What's the proof that you are
the same person
Who is chasing who?
Nobody is chasing anyone
It's a race of 3000 metres
It's the toughest race
What's the proof?
Here is the proof
It's me
Why people wear short clothes
in foriegn country?
You must have enjoyed that view
Tell me how did you go there?
From train or plane?
How do I tell you?
My son is in danger
I have won many medals...
I have served this country
I was a National Champion
Now nobody is listening to me
We don't deal in land case
until few people won't die
What we will do there
I am telling you that they have
beaten my son alot
He is bleeding
and he can't move
But he is still breathing
He didn't die yet
When he will die then I
should come
I have run useless races for country
So you got the medals
Yourjob is to protect the citizens
Not to make breads on dead bodies
Mom is calling you
She is not feeling well
I told you to escape
Now police will kill you
We all will be trap
Everybody listen to me
It's Pan Singh Tomar's Gang
My vengeance is not completed yet
I have not got peace yet
I will be back
Game has just begin
Why you talk like illetrate people
Surrender yourself, finish your
punishment and join coaching here
I should come tomorrow
But after me...
They won't spare my family
Only we both know what's my
relationship with sports
or God knows...
How police will understand it
They have got another Rebel
to discuss in beer bar
He is my nephew
He is innocent
If he will join the army
Why don't you take him to
your gang?
Nobody wants to be a Rebel
We will never meet again
You will get our news
He is a noble man he can't kill a fly
How could he kill a man
Listen to me
We will spare you
Just tell us that where is Pan Singh
He is lying
Make him sit on stick
I am asking you for the last time
tell me where is Pan Singh
What should I tell you?
What happened with us?
Police can arrest us anytime
to ask your whereabouts
Where do we go?
We have arranged few
police uniforms
When uncle was looking for you so
you were having fun
And now police caught you so
you came here
Now Uncle should get you in army
Take us in your gang
If you will become a rebel so
you will die
We won't live there
Have you ever eat hot Ghulab Jamun
in ice cream
I never taste it before
Pick up the bowl
I also have that ice cream what
British made
but the best icecream is made
by Germany
You came to city after so long
that's why you didn't know
So all relatives made a gang
How much is that?
Where did you get the weapons?
We buy them
She will only sing,
Extra charge for other things
You go there
Make an atmosphere I will
just bring the money
Give it back to her
Don't do cheap things
What will you do with this money?
Inform his family members
that we need 125000 cash and if they
will informm the police
then your son won't be alive
Tell Gowardhan to inform his family
You sit here
What are you doing?
If he will try to escape
He can't run faster than me
Put him on some work
He won't get meal for free
Make him cook for entire gang
You have made it wrong
Did you arrange the money?
I have put my all efforts
You will get your son for 125000
I can't arrange more than that
Put your tears of 50000
If Pan Singh will be emotional so
he will spare your son
Now everything is in your hand
That won't work
You will have to make river
of your tears
Remember that Pan Singh
shouldn't be angry
Otherwise I am not responsible of you
and your son
I couldn't arrange 125000
I have sold my house and I could
arrange only 75000
You can search my house
We know he is very clever
Look I am a Rebel not a
businessman
Give me what you have and you son
will come home after one week
If you will inform the police
How could I dare to inform the police
May I tell him where I get
you from?
He was watching dance and I got
him from there
You didn't pay your duty
I am a Rebel and I didn't forgot
my duty
You are a statue ofjustice
I have small kids
Here is your uniform
Now if you will ever wear this uniform
then I will kill you
You are not good for this uniform
Uniform! Please forgive me
You are not good to appologize it
Now go from here
Where are you running?
You can't run faster than me
Now tell me
Where are your protectors?
And where is your licensed gun?
I have such a small land
Please forgive me
Take your land back and take mine too
What my mom has done with you?
You have beaten her with
your gun
You have beaten my old mom
with your gun
I won't die with a single bullet
Let me go!
I don't have shortage of bullets
or my aim is bad
I am an International Athlete
Please forgive me
What mistake I have done
that you have snatched my playground
And you people have made me
carry this gun
Now I am running in Chambal
Who will answer that question?
I know to run
I will run my entire life
Why you are always in hurry?
We are discussing our problems here
And you have killed him
Drop your guns
I will come up and ask the question
My vengeance has completed
But your enemies are over in Bihar
but not enmity
And one day we got an incident
that's why I am telling you
my story
You gave me respect for believing in me
Your arrangements are great and this
village is also good
Whenever I pass from here I came here
Gang is so big and police is everywhere
I don't wanna be a burden on you
If you will stop respecting us then...
I have heard that police is
on petrolling
Until petrolling is not over we
will stay here
Have it!
It's very sweet
Don't call Raam's name either he
shouldn't come to get you
You go from here
I won't let you die
I am finished,
I will take you out from here
Did you ever run in race?
Race has a rule
Once race has started
then whatever your position is
You will have to finish the race
Finish line is so far away
you will have to touch it
So I will finish my race whether I
win or lose
You know your race
What's the important thing that
you have to go
I am missing him so I thought
I should go and meet him
You are going alone I am not
feeling good
Police is searching me in Bihar so
I am going to the city
And police is searching for
entire gang
that's why it's not good for us
to stay together
Everyone make a group of 3-4 persons
and get seperated
We will meet after one month
Except your gang member
don't trust anyone
It's height is so high
Pan Singh practiced on this height
I am notjust your papa
You are looking like a soldier
You looks week
I am getting old
I have heard that you are
getting married
I have seen the girl
She have four brothers...
You have any problem with my name
They are agreed with this marriage
because of you
In their family nobody's photo has
published in newspapers
My defammed worked for you
How is your mom?
She is worried about you
I thought I have come to meet you so
I should send a message to her
You will have a problem to
meet me
If you are scared then I will leave
You surrender yourself
You have no other choice
You mean I should admit that
I made a mistake
and now you will forgive me
and I should renounce a surrender
rebel all my life
Why don't you ask them a question
who made us rebel
First they should surrender then
I will surrender
I am leaving now
I am taking this photo
Why did you came here?
I just came here to see your anger
Who knows I will get a chance
again or not
I was missing everything...
So what's your priest said to
see my horoscope
He said you will surrender
Your priest is a fake
Do you know the meaning
of surrender
Your priest is fake he just said
it to make you happy
You don't worry it's just for a while
everything will be fine
When you will come again?
Will you surrender?
Your priest meant to surrender
something else
And sooner or later everyone
will have to surrender
Fetch me some water
Caste is nothing
Human should help another human
You never says wrong
Gopi is in Pan Singh gang his
in laws are here
Did he came here?
Yes he used to come here
He is coming in wedding here
Let me meet him if he will come again
That will be better for both of us
Get a police job for my son
then it will be better for me
You have said it and it's done
Job is important
It should be done soon
It will be done
You really worried about me
I am telling you let's go
to Rajhistan
Why do you love Rajhistan?
Do you have any keep there
We will cross the border and
go to U. P
What's wrong to stay for a while
Are you tired?
I have got some sweets
Let's have it and leave
You eat first
Not this one
Eat this one
I have got it from the wedding
A strong party came from the village
No! We will have to wait
for few days
People should not be worried because
Pan Singh gang has scared from police
It's published in newspapers
Party is strong?
Wedding will be on next saturday
Listen to me we should
go to Rajhistan
But we won't be scared from
the police
Can we trust your in laws...