You are live in two minutes,
Your Royal Highness.
Sir?
At the microphone,
Do your work Sir.
I am sure you will be splendid.
Just take your time.
Time to go.
BBC NEWS READER :
Good afternoon.
This is the BBC National
Programme and Empire Services
taking you to Wembley Stadium
for the Closing Ceremony of the Empire Exhibition.
where His Royal Highness the Duke of York
will read a message from His Father;
His Majesty, King George V.
58 British Colonies and Dominions
have taken part, making this the largest Exhibition
staged anywhere in the world.
Remember Sir, Three flashes;
then steady 'red' means you are Live.
BBC NEWS READER :
Using the new invention of radio,
The Opening Ceremony was the first time
his Majesty the King addressed his subjects
on the wireless.
At the close of the first Season,
The heir to the throne His Royal Highness
the Prince of Wales, made his first broadcast.
And today,
his younger brother His Royal Highness,
the Duke of York will give his
inaugural broadcast to the Nation and the World.
I have received...
from his Majesty....t' ek
...The King.
SIR BLANDINE-BENTHAM:
Inhale deep into your lungs..
Your Royal Highness.
Relaxes your larynx, does it not?
Cigarette smoking calms the nerves
and gives you confidence.
If Your Highness will be very kind as
to open your hand...
It's Sterilized. Now..
Now...if I may take the liberty?
...insert some into your mouth.
Excuse me, Doctor.
What is the purpose of this?
The classic approach,
it cured Demosthenes.
That was in Ancient Greece...uh
Has it worked since?
Now,
if you would be so kind as to read...
A wealth of words.
Fight against those marbles,
Your Royal Highness.
Enunciate!
A little more concentration
your Royal Higness.
I nearly swallowed
the bloody things!
Thank you so much, Doctor,
its been most...hmm
interesting.
Insert marbles!
He can insert his own bloody marbles....!
Tick, tock, tick, tock.
You know,
you cant keep doing this, Bertie.
I know.
Promise me:
no more.
Hello.
Is anyone there?
Im just in the loo.
Ah, Mrs.Johnson
There you are.
Im sorry, theres no receptionist.
I like to keep things simple.
Poor and content
is rich and rich enough
- Sorry?
- Shakespeare. How are you?
How do you do?
Coughing a lot.
Now, this is slightly awkward, But..
Im afraid youre late.
Yes,
Im afraid I am.
Wheres Mr Johnson?
He doesnt know Im here.
Thats not a promising start.
My husband has seen everyone to no avail.
Awefully 'fraid hes given up hope.
He hasnt seen me.
Youre awfully sure of yourself.
Well,
Im sure of anyone who wants to be cured.
Of course, he wishes to be cured.
My husband is umm..
he's required to speak publicly.
Perhaps he should change jobs?
- He cant.
Indentured servitude?
Something of that nature.
Well we need to  have your hubby pop by...
Uh..Tuesday would be good...
He can give me his personal details and
Ill make a frank appraisal and then, We can take it from there.
Doctor, forgive me.
I do not have a hubby.
We dont pop.
and nor do we ever talk about our private lives.
You...
must come to us.
I'm Sorry, Mrs Johnson,
my game, my turf, my rules.
You'll have to talk over this with your hauband
and then you can speak to me on the telephone.
Thank you very much for dropping by...
Good afternoon.
And what if my husband were the Duke of York?
The Duke of York?
Yes...
the Duke of York.
I thought the appointment was for Johnson?
Forgive me, your ...?
- ..Royal Highness.
Johnson was used during the Great War;
when the Navy didnt want the enemy
to know he was aboard.
- Am I...considered the enemy?
You will be,
if you remain un- obliging.
Of course.
How did you find me, Your Royal Highness?
The President of the Speech Therapists Society.
Eileen McCleod?
Shes a sport.
Dr McCleod warned me your antipodean methods
were unorthodox and controversial.
I warned her...
those were not my favorite words.
I can cure your husband.
But for my  method to work I need trust and total equality;
Here, in the safety of my consultation room.
No exceptions.
Well then, in that case...
When can you start?
Still sounds a bit rough, mate.
You make me drive too slowly, Dad!
Did you pick mum up from Bridge?
Yes, Ive hardly been out of the car all day.
I had a special visitor this afternoon.
- May I please leave this table
- How special, special?
No, You must stay,
bored stupid, listening to your
parents inane conversation.
- Thanks Dad..
- and Mum.
- Me too.
- You meeting Jean?
- No, someone else.
Doctor? Doctor? Can't you help
your brother with the washing...
Im fine.
Who's it Lionel?
Why bring it up
if you cant talk about it?
Myrtle, It's just a woman,
looking to help her husband.
Oh!
And I had a call.
for an audition.
One of my favorites.
- Aren't they all?
It Could be a lot of fun.
I'm sure you'll be splendid.
Theyre a highly regarded group.
From Putney.
Tomorrow, Chapter IV.
The Flight.
Oh, to fly away!
Werent they lucky!
Now Papa tell a  story!
- Could I be a penguin instead?
Once, there were two princesses...
Princess Elizabeth and Princess Margaret.
whose Papa was a penguin.
This was because he  had been
turned into one by the wicket witch.
This was an...
inconvenient for him..
because he loved to hold
his princesses in his arms...
and you cant because he
don't have wings like herrings
- Herrings dont have wings.
- Penguins have wings
which is shaped like herrings
and make matters worse...
is that she
sent him to the South Pole.
which is an awfully long walk..back.
if you cant fly.
So..When he reached the water,
he dived in through the dept so fast...
that he was in Southampton
waters by lunchtime.
And from there,
he took the 2.30 to Weybridge,
changed at Clapham Junction and asked
a passing Mallard the way to Buckingham Palace.
He swam up the Thames,
out through the  plughole,
and gave the cook,
Mama and ...Mrs Whittaker quite a shock.
Now when the girls heard all the commotions,
they ran to the kitchen where
they gave him a good scrub,
a mackerel and a kiss.
and as they kissed him,
guess what he turned into?
- A handsome prince.
A short-tailed Albatross.
With wings so big
that he could wrap them both
his two girls together.
Now, now..
It's time for bed.
Will Mrs Simpson  be there?
- My brothers insisting.
- Is he serious?
- About her coming to dinner?
- No. About her!
- A married woman? He cant be.
- She can.
By the way,
I think I found someone rather interesting.
On Harley Street. A doctor.
- Out of the question.
Im not having this conversation again.
The matter's settled.
- His approach seems rather different....
Now?
Now.
Now is the winter of our discontent,
Made glorious summer
by this sun of York".
And all the clouds
that lourd upon our house
In the deep bosom of the ocean buried.
Now are our brows,
bound with victorious... wreaths;
- Thank you!
Lovely diction Mr...?
- Logue. Lionel Logue.
- Well, Mr.Logue.
I'm not hearing the cries of a deformed
creature yearning to be King.
Nor did I realize Richard the Third
was King of the Colonies.
I do know the lines.
Ive played the role before.
- Sydney?
- Perth.
- Major theater town, is it?
-Enthusiastic.
- Ah.
- I was well reviewed.
Yes...
well...Lionel,
I think our dramatic society,
is looking for someone slightly younger
and a...
little more regal.
Where did you find this...physician?
Classifieds,
next to French model,
Shepherds Market.
He comes highly recommended.
Charges substantial fees
in order to help the poor.
Oh dear,
perhaps hes a Bolshevik?!
No receptionist.
He likes to keep things simple.
- The Johnsons.
You can go in now, Mr. Johnson.
Lionel says...
wait here if you  wish, Mrs Johnson.
Or, it being a p-
pleasant day,
p-perhaps take a stroll.
Was that alright...Lionel?
Marvellous! Willy.
You can stay and wait for your mom.
Mrs Johnson...
Mr Johnson, Do come in.
Hes a good lad, Willy.
He could hardly make a sound, you know,
when he first came to me.
My boys made those.
Good, arent they?
Please make yourself comfortable.
I was told not to sit too close.
Well I believe when speaking with a Prince,
One waits for the prince to choose a topic.
Waiting for me to...
commence
a conversation ..
one can wait a rather long wait.
Do you Know any jokes?
Timing isnt my strong suit.
Cuppa tea?
No thank you.
Arent you going to start treating me
Dr Logue?
Only if youre interested in being treated.
Please,
call me Lionel.
I prefer Doctor.
I prefer Lionel.
Whatll I call you?
Your Royal Highness,
then Sir after that.
A bit formal for here.
What about your name?
Prince Albert ...Frederick Arthur
George?
How about Bertie?
Only my family uses that.
Perfect.
In here, its better if were equals.
If we were equal I wouldnt be
here.
Id be at home with my wife
and no-one would give a damn.
Please, Dont do that.
I'm sorry?
I believe, Sucking smoke
into your lungs will kill you.
My physicians say
it relaxes the throat.
Theyre idiots.
Theyve all been knighted.
Makes it official then.
My castle, my rules.
What was your earliest memory?
What?
an earth do you mean?
Your First recollection.
I'm not...
here to discuss my personal matters.
Whyre you here then?
Because I bloody well stammer!
You have a bit of a temper?
One of my many faults.
When did the defect start?
I've always been this way!
I doubt that.
Dont tell me! Its my stammer!
- Its my field.
I can assure you,
no infant starts to speak with a stammer.
When did yours start?
four or five.
That's typical.
So Ive been told.
I cant remember not doing it.
I can believe that. Do you hesitate
when you think?
Dont be ridiculous.
How about
when you talk to yourself?
Everyone natters occasionally
Bertie.
Stop calling me that!
Im not going to call you anything
else.
Then we shant speak!
Are you charging for this, Doctor?
A fortune.
So, when you
talk to yourself, do you stammer?
Of course not!
Well, that proves your impediment isnt
a permanent part of you.
What do
you think was the cause?
I don't know.
I dont care!
I stammer!
And no one can fix it.
I Bet you,  you can read
flawlessly, right here, right now.
And if I win, I get to ask
questions.
- And if I win?
- You dont have to answer.
One usually ...
wagers money.
A bob each to sweeten it?
Lets See your shilling??
- I dont...
carry money.
- I had a funny feeling you mightnt.
I'll stake you.
You can  Pay me back next time.
- Who says there is a next time?
- I havent agreed
to take you on, yet.
Please stand.
and take a look at that...
I cant  read this.
Then you owe me a shilling ,
for not trying.
To be...
or not to be,....That...
I cant read!
I havent finished yet.
Im going to record your voice and
then play it back to you on the same machine.
This is brilliant.
Its the latest thing from America:
its a Silvertone.
Pop this on?
Theres a bob in this, mate. You
can go home rich!
- Youre playing music.
- I know.
How can I hear what Im saying?!
Surely a Princes brain knows what
its mouth is doing?
Youre not well acquainted with
Royal Princes, are you?
Hopeless.
Hopeless!
You were sublime. Would I lie to a
prince of the realm to win twelve-pence?
Ive no idea what an Australian
might do for that sort of money.
Let me play it back to you.
No.
All right then,
I get to ask you the question.
Thank you Doctor,
I don't feel..
this is for me.
Thank You for your time,
Bye.
- Sir?
the recording is free.
Please..
keep it as a souvenir.
KING GEORGE V (O.S.)
For the present, the work to which
we are all equally bound,
is to arrive at a reasoned
tranquillity...
...within our borders, to regain
prosperity in this time of depression without self-seeking
and to carry with us those whom the
burden of past years has disheartened or overborne.
To all,
to each,
I wish a Happy Christmas.
God bless you.
Easy when you know how.
Have a go yourself.
Congratulations, Sir.
Ah, Mr Wood.
Splendid fellow. Chap taught me everything I know:
let the microphone do the work.
Sit up,
straight back,
face boldly up to the bloody thing
and stare it square in the eye,
as you would any decent Englishman.
Show whos in command.
Papa, I D-d-dont
thu-thu-think I c-c-can read this.
- This devilish device will change
everything if you dont.
In the past all a King had to do was look
respectable in uniform and not fall off his horse.
Now we must invade peoples homes
and ingratiate ourselves with them.
This family is reduced to those lowest,
basest of all creatures...
weve become...actors!
- were not a family,
were a firm.
- Yet at any moment,
some of us may be out of work.
Your darling brother,
and future king!
The only wife he appears interested in
is invariably the wife of another!
- Hes broken off
with Lady Furness.
And taken up a Mrs Simpson,
a woman
with two husbands living!
I told him straight,
no divorced person could ever be received at court.
He said,
"It made him sublimely happy."
I imagined that was because she was
sleeping with him.
I give you my word..'
this is what he said.
I give you my
word weve never had immoral relations,
Stared square into his fathers eyes...
and lied!
When Im dead that boy will ruin
himself, this family, and this nation, within twelve months.
Wholl pick up the pieces?
Herr Hitler, intimidating half of
Europe, Marshall Stalin the other half?
Wholl stand between us, the
jackboots, and the proletarian abyss?
You?
With your older brother shirking his duties,
youre going to have to do a lot more of this.
Have a go yourself.
Son.
Get it out boy!
...m-marvels of m-
- Modern...
just take your time -
form your words carefully
Science, I am enabled, this ...
- Relax!
Just try it!
Do it!
Lying ..
bastard.
To be, or not to be,
- that is the question: -
...whether tis nobler in the mind
to suffer The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune,
Or to take arms against a sea of
troubles, And by opposing end them..
"..to die...
to sleep; no more.."
Strictly  business.
No p..
personal nonsense.
I thought Id made that very clear
in our interview.
- Got the shilling you owe me?
- No I havent!
- Didnt think so.
Besides,
you tricked me!
Physical excercises and tricks are important...
What youre asking will only deal
with the surface of the problem.
Thats sufficient.
As far as i see it,
My hausband...
has mechanical difficulties with his speech.
Maybe...
Just deal with that.
- Im willing to work hard, Doctor Logue...
- Lionel.
- Are you..
are you willing to do your part?
Alright.
You want mechanics?
We need to relax your throat muscles
and strengthen your tongue.
By repeating tongue twisters for example.
I am a thistle-sifter. I have a sieve of sifted thistles
and a sieve of unsifted thistles.
Because I am a thistle sifter.
- Fine!
You have a flabby tummy,
we must build up the strength in your diaphragm.
Simple mechanics.
That is all we ask.
And thats about a shillings worth.
Forget about the blessed shilling!
Perhaps, upon occasion,
you might be requested
some assistance in cope with a minor event.
Will that agreeable?
Of course.
That will be the full extent of your services.
- Shall I see you next week?
- I shall see you every day.
Ahahahahhahahahahahahahahahahahah.
Feel the loosening of the jaw
Take a nice deep breath.
Expand your chest..
How do you feel?
full of hot air.
- Isnt that what public speaking is all about?
Are you alright, Bertie?
This is actually quite good fun,
- Hello, Bertie.
- Hello David.
Whereve you been?
Been busy.
- So was I.
Elizabeth has pneumonia.
Im sorry. Shell recover.
Father wont.
- Ill drive.
Old buggers doing this on purpose.
Dying?
Departing prematurely...
to complicate matters.
Oh for heavens sake, David. You
know how long hes been ill.
Wallis explained. Shes terribly
clever about this thing.
LORD WIGRAM:
... whereas by letters patent underthe Great Seal, bearing date of
Westminster, the eleventh June 1912
his Majesty King George V did constitute,
order and declare that there should be a guardian,
Custos Regni,
in the form of Councillors of State
Its the order of the Council for
the State, Sir.
So we may act on your behalf.
Im still confused...
Approved.
Thank you.
Feeling a little better Sir?
No. Im not feeling any better. I
feel dreadful.
Have you been ice skating?
..Ice skating.
No, George.
...I know, darling, a talk, even a
lovely long talk, is a poor substitute
for holding tight and making drowsy.
Nor making our own drowsies either,
as weve had to dofar too often lately.
David, Dinner?
- Im on with Wallis!
Wallis misses me terribly.
- Mama says youre late for dinner.
- She forgets Papas bloody clocks
were always half an hour fast!
How is the king?
I hope he is not in pain.
No, no, His Majesty,
hes quieter now.
Thank you.
David, If your father were well, tardiness
would not be tolerated.
None of this..
unpleasantness would be tolerated
You know Sir, I appreciate that yo
are different from your father in your outlook and temperament.
I want you to know that whenever
the King questioned your conduct,
I  tried in your interest, to present
it in a most favourable light.
I can always trust you to have my
best interests at heart.
I fear, our vigil will not be of
long duration.
Please, continue.
We commend our brother George to
the mercy of God, our Maker and Redeemer.
Long live the King.
I hope,
I will make good as he has made good.
What on earth was that?
Poor Wallis.
Now Im trapped!
Time for a Shake, dad?
You sure?
Go on.
Put your thinking caps on.
Bet its the Scottish Play.
No, I bet its Othello.
Its always Othello.
Art thou afeard?
Caliban!
Oh! For heavens sake.. that was a
lucky guess!
Dont listen to egghead.
Go on, Dad.
the isle is full ofnoises,Sounds and sweet airs,
that give delight, and hurt not.
Sometimes a thousand twanging instruments
Will hum about mine ears;
and sometimes voices,That, if then I had waked after
long sleep,Will make me sleep again:
Alright, clever clogs,
what comes next?
..and then, in dreaming,
The clouds me thought would open,
and show riches Ready to drop upon me;
that when I'm awake...
...when I waked, I cried to dream again.
Its such a sad thought.
My next patient must be early.
You better go lads, Im sorry.
Wont be a moment, Clifford.
Bertie!
they told me not to expect you.
I am Sorry about your father.
I dont wish to intrude..
oh no...
course. Please come in.
Ive been practising. One hour a
day. In spite of everything.
Whats going on there?
I was, sorry,
mucking around with my kids.
Do you feel like working today?
A Curtis bi-plane.
Ill put on some hot milk.
Logue, Id kill for something stronger.
I wasnt there for my fathers
death. Still makes me sad.
I can imagine so.
What did you father do?
He was a brewer.
At least there was free beer.
Heres to the memory of your father.
I was informed,
after the fact...
that  my fathers last words were:
Bertie has more guts than the rest of his
brothers put together.
He couldnt say that to my face.
My brother.
What about him?
Try singing.
I'm sorry.
Know any songs?
Songs?
Yes songs.
Swanee River.
I love that song.
Happens to be my favorite.
Sing me the chorus.
No.  Certainly not.
Always wanted to build models.
Father wouldnt allow it.
He collected stamps.
we had to collect stamps.
You can finish that off.
If you sing.
I'm not going to sit here,
wobbling.
You can with me.
Because youre peculiar.
I take that as a compliment.
Im not crooning Swanee River!
Try Camptown Races then.
My brother D, he said to me, doo-
dah doo-dah... Continuous sound will give you flow.
Does it feel strange,
now that Davids on the throne?
To tell the truth,
It was a relief...
Knowing I wouldnt be King.
But unless he produces an heir,
youre next in line.
And your daughter, Elizabeth,
would then succeed you.
Youre barking up the wrong tree
now, Doctor, Doctor.
Lionel See?
You didnstammer.
Of course I didnt stammer, I was singing!
Well, as a little reward, you get
to put some glue on these struts.
Your boy,
won't mind?
No, not at all.
David and I were very close. Young
bucks... You know.
Chase the same girls?
David was always very helpful in arranging introductions.
We shared the expert ministrations of Paulette in Paris.
Not at the same time of course.
Did David tease you?
Yes, they all did.
Buh-buh-buh-Bertie.
Father encouraged it. Get it out,
boy! Said it would make me stop.
Said...I was afraid of my father,
and my children are damn well going to be afraid of me.
Are you naturally right handed?
Left.
I was punished. Now I use the right.
Yes, thats very common with stammerers.
Anything other corrections?
Knock knees.
Metal splints were made...worn
night and day.
That must have been painful.
Bloody agony.
Straight legs now.
Who were you closest to in your family?
Nannies. Not my first nanny,
though..she loved David...hated me.
When we are presented to my parents
for the daily viewing, shed pinch me..
I'd cry and
be handed back to her..
immediately.
Then...
she would...
Sing it.
" then she wouldnt feed me,
far far away.
Took three years for my parents to notice.
As you can imagine, it
caused some stomach problems. Still.
What about your brother Johnnie?
Were you close to him?
Johnny..
Sweet boy.
Epilepsy...and...
he was different.
Died at 13, hidden from view.
Ive been told its not catching.
Do you want a top-up?
Please.
You know, Lionel, youre the first
ordinary Englishman...
Australian.
...Ive ever really spoken to.
Sometimes, when I ride through the
streets and see, you know,
the Common Man staring at me,
Im struck by how little I know of hislife,
and how little he knows of mine.
Thank you.
Whatre friends for.
I wouldnt know.
I sifted seven thick-stalked
thistles through strong thicksieves. I sifted seven...
One hundred year old
oaks...removed to improve the view!
Who does she think she is!
Nonetheless...we must try to be
pleasant towards Mrs Simpson.
You know she calls me The Fat
Scottish Cook?
Youre not fat.
Im getting plump.
You seldom cook.
I sifted seven.
Shut up!!
Their Royal Highnesses the Duke and
Duchess of York.
How lovely to see you both.
Welcome
to our little country shack.
I came at the invitation of the
King.
Hello David.
youre making some changes to
the garden, I see
yes, I am.
I am not quite finished.
Dont tell me I behaved badly, Mr Churchill.
On the contrary, your Royal
Highness. Etiquette decrees royalty
must be greeted by the official host: in this case: the King.
Not a commoner.
- Thank you.
What is her hold on him?
I have no idea.
Apparently she has
certain...skills,
...in an establishment in Shanghai.
David,
Ive been trying to see you...
Ive been terribly busy.
Doing what?
Kinging.
Kinging?
is a precarious business!
These days.
Where is the Russian Tsar?
Where is Cousin Wilhelm?
Youre being dreary.
Is Kinging laying off eighty staff at Sandringham
and buying yet more pearls for Wallis while there ar
people marching across Europe singing The Red Flag?
Stop your worrying. Herr Hitler
will sort that lot out.
Wholl sort out Herr Hitler?
And youve put that woman into our
mothers suite?
Mothers not still in the bed,
is she?
Thats not funny.
Wally likes the very best.
I dont care what woman you carry
on with at night,
as long as you show up for duty in the morning!
Wally is not just some woman I am
carrying on with.
We intend to marry.
Excuse me?
Shes filing a petition for
divorce.
Good God.
Cant you just give her a nice
house and a title?
I wont have her as my mistress.
David, the Church does not
recognise divorce and you are the head of the Church.
Havent I any rights?
Many privileges...
Not the same thing.
Your beloved Common Man may marry for love,
why not me?
If you were the Common Man, on what
basis could you possibly claim to be King?!
Sounds like youve studied our
wretched constitution.
Sounds like you havent.
Is that what this is all about? Brushing up..
hence the elocution lessons?
Im trying to t-t...
Yearning for a larger audience are we,
B-b-b-bertie?
D-dont ...
Younger brother trying to push older
brother off throne..
Pa pa..
...Positively medieval.
Where have you been all this time?
- Never you mind.
Ahh..what a complicated
lovely coon you are.
- I try to be.
All that work, down the drain.
My own brother...
I couldnt say..
I couldnt say a word in reply!
Why do you stammer more with David
than you do with me?
Because youre bloody well paid to listen!
Bertie,
Im not a geisha girl.
Stop trying to be so bloody clever!
What is it about David that stops you speaking?
What is it about you, that bloody makes
want you to go on about it, all the time.
Vulgar but fluent. You dont
stammer when you swear.
Bugger off!
Is that the best you can do?
Well, bloody bugger to you,
you beastly bastard.
A public school prig can do better
than that.
Shit !
Shit, shit, shit!
shit!
See how defecation flows trippingly
from the tongue?
Because Im angry!
You Know the f-word?
Fornication?
OH Bertie.
Fuck. Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Yes! You see! Not a hesitation!
Bloody, bloody, bloody! Shit, shit,
shit! Bugger, bugger, bugger! Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Dad? Whats going on?
Sorry. Finish your homework
Well ..thats a side of you we dont
get to see that often.
No. No were not supposed to
really, not publicly.
Lets get some air.
No Logue, I dont think thats a
good idea.
Whats the matter?
Whats got you so upset?
Logue, you have no idea.
My brother is infatuated with a woman whos
been married twice.
Shes asking for a divorce and
David is determined to marry her.
Mrs Wallis Simpson of Baltimore.
Thats not right.
Queen Wallis of Baltimore?
Unthinkable.
Can he do that?
Absolutely not.
But hes going to anyway.
All hells broken loose.
- Cant they carry on privately?
- If only they would.
- Where does that leave you?
I know my place!
Ill do anything...
in my power to keep my brother on the throne.
-Is it that serious?
your place may be on the throne.
I am not an alternative to my
brother.
If you had to you could outshine David...
Dont take liberties!
Thats bordering on treason.
Im just saying you could be King.
You could do it!
That is treason!
Im trying to get you to realise
you need not be governed by fear.
Ive had enough of this!
Whatre you afraid of?
Your poisonous words!
Whyd you come to me?
You are not some middle class bugger,
who needs elocution lessons so you can chit-chat...
Dont instruct me on my duties!
Im the son of a ....
King...
the brother of a king.
Youre the disappointing son of a brewer!
A jumped-up jackeroo from the
outback!
Youre nobody.
These sessions are over!
Its not because shes an American.
That is the least of it.
Its because she is a soon to
be a twice divorced American,
and the King as  head of The Church of England...
can not marry a divorced woman.
And Sir,
I apologize for the nature of this,
according to Scotland Yard,
the King has not always possess exclusive..rights
to Mrs. Simpsons...
favours and affections,
sharing them with a
married used car salesman,
a certain Mr Guy Trundle.
In addition, it is also rumoured...
Hitlers ambassador, Count von Ribbentrop,
sends her 17 carnations every day.
Should your brother continue to
ignore the advice of His Government, He must abdicate.
Otherwise His Government has no
choice but to resign.
Prime Minister,
youd leave the
country without a government?
Does the King do what he wants,
or does he do what his people expect him to do?
Whats the matter, love?
I'm Just having trouble with a patient.
That Isn't like you..
why?
He's scared...
He is afraid with his own shadow.
Isnt that why they come to you?
This fellow could be somebody
great, and hes fighting me.
Perhaps, he doesnt want to be great.
Perhaps thats what you want.
I might have overstepped the mark.
Apologize,
Do you both good.
Im very sorry, Mr Logue,
the Duke is  busy.
Im happy to wait.
Or I could come back later.
As I said,
the Duke is terribly busy.
Thank you.
The parliament will not support their marriage.
But there were other reasons for concern, Sir.
He was careless with state papers.
He lacked commitment and resolve.
There were those that worried where
he would stand when war comes with Germany .
Were not coming to that?
Indeed we are, Sir.
Prime Minister Baldwin may deny this,
but Hitlers intent is crystal clear.
War with Germany will come, and we will need
a King behind whom we can all stand united.
I fear...my brother is not of
sound mind, at this time.
Have you thought what you will call yourself?
Certainly not Albert, Sir.
Too Germanic.
What about George?
After your father? George the sixth.
It has rather a nice continuity to it,
dont you think?
David! Thank God.
You look exhausted!
How are you bearing up?
Bertie.  The decisions been made.
I have to go.
I cannot accept that.
You are in no condition to make that decision.
Im afraid theres no other way.
I must marry her.
My minds made up.
Im... sorry.
Thats a terrible thing to hear.
David, nobody wants that.
I least of all.
" At long last I am able to say,
a few words of my own.
I have never wanted to withhold anything,
but until now,
it has not been constitutionally
possible for me to speak.
A few hours ago I discharged
my last duty as King and Emperor.
Now that I have been succeeded by
my brother, the Duke of York
my first words must be
to declare my allegiance to him.
This I do with all my heart.
You all know the reasons which have
impelled me to renounce the throne.
But you must believe me,
when I tell you
I have found it impossible to carry the heavy burden of
responsibility and to discharge my duties..
as King as I would wish to do without
the help and support of the woman I love...
And I want you to know,
..This decision has been made less
difficult to me
by the sure knowledge that my brother, with his
long training in the public affairs of this country...
...and with his fine qualities...
...will be able to take my place forth with
without interruption or
injury to the life and progress of the empire."
I meet you today...
in circumstances which are -
Mama, will we have space for our
horses in our new home?
Of course we will, darling, well
have a palace of rooms.
Curtsey.
Your Majesty.
How was it?
Im trying to familiarise myself
with what a state paper looks like.
A despatch from Mr Baldwin
which I dont understand a word of.
Davids finances.
The Christmas broadcast -
I think that might be a mistake.
Plans for the Coronation -
I think thats an even bigger mistake.
Im not a King.
Im a naval officer.
Its the only thing I know.
Im not a King.
Dear, dear man...
You  know...
i refused your first two marriage proposals,
not because I didnt love you,
but because I couldnt bear the royal cage.
Couldn't bear the idea of a life
of tours and public duties,
a life that no longer
was really to be my own.
But then I thought...
he stammers so beautifully...
theyll leave us alone.
Waiting for a king to apologize,
one can wait rather a long wait.
Im afraid were slightly late.
This is home. Myrtles at bridge.
Ive made sure the boys are out.
Its lovely.
Absolutely lovely.
Would you like some tea, Maam?
Yes. Ill help myself.
Off you go...
Or must I knock your heads together?
Heres your shilling,
I understand...
what you were tryingto say, Logue.
I went about it the wrong way.
Im sorry.
Now here I am.
Is the nation ready
for two minutes of radio silence?
Every stammerer always fears they
will fall back to square one.
I dont let that happen.
If I fail in my duty...
David could come back.
Ive seen the placards
Save Our King!
They dont mean me.
Every other monarch in history
succeeded someone who was dead,
or just about to be.
My predecessor is not
only alive, but very much so.
What a bloody mess!
I cant even give
them a Christmas Speech.
Like your Dad used to do?
Precisely.
He's not here anymore.
Yes he is. Hes on that shilling I gave you.
Easy enough to give away. You dont have
to carry him around in your pocket.
Or your brother.
You don't need to be afraid of the things
as you were afraid of when you were five.
Youre very much your own man, Bertie.
Am I?
Your face is next, mate.
Lionel?
Myrtle!
- Is it alright?
- Yes.
Bertie, come here.
- Are you alright, Logue?
- Yes.
- Shall we go through?
- Trust me. It's important.
What is it?
- Your... Your...
- It's Your Majesty, the first time.
After that, it's Maam, as in Ham,
not Ma'lm as in Palm.
I haven't told her about us.
Sit down, relax.
I'm told your husband calls
my husband Bertie
and my husband calls your husband Lionel.
I trust you won't call me Liz.
Your Majesty, you may call me
Mrs Logue, Ma'am.
Very nice to meet you, Mrs Logue.
Logue, we can't stand here all day.
Yes we can. Look, I need to wait
for the right moment.
- Logue, youre being a coward!
- You're damn right.
Get out there, man!
Hello, Myrtle darling!
You're early. I believe you two have met!
But I didn't think, you know...
King George the Sixth.
- It's very nice to meet you.
Will their Majesties be staying
to dinner?
We would love to, such a treat,
but alas...
a previous engagement. What a pitty.
- Archbishop.
- Welcome, your Majesty.
What a glorious tranformation, Sir.
I hope you'll forgive us if we continue
out preparations.
And now you will allow me to guide you
through the ceremony.
We begin of course at the West door,
then into the nave.
I see you all your pronouncements are
to be broadcast, Archbishop.
Ah, yes, wireless is indeed a Pandoras Box.
I'm afraid I also have to permit
the newsreel cameras.
The product of which I shall personally
edit.
Without momentary hesitation.
This is Doctor Logue of Harley Street.
He's my speech therapist.
- Your Grace. - Had I known that Your
Majesty was seeking assistance
I shouldve made my own recommendation.
Dr. Logue...
will be attending the Coronation.
Well of course I shall speak with the Dean,
but it was extremely difficult.
I should like the Doctor to be seated
in the King's Box.
But members of your Family will be seated
there, Sir.
That is why its suitable.
And now, if you dont mind Your Grace,
we need the premises.
My dear fellow, this is Westminster Abbey!
The Church must prepare his Majesty.
My preparations are equalized in important
With complete privacy, if you don't mind.
Those are my wishes, Your Grace.
I shall place the Abbey at Your Majestys
disposal... this evening. Your Majesty.
.
I cant believe Im walking on Chaucer
and Handel and Dickens.
Everything alright? Let's get cracking.
Im not here to rehearse, Doctor Logue.
Call me Lionel.
True, you... never...
called yourself "Doctor."
I did that... for you.
No training, no... diploma,
no... qualifications.
Just a... great deal of nerve.
The star chamber inquisition, is this?
You asked trust and... total equality.
Bertie, I heard you at Wembley.
I was there.
My son Laurie said Dad, do you think
you could help that poor man?
What, as a failed actor!?
Its true, Im not a doctor,
and yes I acted a bit,
Well I recited in pubs
and taught elocution in schools.
When the Great War came,
all our Soldiers were returning
straight from the front,
a lot of them shell-shocked,
unable to speak
somebody said, Lionel, you're very good
at all this speech stuff.
Do you thin you can possibly help
these poor buggers.
I did muscle therapy, exercise, relaxation,
but I knew I had to go deeper.
These poor young blokes had cried out
in fear, no-one was listening to them.
My job was to give them faith
in their own voice
and let them know that a friend
was listening.
That must ring a few bells with you,
Bertie.
You give a very noble account of yourself.
Make inquiries. Its all true.
Inquiries have been made! You have no idea
who I have breathing down my neck?
I vouched for you and you have no...
credentials.
But lots of success!
I can't show you certificate -
there was no training then.
Everything I know I know from experience,
and that war... was some experience.
My plaque says,
"L. Logue, Speech Defects."
No Dr., there are no letters
after my name.
Lock me in the Tower.
- I would if I could!
- On what charge?
- Fraud!
With war looming, youve saddled
this nation with a voiceless King.
You destroyed the happiness of my family.
All for the sake of ensnaring a star...
patient you couldnt possibly hope
to assist!
It'll be like mad...
King George the Third,
therell be
mad King George the stammerer,
who let his people down so badly
in their hour of need!
Whatre you doing? Get up!
You cant sit there! Get up!
Why not? Its a chair.
No, that's not a chair,
that is... that is...
That is Saint Edward's Chair!
- People have carved their names on it.
That chair is the seat on which every
King and Queen---
- It's held in a place by a large rock!
- Thats the Stone of Scone,
you are trivialising everything.
- You believe such bollocks.
- Youre trivialising everything!
- I dont care how many royal...
- Listen to me. Listen to me!
-  ...arse have sat in this chair.
- Listen to me... !
- Listen to you?! By what right?
By the divine right, if you must!
Im your King!!!
No youre not! You told me so yourself.
You said you didnt want it.
Why should I waste my time listening to you?
- Because I have a right to be heard!
- Heard as what?!
- I HAVE A VOICE!!!
Yes you do.
You have such a perservance, Bertie,
youre the bravest man I know.
And youll make a bloody good king.
- What on earths going on, Sir?
- It's quite alright, Archbishop.
Mr Logue, you must know that I found
a replacement English specialist
with impeccable credentials. Hence, your
services will no longer be required.
- Im sorry? - Your Majesty's function
is to consult and be advised.
And you didn't consuly, but you've just
been advised.
Now I advise you: in this personal matter
I will make my own decision.
My concern is for the head upon
which I must place the crown.
I appreciate that Archbshop,
but its my head!
Your humble servant.
Thank you Bertie.
Shall we rehearse?
Come on up on your purge.
Now when you and Elizabeth enter through
the West door,
youll be greeted by the hymn
I Was Glad When They Said Unto Me.
Actually you won't be that glad, because
they sing it for a very long time.
Then your friend the Archbishop
will ponce up the stairs toward you
and say Sir, is Your Majesty willing
to take The Oath?
- I am willing.
-  Course you are!
I'm gonna see what it sounds
like in the cheap seats
so even your old nanny can hear.
Will you govern your peoples of
Great Britain, Ireland, Canada,
Australia and New Zealand according to
their lands and customs?
- "I solemnly promise so do so."
- LOUDER! I cant hear you up the back.
I SOLEMNLY PROMISE TO DO SO!
Very good!
"Will you to your power cause Law
and Justice, in Mercy,
to be executed in all your judgements?"
"I will." I WILL!
Then there's a very long bit about
upholding the faith,
goes on, rubbish, rubbish, rubbish.
To which you finally say...
"The things which I have herebefore
promised, I will perform and keep.
So help me God.
And thats all you'll say.
Four short responses,
kiss the book and sign the oath
and you're King.
Easy.
You nearly crowned him backwards
Archbishop!
Someone had removed the thread
marking the back of the Crown, Sir.
Try not lose the thread, Archbishop.
Archbishop, we're missing Papa.
Very good, very good. Archbishop.
Well, I hope Your Majesties are thrilled
with the result.
You could switch that machine off now.
No, wait, keep going.
Do have a seat, Archbishop.
Movie commentary
# German Speaking #
- Papa? - Mmm? - Papa, whats he saying?
I dont know, but he seems to be
saying it rather well.
Sir, I have asked to see you today in order
to tender my resignation as Prime Minister.
I am so sorry to hear that, Mr Baldwin.
Neville Chamberlain will take my place
as Prime Minister.
Its a matter of principal.
I was mistaken.
I have found it impossible to believe
that there is any man in the World
so lacking in moral feeling as Hitler,
but the world might be hurled for a second
time into the abyss of destructive War.
Churchill was right all along.
This was always Hitlers intention.
I am many very sorry to leave you in
this great time of crisis.
I am very much afraid Sir, that your
greatest test is yet to come.
I am speaking to you from the cabinet
room at 10 Downing Street.
This morning the British Ambassador
in Berlin
handed the German Government a final note
stating that unless we heard from them
by 11 oclock
that they were prepared at once to
withdraw their troops from Poland,
a state of war would exist between us.
I have to tell you now that no such
undertaking has been received,
and that consequently this country is
at war with Germany.
At last Sir, here is your speech.
You are on air at six.
Ive timed it at just under nine minutes.
The wording is fully approved.
The Prime Minister will be joining you
for the broadcast
which will go out live across the Nation,
the Empire and to our Armed Forces.
Get Logue here immediately.
- There's the barrage balloons.
- Yes.
They got them up there quickly. Yeah.
.
- Should we pull over and find shelter?
- No, go straight on. Well be alright
.
- Yes. Sir? - Lionel Logue.
Major Hartley's expecting me.
This is my son Laury.
- Thank you, Laurie.
- Good luck, Dad.
- The Kings Speech.
- Thank you, Sir.
We have about forty minutes until
the broadcast.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
There may be dark days ahead, and..."
Try again.
Turn the hesitations into pauses, and say
to yourself, God save the King.
I say that continuously,
but apparently no ones listening.
Long pauses are good: they add
solemnity to great occasions.
Then Im the solemnest king who ever lived.
And Lionel, if I am to be King...
where is my power?
Can I... Can I form a Government? Can I...
Can I levy a tax or declare a war? No!
Yet I am the seat of all authority. Why?
Because the Nation believes that
when I speak, I speak for them.
Yet I cannot speak!
Lets take it all again from the top.
In this grave hour...
In this grave hour fuck fuck fuck
perhaps the most fateful in our history
bugger shit shit
I send to every household of my...
You see "P" is always difficult,
even when I'm singing.
Bounce onto it "a-peoples", not "people".
a-people household of  me...
a-peoples both at home and overseas...
Beaut.
...this message, doo-dah, spoken with
the same depth of feeling, doo-dah-dey,
...for each one of you as if I were able
to shit fuck bugger
cross your threshold and speak to you
In your head, now: I have a right to be
bloody well heard!
Bloody well heard, bloody well heard,
bloody well heard myself!
Now Waltz. Move! Get continuous movement.
For the second time in the lives of most
of us we are at...
- we are... Take a pause.
- Lionel, I cant do this.
Bertie, you can do it.
-  Have a look at the last paragraph.
- Bertie, its time.
There he is.
- Archbishop.
- Your Majesty.
A great moment, Sir.
- Prime Minister.
- Your Majesty.
Nice to see you again, so soon.
Good of you to be here, Im sure
youve had rather a busy day.
Lets hope we have no more interruptions
from those damned sirens, Sir.
Or the wretched dogs.
- Congratulations. First Lord of
the Admiralty. - Your Majesty.
The long walk.
Good luck, Sir.
I too dread this apparatus. Had a speech
impediment myself, you know.
- I didnt.
- Family secret. Tongue-tied.
An operation was considered to be
too dangerous.
I eventually made an asset of it.
- Thank you, Mr Churchill.
- Good, Sir.
Darling.
- How long, Logue?
- Just under three minutes, Sir.
.
Five seconds, Sir.
5, 4, 3 , 2 , 1.
.
- Mr Wood.
- Good luck, Your Majesty.
Mr Wood.
- You'll be decorated, Logue.
- I made it cosy.
Some fresh air.
There you are, Darling.
I'm thistle sifter, I've a sieve of sifted
thistles and a sieve on unsifted thistles.
I've a sieve of sifted thistles and a sieve
on unsifted thistles, because I'm...
Bertie, darling, make sure its not switched on!
Remember the red light will blink four times
and then Ive asked them to turn it off,
because we dont want that evil eye
staring at you all the way through.
One minute, sir.
I am sure you will be splendid.
Fourty seconds, Sir.
Logue, however this turns out,
I dont know how to thank you
for what youve done.
Knighthood?
Twenty seconds.
Forget everything else and just say
it to me. Say it to me, as a friend.
In this grave hour,
perhaps the most fateful in our history,
I send to every household of my peoples,
both at home
and overseas
this message
spoken with the same depth of feeling
for each one of you
as if I were able to cross your threshold
and speak to you myself.
For the second time in the lives of
most of us
we are at... at war.
Over and over again
we have tried to find
a peaceful way out of the differences
between ourselves
and those who are now our enemies.
But it has been in vain.
We have been forced into a conflict.
For we are called, to meet the challenge
of a principle
which, if it were to prevail,
would be fatal to any civilized order
in the world.
Such a principle,
stripped of all disguise,
is surely the mere
primitive doctrine that might is right.
For the sake of all that we ourselves
hold dear,
it is unthinkable that we should refuse
to meet the challenge.
It is to this high purpose
that I now call
my people at home and my peoples across
the seas,
who will make our cause their own.
I ask them to stand calm and firm,
and united in this time of trial
the task will be hard.
There may be dark days ahead,
and war can no longer be confined
to the battlefield.
But we can only do the right
as we see the right
and reverently commit our cause to God.
If one and all we keep resolutely
faithful to it,
then, with Gods help,
we shall prevail.
Very good, Bertie.
You still stammered on the w.
Had to throw in a few so they knew
it was me.
Congratulations, your Majesty.
A true broadcaster.
Thank you, Mr Wood.
Congratulations, your Majesty.
- Congratulations, your Majesty.
- Thank you.
Ready.
- Good?
- Perfect.
Your first war time speech.
Congratulations.
Expect I shall have to do
a great deal more.
Thank you, Logue.
Well done, my friend.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I knew youd be good.
Thank you, Lionel.
Onwards?
Congratulations, Sir.
Almost did it better then myself, Sir.
Your Majesty, Im speechless.
Congratulations, Sir.
Gentlemen.
Congratulations, your Majesty.
So how was Papa, Elizabeth?
Halting at first, but you got much
better Papa.
Bless you.
- And how about you, Margaret?
- You were just splendid, Papa.
Of course I was.
We all ready?
Come on girls.
long2375