Shit!
Stop, please!
In a related story, the
high court had also refused to stay
Friday's execution of former
philosophy professor David Gale.
Gale had sought a review
of his 1994 conviction
for the rape and murder of his
University of Austin colleague,
Constance Harraway.
The case has received
nationwide media attention
because Gale and Harraway
were activists for Death Watch,
a nonprofit abolitionist
organization.
Do you understand how much money taxpayers
pay in Texas to put one person to death?
- What do we want?
- No more executions!
Governor, can't we all admit
the capital punishment system
in this country is not working?
They're not going to stay Gale.
It's on TV right now. Listen.
Defense lawyers
had hoped to argue
that Gale's former activism
against capital punishment
unduly prejudiced
the Texas judicial system.
The deal was Bitsey would get the
interview if the stay was refused.
He'll talk to her for
two hours a day,
Tuesday, Wednesday
and Thursday.
Can't do Friday. No.
Friday's the day
they execute him.
The lawyer said only Bitsey.
Gale's going down.
Shh!
Only Bitsey means only Bitsey.
I don't get to
make the rules, Joe.
Please, I'm a fat black woman.
What we need is to put
her on a plane to Texas.
Why do you get like
that around legal?
Hold on, we're coming over.
What's this "Only Bitsey
means only Bitsey" stuff?
They asked for you,
and no substitutes.
Who's they, exactly?
Gale's lawyers.
More exactly, Gale's lawyer.
Some good old boy in Austin.
Why do they want me?
You don't want the assignment?
I'm not saying that.
I can't see why a guy
about to be executed
should suddenly ask for me.
Maybe they liked your kiddie
porn piece, and going to jail.
Maybe he saw your picture
and thinks you're cute.
So how much access do I get?
Three interviews.
No time for more.
By Friday, the guy's a goner.
What exactly is our story?
Rape, murder, death row.
Very intelligent guy.
Maybe he's even innocent.
Yeah, right.
No, tell him I'll
call him back. Thanks.
So what's your problem?
Hi, Barbara. Morning, Bitsey.
Okay, here's my concern.
Setting aside the cost issue,
although $500,000 in cash
for three days of interviews
is not only illegal,
it's obscene.
That's market value.
The guy's never talked.
Aside from that, I, we are still
uncomfortable with the arrangement.
Why?
You just spent a very
public seven days in jail
for a very public
contempt-of-court citation.
For protecting sources. If you
were uncomfortable with the story,
why did you slap it on the
domestic and international covers?
What makes us uncomfortable
is that a rapist/murderer
has asked to spend the last
three days of his life
giving an interview,
his very first,
to a reporter who is now famous
for protecting sexual deviants.
A reporter who is also
a very attractive woman.
This is disparate treatment.
Oh, boy.
I could go if I
were an ugly guy?
The agenda issue would be diffused
with the presence of a male.
I hear lawyers
gleefully saying,
"Bloom versus
News Magazine Inc."
"Your Honor, I started
to notice my assignments
"were being determined
on the basis of my sex."
You've got to let her go now.
That's not what I meant.
He's got to let you go.
All right. Enough.
But the intern will be
with you at all times.
What? Intern.
No, you've got to be kidding.
That's what he said.
He's a jerk.
He's the boss.
Not an intern.
I always work alone.
Not this time, Bitsey.
I'm not baby-sitting.
Gale's DNA was everywhere.
His semen was inside her.
He was seen leaving her house.
His prints were all over the
kitchen, including one on the bag.
Half a thumbprint.
That's enough.
He could've touched it before
it was a murder weapon.
You fondle your
friends' garbage bags?
Yeah, I get very touchy
around household plastics.
I'm particularly
fond of Tupperware.
Tupperware?
I'm just saying the bag could've
been sitting on the counter.
He did it. Now he's going to die.
And you know something?
Maybe that's exactly
what he deserves.
But the murder's way
too fucking clumsy.
This guy is an intellectual. Top of
his Harvard class, Rhodes Scholar,
tenured at 27,
two books published.
He's an academic stud.
Look at his wife.
A regular Grace Kelly.
Old money svelte. Father
was ambassador to Spain.
Shit! The light's on again.
Ignore it, it's a rental.
Do you smell anything?
The guy's a flaming Liberal.
A person's politics
has nothing to do
with his tendency
to commit crime.
Wrong.
Shouldn't it smell
if it's overheating?
Seventy-three percent of all
serial killers vote Republican.
Throw your cigarette out,
so we can smell.
You'll stink up the car.
Throw it out.
I'm not going to
fucking pollute.
There's definitely
something wrong with this car.
This is so irritating.
How far to Huntsville?
I'm going to pull off.
"News Magazine reporters
Bitsey Bloom and Zack Stemmons
"entered the rest
area with car troubles.
"Little did they know it wasn't
"just their car
that was in trouble."
I'm a reporter.
You're an intern.
Whatever.
Is it hot?
Jesus, yes!
Isn't it always?
What do I do?
Call the office and get the
rental road service number.
No signal.
God damn it.
I've got to pee.
Zack!
Yeah?
Morning.
Hi.
A little early
for that, isn't it?
The nonsmoking
section's over there.
I meant the book.
Dialogical Exhaustion
by David Gale.
The guy's a genius.
What time is it?
9:15 a.m.
There are 10
prisons around here.
Death row is in the Ellis unit,
but they're moving it to the Terrell
unit at the end of the year.
The waitress's
boyfriend works there.
Her last boyfriend worked
in the Huntsville unit.
The two before that in Walker.
The Estelle unit
has the cutest guys.
And I'm quoting, "My butt's too
big to get an Estelle guy."
Ellis is 15 minutes
out of town.
We've got five
and a half hours.
Never eat in a place where the
menus have pictures of the food.
We should drive into Austin.
Check out the crime scene.
That could be some
great stuff for our story.
This isn't our story. It's not even
a story. It's an interview.
Most importantly for you to
remember, it's my interview.
What do I do for
the next five hours?
Drive around. Look for
a decent restaurant.
Your reputation as
Mike Wallace with PMS
doesn't do you justice.
My reputation got
us invited here.
I play by the rules, even if
my colleagues don't like it.
It's called...
Ambition?
Objectivity.
What can I get you, ma'am?
Just coffee.
Don't push me, smart ass.
You know you're
in the Bible belt
when there are more
churches than Starbucks.
When there are more
prisons than Starbucks.
He's ready for y'all now.
Yes, I am.
I'm not gonna debate with you the
rights and wrongs of the situation.
Our job is to run the
state prison system.
This is not France. This is not
Germany. This is Texas.
And we're gonna
follow Texas law.
You're very welcome, ma'am.
Goodbye, now.
Thank you, Margie.
Correspondents Bloom and
Stevens, I presume?
Yes, hello.
Stemmons.
Sorry.
Won't happen again.
I'm Duke Grover, TDCJ,
Community Relations.
He's usually real
good with names.
And these days I
always like to ask
do you prefer Miss,
Mrs., or Ms.?
Bitsey.
Bitsey it is.
Margie, I'm stealing
your guests.
Okey-dokey.
You ever been in a prison?
Yes.
On death row?
No.
ID's again, please.
All executions in the state of Texas
occur at the Huntsville unit.
But death row is here
for the time being.
This is home to all 442
offenders prior to their date.
Average stay on
the row is nine years.
Some get commuted, but
most get put to death.
It'll put you off your supper,
but then, it's supposed to.
New York
guests for Mr. Gale.
Can I get your bags?
We have three concerns here,
safety, safety, and safety.
The visitation area
is entirely secure.
We just ask that you
don't touch the glass.
Windex gets expensive.
You're not carrying a
weapon, are you, Bitsey?
Sorry. No.
Mr. Stemmons, you packing?
No, sir.
Cell phone?
They're not working.
Then you won't mind
leaving them here.
We also have rules against the
carrying of large sums of cash
and the wearing
of open-toed shoes.
Those will do just fine. You
want to step on through now?
There you go.
Thank you, ma'am.
That's right.
Open-toed shoes?
Drives them crazy.
Your turn, Mr. Stemmons.
Right on through there.
Good.
Should anything unpleasant
occur in the visitation area,
we ask you to stay put.
Please follow the instructions of
our fine correctional officers
should they see fit
to give you any.
Anything you say
can be overheard.
Any discussion of criminal activity
on your part is admissible.
You're not planning on
a jailbreak, are you?
The rain seems
to be holding off.
You watch your step here. This
cement can get pretty slippery.
This is our Japanese garden.
We ask you not to
throw coins in the pond.
Right this way.
Almost there.
Here we are. This is our
visitation area right here.
All yours, Mr. Belyeu.
That's it for me. You
folks have a safe visit.
Thank you.
Bye now.
- Ms. Bloom?
- Yes.
Come right on in here and
make yourself comfortable.
Did that PR man
validate your parking?
He said the gift
shop would do it.
She's a smart one.
Braxton Belyeu,
Mr. Gale's attorney.
This is Zack Stemmons.
My good pleasure.
And right over here,
we have the man of the hour.
Hello.
Hi.
Sit down, Gale.
Prisoner will not stand.
Why can't they
turn that thing down?
My lawyer respectfully requests
that you adjust the volume
on the speaker system.
Gale, sit down.
They're practicing
being cruel and unusual.
I'm sure you're
biting at the bit.
It is our understanding
that you are
to have three
two-hour sessions.
Today, tomorrow, and Thursday.
All at 3:00 p.m.
I'm sorry we can't
afford you more time.
But contrary to popular rumor,
we have not yet begun to fight.
It is our understanding
that you will do this alone.
The magazine would prefer that...
Alone.
Understood.
Also, you'll use no
recording equipment of any kind.
- Correct.
- Excellent.
I have a few papers for which
I need your Jo Anne Hancock.
So if you'd stop by my Austin office
at your earliest convenience.
Thursday morning, say?
Expenses and so forth.
Fine. Till Thursday, then.
Good luck.
I'll stop by later.
What say you and me partake
of a death-defying cigarette
in the visitors' parking lot?
Bye-bye, y'all.
So...
Please pull up a seat.
He's quite a character.
Yes.
He's about the only outside
contact I have now.
And a good friend.
Where's your ex-wife?
I don't want you to ask me
questions about her or my son.
What I offer you is one thing.
Questions about them
are not part of our deal.
Okay.
Just say, "Off the record,"
and I'll take it to my grave.
You can trust me on that.
Does this count as
recording equipment?
How do we start?
We start with
you telling me
what I'm doing here.
No one who looks through
that glass sees a person.
They see a crime.
I'm not David Gale.
I'm a murderer and a rapist.
Four days shy of his execution.
You're here because I
want to be remembered
as much for howl led my life
and the decisions that I made
as for how my life ended.
Why me?
Why not?
You've spent some time behind
bars yourself recently.
I certainly have.
Because you do take
things to your grave.
Protecting sources, even kiddie
porn scum, is the magazine policy
and mine.
I know.
That's your reputation.
I have a hard story for
you to tell, Miss Bloom.
It's not going to be easy.
Where do we begin?
I should tell you how
I became Head of Philosophy
at the University of Austin.
Come on, think.
I want you to reach
back into those minds.
And tell me, tell us all,
what is it that
you fantasize about?
World peace?
Thought so.
Do you fantasize about
international fame?
winning a Pulitzer Prize?
Or a Nobel Peace Prize?
An MTV Music Award?
Do you fantasize about
meeting some genius hunk
ostensibly bad, but secretly
simmering with noble passion
and willing to sleep
on the wet spot?
I'll take two!
What was that?
Kimberley will take two.
You get Lacan's point.
Fantasies have
to be unrealistic.
Because the moment, the second
that you get what you seek,
you don't,
you can't want it anymore.
In order to continue to exist,
desire must have its objects
perpetually absent.
It's not the "it" that you want,
it's the fantasy of "it."
Desire supports
crazy fantasies.
Sorry.
This is what Pascal means when he
says that we are only truly happy
when daydreaming
about future happiness.
It came today.
Or why we say, "The hunt
is sweeter than the kill."
Or, "Be careful
what you wish for."
Not because you'll get it,
because you're doomed
not to want it once you do.
So the lesson of Lacan is
living by your wants
will never make you happy.
What it means to be fully human
is to strive to live
by ideas and ideals.
Not to measure your life
by what you've attained
in terms of your desires
but those moments of integrity,
compassion, rationality,
even self-sacrifice.
Because in the end,
the only way we can measure the
significance of our own lives
is by valuing
the lives of others.
All right,
I'll see you all on Monday.
Sorry about being late.
There was, you know, a thing.
There usually is, Berlin.
I know that I'm
not doing too well.
And to torture a cliché,
I would do anything to pass.
Anything?
Anything.
Okay, Berlin.
I will give you
a very good grade
if you would just
study.
The TA's transcribed the
Governor's radio and TV comments.
Listen to this gem.
"Journalist,
'Governor, don't you think
"'three executions in
one week is excessive?'
"Governor, 'I say bring 'em in, strap
'em down, and let's rock and roll."'
It's good that our governor's in
touch with his inner frat boy.
Will you tell me why you're
not doing this debate?
Telegenics.
You have a cuter butt.
I hadn't noticed.
I know.
I didn't mean that.
I've highlighted some stuff.
He'll do the whole
down-home wisdom thing.
"Capital punishment is God's law,"
"An eye for an eye" and all.
Stick to arguments about rational
facts and watch your ego.
Don't come across as,
"I hate authority because
everyone here wears big hats,
"and nobody in charge
reads The New Yorker."
Anything else?
I'm getting new stats
from Amnesty tonight.
Bring them by Greer's party.
I have papers to grade.
If you have
a hangover tomorrow...
I'm walking away.
10:00 a.m.
Bright-eyed
and bushy-tailed!
Bushy-tailed!
Hey, Jamie. Did you
mark your calendar yet?
I sure did.
One, two, three, four more
days until Mom comes home.
Only four more days?
That's great news.
Can I ask you something?
It's really important.
Of course you can.
Can we have
pancakes for breakfast?
With syrup and strawberries?
We'll have to see.
And chocolate shavers?
No, it's chocolate shavings.
And whipped cream?
Whipped cream?
That's a lot of requests
for one little boy.
Why don't you go to sleep?
Do Cloud Dog, too.
Good night, Cloud Dog.
There you go.
You go to sleep.
Good night.
Don't forget to feed the fish.
What?
Okay.
I'll be back before midnight.
Here's the number if
you have to reach me.
There's chicken in the
refrigerator, if you want some.
That's fine. Maybe I'll fix
myself something later.
Bye.
Dad, did you feed the fish?
Yes, I did.
Now go to sleep.
He's the Immanuel
Kant of the NFL.
He's consistent,
accurate, effective,
and let's not forget boring.
He is boring.
If you want boring,
read William Bennett's Book of Virtues.
I'm still asleep.
Someone wake me up.
John, how are you?
Where's your better half?
My wife?
She's in Spain.
Again? I am sorry.
John, have you seen Alma?
She's been looking for you.
My wife's affair is just
this big, open secret.
Hermeneutical bias.
The only fun truths are the
ones someone's trying to hide.
She's been to Barcelona
four times this year.
I don't think she's
trying to hide anything.
Her father is the ambassador.
Yeah, except the
embassy's in Madrid.
By the way, Berlin's here.
Pretty livid.
Why?
We've expelled her.
She got the letter today.
Took the opportunity to
throw a fit in my office.
Talking about me?
As a matter of fact, we were.
Did he tell you I said
when you were circumcised
they threw away the wrong part?
Yes, he mentioned it.
It's called schmuck.
What?
The part of the foreskin they
throw away after circumcision.
It think it's called schmuck.
Aren't we so fucking clever.
Perhaps I should get another.
Black Bush.
You were a jerk this afternoon.
I didn't know about the
expulsion till just now.
Is that supposed
to be an apology?
No.
It's more like a conciliation.
Ross! Ross!
All right.
"As the poets
have mournfully sung
"Death takes the innocent young
"The screamingly funny
The rolling in money
"And those who
are very well hung"
Gale! Gale!
"There once was
a lesbian from Cancún.
"Who took a young man
up to her room
"Where they argued all night
as to who had the right
"To do what and
how much and to whom"
Enough!
I'm spent!
I have no more.
Ross! Ross!
Okay, I'm finished.
I'm done.
I'm not a student anymore.
I do not think I want
to know what that means.
"There once was
a girl named Berlin
"Who liked a bit now and again
"Not now and again
"But now and again
"And again"
Cute?
Yeah. Very cute.
I have a secret.
But I have to come
over there to tell you.
No.
Here...
You stay back.
...I come.
Woman.
You should stay...
I wasn't after the grade.
I don't think this is such a...
Now we can talk, analyze,
contemplate.
Or you can put
your mouth on my body.
Don't reject me.
Please.
Rip them.
What?
Rip them off.
No. From behind.
From behind.
Do it hard.
Harder.
Bite my shoulder.
Thanks for coming, people.
I don't care where you go.
Come on!
All right, you guys, it's time
to go home! Good night!
It won't work.
That's a faulty argument.
Let's say we found an innocent on
death row. What would change?
After the retrial, the Governor
would go on TV and say,
"See? Thanks to the good people
at Deathwatch, the system works."
If we had absolute proof that
he had executed an innocent,
we could demand a moratorium,
like in Illinois.
Are you okay?
Sorry. Yeah.
But that won't happen.
Dead men can't make a case, and
almost-martyrs don't count.
Got it.
So keep it rational.
And stop that!
What?
Active listening.
I hate active listeners.
They're too busy pretending to
listen to hear what I'm saying.
I can listen and
actively listen
at the same time.
I'm good at it.
Did you bring the Amnesty stats?
Yes.
No. I left them at home.
I have a copy.
You want to tell me what's up?
Nothing.
Everything.
Something profoundly stupid
happened last night.
I hope you used a condom.
Jesus Christ, David.
Was she one of yours?
It was Berlin.
Great.
That's great.
I can hear the grapevine,
"They suspended
her so Gale could
"dick her with
a clear conscience.
"A power differential
equals coercion."
That is great.
You're so weak.
You're not my wife,
Constance. Thank God.
Don't worry, it's not a position
I aspire to. So fuck you!
I didn't mean it that way.
Are you okay?
Really?
Yes! Let's go.
There are 17,000 murders a
year in the United States.
Ten states that have
abolished the death penalty
have a murder rate lower
than the national average.
If he starts with the religious
stuff, just say that
nearly every denomination in the U.S.
opposes the death penalty.
Are you listening?
Yes.
All right, 10 seconds.
Count them in, Mac.
Five, four...
Welcome back to Batter's Box.
We continue our special four-part
program with Governor Hardin.
And arguing capital
punishment with him
is deathwatch regional
co-director, Professor David Gale.
You are up, Governor.
I always say the same thing and
I'm gonna keep on saying it.
I hate killing, and my
administration will kill to stop it.
How about it?
Murderers are not deterred
by the thought of execution.
You know it. Every single
study done on the subject,
and there's been over 200,
you've read them,
has reached
the same conclusion.
Maybe you should
read your Bible.
Deuteronomy: 19:21. "An eye for
an eye, a tooth for a tooth."
What did Gandhi say about that?
"The old law of an eye for
an eye leaves us all blind."
I'm sorry, and with respect,
that's fuzzy liberal thinking.
You believe that?
Of course.
Interesting, 'cause you said it
in a speech in
your first campaign.
He got you there, Governor.
How about it?
Yes, he did.
"If you're not a Liberal at
30, you've got no heart.
"If you're still a Liberal
at 40, you've got no brain."
That's Winston Churchill.
Touché.
What you're
essentially saying is,
and this is to
choose another quote,
"A healthy society must stop at
nothing to cleanse itself of evil."
Yes, I'd have to agree.
Did I say that, too?
No, sir. That was Hitler.
Governor, can't we all just admit
the capital punishment system
in this country is not working?
We are condemning
people to death
based on phony expert testimony
on junk science,
on jailhouse snitches.
Did you know Texas has the highest
per capita incarceration rate
in the world, including in China?
Forty-three people,
Governor, that you executed
were represented by lawyers at one
time disbarred or sanctioned.
There are two men on death
row right now, on this day,
whose lawyers fell asleep
during their cross-examination.
I'm not a lawyer.
Texas Court of
Criminal Appeals ruled
that it was not
a basis for a retrial.
Governor, that's just a
flawed, insane, crazy system.
And a flawed system
will kill innocent men!
All right.
Let him answer.
All right,
we'll play your game.
Name one.
Name one innocent
man that Texas
has put to death
during my tenure.
Of the 100 or so executions...
That's 131,
in case you've lost count.
Let him finish.
Fine. Whatever.
Just give me a name.
I'm gonna write it down.
A man that you can
prove was innocent,
and I'll call a moratorium.
Mr. Gale?
Are we through here, Alan?
We're running out of time.
I'd like to thank my guests,
Governor Hardin
and Professor Gale from deathwatch.
Roll credits.
I hope you will join me tomorrow.
Your exact words were,
"Tell me when my ego's getting
in the way of the work."
Now I'm telling you.
I didn't want to do this.
You put up two
seconds of protest
at the thought of
being on a TV debate.
What does that mean?
Deathwatch suffers
because you're so anxious
to finger authority
to publicly prove David Gale is
smarter than the powers that be.
Work without an audience. Try
squeezing money from the donor list.
Have you licked a single
mail-out envelope?
Mr. Gale?
The Governor went that way.
Ramirez. Austin Police.
This is Officer Hasermann.
Is debating the
Governor a crime now?
No, sir. Rape is.
Berlin had my bite marks...
Gale, time's up.
bruises, her clothes
were ripped.
My skin was found
under her fingernails.
It didn't look like
anything but rape.
Then she drops charges
and leaves town,
making it look
like I was guilty,
and she was too
traumatized to face trial.
My wife read all this sitting in
the airport wondering where I was.
Why I wasn't there
to pick her up.
Took me almost two
weeks to get bailed out.
And the grad student, Berlin?
Why do you think she did it?
To poke her
finger at authority.
Show the powers that be
how much smarter she was.
Grad student's revenge.
I don't really know.
Know where I can find her?
No.
First year I was in here I got
a postcard from San Francisco.
It was signed, "From the student
who would do anything."
Did she say anything else?
"I'm sorrier
than you can know."
Move it, Gale.
I'm running out of time.
Can you imagine his wife letting
him stew in jail for two weeks?
Who can blame her?
Get an address for the Berlin
girl from the university.
Still don't think
he's telling the truth?
On the Berlin rap?
On the whole rap.
Who knows? Anyway, there is
no truth, only perspectives.
If you say there's no truth,
you're claiming it's
true there's no truth.
It's a logical contradiction.
Working on our
philosophy merit badge?
With rape, an accusation
is as good as a conviction.
It sticks like shit.
That's an appetizing metaphor.
Technically a simile.
I think he's telling the truth.
This you know from sitting
in the prison lobby?
It's just my perspective.
Three different
courts found him guilty.
That's enough
perspective for me.
What? 330... What?
Seven.
3303.
3305.
3307. Right there.
Jesus, look at the sign.
Hi. I'm Bitsey Bloom.
This is Zack Stemmons.
You want the tour?
There's a $20 mandatory
donation apiece.
You get a re-enactment photo packet.
It's got five pictures.
Okay.
I got to collect first.
Sure.
I got it.
Got to sign the book. It doesn't
have to be your real name.
It says you're here to do
research on violent crime.
State requires it
for nonprofit shit.
Take a re-enactment
photo packet.
If you guys could share
one, it would be cool.
The fuckers that do my
prints jerk my chain.
That's me.
My boyfriend took it.
We also got a video.
It's $50 'cause
you can see my tits.
There's a version
without tits. It's $35.
Do many people take the tour?
Not so much anymore.
We thought it
would be a busy week
with Gale getting
the prune juice.
So you don't mind living here?
It's better than living
with my dickwad parents.
It starts over here.
She let him
crash here sometimes.
He was constantly wasted.
Exhibit one.
He drank Scotch religiously.
The rest is in the kitchen.
Here's number two.
This is where the tripod was.
My boyfriend borrowed the one
we usually show to folks.
They never found a camera, or
photos, a video or anything.
Gale must have buried them.
These serial killer dudes take
photos to whack off to later.
He's not exactly
a serial killer.
Whatever.
She was totally naked,
right here.
The meter man saw
her through the door.
Gale handcuffed her,
taped her mouth,
then taped a bag over her
head so she couldn't breathe.
He used housewife gloves
so he wouldn't leave prints.
They found sticky stuff
from the tape on them.
We ask folks not to
touch the exhibit.
The totally sick part is where they
found the key to the handcuffs.
We know.
Wait. What?
Where was it?
It was in her stomach, dude.
Gale made her swallow it
before he bagged her.
That's pretty
much the highlights.
Got questions?
I can still smell
he cigarette smoke.
It's the barbecue!
Can you imagine?
That key was in her stomach.
That's so fucking cold, man.
- Zack?
- What?
Isn't that the cowboy
from the rest area?
The same truck.
Weird coincidence?
Coincidences are always weird.
That's why they're coincidences.
Off the record.
Okay. We're off.
Constance was murdered by what's
known as the Securitat Method.
You're handcuffed,
forced to swallow the key,
your mouth is taped, a bag
is sealed around your head,
and you're left to suffocate.
The Securitat
did it to Romanians
when they wouldn't
inform or confess.
Sometimes the bag was ripped off
to give you a second chance.
Otherwise, you died
knowing that the
key to your freedom
was inside of you
the entire time.
It's a cheap but
effective method.
The problem is
I once mentioned it in
an article that I wrote.
Prosecution never knew that.
Someone's framing you?
It's more than that.
There was a tripod.
Right.
Facing her body.
Are we back on the record?
Yes.
The tripod had no
fingerprints on it.
That means somebody brought
it there, set it up,
wiped it clean, and left it.
Why?
It's as if they wanted me to
know that somewhere out there
is a record of exactly what
happened that afternoon.
As if they wanted me to die
knowing that the key to my
freedom is out there somewhere.
Maybe you're being paranoid.
I used to be the state's leading
death penalty abolitionist.
Now I'm on death row! Doesn't
that strike you as a little odd?
Any idea who "they" are?
No, but I've got
someone working on that.
Someone I'm relying on
to prove my innocence.
Belyeu has hired a detective?
A journalist.
She has to help me.
You know I'm innocent.
No.
No, I don't.
Wear me like a fur, Daddy.
Okay, who's your hero?
All right,
you go get Cloud Dog.
Hey, Cloud Dog!
Cali me when you land.
Has any couple ever really
survived a trial separation?
Isn't it contrary to the idea
of trying to work things out?
Don't.
Get in, sweetie.
See you later, alligator.
After a while, crocodile.
Take it easy,
Japa-nee-zee.
Okey-dokey,
artichokey.
Scoot.
Listen.
I sent you an e-mail.
An e-mail?
Just read it.
Come on, sweetie.
You could at
least hide the bottle.
Well?
Officially,
you're on sabbatical.
Unofficially, they
want you out of here.
It was four to two.
How did Ross vote?
I'm not supposed to...
Against you.
And you?
For you.
And against my politics.
Please.
Madam, atención.
My name is David Gale.
I have phoned before, yes?
Can...
What? No, never mind.
Can you please get Sharon Gale?
Yes, Miss Gale!
Hello?
I wanted to hear your
feedback on the idea.
Look, Professor Gale,
I could sit here
like others have,
and plead
departmental cutbacks,
claim you need more publications,
I need a minority.
Whatever.
All bull-geschichte.
Your record's brilliant.
You're an original
voice, worth,
in today's
scarcity-defines-value,
capitalist system under which
we toil, your weight in gold.
Hell, it's not even
your alcohol problem.
It would be nice to have a faculty
member whose crutch wasn't Prozac.
But to speak plain,
if I were to hire you,
in the eyes of the
regents, the alumni,
and every freshman
with an ear for gossip,
I'd be hiring a rapist.
Those charges were dropped.
People would say
you had a good lawyer.
I was innocent.
You don't get it, do you?
You're not politically correct.
Welcome to the club.
Socrates is sentenced to death.
I bet you didn't know that.
He was sentenced to death.
But Athenian law
let the condemned
come up with their own
alternate punishment.
Isn't that a great idea?
Where are the Athenians
when you really need them?
So anyway, Socrates...
And he was ugly.
Did I mention that?
Did I mention that
Socrates was ugly?
Socrates was ugly,
Plato was fat,
and Aristotle was
a prissy dresser.
So anyway, Socrates comes
up with this idea.
He says, "What if I pay
a fine instead of death?"
He suggests a fine.
All he has to do
in order to live is
to come up with
an appropriately
punitive figure.
Guess what he
suggested? $30!
Does that make
any sense? $30.
That's 30 mina. That was the
currency of the day, a mina.
Well, minae.
That's plural. Minae.
$30!
Thirty pieces of silver.
And the judges are so pissed that
more of them voted to kill him
than had voted him
guilty in the first place.
That doesn't make any sense.
Thirty pieces of silver.
Just like the Judas guy.
The Jesus-kisser
who was also a prissy dresser.
Without a successful completion
of an alcohol
treatment program,
you can forget visitation.
You'll be lucky to
get a Christmas card.
That's if there even
is a custody hearing.
What does that mean?
If your wife convinces
a Spanish court
that you're a danger to the child,
you'll never see him again.
He just has to come home.
He's got to come back.
Pete, can we have
another round here?
I'm fine.
I'll just have to
go get him then.
Europe's not Mexico, David. They've
got real borders over there.
You might be able to get in, but
getting out with a 6-year-old?
That's a whole different
kettle of crawdads.
You want to see Jamie again?
Then you get
your life together.
I'm fine.
Pronto.
Who wants to start?
Hi, my name is David,
and I am an alcoholic.
Hi, David.
So, Mr. Gale,
tell me three
personal qualities
that you feel you have
that would make you a
successful Radio Shed manager.
Three.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Welcome back.
Thanks.
You look good.
I feel good.
There's something
that you've got to see.
Betty Sue Johnson
has been rescheduled.
Her execution date
is set for the eighth.
I have a call with
Washington tonight.
If the national director
commits to emergency funds...
She gets commuted and you
prove the system works.
But I'll save a life.
Where did you get that bruise?
Just doing chores.
Is your cowboy
getting rough with you?
There he is.
Dusty, does she ever invite you
over and not put you to work?
All right, tell me her story.
She was sentenced at 17.
I really want to get behind this one.
She's so articulate.
Who did she kill?
She'll put a face
on the death penalty.
Constance, who did she kill?
A cop.
You're crazy.
Not just your medium-range, thinks-
she's-Roosevelt's-bath robe,
but I mean stark-raving,
screws-loose, in-the-belfry insane!
Seventeen.
Four years before she could
legally drink a beer.
But she killed a cop, Constance.
Will you help?
Of course.
You're burning up.
Hi, Mr. Gale.
How are you?
It's good to see...
Caffeine jolt.
We deliver.
Howdy, David.
Howdy, folks.
Hello. My, this is service.
Thank you.
Gladly. Latte on the left
there for you, John.
Mocha.
Thanks.
She's on the phone to Washington.
Sinclair, new National Director.
I'm sure we can get some
pulpit time, maybe some cable.
Cable's good. Listen, I need to run.
I agree the first press release
should focus on
the woman's youth.
I'll have Washington
look into counsel competency.
Though I'm almost sure she's
exhausted this on appeal.
See what resources...
David's going to go.
I almost forgot.
Gale's not around, is he?
No.
Good. Keep it that way.
His relationship
with Death Watch is over.
Last thing we need is this rape
thing coming back to bite us.
These guys don't stay
on the wagon for long.
I'm serious, Constance.
Ban him from the premises.
I realize the two of you...
David!
Sharon, pick up the phone.
I'm begging you.
He's my son, all right?
He's my son, too,
and I want to talk to him.
You've not let... Hello?
Jamie, is that you?
Hey, little moose horn.
I miss you so much.
It's Daddy.
Jamie, wait.
Don't hang up the phone!
God damn it!
Fuck!
You scared me.
My sheep needs a manager.
A manger.
My sheep needs a manger.
Are you okay?
I fell off the wagon,
and I hurt myself.
Come on inside.
Do you know why St. Jude is the
patron saint of lost causes?
'Cause his real name was Judas.
Judas! There were
two Judases.
Judae, who was the saint
guy, and then the other one,
Judas, who was the bad one.
He's the one who ratted out
Jesus and tried to kiss him.
In medieval times, they would
never pray to the good Judas
for fear of getting the bad Judas
on the line just by mistake.
Ergo, they never
really gave him business
unless absolutely desperate.
That's why. And then
they changed his name.
Your mail is blowing.
Shit.
Are you the doctor?
What's wrong with her?
She'll be fine.
How do you know?
Calm down.
She was opening her mail and fell over.
I don't know what's wrong.
Please.
Is there a doctor?
Wait here.
I have to go with her!
Hold up, Professor!
You want to get arrested again?
How do you know who I am?
I watch the news.
Now go wait.
How're we doing?
Fine. How's Constance?
Sleeping.
A leukemia patient's
condition is
very susceptible to
external stress...
What?
Constance's illness requires
a degree of regularity.
Constance has leukemia?
You didn't know?
Wait.
No, I didn't.
It's funny how selfish
we can be, isn't it?
When I first heard Constance was
dying, I was so mad at her.
I thought, "How can
you do this to me?
"I mean, you know how hard it is
for me to need other people."
Why hadn't she told you?
She said she was too busy.
I guess since
death was chasing her,
she wanted to help
other people avoid it.
That's what she
did with her life.
Constance left this world a
better place than she found it.
It's a small but difficult thing.
Let's go.
So, what'd you get?
I talked to the Austin prosecutor.
Belyeu's a joke.
Actually, the exact phrase he
used was, "Big hat, no cattle."
He was sanctioned twice.
What?
Seriously fucked up
the penalty phase.
He could have got life
on mitigating factors.
Despite major pro bono offers
from some of the top
lawyers in the country,
Gale stuck with him all through
the appeals process,
which by the way,
Belyeu continued to screw up.
So, Belyeu's a joke.
Great.
Anything else?
Nothing on Berlin.
We pick up the payola money
in Houston tonight.
Houston?
That's what the head office said.
Overheat light came on twice...
Come on.
Oh, man, I never knew $1
million could weigh so much.
$500,000.
It's still heavy.
But $1 million sounds
better for our...
Excuse me, your story.
$1 million.
No, wait.
$1 million in cash.
Just relax, Zack.
It's only money.
So you coming in?
Excuse me?
You want to come in?
Please.
What? I thought you were
into guys with money.
Zack?
What?
It's open.
Well, maybe the maid forgot.
Look.
We got to call somebody.
Wait.
What is that?
I don't know.
This is not good.
I'm gonna check the bathroom.
No, Bitsey.
Wait there.
Bitsey!
What?
Zack, there could
have been prints.
Look.
The lady at reception says
no one asked for you.
All the keys are different. She
and her husband have masters.
What'd you tell her?
You have a jealous boyfriend.
How about the VCR?
She didn't ask.
I think she assumed it had something
to do with why he was jealous.
You sure we shouldn't
call the cops?
Whoever got in
here without a key
in broad daylight,
was smart enough
not to leave prints.
I have the remote. Here.
You sure you want to
see what's on here?
Try three.
I hope this isn't
what I think it is.
Oh, my God.
Is it her?
That's her.
Belyeu said to bring the
tape first thing tomorrow.
He also said you were right
about not calling the police.
You gonna be all right?
He deserves it
though, probably.
There's a lot of sick
people in this world,
and if they done
wrong and found guilty...
All right, let's just say
Gale's telling the truth.
Maybe some right-wing
fuck set him up,
arranged the perfect murder.
Why would you send a
magazine journalist proof
a few hours before you'd won?
It does not make sense.
No, it's perfect.
Whoever this is knows how hard
it is to get a retrial in Texas.
They know the magazine
can't give this
any substantial play
before the execution.
We'd have to give it to a daily or
a network. That won't happen.
But mostly, they know
I'll tell Gale today.
So?
What if Constance's murder was
just a means of getting at Gale?
Not only to get rid of him, but
to make abolitionists look crazy.
Of course, he sympathizes
with murderers. He is one.
They make sure he sits
six years on death row
for a brutal rape and murder,
then they let him die.
Die knowing everyone will
remember him with disgust.
They destroy his life, his work,
his memory. And they make him watch.
That's a lot of hate.
Well, then why release it?
Hate's no fun if you
keep it to yourself.
We got company.
Who? The cowboy?
And doing
a lousy job of hiding.
He must think we're idiots.
Is he gaining?
No. He's just
sitting back there.
Get a license plate number.
God, I'm sorry.
He's turned off.
What does this guy want?
Fine. Bobbi, could you make
a quick copy of that videotape
and bring in Miss Bloom's
original when that's done?
I don't blame you for
not watching that twice.
I couldn't sleep afterwards.
I understand.
I tell folks I'm no more
afraid of the Grim Reaper
than I am of a Presbyterian
on Mother's Day.
But watching that tape,
I had to keep telling myself,
"That's not Constance,"
just to get through.
Unfortunately,
others may argue the same.
But it's in her kitchen.
In her house.
But currently home to
Weirdoes Incorporated.
Arguably, that tape could've
been made by anybody with $20
and a tolerance for vulgarity.
Will it get us a postponement?
Us?
This ain't my first rodeo,
Miss Bloom.
Now, I got to tell you that
there's a machine a-running.
And come tomorrow
night at 6:00,
that machine gonna
want to be fed.
All here, Mr. Belyeu.
Thank you, Aaron.
Now, to add to our troubles,
your own credibility
may come into question.
Why?
You've been fraternizing
with the condemned.
I've been what?
In the court's eyes,
he's the most likely candidate
to have put you onto that tape.
He's a persuasive man. You're
an out-of-state woman.
That don't look good.
Mr. Belyeu, someone put
the tape in my room.
That's a fact for which
we have no evidence.
Thank you, Bobbi.
Thanks.
Let's not throw a pity party
and sit around reading Kafka.
Could be we find
a sympathetic judge.
Now, I'll file within the hour.
You going to see Gale?
Yeah.
Fine. I'll give you
a call over to
the motel later with an update.
My coat.
Shoot.
What?
You saw him?
Who?
The cowboy.
He was here?
He's in the lobby! See if his
truck's out front. Tail him.
Get a license number.
Find out who he is.
Don't screw it.
It's important.
But how will you
get to the prison?
Taxi.
Fuck!
You're not being straight.
I walk out of Belyeu's office,
the guy's in the lobby!
Maybe you should calm down.
Visitor needs to stay seated.
Maybe you should sit down.
His name is Dusty Wright.
He's the local deathwatch
director before Constance.
He's a bullhorner.
He's a zealot who thinks
that a good demonstration has
to end with riots and arrests.
Deathwatch fired him because
he punched someone at a rally.
But Constance kept
him in the organization.
He adored her. They were close.
Real close.
He testified at my trial.
Testified to support you, or
to oppose the death penalty?
He testified against me.
Against you?
He testified
about the drinking.
Alcohol is a mitigating
factor in capital cases.
I always told
myself that he did it
in some sick way to try to help
me get a reduced sentence.
I guess he believes
I really killed her.
Dusty's a man easily
blinded by hatred.
Maybe he hated you because
you were seeing Constance.
I wasn't seeing Constance.
She had your semen inside her.
I know. Look, it's a little
more complicated than that.
Respect
for life means every life.
When you kill someone,
you rob their family.
Not just of a loved one,
but of their humanity.
You harden their
hearts with hate,
you take away their capacity
for civilized dispassion,
you condemn them to bloodlust.
It's a cruel and
horrible thing.
But indulging that
hate will never help.
The damage is done.
And once we've had our pound
of flesh, we're still hungry.
We leave the death house
muttering that lethal injection
was just too good for them.
In the end, a civilized society
must live with the hard truth.
He who seeks
revenge digs two graves.
They're bringing Betty Sues people out.
Thank you, Dusty.
Just look.
Look at those losers.
Rednecks, ghetto hustlers,
drug addicts, schizophrenics!
They're murderers!
And who cares if they die?
Who cares if the cycle
just goes on and on?
Hey, did you make it
to your meeting today?
Yeah. But I think I have to
find one less guru-like.
Did you take your medicine?
Feel better?
You know those stages
of Kubler-Ross?
The ones the dying go through?
Anger. Denial.
Bargaining.
Depression.
Acceptance.
Which one are you?
Denial.
Denial's good.
That's a good one.
The whole idea of there being
a process makes me tired.
I'm not up to the
job of dying person.
Marveling at blades of grass,
lecturing strangers
to relish every moment.
Mending bridges.
Confessing regrets.
What? No regrets?
Nope.
Wow.
I take that back.
I wish I'd had a child.
Yeah, so do I.
I'm sorry, David.
No.
I guess I just wish
I had risked more.
And not enough sex.
I should have had more sex.
Really?
How many lovers did you have?
Including college?
Including college.
Sex is really... It's not
all it's cracked up to be.
It's so overrated.
You should have had more sex.
You work so hard not to
be seen as a sex object.
Before long,
you're not seen at all.
I see you.
You want to make it five?
Complete the hand?
What? A pity lay?
No, thanks.
It wouldn't be pity.
Are you okay?
Yeah, don't worry.
No, it's good.
Just talk to me.
Let me hear your voice.
I'm here. I'm so happy.
Hold me tight.
God, I'm so scared.
It's okay.
No, don't stop.
Just...
No, stay in me, please.
Okay.
I need just to feel you inside.
I'm right here.
I'm so tired.
I'm so tired of being so afraid.
I know. I'm here.
Help me. Please.
Just make it go away.
I'm right here.
I'm not going anywhere.
Can I help you?
No.
I'm leaving.
I'm sorry. Thanks.
It was Dusty.
He had a motive. He knew you both.
He visited that morning.
If I could answer
that for sure,
we wouldn't be
having this conversation.
It's what I need you for.
It's why I chose you.
Now I've told you everything.
But I still don't know.
I need more time.
You'll find time.
You should have
done this earlier.
You're not here to save me.
You're here to save my son's
memory of his father.
That's all I want.
You're gonna let them kill you?
Bitsey, we spend our whole
lives trying to stop death.
Eating, inventing, loving,
Praying, fighting,
killing.
But what do we
really know about death?
Just that nobody comes back.
But there comes
a point in life,
a moment,
when your mind
outlives its desires,
its obsessions.
When your habits
survive your dreams.
And when your losses...
Maybe death is a gift.
You wonder.
That's it.
Let's go, Gale.
All I can tell you is that by
this time tomorrow, I'll be dead.
I know when.
I just can't say why.
You have 24 hours to find out.
Goodbye, Bitsey.
Miss Bloom?
Yeah.
Thought I'd return your coat.
It's getting kind of chilly.
Any news from our
video intruder friend?
No. Any word on the appeal?
Denied. Tape went to a
federal judge two hours ago.
Now what you got was
definitely a snippet.
Could be your
video supplier friend
has more nasty
previews scheduled.
Best you not get into too
much sightseeing right now.
Just stick close
to your motel room.
How's David?
He's holding up.
Gonna be a hard night.
Will you tell him
I'll take care of it?
About his son, I mean.
I'll do that.
You staying for the execution?
Then I'll see you tomorrow.
Watch yourselves.
Were Dusty Wright
and Constance close?
Yeah. Thick as thieves,
those two.
Lovers?
Whoa, now.
You're plowing a little
too close to the cotton.
That was just a rumor.
Nothing more.
Night-night.
Wake up! Did you throw
the towel on the floor?
What? This towel was
on my bathroom floor.
Did you throw it there?
I guess. What?
It's a motel.
Would you do that at home?
No.
It's not like we're staying
in the frigging Four Seasons.
Come on, get the TV.
We're taking it with us.
What are you talking about?
Where are we going?
Austin. Get the TV.
All right.
Hold on.
Want to make $100?
What do I got to do?
We're going
over the crime scene.
Put the TV on the bed, Zack.
Now, for the next hour, I want
you to do exactly what I say
when I say to do it. If I
say, "Jump," you jump.
You want me to jump?
A figure of speech.
Your boyfriend
put the tripod back.
He's not my boyfriend anymore.
Still have the video camera?
Yes.
Good. Get it. I got
to collect first.
Zack, give her the money.
Can you move that stuff
off the counter for me?
By the lamp.
Yeah, thanks.
Put the gloves
on the dish rack.
I don't have a dish rack.
Zack, could you...
Turn them inside out.
Put the duct tape on the floor.
By the stove.
Could you...
What's your name?
Nico's fine.
Nico, I want you to lie
down facing the counter.
We can imagine that part.
Zack, put her in position.
Okay.
Move this way.
- All right.
- Now forward.
There. Okay. On her side.
Right. Her top leg
out a little.
There.
Now look at this.
She moves her foot.
I noticed this
back at the motel.
She moves her foot.
Quite deliberately.
And then she's still.
For another 15
seconds she's still.
And then she
starts to struggle.
That doesn't make sense.
If this was a murder,
she'd just be struggling and then
she'd be still. She'd be dead.
Maybe she was faking.
Hoping he'd go away.
Or...
We've got to bag her.
We're going a bit too far here.
I'll do it.
Thank you, Bobbi.
Supreme Court death clerk
gave the go-ahead.
Give the keys to Zack and
stand over by the tripod.
Wait three minutes before
you take the bag off.
I'm not sure about this.
It's too dangerous.
Three full minutes. Stand
over there with her.
Keep your eyes on your watch.
Twenty-two seconds.
She shouldn't be doing this!
Oh, my God.
This isn't cool!
No more experiments, all right?
Just tell me what's going on.
Are you okay?
She did it herself.
She used the gloves to keep her
fingerprints off the tape and bag.
Then she put them
back on the dish rack.
But upside down and inside out.
A housewives' habit.
A murderer would've
tossed them aside
like you do with
a towel in a crap motel.
All right, maybe.
But why wear these?
They threw me.
But she needed them.
She knew she would instinctively
try to rip the bag off.
And she swallowed the key
so she couldn't get to it.
She made sure
there was no way out.
Why not hang yourself or take pills?
Why take your clothes off?
Why make it look like a murder?
I don't know.
It's so calculated.
She's handcuffed,
taped at the mouth.
The gloves.
The damn tripod.
Why fake your own murder?
It doesn't make sense.
The woman's a
bleeding-heart abolitionist.
Why frame an innocent man?
Why send Gale to the chair...
What?
She had to know some innocent
jerk would take the fall.
Oh, my God, Zack.
That's it.
That's why!
To prove it happens!
To have absolute proof that the
system convicts innocents.
Get out of here!
No.
That's how she thought.
Think about it! This woman
lived for deathwatch!
If she's gonna die anyway,
why not die for it?
That's why the tripod was here.
To record proof.
Undeniable proof!
That's why we got the video!
A dead woman put
the tape in your room?
No, of course not.
I mean, she needed help.
Someone to keep it, release it.
Someone dedicated to the cause.
Someone she could trust.
What a dump.
The guy's a freak.
Dusty's a bullhorner.
A zealot who's OD'd
on too many good causes.
You know, the original plan
was probably for Dusty
to release the tape
after Gale's conviction.
You know, after a year or so.
It'd force him to dry out,
give him back his dignity.
So Dusty Wright is sitting
on this tape, waiting.
And he's the only
one who knows about it.
So Dusty starts to think
that an erroneous execution
is a lot more politically
useful than a last-minute save.
Because a last-minute save would
only prove the system works.
Almost-martyrs don't count.
Dusty's thinking, "What's one
murder if it stops thousands?"
So, he'll release the whole
tape only after the execution.
Which means he must have
the original somewhere.
What time is it?
It's 4:50.
Bitsey, Jesus.
I want to talk about your tape.
No, meet me down the hill at
the gas station in 15 minutes.
So, don't move from the phone.
Call the second you see his pickup.
Let it ring once.
Then get into the woods.
I know. Go.
Into the woods, Zack.
Go!
Oh, shit.
Details of Gale's last meal
were released today...
and they included
pancakes with maple...
All executions in the state of
Texas take place at 6:00 p.m.
Four pancakes! Maple syrup!
fresh strawberries...
after completion of last words,
the injection is administered.
Fresh strawberries, large!
Fresh strawberries.
sodium thiopental
for sedation purposes.
Reddi-wip whipped cream.
Puts you to sleep...
pancuronium bromide...
Chocolate shake.
to collapse the
diaphragm and lungs.
Potassium chloride
to stop the heart.
Chocolate shavings,
extra chocolate.
and chocolate shavings.
The whole cocktail
costs the state of Texas
approximately
$86. 08 per elimination.
Wagons!
- What do you miss most?
- Food.
talk to her in horse talk?
Shit. No.
Damn!
Come on, cowboy, where are you?
At 8:30 p.m., we
checked the next hotel on the list.
Hurry.
Come on.
Shit!
Ready?
- Fuck!
- He didn't show! Come on!
Please, Bitsey, come on!
Call everyone!
The Governor, the warden, New York,
the Supreme Court death clerk!
How far is it?
You've got eight minutes,
maybe more.
Okay, we'll make it.
You can do it.
Go!
Shower. Go.
Oh, my God.
Give me the time.
...on that big pileup on...
Give me the goddamn time!
Oh, no. Not now.
Not fucking now.
Shit!
Fuck!
Stop executions!
Get the fuck out of
my spot, all right?
How tight are you?
One, two...
How's my light?
A little shine. Right there.
Yeah?
I think he's doing
Larry King Live at 8:00.
Can I get some powder?
Opinion polls
conducted over the weekend
show that 66 percent
of all Americans
are in favor of
the death penalty.
Maybe you can get
a shot of the protestors.
You can see over here
that they're
equally represented.
About 50 percent pro and 50
percent anti-death penalty.
Hi-dee, hi-dee, hi-dee-ho.
Time for David Gale to go!
When Cain killed Abel, God cast him out.
He didn't kill him.
He raped and killed that poor girl.
I think he should die.
Murderers!
They said on TV that he
raped her, then he strangled her.
I think he deserves to die.
They stick that thing in
his arm, he goes to sleep.
If you ask me, they should
use a goddamn pickax.
You're the murderers!
He should die.
A little bitty pinprick...
The state of Texas
has executed David Gale.
He was pronounced
dead at 6:12 p.m.
strapped to
the gurney at 6:02 p.m.
David Gale was
officially pronounced dead...
at 6:12 this evening.
Texas has executed David...
Gale was pronounced...
dead at 6:12...
Death was pronounced
at 6:12 p.m.,
at the Walls Prison, Huntsville.
There was no final statement.
Since none of the victim's
relatives was in attendance...
there will be no statement
from the victim's family.
Here's what we know so far.
Last night,
News Magazine posted on their
website a video obtained
by reporter Bitsey Bloom.
The footage appears to show...
Constance
Harraway committing suicide.
Bloom reports that she received
the tape Friday
morning in a motel
in Huntsville,
where she was staying
while conducting
Gale's last interview.
The tape has been
in the possession of
former Death Watch employee,
Dustin Emil Wright.
As you can see, police have
been in and out of his cabin
all morning, looking for
clues to his whereabouts.
Ever since his
1994 conviction...
been on death row,
awaiting execution.
Blacks and Latinos are
five times more likely
to face the death
penalty than whites.
A fanatic in the movement
to stop the death...
It's all there?
actively seeking
a Dustin Wright.
It appears Wright
withheld a tape to make...
a political point
about the potential
for error in capital
punishment cases.
Passport and ticket as well.
Dana, what everyone
here is asking...
It's a terrible tragedy.
There 'II be an investigation.
I assure you that
this man, Dusty,
will be caught
and shown justice.
Justice, for Christ's sakes!
Ever since this world...
The people of
Texas are not deterred.
We're behind the death penalty
because it works. The system
cannot be blamed for the acts
of a deranged individual
with an ax to grind.
People have been put to death
in the name of justice.
Let's not throw the baby
out with the bathwater, folks.
Of course, the ultimate
irony is that David Gale...
a man who became
an unwitting martyr...
may achieve in
death what he worked for...
but could not
accomplish in life.
This is A.J. Roberts
reporting from Bastrop, Texas.
This just came.
"Key to your freedom"?
What?
It's over.