"THE CABINET
OF DR. CALIGARI"
A TALE of the modern re-appearance of an 11th Century Myth
involting the strange and mysterious influence
of a mountebank monk over a somnambulist.
"Spirits surround us on every side -
they have driven me from
hearth and home, from wife and child."
"My betrothed..."
"What she and I have experienced
is yet more remarkable than the story
you have told me. I will tell you..."
"In Holstenwall,
where I was born..."
"...a traveling fair
had arrived."
"With it, came a
mountebank..."
"My friend, Alan..."
Come to the HOLSTENWALL FAIR!
WONDERS! MARVELS! MIRACLES!
SIDESHOWS - ALL NEW
"Come, Francis--
let's go to the fair."
"The Town-Clerk is in
a bad mood today."
Dr. Caligari
"Wait!"
Sit Down fool!
"I want a permit to operate
my concession at the Fair."
"What kind of a show is it?"
"A Somnambulist."
FAKIR!!
"Step up! Step up!
See the amazing CESARE,
the SOMNAMBULIST!"
That night the first
of a strange series
of murders occurred.
...and the first victim
was the Town-Clerk.
"Step up! Step up!
Cesare who has slept for 25 years
is about to wake. Don't miss this!"
The cabinet of
Dr. Caligari
"Wake up, Cesare!
I, Caligari, you master,
command you!"
"Ladies and gentlemen!
Cesare knows all secrets.
Ask him to look into your future."
"How long shall I live?"
"The time is short.
You die at dawn!"
MURDER REWARD
On the way home...
"Alan, we both love her,
but no matter how she chooses,
let us remain friends."
Night...
"Mr. Francis! Mr. Francis!
Master Alan is dead - murdered!"
"The prophecy of the
Somnambulist!"
"There is something
frightful in our midst!"
"Your suspicion of the somnambulist
seems justified. I shall ask the police
for permission to examine him."
When the shadows
lay darkest...
"Help! Help! It is he!
The Killer!"
"Wake him!"
HOLSTENWALL MURDERER CAUGHT
Attempts Third Killing
Anxious about the
long absence of her father...
"It's true that I tried to
kill the old woman..."
"...and I thought they would blame
the mysterious murderer again..."
"...but I swear I had nothing to do
with the two other murders,
so help me God."
"I thought I might find
my father, Dr. Olsen, here..."
"Oh, yes - the doctor.
Won't you come in and wait for him?"
After the funeral...
Night again...
CESARE!
"It can't have been Cesare.
I've been watching him
for hours, asleep in his box."
"Is the prisoner safe
in his cell?"
"I hope so.
Let me see him"
"He must not
be disturbed!"
"Have you a patient
named Caligari?"
"Only the head of the Institute
can divulge the identity of our patients.
Would you care to see him?"
"But... HE is Caligari!"
While Caligari slept...
SOMNAMBULISM
A Collection from Upsala University
Published in the year 1156
"This has always been
his special study."
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
In the year 1093, a monk named Caligari visited the small towns
Of Northern Italy traveling around with his Somnambulist named Cesare,
whom he carried in a rough wooden case fashioned like unto a
He ordered his Somnambulist, when he had completely forced into his power
to carry out his adventurous plans. For months he caused in town after town
great panic by repeated occurences of murder committed
always under the same circumstances.
Case Histories and Notes
March 12th
A somnambulist was admitted
to the asylum this morning. At last...!
Letter
Now nothing stands in the way of my long cherished ambition.
At last I can put the Caligari theory to the test --
I now shall soon know if this patient can be compelled
to perform deeds he would shrink from in his normal waking state.
Can he be made to commit murder?
Temptation.
"I must know - I will
become Caligari!"
"The sleeper has been found
dead in the ravine."
"The circle is closing in -
DOCTOR CALIGARI!"
"Today he is a raving madman
chained to his cell."
"See, there is Cesare.
If you let him prophesy
for you, you will die!"
"Jane, I love you -
when will you marry me?"
"We who are of royal
blood may not follow
the wishes of our hearts."
"You fools, this man
is plotting our doom!
We die at dawn!"
"He is Caligari!"
"At last I recognise his mania. He believes me
to be the mythical Caligari. Astonishing!
But I think I know how to cure him now."
THE END