Pull yourself together Teddy!
Pull yourself together!
It's just water.
It's a lot of water.
Come on.
- You okay boss?
- Yeah, I'm fine. I just... I just can't
I just can't stomach the water.
- So you're my new partner?
- That's right.
Not the best way to meet with my head
halfway down the toilet.
Doesn't exactly square with Teddy Daniels:
The man. The legend. I'll give you that.
The Legend?
What the hell are you boys smoking
out there in Portland anyway?
Seattle.
I came from the office in Seattle.
How long have you been with Marshals?
Four years.
- So you know how small it is?
- Sure
What about you? You got a girl? Married?
I was.
She died.
- Jesus... I didn't...
- Don't worry about it.
There was a fire in our apartment
building while I was at work
Four People died.
It was the smoke that got her
not the fire. So...
- So that's important.
- I'm sorry Boss.
Where are my goddamn cigarettes?
Well here. Have one of mine.
I could of sworn they were in my jacket
when I got on.
Government employees will rob you blind.
Thanks.
They give you a briefing
about the institution before you left?
All I know is it's a mental hospital.
For the criminally insane.
Well, if it was just folks running around,
hearing voices,
and chasing after butterflies,
they wouldn't need us.
- That's where we're headed?
- Yup.
The other side of the island is rock bluffs
all the way down to the edge
of the water.
The dock, it's the
only way on...or off.
We will be casting off as soon as
you two are ashore.
I'd appreciate if you'd hurry up about it.
- Why?
- Storm's coming.
I've never seen a marshal's
badge before.
I'm Deputy Warden
McPherson, gentlemen.
Welcome to Shutter Island.
I'll be the one taking you up to Ashecliffe.
Your boys seem a little on edge
Mr. McPherson.
Right now, Marshal. We all are.
"Remember us for we too have
lived, loved and laughed"
Electrified perimeter.
How could you tell?
I've seen something like it before.
All right. You gentlemen will be accorded
all the help we can give.
But during the stay you will
obey protocol. Is that understood?
Absolutely.
The red brick bulding on my right
is ward A, the male ward.
Ward B, the female ward, is the one
on the left.
Ward C is that building on the bluffs.
An old civil war fort.
The most dangerous patients
are housed there.
Admittance to ward C is forbidden without
the written consent and
physical presence of both myself and Dr. Cawly.
Is that understood?
You act like insanity is catching.
You are hereby required to surrending
your firearms.
Mr. McPherson, we are duly appointed
federal marshals.
We are required to carry our
firearms with us at all times.
Executive order 319 of the Federal Code of
Penitentiaries states that:
when inside the penitentiary
the offices of that institution
have final authority.
Gentlemen, you will not get through
this gate with your firearms.
Okay. Now that the official stuff is done,
come on boys.
What do you say we go find Dr. Cawley?
So when did she escape? This prisoner?
I'm afraid that Dr. Cawley will have to
fill you in on the situation.
Protocol.
Correctional officers at a mental institution.
That's a weird sight,
if you don't mind me saying
It's the only facility of it's kind in the U.S.
Even in the world.
We take only the
most dangerous, damaged patients.
Ones no other hospital can manage.
And it's all due to Dr. Cawley.
He's created something really unique here.
A hospital for people our society normally...
ID's, gentlemen.
Show your badges, gentlemen.
Dr. Cawley's been consulted
numerous times
- By Scotland Yard, MI5, the OSS...
- Why?
What do you mean?
What do the intelligence agencies want
to consult a psychatrist about?
I guess you'll have to ask him.
- Marshal Daniels.
- Doctor.
Marshal Aule.
- Thank you deputy warden, that will be all.
- Yes, sir.
Pleasure, gentlemen.
He had a lot to say about you.
McPherson is a good man.
He believes in the work we do here.
And what would that be exactly?
A moral fusion between law and
order and clinical care.
Pardon me Doc...
a what between what and what?
Those paintings are quite accurate.
It used to be that the kind of patients we
deal with here
were shackled and left in their own filth.
They were beaten. As if whipping
them bloody would drive the psychosis out.
We drove screws into their brains. We submerged
them in icy water until they lost consciousness.
Or even drown.
- And now?
- We treat them.
Try to heal, try to cure.
And if this fails, at least we provide them
with a measure of comfort in their lives. Calm.
These are...
all violent offenders, right?
They've hurt people.
- Murdered them in some cases.
- In almost all cases. Yes.
Then personally Doctor, I'd have to
say... screw their sense of calm.
It's my job to treat my patients not
their victims. I'm not here to judge.
- So this female prisoner...
- Patient.
Excuse me, patient.
One Rachel Solando,
- Escaped sometime in the last 24 hours.
- Last night.
Between 10 and midnight.
- Is she considered dangerous?
- You could say that.
She killed all three of her children.
She drowned them in the lake behind her house.
She took them out one by one and held their
heads under until they died.
Then she brought them back inside and
arranged them around the kitchen table.
She ate a meal there
before a neighbor dropped by.
And what about the husband?
He died. On the beaches of Normandy.
She is a war widow.
She starved herself when first she came here.
She insisted the children weren't dead.
- Sorry doctor. You wouldn't happen to have an aspirin? Do you?
- Prone to headaches marshal.
Sometimes, but today...
- I'm a little more prone to seasickness.
- Ah, Dehydration...
- You alright boss?
- Yes.
In that case you're quite right.
The simpler the better.
Thank you so much.
Rachel still believes
her children are alive.
She also believes this place is her home
in the Berckshires.
You're kidding me.
She's never once in two years acknowledged
that she is in an institution.
She believes we're all...
deliveryman, milkman, postal workers.
To sustain the illusion that her children never died,
she's created an elaborate fictional structure.
She gives us all parts to play in that fiction.
- So have you searched the grounds yet?
- The warden and his men scoured the island,
not a trace.
What's more disturbing is, we don't know
how she got out of her room.
It was locked from the outside
and the only window is barred.
It's as if she evaporated straight
through the walls.
Brought her right back here after
group therapy, locked her in
I came back for a midnight round
and she was gone.
Seriously doctor, how is it possible
that the truth never gets through to her?
I mean, she's in a
mental institution, right?
Seems like something you'd
notice from time to time.
- How many pairs of shoes are the patients given?
- Two pairs.
Sanity is not a choice, marshal,
You can't just choose to get over it.
So... she left here barefoot?
Come on Doc, she couldn't get ten
yards in that terrain.
Marshal?
Well this is definitely Rachel's
handwriting.
- I have no idea what the "law of 4" is, though.
- It's not a psychiatric term?
I'm afraid not.
Who's 67?
Fuck if I know!
I'd have to say that's quite
close to my clinical conclusion.
So you think it's
random scribblings?
Oh no, not at all. Rachel is smart.
Brilliant in fact.
- This paper could be important.
- Excuse me Doctor, but...
- We're gonna have to hold onto this.
- Of course.
And you say she had to come through here.
After lights out, the orderlies play
cards in here.
Last night there were 7 men sitting
at the base of those stairs playing stud poker.
Yet somehow, Rachel managed
to slip past them.
Why?
How? She turns invisible?
Doctor, we're gonna need access to personnel files
of all the medical staff.
The nurses, the guards, the orderlies.
- Anyone who was working then.
- We'll take your request under consideration.
This is not a request, Doctor.
This is a federal facility
and a dangerous prisoner...
- Patient.
- Patient...
- has escaped now. You will comply...
- All I can say is that I will see what I can do.
Doctor, we're gonna need to speak with the staff,
do you understand?
I'll assemble them in the
common room after dinner.
If you have any further questions feel
free to join the deputy warden in the search.
It's 11 miles to the nearest land
and the water is freezing.
The current was strong last night.
The tide pushing in.
She'd have drowned or been crushed on the
rocks, and her body would have washed back up onshore.
What about those caves down there,
have you checked them?
No way she could get there.
The base of those cliffs are covered
in poison ivy, live oak, sumac
and a thousand plants with thorns
as big as my dick.
You said it yourself marshal,
she's got no shoes.
All right!
Let's check the other side!
- What's that tower?
- It's an old lighthouse.
The guards already searched inside it.
- What's in there? More patients?
- Sewage treatment facility.
It's getting dark soon.
I'm calling this off for the night.
Let's go, boys!
- You were on watch on the landing, huh?
- Yeah.
Can't nobody get in or out of their room
in that corridor without me seeing.
Okay, Rachel Solando,
who else does she have to pass
to get down here?
Me.
Glen Miga.
- Sir, I didn't see nothing.
- And you were at your post all night?
Yes. But I didn't see a thing.
Glen.
Tell me the truth.
I maybe... went to the bathroom.
- What? You breached protocol? Christ...
- I wasn't gone more than a minute.
All right, let's back up here.
Let's all just back up.
Miss Solando was put in
her room for lights out.
Does anybody here know what she did
before that?
Anyone?
Come on. Anyone. Anyone. Anyone.
She was in a group therapy session.
Huh. Did anything unusual occur?
Define "unusual".
- Excuse me.
- It's a mental institution, marshal.
For criminally insane.
"Usual", isn't a big part of our day.
I will rephrase.
Did anything happen last night
during group therapy, that was more...
- let's say, more memorable than...
- Normal?
Exactly!
No. I'm sorry.
Did Mrs. Solando say anything
during group therapy?
She was worried about the rain.
And she hated the food here.
Complained constantly.
Last night included.
So... you were there.
Was there a doctor present?
Yes. Dr. Sheehan led the discussion.
Dr. Sheehan?
Yes. He was running the session.
He's Rachels's "primary".
The psychaiatrist who directly
oversees her care.
We're gonna need to speak with Dr. Sheehan.
I'm afraid that won't be possible.
He left on the ferry this morning.
His vacation was already planned.
He'd putting it off too long.
You're in a state of lockdown.
A dangerous patient has escaped
and you let her primary doctor
leave on vacation?
Of course, he's a doctor.
Do you have the phone number for
where he's gone?
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Is anybody there?
I'm sorry sir, but its all down.
All the lines.
The storm's hitting the
mainland like a hammer.
If you get it working, come find me immediately.
The marshalls need to make an important call.
Yes, sir.
I'm afraid I have evening rounds in the wards,
But I'll be having drinks and a cigar at
my house around 9
If you'd care to drop by
Good, we can talk then, right?
We have been talking, marshal.
Gotta say, I'm thinking I got
into the wrong line of public service.
It is a little overwhelming.
it was constructed during the civil war
The same time as the military fort
housing ward C.
This is the original commander's quarters
and Uncle Sam got the bill.
The commander was court-martialed.
I can see why.
Nice music. Who is that? Brahms?
No.
It's Mahler.
Quite right, marshal.
Forgive me, gentlemen...
My colleague, Dr. Jeremiah Naehring.
"Quartet for Piano and Strings
in A minor"
- Your poison, gentlemen?
- Rye, if you've got it.
Soda and ice please, thanks.
You don't indulge in alcohol?
I am surprised.
Isn't it common for men in your
profession to imbibe?
Common enough.
And yours?
- I'm sorry?
- Your profession, doctor. Psychiatry...
I've always heard it was overrun
with boozers and drunks.
Not that I've noticed.
What's that? Iced tea in your glass there?
Excellent marshal.
You have outstanding defense mechanisms.
You must be quite adept at interrogations, hmm?
Men like you... are my specialty.
You know?
Men of violence.
That's a hell of an assumption to make...
No assumption. Not at all. You misunderstand
me, I said you are men of violence
I'm not accusing you of being violent men.
That's quite different.
Please, please, edify us, doctor.
You both served overseas.
Not much of a stretch, Doc. For all you know,
we were both paper pushers over there
No, you were not.
Since the schoolyard, neither of
you has ever walked away from a physical conflict.
Not because you enjoy it, but because retreat
wasn't something you considered an option.
We weren't raised to run, Doc.
Ah, yes... Raised.
and who raised you, marshal?
Me?
Wolves.
Very impressive defense mechanisms.
Do you believe in God, marshal?
I'm quite serious.
That's rubbish.
Have you ever seen... a death camp, doctor?
[In German]
I have, I was there, for
the liberation of Dakau.
Your English is very good, almost flawless.
His English is very good.
You hit the consonants a tad hard, though.
You're German?
- Is legal immigration a crime, marshal?
- Oh I don't know doctor, you to tell us.
Now listen, we're gonne need those files on Sheehan
and the rest of staff as well.
No personnel files will be released for you.
Period.
- We're gonna need those files.
- Out of the question.
Bullshit, out of the question!
Bullshit!
Who the hell is in charge here anyway, huh?
Dr. Naehring acts as liaison to
our board of overseers.
He relayed your request and it's been refused.
Refused? They don't have the authority
to refuse. And neither do you, sir.
Marshal, continue your investigation
and we will do all we can to help.
This investigation is over.
We're gonna file our reports
and hand it over to...
- Hoover's boys.
- Hoover's boys, that's right.
We'll be taking the ferry back in the morning.
Come on, Chuck.
Nice night.
You'll be bunking in the orderlies quarter.
Hey boss?... We really packing it in?
Why?
I guess, I dunno, I just...
never really quit anything before.
We haven't heard the truth once yet, Chuck.
Listen. Rachel Solando did not slip out of
a locked cell barefoot without any help.
I think she had alot of help.
Maybe Cawley's sitting up in his mansion
right now,
rethinking his whole attitude.
- Maybe in the morning...
- You're bluffing?
I didn't say that.
I found a whole stack of these, Teddy.
Jesus, are you ever sober anymore?
I killed alot of people in the war.
Is that why you drink?
Are you real?
No.
She's still here.
Who?
Rachel?
She never left.
Remember when we stayed in the cabin
in the summer, Teddy?
We were so happy.
She's here.
You can't leave.
I'm not gonna leave.
I love you so much.
- I'm just bones in a box, Teddy.
- No.
I am.
You have to wake up.
I won't go.
You're here.
I'm not.
You have to face that.
But she is.
And so is he.
Who?
Laeddis.
I have to go.
No! Please...just let me hold you.
- Just a little bit longer.
- Oh, Teddy...
You have to let me go.
I can't.
Ain't gonna be no ferry in this shit.
Doctor.
Doctor, doctor.
We need to interview the patients who
were in Rachel's group therapy session.
I thought your investigation was finished?
It's not like we can take the ferry.
Now was Rachel receiving any
other treatment for her illnesses?
Do you know the state of the
mental health field these days, gentlemen?
No. Not a clue doctor.
War.
The old school believes in
surgical intervention.
Psychosurgery.
Procedures like the trans-orbital lobotomy.
Some say the patients become reasonable, docile.
Others say they become zombies.
- And the new school?
- Psycho pharmacology.
A new drug has just been approved.
Authority.
Which relaxes psychotic patients.
You could say it tames them.
- And which school are you in, Doc?
- Me?
I have this radical idea that if you treat a
patient with respect,
listen to him,
try and understand.
you just might reach him.
- These patients?
- Even these.
What should be a last resort is
becoming a first response.
Give them a pill, put them in a corner,
and it all goes away.
Rachel Solando was on a combination of drugs
meant to keep her from becoming violent,
but it was only intermittently effective.
The greatest obstacle to her recovery was
her refusal to face what she had done.
"Was."
Is there a reason you keep referring to
your patient in the past tense, doctor?
Look outside, marshal.
Why do you think?
Next up is Peter Breen. Assaulted
his father's nurse with a broken glass.
Nurse survived, but
her face permaanently disfigured.
I can't wait.
She'd smiles at me.
She was so sweet.
But... I could see it in her eyes.
She liked to be naked.
To suck cock.
Okay, Mr. Breen.
And then she asked me if she can have
a glass of water?
Alone in the kitchen?
Like that's no big deal?
- Why was that a big deal?
- It was obvious.
She wanted me to pull out my thing so she
could laugh at it.
Mr. Breen,
we need to ask you some questions, okay?
When I cut her she screamed
But...
She scared me.
What did she expect?
Interesting.
But we are here to talk
Rachel Solando, okay?
Rachel Solando...
Did you know she had drowned her own kids?
She drowned her kids!
This is a sick fucking world
we live in. I'll tell you that...
You know what? They should be gassed.
All of them... the retards, the killers
the niggers. You kill your own kid?
Gas the bitch!
Would you... stop that?
- A nurse?
- Please. Stop that.
A nurse maybe. Maybe she had kids, huh?
A husband...
Just trying to make ends meet,
to lead a normal life...
And it says in your file that uh...
You tore her face off, didn't you?
Congratulations, no more normal
for her, not ever again, no.
Do you know what she was afraid of?
You.
Could you stop that, please?!
Stop that!
Please... stop!
You know a patient by the name of Andrew Laeddis?
- I want to go back.
- Take him!
I'll never get out of here.
I'm not sure that I should.
Excuse me for saying this,
- Miss Kearns...
- Misses.
Mrs. Kearns.
But you seem...
quite normal,...
I mean in comparison
with the other patients here.
Well, I have my dark days
I suppose everybody does.
The difference is that most people don't kill
their husbands with an axe.
Although personally I think if a
man beats you and fucks
half the women he sees
and no one will help you,
axing him isn't the least understandable
thing you can do.
Maybe you shouldn't get out.
And what would I do if I did?
I don't know the world anymore.
They say there are
bombs that can reduce whole
cities to ash
And what do they call "televisions"...
voices and faces coming from a box.
I hear enough voices already
What can you tell us about Rachel?
Um. Not much, she... she keeps to herself.
She believed her kids were alive.
She thought she was still living
in the Berkshire and we were all neighbours
- The milkman, postmen...
- Deliveryman,
And Dr. Sheehan was there that night?
Yes. Um.
He talked about anger.
Tell me about him...
What's he like?
I think he's uh...
Okay... nice.
Not hard on the eyes
as my mother would say.
Did he ever make a pass at you?
No.
No, Dr. Sheehan is a good
doctor, he would never...
Could I have a glass of water, please?
No problem.
Thank you, marshal.
I have just one more question for you
Mrs. Kearns.
Did you ever meet a patient
named Andrew Laeddis?
No.
Never heard of him.
She was coached.
She used practically the same words as
Cawley and the nurse.
- It's like she'd been told exactly what to say.
- Who is Andrew Laeddis?
You asked every one of those patients
back there about him. Who is he?
What the hell, boss, I'm your partner
for the Christ sake!
We just met, Chuck.
Been on the beat a long time.
You got a duty, got a career
and what I'm doing,
not exactly by the book.
I don't give a damn about "by the book", boss
I just to know what the hell is going on.
When this case came over the wires,
- I requested it specifically. Do you understand?
- Why?
Andrew Laeddis,
was the maintenance man in the apartment
building where my wife and I lived.
Okay.
He was also a firebug.
Andrew Laeddis lit the match,
that caused the fire that killed my wife.
Let 'em out!
What happened to Laeddis?
Got away with it.
Laeddis got away with it and disappeared.
About a year ago, I opened up the
newspaper and there he is.
He's an ugly looking son of a bitch.
He had a new scar from his right temple
down to his left lip.
Eyes different colors.
Not the type of face you forget.
He'd burned down a schoolhouse. Killed 2 people.
He said voices told him to do it.
First he was sent to prison
and then he was transferred here.
- Then what?
- Then, nothing.
He vanished like he never existed.
No record whatsoever.
I'm sure he's not in ward B
that leaves ward C.
Or he could be dead.
So could Rachel Solando for that matter.
Lot of places to hide a body here.
Only one place
no one really knows.
That patient, Bridget Kearne,
when she sent me for water,
she said something to you back there, didn't she?
No.
Come on boss!
She wrote it.
Boss!
We gotta get indoors. It's turning
into fucking Kansas out here...
- All right.
- Now. Let's go!
Watch out!
Jesus!
Come on! Let's go back!
Jesus Christ!
Damn it!
- Are you okay boss?
- Yes. That's all right.
So... if Laeddis is here...
What are you going to do boss?
I'm not here to kill Leaddis.
If it was my wife
I'd kill him twice.
When we got through the gates of Dakau,
the SS guards surrendered.
The commandante tried to kill himself
before we got there...
but he botched it.
Took him an hour to die.
When I went outside,
I saw all the bodies on the ground.
Too many to count.
Too many to imagine.
So yeah
The guards surrendered, we took
their guns, we lined them up...
It wasn't warfare,
it was murder.
Yeah I've had enough of killing.
That's not why I'm here.
So what is this all about?
After Laeddis vanished,
I started doing some checking
on Ashecliffe.
A lot of people knew about this place, but no
one wants to talk...
You know? It's like they're scared of something
You know this place is funded by
a special grant
from the House of
Unamerican Activities Committee.
HUAC. And how exactly are we fighting
the Commies from an island in Boston Harbor?
By conducting experiments on the mind.
At least that's my guess.
And you think thats going on in here?
Like I said, no one would talk, right?
Until I found someone
who used to be a patient here.
Guy's name is George Noyce.
Nice college kid.
Socialist.
He gets offered some money for some
psych study. Guess what they were testing?
- Drug tests.
- So he starts seeing dragons everywhere.
Almost beats his proffesor to death
Ends up here in Ashecliffe.
Ward C.
They released him after 1 year, right?
What does he do?
Two weeks on the mainland he walks into
a bar and stabs three men to death.
His lawyer pleads insanity,
but Noyce...
stands up in the courtroom and
he begs the judge,
for the electric chair.
Anywhere but not a
mental hospital.
Judge gives him life in the Dedham prison.
- And you found him?
- Yes, I found him.
He's a mess
But it is pretty clear from what he tells me,
they're experimenting on people here.
I don't know, boss.
- How do you believe a crazy guy?
- That's the beauty of it.
Crazy people are a perfect subject.
They talk, but nobody listens.
I stood in Dakau.
We saw what human beings are capable
of doing to each other, right?
For Christ sake we fought a goddamn war
to stop them,
and now find out it may be happening here?
On our soil?
No.
So what are you really here to do, Teddy?
I'm gonna get the proof,
I'm gonna go back, and blow
the lid off this place.
That's it.
Wait a minute.
You started asking around about Ashecliffe.
Waiting for a chance to get out here
then suddenly they need a US marshal?
I got lucky. There was a patient escape,
it was the perfect excuse.
No, no, no boss.
Luck doesn't work that way.
The world doesn't work that way. They got an
electrified fence around a septic facility.
Ward C is inside a Civil War fort?
A chief of staff with ties to the OSS
Funding from HUAC?
Jesus Christ! Everything about this place
stinks of "government ops".
- What If they wanted you here?
- Bullshit.
- You were asking questions.
Bullshit? We came in for Rachel Solando? Where is
one shred of evidence that she even existed?
There's no way they could of known I'd be
assigned to this case. No way...
While you were looking into them,
they were looking into you.
All they need to do
is fake an escape to get you here.
And now they have you.
They have us both, here, now.
Marshal, are you out here?
This is deputy warden McPherson.
Marshal!
How about that? They found us huh.
It's an island, boss. They're always gonna find us.
I know you are in there...
We're getting off of this Goddamned island.
You and me.
Come on!
- Come on!
- Go!
Get dried off.
Dr. Cawley wants to talk to you. Now!
And hurry up, this thing is turning
into a goddamn hurricane!
I dropped those suits off to be cleaned.
It should be ready by tomorrow.
That is if we don't all wash away first.
Speaking of which, I'm afraid your smokes were
pretty much done for.
So...
This is our only choice, huh?
Got something really nice in prison already
if that don't work for you...
Now that you mention it, these are just fine.
That's why I must repeat my insistence
that all ward C patients
be placed in manual restraints.
If the facility floods, they'll drown.
You know that.
- That would take a lot of flooding.
- We are on an island,
in the middle of the ocean,
during a hurricane.
A lot of flooding seems like a
distinct possibility.
It's a gamble, Steven.
say the power fails
There's a backup generator.
And if that goes? The cell doors
will open.
Where are they going to go?
Hmm?
They can't just hop a ferry, scoot over
to the mainland and wreak havoc.
You're quite right. They're far more likely
to wreak havoc right here on us.
If they're manacled to the floor, they'll die.
That's 24 human beings.
You can't live with that, can you?
Frankly, if it were up to me,
I'd put all 42 in ward A and B in
manual restraints as well.
Excuse me
- Marshal.
- I'm sorry doctor, I just have one quick question.
Yes, I will be with you in a moment.
We spoke this morning
about Rachel Solando's note
The law of 4, I loved that.
You said you had no idea what
that second line could refer to. Correct?
Who is 67?
Yes, I'm afraid I still don't.
None of us do.
Uh huh. Nothing comes to mind.
Nothing?
Because I believe I just heard
you say that there are
24 patients in ward C.
And 42 of patients, in wards A and B
Which means there is a total of what?
66 patients here in this facility.
That is correct, yes.
Then it seems that
Rachel Solando was suggesting
you have a 67th patient, doctor
- But I'm afraid we don't.
- This Is ridiculous.
- What are you doing here?
- We are doing our goddamn job.
Didn't McPherson tell you the good news?
No, what's the good news, doctor?
Rachel has been found.
She's here.
Safe and sound.
There is not a mark on her.
Who are these men?
Why are they in my house?
Police officers, Rachel.
They... have a few questions.
Ma'am.
There's been a sighting of a known
Communist
subversive in this area
passing out literature
Here?
In this neighborhood?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
If you can tell us what you did
yesterday, where you were,
it would really help us narrow our search.
Yes...
Well, I...umm
I made breakfast for Jim
and the children,
and then I...
I packed Jim's lunch
and he left.
Then I sent the children off to school.
And then...
I decided to take a long swim in the lake.
I see...
And after that?
After that...
I thought of you.
I... I'm sorry, ma'am.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't you know how lonely I've been, Jim?
You're gone...
You're dead.
I cry every night.
How am I supposed to survive?
God.
Rachel... it will be all right.
I'm so sorry, but...
everything is gonna be all right? Okay?
I buried you.
I buried an empty casket. Your body
rained down lumps of flesh splashing
into the sea eaten by sharks.
My Jim is dead,
So who the fuck are you?
Who the fuck are you?!
Who are you?! Who are you?!
I'm sorry about that.
I didn't want to interrupt, I thought
she might tell you something, but...
we found her down by the lighthouse,
skipping stones.
We have no idea how she got out there. I'm going
to ask you both to go down into basement.
There's food, water, and cots.
It's the safest place to be
when the hurricane hits.
Are you all right?
You look pale.
I'm fine, it's just uh...
Boss, are you okay?
It's just so Goddamn bright? Isn't it?
Photo sensitivity, headaches sometimes?
Marshal are you having a migraine?
I'll be alright.
- What's wrong with him.
- Take these, marshal. You'll sleep a couple
of hours, wake up clear as a bell.
He's having a migraine.
Imagine someone sawed open your head and
filled it with razors then shook it
as hard as they could.
Take the pills, marshal.
- No... I don't want the pills.
- It'll stop the pain. Take the pills.
He's going to need to lie down.
Careful. All right.
Gonna be okay. Relax.
- Who is that?
- Him?
That's the warden.
Don't you worry about him, alright?
Looks like an ex-military prick.
You know what? I ain't gonna argue
with you on that one.
You should have saved me.
You should have saved all of us.
Hey buddy. Hey.
Laeddis.
Yes.
Hi, buddy.
No hard feelings, right?
No hard feelings.
Little something for later.
Because I know how much you need it.
Clock's ticking, my friend.
We're running out of time.
Give me a hand here.
I could get into trouble.
I'm dead?
I'm so sorry.
Why didn't you save me?
I tried, I wanted to,
but by the time I got there,
it was too late.
See?
Aren't they beautiful?
Why are you all wet, baby?
Laeddis isn't dead.
He isn't gone.
He's still here.
I know.
We need to find him, Teddy.
You need to find him and
you kill him dead.
Shhh. It's okay.
Shh. Again!
The generator is faulty.
Are you okay boss?
This goddamn migraine!
Back up generators failed.
The whole place has gone crazy.
What do you want to do?
Christ!
No, no, no!
Put it down.
Now! Now!
You think the whole
electrical system is fried?
I'd say that it's a good possibility.
All electronic security...
fences, gates, the doors
Come on.
Nice day for a stroll
don't you think?
To ward C for example.
Maybe we'll run into Andrew Leaddis.
The guy I told you about, George Noyce?
He told me this is where they keep
the worse ones.
The guys even the other inmates
are scared of.
Noyce give you anything on the layout?
Not really.
All that he remembers was people
scream day and night. There were no windows.
There were bars everywhere.
Jesus Christ!
First time
on ward C, right?
- Yes, yes...
- Yes.
- Yeah, heard stories, but...
- Trust me, sons. You haven't heard shit.
We got most of the bugsies locked down now,
But some of them are still loose.
If you see one don't try
to restrain him yourselves.
These fuckers will kill you.
Clear?
Alright. Get your asses moving then.
Go on.
He's here.
Laeddis.
I can feel him.
Tag! You're it.
Ted!
Listen to me!
Listen!
I do not want to leave, all right?
Why would anyone want to?
We hear things here.
About the outside world.
About atolls.
About the h-bomb tests.
You know how
a hydrogen bomb works?
- With... Hydrogen?
- That's funny.
- Boss!
- Other bombs explode, right?
But not the hydrogen bomb
It implodes.
Creating an explosion to the thousandth
millionth degree.
- Do you get it?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Do you?
- I get it!
Let em go!
No!
What are you doing?
Jesus Christ, Teddy. Jesus!
You got Billings?
What's the fucks the matter with you guys?
Catch them, not kill them!
He jumped at us.
You give me a hand with him.
We've got to get him to the infirmary.
No! Not you, not you.
Take a walk.
Come on!
Paula's gonna have my Goddamn
balls for this..
Laeddis....
You're dead, we're all dead.
This is hell, we're in hell.
Please...
...................
Stop me.
Before I kill more.
Go!
Please, please!
Laeddis ...
You told me I'd be free of
this place.
You promised.
You lied.
Laeddis?
Laeddis!?
That's pretty damned funny.
Your voice...
Don't you recognize it?
After all the talks we've had?
After all the lies
that you've told me?
Let me see your face.
They say I'm theirs now.
They say I'll never leave here.
Your match is about to go out.
Let me see your goddamn face now!
Why?
So you can lie to me more?
- This isn't about the truth!
- Yes it is.
- It's about exposing the truth.
- This is about you!
And Laeddis.
That's all it's ever been about.
I was incidental.
A way in.
George?
George Noyce?
No, it's not possible,
You can't be here.
Do you like it?
Who did this to you, George?
You did!
What the hell do you mean?
What are you talking
all of your fucking talk
And I'm back here because of you!
George, I how did they get you out of Dedham.
Huh?
However this happened, Im gonna
find a way to fix this. You understand me?
I'll never get out now.
I got out once, But not twice, never twice.
- Tell me how they got you here?
- They knew!
Don't you get it?
Everything you were up to.
Your whole plan.
This is a game. All of this...
is for you.
You're not investigating anything.
You're a fucking rat
in a maze.
George...
you're wrong.
Really?
Been alone much since
you got here?
I'm been with my partner.
You have never worked
with him before, have you?
He's a...
US Marshal from Seattle.
You have never worked
with him before, have you?
George, look...
I know people.
I trust this man.
Then, they've already won.
Fuck!
They're going to...
take me to the lighthouse.
They're going to
cut into my brain.
And I'm only here because of you!
George, I'm going to get you out of here.
You're not going to the lighthouse.
You can't dig out the truth and
kill Laeddis at the same time.
You've got to make a choice
you understand that, don't you?
I'm not here to kill anyone.
- Liar!
- I not gonna kill him! I swear to you ...
She's dead.
Let her go...
Let her go.
Tell him Teddy...
Tell him why.
You've got to do it.
There's no other way.
- Let her go.
- Tell him about the day you brought me my locket...
You've gotta do it!
How I told you my heart was breaking.
And you asked me why?
She's fucking with your head.
And then i told you
it was from happiness.
She'll kill you. She's going to kill you.
You want to uncover the truth?
You've gotta let her go ...
- I can't.
- You have to let her go!
I can't!
I can't.
Then you'll never leave
this island.
Dolores?
He's not in this ward.
He was transferred...
Out of here.
If he's not in ward A,
there's only one place he can be
The lighthouse.
Hey!
God help you.
Boss, we got problems.
McPherson and Cawley are in the building.
They heard an orderly went batshit on a patient,
They're looking all over the place for him.
They're on the way to the roof.
Let's get the hell out of here.
This way.
Just keep going.
We belong here
- What happened to you?
- What do you mean?
Where were you?
After we got that guy to the infirmary,
I took a little detour
to patient records.
Did you ever find Laeddis?
No.
- No. I never found him.
- Well I've got the next best thing.
His intake form.
It was the only thing in his file.
No session notes. No incident reports.
No photographs... just this.
It was weird.
Here, take a look.
I'll look at it later.
What's the matter, boss?
I'll take a look at it later,
that's all.
Ashecliffe's that way.
I'm not going to Ashecliffe.
I'm going to the lighthouse.
I'm going to find out what
the fuck is happening on this island.
Here it is.
Damn!
We're too far South.
We're gonna have to double back.
There's no way we could cross those rocks.
There could be a way behind those trees.
Maybe a path that goes around the rocks
that leads over to the lighthouse.
What are we doing here?
We've got the intake form.
It proves there's a 67th patient...
which they've said repeatedly doesn't exist.
I'm getting to that lighthouse.
Do you understand?
What the hell can I say to you
to stop you?
Why would you want to Chuck?
Why?
Because climbing down there
when it's dark is a thin step short
to suicide. That's why.
Okay.
Maybe you better sit this one out then.
You brought me into this, boss.
And now I am trapped here on this rock.
On this island.
Without no one to rely on but eachother.
And now you're acting like.........
Like what? Like what?
How am I acting?
What the hell happened back there
in those cells, Ted?
- What do you think the weather is like in Portland, Chuck?
- I'm from Seattle.
Seattle?
I'll going on...alone.
I'm going with you, boss.
I said alone.
Fine.
Damn it!
I knew it wouldn't take long.
But I couldn't get to it. The tide was up.
Chuck!
Come on!
Where are you, Chuck?
Chuck!
Who are you?
I'm Teddy Daniels.
I'm a cop.
You're the marshal.
That's right.
Would you mind...
taking your hand from behind
your back, please?
Why?
Why?!
I want to make sure what you're
holding won't hurt me.
I'm gonna keep this...
If you don't mind.
Fine by me.
You're Rachel Solando.
The real one.
Did you kill your children?
I never had children.
I was never married.
And before I was a patient
in Ashecliff, I worked here.
You were a nurse?
I was a doctor, marshal.
You think I'm crazy?
- No, I ...
- And if I say I'm not crazy ...
well that hardly helps, does it?
That's the Kafkaesque genius of it.
People tell the world you're crazy
and all your protests to the contrary,
just confirms what they're saying.
I'm not following you.
I'm sorry.
Once you are declared insane,
then anything you do is called
a part of an insanity.
Your reasonable protests
or denial.
Valid fears,
paranoia.
Survival instincts.
Defense mechanisms.
You're smarter than you look marshal.
That's probably not a good thing.
Tell me something...
Yeah...
What happened to you?
I started asking about these large
shipments of sodium-anatol.
- An opium-based hallucinogen.
- Psychotropic drugs.
I asked about the surgeries, too.
Ever heard of trans-orbital lobotomy?
They zap the patient with electroshocks,
then go through the eye with an ice pick
and pull out some nerve fibers.
Makes the patients much more obedient.
Tractable.
It's barbaric.
Unconscionable.
Do you know how pain enters the
body marshal? Do you?
Depends on where you hurt.
No, it has nothing to do with the flesh.
The brain controls pain.
The brain controls fear, empathy,
sleep, hunger, anger... everything.
What If you could control it?
The brain?
Re-create a man,
so he doesn't feel pain.
Or love. Or sympathy.
A man who can't be interrogated
because he has no memories to confess.
You can never take away
all a man's memories.
Never.
Marshal, the North Koreans
used American POWs
during their brainwashing experiments.
They turned soldiers into traitors.
That's what they are doing here.
They're creating ghosts to go out in the world.
And do things sane men never do.
To have that kind of ability, that kind of knowledge.
That would take years.
Years of research,
hundreds of patients to experiment on.
50 years from now,
people will look back
and say, "Here. This place
is where it all began."
The Nazis used the Jews.
The Soviets
used prisoners in their own gulags
and we...
We tested patients,
on Shutter Island.
No, they won't ...
No
You do understand
That they can't let you leave?
I am a federal marshal ...
They can't stop me.
I was an esteemed psychiatrist,
from a respected family.
It didn't matter.
Let me ask you ...
any past traumas in your life?
Yes. Why? Why would that matter?
Because they can point to some
event in your past and say
it is the reason you lost your sanity......
So that when they commit you here
Your friends and colleagues will say,
"Of course he cracked."
"And who wouldn't have,
after what he'd been through."
That could be said of anyone
- anyone at all.
- The point is they're going to say it about you.
How's your head?
- My head?
- Any funny dreams lately?
Trouble sleeping? Headaches?
I am prone to migraines. Yes.
Jesus!
You haven't taken any pills, have you?
- I mean even aspirin?
- They hit the aspirin?
Jesus!
And you ate the food in the cafeteria and drank
coffee they gave you.
You tell me at least that
you've been smoking your own cigarettes.
No... no.
No. I haven't.
It takes 36 to 48 hours for
neuroleptic narcotics...
To reach sufficient levels in
the blood stream.
Pulse becomes first
First the fingertips and then
eventually the whole hand.
Seen any waking nightmares lately,
marshal?
Tell me what goes on in that lighthouse?
Tell me.
Brain surgery.
"Let's open the skull and see
what happens if we pull on this" kind.
"We learned it from the Nazi's" kind.
It's where they create the ghosts.
Who knows about this?
On the island I mean. Who?
Everyone.
Oh come on. The nurses? The orderlies?
- They couldn't possibly know...
- Everyone.
You can't stay here.
They think I'm dead, that I drowned. I'm afraid
if they come looking for you, they might find me.
I'm sorry, but you have to go.
I'm gonna come back for you.
I won't be here. I move during the day.
new places every night.
But I could come get you
off of this island.
Haven't you heard a word I've said?
The only way off the island
is the ferry and they control it.
You'll never leave here.
I had a friend.
I was with him yesterday,
but we got separated.
Have you seen him?
Marshal...
You have no friends.
There you are.
We've been wondering when
you'd show up.
Have a seat.
Come on.
Taking a leisurely stroll? Were we?
I was just...
just looking around.
Did you enjoy
God's latest gift?
- What?
- God's gift.
The violence.
When I came downstairs in my home
and I saw that tree in my living room,
it reached down for me like a divine hand.
God loves violence.
- I hadn't noticed.
- Sure you have.
Why else would there be so much of it?
It's in us.
It's what we are.
We wage war, we burn sacrifices,
we pillage and plunder
and tear at the flesh
of our brothers
and why? Because God gave us violence
to wage in his honor.
I thought God gave us moral order.
There is no moral order
as pure as this storm.
There's no moral order at all.
There's just this:
can my violence conquer yours?
- I'm not violent.
- Yes you are.
You're as violent as they come.
I know this because I'm as violent as they come.
With the constraints of society,
we are lifted and
If I was all that stood between you and a meal, you
would crack my skull with a rock and eat my meaty parts.
Wouldn't you?
Cawley thinks you're harmless, that you can be
controlled, but I know different.
- You don't know me.
- Oh but I do. Oh I know you.
We've known each other for centuries.
If I was to sink my teeth into your eye
right now,
would you be able to stop me before I blinded you?
Give it a try.
That's the spirit.
Where have you been?
Wandering, just looking at your island.
Oh I forgot. You're leaving.
Now that Rachel has been found.
Sure. Yeah.
Big meeting?
Oh, yes ...
Apparently there was an unidentified man
in ward C yesterday
He subdued a highly dangerous patient.
Quite handily.
Is that so?
It seems he had a long conversation with a
paranoid schizophrenic, George Noyce.
This Noyce,
you said his name was,
- he's delusional?
- Oh extremely. He can be quite upsetting.
In fact, two weeks ago, a patient
got so wound up
by one of Noyce's stories
that he beat him up.
Cigarette?
Oh. No, thanks.
I quit.
So, you're taking the ferry?
Oh yes. Absolutely. I uh...
I think we've gotten
all we came here for so.
"We" marshal?
Speaking of which. Have you
- seen him, Doctor?
- Who?
My partner, Chuck.
You don't have a partner, Marshal.
You came here alone.
You know, I've built something valuable here.
And valuable things have a way of
being misunderstood in their own time.
Everyone wants a quick fix,
they always have.
I'm trying to do something that people,
yourself included, don't understand.
And I'm not going to give up
without a fight.
I can see that...
So tell me again
about your partner.
What partner?
Marshal...
Going somewhere?
No. Just heading out
to the ferry. So...
I'm afraid it's the other way.
If you wait a moment,
I'll find someone who can take you
to the dock.
What is this, doctor?
It's just a sedative.
- It's for precaution.
- Precaution?
What are you going to do?
Kill me? Marshal.
You think you deserve it?
For what?
For provoking you?
and, forgive me,
what doesn't provoke you?
Remarks...
- Words...
- Nazis!
Well that, too.
And of course, memories, dreams...
Did you know that the word "trauma" comes
from the Greek for "wound"?
And what is the German word for "dream"
"Traumen".
Traumen.
Wounds can create monsters.
And you ...
you are wounded, marshal.
Wouldn't you agree,
when you see a monster
you must stop it?
- I agree.
- Yes...
What are you doing, baby?
You've got to get to the ferry.
No. No.
No.
If the world thinks that Chuck is dead,
then he is perfect for their experiments.
There's only one place they'd take him.
You go there and you'll die.
He's my partner. If they are hurting him, if they are
holding him against his will, I've got to bring him out.
I can't lose anyone else.
Don't go, Teddy.
Please don't do this. Don't go.
I'm sorry, honey.
I love this thing because
you gave it to me
But the truth is ...
it's one fucking ugly tie.
No!
Don't move!
Stay where you are!
Are you going to kill me?
No.
I'm not gonna kill you.
Why are you all wet, baby?
- What did you say?
- You know exactly what I said.
The rifle's empty by the way.
Have a seat.
For god's sake dry off
you're going to catch a cold.
Alright.
How badly did you hurt the guard?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yes. He's here.
Have Dr.Sheehan take a good look
at your man before you send him up.
So, Dr. Shehan...
He came on the ferry
this morining.
Not exactly.
You blew up my car.
I really loved that car.
Sorry to hear about that.
Tremors are getting pretty bad.
How are the hallucinations?
Get out of here, Teddy.
This place is gonna be the end of you.
- Not bad.
- They'll get worse.
I know.
Dr. Solando...
she told me about neuroleptics.
Did she now?
And when was this?
I found the doctor, in a cave out by the cliffs.
But you'll never get to her.
I don't doubt it.
Considering she's not real.
But your hallucinations are
more severe than I thought.
You are not on neuroleptics.
You are not on anything
as a matter of fact.
Then what the fuck is this?
Huh, what the fuck is this?
Withdrawal.
Withdrawal?
From what? I haven't even had a Goddamned
drink since I've been on this island.
Chlorpromazine.
I'm not a fan of pharmacology
but I have to say in your case ...
- Clorpro... what?
- Chlorpromazine.
The same thing we've
been giving you for the past 24 months.
So for the past two years
you've had somebody slipping
me drugs in Boston. Is that it?
Not Boston.
Here.
You've been here for two years.
A patient of this institution.
After everything I seen here, doctor,
you really think you're gonna
convince me I'm crazy, huh?
Do you know the kind of people I deal with everyday?
I'm a U.S. marshal. For Gods sake.
You were a U.S. marshal.
Here's a copy of the intake form.
You broke into ward C for
proof of the 67th patient
If you'd gotten it to the mainland,
you could have blown the lid off this place.
- Wait... wait.
- But somehow
you couldn't find time
to look at it. Well read it now.
Go ahead.
The patient is highly intelligent,
highly delusional.
Decorated army veteran.
Present for the
liberation of Dakau.
Former U.S. marshal.
Known proclivity for violence.
Shows no remorse for his crime because
he denies
that the crime ever took place.
Highly developed and fantastical
narratives which preclude facing
the truth of his actions...
I've had enough of this bullshit.
Where's my partner, huh?
Where's Chuck?
Where is he?
Let's try this another way.
Your wife's maiden name was
"Chanal". Am I correct?
- Don't you even talk about her!
- I'm afraid I have to.
Notice anything these four names have in common?
Your rule of 4.
- Andrew, what do you see?
- If you have done anything
- to my partner, doctor. That is a violation ...
- Focus, Andrew. What do you see?
The names ...
have the same letters.
Edward Daniels has exactly the same
13 letters
as Andrew Laeddis.
The same as Rachel Solando
and Dolores Chanal. The names
- Are anagrams for each other.
- Your tactics, they're not going to
work on me.
You came here for the truth.
Here it is.
Your name is Andrew Laeddis.
The 67th patient at Ashecliffe
is you, Andrew.
Bullshit.
You were committed here by
court order 24 months ago.
Your crime is terrible.
One you can't forgive yourself for.
So you invented
another self.
Let's get down to the facts.
You've created a story in which
you're not a murderer, you are hero.
Still a U.S marshal.
Only here at Ashecliffe
because of a case
and you've uncovered a conspiracy
So that anything we tell you about
who you are, what you've done
you can dismiss as lies, Andrew.
My name is Edward Daniels.
I've been hearing this fantasy
for two years now. I know every detail.
Patient 67. The storm.
Rachel Solando.
Your missing partner.
The dreams you have every night.
You were at Dakau,
But you may not have killed any guards.
I wish I could let you just
live in your fantasy world.
I really do.
But you're violent, trained, dangerous.
You're the most dangerous patient we have.
You've injured orderlies. Guards.
Other patients.
Two weeks ago
you attacked George Noyce.
No, no! I am fucking on to you doctor!
- You had Noyce beaten.
- Of course I didn't.
Give me one reason
why I would even touch him.
Because he called you Laeddis
and you do anything not to be him.
I have a transcript of that conversation
you had with Noyce yesterday.
This is about you and Laeddis.
That's all it's ever been about
No. No. He is saying that it's about
"me and Laeddis".
When you've asked him what happened
to his face,
said, and I quote again,
"You did this".
- No. He meant it was my fault he...
- You almost killed him.
The warden and the board of overseers
are determined something be done. It's been decided.
That unless, we can bring you back into sanity now,
right now,
permanent measures will be taken to ensure
you can't hurt anyone ever again.
They'll lobotomize you, Andrew.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
I understand just fine.
If... if I don't play along
with your little game here.
Dr. Naehring is gonna turn me into
one of his ghosts.
What about my partner?
You're gonna tell the U.S. marshal's office
that he's a defense mechanism?
Hello, boss.
What the fuck is going on here?
You working for him?
I'm sorry about that
someone had to stick with you. Keep you safe.
You've been watching me, huh?
Watching me every minute.
Who... who are you?
Who are you?
Tell me.
Don't you recognize me, Andrew?
I've been you primary psychiatrist
for the last two years.
I am Lester Sheehan.
And I told you about my wife ...
- I know.
- I climbed down a cliff to get you.
I trusted you. I risked
everything to come in here after you. Everything!
I know, boss.
We're running out of time here, Andrew,
I swore before the entire board of
overseers that I could construct
The most radical, cutting edge role-play
ever attempted in psychiatry and
it would bring you back.
I thought if we let you play
this out
we could get you to see how
untrue, how impossible it is.
We've had to run of the place for two days.
Tell me, where are the Nazi experiments?
The satanic O.R.'s?
Andrew, listen to me.
If we fail with you
then everything we've tried
to do here will be discredited.
Everything.
We are on the front line of a war here, old boy.
And right now, it'll come down to you.
Don't move! Don't move!
- Andrew, no!
- My name is Edward Daniels.
This one is loaded.
I can tell by the weight.
I see. And that's your firearm marshal?
You're sure?
My initials are on the side and there's a dent in the
barrel from when Philip Stacks shot at me.
You're not going to fuck with my mind on this
one Doc
Then blast away, because that's the
only way you're ever getting off this island.
Andrew, please don't.
My gun...
What have you done to
my Goddamn gun.
It's a toy, Andrew.
We're telling you the truth.
Dolores was insane. Manic-depressive.
Suicidal.
You drank. Stayed away.
Ignored what everyone had told you.
You moved to that lake house after
she, purposely,
set your city apartment on fire
Andrew! Andrew!
Stop it!
You're lying...
Andrew, your children.
Simon...
- Henry...
- I didn't have any children.
Your wife drowned them.
At the cabin by the lake.
And here, the little girl,
the one you dream of
every night.
I never had a little.
The one who tells you over and over that
you should have saved her
Saved them all.
Your daughter...
Her name was Rachel. Are you going to deny
that she ever lived?
Andrew, are you?
I'm so sorry, baby...
I told you not to come in here.
I told you...
this would be the end of you.
I'm back.
We got him
just outside of Oklahoma.
Must of stopped ten places
in between here and Tulsa.
I could sleep for a week.
Dolores?
Baby...
why are you all wet?
I missed you.
I want to go home.
You are home!
Where are the kids?
They're in school.
It's Saturday, honey.
School's not in on Saturday.
My school is.
Oh my God!
My God!
God!
Oh my God, no!
Come on!
Please, God, no.
No!
Let's put them in the room.
We'll dry them off...
We'll change their clothes...
They'll be our living dolls.
Tomorrow we can take them on a picnic.
If you ever loved me, Dolores...
Please stop talking.
I love you.
Set me free!
Honey...
We'll give them baths...
- I love you so much, Dolores.
- And I love you. I love you.
Andrew...
Andrew, can you hear me?
Rachel!
Rachel, Rachel...
Rachel.
Rachel who?
Rachel Laeddis...
My daughter.
Why are you here?
Because I killed my wife.
and why did you do that?
Dhe murdered our children.
And she told me to let her go.
- Who is Teddy Daniels?
- He doesn't exist.
Neither does Rachel Solando.
I made them up.
Why?
We need to hear you say it.
After she tried to kill
herself the first time,
Dolores told me she...
she had an insect...
living inside her brain.
She could feel it...
clicking across
her skull...
pulling the wires,
just for fun.
She told me that.
She told me but I didn't listen.
I loved her so much.
Why did you make them up?
Because I can't take knowing
that Dolores killed our children.
I killed them, because
I didn't get her help.
I killed them...
Here's my theory, Andrew.
we broke through once before,
nine months ago,
and then you regressed.
- I don't remember that.
- I know.
You reset, Andrew.
Like a tape
playing over and over on an endless loop.
I hope that what we've done will be enough
to stop it from ever happening again
But I need to know ...
you have accepted the reality.
You came after me, huh, doctor?
You tried to help me when no one else would.
My name is Andrew Laeddis...
And I murdered my wife
in the spring of '52.
How we doing this morning?
Good.
And You?
Can't complain.
So what's our next move?
You tell me.
I've gotta get off this rock,
Chuck.
Get back to the mainland. Whatever the
hell is going on here. It's bad.
Don't worry, partner.
They're not gonna catch us.
That's right. We're too smart for them.
Yeah, we are.
Aren't we?
You know this place makes
me wonder.
Yeah? What's that boss?
Which would be worse?
To live as a monster ...
or to die as a good man.
Teddy?