How's that going?
The mother's bawling
and the uncle's pissed off.
- She's not married?
- Divorced with four kids.
I guess father was helping out.
Helping out?
Hey, Mr. Burke,
they're in back talking to the bishop.
- And father?
- We put him in the break room.
Any press? Some guy from the Citizen,
but we sent him away.
None of the big papers.
Let's keep it that way.
- Who's that?
- Assistant DA.
It's gonna be hard to keep the papers
away from the arraignment.
What arraignment?
You can tell father Geoghan
I won't be much longer.
Now, Sheila, you know
what good work the church does
in the community.
I give you
my personal guarantee
that I'm going to take father
out of the parish
and this will never
happen again.
- We'll just be another moment, Paul.
- Of course, father.
Now, Sheila,
I'm going to give you my personal card.
Losing a good reporter
is always tough.
But losing one of our best...
uh, well, to put it as eloquently as I can,
it's a real kick in the ass.
But Robby here has known Stewart longer
than most of you have been alive,
so I'll hand it off to him.
Robby.
Oh, well, thanks, Ben.
I think.
Although I take issue
with your reference to my seniority,
I will say that Stewart's departure
is especially painful for me.
Because for...
what, Stewart?
Twenty years now?
Stewart's been more than willing
to part with his money at the poker table.
And I've got a kid
in college.
Yeah, but I'm gonna keep playing.
Oh, problem solved.
Godspeed then.
Now, Stewart,
I find the timing
of your departure
disconcerting.
The corner office
sits empty.
The new editor
arrives on Monday.
So I'm sorry, buddy,
but I gotta ask ya,
what the hell
do you know?
How's the cake?
It's really good.
Are you saving yours?
Nah, it's for Mike.
I can never eat at those things.
They kind of depress me. I know.
Did you see the numbers from Washington?
Yeah. Very interesting.
I think so too.
I'm not asking if the PD's lying.
I know they're lying.
All I'm asking...
who's behind it?
Uh-huh. Okay, I get it.
You don't want to talk.
No, Dan.
I'm not mad, I'm hungry.
I've been talking so long I didn't eat lunch.
So I'm going to get something to eat.
That'll give you an hour to decide whether
you want to be on the right side of this
or read about it
like everybody else.
- Bye, Dan.
- You think Cahill has something?
Maybe. I just don't think
the story's for us.
Ben likes it.
Yeah, it's not bad.
It's just not Spotlight.
What's just not Spotlight?
The PD numbers.
The numbers story. It feels thin.
Oh. You got Cahill to talk?
No. But I will.
Good. Then we'll know
if it's thin.
How'd it go upstairs?
Okay.
Robby gave a good speech.
I'm sure he did.
- I heard Lubin and Connor are going to the Times.
- Come on. Really?
They're leeching us.
They're sending a guy from Miami
to run things. That should help.
Has Baron
even spent time in Boston?
I don't think he's been here before.
We should buy him a map.
A friend down in Miami
said he cut 15% of the staff. Great.
Hey, Robby.
New boss coming in to make some cuts?
I have no idea.
- Aren't you sitting down with him?
- Yes, I am.
So is it about Spotlight?
I don't know, Mike.
But I do know that Ben needs an answer
on the crime numbers story.
I'm telling you,
I really don't think that story's for us.
Mr. Baron.
Oh.
Walter Robinson.
Robby. Yeah.
Thanks for taking the time out
of your weekend. My pleasure.
Appreciate it.
Pleasure.
What are you reading?
Uh, Curse Of The Bambino.
Ah, yeah.
It's a great book.
The Globe has season tickets at Fenway
once you're settled in, by the way.
Thank you. To be honest, I'm...
I'm not much of a baseball fan.
I'm just trying to get
a feel for the city.
Oh. Yeah.
So you're originally
from Boston?
I am.
Born and raised, yeah.
A lot of the newsroom
is from here.
It really feels like a...
like a local paper in that way.
And did that change at all
after the paper was sold to the Times?
No. No, I don't think
that had a big impact.
Good.
And, uh, you're an editor
for the Spotlight team?
I'd prefer to think of myself
as player coach, but yes.
Are you familiar
with Spotlight?
No, not particularly.
Well, we are a four-person
investigative team.
We report
to Ben Bradlee Jr.,
and we keep
our work confidential.
What are you working on now?
We just put out a piece
on a shoddy construction outfit,
and right now we're really just trolling
around for our next story.
How long does that
typically take?
Hard to say.
Uh, a couple months.
- Couple months?
- Yeah.
We don't like to rush it.
Once we settle on a project,
we can spend a year or more investigating it.
Is that a concern?
Not necessarily.
Um, but from what I understand,
readership is down.
Internet is cutting into
the classified business and, uh,
I think I'm gonna need to
take a hard look at things.
So, you anticipate
more cuts.
Uh, I think
it's safe to assume so.
But, uh, what I'm more
focused on right now is finding a way to...
to make this paper
essential to its readers.
I like to think
it already is.
Fair enough. I just think
that we can do better.
Mr. Bradlee.
Hey.
Saw the PD numbers.
Looks interesting.
Yeah, there's
something there.
How long do you need?
Uh, another week.
Where are you going?
To the 10:30.
Since when?
Well, technically,
I am an editor.
Technically.
Your sit-down with Baron go that well?
I couldn't get a read on him.
That's a first.
How about you?
Well, he's a barrel of laughs.
- Morning, everyone.
- Let's get started.
Do you want to
say something, Marty?
Uh, sure.
Uh, hello.
Uh, as most of you
know by now,
my name is Marty Baron.
I'm, uh,
delighted to be here.
Um, if you could tell me your name as we
go around, that'd be helpful.
Thank you.
Okay. Peter?
Peter Canellos, Metro.
I've got a major
big dig closure.
Hey, Steve.
Mike.
Hey. Crappy game
last night, huh?
Yeah, they can't hit
worth a nickel.
Hey, listen, what's, um...
what's Eileen McNamara doing in the 10:30?
Do you need something, Mike?
No, just curious.
Go be curious somewhere else.
I got work to do.
Okay, Steve. See ya.
Yeah.
And it looks like Pedro's
gonna be out till September 1.
Jimmy says he'll be back this year,
but the Doc didn't seem so sure.
When's the Pats opener?
Is that, uh, everyone?
- Yes, that's it.
- Okay. Good. Thank you.
Uh, did everyone read
Eileen McNamara's column this weekend?
That's the Geoghan case?
Yeah.
What's the folo on that?
It... it's a column.
What kind of folo were you thinking?
Uh, well, apparently
this Priest molested kids
in six different parishes
over the last 30 years,
and the attorney
for the victims, Mr., uh...
- Garabedian.
- Thanks, Eileen.
Mr. Garabedian says Cardinal law found
out about it 15 years ago and did nothing.
I think that attorney's a bit of a crank.
And the church dismissed the claim.
He said, she said.
Whether Mr. Garabedian
is a crank or not,
he says he has documents
that prove the Cardinal knew.
As I understand it,
those documents are under seal.
Okay, but the fact remains,
a Boston Priest abused 80 kids,
we have a lawyer who says
he can prove law knew about it,
and we've written all of, uh,
two stories in the last six months.
This strikes me as an essential story
to a local paper.
I think at the very least
we have to go through those documents.
How would you
like to do that?
Well, uh, I don't know
what the laws are here,
but in Florida,
we would go to court.
You want to sue the church?
Technically,
we wouldn't sue the church.
We'd file a motion
to lift the seal on those documents.
The church will read that
as us suing them.
So will everybody else.
Good to know.
Gutsy call for the first day.
That's one word for it.
How do you think
that's gonna play down front?
I think Gilman's
gonna shit a brick.
- Hey.
- Door.
How'd it go?
Well, Baron wants to sue for the
sealed docs in the Geoghan case.
He wants to sue the church?
Hey, that's great. Yeah.
We covered Geoghan
when the story broke three years ago.
Baron was still in Miami.
He might have been at the Times
then, actually. He wasn't here.
So do you think that suit
has a chance?
- Depends on the judge.
- And what parish he belongs to.
Bradlee. Yeah.
Okay.
- Baron wants to talk to us.
- Us?
- Okay, Joe.
- Thank you.
Yes.
Okay, thanks.
I've set up a meeting for tomorrow
with outside counsel.
Joe Albano?
Yeah.
Who's the judge
in this case?
Um...
Constance Sweeney.
- Tough.
- Why's that?
Good catholic girl.
Huh.
So, um, judging from
what I've read,
it doesn't seem like we've done a very
thorough investigation into the Geoghan case.
- Is that right?
- No, it's not.
We looked hard at Geoghan.
David Armstrong from Metro,
Michael Paulson for religion.
Okay, but, uh,
just so I understand,
beyond our daily coverage,
we haven't...
we haven't committed any long-term
investigative resources
to the question of whether or not
Cardinal law knew about this.
No, we haven't.
And that's the kind of thing
your team would do?
Spotlight? Well, yeah.
But we're still prospecting
the Boston PD story I told you about.
- Could you set that aside?
- We could.
Marty, in past Spotlight's
had success in large part
because they pick
their own projects.
Would you consider
picking this one?
I don't know if he's writing about you,
but I will let him know you called.
Okay. Bye.
Hey.
Hey, how'd it go?
Okay.
Uh, Baron wants us
to scrub the Geoghan case.
- That's great.
- Didn't we cover Geoghan?
Yeah, there's a lawyer alleging
Cardinal law knew about it.
Mmm. Mitch Garabedian, right?
Yeah.
I covered him at the courthouse.
Can you get to him?
I only interviewed him once.
He's kind of a character.
- I like characters. I'll take him.
- Good. You take him.
Also, we should be talking to the lawyer
who repped the victims in the Porter case.
- Eric Macleish.
That guy was always on TV.
The Porter case? Remind me.
Yeah, uh...
father Porter, similar story. Molested dozens
of kids in fall river about 10 years ago.
- So we're dropping the Boston PD?
- I-I vote yes.
No. We just gotta
set it aside for now.
I don't need to tell you guys this.
We need to be more discreet than usual.
Everybody's going to be interested in this,
not just the Herald.
We can't let Cardinal law get wind of this
till we know what we have.
Good luck with that.
So when do you leave, Nana?
The bus is picking us up
in the church parking lot at 9:00.
We have
40 people going.
And is father Dominic going?
No. He says he's unlucky.
But luck has nothing
to do with it.
You know, last time Nana won $160.
Wow.
You gonna tell her?
We don't even know
if there's a story yet.
Globe sues church?
It's gonna be a story.
Hey, Lisa. Could you pull
all the relevant clips on that for me?
Yeah.
Is this for Spotlight?
Just drop them off when they're ready.
Thanks.
Excuse me. Do you know where
the publisher's office is?
Will do.
How are you, Marty?
Settling in?
Yeah, I think so.
Good. What can I do for you?
Um...
I'd like to challenge the protective
order in the Geoghan case.
You want to sue
the catholic church?
Um...
we're just filing a motion,
but, uh, yes.
You think it's that important?
Yes, I do.
Because obviously the church
will fight us very hard on this.
Which won't go unnoticed
by our subscriber base.
53% of them are Catholic.
Mm-hmm.
I think they'll be interested.
Okay.
Marty, lake street will probably contact you
about a face-to-face with the Cardinal.
- It's customary.
- Yeah.
They already have.
It's set up for next week.
I wouldn't mention this.
Hello?
Can I help you? Oh, hi. I'm Mike Rezendes
from the Boston Globe.
I'm here to see
Mitchell Garabedian.
He's on a call.
Please have a seat.
Okay.
All right,
I'm listening. Go ahead.
Okay.
Bill! Where the hell
are those papers?
I asked you
to put 'em on my desk!
The famous Walter Robinson
in my conference room.
Good to see you again, Eric.
Sacha Pfeiffer, Eric Macleish.
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
You don't play golf, do you?
- Uh, no.
- Good.
Your colleague here took some money
off me at a charity event last year.
It was a very lucky putt.
I actually had my eyes closed, by the way.
Mm-hmm.
So how can I
help you guys?
Uh, you're familiar
with the Geoghan case?
Sure.
Eighty Plaintiffs.
All of them
individual cases.
Garabedian
must be swimming.
Yeah. And the allegations
against Cardinal law?
Yeah, it's tricky. Um...
this is what you need to understand.
These are shitty cases.
Um, the statute of limitations
is only three years,
and most of these victims don't come
forward till long after that.
- Oh. Why is that?
- Well, they're kids, you know.
Uh, guilt, shame.
And most of these kids
come from tough neighborhoods.
Nobody wants to admit
this kind of thing.
So you're screwed
on the time limit.
And, uh, even if you argue
your way around that,
the charitable immunity statute
caps damages at 20 grand.
Twenty grand
for molesting a child?
That is the way
the system is set up, yes.
The church is tough.
So your best shot
is to try these cases in the press,
uh, like I did
on Porter.
Mmm.
But most of the victims,
they don't want to have
anything to do with TV.
And, uh, Mitch isn't exactly
a people person.
Yeah. And if Garabedian can't get
his victims to go before the press,
then he's really...
that's right.
He has a long road
ahead of him.
My guess is he doesn't
have anything on law.
What? You think
he's bluffing or...
I think he's grandstanding
to cut a better deal.
Seems a bit reckless.
Have you met
Mitch Garabedian?
I asked you to write up
that motion, Bill.
I didn't ask you
to file it!
Mmm?
Hey, Bill.
Hi.
Who are you? I'm Mike Rezendes
from the Boston Globe.
I had an appointment
with you about an hour ago.
I can't talk to you.
I'm very busy. Sharon?
She went out for coffee.
She said she'd be right back.
I'm following up
on an article.
The one in the Phoenix?
No. In the Globe.
- Did you see the one in the Phoenix?
- No, I didn't.
I thought it was very good.
I have a copy here somewhere.
That's all right.
I'll track it down.
I'm actually following up on a column that
Eileen McNamara wrote about your suit.
Suits.
There are 84 of them.
It's not a class action.
You should get your facts straight.
No, you're right.
I should.
So I'm trying to get some
background information on...
you're not recording this,
are you?
Uh, no.
I wouldn't do that without asking.
I can't show you the church documents,
if that's what you're after.
- They're under seal.
- Yeah, I know that.
Did you know
they tried to bring me up
before the Massachusetts board
of bar overseers three times?
They're watching me very closely.
The church?
Yeah. The church. Yeah.
They'd like to get me disbarred.
In fact... put that away. Put it away.
Sure.
I don't want you recording this
in any way,
shape or form.
Not on paper,
not on tape, nothing.
In fact, I probably shouldn't
even be speaking to you, so...
look, Mr. Garabedian,
I know there's things you cannot tell me.
But I also know there's a story here,
and I think it's an important story.
I already talked
to the Phoenix.
Yeah, and there's a reason I didn't see it.
Nobody reads the Phoenix anymore.
They're broke.
They don't have any power.
The Globe does.
If we cover this story,
everybody will hear about it.
The church thinks in centuries,
Mr. Rezendes.
Do you think your paper
has the resources to take that on?
Yeah, I do.
But if you don't mind
me asking, do you?
I can't talk to you right now,
Mr. Rezendes.
I'm very, very busy.
Sharon?
Thank you.
Yep. Can I at least talk to some of
your clients? The victims?
I'd really
like to do that.
Call me tomorrow. I gotta think about it.
Yep. Thank you. Thanks.
I got more clips from the library.
Leave 'em right there.
Are you guys doing a story
on the church?
No, we are not doing
a story on the church.
Matt, you find anything
on this guy, Phil Saviano?
No. Who is he?
He's part of
a victims' organization.
Kurkjian did a story on him
right after the Porter case.
There's a victims' organization?
Yeah.
It's called SNAP. It's, uh, Survivors
Network of those Abused by Priests.
- Crummy Acronym.
- Mmm.
You want me to track him down?
Yeah. Bring him in.
How much longer you need
to get through the clips?
I mean, a few days.
There's a lot.
Lisa's still sending up more.
Okay.
Hey, guys. I think
I got another Priest.
Liam Barrett.
Molested some kids
in Philly
and was moved
to Boston.
Did the same thing
and was moved again.
Really? That sounds
like Geoghan.
Is that one of our clips?
Yeah. Byline's Diego Ribadineira, 1997.
Must've been back when
he was working religion.
Was there any folo?
Not much. One short piece.
Huh.
The church settled the case.
Don't you know
Jim Sullivan?
Yeah. Why?
Looks like the church
brought him in to help out.
Jesus. Has anybody but manny gotten
the ball out of the infield?
Nope.
Why do you even bother with that thing?
It distracts me
from the game.
Know what else
is good for that?
Oh, yeah. Good idea.
My round.
I'll be right back.
Anybody want any food? No.
- I'm all set.
- Hey, a hot dog.
So, you guys making any progress?
Absolutely.
It's a good story.
Why?
'Cause you're another lapsed catholic
pissed off at the church?
We've got a lot of good stuff.
Like what?
I'm just watching the game.
Omertà.
They got another Priest...
Liam Barrett.
We reported on him.
I'm just saying, we did.
Okay, but this guy was shuffled around
from parish to parish every few years,
just like Geoghan
and Porter.
I think there's
a pattern.
Sounds thin.
What else you got?
Sacha's got another guy from a
victims' organization... Phil Saviano.
From SNAP? Oh, boy.
We reported on him too.
I thought you were
watching the game, Steve.
- That guy's pretty banged up.
- We did a couple stories on him.
Guy would not stop
writing letters.
He wants a Holy war.
What, so he's not worth talking to?
Where are you on Garabedian?
I'm working on it.
Robby says Macleish
thinks he's bluffing.
I think there's
something there, Ben.
Get me something solid,
or I'm taking you off it.
I don't want us
chasing our tails on this.
Stay away
from that trap!
You couldn't reach that trap
in a million years, partner.
I've reached
that trap before.
Yeah.
Now, Paul, maybe.
How we doing?
We're good.
We're two up on the front.
Good.
How's that new editor
working out?
Well, he doesn't
like baseball.
But, uh, he seems
like a smart guy.
Yeah, I read
an article about him.
Said he's the first Jewish editor
of the Globe.
Must have been
a slow news day.
He got a family, this guy?
No.
He is not married.
Divorced?
I don't think so, no.
So the new editor at the Globe
is an unmarried man of the Jewish faith
who hates baseball?
Yeah.
Should have given it to Ben.
He's a Bradlee,
for crying out loud.
Didn't raise his hand
fast enough, I guess.
Hey, by the way,
I've been reading about this Priest,
father Barrett.
Said you were involved
with that.
Barrett, yeah.
Bad egg.
Lake street asked for help.
I pitched in.
Victim said Cardinal law knew about Barrett
when he came from Philly.
Is that true?
You know I can't talk
about the case, Robby.
Well... off the record?
Off the record,
I can't talk about it.
All right.
This related to the lawsuit?
You know about that?
Look,
I don't know this guy Baron
or what his agenda is.
Frankly, I don't care.
I just don't want to see you
taking a bullet for him.
I think you're away.
- Put it over here.
- Let's go. Let's go.
So the other day
I was on the World Wide Web.
Anything you want to know,
it's right there.
Now, I have to admit
that as a Priest,
this makes me
a little nervous.
Should I be worried
about job security?
I don't think so.
You see,
knowledge is one thing.
But faith...
faith is another.
Hey.
Shouldn't you be
golfing or something?
Golfing's not a verb.
And I couldn't get
a tee time.
Is that what they call it?
Tee time?
They also call it
a leisure activity.
You oughta try it, Mike.
I do. I run.
Yeah. You run to work.
So why are you
here today?
Going over these clips of Saviano.
Yep.
Ben and Steve think it's a dead end.
They gave me a bunch of crap about it at the game.
Yeah, Ben e-mailed me.
He did?
Yeah.
He said
we should let it go.
What do you want to do?
I want to bring Saviano in.
So, just ignore those guys?
I think we oughta start
ignoring everybody on this one.
I'm good with that.
Well...
do you think Marty has any idea
what's coming down the pike?
Nope.
I don't think he cares either.
That's refreshing.
Yeah.
Unless he's wrong.
I've always been fascinated
with the newspaper business.
I used to sit in on the lectures with the
neiman fellows when I was at Harvard.
I, uh... I read that you
were an editor once.
Ah, yes.
Yeah, that was
a very long time ago.
The Mississippi Register.
Small diocesan newspaper.
But for a 30-year-old pastor,
it was a big responsibility.
Too much at times.
How so?
I was close
with the evers brothers.
We took a stand
on civil rights.
Our readership
was not pleased.
They saw me
as a meddling outsider.
I can imagine.
Tough seat to sit in,
especially in a small town.
I think you'll find that Boston's still
a small town too, Marty,
in many ways.
Hmm.
But if I can be of any help, Marty,
don't hesitate to ask.
I find
that the city flourishes
when its great institutions
work together.
Thank you.
Personally I'm of the opinion that for
a paper to best perform its function,
it really needs
to stand alone.
Ah. Of course.
But my offer still stands.
Thank you.
Come in.
Ah.
Thank you, Maureen.
A little gift, Marty.
Think of it as a Cardinal's guide
to the city of Boston.
I'm here to see
Sacha Pfeiffer.
Your name?
Phil Saviano.
Okay, just a minute.
Mm-hmm.
So, am I the first survivor
you've talked to?
Yeah, Phil, you are.
Okay, well,
first of all let me say thank you
for having me in today.
And I want you to know that you have the
full cooperation of my organization, SNAP.
How many members are in
your organization, Phil?
We had 11
at our last chapter meeting...
uh, no, um, 10.
Karen just moved.
You had a woman in your group?
Of course.
They don't discriminate,
not when it comes to abuse.
And this has nothing to do
with being gay.
What this is is Priests
using the collar to rape kids.
Kids.
Boys and girls.
I was 11,
and I was preyed upon by father
David Holley in Worcester.
And I don't mean prayed for.
I mean preyed upon.
- Are any of you catholic?
- I was raised catholic.
Now I go to my wife's
presbyterian church.
I'm lapsed.
I go to church
with my grandmother sometimes.
It's safe to say we were all
raised catholic, but now...
not so much.
Okay.
Well, let me tell you,
when you're a poor kid from a poor family,
religion counts for a lot.
And when a Priest pays attention
to you, it's a big deal.
He asks you to collect the hymnals or
take out the trash, you feel special.
It's like God
asking for help.
So maybe it's a little weird
when he tells you a dirty joke.
But now you got a secret together,
so you go along.
Then he shows you a porno mag,
and you go along.
And you go along,
and you go along,
until one day he asks you to jerk him off
or give him a blow job.
And so you go along with that too
because you feel trapped,
because he has groomed you.
How do you say no
to God, right?
See, it is important to understand
that this is not just physical abuse.
It's spiritual abuse too.
And when a Priest does this to you,
he robs you of your faith.
So you reach for the bottle
or the needle,
or if those don't work,
you jump off a bridge.
That's why
we call ourselves survivors.
Have you read Jason Berry's book?
He wrote about the Gauthe case in Louisiana.
That's G... G-A-U-T-H-E.
Here. And talk to Richard Sipe.
He worked in one of the church's
treatment centers.
He's an ex-Priest.
Married a nun.
Here. This is his testimony
from the Kos case.
Phil, what's a treatment center?
It's where they send Priests
when they get caught.
This is all here in the box.
I sent this to you guys five years ago.
Uh, to the Globe?
Who did you send it to?
I don't wanna say who, but they
said they weren't interested.
But we did run a couple stories on you.
I saw them in the clips.
Yeah, but to be completely frank,
it wasn't enough.
You guys gotta understand.
This is big.
This is not just Boston.
It's the whole country. It's the whole world.
And it goes right up
to the Vatican.
Do you have any proof
of that, Phil?
No. Not yet.
But there are so many of them.
How else could they
have hidden it for so long?
- So many what?
- Priests!
Priests!
I know of 13
right here in Boston.
You know 13 Priests in Boston
who have molested children?
Yeah! Why do you keep
repeating everything I say?
I just like to clarify things.
Maybe you should have clarified it five years
ago when I sent you all of this stuff.
It's all right here.
May I use
your bathroom?
Yeah, sure, Phil.
Come on.
Well,
what do you think?
Well, the guy's got an agenda,
that's for sure.
You think?
He's obviously been through a lot.
But he's smart,
and if he's right about 13 Priests...
yeah, it might be a big "if" with this guy.
Do a background check on him.
And follow up with some
of the other survivors of his group.
I'll track down
this ex-Priest, Sipe.
Okay, but stay on Garabedian.
That's more important.
Ah. Garabedian.
What a pain in the ass.
You can be
a pain in the ass, Mike.
Mmm.
Mitchell, what a surprise.
How are you?
I'm fine, Mr. Rezendes.
Good.
I haven't heard back from you.
I left you a couple of messages.
I've been very busy.
I-I don't have time for calls.
I'm sure you don't.
Listen, listen, Mitch.
Let me talk to a couple of the victims.
You could sit in on the interview.
If you're not happy,
you could kill it.
I spoke to my clients. They don't want
to be in the press. I'm sorry.
I get that, but I don't
need to name names.
I don't believe you, Mr. Rezendes.
I'm sure you don't.
Listen, Mitchell.
Look, Mr. Rezendes, please...
I'm not writing a profile here.
I'm working on something bigger.
Bigger? I don't know
what that means.
I'm not supposed to tell you this,
but I'm digging around for Spotlight.
Spotlight's on this?
Yeah, we're looking into it.
But you gotta help me. You gotta let me
talk to some of these victims. Please.
Please.
Come back tomorrow, 9:30 am.
Thank you.
Ms. Pfeiffer?
Joe?
Oh, shoot!
That's okay.
Sorry. Please sit.
Thank you.
Is this table okay?
This is perfect.
I had a muffin
while I was waiting.
Two, actually.
I eat when I'm nervous.
I do that too,
actually.
I hope I'm not late.
Phil told me 1:00.
No, you're fine.
I got here early.
About an hour.
Um, would you mind if I took some notes?
Would that be all right?
You don't mind if I
take some notes, do you?
- Are you gonna use my name?
- No.
Not if you
don't want me to, no.
I just had a kid.
He's only one, but I'm not sure
I want him to know about this.
Sure. I get that.
You can stop this interview at
any time, Patrick. All right?
Okay.
All right.
Go ahead with your notes.
Okay. So, um...
where'd you live
when it first happened?
In the projects,
over in Hyde Park.
Over by the Stop & Shop?
Yeah. You know it?
Yeah, I drove a cab
for a few years.
Open early.
Bad coffee, right?
Yeah. I guess.
How old were you
when it happened?
I was 12.
Just after my dad
killed himself.
Oh, geez.
He was a real
piece of shit.
And my Mom,
she wasn't so stable either.
How do you mean?
I mean she was nuts.
She was
a schizophrenic.
Same shit.
When did you
first meet Geoghan?
Well, my sister, she saw him
over in the Dunkin' Donuts.
Tells him about my old man passing,
and he rushed right over.
This nun, sister Barbara, ran this
group for kids from troubled families.
Mm-hmm.
Where was that?
Uh, St. Ambrose
in Dorchester.
Okay.
She's the one who introduced me
to father Shanley.
He was a street Priest.
Long hair. Very hip.
He invited me to his apartment
in back bay.
Where in Back Bay?
Beacon Street.
Beacon. Okay.
Are you from here?
Uh, no. I grew up in Ohio,
but my Mom's from Southie.
All right, so you get it.
I'd never even seen back bay.
So what happened
on that first visit, Joe?
Well, he was very nice at first,
very funny, very casual.
And I think
he could tell I was gay,
so he showed me this mobile he had,
like over a baby's crib.
Mm-hmm.
But with different words.
"Homosexual."
"Transsexual." "Bisexual."
Okay. And did you know
you were gay at that time, Joe?
Yeah.
But that wasn't information I was sharing
with anybody. Not in Dorchester.
Okay.
So, what happened
after he showed you the mobile?
Well, I was
a little freaked out.
I think he could tell.
So he said, you know, what'll help
is if we play strip poker.
Of course I lost.
And, uh, things
went on from there.
Can you tell me
specifically what happened?
Specifically, he...
he molested me.
Joe, I think that the language
is gonna be so important here.
We can't sanitize this.
Just saying "molest" isn't enough.
People need to know
what actually happened.
We should probably get these to go.
Right.
Geoghan shows up, and my Mom,
you know, she's...
she's thrilled.
I mean, this was like God
showing up, you know?
Sure. Right.
So what happened then?
You really want
to hear this shit?
Yeah. Yeah, Patrick, I do.
He offers to take me
to get ice cream.
You know, he's a Priest,
I'm a kid, so I go.
Sure.
So we're driving home and he...
he starts patting my leg and...
you know, then...
His hand just slides
right up and he...
he grabs my dick.
You know, I...
I just froze up.
I was fucking petrified.
I-I couldn't move.
I didn't know what to do.
I was just a little kid.
Yeah.
You know, I never even
touched my ice cream.
It just melted down my arm.
Did you, um...
did you see him again
after that?
Yeah.
All right. That's good.
Let's stop there for now.
Sure.
He said it was a way to make me
more comfortable with my body.
Mmm. So what happened
after that?
Well, he took off
his clothes and he said,
"I've been so depressed,
but maybe you can cheer me up
and give me a blow job."
Classy guy.
And did you?
Yeah.
I know you
must be thinking,
why would I ever do that to some creepy
guy who's 30 years older than me?
But what you have to understand is
that this is the first time in my life
that someone told me
that it was okay to be gay.
And it was a Priest.
Right.
So you had oral sex.
Did you have
intercourse?
Yes.
Not then, but later.
It really messed me up.
I'm sober now, but that... that was
the beginning of it all.
It's very confusing,
you know,
to be introduced to sex
like that and then...
and then to be
attracted to men, it's...
I'm sorry.
I knew I was gonna do this.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
It's okay, Joe.
It's okay.
Of course there is
a church right there.
And a playground.
Joe, did you ever
try and tell anyone?
Like who? A Priest?
Can I use your phone?
Yeah, sure.
You know where it is.
You can use my name
if you want.
Thanks, Patrick.
Don't thank me. Just get
these assholes, will you?
He's one of the lucky ones.
He's still alive.
Do you want a cup of tea, Sacha?
I'm okay, Nana. Thanks.
Hello? Hi, Joe.
It's Sacha Pfeiffer.
Hi, Sacha. How are you?
I'm good, thanks.
Um, listen, Joe, I just wanted to
follow up on one thing.
You talked to Phil Saviano
about all of this, right?
Yeah, I did.
I went to a couple of SNAP meetings.
And did Phil ever suggest
you do anything about it?
No. The meetings
weren't really about that.
A couple of them had gone to a lawyer,
but I didn't think it was worth it.
Why not?
There were just so many forms to fill out.
It was overwhelming.
And he said he could only get me
a small settlement, so...
wh-who said that?
The lawyer told me that.
So you did go
and see a lawyer?
Yeah, but I didn't end up using him,
so I didn't think it was important.
I'm sorry.
I'm not trying to hide anything.
No, I-I-I know, Joe.
Do you remember his name?
The lawyer?
No. But maybe Phil
would know.
The guy was on TV a lot during the
Porter case. He was handsome.
Was it Eric Macleish?
Yeah, that's it.
Macleish.
I thought
he was very handsome.
- Hey.
I was just in the newsroom.
Judge Sweeney set a date for the hearing.
Really? When?
Two weeks.
In Springfield.
Oh.
Canellos started a pool.
Ten bucks to get in.
Anyone picking the Globe?
He's only taking bets
on how fast Sweeney rules against us.
Robby.
Hi. It's me.
Did you get my message?
I did.
Looks like father Shanley
could be our fourth Priest.
Yeah, I think he is.
Did you follow up with Macleish?
I just talked to Phil.
He said Macleish dealt
with a number of these cases.
Guess he forgot
to mention that. Yeah.
I'm gonna go to
the courthouse tomorrow,
see if I can find any cases
he settled against the church.
All right. Call me after you do.
Good night.
Okay. Good night.
Hey.
You wanted to, uh, chat?
Yeah.
I'm late for a dinner.
Wanna walk me out? Sure.
Geez. Does that guy ever go home?
Apparently not.
I got guys who won't leave till he does.
He's wearing out the goddamn newsroom.
Where are we on Geoghan?
Following up on more victims.
I want to expand the investigation.
Why?
We got a fourth Priest.
There might be as many as 13.
Thirteen?
Yeah.
Who's your source?
Phil Saviano.
Jesus Christ, Robby. I told Mike
that guy's a fuckin'... I know, I know.
I think Saviano
might be legit, Ben.
Want to elaborate
on that?
No. Not really.
It just feels like this thing's stacking up.
That's my gut.
Okay.
Okay. Good.
Thank you.
Hello?
Mr. Rezendes?
Uh, yeah. Who's this?
It's Richard Sipe.
Oh, yeah. Hey, Richard.
How are you?
I'm good.
Uh, thanks for calling.
Look, uh, Phil Saviano
g-gave me your name.
I was wondering if I could ask you
a few questions.
Of course. Yeah.
Great.
Uh, so Phil told me
that you were working
a-at one of the church's
treatment centers in Baltimore.
Yes. The Seton
Psychiatric Institute.
It was run by
the daughters of charity.
And, uh,
when was that, Richard?
Well, I started my psychotherapy
fellowship there in 1965,
okay.
And I was there for five years,
but I spent the next 30 studying
abusive Priests and their victims.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
And that's... that's been
your sole focus?
Look, Mike, the church wants us to believe
that it's just a few bad apples.
But it's a much bigger problem
than that.
How much bigger, Richard?
Well, based on the research,
I would classify it as a recognizable
psychiatric phenomenon.
That's big.
Hey, Mac.
Hey.
If I wanted historical data on a Priest,
parishes he's been assigned to,
where would I find that?
The Geoghan case? It's all in the clips.
Lisa has the source material.
What if it was for another Priest, one that
hadn't been in the papers?
You're looking at another Priest?
Who you looking at?
Any ideas?
Come on, Matt.
You're not gonna tell me?
I gotta get to a meeting.
Thanks, Mac. Hey, Steve.
The archdiocese puts out an annual directory,
every Priest and parish.
That's great.
Do these go back
any further than '98?
Oh, yeah. Going back
to the '80s in the Mez.
Beyond that,
you gotta go to BPL.
The Mez, huh?
Thanks, Lisa. You bet.
He said they all target
the same kind of kid.
Low-income families,
absentee fathers, broken homes.
So a guy like Geoghan goes after boys
not because he prefers them,
but because they have more shame,
less likely to talk.
Hmm.
These guys are predators, Robby.
Yeah.
I-I-I talked to Sipe.
He said he's seen dozens of them
in the '60s in Seton.
He called it
a "phenomenon."
Why didn't he go public?
He did.
But the church made a huge effort
to discredit him.
Smear campaigns,
public statements by prominent bishops.
It's just like Saviano said.
And Garabedian.
You getting anywhere with him?
More victims.
You can't empty his pockets?
I'll get to him.
I just need more time.
Come on, Mike.
You gotta get him.
I'll get him.
Jesus. What the hell
is that smell?
There's a dead rat
in the corner.
What have you got?
Church directories.
It's every Priest in Massachusetts,
what parish they're assigned to.
Are these official?
Yeah. I figured it could help us track down
some of the Priests Saviano mentioned,
maybe find some more victims.
Can we turn on some more lights?
I couldn't find the switch.
You wanna borrow my glasses?
No, I'm good. I'm good.
Look. 1983.
John Geoghan,
St. Brendan's parish, Dorchester.
So we can find out
where any Priest is in any given year?
Yeah, I got him here
at...
huh.
What?
1980. The year Geoghan
was pulled from JP.
It says he's
on sick leave.
Come on.
It really says that?
Where is, uh, 1991?
Yeah. Here ya go.
Let me see this.
Barrett. Barrett. Liam.
I can't read that.
Look for a Liam Barrett in there.
1991's the year they pulled him
out of Charlestown.
"Barrett, Liam."
Yeah.
- "Sick leave."
It's an official
designation.
Let's get these upstairs.
Matt, check on those Priests
Saviano gave us.
Robby.
I'm down at the courthouse.
Something's not right here.
Nothing on Shanley either, Sacha.
Okay, thanks.
Um, we need to talk to Macleish again.
Really. Why?
Huh? There's nothing here.
There aren't any records.
Thanks for waiting.
So sorry, guys. Stuck on a call.
Not a problem.
How are you? Good.
Thanks for meeting us.
You bet. What's up, guys?
Mr. Macleish, are you familiar with
a Priest named Paul Shanley?
Yes, I am familiar
with him.
And have you settled cases
against father Shanley?
As I'm sure you can understand,
I can't discuss that with you.
Yeah, h-how about, uh,
father Ronald Paquin?
Well, I can't discuss that
with you either. Come on, guys.
We understand you've settled
several cases against each of them.
Even if I'd been involved
in those cases,
the settlements
would be confidential
and I could be disbarred
for acknowledging their existence.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
Look, I told you guys
these are tough cases.
Most of these folks, they just want
some acknowledgment
of what happened.
We got 'em a sit-down
with the bishop and a little dough,
and that's the best
they could hope for.
Well, it's certainly the best the Priests
could hope for.
No, the church promised
they'd take the Priests out of circulation.
And did you follow up on that?
Do you guys need anything else?
Yes. Why aren't there
any records?
I was down
at the courthouse earlier.
There aren't any records
of any of these settlements.
We dealt directly
with the church.
We would draw up a demand letter
and send it to the chancery.
- You never filed anything in court?
- It's a private mediation.
So, this is just you
and the archdiocese's lawyers
in a room?
- Correct.
- Anyone else?
Occasionally the church would bring in
another defense attorney to help out.
You have names?
Nope. No, I don't.
So this was all
under the table?
There's no paper trail
at all.
The victim has to sign a confidentiality
agreement to get the settlement.
The lawyer takes a third,
and the church sweeps it under the rug.
It's a freakin' Racket.
It's more complicated than that.
Macleish has got a duty to the client
to get the best deal he can.
Sure. But how many victims do you represent
and profit from before you say something?
Garabedian would say none.
That's why he's taking
these cases to court.
He wants people to know about this.
I agree.
And legal ethics aside, Ben,
I mean, operating
the way Macleish has
all but guarantees that
the abuse stays under wraps.
Yeah. Did Macleish confirm
all Saviano's Priests?
No. He's limited by his
confidentiality agreement.
But clearly he's settled cases
against a number of them.
Phil's put me in touch
with some of the other victims.
I'm pretty confident all of his Priests
are gonna check out.
So it is 13 Priests?
- Yeah.
- Looks that way.
Holy shit.
Okay. Keep going.
I'm sorry.
What was the name again?
Uh, Baron.
B-A-R-O-N.
I'm having trouble finding it.
Just give me a second.
It's okay, Kim.
I can vouch for him.
I'm Pete Conley.
I'm on the Board of Catholic Charities.
Welcome to Boston,
Mr. Baron.
Thank you.
I appreciate you joining us.
We're very proud of the work
we do here in Boston.
Oh, the Cardinal said
you had a nice visit.
Yes, we did.
He's an extraordinary man.
I'm glad you had a chance to chat.
Enjoying yourself?
Uh, to be honest,
these events aren't really my strong suit.
Yeah. Are you involved
with the charity?
Not directly, no.
Several of my friends are.
We all went to high school
at BC High.
That's the school across the street
from the Globe.
It's hard to miss.
Yeah.
Hard to get away from too,
apparently.
The, uh, Cardinal's
in the corner,
if you're so inclined.
We've met.
Really?
Did he mention
the suit?
No, but he did give me
a copy of the catechism.
Yeah.
Well, the Cardinal's
not known for his subtlety.
During the Porter investigation,
he literally called down
the power of God on the Globe.
How'd that play out?
A week later, our editor
broke his leg skiing.
Shrimp toast,
gentlemen?
Uh, no, thanks.
Thanks.
You said one of the victims
filed a criminal complaint?
Yeah, there were
a few of them.
But the judge had
the case records sealed
after friends
of the church complained.
And the church
has a lot of friends.
Like Eric Macleish?
Yeah.
Let's just say he's not
part of the solution.
You follow what I'm saying?
Sure.
You work hard,
Mr. Rezendes.
Are you married?
Yeah.
Your wife doesn't mind you working
all the time? Oh, yeah, she does.
That's why I never got married.
I'm too busy.
What I do
is too important.
Mmm.
Your new editor,
he's a Jew, right?
That's right. Yeah.
Well, see, he comes in
and suddenly everybody's
interested in the church.
You know why?
Mmm.
Because it takes
an outsider, like me.
I'm Armenian.
How many Armenians
do you know in Boston?
Steve Kurkjian.
Works at the Globe.
Oh. That's two.
You should get a prize or something.
What are you, Italian?
No, I'm Portuguese.
From where?
Uh, East Boston.
Really? East Boston?
You don't sound like it.
This city, these people...
making the rest of us feel
like we don't belong.
But they're no better than us.
Look at how they treat
their children.
Mark my words, Mr. Rezendes,
if it takes a village
to raise a child,
it takes a village
to abuse one.
Hey, here he is.
Want a beer?
Love one.
Another.
You here with Barbara?
No, no. She hates these things.
Karen too.
Yeah.
Smart ladies.
Sláinte.
Mmm. I met
your new editor.
Seemed like
a decent fellow.
I think he is.
Hey, I had
an interesting conversation
with Eric Macleish
the other day.
Turns out he's been settling abuse cases
with the Archdiocese for years.
You really want
to talk about this here?
Jim, you said you helped out
on father Barrett as a favor.
That was a one-off?
How many of these cases
you been involved with?
You know I can't answer that, Robby.
It's unethical.
Is that all it is?
So, this would be
the Robby Robinson
I've always heard about
but never met.
Huh?
Listen to me, Jimmy.
You want to be
on the right side of this.
This is the church
you're talking about, Robby.
Look around.
These are good people.
Done a lot of good
for this city.
Enjoy the party.
I've been through
a lot of these now.
"Sick leave" isn't
the only designation they use
when they take one of these Priests
out of circulation.
They use a slew of terms:
"Absent on leave,"
"unassigned,"
"emergency response."
They got a word for everything, these guys.
Except rape.
And they move parishes
way more frequently than other Priests.
When I was a kid, a Priest moved after
seven or eight years, sometimes longer.
These guys, it's two
to three years tops.
And did they use these designations
for all of Saviano's Priests?
Yeah.
It's a pretty clear pattern.
Guys, I got Sipe.
I think if you really want
to understand the crisis,
you need to start
with the celibacy requirement.
That was my first major finding.
Only 50% of the clergy
are celibate.
Now, most of them are having sex
with other adults.
But the fact remains that this
creates a culture of secrecy
that tolerates
and even protects pedophiles.
So you believe
the church
is aware of the extent
of this, uh, crisis?
Oh, absolutely.
After the first major scandal
in Louisiana,
Tom Doyle, the secretary canonist
for the Papal Nuncio,
co-authored a report
warning pedophile Priests
were a billion-dollar
liability.
That was in 1985.
1985?
That's right.
Who saw that report?
Anyone from the catholic hierarchy?
Sure. Doyle tried
to introduce the report
at the national conference
of catholic bishops.
In fact, Cardinal law
initially helped to fund the report.
But then he backed out
and they shelved it.
Is he kidding me?
Uh, Richard, Robby here.
We think we have 13 Priests in Boston
that fit this pattern,
which would be a very...
a very big story.
Does that sound right to you,
uh, in terms of scale?
No, not really, Robby.
Sounds low to me.
My estimates suggest six percent
act out sexually with minors.
Uh, six percent
of what?
Six percent of all Priests.
How many Priests
do we have in Boston?
About 1,500.
One percent is 15.
Six percent is... 90.
Wait.
Nine-ninety Priests?
Is that possible?
From a metric standpoint, yes.
That would certainly
be in line with my findings.
Hello?
Uh...
ninety fucking Priests?
In Boston?
That's what he said.
If there were 90 of these bastards,
people would know.
Maybe they do.
And no one said
a thing?
Good Germans.
I don't think that's a comparison
you want to make publicly.
Macleish knew.
He just didn't say anything.
That's 13 Priests.
There's a big difference
between 13 and 90.
Where's this guy Sipe
getting his numbers?
Well, he's been
studying it for 30 years.
He is a trained psychotherapist.
Okay.
But we need something more than a metric
from some hippie ex-Priest
who's shacking up
with a nun.
Okay, so we'll track down more victims.
We'll get more Priests.
Then we could check them
against the directories.
- That's a shitload of victims.
- We'll get there.
How long's it gonna take?
Too long.
Wait. Meeting's over?
Yeah, for now.
What've you got?
What if we work backwards?
What do you mean?
From what? From the directories.
We've been using them to confirm bad Priests.
What if we do it the other way around?
Use the directories to identify bad Priests.
Yeah, exactly.
We search by designation.
We look for any Priest on "sick leave" or "unassigned."
Or have been moved around a lot.
Yeah.
It's gonna take a load of work.
Well, not if we're all on it.
You too?
Generally that's what "all" means.
Yeah, generally.
Library is closing.
Holy shit.
No freakin' way.
- Talbot.
- Yep.
- Tivnan.
Toma.
Yep.
Turnbull.
Walsh.
Yep.
Welsh.
That's it.
- Holy shit.
- Robby.
That's three off Sipe's estimate.
That's incredible.
Robby.
How many?
Eighty-seven.
Eighty-seven Priests
in Boston.
Call Macleish.
I wanna talk to him. Okay.
Can you print it?
Sure can.
Jim Sullivan's office.
Yeah, Walter Robinson
for Jim Sullivan.
Tell him it's important, please.
One moment, please.
Hey, Robby.
Everything okay?
I need you
to tell me something, Jim.
Could it be 90 Priests?
What?
Could it be as high as 90?
Jesus, Robby.
I need to know, Jim.
I wouldn't be asking if it wasn't important.
You gotta stop this,
Robby.
Robby, Macleish's assistant
said he's all booked up. He can't see us.
Yeah. Well, the hell he can't.
All right.
That'll be fun.
You know what?
I'll catch up with you, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
I'm really sorry. I am.
I don't have any time to talk right now...
Mr. Macleish,
we have reason to believe
that there are allegations
against as many as 87 Priests in Boston.
I can't talk to you
about that.
Does that number sound right to you?
You gotta be kidding me.
I just told you
I don't have time for this crap now.
Eric, how many Priests
did you settle?
Robby, you know
I can't tell you that.
You're gonna give me the names
and the names of their victims.
Um...
are you threatening me?
We've got two stories here.
We've got a story
about degenerate Clergy,
and we've got a story
about a bunch of lawyers
turning child abuse
into a cottage industry.
Now, which story
do you want us to write?
'Cause we're writing one of 'em.
I already sent you
a list of names.
What are you talking about?
To whom?
The Globe. Years ago.
After the Porter case,
I got plenty of calls.
I had 20 Priests
in Boston alone,
but I couldn't go after them
without the press.
So I sent you guys
a list of names,
and you buried it.
- I want those names tomorrow.
- Check your goddamn clips, Robby.
We didn't find anything in the clips.
Yeah. Big surprise.
Richard, uh,
do you still go to Mass?
No. No, I haven't been to church
for some time now.
But I still consider myself
a catholic.
H-How does that work?
Well, the church is
an institution, Mike, made of men.
It's passing.
My faith is in the eternal.
I try to separate the two.
Sounds tricky.
It is.
Especially since the church
continues to go after me.
It takes a toll, Mike.
They'll try to silence anyone
who speaks out.
I'm sure they'll come after you
and your team soon enough.
Really. And how do you think
they'd do that?
Hello?
Richard?
Who is it?
It's the Archbishop
of Canterbury.
I had dinner at Santarpio's.
Had some leftovers.
Ah, you're the freakin' best.
Thanks.
You want a beer?
Yeah.
You got it.
Jesus. How much longer
you gonna be in this shithole?
Yeah.
I'm working on it.
She's a good girl, Mike.
Yeah, she is.
We'll figure it out.
I haven't had
a lot of time lately.
I just got off the phone
with Sipe, actually.
Have you met this guy
in person yet?
No, but his knowledge of this
is on a whole other level.
I'm frickin' starving.
So, where are we with the 90?
We're close.
How close?
Just answer the question,
will you?
We got 87 names.
We're trying to get confirmation.
I think we will.
Something bugging you?
It's just surprising,
that's all.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
For everybody.
Wait, Ben.
I forgot to ask you.
Phil Saviano said he sent a bunch of info
over to the Globe years ago.
- Do you have any idea to who?
- No. Why?
I'm just curious. I wanted to see if
there's any leads you guys didn't run out.
Saviano was a fucking train wreck five
years ago. We didn't miss anything.
This story needed Spotlight.
Yeah, I agree.
I'm just following up.
- Good night.
- Yeah, good night.
This is unbelievable.
When did you get this?
Macleish e-mailed
the list this morning.
He settled cases
against 45 Priests.
Where are we on law?
Anything that shows
he had knowledge of this?
We're still working Garabedian.
But nothing concrete.
I keep thinking about
that conversation we had the other night
about how law
called down the power of God
when we reported on Porter.
That's just law being law.
Okay. But I checked the clips, and, uh,
Porter isn't even in the Boston Archdiocese.
He's from fall river.
So... why the extreme reaction?
Law had to know.
That's why he had the reaction.
Because he knew
there were others.
I think that's the bigger story.
Wait.
Bigger than 50 Priests?
If it came
from the top down, yes.
But the numbers clearly indicate that there
were Senior Clergy involved.
That's all they do...
indicate.
Are you telling me that if we run a story
with 50 pedophile Priests in Boston...
Mike.
We'll get into the same catfight
you got into on Porter,
which made a lot of noise
but changed things not one bit.
We need to focus on the institution,
not the individual Priests.
Practice and policy.
Show me the church
manipulated the system
so that these guys
wouldn't have to face charges.
Show me they put those
same Priests back into parishes
time and time again.
Show me this was systemic,
that it came from the top down.
Sounds like
we're going after law.
We're going after
the system.
Make a list of all the victims we have.
Start reaching out.
And bring Matt in if you need help.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Hey, when do you go to Springfield?
Our hearing is Monday.
Okay.
Hey, Robby,
you got a second?
Yeah.
I, uh... I got one of those treatment
centers a block from my house.
We got neighbors
with kids.
I know that the work we do
is confidential,
but I'm feeling like...
I should tell 'em.
We'll tell 'em soon.
You sure?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hi there. I'm Sacha Pfeiffer.
I'm with the Boston Globe.
I'm just looking for a gentleman
by the name of Matthew Walsh.
Uh, no, he's not.
Right there.
Yeah. Okay. Okay.
Hi.
I'm Sacha Pfeiffer
from the Boston Globe.
Yeah, what do you want?
I'd like to speak with Thomas Kennedy.
He doesn't live here anymore.
Do you know where he lives?
Sir, I'd just like
to ask a few...
Sacha Pfeiffer, Boston Globe.
Oh, yeah. Hi.
Hi. Thank you.
Anything else you can recall?
No.
No, but I got
a cousin in Quincy.
She saw him in the street
a few years later.
The bishop
came to the house.
He said nothing like this
had ever happened before.
- He asked us not to press charges.
- And what did your mother do?
My mother?
She put out
freakin' cookies.
There was
a lot of pressure to keep quiet.
From the church?
Yeah, from the church.
But not just
the church.
From my friends.
From the other parishioners.
Well, many of
the Priests that I treated
were psychosexually stunted.
On the emotional level
of a 12- or 13-year-old.
Jesus.
Sure the chief knew.
Everybody knew.
But nobody wants
to cuff a Priest.
Mmm. And what about
the prosecutor?
I shouldn't talk about this shit.
I think you should, actually.
Do you know a father Hurley
or a father Gale?
I do.
I'll beat the shit out of you.
Sorry to bother you.
You leave me alone. You leave my brother alone.
You hear me? Goddamn it.
Hi there. I'm looking
for Ronald Paquin.
Yes?
You're father Paquin?
Yes. That's right.
I'm Sacha Pfeiffer
from the Boston Globe. I...
okay. Could I ask you
a few questions?
Go ahead, dear.
We spoke to several men
who knew you when they were boys
at St. John the baptist
in Haverhill.
Did... they told us you molested them.
Is that true?
Mmm, sure,
I fooled around.
But I never
felt gratified myself.
Right. Um...
but you admit to molesting boys
at St. John the baptist?
Yes, yes, but as I said,
I never got any pleasure from it.
That's important
to understand.
Right.
Um, but can you tell me
where and how you
fooled around with these boys?
I want to be clear.
I never raped anyone.
There's a difference.
I should know.
- How would you know?
- I was raped.
I'm sorry. Who raped you?
Ronny, who are you talking to?
It's okay, Jane.
Father Paquin, who raped you?
Who are you?
Uh, Sacha Pfeiffer,
from the Globe.
Please get off my porch.
I can speak for myself.
Get inside the house, Ron.
Mr...
get inside, Ron.
Okay.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
I'm his sister.
- And I don't want you coming back here.
- Miss Paquin...
beat you to the end
of the street.
- No, you won't.
- I beat you last time.
Boy #1 no, you didn't. You cheated.
You did.
Could you please clarify the Globe's
position for me, Mr. Albano?
Yes, Judge Sweeney.
Our argument to make
these documents public
rests mainly
on first amendment grounds.
We also have a number of other
relevant arguments.
After all, your honor,
this was a discretionary order.
Yes. It was made
at the judge's discretion.
Hey, Mike.
Hey, Joe.
What's a Spotlight reporter
doing in Springfield?
Your boy Albano's
sledding uphill.
You actually think you have a shot
at winning this thing?
You want me
to comment for the Herald?
"Globe reporter
would not comment,
but he did not
seem hopeful."
He didn't try
and hide it at all.
He had this really
odd rationalization for it,
like it was totally normal
to fool around with little boys.
I'd really like to go back.
I think he'd talk to us.
Oh, we will.
Just not yet.
I want you to stay focused
on the victims right now.
Sacha, where'd they send
father Talbot again?
Um, I think...
wasn't that Cheverus?
Cheverus.
That's right. Wait.
Father Talbot from BC High?
Yeah.
You know him?
Yeah. He was there
when I was.
We have a victim?
Yeah. Lives in Providence.
There's nothing personal
in these documents, your honor.
They concern
how the Cardinal is handling...
say "The Archdiocese."
Excuse me?
You don't get to tag
the Cardinal with everything, Mr. Albano.
Say "The Archdiocese."
Judge Sweeney, the Globe is not a party to
this case. They just want to sell papers.
If Mr. Garabedian had not smeared
the Cardinal's good name,
we wouldn't
even be here.
Your honor, I object to the use
of the word "smear."
- Duly noted, Mr. Garabedian.
- Thank you, your honor.
- Anything else, Mr. Rogers?
- No, your honor.
Mr. Albano,
you may continue.
The Globe
believes having...
hey, Mitch, how you doing?
I'm fine.
He's tough,
that Wilson Rogers.
He's smug.
And he's sloppy.
He doesn't seem sloppy.
You don't know the half of it.
Trust me.
What's the half of it?
Tell me the half of it,
Mitch.
Off the record?
Off the record, yeah.
Three years ago,
I get a call from an ex-Priest.
Anthony Benzevich.
He was at blessed sacrament
back in '62,
and he saw Geoghan...
Taking little boys up to
the rectory bedroom, okay?
So he's appalled, all right?
Tells the bishop about it.
And the bishop threatens
to reassign him to South America.
Jesus.
Yeah, all right.
So fast-forward 35 years,
Benzevich reads
that Geoghan has been charged
with molesting hundreds of kids.
All right? So he feels guilty.
He calls me.
So you have testimony
of a Priest
telling his superiors
about Geoghan in '62?
No, I do not.
Because when I called
Benzevich in to give a deposition,
he comes in
with a lawyer.
Wilson Rogers.
Right.
And suddenly father Benzevich
has a very foggy memory.
Can't remember anything.
He's useless.
So I go back to work.
I forget about it. Whatever.
Until about a year ago,
I find an article
about a Priest who warned
church officials about Geoghan.
Benzevich went to the press?
Yeah.
Yeah. Local paper, Patriot Ledger.
Nobody saw it.
But now I got Benzevich
on record.
So I file a motion to depose Benzevich
a second time. All right?
And Wilson Rogers,
that smug son of a bitch,
he files a motion
opposing my motion.
And that's when I have him.
Have... have him how?
Rogers opposes my motion,
so I have to make an argument
as to why I'm allowed to depose
father Benzevich a second time, okay?
But this time,
I'm allowed to attach exhibits.
Do you follow
what I'm saying?
The sealed documents?
Yes.
I can attach
the sealed documents
that I've gotten in discovery,
Mr. Rezendes,
the same documents that your paper
is currently suing for.
You're shitting me.
What? No.
No, I'm not shitting you.
So I pull out
the 14 most damning docs
and I attach them
to my motion.
And they prove everything.
Everything.
About the church,
about the bishops, about law.
And it's all public?
Because your motion
to oppose Roger's motion...
is public.
Yeah. Exactly.
Now you're paying attention.
So I could just walk into that courthouse
right now and get those documents?
No, you cannot, because the documents
are not there.
But you just said
they're public.
I know I did.
But this is Boston.
And the church
does not want them to be found.
So they are not there.
Mitch, are you telling me
that the catholic church
removed legal documents
from that courthouse?
Look, I'm not crazy.
I'm not paranoid.
I'm experienced.
Check the docket.
You'll see.
They control everything.
Everything.
I gotta go back in.
I just got
the fucking documents.
Docket entry number 49,
in the Geoghan case.
Okay, thanks.
We close in 10 minutes.
Ten minutes? All right.
Robby.
Hey, it's me.
Hey.
You're not gonna believe it.
Garabedian gave me a tip.
Some of the sealed docs are already public.
They're part of a motion he filed.
He said they're
the best of the bunch.
We don't have to wait
for Sweeney's ruling.
So we can get them?
Yeah, but they're not there.
Already talked to Albano.
He said all we have to do is file a motion,
and Sweeney will order Mitch
to refile the docs.
And you think
these documents are...
he said these 14 docs are all we need.
They're huge.
Okay.
I'll call Ben. Good work.
Is this purely an accident
or could this have been
an intentional act?
Either way, extensive damage
has been done to this building.
What happened?
They're saying it's a prop plane,
but that's not a prop plane.
Tell Linda to get every reporter
we have in here now.
You pray for the victims.
You pray for the injured.
And you pray
for those who survived.
You pray, too, for the nation.
That our response to this
might reflect
the best ideals of our nation.
And even more,
reflect God's own teaching,
not only as it's shown
in Christianity and Judaism
but in Islam as well.
Not bad.
Who's there? Paulson.
I wanna talk to him
when he's back.
Did Rezendes find a way
to get to Florida yet?
They just opened the airport in Providence.
He's on his way there now.
Ben, I'm gonna need
more people on massport.
I'll give you
three of my guys.
Robby, put your team on that too.
Got it.
- And, Robby, everything else stops.
- Understood.
Why is Mike
going to Florida?
Flight school.
It's where they learned to fly.
Robby, I've got a lot of victim interviews
set up this week.
You're gonna
have to cancel 'em.
That's gonna be hard.
I know. This is nuts.
Two days ago I told my wife we gotta be
working the biggest story on the planet.
Boston Globe.
One Moment, please.
Yes, if you have a tip,
I will transfer you down to Metro.
Mitchell Garabedian.
Mitch, it's Mike.
I've been trying to reach you.
I don't have time to talk
to you, Mr. Rezendes.
Hey, just quickly.
Did you refile those docs yet?
No. I just got the order.
It takes time.
Okay, great. Can you hold off
on refiling them? Hold off?
I have to go to Florida.
Once you refile they're public.
Other newspapers will be able
to get a hold of 'em.
Other newspapers
are not my concern.
I received a judicial order.
I told you the church
is watching me.
Hey, Mitch, please.
All I need is a few more weeks.
I can't make any promises.
Good-bye.
Mitch! Mitch! Shit!
Shit.
Look, I get it.
No one wants to read about kids
getting raped by Priests, especially now.
But you asked
a lot of people
to relive some very painful experiences,
and you just disappear.
Phil, you know why
we were taken off of this story.
It's been six weeks
since 9/11.
I realize that,
and we're gonna get back to it.
When?
You're doing the same thing
you guys did last time. No.
You're dropping us.
No.
Maybe I should tell
the Herald that story.
Okay, Phil,
you go ahead and do that.
It'll undo all the work we've done,
but I can't stop you.
Listen to me.
I am here because I care.
We're not going away.
We're gonna tell this story.
We're gonna tell it right.
We just need a little more time.
That's all we're asking for.
Why bother asking?
You're gonna do
what you want anyway.
You always do.
Phil.
Phil!
Hey.
How's south beach?
Boynton beach.
Remarkably different place.
What's up?
Mitch Garabedian
called me today.
Why'd he call you?
'Cause he knew you'd yell at him.
He refiled the docs.
What?
Robby, those docs
are public now.
We gotta get there before anyone else does.
I know. I know. I know.
Just wrap up whatever you're doing
and get the first flight out.
I'll book a flight now and go straight
to the courthouse tomorrow.
All right. Call me when you get in.
Okay.
Robby, I'd like to let Phil Saviano know
that we're back on it.
Good idea.
Go have dinner with Hansi.
Might be the last time for a while.
Mm-hmm.
Robby,
after we saw Macleish,
I started going back
through the clips.
And I had a little time
last week finally.
So, um, I found that.
It's from '93.
That it?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's... that's it.
Good night.
Okay. Good night.
Hello.
So, I was probably
a few years after you, right?
No, you were more than a few.
Believe me.
Well, after BC High,
I came down to Providence
and played hockey
for the Friars.
Oh, well, you must
have been pretty good.
No. Rode the bench
in college. Yeah.
But I loved the city.
Uh-huh. And we just had
our third kid.
And I still get my Globe,
for the record.
Ah, that's good to know.
Good to know.
Look, Kevin, uh,
that's actually why I'm here.
Yeah?
I...
I need to ask you some questions
about father Talbot.
How'd you find out?
Well...
um...
I guess
it doesn't matter.
Hell, I never even
told my wife.
Excuse me.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I need to get in there.
We're closed. Come on. Let me in.
Five minutes.
- I'm sorry. We're closed.
- Come on. Five minutes.
Here. There.
This is the Geoghan case?
That's right.
- Those records are sealed.
- No. That's a public motion.
Those records are public.
- Look, I work for the Globe.
- Good for you.
Can I talk to your supervisor?
He's not in today.
What about a judge? There must be judges
that work on this kind of thing.
Sixth floor.
We understand the nature
of the allegations against father Talbot.
I'm just not sure what you want
from President Kemeza.
Talbot taught here
long before Bill took over.
Mmm. Of course.
We just want to know
if it's possible
that the president,
the faculty, the board,
that no one knew
what was going on at the time.
I graduated in 1979,
and I had no idea
about any of this.
So if you're suggesting
that father Gibbons
and father Callahan
had in any way...
Gibbons and Callahan.
I mean, they ran this place
like the Navy.
You really think
they didn't know?
It's a big school, Robby.
You know that.
And then we're talking about seven
alleged victims over, what, eight years?
No, we're talking about,
you know, seven that we know about.
This is ridiculous.
You're reaching for a story here...
Jack. Jack.
Jack. If I had been president then,
I would've known.
Bill, I'm not sure
that's relevant.
Why do you think
they sent Talbot up to Cheverus?
You know they wanted him
out of town.
Robby,
as well intentioned
as Bill's remarks are,
I'm hoping we can keep this between
us until we all get on the same page.
Is that why we're here,
to get on the same page?
No, we're here because you're an
important alumnus, Robby, and a friend.
Exactly. And we know you care about
this school as much as we do.
Did you play a sport here, Jack?
Yeah. Football. Why?
Mmm. I ran track.
You know,
I went to Providence yesterday
to talk to one
of father Talbot's victims.
He played hockey here.
And he's one of the better ones.
He's got a wife, kids, good job.
About 10 minutes
into the conversation,
the guy breaks down.
You know,
couldn't stop crying.
Said he could never figure out
why father Talbot picked him.
Father Talbot
coached the hockey team.
So...
I guess we just got lucky.
You and me.
Does Jack Dunn work for the school?
No, he's PR for Boston college.
They call him
when they need help.
And Pete Conley,
why was he there?
Good question.
Pete's a big alum.
But I called Bill directly
and I asked for a sit-down.
I never mentioned
anybody else.
It's like everybody
already knows the story.
Yeah. Except us.
And we work right there.
Judge Volterra?
Yes?
Hi. I'm Mike Rezendes
from the Boston Globe.
I'm having some trouble accessing some
public records down in the records room.
I was wondering
if I could have a word with you?
All right.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
These exhibits you're after,
Mr. Rezendes,
they're very sensitive records.
With all due respect, your honor,
that's not the question.
The records are public.
Maybe so, but tell me,
where's the editorial
responsibility
in publishing records
of this nature?
Well, where's the editorial responsibility
in not publishing them?
You can't take those.
You need to make copies.
I'm going to the copy room.
It closed at 4:00.
Look, I'll give you...
83 bucks
to use yours.
Hey! Cabbie!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Take me to the Boston Globe
on Morrissey Boulevard.
Don't take 93.
Take Dorchester Avenue.
Robby, it's incredible.
Law knew about Geoghan
for years, no question.
There's a letter to law
from a woman, Margaret Gallant,
who lived in Jamaica plain
in the early '80 when Geoghan was there.
Listen to this.
"Our family is rooted
in the church.
Our desire is to protect
the Holy orders
even in the midst of our agony
over the seven boys
in our family who have been violated."
Seven, Robby. Seven boys.
"It was suggested
we keep silent.
We did not question the authority of
the church two years ago.
But since father Geoghan
is still in his parish... "
but she sent it to law
and law did shit.
Here's another one to law,
same year. Listen to this.
"A word on the recent assignment
of father Geoghan...
As an associate
at St. Julia's in Weston.
Father Geoghan has a history
of homosexual involvement with young boys.
I understand his recent departure
from St. Brendan's
may be related
to this problem.
I wonder if father Geoghan
should not be reduced to just weekend work
while receiving
some kind of therapy.
You know how grateful I am to you
for your constant concern.
Sincerely yours
in our lord,
most reverend John M D'Arcy,
auxiliary bishop of Boston.
December 7, 1984."
An auxiliary bishop
wrote that?
That's incredible.
He broke ranks.
I mean, when did Gallant write her letter?
1984.
And law just ignored it.
How do you ignore
that freakin' letter?
We got 'em.
You can't read these letters
and think anything else. It's proof.
Yeah, it is.
This is good work.
Should we take it
up to Ben?
Uh, no. Not yet.
Why not?
We got law. This is it.
No, this is law covering for one Priest.
There's another 90 out there.
Yeah, we'll print that story when
we get it, but we gotta go with this now.
I'm not gonna rush this story, Mike.
We don't have a choice, Robby.
If we don't rush to print,
somebody else is going to find
these letters and butcher the story.
Joe Quimby from the Herald
was at the freaking courthouse.
So we'll write a holding story
and we'll keep our eye on the Herald.
Keep our eye
on the Herald?
They run this and get it wrong,
the church will bury it.
- We gotta do this now.
- Mike, Mike.
What? Why are we hesitating?
Baron told us to get law.
This is law.
Baron told us
to get the system.
We need the full scope. That's the only
thing that will put an end to this.
Then let's take it to Ben,
let him decide.
We'll take it to Ben
when I say it's time.
It's time, Robby! It's time!
They knew and they
let it happen. To kids!
Okay? It could've been you.
It could've been me.
It could've been any of us.
We gotta nail these scumbags.
We gotta show people that nobody
can get away with this.
Not a Priest or a Cardinal
or a freaking Pope!
You finished?
Yeah, I am.
This is bullshit.
You okay?
Mmm.
Hey, Hansi.
Hard day at work, Mike?
Here.
Thank you.
I-I-I-I don't know
why I got so pissed off.
You know,
I think Robby's wrong.
You know, you're just...
you care about the story, Mike. We all do.
Yeah, I guess.
Hmm.
I stopped going to church
with my Nana.
It was...
it was too hard. I...
you know,
I'd be sitting there,
and I would start thinking about
Joe Crowley or someone else,
and I just...
I just got so angry.
Did you...
did you tell her why?
She goes to church
three times a week, Mike.
It really pisses me off.
You know,
I actually really liked
going to church when I was a little kid.
Mmm.
Why'd you stop?
Typical shit.
But the weird thing is is...
I think i...
I think I figured that
maybe one day I w... I w...
I would actually go back.
I was really...
I was holding on to that.
Mm-hmm.
I read those letters,
and it...
and something just... cracked.
It's a shitty feeling.
Yeah.
Looks like a long day.
Hey, Pete.
I'm sorry to make it longer.
Brian.
Has anyone ever said no
to a drink with you, Pete?
Well, sure.
But the trick
is to keep asking.
For Boston.
Boston.
Mmm.
So, um, you here
for the Cardinal?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I wouldn't... I wouldn't presume
to speak for the Cardinal, no.
You know, you got a lot of people here
who respect you, Robby.
Oh, well...
the work you do.
That's good to know.
It's 'cause you care about this place.
It's why you do what you do.
It's who you are.
You know, but people need the church,
more than ever right now.
You know, you can feel it.
And the Cardinal, uh...
you know, the Cardinal,
he might not be perfect.
But we can't throw out all the good
e's doing over a few bad apples.
Now, you know, I'm bringing this up to
you because I know this is Baron's idea.
His agenda.
I gotta tell ya,
I mean, honest to God,
I mean, he doesn't care
about the city the way we do.
I mean, how could he?
This is how it happens,
isn't it, Pete?
What's that?
A guy leans on a guy,
and suddenly the whole town
just looks the other way.
Robby. Robby. Lookit.
Marty Baron is just trying
to make his mark.
He's gonna be here for a couple
of years and he's gonna move on.
Just like he did
in New York and Miami.
Where are you gonna go?
Hmm?
Good night, Robby. Brian.
Hey, uh, Pete.
Yeah?
Uh, when we do run the story,
uh, I'm gonna need a comment
from the Cardinal.
We'll talk again later.
Good night, Robby.
Night, Pete.
Robby.
What?
No shit. When?
Okay. Yeah.
Hey.
What's up?
Sweeney ruled
in our favor.
She ruled
to unseal the documents.
Geez.
Huh.
The church has already
filed an appeal.
But the trial court ruling
is generally upheld in these matters.
And when would we get
the documents?
Probably takes Cohen
a few weeks to rule.
Then there's
a redaction process.
Uh, I'd say they'd be
made public mid-January.
Okay.
All right.
Thanks, John.
You bet.
Nice work.
Thanks.
Metro should
run something, Marty.
We can't
run this one big.
Why wouldn't we?
It's a major first amendment victory.
Not to mention, you get an Irish Catholic
judge ruling against the church?
That's a hell of a precedent.
Mm-hmm.
We don't want the Herald
going deep on this.
Why's that?
You're gonna have
to step out, Peter.
I'm not stepping out.
Peter.
When did you, uh...
a couple of weeks ago.
A couple of weeks?
- Yeah.
- And you're telling us now?
These are substantial.
They clearly show
that law was negligent.
I need more time.
- I wanna keep digging.
- For what?
This is the goddamn story.
It's not the whole story.
Tough shit.
We're on a clock now.
Even if we don't run
Sweeney's ruling,
another paper could find these letters
and fuck the story.
Agreed. But we run
these letters alone,
law apologizes, says it's a one-time thing.
He can bury it.
How? These clearly show he knew
and did nothing about it.
Look, I'm close to stories
on 70 Priests.
We nail that,
along with those letters,
this is proof
that this is bigger than law.
It's the whole system.
You have multiple sources
confirming all those Priests?
- On some. I can get more.
- Too risky.
If we're not buttoned up on every single
one of them, the church will pick us apart.
I think I can get us someone
from the other side of the aisle.
Somebody inside the church?
Yeah. A lawyer.
Will he go on the record?
Deep background.
But he's a solid source.
Rezendes needs time
to write the story.
We don't want to drop it
at Christmas, not after 9/11.
We could run it
just after new year's,
before they release
the rest of the documents.
All right.
Tell Canellos
to bury the ruling in Metro.
You got six weeks.
Thank you.
Tell Mike
I want a draft by Christmas.
And we need a response
from Lake Street.
Who does PR for the Cardinal?
Still John Walsh?
No, somebody new. Donna Morrissey.
She came from TV. She's young.
Good. Get a quote. We need something
from law to appear evenhanded.
Robby, next time give me
a goddamn heads-up.
Will do.
Robby, what a nice surprise.
Come on in.
Hey, hon,
look who I found outside.
Karen, can you
give us a minute?
Sure.
Good to see you, Karen.
What's up?
I'm out of time, Jim.
We've got cover-up stories
on 70 Priests.
But the boss isn't gonna run it
unless I get confirmation from your side.
Are you out of your mind?
Come on.
This is our town, Jimmy.
Everybody knew something was going on,
and no one did a thing.
- We gotta put an end to it.
- Don't tell me what I gotta do.
Yeah, I helped defend these scumbags,
but that's my job, Robby.
I was doing my job.
Yeah.
You and everyone else.
Get out of my house.
Hey!
You come to my home
and lay this shit on me?
You were right, Robby.
We all knew
something was going on.
So where were you?
What took you so long?
I don't know, Jim.
Give me the list.
Larry, we're going to press
in six hours.
Donna Morrissey said she'd call us
with a quote from law hours ago.
That's what I thought.
When did you talk to her?
Okay. Okay, Larry.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, that's good
to know. Thanks, Pete.
Anything?
Conley said Donna Morrissey should've called.
He just left lake street.
Yeah, Rasky said
the same thing.
This is ridiculous.
You'd think they want to get ahead of this.
I mean,
they'd be idiots not to.
I would love to see their faces
when they read this thing.
Sunday's the feast
of the Epiphany.
That seems appropriate.
Mike Rezendes.
Hey, Donna.
Thanks for calling. Yeah, I just had a few
questions if you have a minute.
What?
Another adjective.
Anything?
Law just turned us down.
Jesus Christ.
I just got off the phone
with Donna Morrissey.
She said, quote, "we don't even want to
know what the questions are," end quote.
- She really said that?
- Yeah.
Well, that ought
to do it.
"The church
had no interest
in knowing what the Globe's questions
would be."
Work it in somewhere before the jump.
Anything else?
Matt wants to put the letters online
so the readers can see for themselves.
We can run the URL
at the bottom of the article.
- It's pretty straightforward.
- Okay.
We also put the Spotlight tip line at the
end of the story so people can call in.
Goes directly
to our office.
Matt and I can go in in the morning
in case we get any calls.
Yeah, I'm more concerned
about the phones at reception.
After we ran the Porter case,
the message centers were tied up for weeks.
It's a real problem.
There were picketers too.
Lots of 'em.
I'll talk to Richard about
the security and the phones.
Uh, how are we coming
on the folo story?
Well, we've nailed down
multiple stories on 70 Priests.
- All 70?
- Mm-hmm.
And with confirmation from Robby's source,
we're ready to go.
We can have a draft
next week.
Robby, that source of yours,
is it something we could revisit?
It might be tough.
But he has no problem helping the
church protect dozens of dirty Priests.
- Guy's a scumbag.
- He's a lawyer. He's doing his job.
- He's a shill for the church.
- He knew and did nothing.
He could've said something years ago,
maybe saved some lives.
What about us?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- We had all the pieces.
Why didn't we get it sooner?
We didn't have all the pieces.
We had Saviano.
We had Barrett.
We had Geoghan.
We had the directories
in the basement.
- You know what? We got it now.
- Robby, the story needed Spotlight.
Mike, Spotlight's
been around since 1970.
So what? We couldn't see
the scope of this. No one could.
Robby, this started
with one goddamn Priest.
Macleish sent us a letter
on 20 Priests years ago.
Sacha found the clip.
You freaking kidding?
Twenty Priests?
When?
Uh, just after Porter.
December '93.
We buried the story in Metro.
No folo.
That was you?
You were Metro.
Yeah. That was me.
I'd just taken over.
I don't remember it at all.
But yeah.
Um,
can I, uh,
say something here?
Sometimes it's easy to forget
that we spend most of our time
stumbling around in the dark.
Suddenly a light gets turned on,
and there's a fair share
of blame to go around.
I can't speak to
what happened before I arrived,
but, uh, all of you have done
some very good reporting here.
Reporting that I believe
is gonna have an immediate
and considerable impact
on our readers.
For me, this kind of story
is why we do this.
Having said that,
Cardinal law
and the Catholic Community
are gonna have
a very strong response to this.
So if you need a moment,
you've earned it.
But, uh,
I will need you back here
Monday morning,
focused and ready
to do your job.
- Leaving?
- Yeah.
I, uh, just got a call
from the Cardinal.
Really. Why?
He wanted to tell me personally
that he decided not to comment.
Yeah. Said he wanted to, uh,
extend me that courtesy.
Jesus, the balls on that guy.
What did you say?
I told him he was making a mistake and that
we were gonna run the story.
Damn right
we're gonna run it.
Sacha, can I have
a drink of water?
Yeah. Sure, Nana. Yeah.
Can I keep this?
Sure.
I thought you
should see it first.
Thank you for bringing it by.
Now, I have some clients
I have to attend to.
Yeah.
Both kids were abused.
Jamaica Plain.
Two weeks ago.
Keep... doing your work,
Mr. Rezendes.
- Hello.
How are you guys doing?
- Good, thanks.
- Good.
- Hey.
- Good morning.
How'd you sleep?
Not very well. You?
I haven't slept well for months.
Mmm.
Oh, thanks.
I, uh, actually started writing.
Writing?
Yeah, I've been working on a book.
Gives me something else
to focus on.
What kind of book?
Horror.
Yeah.
Spotlight.
Yeah, of course. Can I, uh...
can I get your name, please?
You do know it's Sunday, right?
Couldn't get a tee time.
No picketers.
Yeah.
Probably still at church.
Hey, Linda.
It's quiet, huh?
Yeah. Easiest overtime
I ever made.
Phone hasn't rung once.
Marty sent two of mine
down to Spotlight.
Great article, guys.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Spotlight?
Okay. Yep.
Spotlight. Can I help you?
Phones have been ringing
all morning.
Spotlight.
- Mike, can you grab that?
- Yeah, yeah.
They're almost all victims,
Robby.
- I'm sorry to make you wait.
- Sacha Pfeiffer.
I'm sorry...
can you...
yes, you can reach me here.
This is Spotlight.
Can I get your name?
Did you happen to have any contact
with anybody that was there afterward?
Do you remember
what year this was?
Which parish was it?
This is Spotlight.