Lydia! Kitty!
My dear Mr Bennet, have you heard?
Netherfield Park is let at last. Do you
not want to know who has taken it?
As you wish to tell me, my dear,
I doubt I have any choice in the matter.
Kitty, what have I told you
about listening at the door?
There's a Mr Bingley
arrived from the North.
- Five thousand a year!
- Really?
- He's single!
- Who's single?
A Mr Bingley, apparently. Kitty!
How can that possibly affect them?
Mr Bennet,
how can you be so tiresome?
You know he must marry one of them.
That is his design in settling here?
You must go and visit him at once.
Good heavens. People.
For we may not visit if you do not,
as you well know, Mr Bennet.
- Are you listening? You never listen.
- You must, Papa! At once!
There's no need. I already have.
- You have?
- When?
Oh, Mr Bennet,
how can you tease me so?
Have you no compassion
for my poor nerves?
You mistake me, my dear.
I have the highest respect for them.
They've been my constant companions
these twenty years.
Papa!
- Is he amiable?
- Who?
- Is he handsome?
- He's sure to be.
With 5,000 a year,
it would not matter if he had warts.
Who's got warts?
I will consent to
his marrying whichever girl he chooses.
- So will he come to the ball tomorrow?
- I believe so.
- Mr Bennet!
- I have to have your muslin!
- I'll lend you my green slippers!
- They were mine.
- I'll do your mending for a week.
- I'll retrim your new bonnet.
Two weeks I'll do it for.
It's not the same!
It's not the same.
I can't breathe.
I think one of
my toes just came off.
If every man does not end the evening
in love with you,
then I'm no judge of beauty.
- Or men.
- No, they are far too easy to judge.
They're not all bad.
Humourless poppycocks,
in my limited experience.
One day,
someone will catch your eye,
and then you'll have
to watch your tongue.
How good of you to come.
Which of the painted peacocks
is our Mr Bingley?
He's on the right.
On the left is his sister.
- The person with the quizzical brow?
- That is his good friend, Mr Darcy.
- He looks miserable, poor soul.
- He may be, but poor he is not.
Tell me.
10,000 a year,
and he owns half of Derbyshire.
The miserable half.
Mr Bennet, you must introduce him
to the girls immediately.
Smile at Mr Bingley. Smile.
Mary.
Mr Bingley, my eldest daughter you know.
Mrs Bennet, Miss Jane Bennet,
Elizabeth and Miss Mary Bennet.
It is a pleasure. I have two others,
but they're already dancing.
I'm delighted to make your acquaintance.
And may I introduce Mr Darcy
of Pemberley in Derbyshire.
How do you like it
here in Hertfordshire?
Very much.
The library at Netherfield,
I've heard, is one of the finest.
It fills me with guilt. I'm not a good
reader. I prefer being out of doors.
Oh, I mean, I can read, of course.
And I'm not suggesting
you can't read out of doors.
I wish I read more, but there
seem to be so many other things to do.
That's exactly what I meant.
Mama, Mama! You will never, ever believe
what we're about to tell you.
- Tell me!
- She's going to take the veil.
- The regiment are coming!
- Officers?
They're going to be stationed
the whole winter, right here.
- Officers?
- As far as the eye can see.
Oh, look.
Jane's dancing with Mr Bingley.
Mr Bennet.
- Do you dance, Mr Darcy?
- Not if I can help it.
I didn't know you were coming
to see me. What's the matter?
We are a long way from Grosvenor Square,
are we not, Mr Darcy?
I've never seen so many pretty girls.
You were dancing
with the only handsome girl.
She is the most beautiful creature
I have ever beheld.
- But her sister Elizabeth is agreeable.
- Perfectly tolerable.
Not handsome enough to tempt me. Return
to your partner and enjoy her smiles.
You're wasting your time with me.
Count your blessings, Lizzie. If he
liked you, you'd have to talk to him.
Precisely.
I wouldn't dance with him
for all of Derbyshire,
let alone the miserable half.
Wait!
- I enjoyed that so much, Miss Lucas.
- How well you dance, Mr Bingley.
I've never enjoyed a dance so much.
My daughter Jane
is a splendid dancer, is she not?
She is indeed.
Your friend Miss Lucas
is a most amusing young woman.
Oh, yes, I adore her.
- It is a pity she's not more handsome.
- Mama!
Oh, but Lizzie
would never admit that she's plain.
Of course, it's my Jane who's considered
the beauty of the county.
Mama, please!
When she was 15, a gentleman
was so much in love with her,
I was sure he would make her an offer.
However, he did write her
some very pretty verses.
And that put paid to it.
I wonder who discovered the power
of poetry in driving away love.
- I thought poetry was the food of love.
- Of a fine, stout love.
But if it is only a vague inclination,
one poor sonnet will kill it.
So, what do you recommend
to encourage affection?
Dancing. Even if one's partner
is barely tolerable.
Mr Bingley is just what
a young man ought to be.
- Sensible, good-humoured...
- Handsome, conveniently rich...
Marriage should not be driven
by thoughts of money.
Only deep love
will persuade me to marry.
- Which is why I'll end up an old maid.
- Do you really believe he liked me?
He danced with you most of the night,
and stared at you the rest.
I give you leave to like him.
You've liked many stupider.
You're a great deal too apt
to like people in general.
All the world
is good in your eyes.
Not his friend. I still can't believe
what he said about you.
Mr Darcy?
I'd more easily forgive his vanity
had he not wounded mine.
But no matter.
I doubt we shall ever speak again.
He danced with Miss Lucas.
We were all there, dear.
It is a shame she's not more handsome.
There's a spinster
in the making and no mistake.
The fourth with a Miss King
of little standing,
and the fifth again with Jane.
If he had any compassion,
he would've sprained his ankle.
The way you carry on,
you'd think our girls look forward
to a grand inheritance.
When you die,
which may be very soon,
they will be left without a roof over
their head nor a penny to their name.
- Please, it's ten in the morning.
- A letter to Miss Bennet, ma'am.
From Netherfield Hall.
Praise the Lord. We are saved!
Make haste, Jane,
make haste. Oh, happy day!
It is from Caroline Bingley.
She has invited me to dine with her.
- Her brother will be dining out.
- Dining out?
- Can I take the carriage?
- Let me see.
- It is too far to walk.
- This is unaccountable of him.
Mama, the carriage for Jane?
Certainly not. She'll go on horseback.
Horseback!
Lizzie.
Now she'll have to stay the night,
exactly as I predicted.
Good grief, woman,
your skills in the art of matchmaking
are positively occult.
Though I don't think, Mama,
you can take credit for making it rain.
"My friends will not hear of me
returning home until I am better.
Excepting a sore throat, a fever and
a headache, nothing is wrong with me."
If Jane does die it will be a comfort
to know it was in pursuit of Mr Bingley.
People do not die of colds.
But she may perish with the
shame of having such a mother.
I must go to Netherfield at once.
Lady Bathurst is redecorating
her ballroom in the French style.
A little unpatriotic, don't you think?
Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
Good Lord, did you walk here?
I did.
- I'm so sorry. How is my sister?
- She's upstairs.
Thank you.
My goodness, did you
see her hem? Six inches deep in mud.
She looked positively mediaeval.
I feel such a terrible imposition.
They're being so kind to me.
I don't know who is more pleased at your
being here, Mama or Mr Bingley.
Thank you for tending
to my sister so diligently.
She's in far better comfort
than at home.
It's a pleasure.
I mean, it's not a pleasure
that she's ill. Of course not.
It's a pleasure that she's here,
being ill.
Not going to be famous, our pig.
Black on the back, but not related
to the learned pig of Norwich.
- Now that pig is...
- Mr Bennet.
It's all going to plan.
He's half in love with her already.
- Who is, blossom?
- Mr Bingley.
He doesn't mind
that she hasn't a penny.
He has more than enough
for the two of them.
- How will we meet them?
- Easy!
Wait for me!
You drop something. They
pick it up. And then you're introduced.
Officers!
You write uncommonly fast, Mr Darcy.
You're mistaken. I write slowly.
How many letters you must have occasion
to write, Mr Darcy.
Letters of business.
How odious I should think them.
It is fortunate, then,
they fall to me and not you.
Tell your sister I long to see her.
- I've already told her once.
- I do dote on her.
I was quite in raptures
at her beautiful design for a table.
Perhaps you will give me leave
to defer your raptures.
I have not room enough
to do them justice.
You young ladies are so accomplished.
- What do you mean?
- You paint tables, play the piano
and embroider cushions.
I never heard of a lady,
but people say she's accomplished.
The word is applied too liberally.
I do not know more than
half a dozen women
- that are truly accomplished.
- Nor I.
Goodness, you must comprehend
a great deal in the idea.
- I do.
- Absolutely.
She must have a knowledge of music,
singing, drawing, dancing
and the modern languages
to deserve the word.
And something in her air
and manner of walking.
And she must improve her mind
by extensive reading.
I'm no longer surprised at your knowing
only six accomplished women.
- I wonder at you knowing any.
- Are you so severe on your own sex?
I never saw such a woman. She would
certainly be a fearsome thing to behold.
Miss Elizabeth,
let us take a turn about the room.
It's refreshing, is it not,
after sitting so long in one attitude?
It is a small kind of accomplishment,
I suppose.
Will you not join us, Mr Darcy?
You can only have two motives,
and I would interfere with either.
What can he mean?
The surest way to disappoint him
would be to ask him nothing.
Do tell us, Mr Darcy.
Either you are
in each other's confidence
and you have
secret affairs to discuss,
or you are conscious
that your figures
appear to the greatest
advantage by walking.
If the first,
I should get in your way.
If the second,
I can admire you much better from here.
How shall we punish him
for such a speech?
- We could laugh at him.
- No. Mr Darcy is not to be teased.
Are you too proud, Mr Darcy? And would
you consider pride a fault or a virtue?
- I couldn't say.
- We're trying to find a fault in you.
I find it hard to forgive
the follies and vices of others,
or their offences against me.
My good opinion,
once lost, is lost forever.
Oh, dear.
I cannot tease you about that.
What a shame,
for I dearly love to laugh.
A family trait, I think.
A Mrs Bennet, a Miss Bennet,
a Miss Bennet and a Miss Bennet, sir.
Are we to receive every
Bennet in the country?
What an excellent room you have, sir.
Such expensive furnishings.
I do hope
you intend to stay here, Mr Bingley.
Absolutely, I find the country
very diverting. Don't you agree, Darcy?
I find it perfectly adequate.
Even if society
is a little less varied than in town.
Less varied? Not at all.
We dine with four and 20 families
of all shapes and sizes.
Sir William Lucas, for instance,
is a very agreeable man.
And a good deal less self-important
than some people half his rank.
Mr Bingley,
is it true you will hold a ball here?
A ball?
It would be an excellent way to meet new
friends. You could invite the militia.
- Oh, do hold a ball!
- Kitty!
When your sister recovers,
you shall name the day.
I think a ball is an irrational way
to gain new acquaintance.
It would be better if conversation,
not dancing, were the order of the day.
Indeed, much more rational,
but rather less like a ball.
Thank you, Mary.
What a fine imposing place to be sure,
is it not, my dears?
There's no house
to equal it in the county.
- Mr Darcy.
- Miss Bennet.
- There she is.
- I don't know how to thank you.
You're welcome any time
you feel the least bit poorly.
Thank you for your stimulating company.
Most instructive.
Not at all. The pleasure is all mine.
- Mr Darcy.
- Miss Elizabeth.
And then there was one
with great long lashes, like a cow.
Ask Mrs Hill
to order us a sirloin, Betsy.
Just the one, mind.
We're not made of money.
I hope, my dear,
you've ordered a good dinner today.
I've reason to expect
an addition to our family party.
His name's Mr Collins,
the dreaded cousin.
- Who is to inherit?
- Everything.
Even my piano stool
belongs to Mr Collins.
When?
He may turn us out of the house
as soon as he pleases.
The estate passes directly to him
and not to us poor females.
Mr Collins, at your service.
What a superbly featured room
and what excellent potatoes.
It's many years since
I've had such an exemplary vegetable.
To which fair cousin should I compliment
the excellence of the cooking?
We are perfectly able to keep a cook.
Excellent.
I'm very pleased
the estate can afford such a living.
I'm honoured to have as my patroness
Lady Catherine de Bourgh.
You've heard of her, I presume?
My small rectory abuts her estate,
Rosings Park,
and she often condescends
to drive by my humble dwelling
in her little phaeton and ponies.
Does she have any family?
One daughter, the heiress of Rosings
and very extensive property.
I've often observed to Lady Catherine
that her daughter
seemed born to be a duchess,
for she has all the superior graces
of elevated rank.
These kind of compliments
are always acceptable to the ladies,
and which I conceive myself
particularly bound to pay.
How happy for you, Mr Collins,
to possess the talent for flattering
with such delicacy.
Do these attentions proceed
from the impulse of the moment
or are they
the result of previous study?
They arise
from what is passing at the time.
And though I do sometimes amuse myself
with arranging such little compliments,
I always wish to give them
as unstudied an air as possible.
Oh, believe me, no one would suspect
your manners to be rehearsed.
After dinner, I thought
I might read to you for an hour or two.
I have with me Fordyce's Sermons
which speak very eloquently
on all matters moral.
Are you familiar with Fordyce's Sermons,
Miss Bennet?
Mrs Bennet, I have been bestowed by the
good grace of Lady Catherine de Bourgh
a parsonage of no mean size.
I have become aware of the fact.
It is my avowed hope
that soon I may find a mistress for it.
And I have to inform you
that the eldest Miss Bennet
has captured my special attention.
Oh, Mr Collins.
Unfortunately, it is incumbent upon me
to hint that the eldest Miss Bennet
is very soon to be engaged.
Engaged.
But Miss Lizzie,
next to her in age and beauty,
would make anyone an excellent partner.
Do not you agree? Mr Collins?
Indeed. Indeed.
A very agreeable alternative.
Mr Collins is a man who
makes you despair at the entire sex.
- Yours, I believe.
- Oh, Mr Wickham, how perfect you are.
He picked up my handkerchief.
Did you drop yours on purpose?
Mr Wickham is a lieutenant.
- An enchanted lieutenant.
- What are you up to, Liddy?
- We happened to be looking for ribbon.
- White, for the ball.
Shall we all look
for some ribbon together?
- Good afternoon, Mr James.
- Miss Lydia, Miss Bennet.
I shan't even browse.
I can't be trusted.
I have poor taste in ribbons.
Only a truly confident man
would admit that.
No, it's true.
And buckles.
When it comes to buckles, I'm lost.
- You must be the shame of the regiment.
- The laughing stock.
What do your superiors do with you?
Ignore me. I'm of next to no importance,
so it's easily done.
- Lizzie, lend me some money.
- You already owe me a fortune.
- Allow me to oblige.
- No, Mr Wickham, please...
I insist.
- I pity the French.
- So do I.
- Look, Mr Bingley.
- Mr Bingley!
I was just on my way to your house.
How do you like
my ribbons for your ball?
- Very beautiful.
- She is. Look, she's blooming.
Oh, Lydia.
Be sure to invite Mr Wickham.
He is a credit to his profession.
You can't invite people
to other people's balls.
Of course, you must come, Mr Wickham.
If you'll excuse me,
ladies, enjoy the day.
Do you plan to go
to the Netherfield ball, Mr Wickham?
Perhaps. How long
has Mr Darcy been a guest there?
About a month.
Forgive me, but are you
acquainted with him, with Mr Darcy?
Indeed, I've been connected
with his family since infancy.
You may well be surprised,
given our cold greeting this afternoon.
I hope your plans in favour
of Meryton will not be affected
- by your relations with the gentleman.
- It is not for me to be driven away.
If he wishes to avoid seeing me,
he must go, not I.
I must ask, what is the manner
of your disapproval of Mr Darcy?
My father managed his estate.
We grew up together, Darcy and I.
His father treated me like a second son,
loved me like a son.
We were both with him the day he died.
With his last breath,
his father bequeathed me
the rectory in his estate.
He knew I had my heart set
on joining the Church.
But Darcy ignored his wishes
and gave the living to another man.
- But why?
- Jealousy.
His father...
Well, he loved me better
and Darcy couldn't stand it.
- How cruel.
- So now I'm a poor foot-soldier.
Too lowly even to be noticed.
- Breathe in!
- I can't anymore. You're hurting.
Betsy.
Betsy!
- There must've been a misunderstanding.
- Jane, you never think ill of anybody.
How could Mr Darcy do such a thing?
I will discover the truth
from Mr Bingley this evening.
Let Mr Darcy contradict it himself.
Till he does,
I hope never to encounter him.
Poor, unfortunate, Mr Wickham.
Wickham is twice the man Darcy is.
And, let us hope,
a rather more willing dancer.
There they are, look.
- Oh, yes.
- Billy.
Jane Martin is here.
May I say what an immense pleasure
it is to see you again.
- Mrs Bennet.
- Miss Bingley.
Charming.
I'm so pleased you're here.
So am I.
And how are you? Miss Elizabeth?
Are you looking for someone?
No, not at all, I was just admiring
the general splendour.
- It is breathtaking, Mr Bingley.
- Good.
You might have passed
a few pleasantries with Mr Bingley.
I've never met a
more pleasant gentleman in all my years.
Did you see how he dotes on her?
Dear Jane,
always doing what's best for her family.
- Charlotte!
- Lizzie!
- Have you seen Mr Wickham?
- No. Perhaps he's through here.
Lizzie, Mr Wickham is not here.
Apparently, he's been detained.
Detained where? He must be here.
- There you are.
- Mr Collins.
Perhaps you will do me the honour,
Miss Elizabeth.
Oh, I did not think you danced,
Mr Collins.
I do not think it incompatible
with the office of a clergyman.
Several people, her Ladyship
included, have complimented me
on my lightness of foot.
Apparently, your Mr Wickham has
been called on some business to town.
Dancing is of little consequence
to me, but it does...
...but it does afford
the opportunity to lavish...
...upon one's partner attentions...
- My informer tells me...
...that he would be less inclined
to be engaged, were it not for...
...the presence
of a certain gentleman.
Which is my primary object.
That gentleman barely warrants the name.
It is my intention, if I may be so bold,
to remain close to you
throughout the evening.
May I have the next dance,
Miss Elizabeth?
You may.
- Did I agree to dance with Mr Darcy?
- I dare say you will find him amiable.
It would be most inconvenient since I've
sworn to loathe him for all eternity.
- I love this dance.
- Indeed. Most invigorating.
It is your turn to say something,
Mr Darcy.
I talked about the dance.
Now you ought to remark on the size
of the room or the number of couples.
I'm perfectly happy to oblige.
What would you like most to hear?
That reply will do for present.
Perhaps by and by I may observe
that private balls
are much pleasanter than public ones.
For now, we may remain silent.
Do you talk as a rule while dancing?
No. No, I prefer to be
unsociable and taciturn.
Makes it all so much more enjoyable,
don't you think?
Tell me, do you and your sisters
very often walk to Meryton?
Yes, we often walk to Meryton.
It's a great opportunity
to meet new people.
When you met us, we'd just had the
pleasure of forming a new acquaintance.
Mr Wickham's blessed with such happy
manners, he's sure of making friends.
Whether he's capable
of retaining them is less so.
He's been so unfortunate as to lose
your friendship. That is irreversible?
- It is. Why do you ask such a question?
- To make out your character.
- What have you discovered?
- Very little.
I hear such different accounts
of you as puzzle me exceedingly.
I hope to afford you more clarity
in the future.
- Is that Mr Darcy of Pemberley?
- I believe so.
I must make myself known to him.
He's a nephew of my patroness,
Lady Catherine.
He will consider it an impertinence.
Mr Darcy.
Mr Darcy. Good evening...
What interesting relatives you have.
Mary, dear,
you've delighted us long enough.
Let the other young ladies have a turn.
... since I was a child,
and then she died.
I have a beautiful grey.
Of course, Caroline's
a much better rider than I, of course.
Oh, yes. We fully expect
a most advantageous marriage.
And my Jane, marrying so grand,
must throw her sisters in the way.
Clearly my family are seeing who can
expose themselves to the most ridicule.
- At least Bingley has not noticed.
- No.
- I think he likes her very much.
- But does she like him?
Few of us are secure enough to be
in love without proper encouragement.
Bingley likes her enormously,
but might not do more
if she does not help him on.
She's just shy. If he cannot
perceive her regard, he is a fool.
We are all fools in love.
He does not know
her character as we do.
She should move fast
and snap him up.
There is plenty of time
for us to get to know him afterwards.
I can't help feeling
that someone's going to produce a piglet
and make us chase it.
- Oh, dear!
- I do apologise, sir.
I'm awfully sorry. Do forgive me.
Emily, please!
Mary, my dear Mary.
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
- I've been practising all week.
- I know, my dear.
I hate balls.
Mr Bennet, wake up.
Oh, I've never had such a good time!
Charles, you cannot be serious.
We'll have a wedding here in less than
three months if you ask me, Mr Bennet.
Mr Bennet!
Mary, please.
Thank you, Mr Hill.
Mrs Bennet, I was hoping,
if it would not trouble you,
that I might solicit
a private audience with Miss Elizabeth.
Oh, certainly,
Lizzie would be very happy indeed.
Everyone, out. Mr Collins would like
a private audience with your sister.
Wait, Mr Collins can have nothing
to say to me that anybody need not hear.
I desire you will stay where you are.
Everyone else to the drawing room.
- Mr Bennet.
- But...
Now.
- Jane. Jane, don't... Jane!
- Jane.
Papa, stay.
Dear Miss Elizabeth,
My attentions have been
too marked to be mistaken.
Almost as soon
as I entered the house,
I singled you out
as the companion of my future life.
But before I am run away
with my feelings,
perhaps I may state
my reasons for marrying.
Firstly, that it is
the duty of a clergyman
to set the example
of matrimony in his parish.
Secondly, I am convinced
it will add greatly to my happiness.
And thirdly,
that it is at the urging
of my esteemed patroness,
Lady Catherine,
that I select a wife.
My object in coming to Longbourn
was to choose such a one
from among Mr Bennet's daughters,
for I am to inherit the estate
and such an alliance will surely...
...suit everyone.
And now nothing remains but for me to
assure you in the most animated language
- of the violence of my affections.
- Mr Collins!
And no reproach
on the subject of fortune
- will cross my lips once we're married.
- You forget I have given no answer.
Lady Catherine will
thoroughly approve when I speak to her
of your modesty, economy
and other amiable qualities.
Sir, I am honoured by your proposal,
but I regret that I must decline it.
I know ladies
don't seek to seem too eager...
Mr Collins, I am perfectly serious.
You could not make me happy.
And I'm the last woman
in the world who could make you happy.
I flatter myself that your refusal
is merely a natural delicacy.
Besides, despite manifold attractions,
it is by no means certain another offer
of marriage will ever be made to you.
I must conclude that you simply seek
to increase my love by suspense,
according to the usual practice
of elegant females.
I am not the sort of female
to torment a respectable man.
Please understand me,
I cannot accept you.
Headstrong, foolish child.
Don't worry, Mr Collins. We'll have this
little hiccup dealt with immediately.
Lizzie. Lizzie!
Mr Bennet, we're all in an uproar!
You must come
and make Lizzie marry Mr Collins.
Mr Collins has proposed to Lizzie,
but she vowed she will not have him,
and now the danger is
Mr Collins may not have Lizzie.
- What am I to do?
- Well, come and talk to her.
Now!
- Tell her you insist they marry.
- Papa, please.
You will have this house
and save your sisters from destitution.
- I can't marry him.
- Go and say you've changed your mind.
- Think of your family.
- You cannot make me.
Mr Bennet, say something.
Your mother insists
upon you marrying Mr Collins.
Yes, or I shall never see her again.
From this day onward, you must be
a stranger to one of your parents.
Who will maintain you
when your father is dead?
Your mother will never see you again
if you do not marry Mr Collins,
and I will never see you again
if you do.
Thank you, Papa.
Ungrateful child!
I shall never speak to you again.
Not that I take
much pleasure in talking.
People who suffer as I do
from nervous complaints
can have no pleasure
in talking to anybody.
Jane!
What's the matter? Jane?
I don't understand
what would take him from Netherfield.
Why does he not know when he'll return?
Read it.
"Mr Darcy is impatient to see his sister
and we are scarcely less eager.
I do not think Georgiana Darcy
has her equal for beauty,
elegance and accomplishment.
I hope to call her hereafter my sister."
Is that not clear enough?
Caroline sees her brother
in love with you
and has taken him off
to persuade him otherwise.
But I know her to be incapable
of wilfully deceiving anyone.
- It's more likely he does not love me.
- He loves you. Do not give up.
Go to our aunt and uncle's in London,
let it be known you are there
and I am sure he will come to you.
Give my love to my sister
and try not to be a burden, dear.
Poor Jane.
Still, a girl likes to be
crossed in love now and then.
It gives her something to think of
and a sort of distinction
amongst her companions.
- I'm sure that will cheer her up, Papa.
- It's your turn now, Lizzie.
You've turned down Collins.
You're free to go off
and be jilted yourself.
What about Mr Wickham?
He's a pleasant fellow
and he'd do the job credibly.
- Father...
- And you have an affectionate mother
who would make the most of it.
- Charlotte!
- My dear Lizzie.
I've come her to tell you the news.
Mr Collins and I are... engaged.
- Engaged?
- Yes.
- To be married?
- What other kind of engaged is there?
For heaven's sake, Lizzie,
don't look at me like that.
I should be
as happy with him as any other.
- But he's ridiculous.
- Oh, hush.
Not all of us can afford to be romantic.
I've been offered
a comfortable home and protection.
There's a lot to be thankful for.
I'm 27 years old.
I've no money and no prospects.
I'm already a burden to my parents.
And I'm frightened.
So dont judge me, Lizzie.
Don't you dare judge me.
Dear Charlotte,
thank you for your letter.
I'm glad the house,
furniture and roads are to your taste,
and that Lady Catherine's behaviour
is friendly and obliging.
What with your departure,
Jane's to London
and the militia to the North
with the colourful Mr Wickham,
I must confess, the view
from where I sit has been rather grey.
As for the favour you ask,
it is no favour at all.
I would be happy to visit you
at your earliest convenience.
Welcome to our humble abode.
My wife encourages me to spend time
in the garden for my health.
I think our guest is tired
after her journey.
I plan many improvements. I intend to
throw out a bough and plant a lime walk.
I flatter myself
that any young lady would be happy
to be the mistress of such a house.
We shan't be disturbed here.
This parlour is for
my own particular use.
Oh, Lizzie, it's such a pleasure
to run my own home.
- Charlotte, come here!
- What's happened?
Has the pig escaped again?
Oh, it's Lady Catherine.
Come and see, Lizzie.
Great news.
We received an invitation to Rosings
from Lady Catherine.
How wonderful!
Do not make yourself uneasy
about your apparel.
Just put on the best you've brought.
Lady Catherine's never been averse
to the truly humble.
One of the most extraordinary
sights in all of Europe.
The glazing alone
costs upwards of 20,000.
Come along. Come along.
A little later we'll play cards.
Your Ladyship.
Miss de Bourgh.
- So, you are Elizabeth Bennet?
- I am, your Ladyship.
This is my daughter.
- It's kind of you to ask us to dine.
- The rug alone cost upwards of 300.
Mr Darcy.
What are you doing here?
Mr Darcy,
I had no idea we had the honour.
- Miss Elizabeth, I'm a guest here.
- You know my nephew?
I had the pleasure
of meeting your nephew in Hertfordshire.
Colonel Fitzwilliam. How do you do?
Mr Collins, you can't sit
next to your wife. Move. Over there.
Harvey, I wonder,
could you get me the fish course...
I trust your family is in good health,
Miss Elizabeth?
They are, thank you.
My eldest sister is in London.
Perhaps you saw her there.
I haven't been fortunate enough...
Do you play the pianoforte,
Miss Bennet?
- A little, ma'am, and very poorly.
- Do you draw?
No, not at all.
Your sisters, do they draw?
Not one.
That's very strange.
I suppose you had no opportunity.
Your mother should've taken you to town
for the benefit of the masters.
My mother wouldn't have minded,
but my father hates town.
- Has your governess left you?
- We never had a governess.
No governess? Five daughters
brought up at home without a governess?
I never heard such a thing. Your mother
must've been a slave to your education.
Not at all, Lady Catherine.
Your younger sisters,
are they out in society?
- Yes, ma'am, all.
- All?
What, all five out at once?
That's very odd.
And you second. The younger ones
out before the elders are married?
Your youngest sisters
must be very young.
Yes, my youngest is not 16.
But it would be hard on younger sisters
not to have their amusement
because the elder is still unmarried.
It would hardly encourage
sisterly affection.
Upon my word, you give your opinion
very decidedly for so young a person.
Pray, what is your age?
With three younger sisters grown up,
you can hardly expect me to own to it.
Come, Miss Bennet, and play for us.
- No, I beg you.
- For music is my delight.
In fact,
there are few people in England
who have more true enjoyment of music.
Or better natural taste.
If I had ever learnt,
I should've been a great proficient.
So would Anne,
if her health would've allowed her.
I'm not afflicted with false
modesty, when I say I play poorly...
Come, Lizzie, her Ladyship demands it.
How does Georgiana get along, Darcy?
- She plays very well.
- I hope she practises.
No excellence can be acquired
without constant practice.
I've told Mrs Collins this.
Though you have no instrument,
you're welcome to come to Rosings
and play on the pianoforte
in the housekeeper's room.
You'll be in nobody's way
in that part of the house.
You mean to frighten me
by coming in all your state to hear me.
But I won't be alarmed,
even if your sister does play so well.
I know that I cannot alarm you
even should I wish it.
What was my friend like
in Hertfordshire?
You really care to know?
Prepare yourself
for something very dreadful.
The first time I saw him,
he danced with nobody,
though gentlemen were scarce
and there was more than
one lady without a partner.
- I knew nobody beyond my own party.
- Nobody can be introduced at a ball.
Fitzwilliam, I need you.
I do not have the talent
of conversing easily
with people I have never met before.
Perhaps you should take
your aunt's advice and practise.
Dear Jane...
Mr Darcy.
Please, do be seated.
Mr and Mrs Collins
have gone to the village.
This is a charming house.
I believe my aunt did a great deal
to it when Mr Collins first arrived.
I believe so.
She could not have bestowed
her kindness on a more grateful subject.
- Shall I call for some tea?
- No, thank you.
Good day, Miss Elizabeth,
it's been a pleasure.
What on earth have you done
to poor Mr Darcy?
I have no idea.
Every mind must have some counsellor
to whom it may apply
for consolation in distress.
There are many conveniences which
others can supply and we cannot procure.
I have in view those objects
which are only
to be obtained through intercourse...
Forgive me, through the intercourse
of friendship or civility.
On such occasions, the proud man steps
forth to meet you not with cordiality,
but with the suspicion of one
who reconnoitres an enemy...
- How long do you plan to stay?
- As long as Darcy chooses.
- I am at his disposal.
- Everyone appears to be.
I wonder he does not marry and secure
a lasting convenience of that kind.
- She would be a lucky woman.
- Really?
Darcy is a most loyal companion.
He recently came to the
rescue of one of his friends.
What happened?
He saved him
from an imprudent marriage.
Who's the man?
His closest friend, Charles Bingley.
Did Mr Darcy give a reason
for this interference?
There were apparently
strong objections to the lady.
What kind of objections?
Her lack of fortune?
I think it was her family
that was considered unsuitable.
- So he separated them?
- I believe so. I know nothing else.
Miss Elizabeth.
I have struggled in vain
and can bear it no longer.
These past months have been a torment.
I came to Rosings only to see you.
I have fought against
judgement, my family's expectation,
the inferiority of your birth,
my rank.
I will put them aside
and ask you to end my agony.
- I don't understand.
- I love you.
Most ardently.
Please do me the honour
of accepting my hand.
Sir, I appreciate the struggle
you have been through,
and I am very sorry
to have caused you pain.
It was unconsciously done.
- Is this your reply?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you laughing at me?
- No.
Are you rejecting me?
I'm sure the feelings which hindered
your regard will help you overcome it.
Might I ask why with so little civility
I am thus repulsed?
I might enquire why you told me you
liked me against your better judgement?
If I was uncivil,
then that is some excuse.
- But you know I have other reasons.
- What reasons?
Do you think anything might tempt me
to accept the man who has ruined
the happiness of a most beloved sister?
Do you deny that you separated
a young couple who loved each other,
exposing your friend
to censure for caprice
and my sister to derision
for disappointed hopes,
involving them both in acute misery?
- I do not deny it.
- How could you do it?
I believed your sister
indifferent to him.
I realised his attachment
was deeper than hers.
She's shy!
Bingley was persuaded
she didn't feel strongly.
- You suggested it.
- For his own good.
My sister hardly shows
her true feelings to me.
I suppose his fortune
had some bearing?
I wouldn't do your sister the dishonour.
- It was suggested...
- What was?
It was clear an advantageous marriage...
- Did my sister give that impression?
- No!
- No. There was, however, your family...
- Our want of connection?
- No, it was more than that.
- How, sir?
The lack of propriety shown by your
mother, younger sisters and your father.
Forgive me. You and your sister
I must exclude from this.
And what about Mr Wickham?
Mr Wickham?
What excuse can you
give for your behaviour?
- You take an eager interest.
- He told me of his misfortunes.
- Oh, they have been great.
- You ruin his chances
yet treat him with sarcasm.
So this is your opinion of me?
Thank you. Perhaps these offences
might have been overlooked
had not your pride been hurt
by my scruples about our relationship.
I am to rejoice in the inferiority
of your circumstances?
And those are the words of a gentleman.
Your arrogance and conceit, your selfish
disdain for the feelings of others
made me realise you were the last man
in the world I could ever marry.
Forgive me, madam,
for taking up so much of your time.
I came to leave you this.
I shall not renew the sentiments
which were so disgusting to you.
But if I may, I will address the
two offences you have laid against me.
My father loved Mr Wickham as a son.
He left him a generous living.
But upon my father's death,
Mr Wickham announced
he had no intention of taking orders.
He demanded the value of the living,
which he'd gambled away within weeks.
He then wrote,
demanding more money, which I refused.
After which,
he severed all acquaintance.
He came back to see us last summer, and
declared passionate love for my sister,
whom he tried to persuade
to elope with him.
She is to inherit 30,000.
When it was made clear he would never
receive a penny of it, he disappeared.
I will not attempt to convey the depth
of Georgiana's despair.
She was 15 years old.
As to the other matter,
of your sister and Mr Bingley,
though the motives which governed me
may appear insufficient,
they were in the service of a friend.
Lizzie.
Are you all right?
I hardly know.
Lizzie. How fortunate you have arrived.
Your aunt and uncle are here
to deliver Jane from London.
- How is Jane?
- She's in the drawing room.
I'm quite over him. If he passed me
in the street, I'd hardly notice.
London is so diverting. It's true.
There's so much to entertain.
What news from Kent?
Nothing.
At least not much to entertain.
Lizzie, tell Mama!
Stop making such a fuss.
- Why didn't she ask me as well?
- Because I'm better company.
- What's the matter?
- I've just as much right.
Let's all go.
Lydia's been invited to Brighton
with the Forsters.
Sea-bathing would set me up nicely.
I shall dine with the officers
every night.
Papa, don't let her go.
Lydia will never be easy until she's
exposed herself in some public place.
And we could never expect her
to do it with so little inconvenience.
If you do not check her,
she'll be fixed as the silliest flirt
who ever made her family ridiculous.
And Kitty will follow, as always.
Lizzie, we shall have no peace
until she goes.
Is that really all you care about?
Colonel Forster is a sensible man.
He will keep her
out of any real mischief.
And she's too poor
to be an object of prey to anyone.
It's dangerous.
I am certain the officers will find
women better worth their while.
Let us hope, in fact,
that her stay in Brighton
will teach her her own insignificance.
At any rate,
she can hardly grow any worse.
If she does, we'd be obliged to
lock her up for the rest of her life.
Lizzie, you're welcome to accompany us.
The Peak District is not Brighton.
Officers are thin on the ground
which may influence your decision.
Come to the Peak District with us,
Lizzie, and get some fresh air.
The glories of nature. What are men
compared to rocks and mountains?
Men are either eaten up
with arrogance or stupidity.
If they are amiable,
they have no minds of their own.
Take care, my love.
That savours strongly of bitterness.
I saw Mr Darcy when I was at Rosings.
Why did you not tell me?
Did he mention Mr Bingley?
No.
No, he did not.
Oh, what are men
compared to rocks and mountains?
Or carriages that work?
Where exactly are we?
Quite close to Pemberley.
- Mr Darcy's home?
- That's the fellow.
Very well-stocked lake.
I've a hankering to see it.
Oh, no, let's not.
Well, he's so...
I'd rather not, he's so... he's so...
- So what?
- So rich.
By heavens, Lizzie,
what a snob you are!
Objecting to Mr Darcy because of his
wealth. The poor man can't help it.
He won't be there anyway.
These great men are never at home.
Keep up.
- Is your master much at home?
- Not as much as I would wish.
He dearly loves it here.
If he should marry,
you might see more of him.
He's a lot like his father.
When my husband was ill,
Mr Darcy couldn't do enough.
He just organised the servants for me.
This is he, Mr Darcy.
A handsome face.
Lizzie, is it a true likeness?
Does the young lady
know Mr Darcy?
Only a little.
Do you not think him
a handsome man, miss?
Yes.
Yes, I dare say he is.
This is his sister, Miss Georgiana.
She sings and plays all day long.
Is she at home?
Miss Elizabeth.
- I thought you were in London.
- No.
No, I'm not.
No.
- We would not have come...
- I came back a day early...
I'm with my aunt and uncle.
And are you having a pleasant trip?
Very pleasant.
- Tomorrow we go to Matlock.
- Tomorrow?
- Are you staying at Lambton?
- Yes, at the Rose and Crown.
Yes.
I'm so sorry to intrude.
They said the house was open
for visitors. I had no idea.
- May I see you back to the village?
- No.
- I'm very fond of walking.
- Yes.
Yes, I know.
Goodbye, Mr Darcy.
This way, sir.
Are you sure you
wouldn't like to join us?
We've just met Mr Darcy.
You didn't tell us that you'd seen him.
He's asked us to dine with him tomorrow.
He was very civil, was he not?
- Very civil.
- Not at all how you'd painted him.
To dine with him?
There's something pleasant
about his mouth when he speaks.
You don't mind delaying
our journey another day?
He particularly wants you
to meet his sister.
His sister.
Miss Elizabeth!
My sister, Miss Georgiana.
My brother has told me
so much about you,
- I feel as if we are friends already.
- Thank you.
- What a beautiful pianoforte.
- My brother gave it to me.
- He shouldn't have.
- I should have.
- Very well then.
- Easily persuaded, is she not?
He once had to put up with my playing.
- He says you play so well.
- Then he has perjured himself.
- I said "quite well".
- "Quite well" is not "very well".
I'm satisfied.
- Mr Gardiner, are you fond of fishing?
- Very much.
Would you accompany me
to the lake this afternoon?
Its occupants have been left
in peace too long.
- I would be delighted.
- Do you play duets, Miss Elizabeth?
- Only when forced.
- Brother, you must force her.
Splendid fishing, good
company. What a capital fellow.
Thank you so much, Mr Darcy.
A letter for you, madam.
Oh, it's from Jane.
It is the most dreadful news.
Lydia has run away...
...with Mr Wickham.
They are gone to Lord knows where.
She has no money, no connections.
I fear she is lost forever.
This is my fault.
If only I had exposed Wickham
when I should.
No, this is my fault.
I might have prevented all this
by being open with my sisters.
Has anything been done to recover her?
My father has gone to London,
but I know nothing can be done.
We have not the smallest hope.
Would I could help you.
Sir, I think it is too late.
This is grave indeed.
I will leave you. Goodbye.
We must go at once.
I will join Mr Bennet and find Lydia
before she ruins the family.
Why did the Forsters
let her out of their sight?
I always said they were unfit
to take charge of her.
- And now she is ruined.
- You are all ruined.
Who will take you now
with a fallen sister?
Poor Mr Bennet will now have
to fight the perfidious Wickham
and then be killed.
He hasn't found him yet, Mama.
Mr Collins will turn us out
before he is cold.
Do not be so alarmed. Our uncle
is in London helping in the search.
Lydia must know
what this must be doing to my nerves.
Such flutterings
and spasms all over me!
My baby Lydia, my baby!
How could she do such a thing
to her poor mama?
- You can't do that!
- Don't be such a baby.
- Kitty, give it to me.
- Who's it for?
It's addressed to Papa.
It's in Uncle's writing.
Papa, there's a letter.
- Let me catch my breath.
- It's in Uncle's writing.
- He's found them.
- Are they married?
- I can't make out his script.
- Give it to me.
Are they married?
They will be if Father settles 100
a year on her. That is his condition.
- You will agree to this, Father?
- Of course.
God knows how much your uncle
must've laid on that wretched man.
What do you mean?
No man would marry Lydia
under so slight
a temptation as 100 a year.
Your uncle must've been very generous.
Do you think it a large sum?
Wickham's a fool if he
accepts less than 10,000.
- Heaven forbid!
- Father!
Lydia married and at 15 too!
Ring the bell, Kitty.
I must put on my things and tell
Lady Lucas. Oh, to see her face.
Tell the servants
they will have a bowl of punch.
- We should thank our uncle.
- So he should help.
He's far richer than us
and has no children. Daughter married!
Is that really all you think about?
When you have five daughters, tell me
what else will occupy your thoughts.
Then perhaps you'll understand.
You don't know what he's like.
- Lydia!
- Oh, Mama!
We passed Sarah Sims in her carriage.
So I took off my glove
so she might see the ring.
Then I bowed and smiled
like anything...
I'm sure she was not
half as radiant as you, my dear.
You must all go to Brighton.
That is the place to get husbands.
I hope you have half my good luck.
Lydia.
I want to hear
every little detail, Lydia, dear.
I've been enlisted
in a regiment in the North of England.
Glad to hear it.
Near Newcastle.
We travel there next week.
- Can I come and stay with you?
- That is out of the question.
Monday morning came
and I was in such a fuss.
I don't want to hear.
There was my aunt preaching away
as if reading a sermon.
- She was horrid unpleasant.
- Can't you understand why?
But I didn't hear a word because
I was thinking of my dear Wickham.
I longed to know if
he'd be married in his bluecoat.
The North of England, I believe,
boasts some spectacular scenery.
So I thought, who is to be
our best man if he doesn't come back?
Lucky, he did,
or I would've had to ask Mr Darcy.
- Mr Darcy!
- I forgot!
- But I shouldn't have said a word.
- Mr Darcy was at your wedding?
He was the one that discovered us.
He paid for the wedding,
Wickham's commission, everything.
But he told me not to tell.
- Mr Darcy?
- Stop it, Lizzie.
Mr Darcy's not half as high and mighty
as you sometimes.
Kitty, have you seen my ring?
Write to me often, my dear.
Married women
never have much time for writing.
I dare say you won't.
When I married your father, there didn't
seem to be enough hours in the day.
My sisters may write to me,
for they'll have nothing else to do.
There's nothing so bad
as parting with one's children.
One seems so forlorn without them.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Lydia. Goodbye, Mr Wickham.
Bye, Kitty. Bye, Papa.
I can't imagine what your
father does with all that ink.
Mrs Bennet.
Did you hear the news, madam?
Mr Bingley is returning to Netherfield.
Mrs Nichols is ordering a haunch
of pork. She expects him tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Not that I care.
Mr Bingley's nothing to us.
I'm sure I never want
to see him again, no.
We shan't mention a word about it.
Is it quite certain he's coming?
Yes, madam. I believe he's alone.
His sister remains in town.
Why he thinks we should be interested,
I've no idea. Come along, girls.
We better go home at once
and tell Mr Bennet.
The impudence of the man.
I wonder he dare show his face.
It's all right, Lizzie.
I'm just glad he's alone
because we shall see less of him.
Not that I'm afraid of myself.
But I dread other people's remarks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
He's here. He's here. He's at the door.
- Mr Bingley!
- Mr Bingley?
Oh, my goodness!
Everybody behave naturally.
And whatever you do,
do not appear overbearing.
There's someone with him.
Mr Whatsisname, the pompous one.
Mr Darcy? The insolence of
it. What does he think of, coming here?
Keep still, Jane. Mary, put that away at
once. Find some useful employment.
Oh, my Lord, I shall have a seizure,
I'm sure I shall.
Kitty.
- We can't have this here.
- Mary, the ribbons, the ribbons.
Mary, sit down at once. Mary!
Mr Darcy and Mr Bingley, ma'am.
How glad we are
to see you, Mr Bingley.
There have been
many changes since you went away.
Miss Lucas is married and settled.
And one of my own daughters too.
You will have seen it in the papers,
though it was not put in
as it ought to have been.
Very short. Nothing about her family.
Yes, I did hear of it.
I offer my congratulations.
But it is very hard
to have my Lydia taken away from me.
Mr Wickham has been transferred
to Newcastle, wherever that is.
Will you stay long in the country?
Just a few weeks. For the shooting.
When you've killed all your own birds,
I beg you will come here
and shoot as many as you please.
Mr Bennet will be vastly happy to oblige
and will save the best coveys for you.
Excellent.
- Are you well, Mr Darcy?
- Quite well, thank you.
I hope the weather stays fine
for your sport.
- I return to town tomorrow.
- So soon?
My Jane looks well, does she not?
She does indeed.
Well, we must be going, I think.
Darcy. It's been very pleasant
to see you all again.
Miss Elizabeth. Miss Bennet.
You must come again.
Last winter, you promised to have
a family dinner with us.
I've not forgot, you see.
At least three courses.
Excuse me.
Most extraordinary.
We were going to walk in
and she was going to say, "Sit down."
So, I feel...
Oh, it's a disaster, isn't it?
It's been...
- Miss Bennet.
- Mr Bingley.
I'll just go in and I'll just say it.
Yes, exactly.
I'm glad that's over. Now we can
meet as indifferent acquaintances.
Oh, yes.
You cannot think me so weak
as to be in danger now.
You are in great danger of making
him as much in love with you as ever.
- I'm sorry he came with Mr Darcy.
- Don't say that.
Why ever not?
Jane.
- I've been so blind.
- What do you mean?
Look, it's him.
He's back. He's come again.
I know this is all very untoward,
but I would like to request the
privilege of speaking to Miss Bennet.
Alone.
Everybody to the kitchen immediately.
Except you, Jane, dear, of course.
Oh, Mr Bingley, it's so good
to see you again so soon.
First, I must tell you I've been the
most unmitigated and comprehensive ass.
Kitty, be quiet.
Yes.
A thousand times yes.
Thank the Lord for that.
I thought it would never happen.
I am confident
they will do well together.
Their tempers are much alike.
They will be cheated assiduously
by their servants.
And be so generous with the rest,
they will always exceed their income.
Exceed their income?
He has 5,000 a year.
I knew she did not be
so beautiful for nothing.
"...must be free from all insincerity.
She only can address herself effectually
to the feelings of others
whose mind glows
with the warmth of sensibility
and whose arguments result
from conviction.
She must feel the influence
of those passions and emotions
which she wishes to inspire..."
Can you die of happiness?
He was ignorant
of my being in town in the spring.
- How did he account for it?
- He thought me indifferent.
- Unfathomable.
- No doubt poisoned by his sister.
Bravo. That's the most
unforgiving speech you've ever made.
Oh, Lizzie, if I could
but see you so happy.
If there was such a man for you.
Perhaps Mr Collins has a cousin.
- What is that?
- What?
Maybe he's changed his mind.
Coming!
Yes.
Lady Catherine.
The rest of your offspring, I presume?
All but one. The youngest
has been lately married, your Ladyship.
My eldest was proposed to
only this afternoon.
- You have a very small garden.
- Could I offer you a cup of tea?
Absolutely not. I need to speak
to Miss Elizabeth Bennet alone.
As a matter of urgency.
You can be at no loss
to understand why I am here.
I cannot account for this honour at all.
I warn you, I am not to be trifled with.
A most alarming report
has reached me.
That you intend to be united
with my nephew, Mr Darcy.
I know this to be a falsehood.
Though not wishing to injure him
by supposing it possible, I instantly
set off to make my sentiments known.
If you believed it impossible,
I wonder that you came so far.
To hear it contradicted.
Your coming will be a confirmation
if such a report exists.
lf? You pretend to be ignorant of it?
Has it not been
industriously circulated by yourself?
I have never heard of it.
Can you declare
there is no foundation for it?
I do not pretend to possess
equal frankness with your Ladyship.
You may ask a question
which I may choose not to answer.
Has my nephew
made you an offer of marriage?
Your Ladyship has declared it
to be impossible.
Mr Darcy is engaged to my daughter.
Now what have you to say?
If that is the case, you cannot suppose
he would make an offer to me.
Selfish girl. This union
has been planned since their infancy.
Do you think it can be prevented
by a woman of inferior birth
whose own sister's elopement resulted
in a scandalously patched-up marriage
only achieved
at the expense of your uncle.
Heaven and Earth! Are the shades
of Pemberley to be thus polluted?
Tell me once and for all,
are you engaged to him?
I am not.
Will you promise never
to enter into such an engagement?
I will not and I certainly never shall.
You have insulted me
in every possible way
and can now have
nothing further to say.
I must ask you to leave immediately.
Goodnight.
I have never been thus treated
in my entire life!
- What is going on?
- Just a small misunderstanding.
For once in your life,
leave me alone!
- I couldn't sleep.
- Nor I. My aunt...
Yes, she was here.
How can I ever make amends
for such behaviour?
After what you've done for Lydia
and, I suspect, for Jane,
it is I who should be making amends.
You must know.
Surely you must know it was all for you.
You are too generous to trifle with me.
You spoke with my aunt last night
and it has taught me to hope
as I'd scarcely allowed myself before.
If your feelings are still what they
were last April, tell me so at once.
My affections and wishes
have not changed.
But one word from you
will silence me for ever.
lf, however,
your feelings have changed...
...I would have to tell you,
you have bewitched me,
body and soul, and I love...
I love... I love you.
I never wish to be parted
from you from this day on.
Well, then.
Your hands are cold.
Shut the door, please.
Lizzie, are you out of your senses?
I thought you hated the man.
- No, Papa.
- He is rich, to be sure.
And you will have
more fine carriages than Jane.
But will that make you happy?
Have you no other objection
than your belief in my indifference?
None at all.
We all know him to be
a proud, unpleasant sort of fellow.
But this would be nothing
if you liked him.
I do like him.
I love him.
He's not proud. I was wrong.
I was entirely wrong about him.
You don't know him, Papa.
If I told you what he was really like,
what he's done...
What has he done?
But she doesn't like him.
I thought she didn't like him.
So did I. So did we all.
We must have been wrong.
- It won't be the first time, will it?
- No, nor the last, I dare say.
Good Lord.
- I must pay him back.
- No.
You mustn't tell anyone.
He wouldn't want it.
We misjudged him, Papa.
Me more than anyone. In every way.
Not just in this matter.
I've been nonsensical.
But he's been a fool about Jane,
about so many other things.
But then, so have I.
You see, he and I are...
He and I are so similar.
We're both so stubborn.
Papa, I...
You really do love him, don't you?
Very much.
I cannot believe
that anyone can deserve you.
But it seems I am overruled.
So I heartily give my consent.
I could not have parted with you,
my Lizzie, to anyone less worthy.
Thank you.
If any young men come for Mary or Kitty,
for heaven's sake, send them in.
I'm quite at my leisure.