I'm the police.
And I'm here to arrest you.
You've broken the law.
I did not write the law.
I may even disagree with the law.
But I will enforce it.
No matter how you plead, cajole,
beg or attempt to stir my sympathies,
nothing you do will stop me from placing
you in a steel cage with grey bars.
If you run away, I will chase you.
If you fight me, I will fight back.
If you shoot at me, I will shoot back.
By the law,
I am unable to walk away.
I'm a consequence.
I am the unpaid bill.
I am fate with a badge and a gun.
Behind my badge is a heart like yours.
I bleed.
I think.
I love.
And yes, I can be killed.
And although I'm but one man...
... I have thousands of brothers and sisters
who are the same as me.
They will lay down their lives for me.
And I them.
We stand watch together.
A thin blue line.
Protecting the prey
from the predators.
The good from the bad.
We are the police.
Thirteen X-ray nine is in pursuit of a
Code vehicle west on two seven.
Go ahead, motherfucker.
Try to run, you son of a bitch.
Hold on, hold on!
Eastbound through the alley at
twenty hundred block from Hooper.
Now eastbound through the alley
at twenty hundred block from Hooper.
Oh shit!
Come around, come around!
Move!
Get the fuck around!
Pull to the right!
He's not going to pull to the right.
You stupid motherfucker!
He almost lost it!
Pit him!
Got him!
Fuck you!
You good?
Good.
This fucker's down.
I'm going to hook him.
You're all good.
Thirteen x-ray nine,
you can show a Code Four.
Thirteen x nine is requesting additional
supervisors to the four thousand block at Naomi.
Walk it off.
You good?
I'm good.
Holy shit.
Yeah, motherfucker.
All right.
This is my day job.
Some of you... Sorry, bro, I'm recording.
Some of you might know me as Brian.
Or Taylor.
But here I am Police Officer Two Brian Taylor.
This is where the forces of good,
prepare to fight to forces of evil.
This is my partner, Officer Zavala.
I'm in my chones.
I know, come on.
- No no, I'm in my chones.
We work basic patrol here at Newton.
One of the toughest divisions in the LAPD.
Shootin' Newton, that's right.
Lucky Thirteen.
This is a department issue sidearm.
Glock nineteen.
Spyderco tactical knife.
This little thing can break windows.
Two Smith and Wesson handcuffs.
Can of OC spray.
Pepper spray.
Two extra mags.
What else?
That's my nametag.
You can see my partner's dirty locker.
Yours is like a woman.
Look at this.
What is this, Pottery Barn?
Are you going to shut the fuck up
and get ready for roll call?
Don't swear.
I have to edit that out, when you swear.
Oh fuck.
Oh shit.
Fuck.
You kids having fun?
Look, it's Officer Van Houser.
Officer Three.
Van Houser.
Considered unpromotable by the department.
And the angriest fucking cop in the world.
I'm going to tell Sarge
that you're taping in here.
What'd you say?
I'm going to tell Sarge
that you're taping in here.
It's not really called taping anymore.
- It uses flash cards, but it's not really a...
- Don't worry about it.
God damn it!
Like that?
Turn it on.
Am I recording you?
Yes, and I'm recording you.
That's so cool.
That thing there?
That's the lens right there.
Just like this right here.
Hey guys, quiet down.
All right, let's settle down.
Let's settle down.
Captain's here, he'd like to say a few words.
Let's quiet down.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Good afternoon.
- Put it down.
I'd like to welcome back Zavala and Taylor.
D.A.cleared these guys
in last month's shooting.
Turned out to be a good shooting.
I know firsthand what you guys went through.
It's a unpleasant experience
being under that much scrutiny.
But you need to remember something.
An on the job shooting
is still considered a homicide.
It's never an easy ride.
If you do the right thing,
I will always have your back.
Do the wrong thing and cross me,
I will personally throw you under the bus.
Am I clear?
Yes sir!
Taylor, am I clear?
- Yes sir.
Sergeant, am I clear?
Have a nice day.
Thank you, Captain.
Quiet down!
See this?
It's a ticket book.
Inside are things called tickets.
Son of a bitch.
You can do things like stop motorists,
and cut citations for speeding
or going through a light.
You all need to write.
Sarge, we cut citations every watch.
I'm not talking to you,
I'm talking to these two idiots.
My partner has a question.
I don't really know how to write.
But I do sign and draw pictures.
Seriously, you don't start writing,
Captain's going to shit on my head,
and in turn,
I'm gonna shit on yours.
And I promise you,
you guys are going to be separated.
Do it, Sarge.
Orozco and Davis, X Twenty-five.
Peterson and Washington, X Forty One.
Zavala and Taylor, you got X Thirteen.
Williams and Cho, X Eight.
Alameda and Green, X Twenty-one.
Van Houser and Sook, X Four.
Yeah, Sarge?
That's not our area.
That's not your area?
No, we work Nine.
I'm sorry.
Oh no, you're right.
You're on X Thirteen.
Sorry fellas, this isn't Monopoly.
You don't get to choose your real estate.
Now go.
Get out.
Zavala, try not to kill anybody
before the end of the watch.
Really, Sarge?
Sir, if we kill someone in X Thirteen,
can we go back to X Nine?
Today is a brand new day.
Get the shop, gas the shop, wash the shop.
Make sure day watch didn't leave
behind any surprises for us.
Look for guns, drugs, puke.
Pay attention, Boot.
Goodbye.
Hurry up- Yes sir.
How you doing, Van Houser?
I warned you about that shit.
Where you running with that piece, Boot?
What?
Why you so scared?
Go, go!
Jesus Christ!
- Go on, shit.
It's like it's day one.
Boot, slow down with that piece.
Slow down!
Orozco, have you been working out?
Yeah, with your mom.
Why are you shooting everything?
It's for his class.
I thought you were studying law.
Pre-law.
I need an art elective.
I'm taking filmmaking.
Well, get my good side.
You don't have a good side.
Listen, you know they can subpoena
that shit if something goes sideways, right?
Think twice.
Two words.
Erase button.
Two words: Just because you guys think
you're these big ghetto gunfighters now,
don't mean you can be dropping your calls.
That was at least two dozen words.
Well, I barely got a G.E.D.
so what do you expect, white boy?
Saddle up, ladies,
we're sick of holding up your end.
Admit it, you'd hit that shit.
Orozco.
Yeah.
With a cinderblock.
Check the roof, Boot.
Where's your shop?
I got Red Bull, Monster, and-
They all say thirteen, check the roof.
Thank you, ma'am.
Faster, Boot, let's go - Get in the car!
- Yes sir!
And then I got you some kombucha
because I know you like that stuff.
Fuck that shit!
What is that?
It's good to be back, man.
Old lady was driving me crazy at the casa,
like making me do shit.
Oh no!
She dared ask for your help around the house.
That's incredible.
Outrageous.
Just because I look like
the dudes from Home Depot,
doesn't mean I do the shit
the dudes from Home Depot do.
I would never profile you as a man
who helps his wife with chores.
Shut up.
Dude, I'm your homie.
I would never do that.
Her brother was always coming
over during the day to swim.
Every day.
I hate everything about him.
He smells like weed sometimes.
Like he's got a prescription.
The guy was like: "No, it's all good"
and I was like whatever, get him the hell out of here.
I swear to God I'm filling
in that pool with cement.
Not personally, cause you'll hire
a Home Depot dude for that task.
Fuck you.
Thirteen X thirteen.
Four fifteen man at nine seven four two Maple.
Code Two.
Incident four five six two.
Thirteen X thirteen.
Roger, show us enroute.
X thirteen roger.
First customer of the day.
I hope they enjoy our police service.
Suck my dick!
That motherfucker's a lying ass nigger.
Fuck him and fuck you too!
Shut your fucking  if you touch me, I will kill you.
Stay where you are.
I don't give a fuck about both you motherfuckers.
I'm ready to die today.
Fuck y'all.
This can go several ways right now.
It is all about your attitude.
Fuck you!
I got my mail!
I helped him!
I helped him give me my mail!
I'm getting tired of this shit!
All right.
- I'm not playing with you all.
Sir, if you've been drinking, you need to stay the
fuck inside and not intimidate the mailman.
That's it.
Fuck you!
You need to shut the fuck up!
- Because without that badge and gun, you ain't shit.
- Yeah?
You're less than motherfucking nothing.
You motherfucking border hopping, donkey riding, Mexican motherfucker.
- Oh yeah?
Is that so?
You want to find out what I'm about?
Show me!
Yeah, I wanna see!
Fuck.
Let's settle this right here like grown men, motherfucker!
Not again, man.
What'd you say?
You wanna take a fade?
You want to fight me?
Yeah, I want to fight you.
Let's go, bro.
I whip your punk ass you going to get the fuck out of my crib?
Hell no.
But you called me out.
Now I'm calling you out.
What's up?
You whip my ass I'll put those motherfucking handcuffs on my motherfucking self.
And that's on the set.
Door.
It's going to be a pleasure beating your bitch ass.
My fucking fantasy.
I don't know who the fuck you think
you're fucking with, but I love this shit.
To beat a motherfucking punk-ass police ass like yours.
Keep talking.
- Let's get this shit popping, motherfucker.
Oh shit.
This shit's crazy!
Fucking kick his ass!
Come on!
Now get the fuck up.
You like that?
This ain't no wrassling match.
You all right?
Come on!
Oh shit!
That's what happens when you fuck with the police.
Yeah, come on.
Take him!
Fuck you, border hopping motherfucker!
You all right?
Gimme the hooks.
What's up, putos?
It's big bad Wicked from Curbside Gang Locotes.
You ready for this shit?
Fuck yeah.
I was born to fucking do this shit.
Show these motherfuckers whose barrio this is.
You almost ran the light, stupid.
You're going to get us pulled over, La.
Fuck that shit.
I gotta fucking be at work.
You better not bust out wasting my motherfucking time, I'm gonna tell you that shit right now.
La La, when are you going to fuck the homeboy?
I am not fucking the homeboy, dog.
Shit, what do I look like?
The little fucking paisa hoochies you guys fucking kick it with?
What you packing?
I'm packing a motherfucking thirty round clip for these swamp ass niggers.
This is it right here.
Slow down, this is the street.
This is it.
All right.
Wicked, you're going to jump
and get the party started, got it?
- I got it.
Listen to the homie.
All right, put your fucking face on, let's go!
Get your shit ready.
Put that fucking shit away!
Your fucking shit is good to go.
What the fuck do I have to fucking tell you?
I don't want to fucking have to baby you!
OK, ready homies.
Get ready.
Get your fucking face on!
- All right.
Fuck.
You guys ready?
- Ready.
All right.
But on some real shit, though,  I wanted to holler at you.
All my niggers keep on talking about how you got your ass
whipped by a motherfucking little punk-ass wonton.
No, these niggers is hating.
Let me tell you something.
Me and the cop got  down, right?
Motherfucker took off his badge, dropped his  gun.
I mean, he kept it gangster.
We straight up squabbled.
Head up.
But they still took you to the County though?
Yeah, but for disorderly conduct.
Not for squabbling with the police, you feel me?
You fought a cop and they didn't put no assaulting a peace officer on you?
Listen to me, my nigga.
I'm trying to tell you all.
They really showed me love to keep it G.
I'm a two time felon, right?
Y'all know that, right?
Could have struck me out and gave me life
for fighting that cop, you feel me?
I got right out, it wasn't shit.
All right, but we heard you got your ass beat.
You better shut the fuck up, CK.
I'll run this fucking fork up in your ass, I swear to god.
Let me tell you something...
win, lose or draw...
...as long as you squabble and get down,
that's gangster, you understand what I'm saying?
Yup.
I mean, that Mexican cop might be acting bull with you, Tre...
But he's still out there out there killing niggers.
Straight out.
No no no.
Listen to me, all y'all.
This whole fucking thing is like changing of the guard.
Back in the day, all these neighborhoods
used to be black, and what are they now?
Mexicans.
Exactly.
There used to be chicken stands on the corner,
and now there's fucking taco stands on every corner.
We're in some real shit and if we don't come together,
we're going to be some extinct niggers pretty soon.
Watch it, watch it, watch it!
Go go go!
Fuck!
Fuck yeah!
We got those putos!
We got them!
Eat shit, motherfuckers!
Fuck!
Show those putos whose neighborhood this fucker is!
Shit.
Fucking proud of you.
And that's what I'm fucking telling you.
Good.
That was fucking good.
That's what I'm fucking telling you.
I'm proud of you.
Fucking did it.
That's what I'm fucking talking about when I'm fucking proud of you.
Fucking proud of you man now you're a fucking man.
Right?
Right, homie.
- Right?
Right.
- All right then.
No fucking fear.
That's how we fucking do it.
Call the motherfucking ambulance!
They got CK!
Somebody call a fucking ambulance!
Bitch ass sewer rats was from Curbside.
I seen them.
Fucking Ese's are serving us.
Curbside's serving us.
Curbside's banging all over us on Bloods.
You got that chopper?
Let's go hit these little punk ass fools.
Cut that fucking camera off!
So this is what we believe to be the Code thirty-seven vehicle used in the drive-by last night.
Curbside Gang's at it again.
It fits the description.
It comes back as stolen.
Curbside likes these vehicles because they blend in,
you can put a lot of people in them.
This door slides back, and the gang members open fire.
The victim was a male black from a Blood set that has basically
been at war with this Hispanic gang over control of narcotic sales.
Partner.
Yeah.
What's up?
- Check this out.
Oh shit.
Those are shell casings.
Detectives told us that three different weapons were used
and we're seeing at least two kinds of shells, so... Shit.
What's up?
Those are the Homicide Detectives working the case.
The hell's this?
What?
Candid Camera?
No sir, it's just a project I'm working on.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I don't want to see that.
There are forty-five and nine millimeter shell casings inside.
How do you know that?
Did you touch them?
No sir.
Did you fuck up my vehicle?
- Sir, we found it, we called you.
The big dogs are here now, so set up some
yellow tape and stand on the other side of it.
It's been two hours, we're still waiting for the detectives
to release the scene so we can go back on patrol.
Comfortable footwear.
Policing is all about comfortable footwear.
Officer Van Houser.
Good evening.
Sarge said I should relieve you guys so you can go
back to being the street gods that you are.
I'm down with that.
On the street.
Watch the street.
Make sure no assholes come up here and kill us.
Yes sir.
Fucking Christ.
Officer Van Houser, have you made a difference today?
You know I see you guys out here, you're being good little company men, aren't you?
Are you doing the Lord's work?
And you're making a difference, as you call it.
It's all fun and games to you, you get to run and jump and fight and shoot.
One day the LAPD is going to bend you over your
black and white... and they are going to fuck you up the ass.
They are going to fuck you so long and so hard...
you're going to want to eat your gun just to make it stop.
And if you don't eat your gun and the fucking somehow
magically stops...they're going to give you freeway therapy.
You're going to end up doing West End Valley daywatch.
Spending two hours every day on the fucking freeway
just thinking about the fucking that they gave you.
Bad guys attack from up front.
The department comes in from the rear.
Watch your six.
I'm ready.
This may say Purell but It's really K-Y.
Officer Zavala.
That's funny.
You kids have fun out there.
The LAPD's got a big fucking cock.
You've got a big heart.
Thank you for sharing that.
Can't wait to get it up the ass.
Are you going to hook up with a Mexican girl?
Quit trying to hook me up with one of them.
It'd be great if you did but--
I get it, man.
Shit.
Sweet brown sugar.
You should marry one of my cousins.
If they're anything like you I wouldn't be able
to stand a fucking hour with them.
Waking up in the morning, they'd be like...
"Hey, can I tell you a story?"
I know.
Here's a story about this and a story about that
and a story about this and a story about that
But all you gotta do is this...
You want to come to my cousin's quinceanera?
My daughter's quinceanera?
My brother's quinceanera?
Yeah.
My sister's quinceanera?
There's always something happening, though, bro.
It's better than like Hey, do you know
the new kind of flavored coffee I have?
Do you like this kind of coffee?
Oh really?
Shut the fuck up.
The baristas are excellent.
You like fucking coffee, don't give me that shit.
I like fucking good Starbucks coffee.
Whatever.
I'll let you lay into me.
Lay into me.
Fine.
Thirteen x-ray thirteen.
Missing juvenile.
Two seven one seven Jefferson.
Code Incident five seven five five and thirteen twenty-seven.
Thirteen x-ray thirteen, we're going
to be Code Six on the missing juvenile.
I can't see dick.
Hi.
We got a call about some missing children.
Yes, my babies are gone.
All right.
My babies are gone.
You want to let us in?
We can talk.
We can have that conversation.
OK.
My babies are gone.
They've been missing all night.
And I've been here.
Why don't you just step over here for a second, ok?
Officer, we're wasting time.
Let me see your hands.
How many children are missing?
Two.
A boy and a girl.
What are the ages of the children that are missing?
One is...
one and the other be three.
Sir!
Somebody took them.
Let me see your hands, please.
Maybe it was when I went to the bathroom.
Let me see your hands.
Someone quick quick quick.
OK ma'm
In and out
- All right.
Ok.
All right.
Hands behind your head.
I've been here all night.
Officer, we're good here.
Don't say anything to them.
I know, but they're not here.
They're gone.
The babies are gone.
What did you say?
I'm going to check the house, ok?
Listen to me, officer.
I'm trying to tell you.
I've looked-
The kids are with their grandma.
Is this your husband?
No, that's not my husband.
Sit the fuck down!Sit the fuck down!
I've been looking.
I understand.
I'm going to check the house.
Sometimes children can hide under a bed or in a closet.
You can talk to my partner.
You're wasting time!
The kids are at grandma's!
The kids are not here!
If you can please go outside and get my kids.
Talk to my partner.
Stop, don't push me!
My babies are missing!
Let me see some type of warrant.
You got a warrant?
We don't need a warrant, she let us in.
Why the fuck did you say anything?
You stupid  why the fuck did you say anything?
Sit down-
I was going to get a cigarette.
Not right now.
I'm trying to tell you, the kids are with their grandma, ok?
I heard you.
They're with the grandma.
Would you please listen to me, Officer?
Let me see some type of warrant.
You shut the fuck up!
Why the hell did you let them in here?
Press charges on this motherfucker!
You fucking bitch, I'm going to kill you!
I'm going to kill you, motherfucker!
Get the fuck off me!
What the fuck's happening?
Wait a minute!
- All right, all right!
Did you head what I said to you?
Did you hear what I said to you?
You just let me know how clear I have to make myself to you.
Why don't you open your fucking mouth and tell me how clear I have to make myself to you.
Partner!
Get off him.
Brian, what's up?
You ok, partner?
What's happening, Brian?
Fuck you, you dumb-ass smoker bitch!
I'm going to kick you in the fucking face!
I found the kids.
Fucking crackhead.
It's ok, it's ok.
You're ok now.
I'm just gonna  oh shit.
It's ok.
It's ok, sweetie.
All right.
Hey buddy, stay still.
All right, you're ok now.
You're ok.
Come here, come here.
You ok?
You gonna take care of your sister?
Fucking kids.
It's so funny.
It's so funny to text.
Who are you texting?
That same bitch?
Dude, yeah.
She's smart.
She's like the first girl I can have a conversation with.
You know she has a Master of Science in Fluid Hydraulics.
Fluid Hydraulics?
Yes.
I wouldn't brag about that.
That she has a master's degree in Fluid Hydraulics.
I date all these girls, man.
They're smoking hot.
Your little fucking badge bunnies
I get laid without a badge, thank you very much.
Because you were in the Marines.
Don't ask don't tell.
There's a pattern.
An M.O. here.
First date is dinner and a respectful kiss.
Second date is dinner, full carnal knowledge.
And then third date is dinner and uncomfortable silences when I try to discuss anything of merit.
Then it's two or three booty calls and it's on to the next.
Ok, I went to prom and I got married a week later.
And I ain't tapped anybody but Old Faithful for like eight years.
So I don't know what you're tripping about.
Ok.
Wait, look at me real quick.
aha
Ok, ready?
Yeah.
I want somebody to talk to.
Not just sleep with.
Do you fucking understand what I'm saying?
Oh.
Yeah.
Jesus, dude.
White people get hung up on this fucking soul mate bullshit.
Just hook up with a chick that can cook and wants kids.
Some bitch that's down for you, that won't fuck your friends, and you're straight.
You're the smartest motherfucker I know, you're not going to find some chick that's as smart as you.
Really?
Yeah, what?
I'm sorry the perfect girl wasn't dumped
in front of me when I was eighteen years old.
Do you talk to Gabby?
Do you even have discussions with the girl?
Do you want me to translate that into fucking His- Spanish?
Into Hispanic?
Whatever the fuck it is.
Yeah, what do you think, we're mutes?
And we just .... like sign to each other?
Yeah we talk, stupid.
Gabby's a trip.
You know she's a trip.
You should hear the shit that comes out of her mouth.
You know what?
She would be great on Jeopardy.
She's way smarter than I am.
All right, so you see what I'm talking about.
That's all I want
I know you want a chick like my girl,
but I'll kill you if you touch her.
Fuck!
I'm going to kill you!
Shut up!
What's this chick's name?
You don't deserve to fucking know her name.
Dude, fuck that!
Jannet.
Did you run her?
Yes, she's clean.
She's kind of the complete package.
We're going out again.
Saturday's my little sister's quinceanera.
You should roll through with Jannet from another planet.
The shit's going to be hardcore Mexican, though.
You know how my familia rolls.
Hey, mija.
What's up?
Come here, baby girl. Drink the Jim Jones, baby, come on.
Hey baby?
Tell me something.
You ever fucked on heroin?
Yeah right.
I could fuck forever on that shit.
I'll eat your pussy for hours, girl.
Get the fuck over here.
Fuck that fool, he's crazy, he's tripping.
You're my fucking lady.
I'll buy you shit.
You see this shit right here?
It's fucking money.
Real shit.
What you like?
Come here.
Ok.
Any Newton unit.
Five oh seven party.
Three six four five Trinity Street.
Incident thirty eight ninety and RD thirteen seventy-six.
X nine, send me the call
X Nine roger.
X twenty five shows code six of x nine.
Twenty-five roger.
X thirteen, we're going to be code six on the party call.
X thirteen, roger.
Cops!
OFFICER Keep your eyes wide, this place is assholed up.
Clear the car.
Put that shit away.
Put that down
What's the occasion?
Can you turn down the music?
Have some respect, La La.
Don't light up in front of us.
Why don't you take a hit, mija.
It'll chill you out.
It'll be like back in the days.
Remember?
No, I don't remember shit.
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
I said put it out.
You know you want this, pig.
I wouldn't fucking touch that
if you were the last bitch on earth.
Fuck you.
No, fuck you.
Why don't you take a seat.
You look in the mirror, you're just a common
fucking gangster bitch (on) like all the rest.
Lock it up, Orozco.
Why don't you sit your ass down.
Why don't you do what the fuck they tell you, puppet?
Want me to make you?
Lock it up, partner.
You know what?
I'll fucking sit down now.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
So Mr. Big Evil... why do they call you Big Evil?
Because ... my evil is big.
Can you turn down the music,
because we got a noise complaint or some shit.
Then you go faster.
I am nailing this.
Hey bro.
Hey.
Hi baby.
Cindy, what's up?
I wanted to introduce you to Janet.
Hi. It's so nice to meet you.
Happy birthday.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
Pick up your dress so you don't step on it.
Yeah.
You look beautiful.
I gotta go.
Bye!
Bye
All grown up.
He spoils her.
But I want to give you the lowdown.
I'm listening.
Everybody here is pretty much family.
Like somehow.
They're all Mexican family.
You got cousins and you got aunts and uncles just like everything
else and then you got cousins' cousins. And then you have Brian.
You stick around, you're going to see someone throw up.
Couple fights.
It's fun.
Enough, enough.
I'm sorry.
Well, I'm Irish, so it's the same thing..
Big families, and no one gets divorced.
And they all wear purple.
Well, less purple... but just as much beer.
They get way too drunk and get in fistfights.
Yeah, same here.
But you mess with one person
you have the whole family after you.
That's the way to do it.
There you go.
You just described Mexican people.
Can I feel it?
Is that ok?
Yeah, he's actually kicking a lot right now.
And I think his feet are right there.
Do you feel it?
Wow.
Oh my god.
I like her, Brian.
Buddy.
How long have you know Brian?.
Three years.
He and Mike went to the Academy together.
Right.
Brian, it's you.
Hi.
I'm going to try not to wake you up.
I can't believe that I stayed over.
This is interesting.
I have never shot one before.
Maybe that could be our next date.
I did go through your wallet.
I'm sorry.
I am naturally curious.
I hope that's ok.
Gotta love a guys who has a picture of his mom in his wallet.
This?
Kristin, Mia, Raquel, etcetera, etcetera.
You won't be needing this anymore.
You were drooling.
What are we looking for again?
All the food groups: dope, money and guns.
The ghetto will provide.
Fucking Sarge.
Serge, We're staking out Curbside.
They're going to spot your unit.
You think they don't know you're here?
Van Hauser wants to file a complaint on you, Taylor.
The USS Van Hauser?
LAPD's stealthiest submarine,
only surfaces at the end of watch?
He said you were videotaping him.
What did I tell you about that shit?
Why is he such a bitter dude?
If he hates pushing the black and white so much, why doesn't he just leave his badge
on the watch commander's desk and go home and eat a bowl of dicks?
Have some empathy for this man.
Taylor, I gotta put in m log that I verbally
counseled you about this fucking camera.
What?
I was documenting a crime scene.
Have a good day, ladies.
Take it easy.
Is that Big Evil's mom right there?
His mom?
Yeah, that's Mrs.Evil.
Who's the cowboy?
I don't know.
He's got money, look at his truck.
I'm going to run him.
You want to jam this fool?
Yes I do.
Plate's clean.
Shit.
What's our PC?
That stupid CD hanging from his rearview mirror,
obstructing his vision.
Let's do this.
All right-.
Come on, fucker.
Wait wait wait.
Light them up.
Thirteen-x-ray-thirteen,
we're code six on three nine street east of Wall.
License plate four boy one seven three two.
Grey Dodge pickup.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger.
Let's get this fucker.
We stopped you because a CD is hanging
from your mirror. Get out of the truck.
Gun!
Get the fuck out of the car.
You good, partner?
I'm good.
X twenty five shows code six with x thirteen.
Thirteen x two five, roger.
You ok?
***
Transport this son of a bitch.
No problem.
Check out this motherfucker's burner.
Holy shit.
He's got more bling than the old lady's wedding ring.
A cell.
You don't have any holes in you?
I'm good.
Let's toss the truck.
Who was he shooting at?
What?
Me.
That's fucked up.
Air eleven, show us responding.
Fucking ... soup.
What's up?
That's big money right there.
Shit.
Oh shit.
What the fuck is it?
Homeboy's a player.
We got a surprise for you.
Liberace's AK.
Holy shit.
Here we have two of the major food groups:
money and guns.
This is the lifeblood of our organization.
Paperwork.
The way red corpuscles carry oxygen through the body
paperwork carries information through the department.
What are corpuscles?
Evening, guys.
How you doing, captain?
Sir.
So this is it?
These are the guns you took off the Cowboy?
Yes sir.
Mind if I pick them up?
Fancy.
That's some nice hardware.
I heard he took a shot at you.
Are you ok?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm good.
Liberace's AK.
Looks like Liberace's AK.
Keep up the good work, guys.
I really appreciate it.
Carry on.
Thank you.
Good evening, sir.
Good night, Van Hauser.
Evening, sir.
Why do you get nervous?
Women want him, men want to be him, man.
He's just
Yeah, I know.
But you want him.
I'm not gay, but I'd go down on him if he asked.
Sometimes I don't know when you're kidding.
And I have to know when you're kidding.
I'm not kidding.
I gotta know when you're kidding.
I gotta go.
I'm taking Janet to the Philharmonic.
Enjoy your white people shit.
Thanks, I'll bring you back a burrito.
No problem.
Hey ma, what's up, let's slide, all right, all  right.
And we gonna get it on tonight.
You smoke   I smoke, I drink   Me too, well good,
cause we gonna get  high tonight
Got drops, got Coups, got trucks, got jeeps,
all right, cause we gonna take a  ride tonight
So ma, what's up, let's slide, all right, all  right
And we gonna get it on tonight .
You're the best...
One more time.
Stop.
Stop, man, fuck.
What are you going to say to the taxpayers
when you crash the fucking car?
Drink more coffee.
I'm on my ninth fucking Red Bull.
We got a fire.
Where?
Go left.
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen,
we're code six on a structure fire.
What's that address?
One zero zero two.
One zero zero two Sixth Street.
Go ahead and send RA and fire.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger.
My babies- my babies are in there!
Where?
They're upstairs in the bedroom.
Z, no!
Wait for fire!
Fuck!
Over there, kids room.
Shit.
It's the kids' room, come on!
Come here.
Come here, come here.
Go with him!
- Come on!
Come here.
Wrap your arms around me.
Wrap your legs around me.
You got it.
There you go.
I'm going down!
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
Yup.
You all right?
I'm good.
Come on.
Go go go!
I'm going.
Fuck!
Come on, put your head right here.
Come down!
Let's go!
Come on!
Where's my baby girl?
Where is she?
Wait, lady, you got more kids?
My girl.
She's two.
Oh shit.
No! Z, no!
Come on!
Go, go go, get up!
Fuck it's hot.
God damn it!
Come here, babe.
Come here.
Cover her face.
Put that blanket around her face.
I got her.
I can't breathe.
Come on, go go go.
I can't see.
Where you at?
I'm right here.
Follow the light.
I can't see you.
I'm right here.
Come on.
I got it.
I got her.
Shit.
I'm going down.
Come on.
All right.
Stay still.
Fuck, I got it.
I fucking can't see out of my...
Where's Z?
I'm right here.
I'm going to check you out, sit down right here.
Can you open your eyes?
You all right?
Give me a bottle of water.
Get the fuck away!
I'm right here.
Get away, get away.
Fuck.
Get away.
I'm right here.
Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Don't fucking freak out.
Shut up, shut up We're good, we're good.
Shut up.
For their selfless actions and their exemplary service to the citizens of this city... the Medal of Valor is presented to Officer Brian Taylor.
and Officer Miguel Zavala.
What's up, Sandra?
Hi Brian.
You feel like a hero?
What?
No.
Yeah, me neither.
What's a hero feel like?
I don't know.
Did I tell you that me and Gabby
got into a huge fight over the fire?
Nope, you didn't tell me that.
She's like you could have died for someone
else's kid when ours hasn't even been born yet.
She's like you're not a fireman.
Janet said the same thing.
Yeah?
I don't think I can go into another burning building.
I only went in because you did.
Now you know.
All right, dickhead, what is it?
You remember that cowboy with the blinged out AK?
Yeah, he's probably my cousin.
I crisscrossed some numbers on his cell.
Couple addresses come up in our basic area.
You're not a detective.
That guy is something.
He's into something.
Oh really, you think?
DA didn't buy the ADW and only filed on the weapons beef.
Gang Unit says they'll get it him
but they're too busy or some shit.
And Narco's not interested because we didn't find dope.
Yeah, but you're not a detective.
You're not a fireman.
Fuck you.
Follow me into the house, dude.
I said you're not a detective.
I want to be a detective.
You wanna be?
Follow me into the house, dude.
Follow me into the house.
Thirteen-x-thirteen with a code six
at ninethree one eight five three street.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger.
The fuck?
What the fuck?
This is weird.
Thirteen x-ray thirteen, you need to send us additional unit.
Thirteen-x-thirteen is requesting two additional units for a building search at one zero zero two six street.
It's ok, it's ok.
it's ok.
Open the door.
It's ok. Goodbye.
Fuck this guy.
Get that shit out of here.
I know what that means.
Shut the fuck up.
Spread your legs.
Spread your fucking legs.
Put your fucking head back.
Gun, partner.
Oh yeah?
Get your fucking head back.
Another gun, partner.
Two?
Wads of cash.
Tell him to get on his knees.
Get the fuck over here.
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen.
We've got one in custody.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger.
All right, we're good.
All right.
What do we got?
Check it out, partner.
I got this motherfucker.
Oh my god.
Take my buddy.
What the fuck, Zavala, you catch them, I clean them?
Take him.
I don't know, we got like-
I'm going to go outside.
Z, you good?
I'm good.
Z!
What are you doing with all these people?
You're a fucking asshole.
Asshole.
What the fuck?
Federal agents.
Who's in charge here?
Are you in charge?
What the fuck.
I need to know who's in charge here.
Is this man under arrest?
Yes sir.
What are the charges against this man?
Turn that fucking camera off.
It's off.
Get that fucking camera off me.
You guys fucked up.
Just lost a POI because of you guys.
Are we clear in there?
Clear.
What the fuck?
What did we fuck up?
I don't fucking know, dude.
Who the fuck is this guy?
I don't fucking know.
We have one POI.
I just want to fucking talk to this guy.
Let's just get out of here.
I just want to fucking talk to him just for a second.
Go ahead.
I don't want to cause any trouble here, but we just fucking  we rolled up here, I don't know what's going on.
This is the second cowboy like this we've run into in a week.
Watch out for these guys.
They operate by a different set of rules.
I know I'm just a ghetto street cop but you've got to give me something here.
We've got indicators he's a runner for the Sinaloa Cartel.
We ran him, he came up clean.
You guys don't have the proper clearance for any of this information, but I'm going to throw you a bone.
Cartels are operating here.
We're on it.
Be careful.
What does that mean though?
It means you and your homeboy need to power down.
Because you just tugged on the tail of the snake and it's going to turn around and bite you back.
I'm throwing you a bone here.
Be grateful for what I'm giving you.
I'm giving you a warning.
Lay low.
Can I get your name for my log.?
Negative, move along.
Yeah, all right.
You know there's five year old kids in there?
For six months?
Good bye.
Get off the crime scene.
Go home.
Bye.
Have a nice night.
Yeah. Fucking feds.
Z, what the fuck?
Fuck them.
I didn't think that shit came over here.
Kids, women.
Did you see that fucking toilet?
Filled up with shit.
We had no fucking business being there.
We didn't even have a call there.
I didn't know what we were fucking rolling up on.
You think I knew what we were rolling up on?
It's human trafficking.
He's so cute.
You did so good.
I love this smell.
Just hold his head a little bit.
I am.
He's fine.
You gotta hold him like this, like a football.
I know how to hold a baby.
Babe, please.
Like that.
Hey.
Hi!
Hey partner, what's up?
Come here.
Look who's here.
How's mama doing?
Mama's tired and cranky.
Just like baby.
Mama wants to choke Daddy.
Come on, babe.
Did you name him Brian?
Sorry.
He's a junior.
Named him after his daddy.
So what's his name?
Fuck you.
Can I hold him?
Yeah.
So sweet.
You're so done.
Hey baby.
What are you wearing?
I can say it.
I don't care.
You still look good.
Yeah, Brian's right here.
OK.
All right, sorry.
OK, I love you.
Bye.
You didn't even say hi.
She was pissed.
How'd you know you were going to marry Gabby?
She told me.
I was just some stoner working at my uncle's muffler shop and one day she grabbed me by the shoulders...
and said we're getting married and you're joining the department'
because you can make a lot of money without a college degree and I was like fuck yeah'.
I mean, you love her.
You guys, you never fight.
You're happy together.
She's my bitch for sure.
I'm just telling you the way it went down.
I popped her cherry in high school.
She's never been with anybody else.
I've never wanted to be with anybody else.
You know, it's easy.
Things are getting super serious with Janet and me.
What, you just found that out?
Did you read that in the paper or something?
Homegirl owns your ass.
She wants to move in.
She's always over.
Why spend the money on two apartments.
It's not about the money.
No, her parents are so traditional.
Oh yeah?
They will go ballistic.
But at least we can tell them we're engaged.
Hold up.
Don't play with that shit.
You don't ask a broad to marry you because her folks are old school.
No, you don't understand.
No, you don't do that shit.
Think about it.
After you think about it, think about it again.
Jesus.
Marriage is forever.
Just realize that.
It's a promise before god.
My grandma was really deep.
She's seen it all.
You know what I'm saying?
When me and Gabby got engaged, she asked me one thing.
Do you want to hear it?
Fine, let's hear it.
She said can you live without her?
And if the answer's yes, man up and forget her.
Don't string her along.
Think about it.
I did.
Thirteen-x-ray- forty-three.
Officer needs help.
Where?
Newton units, stand by.
X forty-three officer needs help.
Thirteen x forty-three, what's your location?
I don't know.
What?
That's Van Hauser's car.
Come on, Boot!
Just book it south.
Go.
Find a street sign, put it out.
I don't see any!
***
Is there a number on a house?
A building number?
The house is three one seven seven.
Sir, back up!
Holy shit.
Hook a left on Maple.
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen show us responding code three from three zero and Maple.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger.
Responding code three Maple and three zero.
Right there!
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen show us code six at Compton and three one street.
Who is that?
Taylor and Zavala.
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen, send me an airship to set up a perimeter.
Oh shit.
Would you call for a rescue?
Do not move.
What did he look like?
Where'd he go?
Northbound through the houses.
Hispanic male, blue checkered shirt.
Zerohead, he's a parolee, he's fucking huge.
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen, suspect headed northbound, heavyset male Hispanic, shaved head.
Weapon used was a knife.
Let's do this shit.
Careful, men.
On your left.
He's fucking huge.
It's clear over here.
Crossing.
The windows?
You got left?
I got right.
Push push push.
You're on my elbow.
You call it out.
You call it out if you see it.
I see him.
On the left.
Ready, go go, split.
Take it, you bitch.
Fuck you!
On the left.
I've got him, you ready?
Fucking bitch.
Fucking whore.
Try to fuck with me?
Fuck you!
Get the fuck off her or I will blow your fucking head off.
I'm done.
I ain't resisting, officer.
Don't fucking look at me!
I ain't resisting, sir.
Shut the fuck up!
Get up.
Put your hands over your head.
Back up towards me til I tell you to stop.
Move.
Stop.
Now get on your fucking knees.
And cross your goddamn feet together, you hear me?
Cross your legs.
If I hear a fucking word out of you, I will blowyou out of your fucking socks.
Hook him, Z.
Thirteen-x-ray-thirteen, show a code four.
Suspect's in custody.
You good, Z?
I'm good.
Are you good?
God damn it.
All right, you're going to be all right.
You're going to be all right.
Fuck man, her face is all fucking broken.
Thirteen-x-ray-thirteen requesting an additional RA.
Thirteen-x-thirteen, roger on the RA.
We're here for you, all right?
We got the cavalry coming.
That motherfucker's going to pay for what he did, you hear me?
Boot, you hear me?
Boot?
Don't call her Boot.
Well I don't know what her fucking name is.
Is there a tag anywhere?
Do you see a tag?
No.
You hearing me?
She's nodding, she's nodding, she hears me.
You're going to be all right.
Do you hear me?
It's all good.
You're going to be OK, brother.
Fucking cut my vest off.
God damn it.
I tell you one fucking thing.
Fucking cut my vest off.
All right, we got your back.
Jesus Christ.
God damn it.
Get back, all right.
You're good.
We got your back.
They cut my fucking vest.
What's up?
You OK?
I'm really tired.
Why didn't you shoot that son of a bitch?
You had him dead to rights.
I just didn't feel like killing anyone tonight, Sarge.
You feel like writing this up?
Brass is going to want clean paper, make sure all the logs match.
Sarge, did you see that?
Van H had a fucking Ginsu sticking out of his eye.
His eye was cut in half.
The lens was hanging out.
He's not coming back.
Rookie too.
What?
She ain't coming back.
She gave me this to give to the Watch commander.
On the spot?
Yeah.
Oh well, she wouldn't have made probation anyway.
Hell no.
What, because her daddy's not a captain?
You know she wasn't cut out for this shit.
Why is that?
The evidence.
She almost got Van Hauser killed.
You guys are cold.
You got cold, dead eyes, you know that?
Yeah, both of us.
Yeah, both of you.
You have a soul?
Yes, we just leave it at home.
We going to sit around yapping or we going to get this done?
You guys saved that rookie's life.
That was one big fucking fat ese.
Can we clear the scene?
Division's fucking falling apart over here.
We good?
You good?
Good good good?
We're all good.
Yes?
Go back to work.
Good night, ladies.
Ladies and gentlemen, introducing Officer and Mrs.
Taylor.
What's up, guys.
All right.
Janet, you got a lot of heart hooking up with a cop.
Because it takes a strong person... and I see like a lot of cops' wives in here, they're all nodding their heads.
You gotta take care of her.
Cause I'm her big brother now. And every cop in here... we're all her family now too.
I'm going to cry, baby, shut up.
And Janet, we're all hoping you can make a man out of Brian.
Because we've all given up.
So here we go.
To Brian and Janet.
Cheers!
Can I ask you something?
Why the fuck did you get married in your dress blues?
If you worked at Best Buy would you wear that fucking stupid polo shirt?
I like that polo shirt.
I'm representing.
You know I love you, man
Jesus.
Here they go again.
I love you too, bro.
I would lay down my life for you.
I love you, man.
I would take a fucking bullet for you.
Why don't you guys get married to each other?
All right, shut up.
Everybody take a shot.
Salud!
Cheers!
My boy Garcia?
He's a fucking beast.
I've seen this motherfucker knock an asshole out with one punch.
Yoked assholes, man.
Yoked assholes from the joint when they had weight piles.
You know what I'm talking about?
You don't know what I'm talking about,
you're fucking twelve years old.
Cops like him... Like soldiers.
He took a bullet for me.
My bullet.
He took my bullet.
That's what he was.
That's what he was to me.
It should have been me.
Cause he was a good guy.
I was shit.
Fuck it.
Gimme a kiss.
You'll learn this.
You'll learn.
Marriage is really basic.
There's just a couple guidelines.
One: you've got to give it up all the time.
All the time.
You love that.
I don't hate that idea.
It's not a bad idea.
It's not a bad thing.
No, seriously, girls throw it at cops.
Throw what exactly?
Their pussy.
Girls throw it.
So you can't give him an excuse, girlfriend.
You can not give him an excuse.
I've actually seen that before.
It's called assault on a peace officer.
You ready?
Hell yeah.
Try new things.
Baby...
Like the gooch.
The what?
The gooch?
Texas twister.
No, that's something that's made up.
The internet made that up.
You want to know what Mike likes?
No!
Babe, I love you so much.
The western, you know?
Open to explore, right?
Gabby!
It's our wedding!
Cup him.
Suck him.
No no no!
You just rub it a bit and then.
What the fuck?
Gabby!
Venture off a little more.
Venture off?
They swear they don't like it but...
Shit!
Really?
I'm happy.
Janet's dope.
You're my brother and everything, but you're a piece of shit.
Does she know that?
Yeah, she knows who I am.
I mean, you can't get into something with somebody without ... She knows who I am.
Yeah.
I know who you are.
You're a piece of shit.
If you break her heart, I'm going to fuck you up.
Good to know.
If anything happened to you, I would take care of your kids.
If you had any.
And I would take care of her.
I would take care of Janet.
What's in the stack?
Anything good?
Let's see here... Business dispute.
Request police mediation.
One neighbor threw a cup of water on the other neighbor's window.
We're not buying that.
Three ninety male.
Intoxicated person outside a liquor store.
Get the fuck out of here.
There's a drunk man outside the liquor store?
Welfare check.
Woman requests PD contact her elderly mother.
Yeah, buy that one.
You serious?
Yeah, if we buy a couple of these, maybe they'll send us a code three call.
Cool.
I'll hit her up for the next hotshots.
On this episode, we're rolling to a call.
A woman called the station to check on her elderly mother.
So we're going to go.
These are the calls most agencies deal with, you know?
Not every call's a foot pursuit or a car chase.
Some guys at other agencies have never even drawn their weapon or been in a gunfight.
Yeah, but here that's just half your shift.
In the south end...
we'll get involved in more capers in one deployment period than most cops see their entire career.
Hell yeah.
Mrs. Williams!
Mrs.Williams!
Police Officers!
Go around back, check it out.
All right.
Here we go.
I'm going to wait for my partner.
He's going to check the back to see if she's around the back over there.
Often times, a lot of these people, they're very old people.
They can't hear us.
You know, they can't hear  the hearing aids, you know.
Nothing.
So the owner of this house is actually the daughter of the woman who lives in it.
She gave us permission for the welfare check, so we're going to... We're going to boot the door.
Officer Zavala specializes in booting doors.
I kick doors down.
There you go.
Say it in English now.
I kick doors down.
Wait, did you check if it was unlocked?
Ladies and gentlemen, always a good idea to make sure a door is locked ... before you boot it.
Are you going to cut that out?
Yeah, sorry.
It was always locked.
Clearly my partner always knew that.
You know what's going to happen, right?
What?
She's going to roll through, come from
the church or the store or whatever.
And then she's going to see property
damage and what's going to happen?
What's going to happen?
We're going to be the bad guys.
Shit.
We got a dead body.
What have we got?
Squatters?
Yeah, I'd say someone's been kicking it back here for sure.
LAPD
Let's roll through.
You good?
Clear.
That is wrong.
I said it was clear.
All right.
I'm just filming it.
I found her.
What's up?
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen, I'm going to need a supervisor and two additional units at our location.
And RA for the elderly female approximately seventy years old.
Not conscious, not breathing.
Thirteen x thirteen's requesting two additional units and a supervisor.
Five one seven one Maple.
Incident one four six seven, RA thirteen fifty-   one.
What is she, grandma praying to the dope gods or some shit?
That's not fucking grandma.
Don't fucking play on them.
No, look.
Hollow.
Somebody's opened it before.
That's what that means.
Take that shit out.
You can't pull it out yourself?
Just fucking pull it out.
Party time.
Z... No, wait wait wait.
What?
Do you see that pot?
Yeah.
That shit's still steaming.
Oh shit.
I'm going in.
Ready?
Go ahead.
What is that?
Is that a body?
Yeah, there's bodies in there.
Thanks for the fucking update.
Fuck.
Is it clear?
Clear.
What does it say?
What's that shit say?
Keep bringing them.
Ha ha ha.
Fuck!
Come on.
Get your shit together.
Pull your shit together.
Fuck out of here.
Let's get out of here.
Fuck.
Sick motherfuckers.
Who would do shit like that?
What is that shit?
I don't fucking know.
I've never seen that kind of shit.
Do you have hand sanitizer?
No, I don't.
I'm Serene Branson on the scene in south Los Angeles
at one of the largest narcotics seizures this year.
In addition to the drugs, officials are telling us
there was a very gruesome discovery.
An unknown number of bodies
showing evidence of torture.
A police official familiar with the investigation denied
rumors Mexican drug cartels are responsible for the murders.
We're having a lot of problems.
The Lord of the South wants something done.
This is just two city cops, right?
Yes, two city cops.
Take care of these assholes or I'll take care of you.
Got a problem with that?
Consider it done.
And don't leave a mess.
People hate cops, people in gangs.
Write down what you spend. I'll get it done.
Gabby wants to know if you and Janet want to roll to the Dodgers game with us tonight.
We're going to Santa Barbara.
All right, fuck you then, I'll sell that shit online or something.
Here's Tre right here.
What's up, Tre?
What's up back.
What you doing?
I'm doing what I do, you know what I'm saying?
Same shit, different day.
Ain't shit changed.
What's up with you all?
Just slow motion.
And that little incident you and I had?
You kept it G.
You didn't snitch on me.
And I respect that.
So check this out, my people just got out of Folsom prison.
From up north.
Oh yeah?
Word is you got a hit on you all.
You all been greenlit.
We're cops, everybody wants to kill us.
I'm just telling you what they're saying.
No, you know what, we appreciate the info, but this don't mean you get a pass if we catch you slipping.
I ain't looking for no fucking pass.
I do what I do, you know what I'm saying?
I had to say it, though, you know how it is.
All right, what you doing this weekend?
You like the Dodgers?
You going to slide a nigger some tickets or something?
Have a good weekend.
Slide me some tickets.
Shut the fuck up!
Did you fuck with my... come on, did you fuck with my shit?
I don't fuck with your shit.
Mike, come on.
Don't be a little bitch about it.
I didn't fuck with your shit.
You fucked with my shit.
It was in totally different order.
Why do you have an investigation report on here?
I don't have an investigation report on there.
It's your handwriting.
Don't be an idiot.
All this is fucked up.
Did you drop it or something?
There's three types of pages.
It's all out of order.
It's all fucking out of order.
No, it's a pain in the ass.
I'm sorry, partner.
Wait until they hit a small street.
At a stop sign, you fucking tap the bumper, we're going to get out and blast.
Fuck no.
What do you mean, no?
We should get them when they go to lunch at the Chinese place.
That Chinese place is crawling with cops.
We gotta get these fuckers when they're alone.
We can fucking follow their asses home and hit them there.
White boy's in fucking Simi Valley and the other fucking fool's in San Gabriel.
We gotta get these fuckers at the same time.
This is the one-time, homie.
Not a bunch of fucking niggers.
Motherfucker.
This fucker is straight from the fucking SHU.
You stop fucking around.
You got in the fucking car.
You want to fucking hang with the fucking carnales... now you fucking pay the fucking price of fucking admission, homeboy.
I'll fucking kill this fucking bitch, all right?
You shut the fuck up.
You get that fucking shit out of my fucking face.
I'll fucking kill you, motherfucker.
Don't you fucking disrespect.
Don't worry.
I got this shit.
Fuck.
I don't know where the fucking rubber band is either.
Don't blame me for the rubber band.
You just took the rubber band off.
If you hadn't fucking put everything out of order, then the rubber band wouldn't be out and the... Look, it's the butterfly effect, ok?
Do you know what the butterfly effect is?
Nope.
It's the butterfly effect.
Look it up.
Just because you say it twice doesn't mean that I get it the second time.
This is fucking stupid.
Those motherfuckers got bulletproof vests.
We need to hit them with some AKs and shit.
Don't fucking rank out.
Fuck you!
When the fuck have I ever backed out from shit?
Get that fucking camera out of my face.
I'm saying we just can't fuck this shit up.
I don't give a fuck.
You know me.
I'll do the motherfucking time.
I just don't want the big homies fucking whacking me.
Fucking whacking me for fucking up.
We need a fucking plan.
And you fucking know it.
Think about it.
That's all I'm saying.
Fucking head back.
I'll get some fucking big guns from the Border Brothers.
Never fall asleep in a room full of cops.
That shit ain't even fucking funny.
Just cause you won the fucking award doesn't give you license to be a fucking asshole.
You got shit on your face.
What is this?
Are we in the third fucking grade?
Keep it up, it's going to earn you a risk management case.
Give me this fucking camera.
He had something....
I'm serious.
This department built you up, they will fucking tear you down.
You know it's fucking funny.
Laugh, you fucking idiot.
Who left their shaving cream on the table?
How was Santa Barbara?
Awesome.
Janet's pregnant.
What?
Get out of here.
Are you serious?
Already?
She's not even Mexican.
Yeah, she's going for the ultrasound tomorrow, but three of those little piss stick things...
Positive, positive, positive.
Whoa, congrats.
That's when we fucking graduate.
We fucking get the upgrade right now.
Not fucking going to be little fucking paisas no fucking more.
Right?
Yeah.
Thats what were going to fucking do.
OK?
They want to come into our fucking hood and fucking talk shit to us?
You fucking do this shit right?
They dont fucking disrespect us. Its our fucking hood.
You guys want to fucking collect?
You guys got to fucking put up.
This time were going to fucking do it right.
Hell yeah, were doing this.
Fucking guys have some fucking balls.
After we get these motherfuckers... you know its gonna be a little hot in the hood.
Were going to get the fuck out of here after that.
Im gonna fucking take you guys to fucking Vegas.
You guys fucking do this shit right, Im gonna treat you right.
But if we dont fucking do this, we can never fucking come back, thats the fucking thing.
Wouldnt it be crazy if our kids were pushing a black and white together one day?
Screw that.
I want my kid to have an honest job.
Like a politician.
Whoa.
Idiot.
Light them up.
Hes running.
Thirteen-x-ray-thirteen were going to be following a possible code thirty seven vehicle northbound Hooper from four two street.
Gray Toyota minivan.
License plate number six queen four nine nine seven three.
Requesting backup, airship, and a supervisor.
Yeah, youre clear right, go.
Go.
Fuck yeah.
You got this motherfucker.
Come on Z.
Whoa!
Fucking Christ.
Fuck.
Get the fuck out of the car.
Go!
Mike, come on!
Lets go!
X thirteen, whats your location?
Thirteen-x-ray- thirteen, suspect running on foot.
Male, Hispanic, dark clothing.
Shit!
Fuck!
Go, go!
Move!
Fucking missed, stupid.
Fuck.
Go.
Go, go, go!
Dude!
Fuck!
Move!
Tell her to get down!
Fuck.
Shit, no dice.
Were fucking trapped.
Call dispatch.
My fucking hand.
Whats up?
What, you got hit?
Did you get hit?
NTQKJH
Shit.
Fucking call dispatch.
I got no signal!
Fuck!
Fuck, I dont...
Fuckers.
Shut up!
This is thirteen x ray thirteen...
Come through the fucking door.
Come on.
Officers need help!
Shut up!
Were barricaded in an apartment building.
Shit! Tell that bitch to shut the fuck up!
Two five zero two two Hooper Place, apartment C.
Those motherfuckers are in there.
Were good, were all good!
Theyre sending the cavalry, theyre sending the whole fucking world.
Fuck!
(OUT LOUD)Fuck!
Reload.
Partner?
Dude.
Partner!
You all good?
Wasnt Big Evil in the army?
Yeah.
We cant hold them off.
Weve got to lay down a base of fire and pivot.
What the fuck does that mean?
Were shooting our way out of here.
Can these fools get out?
Yeah, we got these motherfuckers.
Dudes aint going nowhere.
Z, Look at me.
All right.
On three, youre going to empty your mag and run.
You ready?
OK.
One.
Two.
Three!
Go!
Move!
To the door, to the door!
Go!
Move, move, move!
Over the fence.
You see the fence?
Yeah.
Go, go!
Theres a wall.
Go.
You got me?
I got you.
Go, go, go!
Theyre everywhere.
Z... Z... Move, move!
Take the left.
I think we killed that guy.
Good.
Just the dogs.
Where's the fucking cavalry?
I dont know.
Partner?
What?
This sucks.
Is that us?
Is that PD?
Slow, slow, slow.
Gun!
Hit them!
Curbside gang, putos!
I lit that asshole up! ... Brian!
Is it bad?
Fuck.
Wait, wait.
Let me see.
Fuck.
Its bad.
You know what?
Ive seen guys way worse make it.
What are you fucking doing?
Dont fucking do that to me!
Stay right there!
Stay the fuck down!
Stay down, I need to put pressure on your wound.
Where the fuck is everybody?
I dont want to die here.
Youre not going to die here.
God loves cops.
I fucked up.
Dont tell Janet I fucked up.
Im going to stay right here.
Its OK.
Its OK to do it.
Its OK to do it right now.
I fucking love you, bro.
Officer down!
I need some fucking help!
Please dont go right now.
Im begging you, dont fucking go right now.
Dont go right now.
what the fuck...
Checkmate, puto.
Rest in peace, bitch.
We got you, motherfuckers.
Happy fucking ending, homies.
Hell yeah.
Celebration time.
Look at the streets of L.A.
Shit!
Fuck!
Shit.
Fuck.
X Seventy six showing code six on possible suspects in north-south alley east of Broadway...north of four one.
X seventy six code six on possible suspects   north-south alley east of Broadway, north of four one street.
LAPD!
Drop the guns!
Drop them!
Curbside gang, putos!
Fuck you!
Cease fire!
Shots fired.
Newton units be  advised, shots fired.
X seventy six, shots fired, shots fired.
Go   ahead and show a code four, suspects are  in custody.
Im going to need an RA for two male   Hispanics, two female Hispanics  suffering from multiple gunshot wounds..
Im also going to need additional  supervisors and units to my location.
X seventy six is requesting additional units   and supervisors to the north-south alley East of Broadway, north of four one..
Where the fuck is Taylor and Zavala?
Is there a code four at x thirteens  location?
Thirteen L ten, the original help call was for   X thirteen.
Do we have a code four on x thirteen?
Thirteen L ten, do we have all my people   accounted for?
X thirteen, come in.
Air eleven over Newton, were unable to  locate x thirteen.
Shit.
Fuck.
Their last location was two five zero two two  Hooper Place.
Can you go by that location?
Its them.
Mike!
Shit.
Brian!
Godammit.
Fucking A.
Request an RA for two males approximately twenty-eight years old.
Thirteen X two were roger on the RA.
Uniformed personnel!
Ill help you.
Shit.
He was my brother.
The day of the shooting...
If your kid was a girl would you let her be a cop?
Would I want my daughter packing a burner so she could protect herself from the assholes of the world?
Hell yeah.
I want to have a daughter.
That would be so cool.
Just dont let her date cops.
Shes not dating anyone.
OK.
Ever.
All right.
Did I ever tell you about the first time I spent the night with Gabby?
I dont want to hear that.
I got a hella big family, right?
Fuck, I dont want to hear that.
I got a hella big family.
Someones always at my house.
But one time, Gabbys parents bounced to Ensenada and her brother
crashed at his girlfriends so I spent the night at her house.
And this was going to be the night.
It was going to be the night, you know what Im saying?
No, what are you talking about?
Well Ill tell you what Im talking about.
OK cool
So were in her parents bed, right?
And its on.
Its about to go down.
Im taking off her chones, Im taking off--
Chones?
Her skivvies, come on.
Right.
And Im like finally, right?
Fucking finally.
But then we hear this noise.
Someones in the pad.
So I hide underneath the bed.
And then I hear people coming up.
And its her parents.
This is the second floor.
What?
I got nowhere to go.
Homegirls trying to distract them, but it aint happening.
And the footsteps grow louder.
Louder and louder.
Then the door opens  oh my god, Im naked...
underneath the bed.
And then all I can seeis little footsteps.
I see his hairy feet and I see her nails all painted
and theyre yapping, theyre doing their thing.
And they crash.
And this is the part I never told Gabby... I hear a little smootchie smootch,
and I hear some shit, and Im praying, please no.
And they did it.
What? ... What?
They got down!
Im talking Gabbys parents fucking!
All right, I got it.
No!
The shit was so traumatic.
It must have been a little uncomfortable around the folks after that.
Yeah, because her fathers a freak.
I guess when youve been married that long, you gotta mix it up a little bit.
I tried rolling like that with Gabby and she was like hell no,
youre not touching me there.
It makes me fucking uncomfortable.
I know, you know why?
Because youre a freak too.
Dont go there, just dont go there.
I fucking cant breathe.
Holy shit.
Any Newton unit...
Lets go fight crime or something.
OK.