What, are you kidding me? Sundays?
I love Sundays. I live for Sundays.
The whole family's together. Mom
makes braciole. Dad puts the jersey on.
We're all watching the game.
Yeah, it drives me crazy, and yes,
I was negative. You didn't even know
that I loved it, Nikki, but I did.
I just didn't appreciate
it, or you, before. "
Come on. Time to go.
I lost all that. I blew it. But you
also blew it. We can get it back.
We're gonna get it back.
It's all gonna be better now.
I'm better now and I hope you are,
too. And I'm gonna appreciate... "
Hey, I'll be there in a minute, okay?
Doctor's waiting. Let's go.
I'll be there in a minute.
That's true love.
Yeah, that's when I had long hair.
People say I talk about my hair too much.
And it was just the way I wanted
it, but he cut it back too far.
He cut this side back too far trying to
even it up. I didn't tell him to do that.
I said, "Just cut it
the way you cut it... "
Once you get in the right frame of
mind, I think anything's possible.
I think we get, we so often get
caught in this state of negativity and
it's a, it's a poison like nothing else.
...technically, you can take him
out against our recommendation,
but you assume a lot of liability
in the eyes of the court.
And he's just getting
used to the routine here.
I don't want him to get
Eight months is already long enough.
Hey, Mom. Can we give Danny
a ride to North Philly?
What? I don't understand.
Mom, no, it'll be fine. It'll be fine.
I guess everybody's leaving today!
Hello, Mrs. S. An honor to finally
meet you. Pat told me all about you,
how God made you rich in character,
and you're the mighty oak that holds
the household together, and not to
mention the lasagna you make on game day
when the Birds play.
Danny was in for assault because
of crystal meth and alcohol.
Bad combination.
Yeah. On top of an anxiety disorder.
That was when I was an X-ray
technician with my ADD and my
anxiety. I had a lot of access to
medication and I took advantage of
it. That's when my hair was long, too.
But my hair only grew when I
was older. When I was younger, my
hair didn't grow because my brother...
Remember I told you about my
brother, he had a Jheri curl, and
I couldn't get a Jheri curl because
my hair didn't grow long enough.
I was so jealous of my brother...
But Wait a minute, Wait a minute. Hello?
Yeah! It looks great now. You like it?
No, It's good now. Yes, it is.
Wait, you're going the wrong way!
What? Are you sure about that?
I'll bring him back right away.
You lied to me, Pat.
Danny's not allowed to leave.
All right, Mom, just hold on a sec.
Let's just talk about this.
Mom, just listen... Don't tou
-...
...
- ch the steering... ... wheel!
Pat, this whole thing was a mistake.
I'm sorry, Mom. You okay?
I am out on a limb for you
with the courts right now.
It's my fault. Pat didn't know.
Pat didn't know. He's my friend,
so he was rootin' for me. I'm havin'
a disagreement with the hospital,
but we're working it out.
Take me back to the hospital,
but take Pat home, he's
fine. Trust me. You'll see,
he's fine. It's my fault.
Mom, can we stop at the library? I wanna read
Nikki's entire English high school syllabus.
Mom, it's a good thing.
I'm remaking myself.
DeSean Jackson. What
happened to DeSean Jackson?
Come on, tell me that one.
It's insanity. He spikes the ball at the
one yard line. The one fucking-yard line.
I mean, get into the end zone, dummy. #
I mean, he celebrates before he's even in!
You know something? It's nothing
new. Your team does that all the time.
They get close... and then they blow
it. They got an inferiority complex.
Wait a minute, what are you talking about?
What makes the Cowboys America's Team?
Because we are, we're America's Team.
You should be ashamed of
yourself. We're in Philadelphia,
what's the matter with you?
You're a fucking traitor.
What's more American than a cowboy?
You know what's more American? What?
Benjamin Franklin, that's
what's more American.
Benjamin Franklin?
Benjamin Franklin. The founder of
our country, here in Philadelphia.
You mean the guy with the... ... little
glasses and the long scraggly hair?
What about the lightning with the
kite? He stood in the storm with a kite.
If he wasn't on the hundred dollar bill,
nobody... ... would even know who he is.
What are you doing? No, no, no, no.
Don't touch them, don't touch them.
I didn't even touch 'em. Why
are you..., don't blame me.
Who did this? Who took,
who took, who took the...
the remotes like this?
Did you do this, Randy?
No, I don't touch them. As a matter of
fact, I don't know why you need so many.
Hey, there she is! Look how beautiful!
What! Whats this?
Everything good? Mm-hmm.
Ahh.
Where is it? It's right here.
You got it. Ahh, well, we got that.
We don't want them to steal that.
You still got yours? Yeah, I got mine.
So what, you don't talk to me? You
didn't tell me you took him out.
Well, he's ready. Look at him.
You didn't tell Dad
you were picking me up?
Don't worry about that. I wanna
make sure when you come out
that you're okay, and
she didn't say anything.
You didn't tell me? The
court said yes. Don't worry.
Yeah, but what did the doctor say? Because
the, the court listens to the doctor.
Yeah, and the court said- The court
listens to the doctor, the doctor-
Dad, relax. The court said
it's fine, okay? Let it go.
Don't worry.
Dad, I'm in there because of the court.
That's the agreement that we made months ago.
It was a plea bargain with the courts.
The lawyer, he instructed me, he said
that what we should plead that, and
then I would serve eight
months and then I'd get out.
It's all under control.
Well... okay, okay. Congratulations.
Thank you. So what are
you doing with yourself?
You know, I'm gonna start a restaurant.
It's gonna be a cheesesteak place.
How you gonna pay for it?
I'm gonna pay for it,
don't worry about it.
From your bookmaking?
Who told you that? Mom told me. Outside.
I did not. No, I didn't.
You just told me outside, Mom,
what are you talking about?
Five minutes ago, we were walking up the
stairs, you said, "Don't say anything,
but Dad lost his job
and he's bookmaking. "
Why, Dolores? Why did you say
that to him? He has the wrong idea.
Everything's fine, Patrick. I'm more
concerned about you than anything else.
Good, Dad. Good.
Okay, the question, the big question,
is what are you gonna do with yourself?
What am I gonna do? I'm getting
in shape, I'm getting trim,
I'm getting really fit for Nikki.
I'm gonna read Nikki's teaching
syllabus and get my old job back.
Nikki sold the house. She left.
Didn't your mother tell you that?
Let me tell you something. You don't know
anything about my marriage, okay, Dad?
All right? Our marriage...
we're very, very much in love,
okay? Just like you two.
Listen, Patrick, she's gone. She's
not around anymore. Nikki left.
What are you doing, Dad? You know what?
Excelsior. Excelsior. What does that mean?
It means you know what I'm
gonna do, I'm gonna take all this
negativity and use it as fuel and
I'm gonna find a silver lining,
that's what I'm gonna do.
And that's no bullshit.
That's no bullshit. That takes
work and that's the truth.
What the fuck?!
Stupid fucking book!
I just can't believe Nikki's
teaching that book to the kids.
I mean the whole time
- let me just break it down for you
- the whole time you're rooting for
this Hemingway guy to survive the war
and to be with the woman that
he loves, Catherine Barkley...
It's four o'clock in the morning, Pat.
...and he does. He does. He
survives the war, after getting
blown up he survives it, and
he escapes to Switzerland with
Catherine. But now Catherine's
pregnant. Isn't that wonderful?
She's pregnant. And they escape
up into the mountains and they're
gonna be happy, and they're gonna
be drinking wine and they dance...
they both like to dance with
each other, there's scenes of them
dancing, which was boring, but I
liked it, because they were happy.
You think he ends it there?
No! He writes another ending.
She dies, Dad! I mean, the world's hard
enough as it is, guys. It's
fucking hard enough as it is.
Can't somebody say,
"Hey, let's be positive?
Let's have a good ending to the story?"
Pat, you owe us an apology.
Mom, for what, I can't apologize.
I'm not gonna apologize for this.
You know what I will do? I
will apologize on behalf of
Ernest Hemingway, because
that's who's to blame here.
Yeah, have Ernest Hemingway
call us and apologize to us, too.
Why didn't you run with me? Huh!
I was reading.
Please. Do us a favor,
don't read for a while.
What are you wearing a garbage
bag for? I'm gonna go run now.
Wait, wait, wait. You
have to fix this window.
I'll fix it when I get back. Fix it now.
Get in the car, Pat. You
have to go to therapy.
I don't wanna go to therapy.
You have to go. It's part of the deal.
You can't live with us and not go.
Is that song really playing?
We have music sometimes.
That song is killing me.
Could you please turn it off?
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
I don't have the
controls. I'm sorry, I-
Did Doctor Timbers put you up to this?
Is there a speaker here?
Is, is the speaker here?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Okay... I'm sorry.
I'll fix all this, okay?
That was a messed up thing
you did, Doctor Patel. Alright!
That's a messed up thing.
I'm sorry, but that's...
You can call me Cliff, please.
Yeah, well, Cliff, that's not the way
you're supposed to meet people, okay?
You should write that
down in your, I don't know
your little book you
write stuff down in.
I'm sorry about that song. I just wanted
to see if it was still a trigger for you.
Bravo. It's a trigger. I'm
not gonna take any meds,
I should just tell you that right now.
No, You have to take medicine.
No, I'm not gonna take any
medicine. It makes me foggy-
No, you will have to take medication.
I don't want any meds, Doctor.
Look, I am not the explosion guy,
okay? My father is the explosion guy.
I'm not that guy.
He got kicked out of that stadium he beat up so many
people at Eagles games, he's on the exclusion list.
I had one incident. One
incident can change a lifetime.
But I'm ready. I'm ready to take
responsibility for my side of the street.
She just needs to take
responsibility for hers.
What's hers?
What's hers? Are you joking?
Let's go back to the incident.
I come home from work after I..
fight with Nancy, the
high school ... principal.
I come home and what's playing
but the song from my wedding.
The song that you so charmingly
played out here today for us.
That's playing and I don't think
anything of it. Which is odd,
'cause I should have.
I come home, what do I see? I walk
in the door and I see underwear and
pieces of clothing and a guy's
pants with his belt in it,
and I walk up the stairs, and all...
...ll of a sudden I see the DVD player, and on the D
-...
...
- VD player is the CD and it's playing our wedding song,
and then I look down
and I see my wife's...
...panties on the ground and then-
...I look up and I see
her naked in the shower...
...and I think, "Oh, that's
kinda sweet, she's in the shower.
What a perfect thing. I'm gonna
find her and maybe I'll go in there.
We never
-... ... fuck in the shower anymore.
Maybe today we will. " I...
...pull the curtain back and
there's the fucking history...
...
- teacher with tenure.
And you know what he says to
me? "You should probably go. "
That's what he says to me.
So yeah, I snapped. I almost beat
him to death. But now I get fucking
chastised for it? I'm parallel
to my father? I don't think so.
All right. Can you talk about
something that you did, before or after?
Yeah, about a week before the
incident, I called the cops and
I told them that my wife and the
history guy were plotting against
me by embezzling money from
the local high school, which
wasn't true... It was a delusion. And
we later found out from the hospital
that's because I'm, uh...
...undiagnosed bipolar.
Yeah. With mood swings and weird
thinking brought on by severe
stress, which rarely happens, thank God.
And then the shower incident
happened and that's when everything
snapped, so I then realized that,
oh, wow, I've been dealing with
this my whole life. And without any
supervision I've been doing it all
on my own with no help and basically I've
been white-knuckling it this whole time.
That had to be hard.
Yeah. It's a lot to deal with, especially
when you don't know what the hell is happening,
which I do now. Sort of.
Pat, you have to take your medication.
I can't, Mom. I can't.
I will call them. They'll come for you.
Why would you do that? You wouldn't
do that. Why would you call them?
What's up?
I don't, I don't feel good when
I'm on them, Mom. I don't feel good.
I'm so much clearer without
them. Mom, they make me bloated.
I don't like the way it makes me look.
You've gotta take your medication.
Why don't you just take your medication?
Come on, I'm doing it with my
physicality. I've been workin' out,
that's what I'm doin'.
Why is he wearing a garbage bag?
Why are you wearing a garbage bag?
To sweat.
Sit down. We're seven minutes in, no
score. Come on, help turn the juju around.
I don't believe in juju, Dad.
Come on, Mister Excelsior. You wanna
be positive? Be positive. Sit down.
All right, all right.
Come on.
For a second. I'll watch
the beginning of the game.
He says you're good... luck, honey.
What's that in your hand?
It's a... see?
Handkerchief? Yeah.
That's OCD. That's crazy.
What OCD? I want my son to watch
the game with me, so sue me.
Just sit down, come on. I want
you to watch the game with me.
I'm not superstitious. That's
a small thing that I do.
If I make a lot of money, what's
the difference if I do this or that?
It's a small thing. Sit down. Come on.
I'm making crabby snacks and homemades.
You see?! You see that?!
You're meant to be here!
This is special. Everything
happens for a reason.
That's why you came home.
Embrace it! Embrace it!
I'm the reason? I don't think so.
Yeah, Tommy, Tommy, yes,
yes. I got your whole sheet.
Mom. Yeah. No, no...
...I'm just confirming.
I'm just confirming. Okay.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Can I do.. an interview for a
school project on mental illness? No.
It's for a school project!
Don't pay any attention.
Who's that? That's not Rick
D'Angelo, is it? That's him.
Is he the guy who's having the problem?
People are stupid. They, they, they,
they don't know what they're saying.
Yeah, that's the one.
Don't let them hurt your feelings.
Pat, don't look for Nikki! Take
your camera and get out of here!
Patrick, please. Pat!
Patty! Don't look for Nikki!
Ms. Meckers!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Nance! This is my lucky day!
Look at you working on a Sunday!
How are you? Hey.
What are you doing here?
I just came by to say hi, to let you
know I'm ready to come back to work.
You shouldn't be here.
I'll work
full-time, half-time.
I'll sub, I'll work
history, whatever you want.
Here, let me give you a hand.
I'm sorry. I'm being rude.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
Let me ask you something.
Let me just ask you something.
Does Nikki still work here?
You know I can't tell you that.
But Doug Culpepper is still here.
Why would you tell me that? You
know he broke up my marriage.
What, are you being, a troublemaker?
You know, you look good.
Did you lose a lot of weight?
I did, yeah. I did. Thank you.
Get away from me! Get away!
I'm better. I just want to let
you know, I'm better now. Okay?
I'm better. I feel good. I
feel so good. Look at my eyes.
Look at my eyes. Look
at how clear they are.
I'm not a complainer anymore.
I'm a positive guy. Okay?
You just have to give it some time.
Yes.
You know, a lot went down.
People will get over it.
It'll be all good. It'll work out.
Yes! It will be!
I'm gonna take that as a
silver development, Nancy!
A silver development!
That's a silver lining!
Good luck.
Ronnie! Pat.
There he is! He's back!
Hey.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
Welcome back, man.
Yeah, I'm out.
Yeah? You're out out?
Uh-huh.
Cool, man. Wow, you lost a lot of
weight. I almost didn't recognize you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I didn't visit you in the
hospital. You know, work's out of
control, you know, she had the
baby. I'm really glad you're back.
I missed you. I really need someone to
talk to. You gotta come see the baby.
She's beautiful. And Veronica
wants to make dinner for you.
Congratulations on the baby, but
I'm not buying the invitation.
'Cause you think
Veronica still hates you?
I know Veronica still
hates me. That's not true.
Yes, it is. Nikki always said that
"Ronnie's wife keeps his social calendar
where she keeps his balls, in her purse. "
That's not true.
Ronnie! What are you doing?
Okay, it's a little true. But
if you think she still hates you,
you're wrong because why would she
tell me to invite you to dinner?
Hmm?
Did you invite him?
Yes.
Well, can he make it?
I don't know yet! Can you
make it next Sunday?
Sure.
I'll see you next Sunday.
Now, you guys are still
in touch with Nikki, right?
Does Veronica still talk to Nikki?
Yeah.
Get in here, please. I need you.
Okay.
As soon as you left, the Redskins threw
a trick play, a pitch out to Randal El.
Andy Reid wastes a timeout challenging
it, loses the challenge, loses the game.
You're in this house, please
show some respect for what I do.
And we should spend time together anyway.
I'm trying to keep you out of trouble, please.
I have very, good news,
everybody. Very good news.
What's that? What's the good news?
Things are looking up.
Oh, are they?
You know what, I knew why they
invited me over. I knew it.
Listen, she might be with that guy.
That, the...
Oh, no way!
She..., no, she might be
with him. She's afraid of you.
She doesn't want to talk to you.
No way, Dad. You mean, Doug Culpepper?
Put the phone down. You gotta...
Wait just a minute.
...Put the phone down, please.
What are you doing?
Listen..., stop.
Pat!
You gotta understand me. You wanna
go back? Well then, stop this!
Then don't fucking do this.
Don't talk to me like that.
Well then, don't behave this way.
I got... a call asking to...
...check on this house. Pat
Solatano?
Yeah.
Yeah? Missus Solatano, Mister
Solatano, I'm Officer Keogh.
I work this beat. Look, I heard
about the restraining order.
And I heard you went to your
old house and the school.
It's not okay. I've been
assigned to your case, so you're
gonna be seeing a lot of me. Do yourself a
favor. Respect the restraining order, okay?
Five hundred feet. You hear what he
just said? Youhave a restraining order.
Yeah, Dad, I know.
Thank you, Officer.
If you need anything... my card.
Thank you. Sorry. We understand.
Since when do cops have cards?
Tell me one thing. Would you like
to be a guy who goes back to jail
or to the hospital? Hmm? So take
your medication and if you do fine,
we'll reduce them.
Nikki's waiting for me to get in
shape and get my life in order, and
then she's gonna be with me. And
that's better than any medication.
Pat, there's a possibility, and
I want you to be prepared for it,
that she may not return. True love
is about letting her go and seeing
if she returns. In the meantime,
if you listen to that song, I don't
want you to fall apart. So get
a strategy, okay? You need one.
Let me say something,
I gotta say something.
Okay.
This is what I believe to be true.
This is what I learned in the hospital.
You have to do everything
you can, you have to work your
hardest, and if you do,
if you stay positive,
you have a shot at a silver lining.
Work on a strategy, okay?
Hey, my friend Ronnie's having this
party on Sunday night and it's like
a real hoity-toity thing and his
wife, Veronica's a real stickler for...
I don't know, my mom got this Gap outfit she
wants me to wear, but I wanna wear a jersey
that my brother, Jake,
got me from the Eagles.
Which jersey?
DeSean Jackson.
DeSean Jackson is the man.
Well, that settles that.
Pat! What are you doin'?
I gotta go, man.
Why?
I can't stay, come on. I made a
mistake, I shouldn't have worn this.
Dude, you're fine. I like that jersey.
I wish I was wearing that jersey.
I feel like an idiot.
Are you comfortable?
Veronica's not gonna like it.
Get over here.
Plus you got a tie on.
Don't worry about it, you're the guest
of honor. You come however you wanna come.
Really?
Get over here.
DeSean Jackson's in the house!
You mean rookie of the year?
Yeah.
DeSean Jackson? DeSean Jackson?
Oh, you wore a jersey to dinner.
Isn't it awesome?
Not for dinner.
Look, he got us flowers.
Oh, that's sweet. That's
sweet, Pat. That's lovely.
And wine.
Hey.
Check this out. We just
redid the whole thing.
Wow!
Tremendous. Tremendous.
Isn't it great?
Tremendous.
Yeah, man, I'm, I'm
thinking of redoing it again.
Why?
Because. Gotta be making
a lot of paper to do that.
Yeah, we're doing all
right, man. I can't complain.
Isn't the market down, though?
It is down, but you know, she wants
more, so I'm giving her more, man.
Hey, you know my dad lost his pension.
I'm sorry, man.
Yeah.
A lot of people. My uncle, too.
Really?
Yeah, but you know what? No
disrespect, it's not personal,
but this is the time to strike.
You start snapping up commercial
real estate... cheap... flip it
over, you flip it over and
that's when you make the money.
But the pressure... it's like...
You okay?
I'm not okay. Don't tell
anybody. Listen to me.
I feel like I'm getting crushed and-
Crushed by what?
Everything. The family, the baby,
the job, the fucking dicks at work,
and it's like, you know, like I'm
trying to do this, you know, and,
and, and I'm like... suffocating.
Holy shit.
You can't be happy all the time.
Who told you you can't be happy?
It's all right. You just do
your best, you have no choice.
That's not true at all. You just can't.
Ronnie, Ronnie, Ronnie!
I hope you're okay with
Veronica's sister coming over.
You okay with that? Who?
Veronica's sister.
Tiffany. Tiffany and... Tommy?
Yeah. Just Tiffany.
What happened to Tommy?
He died.
Tommy died? Cops die.
How'd he die?
Please, don't bring it up.
No, how did he die?
How did who die?
Hey, Tiffany! This is Pat.
Pat, my sister-in-law Tiffany.
You look nice.
Thank you.
I'm not flirting with you.
Oh, I didn't think you were.
I just see that you made an effort
and I'm gonna be better with my
wife, I'm working on that. I
wanna acknowledge her beauty.
I never used to do that. I do that now.
'Cause we're gonna be better than
ever... Nikki. Just practicing.
How'd Tommy die?
What about your job?
I just got fired, actually.
Oh, really? How?
I mean, I'm sorry. How'd that happen?
Does it really matter?
Baby, how's it going?
Great, great.
We're gonna go on a tour now.
Let's go see the house.
Come on, let's go for the tour.
I've, I've been planning this
forever. I love our house.
I love our house. I'm
really excited about it.
Come on.
Guess what it is.
Oh, it's a television. It's
a computer screen. Nope.
Just keep going, keep going, keep going.
It's a brick oven, it's a brick
oven. It's a light. It's a...
Ooh, ooh, warmer, warmer, warmer.
...it's a drawer at a morgue
where they pull out dead
bodies and shoot them with formaldehyde.
Where would the body go, though?
It's a joke!
It's a... fireplace.
In the middle of the wall?
We have a port in every
room. Gimme an iPod.
Who, who doesn't have an iPod?
Well, I don't have an iPod.
I don't even have a phone.
They won't let me make any calls.
They think I'm gonna call Nikki.
Don't worry about it.
Don't focus on that.
I would call Nikki.
I'm actually gonna give you one
of my iPods. I have an old one.
Gimme your iPod.
Give it to me. Thank
you, baby, thank you.
Of all the rooms there
are iPod ports in,
I'm happy you brought
us into the bathroom.
I can play music for
the baby in any room.
Can you play "Ride the
Lightning" by Metallica?
Pat was a history sub at
the high school, Tiffany.
Ask him about any
president, he knows 'em all.
Here's a fun fact. You know
where the term "OK" comes from?
No. No, I don't.
Where?
Well, Martin Van Buren, the eighth
president of the United States of
America, is from Kinderhook, New York...
Oh.
...and he was part of a club, a
men's club, called Old Kinderhook.
And if you were cool, you
were in the club, they'd say,
"That guy's OK. " 'Cause he
was in the Old Kinderhooks.
Really?
Yeah. Pretty cool, right?
That's interesting.
You know, Tiffany's been doing
this dance thing for years and she's
real good at it. She's gonna be
competing at the Ben Franklin Hotel.
Oh, really? My wife loves
dance. Nikki loves dance.
Why do you have to
talk about me like that?
I'm just bragging about you. Can't
I brag about my little sister?
Don't talk about me in the third person.
Please, gimme a break.
I'm right here.
Just be nice. Just be nice.
Wow, wow, wow. Fascinating.
Sorry. I don't wanna be mean.
I know. I know, I know.
What meds are you on?
Me? None. I used to be on
Lithium and Seroquel and Abilify,
but I don't take them
anymore, no. They make me foggy
and they also make me bloated.
Yeah, I was on Xanax and Effexor,
but I agree, I wasn't as sharp,
so I stopped. You ever take Klonopin?
Klonopin? Yeah.
Right? Jesus.
It's like, "What? What day
is it?" How about Trazodone?
Trazodone!
Oh, it flattens you out.
I mean, you are done.
It takes the light
right out of your eyes.
God, I bet it does.
I'm tired. I wanna go.
No. No, no, no, no. We haven't,
we haven't even finished the salad
yet, or the duck. I made
the Fire and Ice cake.
I said I'm tired. Are you
gonna walk me home or what?
You mean me?
Yeah, you. Are you gonna walk me home?
You have poor social
skills. You have a problem.
I have a problem? You say
more inappropriate things than
appropriate things. You scare people.
I tell the truth. But you're mean.
What? I'm not telling the truth?
Um, maybe I should drive
them home separately?
You can drive them both home. Now.
Stop talking about me in third person.
You can take Tiffany home first.
You love it when I have problems.
You love it, Von, because then you
can be the good one. Just say it.
No... I don't. I don't. I
just wanted to have a nice,
I just wanted to have
a nice dinner. Oh, God.
What is your problem?!
Nothing's my problem! I'm
fine. I'm tired and I wanna go.
Come on, are you ready?
You really, you really
wanna go right now?
Yes, I really wanna go! It's been great.
Okay, guys, the baby is sleeping!
Sorry. I don't wanna
wake up the baby. Bye.
Listen, I haven't dated since
before my marriage so I don't
really remember how this works.
How what works?
I saw the way you were
looking at me, Pat.
You felt it, I felt it, don't
lie. We're not liars like they are.
I live in the addition around
back, which is completely
separate from my parents' house,
so there's no chance of them walking
in on us. I hate the fact that you
wore a football jersey to dinner
because I hate football, but you can
fuck me if you turn the lights off, okay?
How old are you?
Old enough to have a marriage end
and not wind up in a mental hospital.
Look, I had a really good time
tonight and I think you're really
pretty, but I'm married, okay?
You're married? So am I.
No, that's confusing. He's dead.
Wait, what?
What's happening?
Oh, my God. Hey.
Are you okay? Ronnie called. Hey,
is that make-up on your shirt?
I don't know, Mom.
What happened over there?
When am I gonna get a phone?
You'll get a phone in due time.
What happened?
Pat!
Mom!
I can't find my wedding
video. Mom, wake up.
What is it?
Where's my wedding video?
It's after three o'clock!
What are you doing?
I looked in here, but this is all
your sewing shit up here, for your
sewing and everything.
Did you put it up here?
What about in your father's study?
Don't go in my study.
Dad, not now!
Would you put it in here? It makes
no sense for you to put it in here.
Patty, what are you doing?
He's got all his Eagles videos
and not one video of my wedding!
Is it here? I mean...?
Patty!
It's probably in the attic.
Are you going in my study?
It feels to me like you
wanna hide my wedding video.
Please stop yelling!
I'm not yelling, Mom,
I'm just frustrated
because I should have
my fucking wedding video!
Pat! Pat!
I looked over there! I
already looked all over there!
Calm down, Pat.
I'm not calming down! I
don't give a fuck who hears,
I'm not calming down!
Anybody can wake up!
I'm not ashamed of it!
Let the whole neighborhood
wake up! I... don't care!
Pat! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
What's going on?
What?
I want it! It
-...
Hey!
It's my wedding! It's my wedding video!
Pat! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
I can't watch my wedding video,
but I CAN hear the fucking song
Mom?
What the fuck you doing?!
You... hit your mother?!
No, no, no, no, no!
Stop it!
Get off me, Dad!
Stop hitting him!
I'm not hitting him! He's hitting me!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Police! Open up.
Mister Solatano, I got a lot of calls.
People in the neighborhood
are scared. I gotta come in.
How are we doing in here, huh?
There are a lot of reports from your
neighbors, we got a lot of phone calls.
Nikki is being manipulated and
controlled. You have to talk to her.
Hey, sit down.
Sit down.
You gotta stop with
these crazy theories.
He's a cop. What are you doing?
It's a medication
problem, but he's fine now.
Oh yeah? He's fine now? You
wanna send him back to Baltimore?
We know all about the explosion
at the psychiatrist's office.
What?
What explosion? No. Cliff
is lying, that's not true.
He's not allowed to talk about that.
Jesus Christ, who's that?
Keep an eye on him.
Is this a bipolar episode?
Get outta here, you little fuckin'
idiot! Get outta here!
Someone, help me! Help me!
You can't tell Nikki about this,
Officer.
Look, I gotta make out a report.
No, no! No!
No, no, no, listen, sir.
He's chasing me! This
guy's chasing me! Help me!
Sit down!
I'm sorry. I could just write
you a letter and you could just
let me have five minutes,
explaining how much better I'm doing.
There's a court order against you...
five hundred feet. Listen to me!
...and I'll take that fucking
camera and I'm gonna break it over
your fuckin' head, then I'm gonna
come back and interview you about
what it's like to get that fuckin'
camera broken over your head!
Youwa..., what are you laughing about?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Go back to sleep. The
party's over. Show's over.
...this is not a reflection of
where I'm at. You can't... please,
you can't tell her any of this
You can't tell Nikki about this.
You need to pipe down.
Everything all right?
Who was at the door?
Who was that, Dad?
It was that kid with the camera.
Good luck. I gotta write this up.
Come on, don't write it up!
I don't want her to see this!
It's okay, everything is
okay. We're fine, thank you,
we appreciate it. Thank you.
Hey!
What the hell?
What happened to your face?
Weight lifting accident.
That sounds like bullshit.
Why'd you run by my house?
Did our little conversation
get you upset last night?
Hey, this is my route,
okay? Just back off.
This is my neighborhood.
You just ran by my house.
I like to run by myself, okay?
Me too.
Hey, I like to run alone! Will you stop?
What?
Okay? I'm running here! Me too!
Well then, why don't
you run somewhere else?
There's a fucking ton of roads to
run in! What are you trying to do?
I like this road. This
is my neighborhood.
Oh, come on, please!
Calm down, crazy.
Hey!
What the fuck?!
I'm married!
So am I!
What the fuck are you
doing? Your husband's dead!
Where is your wife?
You're crazy!
I'm not the one that just got
out of that hospital in Baltimore.
I'm not the big slut!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I was a big slut, but I'm not
anymore. There's always gonna be a
part of me that's sloppy and dirty,
but I like that, with all the other
parts of myself. Can you say
the same about yourself, fucker?!
Can you forgive? Are
you any good at that?
You seemed to have trouble last night.
Let me just set the record
straight about last night.
Hurting my mother was a mistake
and I hate myself for it,
and I hate my illness
and I want to control it.
My father, on the other
hand, had no trouble
slapping the shit out of me last
night, which I did not return
'cause I could've killed him and I
didn't. He's sixty-five years old.
You don't think I could've beat
the shit out of him? I mean...
He was scared for your mother
and you hurt him as well.
Yes, last night was a mess. Okay? And I
think he probably just tried to do his best.
Pat, you have to have a
strategy. I told you earlier.
You need to recognize these feelings
coming to you, otherwise you will be sent
back to Baltimore. So when you get
these feelings, you need to get to
a quieter place, and be at peace
with yourself, however you can.
Yeah, but that's easier said than done.
You have to do it. You
have no choice. Excelsior.
Yeah, Excelsior. Listen, I have
a letter I want you to give Nikki,
okay?
No.
Why?
Because you have a restraining
order.
What good are you, man?
Why did you have this
overwhelming urgency to see your
wedding video last night?
Oh, I don't know, because I'm
married and I haven't seen my wife
in eight and a half months?
Maybe you think that Nikki's not
around and Tiffany's an attractive
girl and if you get drawn towards
Tiffany, you will spoil your
chances of getting Nikki back to you?
Not bad, Doctor Jones. But I
don't think I'm gonna blow it
with Nikki because Tiffany's a slut.
Why is she a slut?
After the dinner at Ronnie's,
she said, quote, "We can go to the back house and
you can fuck me as long as we turn the lights out. "
Unquote. And she still
wears her wedding ring.
So she's a loyal,
married-to-a-dead-guy slut.
Maybe she just needs a friend and
she thought if she offers you sex,
it will be easier for you
to become friends with her.
She said she's not a whore anymore,
but she likes that part of herself
along with all the other parts
of herself and can I say the same?
Can you?
Is that...? You're asking me, you're
really asking me that question?
Yes.
With all my crazy sad shit?
What, are you fucking nuts?
Pat, the silver lining thing is
yours. I'm just giving back your
words to you. This "crazy sad
shit, " as you call it, made you a
happier, calmer person with a
beautiful positive philosophy of
going outdoors, working
out, and reading books.
No, not the books. You
said Nikki's friends with
Ronnie, Veronica and Tiffany. So
if you become friends with Tiffany,
Nikki will think that you're
a kind, generous, large-hearted
person, who helps people in need,
who is basically thriving. So if
you help Tiffany, it
will be good for you.
Hey!
How do you know when I run?
I wanted to clarify something.
I just want us to be friends.
Did you hear what I said?
Why are you giving me such a hard time?
No, I'm not giving you a hard time.
I don't know how to act with
you when you do this shit.
You wanna have dinner at this diner?
Pick me up at seven thirty.
Happy Halloween.
Hi.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'm gonna have a bowl
of your Raisin Bran.
Great!
Tea Be right back.
You look nice.
Thanks.
Raisin Bran. Milk.
Thank you.
You want to share this?
Why did you order Raisin Bran?
Why did you order tea?
Because you ordered Raisin Bran.
I ordered Raisin Bran because
I didn't want there to be any
mistaking this for a date.
It can still be a date
if you order Raisin Bran.
It's not a date. So how's your
thing going... your dancing thing?
It's good. How's your restraining order?
I wouldn't actually call the
restraining order "my thing, "
but getting back with Nikki is,
and I've been doing pretty well.
Except for a minor incident
at the doctor's office.
And the so-called
incident with the weights.
Yeah. That was a thing with
my parents. I wish I could just
explain it all in a letter to Nikki
because it was minor and I could
just explain it and let her
know that I'm actually not out of
control and that I'm
actually doing really well.
I can get a letter to Nikki. I
see her sometimes with my sister.
It would be so amazing if you
could get a letter to Nikki from me.
I'd have to hide it from Veronica.
She's not into breaking the law,
which this letter would
definitely be doing.
But you would do it?
I'd have to be careful. I'm
already on thin ice with my family,
you should hear how I lost my job.
How did you lose your job?
By... having sex with
everybody in the office.
Everybody?
I was very depressed after Tommy
died. It was a lot of people.
We don't have to talk about it.
Thanks.
How many were there?
Eleven.
Wow.
I know.
I'm not gonna talk about it anymore.
Okay.
Can I ask you one more question?
Were there any women?
Yes.
Really?
What was that like?
Hot.
Jesus Christ. Was it
like... older women,
a sexy teacher who wants to seduce you-
Made me sit on her lap
and do things? Yeah.
What? You sat on her lap?
Mm-hmm.
She told you what to do?
Oh... my God. Nikki hated
when I talked like this.
Made me feel like such a pervert.
Maybe we should change the subject.
I don't mind it.
You don't, do you.
No. But then people were getting
into fights in the parking lot at
work, and in the bathroom... and the
boss called me in to his office and
tried to pin it all on me. So I
accused him of harassment and then
they fired me, sent me home
and put me on some meds.
I get it. The song that
was playing when my wife...
was in the shower with
the history teacher...
I heard about that.
...it was my wedding song and
when I hear it, I go kinda crazy.
Sometimes I hear it when
it's not even playing.
Wow.
Yeah. So they put me on
medication, which I feel ashamed of.
Yeah.
So I know.
You do.
I just gotta get a strategy, you know?
Me too.
We'd better get back to the letter.
Yeah, let's get back to the letter.
What if you told Nikki when
Veronica was in the bathroom?
Yes. Yes, that could work. I love that.
Oh, my God, I'm gonna go home
and write the letter right now.
Can I at least finish my tea?
Wait, what?
My tea. Can I finish it?
Wait a minute. Did Veronica
tell Nikki about our dinner?
Why would she do that? Was it a test?
I kinda got that feeling, yeah.
Goddamn it. I knew it. It
was a test. How did I do?
I think I did pretty well.
Yeah, she said you were cool, basically.
"Basically"? Was I some
percentage not cool?
No, she said you were
cool, but you know.
No, I don't know.
Sort of how you are. It's fine, relax.
What do you mean? How am
I? What does that mean?
Sort of like me.
"Sort of like you"? I hope to
God she didn't tell Nikki that.
Why?
Because, it's just not right,
lumping you and I together,
I mean, it's just wrong.
And Nikki wouldn't like that.
Especially after all the
shit you just told me.
You think that I'm crazier than you.
Because, well, we're different, I mean-
Oh, my God. Ugh. You're killing me.
You know what? Forget
I offered to help you.
Forget the entire fucking
idea. 'Cause that must have been
fucking crazy because I am
so much crazier than you.
Keep your voice down.
I'm just the crazy slut
with a dead husband!
Forget it!
Shut the fuck up.
Fuck you!
You shut the fuck up!
Tiffany! Hey! Tiffany!
Slow down, Raisin Bran.
Hey, come on. Look, I don't
think you're crazy, all right?
Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
You told your therapist that you
were in a superior mental illness
category, didn't you?
What? Hey, calm down! Hey-
Just leave me alone!
Can I just explain myself, please?
I didn't want Nikki to think that
I was associated with that kind of
sexual behavior because I've never
done anything like that, okay?
You may not have experienced
the shit that I did.
But you loved hearing
about it, didn't you?
You are afraid to be alive, you're
afraid to live. You're a hypocrite.
You're a conformist. You're a liar.
I opened up to you and you judged me.
You are an asshole. You are an asshole!
Get off of me! Get off!
You're harassing me!
Hey, hey!
He's harassing me!
Get off!
Take it easy. Dude, relax.
He's harassing me!
Bro, get off of me.
Hey, hey, stop, stop. Stop, all right?
Hey, get off of me! Shut up, shut up.
Stop it.
Hey, hey, hey, get off me!
What are you doing? Come
on. What are you doing?
What are you doing to these kids?
Are you being a punk on
Halloween with these kids?
You wanna go back to Baltimore?
Is that what you wanna do?
I didn't, I didn't, I didn't-
It's the kids!
Honestly He didn't do
anything, it was all the kids.
Let's go, clear out,
nothing going on here.
Come on man what you gonna do about that song?
You gonna go your whole life scared of that song?
It's just a song.
Don't make it a monster.
Come on breath! There's no
song playing. There's no song.
That's it.
That's it. There you
go. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I took it too far.
Hey, is he messing with you?
No, no. No, this was just a
joke. This is a joke I started.
There's a restraining order on this guy.
I know, I have a stupid sense of humor.
That's not a good thing to do.
Well, I'm fucked up. What
can I tell you? I'm sorry.
You're Tommy's widow, right?
Yes, I'm Tommy's crazy whore widow,
minus the whore thing for the most part.
You're a funny girl. You
wanna get a drink sometime?
What'd I say? She doesn't,
she doesn't do that anymore.
I'm sorry about what
I said in the diner.
I know. I know you didn't mean it.
I didn't mean it at all.
I know, you say shit you
don't mean all the time.
All the time. I'll still give
your letter to Nikki, don't worry.
Wow. I really appreciate that, Tiffany.
I know you do.
You do? Yeah, sure. I'll see
you tomorrow? With the letter?
I'll bet I know what happened
if only one is missing.
Either Dolores or Pat needed an
envelope and one of 'em took it.
That's the only answer. No, no, no.
Dolores, somebody was in my study.
Who took one of my envelopes?
Somebody took an envelope.
Maybe we should call the FBI.
Don't make fun. This is serious.
What FBI? Come on, let's take a
look. I'll show you what this is.
I'm gonna just explain to you
something. I mean, you know what
I'm doing, honey. This
everything, like this.
I got this, it all corresponds.
Dad, I borrowed one of your envelopes.
I hope that's not a problem
No, it's not okay. It's
not okay. You gotta ask.
"Do not go in my study
or I will eat you!"
It's not funny, it's not funny.
What's everybody making
a joke out of this for?
Dolores, you are so beautiful!
Stop that! Hey, hey,
hey, stop, stop, stop!
Listen, a lot of envelopes go
in and out of my office every day
after games with a lot of cash in
'em. So show some respect for what I do.
Yeah, I know. I
saw two-seven-four.
I just wanted to tell you the number.
Thank you.
But the envelope was empty.
I'm sorry, you were sleeping.
I didn't want to wake you,
but I needed an envelope.
You didn't want to wake me?
He didn't want to wake me.
He doesn't have a problem complaining
about Ernest fucking Hemingway.
He doesn't have a problem
asking for his wedding video-
Be nice. It's game day! I'm
makin crabby snacks and homemades.
Yeah, come on, Dad, be nice. Come
on, she's making crabby snacks and
homemades. Come on, Dad!
What are you so up about?
He's very happy. I'm happy.
No, you're so up, up, up, up.
Isn't that a good thing?
You're just up, up, up.
I don't know what that is.
Are you taking the proper
dosage of your medication?
Am I taking the right
dose? Of course I am.
Okay. Taking a little
bit too many or something?
No, if I was taking that,
I'd be on the floor, Dad.
Just stay with us. Stay for the
game. Spend some family time.
Dad, I can't. Look, I'm ready to go.
Spend family time. Wait, you
mean OCD, superstitious time?
Come on, your dad needs
a winner. Help him out.
Come on. I can't. It's the Seahawks.
Put on the jersey and stay, please.
Please. It's important, please.
What are you up to,
Pat? Nothing, come on.
What's in the envelope?
Yeah, what are you doing?
What's in that envelope?
Guys, I'm beating the
song! I'm on the scoreboard!
I'm playing down field! I feel great!
Hey, how you doin'? Is Tiffany here?
What do you want with her?
Is that another creep? What do
you want, creep? Just beat it.
Whoa, no, no, no. No, I'm married.
Oh, great, a married
creep. I'm her friend.
We go running. Have you guys not
seen us? I took her to the diner.
She's not here.
Hi, guys. How's it going?
Hey. Is Tiffany home? Go away.
I know her. I know her,
we've dated. We still date.
What are you doing here? I've
called her, I've texted her.
I still haven't heard back.
We used to work together-
Just get the hell out of here...
I just wanted to give you
my card to give to her.
Another rude creep.
Listen to what he's saying.
Listen to what he's
saying. What's he saying?
He's saying you're being rude.
How am I being rude?
Oh, you know. You know. Come on.
Sometimes it's okay with girls like
this, they wanna have fun and sometimes -
- it's not because they got a
broken wing, and they're hurt,
and they're an easy target. And in
this case, in this particular case,
I think that wing is being fixed.
And you gotta make sure it gets
mended. And you're gettin' in the
way of that right now, okay?
Because she's sensitive and she's
smart, she's artistic. This is
a great girl and you gotta be
respectful of that. Come on.
Let me walk you down to your car.
You're a better guy than this.
I can see it in your
eyes. She just texted me!
Hey! Hey, wait a second! What
are you doing? What happened?
How come you weren't outside?
What the hell's going on?
I can't, I can't do it.
What do you mean, you can't
do it? You can't do what?
I can't give the letter to Nikki.
Tiffany, what are you talking
about? What do you mean you can't
give the letter to Nikki? Because
what am I getting in return?
What are you doing for me? You
said! You said if I wrote a letter,
you'd get it to Nikki. I
know. That was the set-up.
Because I do this time after time
after time, I do all this shit for
other people and then I wake up
and, and I'm empty, I have nothing!
What are you talking about? You
seem like you're a tough girl to
me. Why don't you just
do things on your own?
I always get myself in these
fucking situations. I give
everything to other people and
nobody ever, I never... I don't get
what I want, okay? I'm not my sister.
Alright, well, ask for
you. What can I do for you?
I can't do it. Tiffany,
what do you want me to do?
Think of something. There's this thing.
There's a thing, okay.
What kind of thing?
It's a thing, it's a thing.
It's a, it's a dance thing.
It's a dance thing, all right.
It's a competition thing at
the Benjamin Franklin Hotel.
Tommy would never do it with me
and I missed it every single year.
Well, Tommy's dead, so he's
not gonna fucking do it.
Would you please! I don't
have a filter when I talk.
Can we have one conversation
without you reminding me that my
goddamn husband is dead?
Yes, I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. Okay, I'm sorry.
But I can only do it if I have a
partner... and now I'm about to miss
it for another year.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, I'm not
gonna fuckin' dance with you.
What are you talking about?
What, your schedule is so busy?
"Grapes of Wrath" and watching
football with your dad?
Tiffany, I'm not gonna
do a dance with you.
All right, then I'm not
giving her your fucking letter.
Wait a second! But you
promised you would do this.
Think about it.
Well, I already did do
something for you, you know.
I took care of that jerkoff
that was in front of your house.
What? Jordie?
Let me ask you something. Do
you call him when you're lonely?
That encourages him,
Tiffany. You shouldn't do it.
Couldn't you say the
same about you and Nikki?
It's not at all like me and Nikki.
What are you talking about?
We're in love and we're married.
It's completely different.
How are you in love? Tell me
about that. The big Nikki love.
Tell me about it, I wanna understand it.
We have a very unconventional
chemistry, it makes people feel
awkward, but not me. She's the most
beautiful woman I've ever been with.
Wow. It's electric between us,
Okay? Yeah, we wanna change each other,
but that's normal, couples wanna do that,
I want her to stop dressing
like she dresses, I want her to
stop acting so superior to me,
okay? And she wanted me to lose
weight and stop my mood
swings, both of which I've done.
I mean, people fight. Couples fight.
We would fight, we wouldn't talk for a
couple weeks. That's normal. She
always wanted the best for me.
She wanted me to be passionate and
compassionate. And that's a good
thing. You know? I just, look,
I'm my best self today, and I think
she's her best self today, and our
love's gonna be fucking amazing.
It's gonna be amazing, and you're
gonna be amazing, and she's gonna
be amazing, and you're not gonna
be that guy that's gonna take
advantage of a situation without
offering to do something back.
So think about the dance thing.
Danny, you're out of the hospital?
And you're here on game day?
I'm out. It's official, man.
They didn't convert me to my
Mental Hygiene Law admission status
within two thirds of the maximum length
of my felony sentence, so I'm
out. They had to let me go.
I never understand what he's saying.
Okay, jailhouse lawyer, come on,
let's come back and sit down the
way you were before.
What a treat! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Dad's got you sitting here?
Oh, yeah. He calls me
"Jailhouse Lawyer. "
Hold the remote the way
you were holding it before.
Okay. And now you're holding the remote?
And it's working. Your dad's a genius.
Now sit up. And Danny's
the good luck charm?
Danny's from you. This is your
house, so it comes down to you.
You're the one. Yeah,
you're the one, Pat.
Superstition, Danny. I don't know.
Come sit down.
Don't disappear doing God knows
what with that Tiffany Maxwell.
Dad, Dad, Dad. She's my
friend. Why would you say that?
Oh, she's a mess. You gotta be
careful. She goes to a lot of therapy.
I go to a lot of therapy, Ronnie.
What are you trying to say?
I'm just saying
- Am I messed up?
Why don't you stop judging people?
You judge everybody. You're the one
who has a messed up marriage.
I'm just looking out for you, I'm just
looking out for you. She's unstable.
What's wrong with your marriage?
Nothing's wrong!
You should have seen when I was at his
house. It's like a circus over there.
Shh, shh. What are you talking
about? I'm not gonna hide this.
You need to deal with it.
Stop breaking my balls.
Oh! I got you an iPod.
Whoa! Is this for me?
Yeah. Well, that's my old iPod, but-
Oh, buddy, thank you.
That's so nice of you. Wow.
Thirty-two gigabytes. How many
songs is that? Seven thousand.
Oh, yeah, you got The Stranglers.
You love The Stranglers.
Oh, the Sex Pistols. The
Clash. Got some Clash.
Oh, "West Side Story. " Yeah, "West
Side Story. " It makes me peaceful.
"Maria, I just met a girl named
Maria... " Right, right, right.
And then when I'm angry, which
is a lot these days, I go to the
garage... Metallica... Megadeth.
I start fucking smashing shit.
You gotta get your marriage together.
I start breaking shit,
and I hurt my hand. And -
Ronnie, that's fucked up. Yeah,
but it makes me feel better.
It's like my therapy, you know?
When I'm with Nikki, I'm never
gonna do stuff like that...
Whoa, Nikki? What's
all this about Nikki?
Pan from the framed photo of Jake on
foyer wall, to Jake on the stairs above.
A restraining order is nothing to fool
with, bro. Holy shit, look at you! You
are fit! You look absolutely
amazing. You feel good?
How you doing, Jake? Good. You look
like Schwarzenegger in his prime.
Didn't I say you wouldn't recognize him?
So, listen, I'm sorry that I didn't
come see you down at the hospital.
You know how those places creep me
out, and the firm's been expanding.
I've been helping Pop with the
restaurant 'cause he needs to have
a legitimate business. He needs a
tax return. With all the money that
he's making with his bookmaking,
they're gonna come after him. And
then it looks like I'm making,
I'm gonna make partner at the firm.
Well, I don't even know what to say
to you anymore. You lost your wife,
I'm getting engaged, and I wanna
be able to tell you about those kind
of things. You lost your house, I'm
getting a new house. You lost your
job, things are going
great for me at the firm.
Maybe stop talking about all the
stuff that's good for you and bad
for him. Just, you know, leave
it alone. We're watching the game.
You know what, I'm just gonna,
I'm just gonna, I'm just gonna stop
talking. I'm gonna shut my mouth.
As my friend Danny would say I got
nothing but love for you, brother.
That's right. That's right.
That's nice. That's nice.
Well, thank God, finally.
DeSean Jackson. Yeah. Did it fit?
I wore it to Ronnie's for dinner.
Beautiful jersey. I love that jersey.
Veronica didn't like it.
Veronica hates the jersey.
Whatever you do, watch out for
that restraining order, okay?
Don't let Tiffany get you in trouble.
Pat, you're up to something, I know.
People like Tiffany, or Danny, or
me, maybe we know something that
you guys don't know, okay? Did
you ever think about that? Maybe we
understand something
because we're more-
We have a sixth sense. I mean,
everybody's got it. Everybody's
just not in touch with it.
Oh, no. How you doing, Pat? Jesus.
I guess his sixth sense forgot
to tell him the cops were coming.
I'm taking him back to the hospital.
What? No, no, he
passed his thing, right?
First of all, check with
the latest legal development.
Well, we got a call that they did
convert you to a Mental Hygiene Law
admission status by the
deadline of your sentence, so...
Wait a minute. Are you an Eagles
fan or are you not an Eagles fan?
I'm an Eagles fan.
Well then, what's the problem? He's
not goin' anywhere. Just let him
finish the game, that's all. The
handkerchief is working. We're
killing the Seahawks, twenty-seventen.
What's the matter with
you? Let him stay, please!
I don't know what the hell you're
talking about "the handkerchief".
And I'm glad that the Seahawks
are losing and we're winning, but I
gotta take Danny McDaniels back to
Baltimore, alright? He can contest
his case from Baltimore.
Not correct about the Mental
Hygiene Law. You're not correct.
Come on. You guys oughta
be ashamed of yourselves.
I used the insurance money to build
this. I designed it. All the floors
are hard oak. It has good
bounce for dancers. Wow.
I'm not that great of a dancer,
but who cares? It's therapy and it's
fun. And the walls are good
'cause I can play music really loud
without anybody hearing.
Where do you sleep?
Upstairs. It's a garage, I just
renovated it. You know, I was
thinking about putting
a ballet barre here.
When are you gonna give it to her?
What?
The letter to Nikki.
Probably tonight. Really?
Ronnie and Veronica and I
are gonna see her tonight.
Oh, I actually changed the first
paragraph. I did this thing about
Shakespeare and how it's very romantic-
Mm-hmm. -and that
maybe in the future if
she wanted to go dancing, I can be
able to do that because of all the
training that-No, that's
good, that's really good.
I assume you're a good teacher.
Yeah. I mean, I hope so.
Maybe you can teach us
both, you know what I mean?
And I also mentioned how generous
it is, what I'm doing for you.
Yeah. Mm-hmm. It's really generous.
You know, being of service.
Yeah. To your need. Uh-huh.
All right, let's start simple. Start
at that corner, walk towards me.
Walk across the room.
Can we do something else
besides the dance deal?
Are you fucking kidding me?
I'm good with a hammer. You want me
to fix something? A deal is a deal.
I know. Okay. I was just suggesting
that maybe there's a better scenario.
Why don't you walk
towards me like I'm Nikki.
And the only way to convey how much you've
missed me is by your walk. By your slow walk.
You can't talk. Only walk.
I'm not doing it. Do
it. No. That's stupid.
No walk, no letter. Walk to me like I'm
Nikki, come on. Do it. I'm Nikki. Come on.
You're not Nikki.
Don't look up until you're halfway here.
Yes. Do you feel that? That's emotion.
I don't feel anything.
Has anybody ever told
you how Tommy died?
We were married for three years and
five days, and I loved him. But
for the last couple months, I just
wasn't into sex at all. It just
felt like we were so different and
I was depressed. Some of that is
just me, some of it was he wanted
me to have kids and I have a hard
enough time taking care of myself.
I don't think that makes me a
criminal. Anyway one night after
dinner, he drove to Victoria's
Secret at King of Prussia Mall and
got some lingerie to get something
going. And on the way back, he
stopped on 76 to help a guy with
a flat tire and he got hit by a car
and killed. And the Victoria's
Secret box was still in the front
seat. That's a feeling.
Whoa! Slow down. What?
Your father wanted you to have this.
He wants me to have
- all this Eagles information.
It's his living. Um, tell Dad thanks.
Your father expects to
spend time with you, Pat.
Football stays out of this place,
so does "Lord of the Flies. "
Wait, wait, no, no, no, what are
you doing? I'm behind on my syllabus.
I don't give a fuck. What the
hell are you doing? Hey, hey!
Did you just throw that outside?
What? You're not gonna read that
shit on my time. I can tell you all
about the "Lord of the Flies. "
It's a bunch of boys on an island and
they have a conch... they have a
shell ... and whoever has the conch
has the power and they can talk.
And if you don't have the conch,
then you don't have the power. And
then there's a little chubby boy,
and they call him Piggy and they're
really mean, and then there's a
murder. I mean, humanity is just
nasty and there's no silver lining.
Wow. That was a great synopsis.
I still need to read it, though.
Who's that? What the...?
What are you doing here, man?
If one of your two supervising
physicians loses their license,
then your whole
ajudication is thrown out.
How'd you know we were here?
I went by your parents' house
looking for you and they told me
you was over here.
Danny, this is Tiffany.
Tiffany, this is Danny.
Hello. Pat told me about you. So
is the girl, that you wrote about?
Yeah. What? He wrote
about me? I'm "the girl"?
He wrote about you, all
right. What'd he say?
He said you guys was helping each
other out and you were nice and had
a mouth on you, that
you were mouthy, but-
Whoa, whoa, that's enough.
No, please, tell me more about
what he said in the letter.
Yeah, anything you wanna know,
I'll just tell you. It was nothing.
It was just a very general letter.
Cool. She's fine. She is
my friend with an "F. "
A capital "F. " For "friend. "
Hey, can I see what you guys are doing?
Yeah. Okay. That's it?
Why? What is it, what is it, what is it.
Can I say something? Do you mind? No.
You sure? Just say it. Say it.
No, please. I think Pat,
you should be facing Tiffany.
Let me show you, Pat, let me show
you what I mean. You gotta come at
her with a little bit more soul, man.
You should move more hips.
Just, just sort of come in,
Pat, come in like this. And...
Okay. Yeah. Can you move 'em a
little bit more? Yeah, that's it.
Move 'em a bit more.
You could turn around, too,
there's nothing wrong with that.
Yeah. You're pretty good. Mm, yeah.
Okay, we got it, we got it. Okay. Okay.
Come on, Pat, come on. A little
bit more soul. Black it up, Pat.
"Black it up"? You know
damn well what it means.
I got an idea. Come get
some, Pat. Come get some.
Shuffle back, shuffle back.
Girl, you gotta move your junk.
I gotta get out of here. I
gotta go see this girl, Tanya.
She lives on this side of town.
Yeah, go see Tanya. Good idea.
Okay, man, hey. I'm gonna be
there, man. I want you guys to win!
Bye! Excelsior, Pat!
Excelsior! That's my man. Lets go!
Pat. Patty.
Where have you been?
Huh?
We got a serious situation
on our hands, you know that.
We gotta beat the Giants if we
wanna have a chance of getting into
the division, any chance of playing
in the playoffs. Do you realize that?
I didn't realize that. Yeah,
that's the bind we're in.
I mean, I think it would be wise
if we spent father-son time, reading
about the Eagles, talking about
them, just to strengthen the good
luck thing that you're in.
Okay. Yeah? Right. Hmm?
I just wanted to, maybe I didn't,
spend enough time with you growing
up. I spent too much time with
your brother. It might have made you
feel worse about your behavior,
but I didn't know anything, I didn't
know how to handle it.
I mean, that's what
all this Eagles stuff
is about. It's about us, spending
time now. I wanna do everything I
can to help you get back on your
feet. That's the whole point. Yeah.
I wish you'd watch these games with me so
we could talk, we could get into things.
So would you, would
you just come downstairs
and talk to me and Randy now?
Randy, tell him what I'm doing.
He's betting everything on
the Giant game. Everything.
All the money that he needs for the
restaurant, he's betting on the Giant game.
Tell him why. Because he
believes in you. Is that true?
I believe in you, Patty. I believe
in you. I want you to know that.
So I'm gonna bet heavy on this game.
You understand? Yeah.
Heavy. I want you to go to
the game with your brother.
You want me to go to the game with Jake?
Of course I do. Does he want me to go?
Of course he wants you to go.
He told you that? He told me, yes.
Even with all his friends? With
all his friends. He trusts you.
He's not embarrassed?
No. I'd love to go to the game,
too, but as you know, I'm banned
from the stadium. 'Cause I'd love
to see us beat the Giants and take
a lot of money from this asshole.
Listen, personally, I think it's
a stupid bet. As a matter of fact,
I think it's ridiculous to bet all
that dough for the restaurant on a game.
Randy. I just hope you heard
what I said. It's like a
family business, it's our family
endeavor. We all stick together on this.
That's how it works. That's
a positive, positive vibe.
I made a commitment to Tiffany
about a project, and we have a very
important part of it that we
have to go over on Sunday, and
it's good for me, Dad. It's making
me disciplined and focused, and it's,
it's..., I never would've thought
this, but it's a good thing.
What is this thing you're doing?
Yeah, what is it? What
is this project, hon?
It's a dance thing, okay? There's
nothing more to it, Dad. I swear.
Listen, I need to ask you something.
Tomorrow can I spend half the day with
you and half the day at the Eagles game?
I'm gonna pretend that you
didn't just ask me that.
Why? These are the two days that
you have promised me and that we have
prepared to nail the big
move. It's not ready yet.
And we don't have a move yet.
I know, but my dad opened up to me
and it was really beautiful and I
wanna be of service to him, okay?
And he's worried that the juju from
the Eagles is being fucked up and
he's concerned that it's because
I'm spending time with you.
Oh, I messed up the Eagles' juju?
No, you're not messing up the juju,
but the juju is messed up because
I'm not with him during the games.
Guess what? What?
Nikki replied to your letter.
But you can't read it until after
you nail the big move. Go.
Tiff, I'm sorry. I can't do
anything else without reading
Nikki's letter, okay? It's just...,
it's in the back of my head.
We don't almost have it, all right?
I just hope you can
handle it. Thank you.
What was her energy
when she gave it to you?
She was intrigued, excited,
and a little scared.
She was scared? About
what? Did she tell you?
Try to stay positive.
I'm just gonna read it out loud,
okay? Because if she says anything
that's, you know, is
that too much to ask?
No.
I thought you were
gonna read it out loud.
Okay. Sorry.
"Dear Pat,
It was very emotional for
me to get your letter, as I'm
sure you can imagine, but I'm glad
you took the risk of discreetly
getting it to me through Tiffany.
This gives us a chance to communicate while I
keep the restraining order until I feel safe.
I must admit you sound terrific
and I'm happy that you are
feeling so positive and becoming a
more loving and caring man, which I
always knew you were.
I was moved to read
about 'Excelsior' and your
belief in happy endings. I am also
moved by your act of love to read
the books I have taught at the high
school. I'm sorry you find them so
negative, but I disagree. I think
they are great works of art that
reflect how hard life can be and
they can also help kids prepare
themselves for the hardness
of life. In spite of all these
positive developments, Pat, I
have to say if it's me reading the
signs, I need to see something to
prove you are ready to resume our
marriage. Otherwise I find myself
thinking that we might both be
better off moving on
with our lives separately.
Please don't react quickly
to this, but take
time to think about it.
I'm glad you're doing
so well. Love, Nikki. "
I think I'm done for today, okay?
She said to show her something,
Pat. This dance can be that
something. You would have never
done something like this in a
million years. It shows all kinds
of skills on so many different
levels: focus, collaboration,
discipline. It's romantic, like
I said it would be. It's for her.
Thanks for the letter.
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
Can I use your phone?
Is it an emergency?
Yeah, kind of. What kind of emergency?
Well, I'm just doing this project
with Tiffany and I wanted to tell
her I'm not gonna be on time.
Just don't make her an emergency,
that crazy girl, you know?
She's not crazy... I'll just borrow
Jake's phone. It's too bad you
can't come in to the stadium, but I
know you were kicked out, you know,
for beating everybody up. Guess
we're not that different, huh, Dad?
That a bad thing?
No, I think, it's a good thing.
Don't drink too much. Don't
hit anybody. You'll be fine.
Yeah. I'm solid.
This is my little brother Pat.
Hey, how you doing?
So, Pat, what's this I hear
about you just gettin' out?
Yeah, from the looney bin!
What the fuck?! I talked
to you about that already!
I told you guys
- It's all right.
Huh? No. It's alright.
He's a good dude! He's a good dude.
Oh, shit! The Asian invasion!
They're here every week! No!
Uh, Jake you better get your brother.
Cuckoo bird's takin' off. Doctor Patel!
Pat! Hey! What are you doing here?
You know, we must beat
the Giants, my brother.
I'm not supposed to be seeing you,
right? Outside the office?
Pat, Pat. That's illegal!
Pat, today I'm your brother in
green, not your therapist. I'm so
happy to see you. How
wonderful that you are here!
Hey, Jake this is Cliff.
This is my doctor, Cliff.
Look, two things. We gotta watch
that bubble screen for fuckin'
Manning in the backfield and
we gotta make sure we knock the
receivers on their ass
on the line of scrimmage.
You can say that again.
Those cocksuckers!
Okay, you know what? I don't have
her phone number. If you want, if
you really want, you can call
Veronica 'cause she does, but I
don't want to talk to Veronica.
Why don't you wanna talk to Veronica?
Because she brings me down,
man! She just brings me down.
You have to change. You're not
gonna throw the marriage away.
There's some kind of love
there. I know, I used to see it.
You guys have a beautiful thing
that got broken somewhere along the
line and you gotta fix
it like a chiropractor.
You gotta give it a
chiropractic adjustment.
Enough with awkwardness! I don't
wanna walk in your house and not be
able to say what I wanna say.
You're right, man. You're
right, you're right,
Eagles, baby! Yeah! Let's go!
What the fuck? What's that smell?
Nasty Indian curry! This is America,
baby! Go back to your country!
What, what's wrong? Hey!
Whoa, whoa, what's going on?
Stay back, Pat. Stay back.
Leave the fucking Indians
alone. Stay here, stay here!
I'm not gonna go anywhere.
Don't get in a fight!
I'm not gonna fight.
Hey, not my brother! Hey, hey, hey!
Break it up or you'll be arrested!
What'd you do? What happened? Dad-
What the fuck happened? Dad.
The birds lose, I lose a fuckin'
fortune, a fortune to Randy!
What the fuck did you
do?! You fucking lost it!
I thought you said you had
it together! You were solid!
I am solid. I was
solid at the game, Dad.
I'm solid, I'm solid now.
You fell apart! What are
you fucking talking about?!
Your son was trying to-
It's all fucking ruined
now. It's all ruined.
No, Dad! It's all fucking ruined
now! It's all fucking ruined!
No, Dad, Dad, Dad, don't!
It's all ruined, you
little fucking shit!
No, Dad! I didn't do a
fucking thing! Come on, Dad!
You loser! You loser!
I'm not a loser.
You fucking loser!
You ruined everything!
He was defending his brother!
You fucking idiot! You spike
the ball on the one yard line,
Who is this?! Who's this?!
We need to talk right now! When
you make a serious commitment to
somebody, it is not cool to not show up!
Wait a second, I tried to
call, my God, what's happening,
I called..., but I tried
to call you, Tiffany, I-
Oh, really? Yes.
I told you I was gonna split my
time with my dad and you, and my
dad was pulling me in one
direction. Doctor Patel, Ronnie-
Well, that sounds great, Pat.
That's great for all of them, but
all of them didn't make a commitment
to me in return for my help.
I'm Tiffany, by the way.
What is this craziness
with Tiffany Maxwell?
There's no craziness.
I told you who she was,
I was doing this thing with
her. We had a conversation!
She's fucking nuts! When you
started spending time with her,
it all fell apart. This is
the fucking reason right here.
You think I fucked up the
Eagles' juju, don't you?
Ever since, ever since he
was with you, ever since-
You think that I'm why today's happened?
That's right, you are
why today happened.
I'm the reason why today happened?
I think so. Let's talk about that.
Be my guest.
The first night that Pat and I met
at my sister's, the Eagles beat the
Forty Niners handily, forty to
twenty-six. The second time we got
together we went for a run and the
Phillies beat the Dodgers seven to
five in the NLCS.
She's right, Dad.
The next time we went for a run
the Eagles beat the Falcons, twenty-
seven to fourteen.
Wow.
The third time we got together we
had Raisin Bran in the diner and
the Phillies dominated Tampa Bay
in the fourth game of the World
Series, ten to two.
Oh, wow.
Let me think about that. Wait a minute.
Well, why don't you think about
when the Eagles beat the Seahawks,
fourteen to seven.
He was with you? He was
with me. We went for a run.
Really? That's crazy.
There have been no games since Pat
and I have been rehearsing every
day and if Pat had been with
me like he was supposed to, he
wouldn't have gotten in a fight,
he wouldn't be in trouble, maybe the
Eagles beat the New York Giants.
She's making a lot of sense, Pop.
That's all right on all counts.
Does anybody here happen to know
what the official motto of the
state of New York is on the official
seal of the State of New York?
Huh? Anybody? Do you? Do you know?
"Excelsior. " Look it up.
Yeah, "Excelsior. " Oh Pat.
Not that I give a fuck
about football or about your
superstitions, but if it's me
reading the signs, I don't send the
Eagles guy whose personal motto is
"Excelsior, " to a fucking Giants
game, especially when he's
already in a legal situation.
Unbelievable. Wow. How did
you know all that stuff?
I did my research. Well,
I gotta say, I'm impressed.
Thank you.
I gotta rethink this whole
thing. I didn't trust it before,
but I gotta say, now I do.
Oh, now you like her, Dad?
I have to say I do. Yup.
Patrizio, I feel terrible, you
know? You made the bet, I won a lot
of money, and now look, your
whole family is in turmoil.
Oh, fuck off, Randy. You love it.
You live for this shit. You've been
betting against my father for years.
Is that right?
You're twisting the knife
right now. You get off on it!
That's bullshit! That's
not true! Don't say that!
You get off on it! If not,
then prove it. Prove it.
Yeah, prove it, prove it!
How do you want me to prove
it? How's he gonna prove it?
By giving them the chance to win
back everything, double or nothing.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Double or nothing on the Bengals,
next week? Is that what you're saying?
Against the Cowboys.
That's your team isn't
it, Randy? That's his team!
I know who his team
is. When is the game?
December twenty-eight,
last game of the season.
Oh, my God. Same day
as the Benjamin Franklin
Pairs Open Freestyle Dance Competition.
Oh God. Randy, I thought
they were America's Team.
Don't you believe in America's Team?
Yeah, Randy, don't you
believe in America's Team?
Yeah, I believe in America's Team
but if I win that bet, I win your
book, you're out of action, you
get no restaurant, no nothing.
I like it. No. No, Patrizio-
I believe in the Eagles,
I believe in my son,
I'll take the action. I'll take it.
Dad! Patrizio, don't! It's toxic!
I have faith, I have faith.
Excelsior belongs in this house-
Dad
- ... not in the State of New York. In this house.
Dad, listen to me. I didn't know
that "Excelsior" was the state
motto of New York, okay?
I didn't know, either, but now I know.
I know, but listen to me, this
is toxic. Dad, Dad, Dad, this is
toxic, you shouldn't be doing
this, you shouldn't be doing-
Randy, what do you say...
Be quiet, shut up. You already
did enough. Randy, what do you say?
My birds, Benjamin Franklin's team
favored by one and a half points.
I'll give you three more.
Patrizio, stop it! And
Randy, don't you take the bet!
In fact, I'll give you
ten points. No, Dad! Dad!
Dad! You have to take
that bet on the Cowboys.
Dolores, would you stop him? Jesus!
How could you not take that bet?
Even with the ten points I give
you, that's an insane spread
to your advantage. Cowboys are
cowards. And I'll bet you're such
a coward, you won't take the ten.
Plus, are you listening, plus
whatever their score is at the
dance thing. What's that?
Tiffany, what's that?
What? No, no, no, no. You're
crazy to give away that many
points. That's ridiculous!
I won't take that!
However, wait a second. I
do like the idea of a parlay.
What? No parlay! No! No,
don't do it. Don't do it.
Pat, how do they run
this dance competition?
I mean, how do they
score it and everything?
I don't know, I don't know how they
fucking score! We're participating.
We're not, we're not a part of it.
There are people, this is a high-
end dance contest. I don't know.
Do not put it as part of the parlay,
Randy. Don't
- They go by the Philadelphia rules.
Each dancer is scored on a scale of
one to ten, ten being the highest.
You have to average
the four judges' scores.
Okay, score is from one to ten,
right? And you guys are how good?
We suck. We don't
suck. Pat's a beginner,
I'm okay, we're happy
just to be going there.
And how are the people
you're competing against?
They're good. Some of
them are professionals.
They're good? Better
than you? A lot better.
A lot better. So if I was to
say you only have to score five,
I would be really very generous, right?
No, no, that would be amazing if
we got five. Let's not get away-
Oh, come on, we can
get a five out of ten!
Gimme a break! Gimme me a break!
We can't get five! Give
'em a five. Give 'em a five.
We can do a five.
What are you talking about, Dad?
You haven't even seen us dance!
That's the parlay.
Will somebody please explain
to me the parlay? Please?
You gotta win two bets or you lose
the whole thing. For Pat Sr. to
win, the birds gotta beat the
Cowboys plus Pat and Tiffany gotta
get at least a five at the dance.
That's very, very manic indeed.
That's the parlay. Shake on it.
You know what? I'm not gonna
be a part of this. Randy,
Randy, you're a sickness. You're
a fucking sickness, Randy. I'm out.
Pat, you can't quit. I'm
not doing the dance. I'm out.
Pat, calm down. Thank
about it. See you later.
Pat, no. What are you doing?
Pat. I'm out.
Here we are again at the one yard
line. DeSean, snatching defeat from
the jaws of victory. There you go.
What does that even mean, Dad?
I'm not gonna make that, that, that
connection that you're making with
DeSean Jackson. It doesn't matter
anymore okay? Just because I
have the fucking jersey on...
I'm not gonna do it. I'm sorry.
You are not a stand up guy
right now. If it's me reading the
signs... if it's me reading the signs-
If it's you reading the signs?
You're reading the signs? Oh, okay.
Pat! You are not a stand up guy!
Pat! I told you not to push it.
Yeah, but he's gotta do this
thing. He can't be a quitter.
He cannot be a quitter.
You took that stupid parlay thing,
and now he won't do the dance and
it was very constructive
for him, and you ruined it.
There's only one way to get him to show.
What's that? Oh, what's that?
We have to tell him
Nikki's gonna be there.
We have to tell him that she's going.
But that's a lie! It's a white lie.
It's a white lie, what's that
matter? That's no big deal.
So it's a little lie.
There's no other way.
You know, we gotta leave a
trail of bread crumbs so that
he can live his life without ruining it.
No. I don't approve. You can't do it.
Well, you know, I didn't approve
when you called her and you told
her where he was running, so she
could ambush him. I didn't approve
of that, but you did it anyway, so
I'm doing this anyway. That's it.
We're gonna tell him Nikki'll be there.
You gotta be part of
it. We have to do it.
Aren't you nervous to be lying?
Yeah. A little bit.
But it's for the best.
"... but if it was me
reading the signs... "
That's it. Okay.
Hey.
Hey, what's up?
Sorry I'm late.
It's fine.
Come on, it's gonna be great.
Nikki's gonna be there. You know?
Everything's gonna come together.
It's what's meant to be. You okay?
Don't get wobbly on me. I'm not.
We have a dance to do. We have
a parlay. You gotta stay focused.
I'm focused. Okay, let's go.
Look at the dancers. You see them? Shit.
Hey, Randy, Jake. What do we got?
Dallas just tied with another
field goal, three-three.
I'm worried about the bet.
Don't worry about the bet.
Holy shit.
Is this "Dancing with the Stars"?
Well, you knew that. Maybe
you should've scouted 'em.
Look at those fucking dancers!
You can give me the money now, you know?
Patty, Patty, all we have to
do is we have to make a five.
That's all. You stay here
and watch the game with me.
The birds are better when Pat
is with me. We settled that.
Relax, we're gonna do fine, okay?
I'll see you in a little bit.
I'll see you up there, okay? Okay.
Hey, Pat, Tiffany!
Hey. What a glorious,
beautiful occasion, man.
Yeah, yeah. All right,
buddy, I'll see you. Alright.
Wish me luck, man.
Excelsior!
Wait, what's this?
What? I thought you were doing it.
Oh, I thought you were doing it.
We're doing a dance thing anyway
for God's sake.
I want you to remember everything.
I want you to remember all of the
good stuff that we have here.
Of course I do. Just check
in. I gotta go find Veronica.
Hi, good evening. Evening.
Check in? How many dancers are there?
What?! Nikki? Nikki.
Oh, Jesus.
What the fuck?
Sweetie, sweetie. Honey, calm down.
You're killing me. You're killing me!
Tiffany, please. She'll
see how well he's doing,
maybe she'll lift the restraining order.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Pat told me. He told me you
should never throw a marriage
out the window.
Pat did not say that.
He didn't say that.
He said it several times,
Tiffany, and this is his chance.
You gotta give him a chance.
Bartender! Bartender,
can I get a vodka, please?
So, you want another one? Sure.
So what do you do? I'm a
lawyer. Litigator, actually.
Oh, the arguing kind.
And the scores for Santos and Aguilar are: seven
point six, seven point three, seven point four, and
six point nine for an average
score of seven point three.
Three, two, one! Philadelphia beats Dallas!
They are on their way to the playoffs.
Where's Tiffany?
I don't know, Mom. Have you seen her?
You gotta find her. I know, Mom, I know.
Hey, WHAT are you doing? She's
fine, buddy, she's with me.
She's fine? Yeah.
Why don't you shut up, okay?
How many drinks have you had?
I've had two vodkas. Listen,
I don't know what choices
you've made, but you gotta deal with
it right now, okay? We're in this.
We're in what?
Next, Pat Solatano and Tiffany Maxwell.
You know, I used to think that
you were the best thing that ever
happened to me, but now I think
that you might maybe be the worst
thing and I'm sorry that I ever met you.
Good for you.
And the scores for Makarov and
Tretiak are: six point seven, eight
point one, seven point five and six
point five for an average score of
seven point two.
They were great and they
only got a seven point two.
This is a tough room.
Got it.
Up next, ladies and gentlemen please welcome
Pat Solatano, Jr. and Tiffany Maxwell.
Damn. Let's go, Patty! Come on, Pat!
Alright, let's see the scores
for Solatano and Maxwell.
We have a four point nine,
four eight, a four nine...
That's really too bad,
guys. That's a lot of fours.
...and and a five point four for an
average score of.. five point zero.
Sorry about that, guys.
Dad, Dad, did the Eagles win?
The Eagles won, forty-four-six!
They won, forty- four-six!
Come on!
Why are they so excited about a five?
How are you? You okay? Good. How are
you? I'm really good. Yeah, thanks.
You looked really
happy out there. Did I?
Yeah. Yeah, who'd have thought, dancing?
You look incredible. Thank you.
You lost a lot of weight. I've
been reading your books and,
I have a positive attitude. I'm
on medication, I'm in therapy.
Where's Tiffany? She left.
What do you mean, she left?
She left. What do you
think! Where is she?
Let me tell you, I know you
don't wanna listen to your father,
I didn't listen to mine but
I'm telling you, you gotta pay
attention to the signs. When life
reaches out with a moment like
this, it's a sin if you don't reach
back. I'm telling you, it's a sin
if you don't reach back, and it'll
haunt you for the rest of your days
like a curse. You're facing a big
challenge in your life right now,
at this very moment, right here.
That girl loves you, she really
loves you. And I don't know if
Nikki ever did, but she sure as
hell doesn't love you right now.
I'm telling you, don't fuck this up.
I love you, Dad.
Hey! Would you just leave me alone?!
Wait a second! I have one more
letter for you to read, okay?
What the fuck is the matter with
you? Give it to her yourself!
Let me say something. You don't
ever have to see me again if you
just read it, alright?
This is so fucked up.
Yeah, just read it.
"Dear Tiffany...
"... I know you wrote the letter.
The only way you could
meet my crazy... "
"... was by doing something
crazy yourself. Thank you.
I love you.
I knew it the minute I met you.
I'm sorry it took so long for me to
catch up. I just got stuck. Pat. "
I wrote that a week ago.
You wrote that a week ago? Yes, I did.
You let me lie to you for a
week? I was trying to be romantic.
You love me? Yeah, I do.
Okay.
The world will break your heart ten
ways to Sunday, that's guaranteed.
And I can't begin to explain that-
-or the craziness inside myself and
everybody else, but guess what?
Sunday is my favorite day again.
I think of everything everyone did for
me and I feel like... a very lucky guy.
We have to beat the Vikings by
three. I'm givin' you a six, which
is very generous after the beating
you just took. So what are we
doin', what are we talkin' about here?
I'd like to do another parlay if we
make it to the next round, that's all.
But we are gonna make it to the
next round. We're gonna beat...
No, that was me that
did that. No that was me.
That was me. I played the Jack.
So you put the bread crumbs, the
garlic in the steak and you
roll it up with the toothpicks?
Yeah. For, oh, maybe three hours, plus.
Everything's good, everything's
good, yeah. I got you, you're all
down. No, Randy, he's
complaining. You know he lost a lot
of money. He's moaning and
groaning. The restaurant's
happening because of
Randy, so everything's good.
Created By: Usman Title: Silver inings
Playbook http:/www. facebook. com/usman. zubair5