CITY LIGHTS
"To the people of this city we donate this
monument; 'Peace and Prosperity'."
Afternoon.
"Did you pick it up, sir?"
"Wait for your change, sir."
Evening.
"Grandma."
Night.
"Tomorrow the birds will sing."
"Be brave! Face life!"
"No, I'll end it all!"
"I'm cured. You're
my friend for life."
"We'll go home and
get warmed up."
"Any news?"
"Only that your wife
sent for her baggage, sir."
"Good!"
"Here's to our friendship --"
"No, I'll live!"
"James - the Rolls-Royce.
We'll burn up the town!"
Early morning;
homeward bound.
"Be careful how
you're driving."
"Am I driving?"
"I like your car."
"Then keep it, it's yours."
"Where's my friend?"
"Let him in, he's my guest!"
"Let's buy some flowers."
"Here's ten dollars."
"I haven't any change, sir."
"James!"
"Take these inside;
I'll be right back."
"Thank you for your kindness, sir."
"May I see you home again?"
"Whenever you wish, sir."
The sober dawn
awakens a different man.
"I'm out to everybody!"
"Whoever he is,
get rid of him!"
"-- and then he brought me
home in his car."
"He must be wealthy."
"Yes, but he's more than that."
That afternoon.
"My friend!"
"Come on home, I'll
give you a swell party."
The party.
The morning after.
"I'm sailing at noon, so hurry!"
"She has a fever and
needs careful attention."
Determined to help
the girl, he found work.
FINAL NOTICE
Madam: You are owing $22.00 rent.
Unless paid by tomorrow morning,
we shall take possession.
"Grandma, he's coming today!"
"Grandma, what's wrong?"
"Grandma, I wish you'd meet him;
you're never here when he calls."
Lunch time.
"Have you seen the soap?"
"Be back on time!"
"To play the part of a gentleman
without the millionaire was difficult,
but he did his best."
VIENNA DOCTOR HAS
CURE FOR BLINDNESS
Thousands journey from
all parts of the world.
FREE OPERATION FOR POOR
Miraculous Work Of Surgeon
Astounds Medical Profession
"Wonderful! Then I'll
be able to see you."
"For me? Read it please."
FINAL NOTICE
Madam: You are owing $22.00 rent.
Unless paid by tomorrow morning,
we shall take possession.
"Now don't worry, I'll pay it
the first thing in the morning."
Late.
"You're late for the last time!"
"Get out!!!"
"Do you want to make
some easy money?"
That night.
"Remember, we split fifty-fifty;
and you promise you won't hurt me."
"Be careful, the boss
might hear us."
TELEGRAM
EDDIE MASON
MAIN STREET ARENA
GET OUT OF TOWN
THE COPS ARE AFTER YOU
JIM
"I've got to beat it; boss!"
"Do you want to fight
for a fifty dollar purse?"
Winner take all.
"You'll fight him!"
"That's my lucky
rabbit's foot."
"Let's take it easy and
we'll split fifty-fifty."
"Winner take all!"
Still hoping to get
money for the girl,
he wandered the city.
Back from Europe.
"Now don't worry about
the girl, I'll take care of her."
"Will a thousand
dollars be enough?"
"Police! Help!!"
"He has been robbed,
search that man!"
"Where did you get this money?"
"Tell him you gave
me that money."
"Who is this man?"
"This is for the rent."
"And this is for your eyes."
"I must be going."
"How can I ever thank you?"
"You're not going away?"
"For awhile."
"But you're coming back!"
Autumn.
"I'd like to order
some flowers."
"Why, what's the
matter, child?"
"Nothing, only I
thought he had returned."
"I've made a conquest!"
"You?"
"You can see now?"
"Yes, I can see now."
THE END