Hold it!
Ten. 20.
Did you hear about
Mrs Mason's little Willy?
Sent him to school and found him
buried ten foot deep in a snowdrift.
- How did they get him out?
- Brought the fire engine round.
Put the hose pipe in, pumped it
backwards and sucked him out.
(piano starts)
(laughter)
- Perfect bull's-eye.
I want a room and a fire.
- Jenny?
- Hello?
There's a gent here
what wants a room and a fire.
What, a room?
I said a room.
We ain't got none ready,
not at this time of year.
We don't usually have folks stopping,
except in the summer.
You can get one ready.
Certainly, sir. Millie!
Yes?
- I want a private sitting room, too.
- Certainly, sir.
Will you come through, sir? This way, sir.
It's the coldest winter
we've had down here for years.
They put all the sheep and the cows in
for a fortnight now.
Poor things. They can't get
a blade of green grass.
You may be near-sighted,
but you can't be deaf-and-dumb as well.
Could I take your coat and hat, sir,
and give 'em a nice dry in the kitchen?
No.
- I prefer to keep them on.
- Very good, sir.
The room will be warm soon.
I've got some luggage at the station.
How can I have it sent?
I'll get it dropped over tomorrow.
Are you staying a bit?
Yes.
- Is there no way of getting it tonight?
- Not tonight, sir.
Very well.
Bring me some food.
Right away, sir.
If you ask me,
he's a criminal flying from justice.
Go on. He's snow-blind, that's what he is.
Has to wear goggles to save his eyes.
Anyway, you be careful,
and lock your money up.
A bottle of Bass, Herbert.
Here you are, dear.
I hope he'll be a bit more
communicative this time.
Your supper's there.
Is there a key to that door?
A key, sir? Ooh, I haven't ever seen one.
I don't think there was one
when we came here.
I want to be left alone, and undisturbed.
I'll see that no one disturbs you, sir.
The mustard, ma'am.
You'll be the death of me
with your slowness.
You let me take his supper in
and forget the mustard.
And him wanting to be left alone!
There she goes again.
I told you not to disturb me.
It's only the mustard, sir. I forgot it.
- I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
Have you been motoring
on them slippery roads, sir?
You can take my overcoat and dry it.
Very good, sir.
- Leave the hat.
- Yes, sir.
Bandages, right up to the top of his head.
All round his ears.
- Any blood?
- No. No blood.
Looks like some kind of 'orrible accident.
Bumped his head
on the prison wall gettin' over.
Father.
I wish you'd leave me alone,
Flora, when I'm working.
I can't bear it. We've got to do something.
- Do something? What about?
- About Jack.
He'll come back. Don't you worry.
Father, please put
that horrid thing down and listen.
It's nearly a month now, without a word.
But the note he left was quite clear.
He said we might not hear for a while.
It's good to go away when
you're finishing a difficult experiment.
- What kind of experiment is it, Father?
- Something of his own.
I had a terrible feeling last night.
I felt he was in desperate trouble.
Hello, Kemp. Flora's worried about Griffin.
I don't wonder. I should have thought
at least he could drop a line.
It's a queer thing.
It certainly is,
considering he was in your employ.
He had my permission to carry out
his own experiments in his spare time.
And to clear off when he liked?
What does it matter, if he's in trouble?
I've got the car outside.
It'll give you a rest to come for a run.
Do you think there are
any papers in his room?
Surely he must have arranged where
he was going. There may be letters.
He left burnt papers
in his fireplace, that's all.
He was so strange those last few days
before he went. So excited and strung up.
Yet he wouldn't say a word to explain.
I've never seen him like it before.
He was always so keen
to tell me about his experiments.
He meddled in things
men should leave alone.
Your father's a scientist. He's discovered
more about preserving food than anyone.
Jack and I were employed to help him.
That's a plain, straightforward job.
It's not romantic, but it saves
hundreds of deaths and stomachaches.
What things should men leave alone?
He worked in secret. He kept a lot of stuff
locked in a big cupboard in his laboratory.
He never opened it until he'd barred
the door and drawn the blinds.
Straightforward scientists have no need
for barred doors and drawn blinds.
He cares nothing for you, Flora.
He'll never care about anything
but test tubes and chemicals.
How can he go away like this
without a word?
Flora, dear. Please, darling,
let me tell you how I feel.
- I can't work or sleep until I know.
- Leave me alone! How can you?
There's a way back, you fool.
There must be a way back.
- What is it?
- Your luncheon.
- Take it away.
- You don't want it cold, do you?
Do you suppose that I'm going to carry
trays backwards and forwards all day?
Luncheon's at one, and it's one now!
Get out!
He's not gonna stay under this roof,
not another hour!
Crashed the tray out of me hand,
and swore at me.
Turns my best sitting room
into a chemist's shop.
Spillages on the carpets!
And him a week behind with his money!
Go and tell him if he ain't
packed up and gone in half an hour,
we'll have the law in to turn him out.
And take him his bill.
Three pounds ten.
And see you get it before you come out.
Go on.
Let's leave him a bit, Jenny,
till he cools off.
Go on, do it now. Him and his goggles
and his chemist's shop!
If you don't kick him out, I'm clearing out
myself, and I mean it this time!
And a whole day's work ruined
by a foolish, ignorant woman!
There must be a way back.
- God knows there's a way back.
If only they'd leave me alone.
Look 'ere, mister,
we can't have this no more.
You broke the wife's best china, you're
behind with the rent. Pack up and go.
I'm expecting some money, Mr Hall.
I'll pay you directly it comes.
You said that last week.
I came here for quiet and secrecy.
I'm carrying out a difficult experiment.
I must be left alone. It's vital. It's life
and death that I should be left alone.
- You don't understand.
- I understand all right.
You don't pay. And what's more,
you're driving folks away from our house.
Mr Hall, I've had a serious accident.
It's disfigured me, affected my eyes.
I mean the way you carry on, throwing
things about on the carpets and swearing.
- It's no good, mister, you've got to go.
- I implore you to let me stay. I beg of you.
The wife says if you don't go, she is,
so it's gotta be you.
Come on. I'll help you
to get this stuff packed up.
Leave that alone and get out of here!
Look here! Is this my house or yours?
What are you doing?
Help! Help! Police!
He's a raving lunatic!
Go and get a policeman.
Please don't cry, now.
- He's all right.
Oh, shut up!
- Come on, Jaffers!
- Here, what's all this?
It's the stranger with the goggles.
He's gone mad. He's assaulted Mrs Hall
and nearly killed her husband.
Oh.
- Where is he?
- He's upstairs in the sitting room.
He's in there, in the sitting room.
He's homicidal.
Oh.
Let that there.
Here, keep back, you kids there.
- Here, what's all this?
- Keep back there.
Keep back, me?
Do you know who you're talking to?
I give you a last chance
to leave me alone.
Give me a last chance? You've committed
assault, that's what you've done,
and you can come along
to the station with me.
Come along, now. Come quietly, unless
you want me to put the handcuffs on.
Stop where you are.
You don't know what you're doing.
I know what I'm doing all right. Come on.
- Get hold of him.
- Lock him up!
All right, you fools.
You've brought it on yourselves.
Everything would have come right
if you'd only left me alone.
You've driven me near madness
with your peering through the keyholes
and gaping through the curtains.
And now you'll suffer for it!
You're crazy to know who I am,
aren't you?
All right! I'll show you!
There's a souvenir for you.
And one for you.
I'll show you who I am and what I am.
Look. He's all eaten away.
How do you like that, eh?
- It was 'orrible.
- What's wrong?
- Jaffers, what do you think?
- He's invisible, that's what's the matter.
If he gets the rest of them clothes off,
we'll never catch him in a thousand years.
Come on.
They've asked for it,
the country bumpkins.
This'll give them a bit of a shock.
Something to write home about.
A nice bedtime story for the kids,
too, if they want it.
- Put the handcuffs on.
- How can I handcuff a bloomin' shirt?
- Quick! Get hold of him!
Ow!
Are you satisfied now, you fools?
It's easy, really, if you're clever.
A few chemicals mixed together,
that's all,
and flesh and blood and bone
just fade away.
A little of this injected under the skin
of the arm every day for a month.
An invisible man can rule the world.
Nobody will see him come,
nobody will see him go.
He can hear every secret.
He can rob and kill!
Not if he can't get no further
than this room, he won't.
Here, shut that door.
- You'd better come along quietly.
Look out! Mind that window!
You think I'd escape
like a common criminal?
You need a lesson.
I think I'll throttle you.
Let go of me!
Let go!
You must be made to understand
what I can do.
Hey, look out!
Hey, whoa!
Hey, hey!
Look out! Get indoors!
Everybody get indoors!
I'm afraid I need this bicycle. Ha-ha!
He stole me bike!
Here's your blooming bicycle.
You can do what you like with it.
How's that for a hairbrush, George Henry?
Good morning, Grandfather.
How do you do?
We'll do our part.
Mama, give me the diamonds!
On the gospel, it's the truth.
He tried to strangle me, sir.
Where are you speaking from, Jaffers?
Lion's Head inn, eh?
Did you say an invisible man?
Well, look here, you put
more water in it next time!
He won't believe me. You tell him.
Mr Hall speaking.
The constable's telling the truth all right.
Not the slightest clue.
I didn't expect there would be.
That's where the clues are.
He wasn't leaving anything to chance.
Griffin was never the man for secrets.
He came to me with everything.
He kept a lot of stuff locked in here.
I came in one evening
when he wasn't expecting me.
He was by this cupboard.
It was full of instruments.
When he saw me, he slammed the door
and turned the key.
You say he brought
a packing case up here?
The night before he disappeared. I heard
him hammering, packing everything up.
- Here's something, Kemp.
- What is it?
- Bad news?
- It's only a rough note.
A list of chemicals,
and the last on the list is monocane.
Monocane? What is monocane?
- Monocane's a terrible drug.
- I never heard of it.
You wouldn't, Kemp. It's never used now.
I didn't know it was even made.
It's a drug that's made from
a flower that's grown in India.
It draws colour
from everything it touches.
Years ago they tried it for bleaching cloth.
They gave it up because
it destroyed the material.
- That doesn't sound very terrible.
- I know, but it does something else.
It was tried out on some poor animal -
a dog, I believe.
It was injected under the skin,
and it turned the dog dead white,
like a marble statue.
- Is that so?
- Yes, and it also sent it raving mad.
You surely don't think...?
I only pray to God that Griffin hasn't
been meddling with this ghastly stuff.
- He'd never touch a thing with madness.
- He might not know.
I found that experiment
in an old German book just by chance.
The English books only describe
the bleaching power.
- What are we going to do?
- Tell the police that Griffin's disappeared.
But only that he's disappeared.
I put you on your honour, Kemp,
not to breathe a word of this to anyone.
- Shall I go with you?
- It's all right, Kemp.
I'll go tonight,
when Inspector Lane's on duty.
I'll run along back home, then.
- Good night.
- Good night, Kemp.
This is the national station
broadcasting this evening's news.
Remarkable story from country village.
Police and doctors
are investigating a story
told this afternoon by
the people of the village of lping.
A mysterious disease has broken out
infecting many of the inhabitants.
It takes the form of a delusion that
an invisible man is living among them.
Several people have been
seriously injured,
probably through fighting, in their belief
that their opponent is an invisible man.
The whole village is
in a state of panic and everyone...
Everyone deserves the fate
that's coming to them.
Panic, death, things worse than death.
Don't be afraid, Kemp.
It's me - Griffin. Jack Griffin.
How are you, my friend?
Brrr! I'm frozen with cold.
Dead tired. Thank God for a fire.
Sit down, you fool.
Let's have a decent fire.
D'you hear me? Sit down, unless
you want me to knock your brains out.
Sit down!
I want you to listen carefully, Kemp.
I've been through hell today.
I want food and sleep, but before
we sleep, there's work to do.
May I have a cigarette?
You always were
a dirty little coward, Kemp.
You're frightened
out of your wits, aren't you?
Oh, it's no good talking like this.
Have you got a good long
surgical bandage?
Good. And a pair of dark glasses?
Right. Go and get them, at once.
Let me have a dressing gown
and pyjamas and a pair of gloves.
You'll feel better
if you can see me, won't you?
Come on. You've no time to waste.
You'll find some pyjamas in that room.
Here are the gloves and bandages.
- I'll bring you the glasses.
- Thank you. Don't be long.
Put them on the table.
Now go down and draw the blinds
in your sitting room.
- Are we alone in the house?
- Yes.
Good. All right, go now. If you raise
a finger against me, you're a dead man.
I'm strong and I'll strangle you.
Understand? Wait for me downstairs.
The sitting room, I said, Kemp.
And if you try and escape by the window,
I shall follow you,
and no one in the world can save you.
Here comes the inspector now.
Get up.
Nice fool you've made of me.
I've got reports for ten miles around.
Not a sign of anything.
I'll tell you what I think
of your invisible man: It's a hoax.
Good business for the saloon bar,
eh, Mr Hall?
Suppose I'd break my neck
to sell a gallon of beer?
I'll have an inquiry right now.
Bring in everybody who thinks
they saw or heard anything.
I'll get to the bottom of this.
Get those tables together.
Now, Kemp.
Now then, we can talk as man to man.
Sit down.
One day I'll tell you everything.
There's no time now.
I began five years ago in secret,
working all night, every night,
right into the dawn.
A thousand experiments,
a thousand failures,
and then at last the great, wonderful day.
- But, Griffin, it's ghastly!
- The great, wonderful day.
The last little mixture of drugs.
I couldn't stay here any longer, Kemp.
I couldn't let you see me
slowly fading away.
So I packed up and went to a village
for secrecy and quiet,
to finish the experiment
and complete the antidote,
the way back to visible man again.
I meant to come back
just as I was when you saw me last.
But the fools wouldn't let me work
in peace. I had to teach them a lesson.
But why? Why do it, Griffin?
Just a scientific experiment at first.
That's all. To do something
no other man in the world had done.
But there's more to it than that, Kemp.
I know now.
It came to me suddenly. The drugs I took
seemed to light up my brain.
Suddenly I realised the power I held,
the power to rule,
to make the world grovel at my feet.
We'll soon put the world right now, Kemp.
You and I.
I? You mean...?
I must have a partner, Kemp,
a visible partner,
to help me in the little things.
You're my partner, Kemp.
We'll begin with a reign of terror.
A few murders here and there.
Murders of great men,
murders of little men,
just to show we make no distinction.
We might even wreck a train or two.
Just these fingers
round a signalman's throat, that's all.
Griffin, for heaven's sake!
- Do you want me to take these off?
- No, no.
Very well, then.
We'll make our plans tomorrow.
Tonight we have a small job to do.
Go and get your car out, Kemp.
- Where are we going?
- To the village I left this morning.
I came away without my notebooks. They
contain all the results of my experiments.
- But it's past eight o'clock.
- It's only 15 miles.
Go now. Quickly.
Take a bag with you for the books.
Put a warm rug in the car. It's cold outside
when you have to go about naked.
- All ready?
- Yes.
Come on! Get in!
- Where's that rug?
- In the back.
I'm frozen. It's cold enough
to freeze the icicles off an Eskimo.
We'll stop in a lane near the inn. I'll give
you the books through the window.
- They'll have a guard.
- What can a guard do, you fool?
I must have those books, Kemp. I'll work
in your laboratory till I find the antidote.
Sometimes I'll make you invisible,
give me a rest.
I was walking home to me lunch, sir,
when all of a sudden something takes
hold of me hat and throws it in the pond.
- How many drinks did you have?
- Only a couple, sir, that's all.
A couple of drinks and a gust of wind.
So much for you.
Now then, about the bicycle.
Where's the owner of the bicycle?
Here, sir.
It was pulled clean out of me hands, sir.
Then it pedalled off
down the street, all by itself.
Stop here.
Come on, get out.
Take your bag and walk down the street.
I'll guide you.
Wait outside the window
till the books come out.
Put them in your bag and come back
to the car. Then wait for me.
Don't stare at me, you fool.
Look in front of you.
Come on! Get a move on.
Here we are, Kemp, in here.
Here. Stroll up and down
as though you were waiting for someone.
Watch for that window to open.
Griffin? Griffin? Are you there?
- Who's that, opened that door?
- It's them boys again, sir.
Here, you leave this door alone!
It's private, see!
- Aw, we never touched it.
- Yes, you did.
Go on, hop it. Go on!
There you are, Kemp.
Lies from beginning to end!
I've a good mind to prosecute
all of you for conspiracy.
I shall announce this evening
that the whole thing's a hoax,
and you'll be the laughing stock
of the entire country.
He's here! The invisible man!
Don't leave me! Wait for me!
A hoax, is it? All a hoax?
All a hoax?
There.
All right. Off you go.
Go for your life, too.
- Did you hear shouting and screaming?
- What was that screaming?
I had to take some exercise to keep warm.
I killed a stupid policeman.
Smashed his head in.
We start in earnest
tomorrow morning, Kemp.
- Good evening, Doctor.
- Is Inspector Lane at the station?
- I want a word with him.
- Yes, sir.
Extra special!
Invisible man slays policeman!
- Nasty business, this.
- It's a conjuring trick, that's what it is.
I saw a fella
make a peanut disappear once.
There are one or two things
you must understand, Kemp.
I must always remain in hiding
for an hour after meals.
The food is visible inside me
until it is digested.
I can only work on fine, clear days.
If I work in the rain, the water
can be seen on my head and shoulders.
In a fog you can see me, like a bubble.
In smoky cities the soot settles on me
until you can see a dark outline.
You must always be near at hand
to wipe off my feet.
Even dirt between my fingernails
would give me away.
It is difficult at first to walk down stairs.
We are so accustomed
to watching our feet.
But these are trivial difficulties. We shall
find ways of defeating everything.
You will sleep in the room opposite.
And bring me some more food
at eight o'clock.
Good night.
Now you will understand my plans.
You're in charge of all country
to the east, Thompson,
- for 20 miles to the north of the road.
- Very good, sir.
Neville, you take
the opposite section to the south.
Stoland, you take charge
of the search in the hills.
And, Hogan, you take all the villages,
out to the river.
Now, we shall comb the country
for 20 miles round.
We've got a terrible responsibility.
He's mad and he's invisible.
He may be standing beside us now.
But he's human and we shall get him.
We shall have 1,000 men out tonight.
Tomorrow we shall have
10,000 volunteers to help them.
There's a broadcast warning
going out at 10.30.
Now, at all costs,
we must avoid a panic spreading.
Get word to your districts,
and send me a note of your headquarters.
And remember, he'll leave tracks,
even if he himself is invisible.
I must interrupt the music for a moment.
I have an urgent message from the police.
Earlier this evening we broadcast
a report of an invisible man.
The report has now been confirmed.
It appears that an unknown man
by scientific means
has made himself invisible.
He has attacked and killed
a police inspector and is now at large.
The chief of police appeals
to the public for help and assistance.
Those willing to cooperate are requested
to report tomorrow to their local station.
The invisible man works without clothing.
He will have to seek shelter.
You're requested to lock
every door and window,
and every outbuilding
he may use to hide in.
The police will be glad of any suggestions
that will help in capturing the fugitive.
Remember, he's solid but cannot be seen.
A reward of 1,000
will be given to any person
whose information leads to his capture.
The police appeal
to the public to keep calm
and to admit uniformed
search parties to all property.
- I've got the doors padlocked.
- I'll keep him out!
Hello.
Hello. Get me Esher, 1021.
Hello?
Doctor, it's something ghastly.
It's Griffin. He's come back.
He's the invisible man.
He's asleep in my room.
He's mad, a raving lunatic.
He's killed a man tonight.
Listen to me, Kemp.
No one but you and I know that it's Griffin.
- I shall come in the morning.
- You must come now. I can't bear it!
If I come now,
he'll be suspicious and escape.
You must keep him calm and quiet
for tonight. I trust you, Kemp.
- Who was that, Father?
- It was Kemp.
It was about Jack. I know it.
What is it? Tell me.
- Leave me alone, Flora, please.
- I'm not afraid. Tell me.
Jack Griffin's come back.
He's at Dr Kemp's house now.
Jack Griffin's the invisible man.
Is that the police?
Was that 1,000 reward all right?
Well, listen, I've got a way to catch him.
The paper says he threw ink
at the man he killed.
Get your own back and squirt ink about
with a hose pipe till you hit him.
The ink'll stick on him.
Then you can shoot him.
Is that the police? I wanna tell you
how to catch the invisible man.
The paper says it's going to be
frosty in a day or two.
Well, you watch out when there's frost,
see, then you can see his breath.
Police, quickly.
Is this the police? This is Dr Kemp.
The invisible man is in my house,
asleep upstairs. Come at once. Hurry!
But, listen, Doctor,
I've only got five men here.
I'd want 100 to surround the house.
Yes, all right. I'll send them up
as soon as possible.
Leave it to me and Kemp. We shall work
day and night to undo this experiment.
- You must let me go to him.
- Only when he's well again.
No, now. I can do far more
with Jack than you or Dr Kemp.
But, Flora, he's not normal.
His mind's unhinged. At present he's mad.
I can persuade him to help you.
You're powerless unless he does.
- I'll be ready in five minutes.
- Wait till the morning.
It's life or death, Father. You know that.
- I'll go alone, then.
- Flora.
Who's that? Who's that?
Unlock the door, Kemp.
Let me in.
- What are you doing here, Kemp?
- I couldn't sleep.
I had to get up and come down.
- Why did you lock the door?
- I... I was afraid.
Wouldn't you be afraid
if I were invisible like you?
There's no need to be afraid, Kemp.
We're partners. Bosom friends.
We've a busy day ahead.
You must sleep.
I see. You told the police.
That was why you went downstairs.
No, I didn't. I swear I didn't.
Look, it's not the police.
It's Dr Cranley and Flora.
Flora.
- Why, yes, of course.
- I had to tell them you were back, Griffin.
- Flora was nearly mad with anxiety.
- How could I forget?
Shall I let them in?
Yes, of course you must let them in.
I shall go and prepare myself in my room.
I shall see Flora. Alone.
- He knows you're here.
- He was asleep.
He saw you from the window.
He wants to see Flora alone.
- No, Flora, don't.
- He's calm now, and quiet.
- Jack won't do me any harm.
- He's insane.
It's for us to cure him - Kemp and I.
Keep away, Flora.
I must go to him.
Doctor, he was a different man
when he saw Flora leave the car.
He won't hurt her. We must play for time.
- Why for time?
- We... we must prepare things.
If we try and bind him now, he'll escape.
We must take him when he's asleep
and chloroform him. Wait here.
- Flora, my darling.
- Thank God you're home, Jack.
I would have come to you at once,
Flora, but for this.
How wonderful it is to see you.
How beautiful you look.
That funny little hat. I always liked it.
- You've been crying.
- I want to help you. Why did you do this?
- For you, Flora.
- For me?
Yes, for you, my darling.
I wanted to do something tremendous,
to achieve what men of science
have dreamt of since the world began,
to gain wealth and fame and honour,
to write my name above
the greatest scientists of all time.
I was so pitifully poor.
I had nothing to offer you, Flora.
I was just a poor, struggling chemist.
I shall come back to you,
Flora, very soon now.
The secret of invisibility
lies there in my books.
I shall work in Kemp's laboratory
till I find the way back.
There is a way back, Flora.
And then I shall come to you.
I shall offer my secret to the world,
with all its terrible power!
The nations of the world will bid for it -
thousands, millions.
The nation that wins my secret can
sweep the world with invisible armies!
Jack, I want you to let my father help you.
You know how clever he is.
He'll work with you until you find that
second secret that'll bring you back to us.
Then we'll have lovely,
peaceful days again
out under the trees,
after your work in the evening.
Your father? Clever?
You think he can help me?
He's got the brain of a tapeworm,
a maggot, beside mine.
Don't you see what it means? Power.
Power to rule, to make
the world grovel at my feet.
Jack, listen to me. Listen!
My father found a note in your room.
He knows something about monocane
you don't.
It alters you, changes you,
makes you feel differently.
Father believes its power will go
if you know what it is.
Come and stay with us.
Let's fight this thing out together.
Power, I said.
Power to walk into the gold vaults
of the nations,
into the secrets of kings,
into the holy of holies.
Power to make multitudes
run squealing in terror
at the touch of my little invisible finger.
Even the moon's frightened of me,
frightened to death.
The whole world's frightened to death.
So, I see. Kemp couldn't sleep.
He had to go downstairs.
He was frightened.
I put my trust in Kemp.
I told him my secret
and he gave me his word of honour.
- You must go now, Flora.
- I want to help you.
There is nothing for you to do
except to go.
I shall come back. I swear I shall
come back, because I shall defeat them.
- Go now, my dear.
- No. I want to stay. You must hide.
Don't worry.
The whole world's my hiding place.
I can stand out there amongst them
in the day or night and laugh at them.
Come along, my darling.
Oh, Father!
Link hands, all around the house.
- Link hands.
Keep close together,
or he'll slip under your arm.
Now, boys, forward.
Thank you, Kemp,
for opening the window.
You're a true friend, Kemp. A man to trust.
I've no time now but, believe me,
as surely as the moon will set
and the sun will rise,
I shall kill you tomorrow night.
I shall kill you even if you hide
in the deepest cave of the earth.
At ten o'clock tomorrow night
I shall kill you.
Help! Help!
He's here! He's here!
- Here he comes.
- Stand where you are.
- What is it?
- Something smacked my face.
Naughty boy.
Ow! Let go!
- What's the matter with you?
- He twisted my nose.
Now, steady, boys.
We've got him all right this time.
Good shot.
Get that hat.
Now then, boys, advance slowly.
It's all right. He's unarmed.
We've got him easy.
Help! Help! He's got me by the feet!
Here he is! Help!
It's the invisible man! He's got him
by the feet! After him! Quick!
What do you know about that?
Help!
Murder! Murder!
# Here we go gathering nuts in May,
nuts in May, nuts in May
# Here we go gathering nuts in May
on a cold and frosty morning
Whoops!
He threatened to kill me at ten o'clock
tonight. You must lock me up.
You're not the only one
in danger, Dr Kemp.
I'll see that you have protection.
Now, Dr Cranley,
you're concealing something from me.
One moment.
Why were you and your daughter
in this house at two o'clock this morning?
Dr Kemp called me up.
He told me the man was here.
- He wanted my help.
- Why did he ring you before the police?
- Why did your daughter come too?
- She came to drive the car.
You know who
the invisible man is, Doctor.
I understand you have another assistant
besides Dr Kemp, a Dr Griffin.
- Where is Dr Griffin?
- He's gone away.
It is Griffin!
What's the good of concealing it?
It's Griffin,
and he's threatened to murder me.
He may be here now, in the garden
looking through the window,
or in the corner of my bedroom
waiting for me, waiting to kill me!
And you all sit there
doing nothing! Nothing!
We've doubled the search party
around Kemp's house.
Nothing to report, sir. The policeman's
trousers were found a mile away.
- That's all.
- Well, it's beaten me.
I'll give 1,000 for a practical idea.
He's roaming the country at will,
a madman.
Here I am.
Aren't you pleased you've found me?
Aagh!
Would you like
to keep him company?
Stand away! Keep back!
Thank you.
- Give me 5 worth of silver, please.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you. Good day.
- Morning.
- Morning, sir.
There you are. A present
from the invisible man.
Money! Money! Money! Money!
# Up and down the City Road
# In and out the Eagle
# That's the way the money goes
# Pop goes the weasel!
Money! Money! Money! Money!
20 men of the search parties
have been killed,
and 100 in the train disaster.
The invisible man has been reported
in a hundred different places.
Now I appeal to you to help us
keep the public calm.
What plans have you got
for capturing him?
100,000 men are searching and watching.
But have you any special
secret means of getting him?
The police have offered 2,000
for the first effective means.
- Why not bloodhounds?
- The bloodhounds have lost the scent.
Why not put wet tar on all the roads,
then chase the black soles of his feet?
Because he's not a fool.
Now, we've got one hope, gentlemen.
But I daren't say a word of it here.
He may be standing there
beside you listening.
Try and sleep now, my dear.
There's nothing you can do.
We must just pray that the police
can take him without harming him.
Stand back, close against the wall.
Now then.
Drag that net clear across the room.
Now everything depends on
the way we carry out my plan.
I'll tell you it after we've made certain
he's not in this room.
Good. Now we're safe here at last.
Constable, keep an eye on that window.
Now, come here. All of you, sit down.
Now listen carefully. We've got a chance
tonight that will never come again.
He's threatened to murder
Dr Kemp at ten o'clock.
From what we know of him,
he'll do his utmost to carry that out.
He's certain to be near this house,
watching, for some time beforehand.
Now, at half past nine,
Dr Kemp, with a bodyguard of police,
will leave this house
and walk down to the police station.
It's a natural thing
for Dr Kemp to seek protection.
The invisible man is certain to be near.
He's certain to see what's happening.
You mean you're going to
use me as a bait? I can't!
- You must. You'll be perfectly safe.
- Safe? He's not human.
- He can go through prison walls.
- Don't be a fool.
I can't sit in that station waiting.
He'll kill you, kill you all,
and then take the keys and come to me.
Very well. If you're afraid
of waiting in the police station,
you can leave it directly you're inside.
There's a secret way out
through the inspector's house.
We'll disguise you as a policeman
and you can walk out and drive away.
Even if he sees you,
he won't recognise you.
He'll probably be waiting
to break in at ten o'clock.
- What happens to me then?
- I'll have you driven quietly back here.
Then get into your car and drive away
into the country, miles away,
and stay there until we've got him.
Now, you needn't be afraid.
We'll get him all right this time.
I'll lay traps that even
an invisible man can't pass.
You see? It covers a fairly wide range.
Now, I've got 20 of these guns
and a good man to each.
One splash of this on his skin
and we've got something to follow at last.
- Why not paint the top of the wall?
- Because he'd smell it.
I've got a better plan. I'm going to put a
thin layer of loose earth on top of the wall.
The slightest touch will disturb it,
and we've got him trapped.
Oh, I see. Pretty good.
Quick march!
They think they're very clever.
All right, take him straight inside.
20 minutes to ten.
Keep your eyes open now, boys.
Here, quick, sir.
I heard footsteps outside,
soft footsteps, like naked feet.
Listen.
Come on.
- Where are you going to?
- The mountains, 100 miles away.
Drive away quickly.
It's ten minutes to ten.
He's bound to do something in a minute.
- Will he try and get into the station?
- Every door and window is barred.
No, he'll try the wall right enough.
There he goes!
- Go to your stations now. Watch the wall.
- He's over the wall!
I felt breathing down my neck.
He's in here.
Ten o'clock!
Ten o'clock he wanted to murder me.
I think this'll do nicely, Kemp.
We'll stop here.
It's ten o'clock.
I came with you to keep my promise.
No! It's all a mistake, Griffin.
I swear I never told the police. I want
to help you. Let me be your partner.
I've had a cold and uncomfortable journey
just to keep my promise at ten o'clock.
I went into the police station with you.
I stood by
while you changed into that coat.
I rode on the running board
of the car that took you home again.
There. You sit there.
I've got you where I want you.
I hope your car's insured. I'm afraid
there's going to be a nasty accident.
A very nasty accident.
- I'll do anything. Everything you ask me.
- You will? That's fine.
Sit where you are. I'll get out and take the
handbrake off and give you a little shove.
You'll run down and through the railings.
Then you'll have a big thrill for 100 yards
till you hit a boulder.
Then you'll do a somersault
and break your arms,
then a grand finish-up
with a broken neck.
Well, goodbye, Kemp. I always said
you were a dirty little coward.
You're a dirty, sneaking
little rat as well. Goodbye.
1,000 replies have come to my appeal
for ways of catching the invisible man.
Some are clever, some stupid,
but all are impossible.
He's got to sleep.
They might catch him asleep.
- He's got to eat and drink.
- A caf was robbed last night in Manton.
There's no proof he did it.
There are robberies every night
by ordinary burglars.
This feels good.
Look there. We wanted help - there it is.
It's now or never. The snow
won't lie long at this time of year.
It may be gone in a few hours.
Norton, find out if the snow
is yet all over the country.
Send out a broadcast message.
He can't stay out in this bitter cold.
He'll seek shelter.
Excuse me, sir.
There's breathing in my barn.
What do you mean,
breathing in your barn?
The invisible man, sir.
Sure as I stand here.
The farmer may have imagined it,
but we can't leave it to chance.
Surround the barn.
No use trying to take him on the inside.
Force him out into the snow. Take
some wood and gasoline and set fire to it.
That's it, sir. He's in there
under a pile of straw, sir.
Are there any windows
he can watch from?
No, sir. Only the door, sir.
There's a reward of 1,000
waiting for you if we're successful.
We're lucky to have the open country.
Take your men and cover the country
from the road to the hill.
Line the ridge through those trees.
There's no time to lose. We can't wait
till he comes out to search for food.
We must fire the barn at once
and drive him out into the snow.
Keep in single file. We don't want
a lot of your footprints around the barn.
We want to keep the snow
for his feet alone.
Get that searchlight
on the door of that barn.
He's out! Look!
Shall I give the signal to advance?
I don't think your guard
is needed any longer.
- How is he?
- He's very near the end.
- Are you Dr Cranley?
- Yes. I got word to come immediately.
Towards dawn this morning
he grew quiet.
He called the name of a girl -
I understand, your daughter.
She's waiting below. Is there any chance?
The bullet passed through both lungs.
It's impossible to treat the wound.
Do you think your daughter
could bear to go to him?
I'm afraid the end may be rather terrible.
The effect of the drugs will die with him.
His body will become visible as life goes.
I'll bring her now.
- Is Flora there?
- She's coming now.
I knew you would come to me, Flora.
I wanted to come back to you.
My darling.
I failed.
I meddled in things...
that man must leave alone.
Father, come quickly.