They'd better not push me on him,
or I'll just kick them
in the teeth on it.
Well, I think, if they...
Internal Revenue people that are kicking
Billy Graham around is Rosenberg.
He is to be out.
I don't give a goddamn
what the story is.
He went on television.
I have not. I've
already ordered Connally,
we're going after the Chandlers,
every one individually, collectively,
their income taxes
are starting this week.
Every one of those sons of bitches.
Well, this is something that
we can really hang Teddy or...
Yeah.
or the Kennedy clan with.
I'm gonna want to put
that in Colson's hands.
And we're gonna want to run with it.
A controversial day in politics.
A man arrested trying to bug the offices
of the Democratic National
Committee in Washington
turns out to be an employee
of President Richard Nixon's
re-election campaign committee.
He is one of five persons
surprised and arrested yesterday
inside the headquarters of the
Democratic National Committee
in Washington.
And guess what else he is.
A consultant of
President Richard Nixon's
re-election campaign committee.
The trial started today
at the federal courthouse
for the five burglars
caught breaking into
the Democratic National
Party headquarters.
Stand by for camera.
John Dean, the ex-White
House Counsel, testified today
that President Nixon knew
about the Watergate cover-up.
At one point in the conversation,
I recall the President telling me
to keep a good list of the
press people giving us trouble
because we will make life difficult
for them after the election.
Dean read through a 245-page statement
characterizing a president
who was easily outraged
over war protesters and
political adversaries,
and outlining a range of offenses,
including wiretapping of newsmen,
a Charles Colson plan to firebomb
and burglarize the
Brookings Institution,
and spying on Senator
Kennedy and other Democrats.
The misuse of power is the
very essence of tyranny.
And consider, if you will,
the frightening implications
of that for a free society.
The President today accepted the
resignation of three of his closest aides.
Out is H.R. Haldeman, Chief of Staff.
Also quitting under
fire is John Ehrlichman.
Ehrlichman was a key political advisor.
Good morning. The Supreme Court
has just ruled on the tapes controversy,
and here is Carl Stern,
who has that ruling.
It is a unanimous decision,
Doug, eight to zero.
Justice Rehnquist took
no part in the decision
ordering the President of the
United States to turn over the tapes.
It's an eight-to-zero
unanimous opinion.
A White House aide told NBC News today
that impeachment of the President
by the full House of Representatives
now is a virtual certainty.
These are, with no serious doubt,
the last hours of the 37th
presidency of the United States.
This is indeed an historic day,
the only time a president
has ever resigned from office
in our nearly 200 years of history.
You see the White House
there, and in the White House,
in just a few moments now,
President Nixon will be
appearing before the people,
perhaps for the last time as
President of the United States.
15 seconds, Mr. President.
Okay, that's five, four, three...
Good evening. This is the 37th time
I have spoken to you from this office
where so many decisions have been made
that have shaped the
history of our nation.
I remember exactly where I was.
My father called. The phone rang,
my father called and he said,
"Turn on the TV right now.
Richard Nixon's going down."
I was at home with friends, and we
were watching television at home.
We stayed up and, like
everyone else, I'd been glued to
the Select and Judiciary Committee
hearings night after night.
And then finally, it had come to this.
Therefore, I shall resign the
presidency effective at noon tomorrow.
But instead of the satisfaction
I imagined I'd feel,
I just got angrier and angrier,
because there was no admission of guilt.
There was no apology.
Little did I know
that I would one day be part of the team
that would try and elicit that apology.
To leave office before
my term is completed
is abhorrent to every
instinct in my body.
I have never been a quitter.
And that that team would be led
by the most unlikely of white knights,
a man with no political
convictions whatsoever,
a man who, as far as I know, had
never even voted once in his life.
But he was a man who had one big
advantage over the rest of us.
He understood television.
And now, the host of
Frost Over Australia,
Mr. David Frost!
Thank you, thank you.
Hello. Good evening.
And with the eyes of the world
focused on the White House,
here in Australia,
burglars have broken into
a meat factory in Brisbane
and stolen a ton of pork sausages.
The Queensland police are looking
for men in a long, thin getaway car.
Now, my first guest tonight...
Well, we in the Nixon camp
really didn't know that
much about David Frost,
other than he was a
British talk show host
with something of a playboy reputation.
He'd had a talk show here in
the US that had won some awards
but hadn't syndicated well and
had been dropped by the network.
He ended up taking it down to Australia,
which is, I believe, where he
was when the President resigned.
Next week's guest will
be Evonne Goolagong.
We'll see you then. God bless.
Great show, David. Thanks, Noah.
Come and look at this.
Nixon leaving the White House.
A dark day for Richard
Nixon, who has drawn crowds
to the vast Ellipse south
of the White House before.
What, this is live? Yeah.
But those were triumphs. This is not.
What time is it in Washington?
9:00 a.m.
Why didn't he wait?
It's 6:00 in the morning
on the West Coast.
Half his audience is still asleep.
All right, you blokes, let's
get the set broken down.
are witnesses to the saddest
day in the life of Richard Nixon,
his last moments as President
of the United States,
a moment unlike any other in
the history of this country.
Richard Nixon, who goes now
from the power of the presidency
to a form of exile in California.
Find out the numbers for
this, will you? Worldwide.
I remember his face.
Staring out the window.
Down below him, a liberal
America cheered, gloated.
Hippies, draft dodgers, dilettantes,
the same people who'd spit on
me when I got back from Vietnam.
They'd gotten rid of Richard
Nixon, their bogeyman.
So what's so important that it
couldn't wait, that it had to be today?
I've had an idea, John, rather
a bold idea for an interview.
Fish and chips, please.
And in a moment...
Well, it's too late now. It's done.
I've called his people...
You?
Beans, peas and lamb, please.
And made an offer.
Now, if the subject were to say yes,
well, he's rather a big fish
that swims in not-untricky waters.
So it goes without saying
that I'd want a dear friend
and the finest producer
I know by my side.
So who is it?
Richard Nixon.
Richard Nixon?
Well, come on, don't look like that.
Well, how would you expect me to look?
I spent yesterday evening watching
you interview the Bee Gees.
Weren't they terrific?
Come on, John, we've done
political interviews before.
So, okay, so what kind of interview?
A full, extensive look-back
over his life, his presidency.
And?
And what? Come on, David.
Surely the only thing
that would interest anyone
about Richard Nixon
would be a confession.
A full, no-holds-barred
confession.
Well, we'll get that, too.
From Richard Nixon?
Come on, John.
Just think of the numbers it would get.
Do you know how many people watched
his farewell speech in the White House?
Four hundred million.
But in the end, David heard nothing.
And soon after arriving in California,
Nixon was rushed to hospital
with an acute attack of phlebitis.
I think it was around
this time that Gerald Ford,
who was the new President,
and who was desperate to move
the agenda on from Watergate,
gave Nixon a full, free
and absolute pardon.
Now therefore, I, Gerald R. Ford,
President of the United States,
have granted, and by
these presents do grant,
a full, free and absolute pardon
unto Richard Nixon for all
offenses against the United States.
It meant that the man who had
committed the greatest felony
in American political history
would never stand trial.
It was like he slipped
out the back door.
A public opinion poll indicates
a two-to-one disapproval of
the pardoning of Richard Nixon.
One telegram from Virginia said,
"Roosevelt had his New Deal,
"Truman had his Fair Deal, now
Ford has his crooked deal. "
There was no deal, period.
I don't think the truth
will ever come out.
The American people
need to know the truth,
and I don't think it will
ever now be fully known.
So how do we want to
address the college protests?
Well, do we want to lift some quotes
from the "stand up and be
counted" speech in 1970?
Sir? You know, maybe
we're just better off
using the whole Lincoln Memorial memo.
Just include the whole thing.
Mr. President, Swifty Lazar is here.
Okay. No, no, stick around.
You're gonna get a kick out of this.
This is my literary
agent from Hollywood.
Hygiene obsessive.
Mr. President, good to see you.
Nice to see you.
These are folks helping me with my book.
Diane Sawyer, Frank
Gannon, Irving Lazar.
Nice to meet you. Miss Sawyer.
Pleasure. Mr. Gannon.
Okay, that's it. I'll
see you after lunch.
So how you feeling, sir?
I'm better, thank you. Though
not yet well enough to golf,
thank God. I despise that game.
Imagine, six weeks out of office
as President of the United States,
and they'd have me putting
in my hospital room.
Never retire, Mr. Lazar.
To me, the unhappiest people
of the world are retired.
No purpose.
What makes life mean
something is purpose.
A goal. A battle. A struggle.
Well, even if you don't win it.
When my doctor declared me unfit
to give testimony in
the Watergate trial,
everybody thought I'd be relieved.
Well, they were wrong.
That was the lowest I got.
Well, if it's a challenge you
want, here's one you might enjoy.
How to spend $2 million,
2.3 to be precise.
It's what I got for your memoirs.
Well, thank you.
Eh...
It might be a little
short of what I wanted,
but let me assure you, it's a
whole lot more than they wanted.
That book is important to me.
It's probably the only chance I'm
gonna get to put the record straight
and remind people the
Nixon years weren't all bad.
You know, if you're trying
to put the record straight,
I'd at least talk to him.
Who?
David Frost. English talk show guy.
Why would I want to talk to David Frost?
Well, a while back, he wrote
asking for an interview.
No.
Well, we didn't get back to him.
Frankly, we didn't find him appropriate.
Well, I thought that we
were doing one with CBS.
We are. I just figured
doing it with Frost
would be a whole lot easier
than doing it with Mike Wallace.
It would, but it would have a
lot less, you know, credibility.
True, true. Could
probably get more money.
Really? Look.
We'll always have 350
on the table from CBS.
But if I could get Frost to pay
more and secure better terms,
it might be a shame to pass.
It'd be interesting to
know where he is right now.
We tied him to railway
tracks, and he escaped.
We buried him alive, and he walked free.
Today we're lowering escape artist
Derek Harrison into the water
to see if he can miraculously
cheat death once more.
Good evening, and
welcome to Great Escapes.
My name is David Frost.
Okay, that is a cut.
Thank you.
In any deal, you need to know
your opponent's breaking point.
To assess that, you might call them
late at night or at the weekend.
If they take the call,
you know they're desperate.
And from that moment on, you
know you have the upper hand.
Hello?
Mr. Frost? Irving Lazar.
Who?
Swifty Lazar. I
represent President Nixon.
What time is it?
Bad time?
No! Not at all.
I'm calling with regard to
your request for an interview
and to say, having considered it,
my client is not necessarily
opposed to the idea.
Really? Well, that's terrific news!
For God's sake.
I got $500,000.
Is that good?
Mr. President, it's a half a
million dollars for a news interview.
It's unprecedented.
Yeah? Well, what's the catch?
With Frost? None.
It'll be a big wet kiss.
This guy'll be so grateful
to be getting it at all,
he'll pitch puffballs all night
and pay a half a million
dollars for the privilege.
Well, you think you could get 550?
I got 6.
David, how could you
have done that? What?
$600,000. That's a fortune.
200 on signature?
Don't worry about the money.
My God. Most Americans
think he belongs in jail.
You're making him a rich man.
Plus, by outbidding them,
you've already made enemies
of the networks. They're just jealous.
They're already sounding off
about checkbook journalism.
And if the networks are against you,
syndication's always
going to be a struggle.
No syndication, no advance sales.
No advance sales, no commercials.
No commercials, no revenue.
And here's the bigger question,
why do it? You don't need it.
Your career's in great shape.
This will just spread you
across three continents,
jeopardize the other shows.
Isn't it true that
Channel Nine in Australia
want you to do another season
of your talk show for them?
Yes. And London, too?
Yes, but that would be
London and Australia.
This would be... What?
You wouldn't understand, John.
You were never part of
the show in New York,
but it's indescribable.
Success in America is
unlike success anywhere else.
And the emptiness when it's gone.
And the sickening thought
that it may never come back.
You know, there's a restaurant
in New York called Sardi's.
Ordinary mortals can't get a table.
John, the place was my canteen!
You know, I'd be happier
if I heard some kind of vision
that you had for this interview.
Excuse me, Mr. Frost.
I'd heard you were going to be here.
Would you mind? Of course.
But I don't. I just hear a man doing it
because it would create headlines
or give him a place at the top table.
And that is what makes me nervous.
And you do nervous so beautifully, John.
"Hello, good evening and welcome."
I don't actually say that.
Hello, Mr. Frost.
Champagne?
No, thank you.
Another glass, sir?
You don't like champagne?
Not on airplanes.
Yes, it dehydrates one terribly.
The trick is to have a glass
of water on the go, too.
Like the Viennese serve coffee.
Well, I've never been to Vienna.
Oh. Well, you'd like it.
It's like Paris without the French.
What's your name?
Caroline.
David.
Yes, I know. David Frost.
"Hello and good evening and welcome."
You know, I heard an interview
with you recently on the radio.
You were giving it from the
back of your Rolls-Royce.
Bentley.
On the phone.
They said that you were a person
who defined the age we live in.
Really? Mmm.
You and Vidal Sassoon.
But what made you
exceptional, they said,
was that you were a person
who had achieved great fame
without possessing any
discernible quality.
How kind. Mmm-hmm.
And that you fly around a great deal.
Well, that's true.
Why?
I like to keep busy.
I find it more interesting
than keeping still.
You know, you have very sad eyes.
Do I? Mmm.
Has anyone told you that before?
No.
Are you a sad person?
Let's talk about you a little bit.
Of course, you feel more
comfortable asking questions.
How right you are!
This is your captain speaking.
You may have noticed we've begun
our final descent into Los Angeles.
If you could please return to your
seats and fasten your seat belts,
we'll be landing very
shortly. Thank you.
So how about you? Where are you going?
To meet Richard Nixon.
Really?
You know, they say he has
the most enormous head,
but the sexiest voice.
Where is he now?
In some dark underground
cave licking his wounds?
Actually, no. In his
rather smart beachside villa
in California.
Really? Richard Nixon
in a beachside villa?
How incongruous.
You can come if you'd like.
To meet Nixon?
Why not?
Are you sure?
You know, I would love that.
Cabin crew, please prepare for arrival.
Well, I'll get my office to call
you first thing in the morning
and send a car with a phone.
Oh.
He did, too. Money no object.
Everything glittered and was golden.
Well, on the outside.
Of course, what I didn't
know was that in the meantime,
he'd gone to all the major networks
to try and get interest
in the interviews.
I'm sorry, David, but we have a policy
of not paying for a news interview.
Look, we love your
work as an entertainer.
That Guinness show?
Love it. You're a funny guy.
But an interview like this?
You're asking us to pay
a British talk show host
to interview an American president
with absolutely no editorial
controls whatsoever in return?
Well, you can't say it's
not a fresh approach.
I know you're very busy.
I'm not gonna keep you from it.
Thank you for coming in.
I'm gonna have to get back to you.
Okay, thank you so much for your time.
David, good luck.
He never let on to anyone at the time,
not even me. You know,
that would have meant...
Thanks.
... admitting failure, and
David doesn't do failure.
There you are.
See, you don't have
to do a thing yourself.
Well.
You found it okay.
Yes, thank you.
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Frost.
And you, sir.
May I present Caroline Cushing?
Miss Cushing.
Hello. Your house is very beautiful.
Really. Very romantic.
Well, thank you.
And my producer, John Birt.
Nice to meet you. How do you do?
This is Mr. Lazar, and
this is Jack Brennan.
Now, Miss Cushing, would
you like to take a tour,
you know, maybe stretch your
legs after your long journey?
Yes, please. I'd love that. Thank you.
Come on in. This is my office.
Now, this is where Brezhnev
and I had our summit.
Yeah. Brezhnev was there, and
Gromyko there, Dobrynin there.
We talked for nine hours straight.
After the meeting, as
a souvenir of the visit,
I remember that we had
a Lincoln specially made.
Dark blue, cherry wood, leather.
Well, we got inside
for the photographers,
when the next thing you
know, he steps on the gas.
Now, the first rule of political life is
you never let a president get
behind the wheel of a car, ever.
I mean, we're not used to doing anything
for ourselves, let alone drive.
And the Chairman, Jesus,
the way he put his foot down,
my guess is the last thing he drove was
a tractor on some Ukrainian potato farm.
He crashed into curbs.
He went over speed bumps.
He went twice around my whole estate.
Finally, we ended up at some
remote point on the coast,
out there overlooking the sea.
He turns off the gas,
and he talks for two hours
about his favorite subject, steel mills.
He said, "Mr. President,
most politicians
"have tragedy in their early lives."
Well, I told him that I lost
two brothers to tuberculosis.
And he watched his father die from
the cancer he caught in the steelworks.
He was a sad man and a noble adversary.
I wouldn't want to be a Russian leader.
They never know when
they're being taped.
Okay, I guess that's it then, huh?
Until March. I look forward to it.
Well, thank you, Mr. President. So do I.
You know, it's a funny thing that
I've never been challenged
to a duel before.
I guess that's what this is.
Yeah, well, not really.
Of course it is.
And I like that.
No holds barred, eh? No holds barred.
Mr. Frost, there's still
the small matter of the...
Of course.
I do beg your pardon.
Right. $200,000.
I do hope that isn't coming
out of your own pocket.
Well, believe me, sir, I wish
my pockets were that deep.
Made out in the name of?
Irving Paul Lazar.
Richard M. Nixon.
Here you go.
Okay, smile.
There. Now you can put that
in your apartment in New York,
and all your liberal friends
can use it as a dartboard.
Well, actually, I'm living
in Monte Carlo at the moment.
Really?
Yes. Goodbye, Mr. President.
Hey. Take my advice.
You should marry that woman.
Yes. Lovely, isn't she?
More important than that,
she comes from Monaco.
They pay no taxes there.
Bye-bye. Goodbye.
I bet you it did.
What?
Come out of his own pocket.
You know, he couldn't
look me in the eye.
Well, I hear the networks aren't biting.
Without the networks, the ad
agencies don't want to know.
So if you ask me, there's a good chance
this whole thing may never happen.
Really? So that meeting we just
had might have cost him $200,000?
Correct.
Had I known that, I would
have offered him a cup of tea.
Say, did you notice his shoes?
No.
Italian. No laces. What do you think?
My people tried to get me
to wear a pair like that.
I think a man's shoes
should have laces, sir.
You do?
Yeah. Personally, I find those
Italian shoes very effeminate.
Yes, quite right.
I'm sorry, David, but it's a no.
Try to look at it
from our point of view.
Why would an American
network hire a total outsider,
and someone who's already had his
own show canceled, incidentally?
I see. Well, I'm sorry
you feel this way.
Obviously, I think you're
making a terrible mistake.
NBC.
Well, that's the
networks out, all of them.
Well, that's the end of that, then.
I'm sorry, David.
Not so fast.
Where's your adventurer's spirit?
The idea is we pay for the program
and syndicate it ourselves,
completely bypassing the networks.
Just imagine it, we'd be our
own network for the night.
Hey, Bob. How does that grab you?
Hey, come on in. David's on the phone.
No, never been done before.
Historic stuff.
Just think about it,
okay? And call me back.
Yeah? Yeah.
David, I'd like you to meet
Jim Reston and Bob Zelnick,
our two prospective corner men.
Delighted to meet you.
Come on in. Make yourselves at home.
Bob's been Washington correspondent
for Public Radio for the past 10 years.
Moving to ABC in the new year.
The general feeling, David,
is that I have been wasting
my matinee idol looks on radio.
Jim here teaches at the
University of North Carolina
and is writing a book about the
criminal dishonesty, corruption,
paranoia and abuses of
power of Richard Nixon.
Second on the subject.
Fourth.
Well, delighted to have you both aboard.
Actually, before I sign
on, I would like to hear
what you were hoping to
achieve with this interview.
What I want to achieve?
Yeah.
Jim, well, I've secured 12 taping days.
That's close to 30 hours
with the most compelling
and controversial politician
of our times.
Isn't that enough?
Well, not for me.
Look, I'd be giving up a year
of my life. I'm leaving my family
to work on a subject
matter that means more
than you can probably imagine,
and the idea of doing all that
without achieving what
I want to, personally,
would be unthinkable to me.
No, all right.
Well, what is it that
you want to achieve?
I'd like to give Richard
Nixon the trial he never had.
Of course, we'll be
asking difficult questions.
Difficult questions.
The man lost 21,000 Americans
and a million Indo-Chinese
during his administration.
He only escaped jail
because of Ford's pardon.
Yes, but equally, going after
him in some knee-jerk way,
you know, assuming he's a terrible guy,
wouldn't that only create more
sympathy for him than anything else?
You know...
Right now, I submit it's impossible
to feel anything close to
sympathy for Richard Nixon.
He devalued the presidency,
and he left the country
that elected him in trauma.
The American people need a
conviction, pure and simple.
The integrity of our political system,
of democracy as an idea,
entirely depends on it.
And if in years to
come, people look back
and say it was in this interview
that Richard Nixon exonerated himself,
that would be the worst crime of all.
Did you know that Mike Wallace
is doing a piece on this?
And that in the bars around
Capitol Hill and Georgetown
this entire project is a joke?
Come on. Jim, come on.
Thanks for that, Jim.
Could you give us a couple of minutes?
You're unbelievable. I'm sorry, Bob.
You know, Jim, I went
way out on a limb for you.
I mean, some of us
actually want this job.
I want it, too, if it's done right.
Well, how do you know
they're not gonna do it right?
Little Lord Fauntleroy in there?
Sympathy for Richard Nixon?
What the... He's full of shit, man!
How do you know that?
Is Mike Wallace doing a piece on this?
Apparently.
Why didn't you tell me?
It isn't relevant.
What's the angle?
"British talk show host,
"good with actresses, not so good
with stonewalling presidents."
That's the general idea, yeah.
Right.
It's hard not to feel a
little insulted by that.
Well, Bob's obviously a pro.
What are we gonna do about Reston?
Well, the man's an
idiot. He's overemotional.
Send him home.
Well, I think he should stay. Why?
I liked his passion.
He will drive us all bloody mad.
Well, maybe, but sometimes
being out of your comfort zone
is a good thing, I'm told.
He stays.
I took my seat next to Mrs.
Mao at the banquet table.
Now, one of the challenges
of life as a president
is the endless round of cocktail
parties, social engagements, banquets.
And people who know me would tell you
that small talk is not one of
my strong suits, either. No.
Particularly not in Mandarin.
So Mrs. Mao and I, we just, well,
you know, stared at one another.
And then across the table, Mrs.
Nixon and Chairman Mao himself, well,
they stared at one another, too.
And then further down, Dr. Kissinger
and their foreign minister, well,
you're getting the picture now.
I can't stand it, Jack!
Reducing the presidency to
a series of banal anecdotes.
I feel like a circus
animal doing tricks.
And I thought I made it clear!
I didn't want to take any
questions on Watergate, damn it!
Soon as it came to question time,
all those sons of bitches ever
want to hear about is Watergate!
It's as if all my other
achievements have ceased to exist.
Well, sir, you're gonna get a chance
to talk about them
sooner than you think.
Yeah? How?
Frost got there. He got the money.
What?
I understand most of it's borrowed,
that his friends have bailed him out.
But the point is, we start
taping at the end of March.
Really? Now, that's terrific.
How much time is devoted to Watergate?
25%. Just one of four 90-minute shows.
What are the other three divided into?
Domestic Affairs, Foreign Policy,
and Nixon the Man.
"Nixon the Man"?
As opposed to what? Nixon the horse?
Well, I imagine it's some
kind of biographical piece.
I can see it now. The father that
neglected me, the brothers that died.
Spare me.
Still, now, the fact it's come
together, now, that's a good thing, no?
Mr. President, it's fantastic.
Frost is just not in your
intellectual class, sir.
You're gonna be able to dictate
terms, rebuild your reputation.
If this went well, if enough people
saw it, revised their opinion,
you could move back East way,
way earlier than we expected.
You think? I'm certain.
It would be so good to go
back to where the action is.
You know?
The hunger in my belly
is still there, Jack.
I guess it all boils
down to Watergate, huh?
Well, that's nothing
to worry about, sir.
It's not as if there's
gonna be any revelations.
That stuff's been combed
over a million times.
No one has pinned anything on you.
Yeah, still, it's been a while
since I spoke about it on the record.
I'm gonna start doing my homework.
Hey, you know what would be an
interesting thing to find out?
What his strategy is.
Now, where's he staying?
I believe The Beverly Hilton.
The Beverly Hilton, you say.
Well, I got the numbers someplace
of some fellows that we could send in.
Cubans with CIA training.
Jesus, Jack, it was a joke.
Yes, sir.
A week later, we said
goodbye to our families,
we hopped on a plane, and we
moved into The Beverly Hilton.
And that's where we started
to dig into our research
and prepare for the interviews.
Yeah, as it happens, we took
the whole question of
security very seriously.
And from day one, we kept all
our files in a locked safe.
Who was the guy that Mike
interviewed? Was that Haldeman?
Haldeman. Haldeman. And Ehrlichman, too.
I always get the Germans mixed up.
I'm a little confused by that.
What is Haldeman's
official... Hello, darling.
As for the work over the months,
we divided it into three sections.
Birt took Vietnam, Bob took
Foreign and Domestic Policy,
and I got Watergate
and the abuses of power.
And David, we never
really saw much of David.
All right, so what
about the Huston Plan?
You can see the seeds of dirty tricks.
Essentially, it's an attempt
to legalize dirty tricks.
That's why you gotta get David
to put it in the question.
Wiretapping students.
But they've traced the money to him.
Opening people's mail.
What about wiretapping?
How many people has he wiretapped?
This guy wiretapped 17 people.
Seventeen?
Including his own brother.
But you know what? We can't
ask him about his brother,
'cause frankly, if Donald
Nixon was my brother,
I'd wiretap him, too.
But wait, okay, so we
have breaking and entering.
We have wiretapping, conspiracy
to foster prostitution.
And that's Liddy, right?
Delivery courtesy of Nate 'n Al's
finest deli selection.
We're going to need napkins.
We'd better have some napkins.
How do we frame a
question about Cambodia,
about the illicit bombing of Cambodia?
I think you should say,
"How far do you take executive privilege
"before it becomes an
undemocratic event?"
I think you frame the
question to him as a Quaker.
"How do you feel as a Quaker about
annihilating an entire people?"
Come on. Are they really
interested in buying time?
Are they going to give us the money?
How serious are they?
You have to set up that he has
an anti-democratic personality.
There's a reason they
call him Tricky Dick.
Because I had written about
and watched Nixon for years,
I got to play him in our rehearsals.
You know, the fellas
would throw me a question,
and I would try and anticipate
what his response might be.
Okay, the White House taping system.
Ours is not the first
administration to use taping systems.
Lyndon Johnson's White House
used them. So did Kennedy's.
Huston Plan. Wiretapping
and alleged abuses of power.
Let me tell you, other
administrations were up to far worse.
And just for fun, your
close friend Jack Kennedy.
That man, he screwed
anything that moved,
fixed elections and
took us into Vietnam.
And the American people,
they loved him for it!
Whereas I, Richard Milhous Nixon,
worked around the clock in
their service, and they hated me!
Look. Look. Now I'm sweating.
Damn it! Damn it!
And Kennedy's so goddamn
handsome and blue-eyed!
And women all over him!
He screwed anything that
moved, and everything.
Had a go at Checkers once.
The poor little bitch
was never the same!
Gentlemen, finally a friend
in the American press.
Jack Anderson in The Washington Post,
"When Richard Nixon faces
the television cameras
"for his first interview since
he abandoned the White House,
"he'll be cross-examined as if
he were on the witness stand.
"Frost has hired three
crack investigators
"to help him with the research.
"Clearly the famous TV
interviewer will pull no punches."
"Crack investigators"?
Can I be Crack One?
Can I be Deep Crack?
David, can I talk to you for a sec?
After researching my last book,
I was pretty certain Colson...
You know, Charles Colson?
His darkest henchman?
Colson, right. Colson
had a meeting with Nixon
sometime before June 23,
but I never knew the exact date,
so I couldn't find the transcript.
But if you gave me a week back in
the Federal Courthouse library...
A week? Goodness, Jim, we
can't lose you for that long.
I think this is really good stuff, Dave.
Would there be something
I could help you with?
You know, if we're gonna nail
Nixon in these interviews,
we're gonna have to ambush him.
We're gonna have to
take him by surprise.
Don't worry, Jim. We'll get him anyway.
Hang on a second. David, Jack Brennan.
He sounds a little emotional.
I'll take it in here.
He'll be right with you. Yeah.
Jack. Watergate.
Yes, Jack.
Our lawyers want us to agree
on a definition of the word.
Well, I believe it's a large hotel
and office complex in Washington, Jack.
You know what I'm talking about.
For the interviews.
We want to propose that Watergate
be an umbrella term
for everything negative.
Hold on a minute.
So all the other domestic charges
against him, the Brookings Institute,
the Plumbers Union, the Enemies List,
you're saying all that
goes into Watergate?
Correct.
That is absurd and a clear breach
of the terms of our agreement.
Okay. How would you define Watergate?
Well, that it covers just that.
The Watergate break-in of June 17th
and the subsequent
cover-up and investigation.
Fine. In which case, the deal is off.
Fine. In which case,
you can expect a lawsuit
for something in excess of $20 million
in damages and loss of earnings.
The terms of the
contract clearly stipulate
that Watergate take up no
more than 25% of the time.
Yes, but nowhere does it say
that for the rest of the 75%
he gets to drone on
and sound presidential.
"Drone on"? Jesus Christ.
Where's your respect?
You remember who you're
talking about here.
You know as well as I do that 60%
of what he did in office was right,
and 30% may have been wrong, but
he thought it was right at the time.
Yes, but that still leaves 10%
where he was doing the
wrong thing and knew it.
You goddamn media
people. You are so smug.
Well, I can guarantee you
if you screw us on the 60%,
I will ruin you if it
takes the rest of my life.
Prick.
Look at you. Gorgeous.
Good night, sweet princes.
Cheerio. Bye.
See you in the morning.
Why the monkey suit?
David has a film premiere
he needs to attend.
What? The night before we start taping?
What's the movie?
It's The Slipper and the Rose.
The Cinderella movie?
Yeah. David's the executive producer.
You don't think it might be
an idea for our interviewer
to be rested and focused
on the job in hand?
Don't worry.
David is a performer
of the highest caliber.
He's been in these pressure
situations many times before.
Come the hour, he'll be fine. Okay?
What did he say? Did he say "performer"?
Yeah. That's the word he used?
Yeah, he said "performer."
Not "journalist" or "interviewer"?
No. He said "performer."
Out of curiosity, where are
you at this moment? Psychically?
I am imagining the dust, the darkness,
the agony and the
unimaginable Ioneliness
of the wilderness I am
about to be dispatched to
by my Washington political colleagues.
So any opportunity you get, go right
to foreign policy, go right to Mao,
go right to Khrushchev.
Just go right!
You could do all day
on foreign policy, sir.
I disagree that the Mao
banquet story is stale.
Excuse me, sir. Something
I think you should see.
People love that story.
Why don't we save it for the book?
Yeah, right, come on.
David. Mr. Frost.
David, some people in
the media have suggested
that you're not the
right man for the job,
that you'll be too
soft on the President.
What will you do if he stonewalls you?
Well, I shall say so again and again.
But I should say right
now that I'm not expecting
his approach to be to stonewall.
I'm hoping that it'll be
that of a cascade of candor.
REPORTER 1. "A cascade of candor"?
From Richard Nixon?
You think that's what you'll get?
No, I just thought it was a
phrase that might appeal to you.
So what about the money?
That's a strange fellow.
Started life as a comic, you know.
Is that so? Mmm-hmm.
Almost married Diahann Carroll.
Who?
The singer.
Isn't she black?
Yes, sir.
Right here in the Frost
file, which we put together
as part of our general preparations.
Okay. Let's get back to work.
That's fact, this is fiction.
So now it's about The
Slipper and the Rose.
It's a cracker of a movie.
I hope you'll all
come and see it, and...
I shouldn't have ordered that coffee.
Just don't drink any more.
Good luck. Thank you.
I'll be thinking of you.
Dick. Wait.
For the record, I'm gonna
be starting with John's idea.
"Why didn't you burn the tapes?"
No. Fuck.
Please, God, no! You can't.
David, you can't do that.
It would be a disaster.
It would get us into Watergate
way ahead of the agreed time.
What is the point of
having contractually set
specific times to deal
with certain subjects
if you're just going to
ignore it right off the bat?
'Cause it's war, isn't it? Gloves off.
I like it. It's ballsy.
Strategically, it'll
give us the upper hand.
It's insanely risky.
He could walk right off the set,
and there's nothing
we could do about it.
Worse, he could sue you!
We were sadly unable to do
the taping at Casa Pacifica
because of the Coast
Guard radio interference,
so we ended up at the rather
more modest Smith house,
which was owned by a local
Republican businessman.
Right here!
Mr. Frost, look over here.
Over here, sir!
Here we go. Back up behind the curb.
A few questions, please.
Right here, Mr. Frost.
David! David! David!
Well, hello there.
Excuse me, fellas.
Nixon, there's blood on your hands!
Liar!
Here comes the President!
Mr. President!
How are you feeling, Mr. President?
The Smith family requested that
the furniture be put back in place.
They talked to you about that, too?
They're bugging everybody.
You know, I've written
four books about him,
but this is the first time I've
actually seen him in the flesh.
He's taller than I imagined, and tanned.
The least he could do is look ravaged.
You gonna shake his hand?
Am I gonna shake...
Are you kidding me?
After everything that
prick's done to this country?
I'm not gonna shake his hand.
Gentlemen.
May I present Bob Zelnick,
my executive editor?
How do you do?
Pleasure, Mr. President.
And Jim Reston, one of my researchers.
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Reston.
Mr. President.
Excuse me, sir? Got a
room for you right here.
Wow. That was devastating, withering.
I mean, I don't think he's
ever gonna get over that.
Yeah, fuck off.
I got you guys set up back here.
Now this is your green room.
And the President will
be on the large monitor.
Craft services is that way.
Keep it about that temperature, okay?
Mr. President?
Yeah.
Before we start, I just want to say
how delighted we all are
by Mrs. Nixon's recovery.
Well, thank you. It's true.
She's much better now.
She's just getting round to the
business of replying to all the cards.
And from our point of view, well,
I'd just like to say how pleased we are
that you got this all together.
Thank you.
As I understand it, it's
been quite a struggle.
Well...
How much has it cost?
You mind me asking? Hey, come on.
Come on, it's just between us.
Very well. Two million.
Two million? Jeez. I didn't
realize we were making Ben-Hur.
But tell me something.
You raised it all now?
Not quite. But we're getting there.
Everyone's been kind and deferred fees.
Well, not quite everyone.
David, I'm gonna go
in with you on camera.
Excuse me.
I want to put a
handkerchief here, if I may.
Is that out of shot?
That's fine, Mr. President.
Contractually, I think that we made
an agreement that after each question
I might dab my upper
lip before answering it.
Which you won't show, you
know, when you cut it together.
You're probably aware of my
history with perspiration.
If you're referring to your TV
debate with Jack Kennedy in 1960.
They say that moisture on my
upper lip cost me the presidency.
People who heard it on the
radio, well, they thought I'd won.
But television and the close-up,
they create their own sets of meanings.
So now they insist I
bring a handkerchief
and that I have my eyebrows trimmed.
Sixty seconds, everyone.
You trim yours? No.
No, of course not.
Yeah, you're light-skinned. Yeah.
You got blue eyes. You've got no
troubles with perspiration, I imagine.
No, not that I'm aware.
You were obviously
born to be on the tube.
Stand by to roll tape in 30 seconds.
Settling.
Those shoes.
They're Italian, aren't they?
My shoes? I believe so.
Yeah, that's interesting.
You don't find them too effeminate?
No.
Well, I guess somebody in your field
can get away with them, you know.
Manolo, just check my collar, will you?
David, starting with camera two,
in four, three, two. Cue David. And...
Mr. President. Now, we're going
to be covering a lot of subjects
in a great deal of detail over
the course of these interviews,
but I'd like to begin
completely out of context
by asking you one question,
more than any other,
almost every American
and people all over the
world want me to ask.
Why didn't you burn the tapes?
Son of a bitch!
Well, Mr. Frost, I'm
surprised by your question
since we have an agreement, a
contractual agreement, I believe,
that we would cover Watergate
in our last taping session.
But if your viewers really
do have a major concern,
then perhaps I should
briefly respond to it now.
What probably very few people realize
is that the taping
system in the White House
was set up by my predecessor,
President Johnson,
partly to avoid the necessity of
having a secretary in every meeting,
and partly to ensure there was
a record kept of every verbal agreement,
no matter how off the cuff or casual.
Now, initially, on coming
into the White House,
I insisted on dismantling the system.