Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
They're going!
Wait for me, shit!
Hurry up!
You're not fast enough!
Hurry!
- They bet 1200.
- On what?
First one to dive in the lake.
Go!
The water's ice cold.
Wait for me!
- Jump!
- No, I don't wanna!
It's freezing.
November
Shit, I got a cramp!
Damn!
I'm coming!
Looks like a beached whale.
Give him heart massage.
Don't fuck around!
Did you check the eel traps?
I want 600. I was second.
There's grog in the car.
THE HUNT
There's something fishy here.
It's you, Pelle!
Are you alone?
Get him!
I'm done for!
Careful!
Pelle is my new weapon.
Hang up your clothes.
I need to go!
- Pee or poo?
- Poo.
Okay, Lucas will help you.
Lucas, would you?
Take off his clothes.
Does it help to jump like that?
- I'm done.
- Good.
Can you manage alone?
Wipe me!
Watch your tone.
Get down.
Soap up.
Come!
Hi, Klara.
Anything wrong?
I'm lost.
Really? Where are Mom and Dad?
Home.
I forgot to look where I was going
and I found myself here.
You were busy avoiding
the lines in the sidewalk...
and now, you don't know where to go?
No, and I don't remember the way.
That's annoying.
I know the way.
Shall I walk you home?
I'll watch the road,
you watch out for the lines.
Alright.
- Is Fanny coming too?
- Yes, of course.
This way, she'll protect us.
What is your favorite food?
Without a doubt, wild game.
Me, it's fish sticks.
Why are you working
at the kindergarten?
I used to teach at
your brother's school,
but it closed.
My dad says you're sad because
you live alone in a big house.
He said that?
"Keep your head up
"And your feet on the ground.
"If you sulk, you'll get
a kick in the ass."
Your father said that?
Mm-hm, "A kick in the ass."
Can I come and take
Fanny for a walk?
Whenever you want.
Try calling her.
Fanny!
Louder.
Heel!
- Klara, where were you?
- At the supermarket.
I found her there.
Sweetie,
I told you not to run off.
Sorry.
- Coffee?
- Gladly.
Come in.
Go to your room.
Look what the cat dragged in.
Lucas!
Hello, Agnes.
You're a good dog!
Hi, honey.
You didn't put it away,
like you promised.
You leave your carabine
hanging about, too?
My carabine?
This is not a carabine.
It's a rifle.
Torsten!
Girl, you need to think.
We're going to buy soccer shoes.
Don't touch the pie.
Keep your paws off!
I want to find it in one piece.
Torsten, you coming?
Come by one of these days.
We'll make lasagna.
Lasagna!
She'll complain.
Damn, it's hot!
It's good, I got it.
What's the latest about
your troubles with your ex?
It's alright.
I know when you're lying.
You blink.
Really?
Don't lie to me.
She lets me see him
every second weekend.
Call Kirsten...
Forget the lawyers.
Silence, Fanny!
Don't talk about Kirsten.
Stop, Fanny!
You miss Marcus?
Obviously I miss my son.
- Phone Kirsten.
- Stop it!
Down!
- Down, you nasty mutt!
- Stop it!
Lie down!
Naughty!
He isn't happy to spend
12 days with you
and two days with me.
I think it works well.
Can I say something?
Thank you.
He wants to spend more time here.
I found a job and
he said you agreed.
Isn't it true?
Of course he'd say that, Lucas.
He feels sorry for you.
What? Feels sorry for me?!
Of course!
Behave like an adult.
Don't just think about yourself.
Exactly!
It was he who asked.
You're not even able to
respect our agreement.
You're not supposed to call me.
How can we discuss this
if you don't call me
and I'm not allowed
to call you?
When can we talk then?
I'm hanging up.
No. When can we talk?
Kirsten?
Old cock, big cock,
bent cock, gnarly cock!
Cocks, cocks!
Hi, Klara.
Look stiff as a club!
Let's go to my room.
Damn, what a huge cock!
Hello, Klara.
Good afternoon.
Listen, you have to take her.
You don't respect
any agreement!
What agreement?
Are they arguing?
Are you sad?
No, he needs a kick
in the ass.
When you have kids,
you take them to kindergarten.
Want me to walk you to kindergarten?
Good idea.
I'll tell your father.
Hi. What's all the noise?
It's Agnes. We can't find Klara.
She's here.
Shall I take her?
Gladly. Bye.
It's alright.
Let's go.
You, look where we're going
and I'll watch out for the cracks.
Let's do that.
You softies!
Who wants to fly?
Me too!
Alright, come on.
Let's take a break!
I can't take any more.
- To me!
- Me too!
He's dying.
Wake up!
Come on, wake up!
Who can raise the dead?
This is the hand of death.
It's time for fruit snacks.
- Fruit!
- Coming.
Put away the stuff first.
Klara?
Come see me.
I found a little gift
in my pocket.
Give it to a friend.
It's not from me.
It says "Klara".
Someone must have
played a trick.
How about you give it
to your mom
or to whoever made it?
And kisses on the mouth,
that's only for mom and dad.
It's not from me.
You lie.
Boys, put it away
and wash your hands.
- For real?
- Yes.
Hi, Pelle and Janus.
Hey, sweetie!
You still here?
Your mom won't be long.
Can't wait for Christmas?
Do you remember the song?
How about we sing it?
I hate Lucas.
I thought you were friends.
No way.
Why?
He's stupid.
And ugly.
And he has a weenie.
Like most men.
Like your dad and Torsten.
Yes
but his is stiff...
as a club.
What?
It's true.
What happened?
He gave me this heart
but I don't want it.
If that's how you feel,
just throw it away.
Will Santa come?
Y-yes...
- Who knows...
- I think so.
If you've been good, he will.
Hi, Grethe.
- Hi, Mommy.
- Hi, sweetie!
Why are you in the dark?
I'm really sorry.
I came as soon as possible.
Was everything fine?
Is there a problem?
No, we collected
mushrooms and animal poop
in the woods.
Sounds great!
Come, let's go.
See you soon, Klara.
Goodbye, Grethe.
Come on, sweetie.
We'll go home quick
and take care of dinner.
OK?
I'm delighted to hear it.
Something happened?
Goodbye.
See you soon!
Did you talk about it?
Yes. He wants to live with you.
He's very angry.
Everything will be fine.
I'll bring him to you
whenever he likes.
Okay?
You should talk to him.
I'll get him for you.
Sorry, I'm just passing through.
Dad?
Okay, Marcus?
Yes, but I can't change schools.
We'll manage.
I must go see mom.
You're right.
Marcus
Be nice to her.
She's in pain.
'Course. Bye.
I love you. See you soon.
Sorry. Hi.
Hi.
It was my son.
He's coming to live with me.
OK! Great
So maybe we should have
a cup of coffee to celebrate?
- "Kaffe".
- Kaffe.
Coffee now? Here?
Alright coffee.
With milk?
No, I take it black and strong.
But I make the coffee.
Yes, I make the coffee,
and you do the dishes.
I do no more dishes today.
So, that's it. Okay?
Like this?
Better to do it this way.
Like that.
You're very good at this.
Thank you.
Can you straighten up
the courtyard?
'Course.
Hey, very good!
So far I haven't found any job
that matches my education.
But, hey, I like it here.
I like all the fresh air, I like
the kids, I like all the nice people,
all the good-looking men.
Well, see you to-Moh.. Moh.
(Vi ses i morgen.)
Monday.
(Mandag)
See you tomorrow.
No, Monday. This is the weekend.
I enjoy seeing each other.
So do I.
Come here.
"Du er sd."
You're cute.
You too.
Just put it there.
You bagged nothing at all!
This is the first time
I came back empty-handed.
I assure you.
Your eyesight might be
deteriorating. Try these.
Listen everybody.
I'm going to call Ulla.
You bring the roast pork.
Eel.
Pudding.
- Johan, pork with apples.
- Let's toast
You take care of
the pork with apples.
This is Lucas.
Hello?
I can't hear a thing.
Just a moment.
Hello? Lucas, here.
Why do you never call me?
Sorry, what?
Because I don't
have your number.
Look on your phone.
It is on the display, right?
Yes it is.
So, call me.
Hello, it's Nadja.
It's me.
Who?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
And you?
I'm at a meeting.
(Some pussy!)
- No, not really.
- A meeting?
I'm really happy you called.
I think a lot about you.
So, should we meet?
Yeah, I'd like that.
Who did you call? A girl?
Stop, Bent.
I'm just trying to tell you
all he just called a woman.
Can Lucas, can Lucas,
can Lucas, drink a beert?!
Of course, but of course
But of course he can drank!
- I have a gift for you.
- And it's not even Christmas yet.
Come on, I'll help you.
- Did he drink a lot?
- Too many for me to count.
Thank you very much.
Lucas...
You're my best friend.
My best friend.
- See you next...
- Kisses.
Can you handle him?
Thanks for your help.
I'll call you in case of problems.
Agnes...
I have to speak to you.
You know why you're so pretty?
No.
Because you don't know it.
- My love...
- I love you.
I love you.
I love you very much.
- Did you wait long?
- Yes.
Sorry.
This is my dog, Fanny.
This is my kitchen.
- You want some coffee? Or...
- No.
Fanny!
Where are you?
Come!
Thanks for the ball.
She learned that when
she was one year old.
Fanny! She wants
to see it again.
She wants to see it again.
Where does the dog sleep?
Downstairs.
- Good Idea?
- Yeah.
- I throw the ball.
- Throw it.
Good.
- Can you see?
- I see you.
You won't strangle me, eh?
Socks or no socks?
Socks.
I scared you for once!
Lucas!
Hi!
- I'll get you!
- Can you come here?
Yeah, coming.
I can't catch you, kids.
I'll drink some magic potion
and I'll come back.
Hello, Grethe.
Hello, Lucas. Sit.
How's little Marcus?
Fine. Not so little anymore.
He wants to move in with me
before Christmas.
Try as I might...
but I can't stop
thinking about this:
A child told me something.
I must speak to you about it.
Sure.
This child has a vivid imagination,
but we should discuss it.
Sure.
Who it is?
I can't say.
According to this child,
some things happened.
Adult things.
What things? What happened?
This child, girl or boy, claims...
it doesn't like you.
And he or she saw
your private parts.
How is such a thing possible?
I don't know.
Damn!
This is serious,
but don't worry.
I draw no conclusion.
We'll see.
What was said, exactly?
I can't answer that.
It's time for fruit snacks,
let's go.
Take a few days off,
until we find out more.
Finish your day.
We'll find a solution.
Alright.
Did I make you wait?
No, it's okay.
I don't know how
to go about this.
Let's start now.
Klara...
can you tell me exactly
what you said to Grethe?
Please, tell him
what you told me
about the heart-shaped cookie.
I said nothing.
So, it's just...
Grethe who made it all up?
- Or did you make it up?
- No.
Good.
So try telling me.
You can tell.
Is it true what you said?
That you saw...
Lucas' weenie?
Can you tell me what Lucas did.
You can try, Klara.
I wanna go play.
But you need to answer.
Don't be afraid.
Ole is nice.
He just wants to know
what happened.
Did he show you
his weenie, here?
Is that it?
You nod your head.
It was here, in kindergarten?
Tell me what happened.
Grethe said you explained
his weenie was all hard.
His weenie was quite hard?
I think so. I don't remember.
But he showed you his weenie?
Does it upset you
to talk about Lucas?
Because you don't like
what he did?
You're doing very well
at answering my questions.
We're almost done.
What did he do...
after showning you his willy?
I don't know.
Did you touch it?
Do you remember?
Did some white stuff come out?
Maybe too much all at once.
You can go play.
You think?...
Yeah, just keep an eye on her.
You and me, we know.
That's a good thing.
But this case,
concerns the police.
And we need
the parents' consent.
Thanks for your help.
I don't know how
to handle it.
Klara has a wild imagination.
But I believe her.
Anyway, she doesn't seem
to have made it all up.
No.
Ole thinks we must
report this matter.
We must notify
the authorities.
Is the parents'
meeting canceled?
I don't think so.
We are obliged to
inform other parents.
Where's Klara?
She's playing outside.
Where's Lucas?
He's also playing outside.
What if he went home?
Yes, that's better.
- Hi, Grethe.
- Hi.
- Torsten.
- Grethe.
We were leaving for
soccer when you called.
Sit.
I thought it was at 7:PM.
Everything okay?
We need to talk about Klara.
It's better if Torsten waited outside.
Torsten wake up.
Go text somebody, or play.
I won't be long.
What did that
rascal do, now?
Something happened that's forbidden
between children and adults.
I'm sincerely sorry.
I couldn't prevent it.
Klara gave
sexual details
about an adult.
I don't think children lie
about these things.
I don't understand.
What are you trying to say?
It seems...
Klara was a victim
of sexual abuse, here.
Probably by a
close family friend.
Sexual abuse?
What she said...
She'll surely deny it all
because she is ashamed.
But...
How?
We'll check to see how
serious the situation is.
Hello! Here's the cake.
- No lactose?
- Yeah.
Your attention, please.
There's a new item
on the agenda.
There is suspicion of
indecent behaviour...
towards children.
It may be assumed that
an adult has abused a child.
There may be several victims.
Watch for
any consequent symptoms.
Bedwetting, headaches, nightmares.
We will go into details.
Please read this brochure.
This is a serious accusation!
No need to panic.
We will follow procedure
to the letter, of course.
Hello, Marcus.
Hello?
Dad?
Why are you whispering?
I'm not allowed to call you.
Who forbids you?
Did something happen?
Are you crying?
They say stuff about you.
I'm not allowed to talk to you.
Or live with you.
Who said that? Your mother?
They say disgusting stuff
happened at the kindergarten.
Don't listen to them.
It's not true.
Who called?
Grethe from the kindergarten.
Go to school as usual.
We'll talk tonight.
Don't worry.
Okay, m'dear?
I should have told you,
I'm sorry.
Yesterday...
I was told that a child said
I had shown him my weiner...
or "her".
I'm sorry, but...
that is...
really far out!
Marcus's mother was informed.
By whom?
Hi, Lucas!
Hi.
Not now, guys.
Is Grethe in?
I thought you were on leave.
I just need to...
What are you all doing here?
I need to speak to you.
I'm busy.
Go home.
Leave Grethe alone.
Grethe!
Come back!
Stop!
Where are you going?
This is absurd.
I asked you not to come!
I'm not hurting anyone.
Stop where you are.
How could you?
You disgust me!
What have I done?
It feels wrong
just to be around you.
Let me tell you what's wrong.
You called Marcus' mother
and now he's not allowed
to come see me.
What do you think he's thinking?
I think kids don't lie.
Leave Marcus alone. Got it?
Leave my family out of it.
Got it?
You, leave my kids alone.
You are sick!
Klara is an innocent little girl.
It's Klara?
- Come on.
- I'm talking, Johan.
- Let's go.
- What did she say?
She's the daughter
of my best friend.
Come on.
Shit, it's Klara!
I need to talk to Theo.
Come on.
What are you doing here?
Why is Ulla crying?
You can't stay there.
What the fuck?
What is it?
We have nothing to say. Go!
Have you lost your head?
Maybe. Move it.
What are you looking at?
Go, Lucas.
Hi, Theo.
We need to talk.
The others are asleep.
I'll get something to drink.
I made lemonade.
If you're thirsty...
Thanks.
Listen,
we need to talk.
What are they saying?
You need to ask
your daughter.
They won't tell me anything.
It's gotten way out of hand.
You and me have to bring
things out in the open.
We need to see Grethe
before it degenerates all the way.
You want me to ask Klara?
- Is this what you want?
- That you ask Klara?
Of course. Why?
I know her.
She doesn't lie.
She's never lied.
Why would she lie?
I don't know.
But she's lying about this.
Damn, Lucas...
I haven't touched your daughter.
You know that.
Do you believe me...
or not?
I don't know.
Theo, I haven't touched your daughter.
What's he doing here?
He isn't supposed to be here.
I suppose not.
- Lucas, go away.
- What have I done?
Get out!
What do you think I did?
Shut up and go!
I don't wanna talk to you!
Disappear!
I forbid you to sit
on our couch, bastard!
I never want to see you again!
I'll cut your prick off!
Are you crazy?
If you have, touched my daughter,
I'll put a bullet in the head.
And I believe you did it,
because she says so.
You wanna fuck up my life,
is that it?
Look at me!
What are you doing?
Hi, Klara.
Hi, Lucas.
Go to your room.
Agnes!
Come into the living room.
Dad is sad?
It'll pass,
you know.
We'll stay here until
we're all wide wake.
You angry at Lucas?
Let's cuddle a bit like this.
He hasn't done anything.
I made up nonsense, that's all.
Now all the kids
talk about it.
It didn't happen.
Klara... Sweetheart.
It's hard to understand
but it can happen.
Your brain would rather
forget what happened.
It's unpleasant
to think about.
But it happened.
And we're very happy
you told us about it.
Okay, darling?
Come!
Let's eat some cake.
Hello, Nadja.
Come in, sit.
Surely you're aware...
we reported the incident to the police.
Should I speak English?
No, it's okay.
Knowing the symptoms
of sexual abuse,
parents have asked their children
if they had nightmares.
You know?
Several parents
reported symptoms of abuse.
So we took action.
Why am I here?
Are you seeing Lucas?
Is Lucas your boyfriend?
- Yeah.
- I'll try to say it in English.
It is our duty
to inform the authorities
about such matters,
in a very serious
case like this.
OK. Why?
I don't think,
that anyone here
is any longer in doubt about what Lucas
has done.
Lucas brought Klara here.
They were seen together.
He is alone with the children.
In the toilet or the playroom.
Kirsten, it's me again.
Call me.
Doesn't answer.
Maybe she needs more time.
I need to talk to Marcus.
What are they saying at work?
Hi Klara.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Can I take Fanny for a walk?
OK, sure.
Does mom know where you are?
You should tell her before coming.
They say you hurt me.
Do you think so, too?
I don't know, I don't remember.
What did I do, sweetie?
I don't remember anymore.
And also the others.
What others?
Who do you mean?
I'm scared.
You want to go home?
What about Fanny?
You can walk her another time.
You'd better go home.
Did you touch that girl?
What?
You're not a sick person, right?
What do you think?
No... Ahm.. I'm just...
I'm getting a little...
disoriented.
How so?
Sorry it doesn't matter.
You think I'm crazy?
Is that it?
Go away. Take your stuff.
Stop it.
- I want you to go.
- Hey, hey...[Russian?]
Why are you doing this?
I abused a child.
That's what you're implying, idiot!
Go!
Clear off!
Look, it's snowing.
- Pile it on the elf.
- Yes.
Him...
he should be on the lake.
That's right.
They're skating.
Where does he go?
You choose.
There.
And he goes on top.
That way, he can see everything.
Shouldn't he join the others?
It's snowing!
Don't you wanna see?
- I'm coming.
- Come on!
How beautiful it is!
Don't catch cold.
December
What the...?!
Marcus?
Is that you?
Sorry. Come.
You scared me.
I didn't mean to.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Hi, Fanny.
Old girl!
Let's go in.
Your mother know you're here?
Yeah.
Where's the key?
I gave it to someone.
I'll ask for it back.
Fanny, come!
Are you hungry?
What a mess! It's filthy.
Come.
Stop it.
Mom suggested
I come to say hello.
Shouldn't you be in class?
I took a few days off.
You know the situation
is not normal around here.
I was fired.
The police is on the case,
but no one tells me a damn thing.
I'm going crazy.
Mom know you're here?
Right?
Fuck!
I'm crying again.
You want to talk?
It's okay.
- I'll be alright.
- Don't worry.
- Sorry.
- It's alright.
This is ridiculous.
Come.
Hi.
My godson!
Hi, Marcus.
You were able to come!
What an atmosphere in here!
Coffee?
- Have you talked to the police?
- Yeah.
What did they say?
They asked a lot of questions.
Apparently, I'm supposed to
have touched other children.
This is madness.
Altogether.
But damn, you did nothing!
Now they're all ganged up.
Johan, Bent...
They all lost their marbles.
You let them walk all over you.
I already told you.
Is Fanny okay?
Kirsten!
Still works.
I don't know.
Thank you.
It'll be alright.
Marcus is here.
He won't even pour a coffee
for his godfather.
How about your hunting license?
- October 16.
- The 16th?
The day when the man becomes a boy
and the boy becomes a man.
Tell mom that you're here.
Marcus?
If she gets angry,
I'll set her her straight.
That'll be 269.50.
- There.
- Thank you.
- And here's 30.50.
Hi, Marcus!
Your father around?
Tell him, we don't want
either of you here, anymore.
- Why?
- You know how it is...
We have other customers.
Just don't come.
What's going on?
- Is this your son?
- Yes.
Do you mind?
Call mom, tell her
to come get you.
I've been arrested.
I have to go.
Okay?
Get in.
Slide over.
Fuck!
Do you have a key
to our house?
A key? I don't think so.
- I'm going.
- Marcus!
Okay?
Look, we know they
nabbed your father.
Can I talk to you?
What?
Yes, but...
Come in. Are you hungry?
Say hello to Marcus.
Klara, you can get the glasses?
Hi, Marcus.
Hi.
So ... Later!
He's there.
Marcus... we can drop you off.
Or, call your mother.
Marcus, you okay?
Will you help my father?
Help your father?
How so?
Will you think about it?
Marcus, you're a nice boy
and I understand how you feel.
You don't have to pay for his mistakes.
He hasn't done what he's accused of.
Go to your room, dear.
I want to talk to Klara.
- Hi, Klara.
- Hi.
Are you okay?
Why are you lying?
I'm not lying.
Come on, Klara.
I just want to talk...
Enough!
Stop it!
- Don't touch her.
- Piss off!
Enough!
I just wanna talk to her!
Why are you lying, bitch?
It's not true!
- Get him out!
- I wanna talk to her!
Enough.
Fuck!
Stop, Johan!
Enough!
Stop.
Get off me!
Leave him alone!
- Get up and go home.
- Move it!
Go home.
Bunch of bastards!
Come.
I'm glad to see you.
Come in and get warm.
Damn, you're exhausted.
Did somebody hit you?
No.
Holy shit!
Less noise, girls!
We've got relatives visiting.
My two sisters.
You met them when
you were little.
It's been a while!
Okay?
Fine.
Chip and Dale.
Cracking nuts.
My father... He's trying
to help out yours.
Here's Lucas' son, Marcus.
My brothers-in-law.
Elias
and Erik.
I'm Erik.
This jerk is Elias.
Sit.
Offer him a drink.
You thirsty?
Is water, okay?
Thank you.
Marcus, I spoke to your mother.
Don't forget to call home.
Okay?
You know what'll happen to Dad?
What did your old man say?
He said Lucas will have
a preliminary hearing tomorrow.
At 8 h 30.
There are two options.
Either the judge upholds
"preventive detention",
or he finds no reason to
continue holding him.
Which do you think it'll be?
I don't know.
But...
apparently all the children
say the same thing.
They describe your basement.
Wallpaper, color of the sofa...
But when the police searched
the house this morning...
What did they discover, Marcus?
We have no basement.
Exactly.
- What does that mean?
- They have no basement.
What does it mean for Lucas?
That there is still hope.
What's the story?
Children often invent
details that do not exist.
I don't know if it's their imagination
or if they repeat what their peers
or their parents say.
We always assume
that children don't lie.
Unfortunately, they lie often.
And now?
Now?
We'll see.
They'll call us tomorrow.
Morning, big guy.
Sleep well?
I brought bread
cheese and coffee.
Thanks.
I need to talk to you.
I must tell you,
I'm your godfather
and you can count on me.
Whatever happens. Okay?
I just spoke to your father.
It looks good.
He's coming by taxi.
What?
They released him.
Eat your toast and drink your coffee.
Afterwards, we'll go downstairs
to welcome to your father.
Hello!
If you fondle your kid
you'll end up back in jail.
The eggs and bacon
won't eat themselves.
Come on.
It's nice to see you again,
scoundrel!
Fanny! Hello, my girl!
It could have been worse.
You two, take a shovel
and dig a basement.
Fanny peed on the floor.
No, it must have been
the policemen!
- Fanny!
- She'll come back.
You want me to wash
the pants that I found?
Well?
What are you getting at?
Nothing.
I just wonder if
I should wash it.
Yes, if you found it.
I'll be a minute.
You're gonna wear it dirty.
Is this your girlfriend?
I thought she was,
before all this happened.
I wanted to introduce you,
but we'll see.
- Do you have a girlfriend?
- No.
It's not my thing.
To have a girlfriend?
No.
And Jasmin?
That was over a year ago!
Stay there.
Don't move.
What is it?
- What is it, Dad?
- Go back in.
Let's go back.
Come on, Marcus.
Forget it!
- You're all dead!
- Stop.
- Calm down.
- You will die!
Come here.
- Let go of me!
- Stop it.
I'll kill you!
Don't leave her out there.
Lucas?
I'd like to be alone.
Where's Marcus?
You sent him back
to his mother?
Yeah.
Go back home.
Please leave me, Bruun.
Come inside.
I told you to leave!
Get out! Go home!
Go away.
There you are.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Per.
I'd like two cutlets.
I don't have any.
I meant these pork cutlets.
I won't sell you anything.
I have the right to be here.
Go away.
Hit the road.
I want two cutlets.
And now go away.
Don't set foot in here again.
We don't want
anything to do with you.
He hit me.
You can't just hit
someone like that.
Go now.
- Is that okay - to hit someone?
- Outside!
- I can walk.
- Then go away.
- I want my stuff.
- Get out, quick!
I want my stuff!
- We have to actually
'throw' this guy out!
- C'mon!
Get out!
Thanks for the visit.
And go get fucked!
Go home.
Don't set foot here again.
Don't let me see you again.
Didn't I tell you
to go fuck yourself?
I won't tell you again!
I just have one thing to say.
- Damn!
- What's wrong?
That's my business.
Give him his stuff.
Fuck, shit!
45.50.
My God, it's Lucas!
Look at the state he's in!
I'll talk to him.
Let's stay here until he goes.
Where's Fanny?
I don't know.
Shit!
CHRISTMAS EVE
I'd like to come in.
Welcome, everyone.
And Merry Christmas.
We will celebrate Christmas mass.
As always,
we begin with a prayer.
Lord,
I'm in your house
to hear Your word.
God the Father
You, Lord Jesus,
and the Holy Spirit, you
comfort me in life and death.
Lord
may the Holy Spirit open my heart,
in the name of Jesus Christ,
so that I may learn
to repent my sins,
to believe in Jesus,
and to live each day
in holiness.
Hear me and grant my prayer,
my God,
in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.
Christmas Eve is dedicated
to the Child Jesus.
The son of God is born.
What is it?
I see it in his face.
You see what?
We can think about that
as we pray to the Lord.
You say "Father"
and then
you become
a child of God.
This is the beginning.
Christmas time
is a time of children.
This year, we celebrate Christmas
by relying on the gospel.
We've invited
the kindergarten choir
who have rehearsed,
and now perform for us
"A Child is born in Bethlehem"
Come forward.
Stand there.
Like that.
Klara, stand there.
One step forward.
A child is born in Bethlehem!
In Bethlehem!
Rejoice,
Jerusalem!
Hallelujah!
What do you say?
You got something to tell me?
- Wanna talk to me?
- Stop.
You got something to say?
Calm down!
- Calm down!
- The whole town is here.
- Calm down.
- Wanna talk to me?
You're sick!
I'm listening!
Enough, you dirty psycho!
I want to talk to Theo.
Look me in the eye.
In the eyes.
What do you see?
You see something?
Nothing.
There is nothing.
Nothing at all.
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone now, Theo. OK?
I'll go. Thank you.
You sure got enough gifts!
You're lucky.
It's exactly what you wanted.
I got her.
Fanny...
Lucas...
Hi, Lucas.
It shouldn't have happened.
Klara, my dear.
It's not Lucas, it's dad.
- Dad, are you crying?
- No.
It's just that...
the world is full of wickedness.
But if we support each other,
it will eventually go away.
You're really sad?
No.
You know...
Lucas
is daddy's
best friend.
Together...
we rode our mopeds,
stole apples and everything.
I've told you that.
I just said some stupid stuff.
He didn't do anything.
No.
Go beddy-byes.
What are you doing?
Go join the others.
Who is that for?
Give me ten minutes.
I'll be back.
Theo...
don't go to him.
Let me do this, Agnes.
It's only me.
What are you doing here?
I brought you some food.
Just in case...
Are you hungry?
Go ahead, eat,
if you want.
This is very good.
You can go home if you want.
Actually, I'd like
to stay a while.
If it's OK with you.
ONE YEAR LATER
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Hello, Jorgen.
- Torsten.
- Marcus.
Hi, Dan. We're back.
- Glad to see you.
- Me too.
Silence, please.
We're all gathered here
for a reason.
This is the day
when the boy becomes a man
and man becomes a boy.
Marcus, big guy,
you have your hunting license
and tomorrow, at daybreak,
it will be your turn.
You'll become a man.
You'll conquer the forest.
Come here, buddy.
It's a great joy to see you here.
This is for you.
I'd be delighted
if you were my son
and if this gift came from me.
But it's a gift from your father.
He passes it on to you.
It's been in the family
for generations
and now
it's yours.
Take good care of it.
Your grandfather
missed many a deer
before he could feed
your family with it.
Do not forget it. Congratulations.
Hopefully he'll drink a cup with us!
A shot with us!
Health and congratulations!
Lunch is served.
Any more left?
- We'll bring more.
- Thank you.
This is not easy.
All these lines you must avoid!
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Hi, Klara.
Are you okay?
How 'can' you avoid these lines?
I don't know. There are so many.
Come.
Careful...
Must take giant steps.
Made it!
I think your dad is there.
- Thanks.
- Not at all.
You're scaring the deer.
What?
- Did I ruin everything?
- No.
They'll be back.
Stay at your post.
It may take a while
but the deer will come.
Are you ready?
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player