Dawn Of The Planet Of The Apes
Caesar
They're close
koba
Everybody! Take your positions
Now, Father?
son, stay.
stay back
Thank You, Koba.
my son
Think before you act, son.
Done feel bad, Blue Eyes...
scars make you strong.
come meet your new brother.
another son?
makes me think how far we've come
seems long ago.
still think of them?
humans?
sometimes.
Didn't know them like you did.
Only saw their bad side.
Good, Bad... doesn't matter now.
Humans destroyed each other
apes fight too..
but we are family
wonder if they are really all gone.
Ten winters now...
Last two... no sign of them.
They must be gone.
That bear wouldn't get me blue eyes. I'm quick!
Shut up, Ash!
they shot Ash! Shot my son!
Rocket, Wait..
koba
follow them
Must attack them now!
Before they attack us!
We dont know how many there are.
How many Guns they have?
Or why they came up here?
They shot your son, Rocket!
Dont you want to fight?
I follow Caesar.
Koba's right!
They almost killed you, Ash.
If we go to war...
We could lose all we've built
Home!
Family!
Future!
I will decide by morning.
Caesar
For years I wan prisoner in their lab...
They cut me
tortured me
you freed me.
I would do anything you asked.
But we must show strength!
We will, Koba!
If they get power, they'll be more dangerous!
Why help them?
They seem desperate...
If we make them go, they will attack.
LET THEM!
we'll destroy them while they are weak.
And how many apes will die?
we have one chance for peace..
Let them do their human work, then they'll go
Human Work?
Human work.
Human! work!
Koba says, Apes should hate humans..
Enough!
From Humans, Koba learned hate...
But nothing else..
You sound sick... You ok?
Just need rest..
You worry about humans...
Where's Koba?
Still angry.
said he was going hunting...
Look! Humans below...
Why are we here?
Caesar, trusts humans...
Koba, does not..
Enough guns here to kill every Ape...
Must warn Caesar.
Who knows what humans are really doing up there?
Father, No..!
I will not help!
Just came from city.. Humans very dangerous!
Where's Caesar?
with the Humans...:(
You are my son...
I need you to listen...
You didn't tell Caesar about the guns we found?
Neither will you...
Your father doesn't trust me now
You need to protect him.
His love for humans
makes him blind.
I know.
As long as they are here
I fear for Caesar's life
Feeling better?
Human Gun!
Go! Get them!
Females and young stay in the woods...
We go to the city!
We Will Avenge Your Father's Death.
Humans Escaping! Capture them!
Followed the Humans here! They are escaping everywhere
We must catch them all!
Go ahead Ash...
...make Humans pay.
Caesay wouldn't want this.
Maurice...?
Koba said...
.. we're too loyal to your father.
Protect yourself!
for now.
I'm so sorry.
For everything
But KOBA betrayed you.
on the Human Tower
Loyal Apes around him.
Prisoners
Maurice
Rocket
Koba killed Ash
Fear makes other follow
But when they see you alive
They will turn from Koba
Koba sent for females and young
They are on their way
Mother too