You must go home! Mama said that
you should come home immediately!
There is a man, with a
big, big motorcycle!
He said Rosa is dead.
Gelsomina! You know Zampano,
Rosa's husband?
My poor daughter! She died far from
home. I'll never see her grave!
She is dead, the poor thing!
She was so beautiful, worked so hard!
She could do everything!
Look at her, Zampano,
she looks like Rosa.
This is Gelsomina.
How miserable we are!
Of course, Zampano,
she isn't Rosa, but she's of
good nature and disciplined,
just a little bit strange,
but if she gets food every
day, she'll get better.
Do you want to go with Zampano
and take Rosa's place?
You can learn something,
earn money,
and we'd have one hungry
soul less to feed.
Zampano is a kind man,
he'll be good to you.
You will see the world,
learn to sing and dance,
and look what he did:
He gave me 10.000 Lire!
We could repair the roof and
buy some food again...
Why did your father have to
leave us so early...
You've already grown
but never worked.
It's not your fault, that you're
not like the other girls.
Don't you want to help your mother?
Zampano, will she learn something?
Sure, I can teach things
even to a dog!
All right,
buy salami, 1/2 cheese
and two bottles of wine.
- That's how I am.
- Thank him, children.
Where are you going?
Come here!
What are you doing?
- You'll go away, Gelsomina?
- I'll work, learn something
and send some money home.
I'll become an artist,
will dance and sing like Rosa...
- And, when you'll return?
- When she'll return?
Don't go away!
My dear child! Stay with me!
We'll be back soon!
Departure!
Your things, Gelsomina!
Your scarf!
Get in!
My daughter!
My poor daughter!
This chain is 0.5 cm thick,
pure iron, stronger then steel!
With a simple expansion of
the chest muscles...
I'll blow up the hook!
Thanks.
For that I have to blow up
my lungs like a hose!
There is a danger that a vein
bursts and I spit blood!
Once in Milan,
a 70 kg man lost his eyesight,
when he tried it.
The eyeballs have to
stand the pressure!
And when the eyesight is
lost, then it's over!
Those, who have weak nerves,
should better look away.
It could bleed!
You never used to cook
at home, didn't you?
What a rank shit!
Here are enough clothes for ten
people. Shoes, dresses, anything.
Come here, maybe some of
them will suit you right.
You have to look exquisite. You don't
travel with Zampano in rags.
My ladies always looked tasteful!
Now say: "Here comes Zampano!"
Here comes Zampano.
Come here!
That's a trumpet.
You do only, what I tell you.
This is a tambour.
Here comes Zampano!
Here comes Zampano.
Zampano is here.
Once again!
Here comes Zampano.
Come here.
Here.
Again!
Zampano is here!
That's how you have to say it:
Here comes Zampano!
Come on!
Here comes Zampano...
Fire which burns, sparks in heaven,
night without an end... Booh, booh...
What are you doing?
It'll rain in two days.
- How do you know?
- It'll rain!
Come here.
Get in.
- I'll sleep outside.
- Oh really?
Now listen:
- What's your name?
- Di Costanzo Gelsomina.
Come on, Gelsomina, move.
- Tomorrow.
- Come on, get in!
Thank You.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for the first time in this city,
a new posse, about which you
can laugh from the heart!
Enjoy it!
Those, who have a weak
heart shouldn't watch,
they could die from laughter!
And because not even the greatest
artist can live with air only,
my wife will reach the
hat around afterwards.
Go, go!
Quickly!
Good day, Signorina Gelsomina!
Zampano!
Pardon my question, aren't You
afraid of my "Rufle"?
I said, aren't You afraid
of my "Rufle"?!
All right, then we'll go and
hunt some with my "Rufle".
Ha-ha-ha, that's not a "Rufle",
that's a "Rifle"! Dummy!
Where are the ducks?
If here are no ducks, you're
the duck and I am the hunter!
No! That's a donkey, not a duck!
Thank You!
My wife asks you now
for a small donation.
Whoever gives something and those, who can't
afford anything, all are appreciated.
- Good evening.
- Close the door!
- What's up, fatso?
- Hi, Zampano.
- Hey, Zingaro, you're here too?
- Zampano, how is it goin'?
That's my wife.
wife? A new girlfriend,
I'm glad to hear.
- Sit down.
- It's fine, we'll sit there.
Waiter!
- Should I leave?
- No, stay here!
- Waiter!
- I'm coming.
Give us some food.
Lamb roast and ragout are
ready to be served.
What would you have?
- This.
- Lamb or ragout?
Both of them.
- Both?
- Yes, both.
- Lamb roast with noodles for me.
- All right.
And one litre of red wine.
- Where are you from?
- From my home village.
You speak different from the people
here. Where were you born?
In my father's home.
Waiter, one more bottle!
That supposed to be wool? It's wadding!
It'll hang between the toes!
Hey, redhead! Come here!
- You're talking to me?
- Yea, come here!
Good evening.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Sit down there.
- You want something to drink?
- Gladly.
- Wine, but fast!
- This restaurant doesn't please me at all.
A cigarette?
- I know you from somewhere.
- It's possible, I have been around.
Here, the wine.
- Have you already eaten?
- Yes.
Here to you!
Where have I seen you?
What do you work?
I'm a travelling artist.
She's my assistant.
I taught her everything,
She couldn't even say
"I-A" on her own!
Here, feel it.
What a nasty guy you are!
Here, look at this.
Earned all of it within
an hour with those.
May I?
She's a real brand!
Let's go outside, it stinks here!
- Let's watch the fireworks.
- Let's go then.
Waiter, two more bottles!
- What do you get?
- 4.200 with these two.
Still here at this time?
- How's the business?
- It's okay.
Put the bottles in the wagon.
Redhead, where do you go?
- Get in!
- Is this your car?
- Are you crazy?
- That's an American,
never failed in seven years!
- Oh my God, what are you doing?
- Do you hear, what motor it is?
- Should I enter in the back?
- You wait here.
Where do you go?
Still here?
Why you don't eat the soup?
Why she doesn't eat?
She doesn't want to, something
is wrong with her.
No, I won't eat my soup!
Do you see? Ingratitude
is the world's wage.
Is that not your husband
with that strange car?
That's surely him.
His vehicle is near the sand pits.
- Where?
- Where the city ends.
You have to climb over.
Are You awake?
I sowed some tomatoes.
Tomatoes!
I found some real tomato seeds
and put them into earth.
Get in, let's go!
- We move along?
- You want to wait for the tomatoes to grow?!
Go and push.
You did it the same way with Rosa?
What?
With Rosa.
What are you talking about?
Why You left with that woman?
- You did it the same way with Rosa?
- Stop it!
What do you want?
So You go with other women?
What?
You go with other women?
If you want to stay with me, you'll
need to learn one thing before all:
to shut your mouth!
Tomatoes!
What thoughts you got in your head?!
Here.
Dear guests!
To the wedding couple!
The funny Bajazzo.
- Hey, you there!
- She calls us.
- You have to eat something too.
- Thank You, we're coming
- Where are You?
- Come and sit with us!
No time.
Come with me!
- I have to eat first.
- Come!
Where are you taking me?
I'll slap you, if you
won't let me go.
Oswaldo, look who's here!
This is Oswaldo, he's ill
and may not go outside.
No one visits him. Make
him laugh a little.
How?
The way you did before, downstairs.
Birdie-bird...
What are you dong here?
I'll teach you manners!
And what do You want? Out!
Do You always eat standing,
like a horse?
I always eat that way.
I saw enough marriages, was married
twice myself, both husbands are dead.
I'm standing in the kitchen since three
o'clock, but I'm not tired yet!
I could dance the whole night long,
the youngsters can't handle it anymore.
Why You won't marry?
One more husband? No, thanks.
I like to decide on my own!
Do You need men only to make...
decisions?
Why? I'm not made of stone,
everybody needs some joy, or not?
What do you want? Get lost!
My first husband was as big
and strong as You are.
I still have his suits,
they fit for no one.
There, upstairs...!
I'll bring You some.
There is a boy with a inspectrice...
Here, eat some.
Help me to get some wine -
there is not much left.
Tell me, all the suits...
are just hanging there?
- There are no big men anymore.
- Is there a hat too?
- I could use one.
- Yes, come and see for yourself.
Good bye!
Zampano, do You remember,
how beautiful it sounded?
The day when it rained...
Teach me to play the trumpet,
I'll learn it fast for sure.
You taught it to Rosa too?
She worked the same like me?
And, how do I look?
Right for the women!
May I smoke in here?
- What's up with you?
- Nothing!
- Why are you blubbering then?
- Because...
Come up!
Come on.
- You want to stay there the whole night?
- Yes, the whole night!
I go away.
Back to my village. I don't like
it here with You anymore!
It's not because of the work:
I like this work.
I like being an artist!
But I don't like You!
What?
I leave!
- I go home.
- Stop the bullshit.
I let the shoes here. And
this coat I leave too.
I let everything here.
Enough! Always the same!
I leave!
And now "Il Matto" will show us
his most dangerous attraction!
He'll eat spaghetti standing
in a forty meter height!
We ask for absolute silence,
already the smallest distraction
can let it end deadly!
Dear audience!
Now you'll see "Il Matto"
with his unique performance!
Hey, how are you up there?
Everything is fine?
I'm fine, but it freshens up a little,
additionally I have a hunger!
You can say, I'm 2
times hungrier now!
This wind! It stole my napkin!
Why You don't ask, whether someone
want to take a place with You?
Who wants to come, is welcome!
Thanks, thank You very much.
One moment!
- Anna, I'll wait for you at the tavern.
- All right.
Watch out!
Make some room!
Soldats! Attention!
- One, two, one...
- A crazy girl!
I go home.
- Hey, you want to drink some?
- She already drank more then us!
Get in.
I don't want to go with You.
I don't want it anymore!
No, never!
Get in!
Come here!
Move!
Quickly!
And be quiet!
You want to say something?
Good, already thought you don't!
Good morning.
Come over here!
Please, take a seat!
Say hello to the boss and his wife.
Everything she knows,
she learned from me.
Do You want some coffee?
Come on! Drink it.
When I picked her up, she
didn't even have shoes.
But she didn't come around
much in the world yet.
Strong wind today. Do not
let the tent fly away!
There is no wage, you'll get anything,
what you'll be able to collect.
Every artist goes around with
the hat, no one gets short.
- I never had any controversies.
- You'll start today then.
I can see, You have one
for the hat already.
Take care of the tent, it flies away!
- Where are we here?
- In Rom, this is St. Paul.
And we'll work in a circus?
- Good material it is.
- Come with me, please.
- How many people go here altogether?
- 400 places, and ones, who stand...
Do You know him?
Good morning.
Who we've got here! Mr. "Rufle"!
It's great, that You gave him an appointment,
a good circus needs animals!
Sorry, I'm just kidding.
A cigarette?
Oh, you got one already.
He's really a great artist.
A great programme, but
your best piece is
that chain thing, this is phenomenal.
I give you a good advice:
Don't speak to me. Never!
Otherwise there'll be a tragedy.
Got it?
- It was just a joke...
- I warned you.
Madame!
Well done!
Be brave, "Rufle"!
What a poseur!
Stay calm, otherwise you'll fail!
And now a new attraction in
the world famous circus "Girafa":
Zampano! A man with lungs of steel.
Dear audience!
Here is a chain, from what each
limb is thicker then 0.5 cm, pure
iron, stronger than steel!
I'll put it around my chest and
close it with this hook.
By a simple expansion of the chest
muscles, I'll blow up the hook.
You think the hook is a fake?
Wait a moment!
Convince yourself!
This patch I got for
protectional purposes...
Bravo! Bravissimo!
...but not to let you see how the
hook bores itself in the meat.
You don't need to have
the strength of 4 bulls,
You don't have to be a professor,
in order to understand, that
for this unique attraction
only three things are necessary:
steel muscles, iron lungs
and superhuman strength.
Leave the audience!
Those, who have weak nerves,
should better look away...
It starts with a dull drumroll.
Signorina Gelsomina, please!
Zampano, excuse me,
a phone call for you!
You bastard!
It's your turn now, come on, quick!
Don't get angry, let me talk to him.
I'll kill him!
Where is he?
Where are you?
- Where are you?
- Be reasonable! Stay here!
- Did he hide here somewhere?
- Nobody's here.
Behind which stone did you crawl?
You'll have enough of
your dumb jokes!
This coward hides from me...
- Why is he so hostile to You?
- I don't know.
- You did something to him?
- Nothing, never did!
He insults me, but one day
there'll be a payoff!
Who is he?
A son of a gipsy.
- You know him from former times?
- Unfortunately I do.
Did Rosa know him too?
He doesn't know anybody - neither
Rosa nor me, understood?
I don't want to hear anything about
him anymore. I go to bed.
Here she comes! Look, how she walks!
And what a face she has!
You see?
You take this. Let's go.
Put the bucket away.
I've got my own methods,
they always work.
- Gelsomina works with us!
- Calm down.
Try it.
Wonderful, what a talent!
And now, attention!
I play the violin, and
when you hear this...
you sneak quietly behind
me 'till there,
and blow the trombone.
- Got it? Let's try.
- I can't.
- Why?
- Zampano doesn't want me to.
Do You hear that? Afterwards
I'll be accused again.
Get Zampano. Let's see, who
decides here about whom.
- He went to the city.
- I'll talk to him later then.
Don't be afraid, we're one family,
we work together. What you
learn is good for all of us.
Attention: when I play this...
Got it? Really?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'll play a very,
very sad melody for you.
Come on, now!
Wonderful! Very good.
Travelling with Zampano
harms the intelligence!
You should interrupt me
and come where I am standing!
We try it again. Now!
Nice, you see?
Watch out: we do it three times.
Then I go around the manege,
while you walk behind me
and blows the trombone.
Got it?
It's very simple.
One finger here and the other there.
Bravo, Gelsomina!
And now let's go:
One, two...
What's the problem, Zampano?
I told her to work with him.
She works only with me.
You weren't here, or I
would have ask You.
What's the big deal?
We work together here.
She won't work with him!
You will leave her in peace!
I don't talk with you. You've
forbidden me to do it.
Although I won't say anything.
Go to my wife, Gelsomina,
I'll deal with this.
She stays here. I decide,
what she's got to do.
And she's not allowed to
work with this vagabond!
- Why not?
- Because I want it that way.
I want it that way.
If I'll see you once
again with him...
Zampano, let off him!
Hold him back!
Run after them!
These goddamn gypsies!
He's got a knife!
Calm down, nothing bad will happen.
Be careful, he's got a knife!
Don't make a step, or I'll kill you!
Open up the door!
Open up!
Stay back!
- What's the problem here?
- Nothing.
Hey you, put the knife away!
Nothing like that ever
happened in my circus!
The police handcuffed
and arrested him!
- But it wasn't his fault...
- We never had problems with police!
What do you want to do now?
You stay with us, otherwise
she'll look for this rude.
You can be lucky, that it happened
this way, now you're free.
What will you do alone? With us
you finally won't be hungry.
But the motorcycle?
- The police will keep an eye on it.
- Gelsomina, stay with us.
- Where should I sleep?
- There's some room in my wagon.
Now move it! The tractor will
arrive at half past four.
You can come with us,
but if you want to wait, then tell him,
that I'll never work with him anymore.
And not with the other one! Never!
Let it down!
You were asleep already?
It stinks awful in here!
How you can stand it?
No, Zampano is still in jail.
He'll be free by tomorrow, perhaps.
- Tomorrow?
- Yes, perhaps.
It's all Your fault. Zampano
didn't do anything to You.
And they let You go first.
I agree, in a certain way I'm
the cause of his misfortune.
But he had the knife.
Come out.
Come!
Perhaps the prison will
be of use for him.
He still got so many years to live!
But with me it'll be over soon.
Nice gown you have!
Take a seat.
Come on. Sit down
What a strange face!
Are you really a woman?
You look like an artichoke!
I don't know yet, if I'll
stay with Zampano.
I can go with the circus.
The best chance to get rid of him.
He'll look funny, when he'll be
released from jail and all are away!
That's how you have to do it!
That will be fun!
I don't have anything against him.
But when I see his face, all
my limbs itch to hit him.
I don't know why at all.
I just can't hold me back.
But you, how you two came together?
He gave 10.000 Lire to my mother.
That much?
I've got four sisters,
all younger than me.
Do you like him?
- Me?
- Yes, you! Who else?
Why you won't run away from him?
I tried already, but I can't.
What do you mean, "but I can't"?
You can stay with him
or go with the circus.
If I go with them or with Zampano,
it's the same for me.
It doesn't make a difference.
Nobody needs me.
What for do I live?
- Can you cook?
- What?
You're a good cook?
No.
What can you do then?
Dancing? Singing?
A little.
Maybe...
it's love, which brings you joy?
You have to enjoy anything.
If you would be not that ugly...
Why am I born to this world?
And if I'll offer you
to come with me?
I'll teach you to become a ropedancer.
High above, in the spotlights!
I've got a car, we can drive around,
we'll have a lot of fun!
What do you think?
You don't want to...
You have to stay with Zampano, to be
involved in all his stupid things
and let him hit you like a donkey!
That's life.
But, Zampano must keep you only,
because he's got something on you.
You already ran away once,
what he did then?
He's beaten me up.
Why he didn't let you go?
Strange,
I won't keep you one day
more then necessary!
Maybe...
Maybe he likes you?
Zampano? Me?
Yes, he's like a dog:
a dog, who looks like he's trying
to speak, but can only bark.
Poor Zampano.
Yea, poor...
But...
if you won't stay with him,
who else will?
I'm not educated well, just
read a couple of books.
Every existing thing,
is here on purpose.
For example...
- This stone here...
- Which one?
This one. It's here for some reason.
And this little stone...
- For what?
- For...
What do I know?!
If I knew that, then I would be...
the almighty God, who knows everything.
When you're born, when you
die, who knows that.
I don't know for what that stone is
good, but it has got its function.
Or everything would be meaningless.
Even the stars.
That's, what I believe at least.
And you...
You're good for something as well.
With your artichokelike face.
I'll buy some matches tomorrow
and lit everything!
Mattresses, sheets, everything!
So he'll understand!
I didn't say, I don't
want to go with him.
He paid 10.000 Lire, I do the
whole work and he sleeps!
That's his nature. He
doesn't think at all.
I tell him that and
he says: "Whatever."
What is that good for?
And he'll get some poison either!
In his soup.
No, I better burn it all up!
And if I won't stay with him,
who else will do?
So they said, that you
can stay with them?
Wake up!
Did they really say, that
you could stay with them?
They didn't say anything about me?
They didn't want to work with
You anymore. Or with Zampano.
As if it is of a big value
for me, to work with them.
They need me, but I
don't need anybody!
Today I'm here, tomorrow somewhere else!
I get bored too fast. Freedom is
the most important thing for me.
That's how I am.
I don't even need a warm place to sleep.
Why did You say, that You'll die soon?
I am often thinking  about death.
Must be the profession.
...and suddenly it's over.
Once I'll break my neck,
no one will cry for me.
- And Your mother?
So, will you wait for him?
Or you'll go with them?
So you want to be with him,
I'll bring you to the police.
Then you'll be right there,
when they release him.
He'll be surprised!
What a hell of a device!
Get out!
There are the barracks.
So long.
You're leaving?
Yes, or do you want to come with me?
What should I do with a girl,
who isn't good for anything?
Gelsomina...
Here is...
a little souvenir.
So long, Gelsomina!
Zampano, here I am.
The circus people wanted to keep me,
- but...
- You could have gone then.
- In which direction is our house?
- There.
I wanted to go back home once,
but now it's not important anymore.
Now my home is with You.
Really?
What a great discovery,
you were hungry at home!
You're better with me.
You're an animal!
Nothing in your head!
- Then it'll be a time for fasting?
- Never!
A storm is coming up, where
is the next village?
Magliano, 18 km from here,
but it's behind the mountains.
We won't get there - not
enough fuel in tank!
There is our monastery.
Please, wait.
Matron, I've got the oil.
May this man stay with
us for one night?
Excuse me, we don't have
enough fuel left,
it's getting dark soon, it's still
far until we reach the village
and my wife doesn't feel well...
- He can sleep in the barn, maybe?
- Well, but only for one night.
She allowed it, there is
enough room in the barn.
Thank You, matron.
- I've got something else for You.
- Thanks.
- And You, You want some more?
- Come on and take it.
She works with You?
She helps me a little bit.
Blows the trumpet, plays the tambourine.
Show, what you can do to the sister.
Great!
- How well you can play!
- Yes, now do the dishes!
- No, I'll do it.
- That's her job to do.
We'll do it together.
How beautiful it sounded!
- What's this melody?
- I don't know.
What are you trying to do?
That's not the right work to
do for a sister like You.
- Hand it over.
- I'm doing this every day.
You always sleep inside of it?
It's enough space. I got a lamp,
some pottery, like in a real home.
Very nice. Do You like the travelling?
- That's his work.
- We use to move along as well.
Every two years we have to
move to another monastery.
- This is my second already.
- And why?
So we can't get used to secular things.
If you stay longer at one place,
you start to like it
and forgets, what's more important,
then anything on earth, God.
We both are travellers: she
follows her God, I follow mine.
- Yes, each one follows her own.
- You would like to inspect the monastery?
Please, accompany me. The monastery
is over 1000 years old.
Why are You taking me with You?
I don't look good, I can't cook,
can't do anything...
What happened?
Go to sleep.
What strange things you're
thinking about?
It's raining.
It is nice here.
Will You be sorry about
me, if I'll die?
Why do you want to die?
I wanted to die once.
Be dead is better then to
stay with him, I thought.
Now I'm ready even to marry You.
We'll stay together. Even a
stone is good for anything.
You have to consider sometimes.
But You never reflect on things!
- There is nothing to think about.
- But yes, there is!
And what do you want to think?!
Sleep immediately.
I don't want to listen
to this crap anymore!
Sleep, I'm tired.
Do You like me a little bit?
Stop it!
There are silver hearts hangin,
but my hands are too big,
you have to try!
- No, I don't want to.
- What has got into you?
- No, You can't do this!
- Be quiet!
Thank You, venerable matron.
Thank You, good bye.
She cries! Wait a moment.
Why are you crying?
Do You want to stay here?
I'll speak to the matron.
Sisters!
Here, put that away.
Thank You for Your kind heart
and the hospitality.
Thank You very much from
a modest artist like me.
Push!
"Rufle"! You're right on time.
I would also help you.
But, "Rufle"!
Throw that thing away!
That's for your dumb jokes!
Zampano, stop it! That's enough!
You're trying to kill me?
- That was the gift from the "Rufle"!
- Come on! Please!
- Next time you'll have more!
- Any more?
He broke my watch!
Zampano, come quick, he's really bad!
He's bad...
He dies...
- Don't be a fool!
- He dies...
He dies...
Be quiet!
Hey, you?
Be quiet finally!
I'm in deep shit now.
Those, who are sensible,
should look away,
when the hook gets into
the flesh, it can bleed!
Here comes the announcing drum roll!
Gelsomina, please!
Signorina Gelsomina!
Drum roll, please!
"Il Matto", he feels bad...
What do you think?
What has got into you?
Nobody have seen us,
nobody is looking for us!
No one think about it, not even us.
I'm hungry.
Stay here.
I'll deal with it.
Where are you going?
Where are you heading? Tell me.
You want to go back home?
Here.
Eat something.
Stop the blubbering! That's enough!
I can't hear it any longer!
- I'll take a rest now.
- No!
Don't come in!
All right, I'll sleep outside.
- It's nice here.
- It's cold.
Sit down.
Get some sunlight.
Let's eat some soup.
Something's missing.
No need, I'll do it.
Finally! You didn't make
a move for ten days!
I didn't want to kill him.
I only hit him twice.
He was fine, just some nose bleeding.
Then I let off him.
Do I have to end in jail
because of some fight?
I only want to do my work.
Do I not have a right to live?
Finally we can move along once again.
There is a big fair,
a couple of kilometers ahead.
We can earn good money there.
What? What do you have again?
"Il Matto", he feels bad.
I'll bring you back home.
You want back to your mother?
You don't want back to your mother?
If I won't stay with you,
who else will do?
But it can't go on like that.
I have to earn money again!
You're crazy! Crazy!
If you want to sleep, then go
inside, it's too cold here.
We have to move on.
You have killed him.
It's really nice here, outside.
I wanted tog o away from You,
but he said, I should stay.
We need more wood for the fire.
Today, Gala performance by the
world famous circus "Medini"!
International attractions!
Oriental artists!
and sketches, from which You'll
fall off the chairs!
Our name means a
quality obligation for us!
Let's go home now, children.
Come with your parents today!
Children pay half entrance.
- Where do you go?
- Just a bit.
Should I accompany you?
No, I'll be back n a minute.
One for 30.
And some lemon.
Hey, You there!
Where do You know it from?
That melody.
- Which melody?
- One You just sang.
Oh, You mean this one...
It's from a girl, who stayed with us.
When?
That was long time ago.
Four or five years back.
She always played it on her
trumpet, I'll never forget it.
And where is she now?
She has died.
Are You a circus artist? She was
of the same kind, a vagabond.
Maybe you have known her. Nobody
around here used to know her.
She never have spoken.
She was a little bit crazy.
My father found her near the beach.
She was ill. Some sort of fever.
We took her to us, but
she never said anything,
only cried. She hasn't
eaten anything too.
When she felt better, she used to
sit outside and play the trumpet.
And one morning. she didn't wake up.
Our mayor tried to find
some relatives of her.
Do You want to see the mayor?
And now Zampano, the
man with iron lungs!
After him a posse, You'll
laugh about a lot!
Music!
Ladies and gentlemen,
a chain and a hook, 0.5 cm thick,
pure iron, stronger then steel,
through an expansion...
of my breast muscles...
and my lungs...
I blow up this hook. This
here is not to protect me,
but to spare You
the view of a blood stained
hook in my flesh.
If somebody has got weak nerves,
then look away, please.
- Finish, you had enough.
- Leave me alone.
- Then go somewhere else.
- I said leave me alone!
I'll bring you out!
- You're disturbing other guests.
- Waiter!
Go now, come on.
And stop the drinking!
Please, get reasonable.
Come, I'll bring you out.
Go to hell, I'll go alone!
- Don't touch me!
- There is the exit.
- He gets drunk like this every day.
- Son of a bitch!
- Stop it, please!
- Damn vagabond!
I'll break all your bones...
Let off me!
Let me...
Go away!
Come here, I'll get done
with all of you!
Let off me, I'll show it to
that son of a bitch!
Teach him a lesson, so
he'll have enough.
Miserable drinker! You
still haven't had enough?
- Zampano, get calm.
- Let off me!
- It has no point...
- Don't touch me!
If I wouldn't be your friend,
I've already called the police.
I don't want any friends!
Why all of you don't come out?
Come out now!
I'll show you!
I'll finish you all!
I don't need anybody!
I want to be alone!
Alone!