? Bright ?
? Stars glittered ?
? On the banks
the pale moon shone ?
Somebody's coming, Pa.
? And twas from Aunt
Dinah's quilting party ?
Well, let him come.
? I was seeing
Nellie home ?
? I was seeing Nellie ?
? Home ?
? I was seeing ?
? Nellie ?
? Home ?
? And twas from
Aunt Dinah's ?
? I was seeing... ??
Hope you don't mind
my cutting through your place.
No, I guess not.
I'm heading north.
Didn't expect to find
any fences around here.
Hello, boy.
You were watching me
quite a spell, weren't you?
Yes, I was.
You know, I...
I like a man
who watches things go on around.
It means he'll make
his mark someday.
Been a long time
since I've seen a Jersey cow.
Well, you'll see a lot more...
Jerseys and...
Holsteins and...
the like.
Can I offer you
some water?
Thanks.
[Click Click]
You're a little touchy,
aren't you?
Joey.
You know better than to point guns
at people.
I wasn't pointing at anybody,
Mother.
[Rooster Crows]
Sure had me snortin',
Son.
I just wanted you
to see my rifle.
Bet you can shoot.
Can't ya?
Little bit.
Giddyup!
Looks like your friends
are a little late.
What are the Ryker boys
up to this time?
Rykers?
That's what I said.
I wouldn't know a Ryker
from your Jersey cow.
Don't forget to close the gate
on your way out.
Would you mind
putting down that gun?
Then I'll leave.
What difference
does it make?
You're leaving anyway.
I'd like it to be my idea.
Howdy, Starett.
Expecting trouble?
Heh heh heh heh heh.
I don't want
no trouble, Starett.
I came to inform you.
I got that beef contract
for the reservation.
It took this many
to say that?
I mean business.
Then tend to your own.
That's just what I'm doing!
I'm going to need
all of my range.
Now that you've warned me,
would you get off
my place?
Your place?
You're going to have to get out
before the snow flies.
And supposing I don't?
You and the other squatters...
Homesteaders you mean,
don't you?
I could blast you
out of here right now.
You and the others.
Now, you listen to me.
The time for gun-blasting a man
off his own place
is past.
They're building
a penitentiary...
Joe, that's enough.
to take care of...
Who are you, stranger?
I'm a friend of Starett's.
Well, Starett...
you can't say
I didn't warn you.
All right, you've told me.
Now, you get off of my claim.
Supper will be ready
in a little while, Joe.
Won't be very long.
Wait, mister, I...
I swear, I...
Wait a minute, please.
I... I take that back what I...
Well, look, this...
this thing ain't even loaded.
Not loaded?
No, no.
Joey is too young to go loaded.
That's his gun.
If this don't beat all.
My name is Starett,
Joe Starett,
and, uh, this here is Joey.
You heard what
my little woman said.
Come on in, please.
I... I feel like eating.
You can call me Shane.
I guess I spook
kind of easy these days.
Hello, Joe.
My place ain't
very much yet,
but I'll tell you
one thing,
my wife sure can cook.
But it... it won't be long
till supper.
Here, you can... you can
wash up right here.
In case you want to know,
that's, uh...
that's Ryker's spread,
all that over there.
He thinks the whole world
belongs to him.
These old-timers,
they just can't see it yet,
but running cattle
on open ranges
can't go on forever.
It takes too much space
for too little results.
Those herds aren't
any good.
They're all horns
and bone.
Now, cattle
that is bred for meat
and fenced in and fed right,
that's the thing.
You got to pick your spot,
get your land, your own land.
A homesteader,
he can't run but a few beef,
but he can sure grow grain
and cut hay
and what with his garden
and the hogs and milk,
he'll make out all right.
We make out, don't we, Marian?
Of course.
[Clanging]
[Moo]
Oh, it's that calf again.
Joey, you run
and chase her out of there.
Joey.
Run on, Son.
Don't forget
to shut that gate.
[Joe] Joey!
[Moo]
Come on, shoo!
[Moo Moo]
I wouldn't ask you
where you're bound.
One place or another.
Someplace I've never been.
Hmm.
The only way they're getting me out
is in a pine box.
What do you mean, Pa?
I mean they'll have to shoot me
and carry me out.
Joe, I wish you wouldn't
talk like that.
Well, that's the truth.
We've got our roots down.
I know, but I wish
you wouldn't talk that way.
First real home
we've ever had.
What did you mean...
Joey.
Be quiet.
The men want to talk.
The only thing is
there's just more work here
than I can do.
If I could hire me
a man that...
Ahem.
Had one once,
but the Ryker brothers
roughed him up,
so he lit out,
cussing me.
They knocked
his teeth out.
Ready for pie?
Well, if nobody else
is going to eat
this last biscuit,
I guess I'm going
to have to.
Say, we're kind of fancy,
aren't we?
What is, Pa?
Our good plates
and extra fork and...
What about me, Ma?
What's the matter, Marian?
Nothing.
That... that was an elegant dinner,
Mrs. Starett.
Excuse me.
Where's Mr. Shane going?
He didn't
even say goodbye.
He's not going, Joey.
He wouldn't go
without taking that.
I'm going outside
with him.
Did you ask him to stay the night,
Joe?
Well, I'll... I'll
do that right now.
Well, I'll be doggone.
Come here a minute.
Joe, why don't you
hitch up a team?
Marian, I've been
fighting this stump
off and on for two years.
Use a team now
and this stump could say
it beat us.
Sometimes there ain't
nothing that'll do
but your own
sweat and muscle.
All right.
[Rooster Crows]
[Lapping Water]
[Snorts]
Bang!
I wish they'd give me some bullets
for this gun.
Good morning, Joey.
How did you know
it was me?
Well, I figured the cow
couldn't work that latch.
What are you doing up
so early?
You're to stay
for breakfast, you know.
Oh?
Well, thank you.
Then where will you go?
Where would you say,
Joey?
I...
I wish you'd stay here.
Would you teach me
to shoot?
You'd like to learn
to shoot, huh?
Pa wishes
you'd stay, too.
I heard him tell mother.
Oh?
He said
he didn't want you
to fight his fights
for him,
but just help
with the work.
I bet
you wouldn't leave
just because it's too dangerous
around here.
Joey? Joey?
Joey, come here this minute.
I hope you'll stay,
Mr. Shane.
Coming, mother!
Close the gate, Joey.
What are you doing out here
in your nightshirt?
Come in and put
your clothes on.
Shane, you like
to hitch up the team
and haul that load
of wire from Graftors?
Anything you say.
Get off the bed, Joey.
Go on.
He's holding it
for me at the store.
While you're there,
you might as well get yourself
some sure-enough
work clothes.
What can I bring you,
Joey?
Soda pop!
You don't need anything, Joey.
You know better.
You just be careful.
I don't want my troubles
to be yours.
Aren't you going to wear
your six-shooter?
I didn't know there was any wild game
in town, Joey.
Come on, Son.
Joey!
Come back here.
Bang!
What are you shooting at?
Rykers.
Bang!
You getting any?
Missed one.
Well, can't stand for that.
Pa, you guess Shane will teach me
to shoot?
I'll teach you myself
once I get the time, Joey.
Can you shoot
as good as Shane, Pa?
How do I know?
I've never seen him shoot.
But I doubt it.
He didn't wear
his gun today.
Why is that, Pa?
Well, he's trading at the store,
not holding it up.
But why, Pa? Honest.
Why didn't he?
I don't wear one myself.
It goes with him, though.
Somebody's coming, Joe!
I know.
It's Ernie Wright.
Could you whip him, Pa?
Could you whip Shane?
Can't you ask nothing
but questions?
But could you?
Oh, maybe.
No call for that,
though, Joey.
Shane's on our side.
Howdy, Joe.
How are you, Ernie?
No good.
What's the matter?
I'm pulling stakes.
No use of your talking,
Joe Starett.
Now, what's the matter?
My wheat.
Them Ryker brothers
raided it.
Fence cut,
steers drove in.
It's just stubs now.
When?
Last night.
I'm leaving.
I'm getting out,
I tell you.
I got enough.
Don't try to talk me out of it.
You can't...
Don't try.
I listened to you too much already.
Go ahead.
Nobody's holding you.
You wouldn't leave
your home and land and...
Oh, Ernie, you...
I'm wore down and out,
tired of being insulted
by them fellas,
called a pig farmer.
And who knows
what comes next?
Well, don't throw your tail up.
I tell you what.
We'll all get together
right here tonight,
and we'll...
we'll figure out something.
I don't know about me.
I'll get the word around.
It'd help if you could see
Shipstead and Torrey, huh?
All right,
I'll tell them.
But if we're going
to have a meeting,
it had better come to more
than just poking holes
in the air with your finger.
Giddyup!
[Bell Rings]
Anything I can do you for?
Came in to pick up some wire
for Joe Starett.
Oh, yes. I've been
holding wire for Starett
for quite a spell.
You new?
Yes, I'm working for Starett.
Got any ready-made pants
that might fit me?
Farm rig?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I outfit
all these farmers.
Step right in back
and try them on.
Will.
Hey, Will.
You're dreadful thirsty,
ain't you, Chris?
[Laughter]
Hey, Will, who's
tending bar around here?
Coming right in.
How is it?
Good enough.
How much do I owe you?
Well, let's see.
Pants... $ 1.00.
Two shirts... 60 cents.
Belt.
Young man,
you owe me $2.00 and 2 bits.
What's the matter, Son?
You look kind of pale.
It's been a long time
since I got store-bought clothes.
Money don't go
very far these days.
Oh, new sodbuster, huh?
I thought I smelled pigs.
Anything else
I can do you for?
Got any soda pop?
I sure do.
I wish more men around here
would drink it.
In my bar, in there.
Thanks.
Will! Let's keep
the smell of pigs out
from where
we're drinking.
Bartender.
Yes?
What can I do for you?
You have any soda pop?
[Laughter]
Are you going to get him out,
or will I have to?
Let me take him, Chris.
[Laughter]
Well, what'll it be?
Lemon, strawberry,
or lilac, sodbuster?
You speaking to me?
I don't see nobody else
standing there.
Here, have some of this.
Smell like a man.
Don't it smell better in here,
Grafton?
Chris just fumigated
a sodbuster.
Just take it easy.
I was just asking
about sody pop,
pigs and taters,
and one thing or another.
Say, which one of them tater pickers
are you working for?
Or are you just squatting
on the range?
Joe Starett,
if it's any of your business.
Supposing I make it
my business?
Here's your soda pop,
Mister.
[Laughter]
Now, you and your soda pop
get out of here
and stay out
of here.
And don't come back.
Did you see that, Rufe?
What, Bubba?
Chris just put the run
on a sodbuster.
That's it, Chris.
Keep them squatters
on the move.
Warm it up for you a bit?
Thank you.
It's getting so I don't
like to ride at night.
Yeah, well, let's hope this meeting
will get started.
Is Shane going to be
at the meeting tonight?
Mr. Shane, Joey.
Yes, I suppose he will be.
I guess we all know
why we're here.
I guess Ryker's war party
has been around
to see all of us.
I'm here to tell you,
for one,
that I ain't leaving now
or any other time.
We'll start with you,
Axel.
What do you say?
Vell, Yoe, you see...
I know what I want to say.
Start with me.
Ernie, we're going to hear everybody
in their turn.
Go ahead.
I guess most of you don't know
Shane here.
Shane, this is Yank Potts.
Howdy, Shane.
Fred Lewis here.
I seen you in town.
Ernie Wright here.
And, uh, Ed Howells.
Howdy.
And, uh, Johnson.
Did you see
anybody else coming?
No.
We're waiting for Torrey.
Just how far is this Ryker going
to push us?
Let's not talk scare.
That's exactly
what Ryker wants.
He thinks he can shoo us off of here
like chickens.
Well, here's Torrey now.
Here he is.
Hello, Reb.
Hello, Yank.
[Playing Marching Through Georgia
On Harmonica]
That's enough out of you,
Yank.
[Whistling]
You, too.
Let's cool off now,
Stonewall.
Just cool off.
Shake hands with Shane there.
Shane's working for me.
Shane.
Oh, yeah. I heard about you
over at Graftors.
Sit down.
Go on with the meeting, Joe.
Well, Stonewall,
it's like this, um...
with... leaving Ernie
out there maybe,
I think we've all agreed
we're going to stick.
Now you're whistling.
There ain't nobody
pushing me off my claim,
and that's for certain.
I'm staying.
I, too, vill stay.
I'll string along
with that,
leastways till
the shooting starts.
There ain't but seven
of us figure,
if it comes to a fight.
Him. That makes eight.
You can't count on him.
He's proved that much.
You watch what you're saying.
Maybe Shane can tell you what happened
between him and Calloway.
They're talking about Shane.
What is this, Shane?
Let him say.
Lewis seen it
and heard it.
He let this Chris buffalo him
in Grafton's saloon.
Fred, I told Shane
to stay away from trouble.
If he did, he did right.
Let's finish
the story, Joey.
He didn't.
Shane didn't let him
do that.
Chris went around
afterwards bragging
how he put the run
on a sodbuster.
Shane?
You don't have to leave.
I figured you could
talk freer
if I weren't around.
[Playing Harmonica]
It's too late
to finish this now.
He didn't, did he?
Joey, I want you
to go to sleep.
It's all right.
Everything's all right.
Shane isn't going to go away,
is he?
No, he isn't, dear.
Now, get back into bed.
Stay there.
Shane.
I know you ain't afraid.
It's a long story, Joey.
I think we know...
Shane.
Shane, don't just
stand there in the rain.
You'll catch your death
of cold.
So on Saturday,
we'll all get together in one bunch,
and we'll go
into town for our supplies.
I reckon that's a good idea.
There's some strength
in a whole bunch.
I'll put on my .38
and go into town
anytime I please.
[Playing Dixie]
[Playing Beautiful Dreamer]
Joey?
Yes?
Don't get to liking Shane
too much.
Why not?
I don't want you to.
Is there anything wrong
with him?
No.
Then what, Mother?
He'll be moving on one day,
Joey.
You'll be upset...
if you get
to liking him too much.
All right, Marian,
you're pretty enough!
Come on, now,
you're holding everybody up!
I vish she vould hurry
so ve could get going.
I don't like
this business.
Joey, get in the wagon, Son!
One thing a married man
has got to get used to
is waiting for women.
Hurry up, Ma!
[Joe]
Here she comes.
Good afternoon,
Mrs. Starett.
Hello.
Sometimes the waiting
is worth it.
Take care, Shane,
you get a woman
that's worth waiting for.
Water is sure good.
Think I can get ready
in the time it takes
to hitch up a team?
Hold on. We wanted to see
how pretty you were.
Couldn't wait.
Come on in.
All set?
[Thunder]
Hyah! Hyah!
Come on!
Hyah!
Come on, girl!
Hello, Ernie!
Good morning, Joe.
You all set, Fred?
Yeah, reckon we are.
Where's Stonewall?
Thought he was
coming with us.
He got thirsty
and went on.
Said he had business
that couldn't wait.
I'd like to go, too,
but I got to mind the girls.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Come on.
Come on, Red.
Goodbye, Marian.
Bye-bye.
We'll come out later.
Goodbye.
Bye-bye.
Stonewall, what are you doing
in town ahead of us?
I had some business
to attend to.
We can't buy a drink.
Get off that horse.
You're acting
like a fool.
[Bell Rings]
A whole bunch came in.
They brought
their women with them
to protect them.
My jars come yet?
Heard you were
coming in.
What can I
do you for?
My, my, my.
What will they
think of next?
Susan.
You bring that list of things
your mother wanted?
The coal-oil cars
in the wagon.
Run and get it.
My voman wanted we should
get together on the 4th of July.
Ja, we make
big celebration.
I already
tell your wife.
That's just
what we need...
a real get-together.
It's Joe Starett's
anniversary.
Got to celebrate that.
We'll have a big party.
Oh, and... and... and,
Mr. Grafton...
Have you got gunpowder?
We need it
for fireworks.
I'll barter the two chickens
I brought for it.
We'll talk
about that later.
What do I get
for the empty?
The usual.
Thank you.
Give the bottle to Will.
I need white flour
and 4 pounds of coffee.
Joey...
Let me take it in.
You come, too, Shane.
Thank you.
Ve'll talk
about that later.
Well, now, look
what we got.
That's one
of the new ones.
They call him Sody Pop.
Deal me out.
Why, what's the matter,
Pete?
Just say
I'm superstitious,
that's all.
I guess you don't
hear very well, sodbuster.
I thought I told you if you wanted
to keep healthy,
to stay out of here.
Now, get going.
Look, pig farmer.
You better get back inside
with the women and kids
where it's safe.
Don't push it, Calloway.
Did you hear me?
I said, get going.
Did you think you was
going to come in here
and drink with the men?
Set 'em up, bartender.
Two whiskeys.
You bought me a drink
last time I was in.
Now I want
to buy you one.
You ain't gonna
drink that in here.
You guessed it.
Let me have him.
Let him go.
Go get him, Chris.
Tear him apart.
Tear that sodbuster
in half.
Hang one on him,
Chris.
Bust that mug
of his.
Let him have it.
This is bad.
I'm going in there.
You're gonna
stay right here.
This ain't our fight.
We'll get run out
of this country.
Go get him,
Chris.
That's the trouble
around here...
ain't a marshal
within 100 miles.
Get after him,
Chris.
Plow him under,
Beat his brains out.
Get him.
Now land that right,
Chris.
Knock him
into that pigpen.
Dirty pig farmer.
Stop this, men.
Here, men!
Here, stop this!
Settle it outside.
Well, it looks like
it's all over.
I think ve should
get out of here.
Let's all go now.
Ja.
Maybe you'd like
to draw str...
Hold on, young fella.
Cool off a bit.
You may have a friend
you don't know you've got.
I need a man like you.
I'm working for Starett.
You don't belong
on the end of a shovel.
Anything to keep you
from drawing your time?
I like working
for Starett.
Whatever he's paying,
I'll double.
It's no use.
What are you
looking for?
Nothing.
Pretty wife Starett's got.
You dirty,
slinking old man!
Nobody talks
to me that way.
I'm talking that way.
You had your chance.
Nobody messes up
one of my boys.
We're gonna ride you
out of this valley.
We're gonna rough you up,
and you're gonna stay out.
Shane, come on.
Joey, get out of here.
But, Shane,
there's too many.
You wouldn't want me
to run away, would you?
But there's
too many, Shane.
Go on, son. Please.
Here, men, stop this.
I'll pay the damages.
No more fighting here.
You keep out of this.
This man's unarmed.
It ain't a shooting.
Quit butting in.
I'll take him.
Stop it, men!
Stop fighting!
Stop this!
Break his neck.
Where's Joey?
They're going
to kill Shane!
They're all trying
to kill him in there.
Stay with your mother.
Joe, don't go in.
What Ryker's got coming to him
ain't fit
for women to see.
Bust him.
You'll get us
in trouble.
Kick his brains in.
Stop it!
Stop it, men! Stop it!
You fools,
you've had enough of it.
You'll all
get killed.
Starett, Shane,
back on out of here.
That's making
some sense, Starett.
You've won.
Get out of here.
Ryker ain't paying
for this damage.
I'll pay you
for what's broke.
No. We're paying
for what's broke,
Me and Shane.
Morgan, put one of the boys
on a good horse.
He's got a long trip,
All the way to Cheyenne.
I'm through fooling, Grafton.
From now on,
when we fight with them,
the air is gonna be filled
with gun smoke.
I saw it all, Mother,
every bit of it.
It was no place for you, Joey.
No place for you, either, Marian.
I was scared.
Then Pa came in,
picked up that man,
and slung him on the floor.
I didn't do much.
It was all Shane.
How you feeling, Shane?
Much better.
You did, Joe.
It was ugly,
and you were
both wonderful.
When that chair hit you, Shane,
I thought
you were a goner.
It was an easy chair, Joey.
I bet you two
could lick anyone.
Well, one thing for sure...
Ryker's going to think twice.
Don't talk about Ryker,
not anymore tonight.
I wish we could forget him.
This turpentine's
going to hurt.
He wouldn't say nothing,
no matter
how much it hurt.
Well, I'm afraid I would, Joey,
if it hurt bad enough.
Stings like anything.
Joey, go on to bed.
It does smart.
I know.
Ouch!
Gosh.
Joey, for the last time,
go to bed.
Yeah, me, too.
Come on, Son.
Will you come in
and kiss me good night, Mother?
All right.
Your head...
your head
needs a bandage.
Oh, it's good enough,
Marian.
It's fine.
Thanks very much.
You want to know something,
Mother?
What is it?
What is it, Joey?
Mother, I just love Shane.
Do you?
I love him almost as much
as I love Pa.
That's all right,
isn't it?
He's a fine man.
He's so good.
Don't you like him,
Mother?
Yes, I like him,
too, Joey.
Good night, Joey.
What's the matter,
honey?
Joe...
hold me.
Don't say anything.
Just hold me... tight.
Good night, Ma.
Good night, Joey.
Good night, Pa.
Good night, Son.
Night, Shane!
Where's Ryker?
He's getting
a little sleep.
He sent for me.
Won't you sit down
for a minute?
We're having
a celebration today.
Where's the coffee?
I'll put it right on.
What's going on here?
Plenty.
Going somewhere?
Well, it looks that way,
don't it?
Don't let them bluff you,
Ernie.
Bluff, huh?
See that?
They killed my sow
last night.
Kept shooting
and yelling what
they'd do next.
Woke up the kids
and scared the missus
half to death.
We're gonna put
a stop to that.
I said I'd stay
for one more hand.
Well, this is it.
I had enough of Ryker.
[Yelling]
Here they come again!
Right through
my plowed ground.
Well, what do you think of that,
Stonewall Torrey?
Well, Starett and the rest of us
are gonna take the juice
out of them...
one of these days.
I'm going into Grafton's
and get a bottle for the picnic.
I'm going to show them
it's Independence Day.
Ma, you getting ready?
Good luck, anyway.
Hope good luck for you, too.
[Laughter]
I don't see
a pig in sight.
I don't see none,
but I sure can
smell 'em.
[Laughter]
They cut
Mr. Wright's fence
and Mr. Shipstead's,
too.
They did?
Shane, what would you do
if you caught them
cutting our fence?
Well, I'd ask them
to please go around
by the gate.
Aw, Shane.
I'll race you
to the barn.
It's a go.
Why don't you ever wear
your six-shooter, Shane?
Well, I guess I don't see
as many badmen as you do.
Shane.
Mm-hmm?
You want me to tell you
something?
If you want to.
I saw your gun
in there one day.
I took a look at it.
Oh?
Are you mad?
No, I guess not,
but if
I were you, Joey,
I'd leave a thing
like this alone.
I wrapped it up careful
in the blanket again.
Well, that's a good boy.
Could I see it again?
You promised you'd
show me how to shoot.
Please.
All right, Joey. Come on.
Get 'em up.
Well, we got some learning
to do, huh?
Come on.
Now, you stand right here.
Put your arms
on your side.
Mm-mm.
Your holster's too low.
Never have your holster
at arm's length.
Here, let's fix this.
You always
have it here.
Where the grip's between
the elbow and the wrist.
When your hand comes up,
the gun will
clear the holster
without coming up too high.
Try it.
Real fast.
Oh, that's it.
Is that the way
real gunfighters do?
No, Joey.
Most of them have
tricks of their own.
One, for instance,
likes to have
a shoulder holster.
Another one puts it
through the belt of his pants.
And there are some
who like two guns.
But one's all you need
if you can use it.
It's not certain
over 10 or 15 paces.
It's no good at all...
Which way is best?
What I'm telling you
is as good a way as any
and better than most.
Let me see you shoot.
What should I shoot at?
The little white rock over there.
See?
[Whistles]
Gosh almighty!
That is good!
Now, you see, Joey...
Now, look...
Remember, now...
when your hand comes up,
you still have room
to clear your holster.
Shane.
Oh, hello,
Mrs. Starett.
I was teaching Joey
how to do a little shooting.
I don't want...
You ought to
see Shane shoot.
I did, Joey.
He's teaching me to shoot.
You run along and get ready
for the party.
Go on, Joey.
Guns aren't going
to be my boy's life.
Why do you always have
to spoil everything?
Bang!
A gun is a tool, Marian.
No better,
no worse than any other tool...
an ax, a shovel,
or anything.
A gun's as good
or as bad
as the man using it.
We'd all be better off
if there wasn't a single gun
left in this valley,
including yours.
What's all
the shooting about?
You're starting the celebrating
a little early,
aren't you, Shane?
Well, look at that woman.
In her wedding dress.
Shane,
you'd better
hitch up that team
'cause today we're gonna celebrate
the 4th of July.
They squat on my range.
I'm supposed to say,
"I'm busted, but you're welcome."
It ain't that bad.
That's easy for you to say.
I'm your friend.
You know I want
to be reasonable,
but something's
go to give.
Nowadays a man
can go just so far.
I've gone along
with the new law.
I've stayed away
from gun play.
Sure, I tried to buffalo
the sodbusters.
You've got to admit
my men have kept
their six-guns cased.
[Yelling Outside]
And now?
I don't have to guess
what's on your mind.
Keep your guesses
to yourself.
I want you to know
I like Joe Starett.
The fool ought to
listen to reason.
Your reason?
Nothing I say
strikes you right.
No offense, Rufe.
No offense.
It's your own conscience
eating on you.
Conscience.
[Bell Rings]
What, Torrey?
Something I can do you for?
A jug.
It's the 4th.
Come in. Come in.
Come on.
Jug and a whiskey.
Here's to you, Ryker,
for running Ernie Wright
off his claim.
Another.
Is that one of them?
Yeah.
It's a downright
dirty shame.
'Cause it's all
he had,
and he worked hard
for it.
And I want to tell you
something, Ryker.
He's running because
he's a coward.
And here's to me,
'cause I ain't a coward.
And you ain't
getting my claim.
A hothead.
I could get him to draw
without any trouble.
It would be easy.
You can't scare me any more than you
can Joe Starett.
No.
It's Starett we want.
Any of the rest
of you care to join me
in drinking a toast
to the independence
of the greatest state
in the union?
[Man Outside]
I'm from Wyoming!
Here's to the independence
of the sovereign state of Alabama.
Heh heh heh.
There you are.
[Explosion]
[Spinet Music Plays]
Now, you see how good...
[Harmonica Plays]
That's enough out of you, Yank.
Listen, you Yank.
Hello, Yank.
You're late, Reb.
We took Richmond
two hours ago.
Everybody, come here,
I ... Marian...
Ja, Marian!
You come, too.
I have something very important
to tell you.
Axel...
Ja, Mama.
Now, uh,
You all know
vat day today is.
It's Independence Day,
except for one man here.
Yes, sir.
This was the day Yoe Starett
got himself hooked,
by golly!
[Laughing]
Well, no, uh...
What I'd like
to say is that...
Well, say it, Joe!
No, uh, I'd like
to say that Axel's right.
What do you say, Joe?
I gave up my independence
10 years ago today.
But, uh, no man ever gave
it up as easy as I did.
And... and what's more,
I wouldn't trade places
with any man in this world.
[Sighs And Applause]
Go on, Joe,
give her a kiss.
Go ahead! Give her a kiss.
Come on.
[Spinet Music Plays]
? Abide with me ?
? Fast falls
the even tide ?
? The darkness deepens ?
? Fail and comforts flee ?
? Help of the helpless ?
? Oh, abide with me ??
Pass the word to the boys
I got some cheer.
Here... many more, Joe.
We were about ready
to give you up,
you and Ernie.
Ernie's quit.
He's getting out today.
He's packed up,
kit and kaboodle.
I'd kind of been
expecting that.
Ryker's boys have
bluffed him out.
He had more sense
than we thought.
What was you doing
in town, anyway?
Come on, now,
you can't get away.
Well, Marian,
they fenced me out here.
[Spinet Music Plays]
? Goodbye, old paint ?
? I'm leaving Cheyenne ?
? I'm off for Montana ?
? Goodbye, old paint ?
? I'm leaving Cheyenne ?
? I'm off for Montana ?
? Goodbye, old paint ?
? I'm leaving Cheyenne ??
Joe don't want you going into town
by yourself.
Ain't nothing to be
afraid of in town.
Just Ryker and Grafton gabbing.
Yeah, Grafton's
fair enough.
Another man was there,
but just likely he's hired by Ryker.
Who? Who was that?
A stranger,
decked out like a gunfighter.
I didn't let
that scare me.
Did you say guns?
Yeah, two guns.
What did he look like?
You'll know him.
Packs two guns,
kind of lean.
He wears a black hat.
Is he a friend of yours?
No.
There's a man named Wilson
who looks like that.
He's a gunfighter.
Jack Wilson?
A gunfighter out of Cheyenne
named Wilson.
I didn't ask him his name.
Vat about him?
What's a gunman like
Wilson doing around here,
pow-wowing with Ryker?
Don't start.
Torrey didn't say it was Wilson.
This Wilson, would
you know him, Shane,
if you saw him?
Maybe.
If it is Wilson, he's fast,
fast on the draw.
So be careful.
You seem to know an awful lot
about this business.
Ja, dat is enough
of dat, now.
Come eat before
things get cold.
I don't want
no gun-slinging.
Murder's a better
name for it.
Ve eat now, everyone!
You fellows
vith the shoe game...
Torrey, I've been vanting
to go to de blacksmith,
but Yoe said we
shouldn't go alone.
Anytime you want to go
to town, Shipstead,
I'll ride with you.
I'm a soldier who's
fought in real battles.
I can shoot just
as straight as that...
Shane?
Yes, Joey?
Think that was him?
Who?
That man Torrey
seen in town.
You think that
was Wilson?
You shouldn't worry about things
like that.
You rest, Joey.
It's way past your bedtime.
Yes, Mother.
No, Joey.
I'll open it, Son.
All right.
I'll open
the gate for you.
Who goes there?
Brother Rufe's come to pay you
a little visit.
Howdy, Starett.
Good evening, ma'am.
I had something I wanted to talk over
with you, Starett.
Whatever business
you and I have got,
we can talk over
right here.
I'll just lay it
on the barrel head.
How would you like
to work for me?
I'm working
for myself.
Done enough working
for others.
Wait till I tell you.
I'll pay you top wages.
More than you can make
on this patch of ground.
No, I'm not interested.
I haven't said it all.
You can run your cattle
with mine.
What's more...
I'll buy your homestead.
Set a price you
think is reasonable,
and you'll find
me reasonable.
Is that fair?
You've made things
pretty hard for us, Ryker,
and us in the right.
Right?
You in the right?
Look, Starett,
when I come to this country,
you weren't older than your boy.
We had rough times.
Me and other men
that are mostly dead now.
I got a bad shoulder yet
from a Cheyenne arrowhead.
We made this country.
We found it,
and we made it.
Work, blood,
and empty bellies...
Cattle we brought in were hazed off
by Indians and rustlers.
They don't bother you much anymore
because we handled them.
We made a safe range
out of this.
Some of us died doing it,
but we made it.
And then people move in
who never had to rawhide
it through the old days.
They fence off my range
and fence me off
from water.
Some of them like you
plow ditches
and take out
irrigation water,
and so the creek
runs dry sometimes,
and I've got to move
my stock because of it.
And you say we have
no right to the range.
The men that did the work
and ran the risks have no rights?
I take you for a fair man,
Starett.
I'm not belittling what
you and the others did.
But you didn't find
this country.
There was trappers here
and Indian traders long before you.
They tamed this country
more than you.
They weren't ranchers!
You talk about rights.
You think you've
got the right
to say nobody
else has any.
That ain't the way
the government looks at it.
I didn't come to argue.
I made you
a fair proposition.
What about the others?
Shane already knows
he can work for me.
The other homesteaders.
Look, be reasonable.
After all, there's just so many hands
in a deck of cards.
Then I've got to say no.
You don't give a man much choice,
do you, Starett?
How do you feel about it, son?
Wouldn't you like
to go partners with me?
I don't want trouble
with your father.
We don't want anyone
to get hurt.
Joey ain't quite of age.
How about it, son?
[Marian]
Come here, Joey.
I don't want you
to be sorry, Starett.
I'll see ya.
What do you make of him?
He's no cowpuncher.
No... he doesn't look the part,
sure enough.
I like Starett, too,
but I'll kill him
if I have to.
I tell you,
I'll kill him if I have to.
You mean I'll kill him
if you have to.
I can't have any
run-in with the law.
You heard Grafton.
You just get
Starett in here.
It wouldn't take
much to bait him.
Well, lookee here.
Lookee here.
Why don't we just gun him
and get on with it?
One's run already.
It won't take much to stampede
the rest.
Remember, Wilson,
we've got to make this
look right to Grafton.
[Thunder]
Hey! Come here.
Torrey... I vouldn't go over there,
Torrey.
Nobody's going to buffalo me.
What can I do for you?
Where do you think
you're going?
Well, to get a whiskey.
Torrey.
[Thunder]
Torrey?
They tell me they call you
Stonewall.
Anything wrong with that?
That's just funny.
I guess they named
a lot of that...
southern trash
after old Stonewall.
Who'd they name you after...
or would you know?
I'm saying that Stonewall Jackson
was trash himself.
Him and Lee and all the rest
of them rebs.
You, too.
You're a low-down lying Yankee.
Prove it.
No, Torrey!
[Brown]
One less sodbuster.
What?
He tried to pull
on Wilson.
Ain't that right,
Swede?
Vell, he...
he tried to reach for a...
[Morgan]
All right...
get him out of here.
Then you can go back
and tell your friends
we'll be waiting right here
for any more of them
that comes in looking
for trouble.
You understand that,
Swede?
Now, get him out of here.
What happened?
A sodbuster
tried to kill Wilson.
What's the shooting?
A sodbuster
tried to pull on Wilson.
[Morgan]
Ha ha ha.
Lewis!
Pa...
what's happened?
Lewis!
Fred!
Lewis, he is dead.
Ryker did it.
I go for Starett.
Shane, we've sure enough
earned our keep today.
If they just
leave us alone,
we're going to make a farm
out of this place yet.
Somebody's coming, Pa.
It looks like Shipstead.
It's Mr. Shipstead.
Starett!
Torrey... he is dead!
Torrey.
Torrey, he is dead!
Torrey's dead.
The new man shot him.
The new man that works for Ryker
did it.
I vas across the street
and hear anger in the voices.
And they reach
for their pistols,
but the new man is quick,
terribly quick.
One shot, Torrey's dead,
One shot.
What happened?
Vell, ve go to town together.
He say it be safe.
Vas all quiet.
Ve separate.
Then the anger
in the voices I hear,
only the anger,
not the words.
Ryker's men
vas all around.
What started it?
I pass Lewis, him and his missus,
and Yohnson.
They scared.
Who saw it?
Just the Ryker men and me.
Morgan say
they vait in town
for any more that vant to come around
looking for trouble.
Marian...
honey, you get ready.
Mrs. Torrey
will need you.
Shane, hitch up the team.
What are you
going to do?
Go to town.
I'm going to see about this.
You can't go alone.
Marian, I'm going.
She's right, Joe.
But the others
are all in this.
It's not just you, Joe.
Wait. Wait for them.
Sooner or later,
someone's got to go.
[Marian]
But not now.
Don't you go alone.
The other homesteaders,
I think they run.
I think they
get out of here.
Here comes Joe Starett.
Wish he'd tend to his own business.
What goes on, Fred?
Just us.
We're going on.
I've had enough.
I sure figured you
for a better man.
You've already saw what happened,
haven't you?
Torrey's dead, ain't he?
Just going to pile up your plunder
and skip.
Too scared to even see Torrey
get a decent funeral.
I don't want him killed.
We're going.
Martha, it ain't a question
of who stays or who runs.
The thing is, we've got to see Stonewall
get a Christian burial.
And his wife hear some words of comfort
said over her man.
Some of us will make sure
that gets done.
Torrey's dead.
I don't want it
to happen to my man.
Fred, if you ain't
at that funeral,
I'll sure take it
bad of you.
Well, the cemetery hill's
on the way out, Martha.
? Before my
closing eyes ?
? Shine through
the gloom ?
? And point me
to the skies ?
? Heavers morning breaks ?
? And Earth's
vain shadows flee ?
? In life, in death,
oh, Lord ?
? Abide with me ??
[Mrs. Torrey Sobs]
Shipstead, would you please lead us
in the Lord's Prayer?
Our Father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for Thine is the kingdom
and the power
and the glory forever.
Amen.
[Mrs. Torrey Sobs]
[Harmonica Plays Dixie]
That's going to bite you.
[Playing Taps]
Ha ha ha ha.
Goodbye, Mrs. Starett.
We're going.
Goodbye, Joe.
Goodbye, Axel.
Goodbye, John.
Sue, put the kids
in the wagon.
Wait for me, Lewis.
I'm coming with you.
Now, wait a minute.
Let's not be in a hurry.
One more thing.
Torrey was
a pretty brave man.
And I figure
we'd be doing wrong,
if we wasn't the same.
Joe, last time
you argued us into staying,
Torrey was alive.
Do you want more of this?
We can have a regular
settlement here.
W-We can have a town
and churches
and a school.
Graveyards?
I... I don't know,
but you just got to,
that's all.
You know why he
wants you to stay.
Something that means more to you
than anything else...
your families.
Your wives and kids.
Like you, Lewis.
Your girls.
Shipstead with his boys.
They've got a right to stay here
and grow up and be happy.
That's up to you people
to have... nerve enough
to not give it up.
That's right. That's...
We can't
give up this valley,
and we ain't
going to do it.
This is farming country,
a place where people can come
and bring up
their families.
Who is Rufe Ryker
or anyone else
to run us away
from our own homes?
He only wants
to grow beef.
What we want to
grow up is families,
to grow 'em strong,
the way they was
meant to be grown.
God didn't make
all this country
just for one man
like Ryker.
He's got it, though.
That's what counts.
Look. Look there.
Hey, a fire.
It's Lewis' place.
That's our place.
Ryker lit it.
He had no right.
If you hadn't packed up
and left it...
That was ours.
I built it myself.
The girls' room
wasn't started.
I was getting to it.
We stick together,
we can put that place
right back up.
Right, Johnson?
That's right.
We'll help you build
the extra room.
Johnson, Joe,
Shane will help, right,
Shane?
That's right.
We'll get the timber,
and we'll put her
right back up.
Right?
Yes, sir.
We'll get it done.
I vill help.
You'll do that for us?
All that, just for us?
Not just for you, Martha.
For all of us
here in this valley.
Some of you come help.
Maybe we can save
part of that.
That's the spirit,
Fred.
Come on, men.
Let's get to Lewis' place.
Let's get going.
Come on, men.
Boss, looks like Lewis
is going back.
Starett's holding 'em
together.
What if Ryker sets
fire to my place?
Just stay on your ground.
He'll do to us what he done
to Torrey.
There's a law in this country
against killing.
The law's three days from here.
You know that, Yoe.
What's that leave us with, Starett?
Just give me some time.
Who's going to
fight with Ryker?
He's got us on the run.
You men hang on,
that's all.
That's it.
Just hang on.
I promise something
will be done.
But just vat, Yoe?
You leave that to me.
I'll have this out with Ryker.
You're taking on too much
all by yourself.
If I have to kill him...
That's wrong.
Don't even think that.
[Coyote Howls]
Starett's got to go.
I've warned him twice,
but he's pigheaded,
and he's going to
have to pay for it.
Joe, you can't do it.
Marian, if the Lewises
had courage enough
to start over again,
I ain't letting them down.
But you can't, Joe.
Can't what?
Go in town
to kill Ryker.
He'll kill you.
Tell him I'm a reasonable man.
Tell him things have
gone far enough.
Tell him I'm beat.
Tell him anything, but,
by Jupiter, get him here.
He'll come.
He thinks he's
a reasonable man.
Hello, Calloway.
Joe, he'll kill you.
It's a chance
I got to take.
This is a false
square knot, Joey.
It won't hold.
Shane, tell him.
Tell him he can't go.
It won't work.
Tell him.
Shane!
Wait, Joe.
Wait till things
cool off.
Wait that long anyway.
That's right,
isn't it, Shane?
I can't tell Joe
what's right, Marian.
Please wait, Joe.
Won't you do...
even this for me?
[Dog Barks]
[Barking]
Starett!
Mr. Starett!
Who is it?
Peace party from Ryker.
One of you can
come across and talk.
Stay out of
that garden.
We ain't armed.
Brother Rufe
wants to see you.
He says to tell you
he's a reasonable man.
Your brother's responsible for killing
my friend Torrey.
My brother wouldn't
kill anybody.
He don't want
to go to jail.
Torrey was a hothead.
He picked on a stranger.
Torrey didn't want
to be reasonable.
You want to be reasonable,
don't you, Starett?
I always figured
on being reasonable.
My brother's waiting.
He'll see you
at Grafton's.
Who else?
Not us.
We're heading home.
I'll see your brother.
Shane.
Who is it?
Calloway.
Chris Calloway.
Stay there.
I can drill you.
Hold it, Shane.
Something to tell you.
What do you want?
Starett's up against
a stacked deck.
Bang, bang.
Bang, bang, bang.
Why you telling me?
I don't know.
I reckon something's
come over me.
I don't figure you.
I'm quitting Ryker.
Bang, bang.
So long.
Chris...
Thanks.
Be seeing you.
Bang, bang, bang.
No use to argue, Marian.
I'm going into this
with my eyes open.
No!
Isn't there anything
I can say that will change things?
Can't you see maybe
this is a chance?
Morgan and them boys
went home.
You don't really
believe that.
That's not the reason.
It's just too much
to give up...
This place and our valley...
all the things
that will be.
Will be...
Bang!
Bang, bang, bang,
bang, bang!
Bang, bang, bang!
Don't point that thing.
Go play outside!
Bang, bang!
Play outside, Joey!
Bang, bang...
Please, dear...
go outside and play.
It's just pride, that's all.
A silly kind of a pride.
Don't I mean anything
to you, Joe?
Doesn't Joey?
Marian...
honey...
it's because you mean so much to me
that I've got to go.
Do you think I could
go on living with you,
and you thinking
that I'd showed yellow?
Then what about Joey?
How would I ever
explain that to him?
Oh, Joe...
Joe...
I-I've been
thinking a lot,
and...
I know I'm kind of
slow sometimes, Marian,
but I see things...
and I know if anything
happened to me,
you'd be took care of.
You'd be took care of
better than I could do it myself.
I never thought I'd live
to hear myself say that,
but I guess now's a pretty good time
to lay things bare.
You talk as though
I'd be glad for you to go.
Honey, you're the most honest
and the finest girl
that ever lived,
and I couldn't do
what I got to do
if I hadn't always knowed
that I could trust you.
Now, don't you go
counting me out.
I wouldn't have lived
as long as I have already
if I wasn't pretty tough.
Pa! Shane's got his gun on.
He's coming!
Gun?
What's the idea?
Don't let him go, Shane.
Don't anybody go.
This is my kind of game, Joe.
Except it ain't yours.
Maybe you're a match
for Ryker...
maybe not.
But you're no match
for Wilson.
Well, then I'll outlast him.
But I do appreciate it, Shane.
You're both out of your senses.
This isn't worth
anybody's life.
What are you
fighting for,
this little
piece of ground
and nothing but work,
work, work?
I'm sick of it.
I'm sick of trouble.
Joe, let's move.
Let's go on. Please?
Marian, don't say that.
That ain't the truth.
You love this place.
Not anymore.
Even if that was true,
it wouldn't change things.
There must be some way, Shane.
Some way?
It's no use, Joe.
No use?
Well, what's stopping me?
I am.
You get out of my way.
Am I going to have
to fight you, too?
That depends on you.
Aah!
No!
[Whinny]
Stop!
Oh...
Hyah.
Shane! You hit him with your gun.
I hate you!
Have him walk around
when he comes to.
Joey, bring some
water and a towel.
Here, Marian.
Hide this.
He'll be all right.
No one can blame him
for not keeping that date.
Shane...
wait.
You were through
with gunfighting.
I changed my mind.
Are you doing this
just for me?
For you, Marian...
for Joe and little Joe.
Then we'll never
see you again?
Never's a long time,
Marian.
Tell him...
tell him I was sorry.
No need to tell him that.
Please, Shane...
Mother...
Please...
Take care of yourself.
Mother...
Pa's coming along
all right.
Yes, Joey.
Why did Shane...
Shane did what he had to do,
Joey.
You don't hate Shane.
I know, Mother.
Shane.
I'm sorry.
He didn't hear you.
Shane!
Shane, I'm sorry!
I came to get
your offer, Ryker.
I'm not dealing
with you.
Where's Starett?
You're dealing
with me, Ryker.
I got no quarrel
with you, Shane.
You can walk out now
and no hard feelings.
What's your offer, Ryker?
To you...
not a thing.
That's too bad.
Too bad?
Yeah. You've lived too long.
Your kind of days are over.
My days?
What about yours,
gunfighter?
The difference is,
I know it.
All right.
So we'll all
turn in our guns,
and we'll all start hoeing spuds.
Is that it?
Not quite yet.
We haven't heard
from your friend here.
I wouldn't push too far
if I were you.
Our fight
ain't with you.
It ain't with me,
Wilson?
No, it ain't, Shane.
I wouldn't pull on Wilson,
Shane.
Will, you're witness to this.
So you're Jack Wilson.
What's that mean to you, Shane?
I've heard about you.
What have you heard, Shane?
I've heard that you're
a low-down Yankee liar.
Prove it.
Shane, look out!
Shane.
I knew you could, Shane.
I knew it.
I knew it just as well
as anything.
Was that him?
Was that Wilson?
That was him.
That was Wilson,
all right.
He was fast,
fast on the draw.
Joey, what are you doing here?
I'm sorry, Shane.
You don't have to be.
You better run back.
Can't I ride home behind you?
Afraid not, Joey.
Please? Why not?
I got to be going on.
Why, Shane?
A man has to be
what he is, Joey.
Can't break the mold.
I tried it,
and it didn't work for me.
We want you, Shane.
Joey, there's no living with...
with a killing.
There's no going back from one.
Right or wrong,
it's a brand...
and a brand sticks.
There's no going back.
Now, you run on home
to your mother
and tell her
everything's all right,
and there aren't any more guns
in the valley.
Shane...
it's bloody.
You're hurt.
I'm all right, Joey.
You go home to your
mother and your father
and grow up to be
strong and straight.
And, Joey...
take care of them.
Both of them.
Yes, Shane.
He'd never been able to shoot you
if you'd seen him.
Bye, little Joe.
He'd never even have cleared
the holster, would he, Shane?
Pa's got things
for you to do!
And mother wants you!
I know she does!
Shane!
Come back!