Singin' in the rain
Just singin' in the rain
What a glorious feelin'
We're happy again
We'll walk down the lane
With a happy refrain
And singin'
Just singin' in the rain
This is Dora Bailey...
talking to you from the front of
the Chinese Theater in Hollywood.
What a night, ladies and gentlemen!
Every star in
Hollywood's heaven is here...
to make Monumental Pictures'
premiere of 'The Royal Rascal'...
the outstanding event of 1927.
Everyone is breathlessly awaiting...
the arrival of Lina Lamont
and Don Lockwood.
Look who's arriving now!
It's that famous
Zip Girl of the screen...
the darling of the flapper set,
Zelda Zanders.
Zelda! Oh, Zelda!
With her new red-hot pash,
J. Cumberland Spendrill III...
that well-known eligible bachelor.
Zelda's had so much unhappiness.
I hope this time it's really love.
And here comes that exotic star,
Olga Mara...
and her new husband,
the Baron de la Bonnet de la Toulon.
They've been married
two months already...
but still as happy as newlyweds.
Well, well, well.
It's Cosmo Brown!
Cosmo is Don Lockwood's best friend.
He plays the piano for Don and Lina
to get them into those romantic moods.
Oh, folks, this is it!
The stars of tonight's picture,
those romantic lovers of the screen...
Don Lockwood and Lina Lamont!
Ladies and gentlemen,
when you look at this gorgeous couple...
it's no wonder they're
a household name all over the world...
like bacon and eggs.
Lockwood and Lamont.
Don, you can tell me confidentially...
are these rumors true that wedding bells
are soon to ring for you and Lina?
Lina and I have no statement to make
right now. We're just good friends.
You've come a long way together, Don.
Won't you tell us how it all happened?
Well, Lina and I have made
a number of pictures together...
No, no, Don.
I want your story from the beginning.
Dora, not in front
of all these people.
Yes!
But, Don, the story of your success
is an inspiration...
to young people all over the world.
- Please.
- Yes!
Well, to begin with,
any story of my career...
would have to include
my lifelong friend, Cosmo Brown!
We were kids together,
grew up together, worked together.
Yes?
Well, Dora, I've had one motto
which I've always lived by:
Dignity.
Always dignity.
This was instilled in me by Mom and Dad
from the very beginning.
They sent me to the finest schools,
including dancing school.
That's where I first met Cosmo.
And with him, I used to perform for
all of Mom and Dad's society friends.
They used to make such a fuss over me.
If I was good, I was allowed to
accompany Mom and Dad to the theater.
They brought me up on Shaw, Moliere...
the finest of the classics.
To this was added musical training
at the Conservatory of Fine Arts.
We rounded out our apprenticeship...
at the most exclusive
dramatics academy.
And at all times...
the motto remained: Dignity.
Always dignity.
In a few years, Cosmo and I embarked
on a dance concert tour.
We played the finest
symphonic halls in the country.
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
I can jump over the moon up above
Haven't a worry, haven't a care
Feel like a feather
that's floatin' on air
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
Soon the church bells
will be ringin'
And a march with Ma and Pa
All the church bells will be ringin'
With a hey-nonny-nonny
and a hot-cha-cha
Hi-diddle-diddle, my baby's okay
Ask me a riddle, I'm happy to say
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
Audiences everywhere adored us.
Finally, we decided
to come to sunny California.
We were stranded...
We were staying here when the offers
from movie studios started pouring in.
We sorted them out and decided
to favor Monumental Pictures.
Okay, Lina, you hate him.
Keep that mood music going.
Phil, you come in. Keep on grinding.
Now you see her.
Now here's the bit, Bert,
where you get it on the jaw.
Cut! No, no!
That wasn't right, Bert!
You were supposed to go over the bar
and crash into the glasses!
Try it again, okay, Bert? Bert!
Oh, that's just swell!
Take him away, fellas.
You'll be all right, Bert.
We've lost more darn stuntmen
on this picture!
It'll take hours to get
a new one over from central casting!
Mr. Dexter, I can do that.
- You're a musician!
- That's a moot point.
No kidding!
What's your name?
Don Lockwood, sir,
but the fellas call me Donald.
Wise guy, huh?
Okay, I'll try you.
Get this guy into Bert's suit!
And remember, Lockwood, you might be
trading that fiddle in for a harp!
Camera!
Phil, come in!
Now you see him!
Here's where you get it
right on the jaw!
Cut! That was wonderful!
You got any more little chores
you want done?
Plenty.
My roles in these films were urbane...
sophisticated, suave.
And of course,
all through those pictures...
Lina was, as always,
an inspiration to me.
Warm and helpful. A real lady.
Hello, Miss Lamont.
I'm Don Lockwood, the stuntman.
It was sure a thrill
working with you, Miss Lamont.
Don, I want you to meet the producer
of the picture, Mr. R.F. Simpson.
I just saw some rushes for the picture
and asked Dexter who the stuntmen were.
He told me they were all you.
I'm putting you and Lina together
in a picture. Come to my office.
- We'll discuss a contract.
- Thanks, Mr. Simpson!
Are you doing anything tonight,
Miss Lamont?
Well, that's funny.
I'm busy.
Lina and I have had the same
wonderful relationship ever since.
But most important of all,
I continue living up to my motto:
Dignity.
Always dignity.
Thank you, Don.
And I'm sure you and Lina will continue
making movie history tonight...
in your greatest picture,
'The Royal Rascal.'
Get enough, boys?
She's so refined.
I think I'll kill myself.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
We're pretty darn thrilled at your
response to 'The Royal Rascal.'
We had fun making it, and we hope
you had fun seeing it tonight.
We screen actors aren't much good
at speaking in public...
so we'll just act out our thanks.
It's a smash, eh, Mr. Simpson?
- Don. Lina, you were gorgeous.
- You look pretty good for a girl.
For heaven's sake, what's the big idea?
Can't a girl get a word in edgewise?
After all, they're my public too!
The publicity department, Rod here,
thought it would be much better...
if Don made the speeches
for the team.
Why?
You're a beautiful woman. Audiences
think you've got a voice to match.
The studio's gotta keep their stars
from looking ridiculous at any cost.
- No one's got that much money.
- What's wrong with the way I talk?
What's the big idea?
Am I dumb or something?
No. It's just that Don's
had so much more experience...
Next time, write me out a speech.
I could memorize it.
Why don't you go out now
and recite the Gettysburg Address?
What do you know about it,
you piano player? Are you anybody?
Donnie, how can you let him
talk to me like that, your fiance?
My fian...
Now, Lina, you've been reading
those fan magazines again.
You shouldn't believe
all that banana oil...
that Dora Bailey
and the columnists dish out.
Now try to get this straight.
There is nothing between us.
There has never been
anything between us. Just air.
Oh, Donnie, you don't mean that.
Come on. We'll be late
for R.F.'s party.
You better go in separate cars
to break up the mobs, huh?
Ta-ta, Donnie! See ya there!
Donnie. What's wrong with that girl?
Can't she take a gentle hint?
Haven't you heard? She's irresistible.
She told me so herself.
I can't shake her. This cooked-up
romance, just for publicity.
The price of fame.
You've got the glory.
You've gotta take the little heartaches
that go with it. Look at me.
I got no glory. I got no fame.
I got no mansions. I got no money.
But I've got...
What have I got?
- I don't know. What?
- I gotta get outta here.
Don't tell me.
It's a flat tire.
I don't understand. This car hasn't
given me trouble for six hours.
There's Don Lockwood!
- Give me your autograph!
- Hi, kids!
I want a souvenir!
- I want a souvenir too!
- Hold on there!
You're tearing my...
Hey, Cos, call me a cab!
Okay, you're a cab.
Thanks a lot!
- Lady, keep driving.
- Get out of here!
- I'll call the police!
- Don't do that.
- Don't hurt me!
- I'm not a criminal.
You are a criminal!
I've seen that face before.
- You're a famous gangster!
- Let me explain...
I've seen your picture
in the post office. Officer!
This man jumped into my car...
- Why, it's Don Lockwood!
- Don Lockwood?
- Out for a joyride?
- Just a lift, Officer.
My car broke down,
I got surrounded...
You're a lucky lady.
Anything wrong?
- Why, no.
- I should think not. Good night.
Good night, Officer.
Well, thanks for saving my life.
I'll get out now.
I'm driving to Beverly Hills.
Can I drop you someplace?
I'd like to get out of this torn suit
if you're going by Camden and Sunset.
Yes, I am.
I'd very much like to know
whose hospitality I'm enjoying.
Selden. Kathy Selden.
Enchanted, Miss Selden.
I'm sorry I frightened you.
I was getting a little too much love
from my adoring fans.
Oh, that's what you were
running away from.
They did that to you?
That's terrible.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
It is terrible.
Well, we movie stars get the glory.
I guess we have to take
the little heartaches that go with it.
People think we lead lives
of glamour and romance...
but we're really lonely.
Terribly lonely.
Mr. Lockwood, I can't tell you how sorry
I am about taking you for a criminal...
but it was understandable
under the circumstances.
- I knew I'd seen you.
- Which of my pictures have you seen?
I don't remember.
I saw one once.
- You saw one once?
- You were dueling.
There was a girl, Lina Lamont.
Though I don't go to the movies much.
If you've seen one,
you've seen them all.
- Thank you.
- No offense.
Movies are entertaining
enough for the masses...
but the personalities on the screen
just don't impress me.
They don't talk, they don't act.
They just make a lot of dumb show.
Well, you know.
Like that.
You mean, like what I do?
Well, yes.
Here we are, Sunset and Camden.
Wait a minute.
You mean, I'm not an actor?
- Pantomime on the screen isn't acting?
- Of course not.
Acting means great parts, wonderful
lines, speaking those glorious words.
- Words.
- Shakespeare, Ibsen.
What's your lofty mission in life that
lets you sneer at my humble profession?
Well, I'm an actress.
On the stage.
Oh, on the stage.
I'd like to see you act.
What are you in now?
I could brush up on my English
or bring along an interpreter...
if they'd let in a movie actor.
I'm not in a play now, but I will be.
I'm going to New York...
You're going to New York.
Someday we'll all hear of you, won't we?
Kathy Selden as Juliet,
as Lady Macbeth, as King Lear.
You'll have to wear a beard
for that one.
Laugh if you want to, but at least
the stage is a dignified profession.
What are you so conceited about?
You're nothing but a shadow on film.
You're not flesh and blood.
- Stop!
- Why? I'm only a shadow.
Just because you're
a big movie star...
you expect every girl to fall
in a dead faint at your feet!
Well, don't you touch me!
Fear not, sweet lady.
I will not molest you.
I am but a humble jester...
and you are too far above me.
Farewell, Ethel Barrymore.
I must tear myself from your side.
- Is this R.F. Simpson's house?
- Yes, miss.
- I'm from the Coconut Grove.
- Around the back, please.
I see. Thank you.
- Nice party, R.F.
- Thanks, Roscoe.
Mr. Brown, do you really think
you could get me in the movies?
- I should think so.
- Really?
There's Don!
I loved the picture tonight.
- Don, did you come by way of Australia?
- Hello, Cos.
Listen, Cos, tell me the truth.
Am I a good actor?
As long as I'm working for Monumental,
you're the greatest.
You're my pal.
You can tell me.
What's the matter?
Of course you're good.
Maybe you should tell me
from time to time.
- I feel a little shaken.
- The new Don Lockwood.
Where have you been?
We've been waiting for you.
There you are, Donnie.
I was lonely.
- Hello, Lina.
- Okay, fellas, hold it.
Together again, like two little stars.
Don and Lina.
No kidding, folks.
Aren't they great?
All right, open that screen.
- A movie? We've just seen one.
- Hollywood law says we have to.
I've got a few little
surprises for you tonight.
All right, everyone, sit down.
This will give you a lot of laughs.
There's a madman coming into
my office now for months, and...
- Got that gadget working, Sam?
- All set, Mr. Simpson.
Okay, let her go.
Hello.
This is a demonstration
of a talking picture.
Notice, it is a picture of me,
and I am talking.
Note how my lips
and the sound issuing from them...
are synchronized together...
in perfect unison.
- Who's that?
- Somebody's talking behind that screen.
- Come out from there, Mr. Simpson.
- No, I'm right here.
My voice has been
recorded on a record.
A talking picture.
Thank you. Good-bye.
- Well?
- It's just a toy.
- It's a scream!
- It's vulgar.
- Think they'll ever use it?
- I doubt it.
The Warner Brothers are making a whole
talking picture, 'The Jazz Singer.'
They'll lose their shirts.
What do you think, Dexter?
- It'll never amount to a thing.
- They said that about automobiles.
Let's get on with the show, boys.
Come on, my little starlets.
I have a delicious surprise.
A very special cake.
I want you kiddies
to have the first piece.
Well, if it isn't Ethel Barrymore.
I do hope you're gonna favor us
with something special.
- Please.
- Say Hamlet's soliloquy.
- Or a scene from 'Romeo and Juliet.'
- Mr. Lockwood...
Don't be shy. You'd make about the
prettiest Juliet I've ever seen, really.
All I do is dream of you
the whole night through
With the dawn I still go on
dreaming of you
You're every thought
You're everything
You're every song I ever sing
Summer, winter, autumn and spring
And were there more
than 24 hours a day
They'd be spent in sweet content
dreaming away
When skies are gray
When skies are blue
Morning, noon and nighttime too
All I do the whole day through
is dream of you
You're the cat's meow!
All I do the whole day through
is dream of you
- I have to tell you how good you were.
- Excuse me.
Now that I know where you live,
I'd like to see you home.
- Listen, Mr. Lockwood...
- Say! Who is this dame?
Oh, someone lofty
and far above us all.
She couldn't learn
anything from the movies.
She's an actress
on the legitimate stage.
Here's one thing
I've learned from the movies!
Lina, she was aiming at me!
- You've never looked lovelier.
- It was just an accident.
It happens to me
five or six times a day.
Where is she?
Donnie?
Excuse me.
Where'd Miss Selden go?
She just grabbed her things and vaulted.
Anything I can do?
Sorry. I don't have time
to find out.
Keep that action going.
Let's have more steam in the kettle.
A little more action, boys.
More steam and water in that kettle.
- Good morning, fellas.
- Did you read 'Variety' today?
'First talking picture, The Jazz Singer,
all-time smash by end of first week.'
- All-time flop by end of the second.
- We start today.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
I am now Count Pierre de Battaille,
better known as the Dueling Cavalier.
- What's this one about?
- It's a French Revolution story.
You're a French aristocrat,
and she's a simple girl of the people...
and she won't even
give you a tumble.
Well, it's a living.
Hit him. Hit him.
Knock him down.
Get up there and hit him again.
Why bother to shoot this picture?
Release the old one under a new title.
If you've seen one,
you've seen them all.
- What'd you say that for?
- What's the matter?
That's what that Kathy Selden
said to me that night.
That's three weeks ago.
Are you still thinking about that?
- Well, I can't get her out of my mind.
- How could you?
She's the first dame who hasn't fallen
for your line since you were four.
- I guess she's on my conscience.
- It's not your fault she lost her job.
- I've got to find her.
- You've been trying to...
short of sending out
bloodhounds and a posse.
Snap out of it. Don't let
a little thing get you down.
You're Don Lockwood, aren't you?
Donald Lockwood's an actor, isn't he?
What's the first thing an actor learns?
The show must go on!
Come rain, come shine, come snow,
come sleet, the show must go on!
Ridi, Pagliacci, ridi.
The world's so full
of a number of things.
I'm sure we should all
be as happy as...
But are we? No.
Definitely no.
Positively no!
Decidedly no!
Short people have long faces,
and long people have short faces.
Big people have little humor,
and little people have no humor at all.
And in the words of that immortal bard,
Samuel J. Snodgrass...
as he was about to be led
to the guillotine...
Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh
Don't you know
everyone wants to laugh
My dad said
Be an actor, my son
But be a comical one
They'll be standin' in lines
For those old
honky-tonk monkeyshines
Now you could study Shakespeare
and be quite elite
And you could charm the critics
and have nothing to eat
Just slip on a banana peel
The world's at your feet
Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh
make 'em laugh
Make 'em laugh
Don't you know
everyone wants to laugh
My grandpa said
Go out and tell 'em a joke
But give it plenty of hoke
Make 'em roar
make 'em scream
Take a fall, butt a wall
split a seam
You start off by pretending
you're a dancer with grace
You wiggle 'til they're giggling
all over the place
And then you get
a great big custard pie in the face
Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh
make 'em laugh
Make 'em laugh
Don't you... All the...
My dad...
They'll be standin' in lines
For those old
honky-tonk monkeyshines
Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh
Don't you know everyone...
Make 'em laugh
Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh
- Ready, Don?
- All set, Roscoe.
Here we go again. I think we have
another smash on our hands.
- I hope so.
- You're darn tootin' we have.
- Where's Lina?
- Here she is.
Well, well, here comes
our lovely leading lady now.
This wig weighs a ton.
What dope would wear a thing like this?
- Everybody used to wear them.
- Then everybody was a dope.
Honey, you look beautiful.
Yes, you look great.
Let's get into the set.
Thanks, Joe.
I looked for you the other night
at Wally Ray's party.
- Where were you?
- I've been busy.
And I know what you've been busy at...
lookin' for that girl.
- As a matter of fact, yes.
- Why?
- I've been worried about her.
- You should've been worried about me.
After all, I'm the one who got
the whipped cream in the kisser.
But you didn't lose your job,
and she did.
You're darn tootin' she did.
I arranged it.
What?
They weren't gonna fire her, so I called
them and told them they'd better.
Okay, Don, remember.
You're madly in love with her, and you
must overcome her shyness and timidity.
Cosmo, mood music.
Roll 'em!
Okay, Don.
Now enter.
You see her.
Run to her!
Why, you rattlesnake, you.
You got that poor kid fired.
That's not all I'm gonna do
if I ever get my hands on her.
I never heard of anything so low.
Fine. Looks great.
What did you do it for?
'Cause you liked her.
I could tell.
So that's it.
Believe me, I don't like her
half as much as I hate you.
You reptile.
Sticks and stones may break my bones...
I'd like to break
every bone in your body.
You and who else, you big lummox?
Kiss her, Don.
That's it! More!
Great! Cut!
You couldn't kiss me like that
and not mean it just a teensy bit.
Meet the greatest actor in the world.
I'd rather kiss a tarantula!
- You don't mean that.
- I don't...
Joe, bring me a tarantula.
Listen, Lina...
Stop that chitchat, you lovebirds.
Let's get another take.
Hold it!
- Hold it!
- Hello, Mr. Simpson.
- We're really rolling.
- Stop rolling at once.
All right, everybody, save it!
Tell them to go home.
We're shutting down for a few weeks.
- What?
- Don't just stand there, tell them!
Everybody go home until further notice!
What is this?
- What's the matter, R.F.?
- 'The Jazz Singer,' that's what.
My darlin' little mammy
down in Alabamy
This is no joke, Cosmo.
The public is screaming for more.
- More what?
- Talking pictures!
- It's just a freak.
- We should have such a freak here.
I told you talking pictures were
a menace, but no one would listen to me.
Don, we're going to put
our best feet forward.
We're going to make 'The Dueling
Cavalier' into a talking picture.
That means I'm out of a job. I can start
suffering and write that symphony.
We're putting you in as
head of the new music department.
Thanks, R.F.! I can stop suffering
and write that symphony.
Wait a second, Mr. Simpson.
I think you should wait...
Every studio
is jumping on the bandwagon.
Theaters are putting in sound equipment.
We don't want to be left out.
- We know nothing about this gadget.
- What do you have to know?
You do what you always did.
You just add talking to it.
- Yeah?
- Believe me, it will be a sensation.
'Lamont And Lockwood: They Talk.'
Well, of course we talk.
Don't everybody?
I got a feelin' you're foolin'
I got a feelin' you're havin' fun
I'll get the go-by when you are done
foolin' with me
It's a holiday, today's the wedding
of the painted doll
It's a jolly day
The news is spreading
Should I reveal exactly how I feel
Should I confess
Beautiful girl
You're a lovely picture
You're a gorgeous picture
Of all that lies
under the big blue skies
My heart cries
That girl on his right
looks familiar.
You're a dazzling eyeful
- I've featured her in nightclub shows.
- That's probably where I've seen her.
She'd be good in the part
of Zelda's kid sister.
- That's a good idea.
- Excuse me.
There may be blondes and brunettes
That are hard to resist
You surpass them like a queen
You've got those lips
that were meant to be kissed
And you're over sweet 16
Oh, beautiful girl
What a gorgeous creature
Beautiful girl
Let me call a preacher
What can I do
But give my heart to you
A beautiful girl
is like a great work of art.
She's stylish.
She's chic.
And she also is smart
For lounging in her boudoir...
this simple, plain pajama.
Her cloak is trimmed
with monkey fur...
to lend a dash of drama.
Anyone for tennis?
Well, this will make them cringe.
And you'll knock 'em dead at dinner...
if your gown just drips with fringe.
You simply can't be too modest...
at the beach or by the pool.
And in summertime it's organdy...
that'll keep you fresh and cool.
You'd never guess what loud applause...
this cunning hat receives.
And you'd never dream
the things that you could hide...
within these sleeves.
A string of pearls
with a suit of tweed.
It started quite a riot.
And if you must wear fox
to the opera...
Dame Fashion says, 'Dye it.'
Black is best when you're in court.
The judge will be impressed
But white is right
when you're a bride
And you want to be well-dressed
Beautiful girl
For you I've got a passion
You're my queen of fashion
I'm in a whirl
Over my beautiful
Girl
- That's stupendous!
- Thanks.
- Kathy, come here.
- This'll start a new trend in musicals.
Kathy, Mr. Simpson is thinking of
casting you as Zelda's kid sister.
That's wonderful, Mr. Simpson.
- That's Kathy Selden!
- Thanks anyway.
- Wait a minute.
- That's all right.
Before Mr. Lockwood reminds you,
you might as well know...
I'm the girl who hit
Miss Lamont with a cake.
Believe me,
it was meant for Mr. Lockwood!
Good-bye, Sid.
I should have told you.
Wait a minute.
What's this about, R.F.?
We wanted to use her in Zelda's picture,
but if it made you and Lina unhappy...
I think it's wonderful.
- He's been looking for her for weeks.
- Are you speaking for Lina also?
R.F., the owner of the Coconut Grove
may do what Lina tells him to...
- but you're the head of this studio.
- Yes, I am.
She's hired. But don't let
Lina know she's on the lot.
- Take care of that, Phillips.
- Thank you!
I'm glad you turned up.
We've looked inside every cake in town.
Is it all right for you
to be seen with me?
You mean, lofty star
with humble player?
Not exactly, but for lunch, don't you
usually tear a pheasant with Lamont?
Look, Kathy, all that stuff about
Lina and me is sheer publicity.
Oh? It certainly seems
more than that.
From what I've read in the columns
and the fan magazines...
You read the fan magazines.
I pick them up in the beauty parlor
or the dentist's office...
just like anybody.
Honest?
- Well, I buy four or five a month.
- You buy four or five?
Anyway, to get back
to the main point...
you and Miss Lamont do achieve
an intimacy in all your pictures...
Did you say all my pictures?
I guess now that I think of it,
I've seen eight or nine of them.
Eight or nine. It seems to me
I remember someone saying...
'If you've seen one,
you've seen 'em all.'
I did say some awful things
that night, didn't I?
No. I deserved them.
Of course, I must admit
I was pretty much upset by them.
So upset that I haven't been able
to think of anything but you ever since.
Honest?
Honest.
Well, I've been pretty upset too.
Kathy, look.
Seeing you again,
now that I...
Kathy, I'm trying to say
something to you, but I...
I'm such a ham.
I guess I'm not able to
without the proper setting.
- What do you mean?
- Well...
Come here.
This is the proper setting.
Why, it's just an empty stage.
At first glance, yes.
But wait a second.
A beautiful sunset.
Mist from the distant mountains.
Colored lights in a garden.
Milady is standing on her balcony...
in a rose-trellised bower...
flooded with moonlight.
We add 500,000 kilowatts
of stardust...
a soft summer breeze...
and...
You sure look lovely
in the moonlight, Kathy.
Now that you have the proper setting,
can you say it?
I'll try.
Life was a song
You came along
I've laid awake
the whole night through
If I but dared
To think you cared
This is what I'd say to you
You were meant for me
And I was meant for you
Nature patterned you
And when she was done
You were all the sweet things
Rolled up in one
You're like a plaintive melody
That never lets me free
But I'm content
The angels must have sent you
And they meant you
Just for me
But I'm content
The angels must have sent you
And they meant you
Just for me
Now...
ta, te, ti, to, tu.
Ta, tay, tee, toe, too.
No, no, Miss Lamont.
Round tones, round tones.
Now let me hear you read your line.
And I can't stand 'im.
And I can't stand him.
Can't.
'Cahn't.'
'Can-t.'
Can't. Can't.
Very good. Now...
Around the rocks the rugged rascal ran.
- Around the rocks the rugged...
- No, rocks, rocks.
Around the rocks the rugged rascal ran.
- Shall I continue?
- Go ahead.
Don't mind me.
Sinful Caesar sipped his snifter...
seized his knees and sneezed.
- Sinful Caesar snipped his sifter...
- No, sipped his snifter.
- Sipped his snifter.
- Oh, thank you.
Sinful Caesar sipped his snifter,
seized his knees and sneezed.
- Marvelous.
- Wonderful.
Oh, here is a good one.
Chester chooses chestnuts,
cheddar cheese with chewy chives.
He chews them and he chooses them.
He chooses them and he chews them,
those chestnuts...
cheddar cheese and chives
in cheery, charming chunks.
- Wonderful! Do another one.
- Thank you.
Moses supposes his toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously.
Moses, he knowses
his toeses aren't roses...
as Moses supposes his toeses to be.
Moses supposes his toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously.
But Moses, he knowses
his toeses aren't roses...
as Moses supposes his toeses to be.
Moses supposes his toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously.
- A Mose is a Mose.
- A rose is a rose.
A toes is a toes.
Moses supposes his toeses are roses
But Moses supposes erroneously
For Moses, he knowses
his toeses aren't roses
As Moses supposes his toeses to be
- Moses
- He supposes his toeses are roses
- But Moses supposes erroneously
- Eenie meenie minie Moses
- He knowses his toeses aren't roses
As Moses supposes his toeses to be
A rose is a rose is a rose
is a rose is
A rose is what Moses
supposes his toes is
Couldn't be a lily
or a taffy-daffy-dilly
It's gotta be a rose
'cause it rhymes with Mose
All right, here we go.
- Quiet!
Roll 'em!
Oh, Pierre, you shouldn't...
She's gotta talk into the mike.
I can't pick it up.
Cut!
- What's the matter, Dexter?
- It's Lina.
Look, Lina, don't you remember?
I told you.
There's a microphone right there
in the bush.
- Yeah.
- You have to talk into it.
I was talking,
wasn't I, Miss Dinsmore?
Yes, my dear, but please remember:
round tones.
Pierre, you shouldn't have come.
- Yes, that's much better.
- Hold it a second!
Now, Lina, look.
Here's the mike,
right here in the bush.
- Yeah.
- Now you talk towards it.
The sound goes
through the cable to the box.
A man records it
on a big record in wax.
But you have to talk
into the mike first...
in the bush!
Now try it again.
- Gee, this is dumb.
- She'll get it, Dexter.
Lina, don't worry. We're all
a little nervous the first day.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Roscoe, you know the scene where I say,
'Imperious Princess of the night'?
I don't like those lines there.
Is it okay if I say what I always do?
'I love you, I love you, I love you'?
Sure. Any way it's comfortable.
But into the bush!
Okay, again! Quiet!
- Quiet!
- Roll 'em!
...you shouldn't have...
...flirting with danger.
...surely find you out.
Cut! Lina, we're missing
every other word.
You've got to talk into the mike!
Well, I can't make love to a bush!
All right, all right.
We'll have to think
of something else.
What are you doing?
- You're being wired for sound.
- What?
Watch out for those dentalized
D's and T's and those flat A's.
Everybody's picking on me!
Okay, Lina,
now look at this flower. See?
The mike is in there.
That's it.
Now the sound will run from it...
through this wire onto the record.
It'll catch whatever you say.
Now, let's hear how it sounds, Lina.
Okay, quiet!
- Quiet!
- Roll 'em!
Oh, Pierre, you shouldn't have come.
You're flirting with danger.
They will surely...
- What's that noise?
- The mike's picking up her heartbeat.
Swell.
Cut!
That's right.
That should do it.
Now don't forget, Lina,
the mike is on your shoulder...
and whatever you say goes
through the wire onto the record.
- Now please, Lina, talk into the mike.
- Yeah.
Don't make any quick, jerky movements
or you might disconnect it.
Okay, let's go.
Quiet.
Quiet!
Roll 'em!
Pierre, you shouldn't have come.
You're flirting with danger.
What's this wire doing here?
It's dangerous.
You two shouldn't go
into the theater together.
Lina's probably waiting
right inside the door.
- How I wish...
- Don't worry.
I'll be leading the cheering section
in the balcony. Good luck.
What's that,
the thunderstorm outside?
It's those pearls, Mr. Simpson.
I am the noblest lady of the court,
second only to the queen...
yet I am the saddest
of the mortals in France.
What is the matter, my lady?
I'm so downhearted, Theresa.
My father has me betrothed
to the Baron de Landsfield...
and I can't stand 'im.
But he is such a catch.
All the ladies of the court wish
they were in your pretty shoes.
My heart belongs to another.
Pierre de Battaille.
Ever since I met him,
I can't get 'im outta my mind.
Sounds good and loud, huh?
Oh, Pierre, you shouldn't have...
You're flirting with danger.
They will surely...
...too valuable.
She never could remember
where the microphone was, boss.
'Tis Cupid himself
that called me here, and I...
smitten by his arrow...
The night is full of our enemies.
Hey, Lina, whatcha hittin' him with,
a blackjack?
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
Did somebody get paid
for writing that dialogue?
Sounds like a comedy inside.
- It's a Lockwood-Lamont talkie.
- What?
This is terrible.
What's that?
The sound.
It's out of synchronization!
- Tell them to fix it!
- Yes, sir.
What's this?
Yvonne, captured by Rouge Noir
of the Purple Terror?
Oh! Oh, my sword!
I must fly to her side.
Yvonne, Yvonne, my own!
Pierre will save me! Pierre!
Pierre is miles away, you wench!
No, no, no!
Yes, yes, yes!
No... no... no!
This is a scream.
Give me pictures
like 'The Jazz Singer.'
I love you! I love you!
We're all ruined.
- You can't release this picture.
- We've got to.
We're booked to open in six weeks
all over the country.
But you're such big stars,
we might get by.
I never want to see
Lockwood and Lamont again.
- Wasn't that awful?
- This is the worst picture ever made.
I liked it.
Take a last look at it.
It'll be up for auction
in the morning.
You're out of your mind.
Besides, it's Saturday.
No bank's gonna foreclose
until Monday.
- It wasn't so bad.
- That's what I've been telling him.
There's no use kidding myself.
Once they release
'The Dueling Cavalier'...
Lockwood and Lamont are through.
The picture's a museum piece.
I'm a museum piece.
Things went wrong with the sound. If you
straighten out the technical end...
It wasn't that. This is sweet
of both of you, but I...
Something happened
to me tonight. I...
Everything you ever said about me
is true.
I'm no actor.
I never was.
Just a lot of dumb show.
I know that now.
Well, at least
you're taking it lying down.
No kidding. Did you ever see anything
as idiotic as me on that screen tonight?
Yeah. How about Lina?
All right.
I ran her a close second.
Maybe it was a photo finish.
Anyway, I'm through.
- You're not through!
- Of course not.
With your looks and figure, you could
drive an ice wagon or shine shoes.
- Block hats.
- Sell pencils.
- Dig ditches.
- Or go back into vaudeville.
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
I could jump over the moon up above
Fit as a fiddle
and ready for love
Too bad I didn't do that in 'Dueling
Cavalier.' They might have liked it.
- Why don't you?
- What?
- Make a musical.
- Musical?
Sure. Make a musical.
The new Don Lockwood.
He yodels. He jumps about to music.
The only trouble is that after they
release 'Dueling Cavalier'...
nobody would come to see me jump off
the Woolworth Building into a damp rag.
Why don't you turn
'The Dueling Cavalier' into a musical?
- 'Dueling Cavalier'?
- Sure.
They've got six weeks
before it's released.
Add songs and dances,
trim the bad scenes, add new ones.
And you got it.
Hey, I think it'll work.
Of course!
It may be crazy,
but we're gonna do it.
'The Dueling Cavalier'
is now a musical.
- Hot dog!
- Hallelujah!
Fellas, I feel this is
my lucky day. March 23rd.
- No, your lucky day's the 24th.
- What do you mean?
It's 1:30. It's morning.
Yes, and what a lovely mornin'.
- Good mornin'
We've talked
the whole night through
- Good mornin'
- Good mornin' to you
Good mornin', good mornin'
It's great to stay up late
Good mornin'
Good mornin' to you
When the band began to play
the stars were shining bright
Now the milkman's on his way
It's too late to say good night
So good mornin', good mornin'
Sunbeams will soon smile through
Good mornin'
Good mornin' to you
And you and you and you
Good mornin', good mornin'
We've gabbed
the whole night through
Good mornin'
Good mornin' to you
Nothin' could be grander
than to be in Louisiana
In the morning
It's great to stay up late
Good mornin'
Good mornin' to you
Might be just as zippy
if we was in Mississippi
When we left the movie show
The future wasn't bright
But came the dawn, the show goes on
and I don't wanna say good night
So say good mornin'
Good mornin'
Rainbows are shining through
- Good mornin'
- Bonjour
Monsieur
- Buenos das
- Muchas fras
Buon giorno
Guten Morgen
Good mornin' to you
- Ol!
- Toro!
Toro! Ah-ha!
Charleston!
Hey, we can't make this
a musical.
What do you mean?
She can't act, she can't sing
and she can't dance.
- A triple threat.
- Yeah.
What's so funny?
I'm sorry.
I was just thinking.
I liked her best when the sound
went off and she said...
'Yes, yes, yes!'
No, no, no!
Wait a minute.
I am just about to be brilliant.
Come here, Kathy.
Now sing. I said, 'Sing.'
- Good mornin'
- Keep your eyes on my face.
- We talked the whole night through
Good mornin'
Good mornin' to you
Watch my mouth.
Good mornin', good mornin'
It's great to stay up late
Good mornin', good mornin' to you
Well? Convincing?
Enchanting. What?
Don't you get it?
Use Kathy's voice.
Lina moves her mouth, and Kathy's voice
comes over singing and talking for her.
- That's wonderful.
- I couldn't let you do it.
- Why not?
- Because you wouldn't be seen.
- You'd be throwing away your own career.
- It has nothing to do with my career.
It's only for this one picture.
The important thing now
is to save 'The Dueling Cavalier'...
save Lockwood and Lamont.
All right, if it's only
for this one picture, but...
- Do you think it'll get by?
- Of course it will.
Sure, and it's simple
to work the numbers.
Just dance around Lina
and teach her how to take a bow.
All right, we'll spring it
on R.F. in the morning.
Don, you're a genius.
I'm glad you thought of it.
Good night, Kathy.
See you tomorrow.
Good night, Don.
Take care of that throat.
You're a big singing star now, remember?
This California dew is just
a little heavier than usual tonight.
Really?
From where I stand, the sun
is shining all over the place.
I'm singin' in the rain
Just singin' in the rain
What a glorious feelin'
I'm happy again
I'm laughin' at clouds
So dark up above
The sun's in my heart
And I'm ready for love
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I walk down the lane
With a happy refrain
Just singin'
Singin' in the rain
Dancin' in the rain
I'm happy again
I'm singin' and dancin'
in the rain
I'm dancin'
And singin'
In the rain
That's wonderful!
Now look.
We'll keep it secret until we're ready
to release, in case it doesn't come off.
But I'm worried about Lina.
She doesn't like Miss Selden.
- There might be fireworks.
- Lina won't even know she's on the lot.
Okay. Boys, this is great.
'The Dueling Cavalier' can be saved.
Now, let's see.
'The Dueling Cavalier' with music.
The title's not right.
We need a musical title. Cosmo?
'The Dueling Mammy.'
I've got it.
- 'The Dancing Cavalier.'
- That's it. 'The Dancing Cavalier.'
Cosmo, remind me to make you
a scriptwriter.
- Thanks, R.F. Have a cigar.
- Thanks.
Now what about the story?
We need modern musical numbers.
How's this? We throw
a modern section into the picture.
The hero's a young hoofer
in a Broadway show.
He sings and dances.
One night backstage, he's reading
'A Tale of Two Cities'...
and a sandbag falls
and hits him on the head...
and he dreams he's back
during the French Revolution.
This way we get in the modern
dancing numbers... Charleston.
But in the dream part,
we can still use the costume stuff.
Sensational! Cosmo,
remind me to give you a raise.
Gimme a raise.
He holds her in his arms
Would you
He tells her of her charms
They met as you and I
And they were only friends
But before
The story ends
He'll kiss her with a sigh
Would you
And if the girl were I
And would you dare to say
Let's do the same as they
I would
Would you
And would you dare to say
Let's do the same as they
I would
Would you
Perfect.
That Selden girl is great.
Once the picture is released,
I'll give her a big buildup.
- Swell!
- How much is there left to do?
- One scene and a number.
- What number?
It's new. It's for
the modern part of the picture.
It's called 'Broadway Melody.'
It's the story of a young hoofer
who comes to New York.
First, we set the stage
with a song.
It goes like this.
Don't bring a frown
to Old Broadway
Ah, you gotta clown on Broadway
Your troubles there
They're out of style
For Broadway
always wears a smile
A million lights
They flicker there
A million hearts
beat quicker there
No skies of gray
on that Great White Way
That's the Broadway
Melo-dy
Gotta dance
Shh!
Broadway rhythm
It's got me
Everybody dance
Broadway rhythm
It's got me
Everybody dance
Out on that gay White Way
In each merry cafe
Orchestras play
Takin' your breath away
Broadway rhythm, it's got me
Everybody sing and dance
That Broadway rhythm
When I hear that happy beat
Feel like dancin' down the street
That Broadway rhythm
Writhing, beating
Rhythm
Gotta dance
When I hear that happy beat
Feel like dancin' down the street
Feel like dancing down the street
Gotta dance
That's the Broadway
Melo-dy
That's the idea of the number.
What do you think of it?
I can't quite visualize it.
I'll have to see it on film first.
- On film it'll be better yet.
- Get goin', fellas.
You've got to have that Selden girl
rerecord all of Lina's dialogue.
- It's all set up.
- And remember:
Don't let Lina know about it.
All set in there?
Nothing can keep us apart.
Our love will last
'til the stars turn cold.
All right, Kathy. Go ahead.
Nothing can keep us apart.
Our love will last
'til the stars turn cold.
That's great. Perfect. Cut.
'Til the stars turn cold.
Oh, Kathy, I love you.
I can't wait
'til this picture's finished.
No more secrecy.
I'm gonna let Lina and everyone know.
Your fans will be
bitterly disappointed.
From now on, there's only one fan
I'm worrying about.
There! What did I
tell you, Lina?
Thanks, Zelda.
You're a real pal.
I want that girl
off the lot at once.
She ain't gonna be my voice.
Zelda told me everything.
- Thanks, Zelda. You're a real pal.
- Any time, Don.
- Look, Miss Lamont. Don and I...
- Don? Don't you dare call him Don!
I was calling him Don
before you were born!
I mean... I mean...
You were kissing him!
I was kissing her!
I happen to be in love with her.
That's ridiculous. Everybody knows
you're in love with me.
Look, Lina.
Try and understand this.
I'm going to marry her.
Silly boy.
She ain't the marrying kind.
She's just a flirt trying
to get ahead by using you.
I'll put a stop to that.
I'm gonna go see R.F. right now!
You're a little late.
The picture's already finished.
If she weren't in the picture,
you would be finished too.
As far as I can see,
she's the only one who's finished.
- Who will ever hear of her?
- Everybody.
Why do you think Zelda's
in such a sweat?
Because Kathy nearly stole
the picture from her.
She's doing you a favor,
helping you in 'The Dancing Cavalier.'
And she's getting
full screen credit for it too.
You mean it's gonna say up on the screen
that I don't talk and sing for myself?
Of course. What do you think?
- They can't do that.
- It's already done.
And there's a whole publicity campaign
being planned.
Publicity?
They can't make a fool
outta Lina Lamont!
They can't make a laughingstock
What do they think I am,
dumb or something?
I make more money than...
than Calvin Coolidge...
put together!
'Monumental Pictures
wildly enthusiastic...
over Lina's singing pipes
and dancing stems.'
I never said that.
'Premiere tomorrow night to reveal
Lina Lamont big musical talent.'
Boss, you can't pull a switch
like this on the publicity department.
We were all prepared on the campaign
for Kathy Selden.
Now you do this.
At least keep us informed.
I don't know anything about this.
I had nothing to do with it.
- What are we gonna do?
- Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
You wouldn't want to call the papers and
say that Lina Lamont is a big fat liar.
Lina, did you send
this stuff out?
I gave an exclusive story
to every paper in town.
You'll never get away with it.
Rod, call the papers back.
- I wouldn't do that if I were you.
- Don't tell me what to do!
What do you think I am,
dumb or something?
I had my lawyer
go over my contract.
And I control my publicity,
not you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
The studio's responsible for every word
printed about me.
If I don't like it, I can sue.
What?
I can sue.
If you tell the papers
about Kathy Selden...
it would be 'detrimental
and deleterious' to my career.
I could sue you for the whole studio.
- That's a lot of nonsense.
- Says so right here.
Contract dated June 8, 1925...
paragraph 34,
subdivision letter 'A':
'The party of the first part'...
That's me.
You win, Lina.
Take Kathy Selden's
credit off the screen.
Go ahead. Let's just get
this premiere over with.
Satisfied?
Just one little thing more.
You want me to change
the name of the studio...
to Lamont Pictures Incorporated?
Oh, R.F., you're cute.
I was just thinking...
you've given this little girl
a part in Zelda's picture...
and you're gonna give her
an even bigger one in the next?
- So what?
- So, if she's done such a grand job...
doubling for my voice, don't you think
she oughta go on doing just that...
and nothing else?
You're crazy.
I'm still more important
to the studio than she is.
I wouldn't do that to her
in a million years.
You'd be taking her career away from
her. People don't do things like that.
People?
I ain't people.
I'm a...
'A shimmering, glowing star...
in the cinema firmament.'
It says so. Right there.
Oh, Pierre.
Pierre, my darling.
At last I've found you.
Oh, Pierre.
Pierre, you're hurt.
Oh, speak to me.
I'll kiss her with a sigh
Would you, would you
And if the girl were I
Oh, Pierre, hold me
in your arms always.
Lockwood's a sensation.
Yes, but Lamont. What a voice!
Isn't she marvelous!
- It's going over wonderfully, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Our love will last
'til the stars turn cold.
And would you dare to say
Let's do the same as they
I would
Would you
- R.F., it's a real smash.
- Congratulations, kids.
- We owe you a lot.
- Thanks, Mr. Simpson.
- Kathy, we made it!
- Don, it's a miracle!
It's just great, Don.
Lina, you were fabulous.
You sang as well as Kathy.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
for a long time.
- What do you mean by that?
- She's gonna go right on singing for me.
Listen, Lina.
I thought something was cooking
beneath those bleached curls of yours.
Now get this!
Kathy has a career of her own.
She only did this
for the one picture.
That's what you think.
Come on!
Lina's getting carried away,
isn't she, boss?
- Yes, she is.
- Listen, you boa constrictor.
Don't get any fancy ideas
about the future. Tell her.
Never mind! Listen to that applause, and
wait 'til the money starts rolling in.
You won't give all that up because
some nobody don't wanna be my voice.
She's got something there.
It's a gold mine.
Part of that choice is mine,
and I just won't do it.
You got a five-year contract.
You'll do what R.F. says.
Why don't you tell her off?
I'm confused.
This thing is so big...
- They're tearing the house apart.
- Take a curtain call.
I once gave you a cigar.
Can I have it back?
- Wait a minute...
- Listen to 'em! I'm an avalanche!
Selden, you're stuck!
If this happens, you'll get yourself
a new boy. I won't stand for it!
Who needs you? They'd come to see me
if I played opposite a monkey!
Just a minute. Don's a smash too.
I'm still running the studio!
I'm not so sure!
You're the big Mr. Producer,
always running things, running me.
From now on, as far
as I'm concerned, I'm running things.
Lina Lamont Pictures Incorporated, huh?
- Yeah.
- You've gone too far.
- Don, they're yelling for a speech.
- A speech.
Yeah, everybody's always
making speeches for me.
Tonight I'm gonna do
my own talking.
I'm gonna make the speech!
- You can't do that!
- Wait a minute, Rod.
This is Lina's big night,
and she's entitled to do the talking.
- Right?
- Right.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I can't tell you how thrilled we are
at your reception...
for 'The Dancing Cavalier,'
our first musical picture together.
If we bring a little joy
into your humdrum lives...
it makes us feel as though our hard work
ain't been in vain for nothin'.
Bless you all!
She didn't sound that way
in the picture.
Cut the talk, Lina. Sing!
I got an idea.
What am I gonna do?
We've got it. Rod, set up
a microphone back of that curtain.
Kathy, come here. Kathy will
stand back there and sing for you.
She'll be back of the curtain singing,
and I'll be out in front doing...
like in the picture?
- That's right.
- What?
You gotta do it.
This thing is too big.
Of course she's got to do it.
She's got a contract.
- Get over to that microphone.
- You heard him. Do it!
I'll do it, Don...
but I never want to see you again,
on or off the screen.
Come on, Lina.
What are you going to sing,
Miss Lamont?
'Singing In The Rain.'
In what key?
'A' flat.
In 'A' flat.
I'm singin' in the rain
Just singin' in the rain
What a glorious feelin'
I'm happy again
I'm laughin' at clouds
So dark up above
The sun's in my heart
and I'm ready for love
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I'll walk down the lane
With a happy refrain
I'm singin'
Just singin' in the rain
I'm singin' in the rain
What a glorious feelin'
I'm happy again
I'm laughin' at clouds
So dark up above
The sun's in my heart
and I'm ready for love
Let the stormy clouds chase...
Ladies and gentlemen,
stop that girl running up the aisle!
That's the girl whose voice
you heard and loved tonight!
She's the real star
of the picture. Kathy Selden!
You are
My lucky star
I saw you
From afar
Two lovely eyes
At me they were gleaming
Beaming
I was starstruck
You're all
My lucky charms
I'm lucky
In your arms
You've opened heaven's portal
Here on Earth
for this poor mortal
You are
My lucky
Star