Tell your client that Reata is my property.
And the name of Reata is my property.
The Texas courts are fair.
He is to cease using the name of my ranch
in his oil schemes.
I won't have oil digging on Reata.
I won't stand for its name being used.
Is that clear?
[Dynamic instrumental music]
Mom?
Mother?
[Mellow band music]
They say Aunt Luz was really in love
with Jett Rink herself.
Even if she was old enough
to be his mother.
Now, Luz....
She was a character.
She was always trying to keep him
from getting married.
He had to run off to marry you.
What's that?
Who said what?
Somebody. I forget.
You know what they say?
That every girl in Texas was trying
to catch Papa.
They said, quote:
"There wasn't a prize bull like him
since Sam Houston got married."
That's enough from her.
I'm sure it's quite true, darling.
It took me two whole days to land him.
Really? It all sounds so fascinating
and uncouth.
Where are you going?
Down the road to Smitty's for Coke.
BICK: With who?
Nobody.
Stay at home.
Hey, you!
Hello, Papa.
Hi.
Where have you been?
Down the road for a Coke.
With who?
Bob.
BOB: Howdy, Mr. Benedict.
BICK: Hello, Bob.
Well, good night, Mr. Benedict.
Excuse me, Papa.
JUDY: Look, Papa, are you busy now?
Never too busy for you, young fellow.
BICK: What's on your mind?
Well, Daddy, it's like this.
JORDAN: I am, Mama. I'm going to be.
I want to go to Harvard
and then to Columbia premed.
So you want to be a doctor?
Yes.
How about Reata, Jordy?
He's counting on you to take over.
Yes, I know he is. I know it.
But there are 50,000 guys who can do it
better than I can.
I don't want to live my life
pushing cows around.
I'd die for Papa if I had to.
Your father doesn't want you to die
for him. He wants you to live for him.
Talk to her, will you, Daddy?
Reason with her.
I don't want this pinned on me.
I'll take all the blame.
You just sort of soften the blow a little bit.
I'll talk to him myself.
You can persuade him, Mom.
I know you can.
It's not gonna be easy, honey.
Maybe I can catch her at a weak moment.
You can do it, Daddy. I know you can.
LESLIE: Darling, I've been thinking....
Me, too.
LESLIE: About the children.
That's funny. Me, too.
We must be getting old.
LESLIE: Speak for yourself.
I wonder if we love them enough
to do what's really right for them.
Why, sure.
I hope so.
LESLIE: I mean...
so we love them too much perhaps.
So much that we keep from doing
what's right for them.
Not me.
You don't have to worry about me.
It's always the mother.
The theory is she doesn't want
her fledglings to leave her nest.
Try their own wings. All that sort of stuff.
You mean...
you'd be perfectly willing to sacrifice?
Yeah.
I'd sacrifice for her. You know that.
I'm not so sold on that...
girl's school in Switzerland you're stuck on.
Now, don't get your feathers up.
Judy's not crazy about that school either.
Of course she isn't.
That's exactly why she needs to go.
I wouldn't push her.
She...
wants to go to Texas Tech.
That's a man's school.
Girls go, too.
It's got the best animal husbandry course
in the country, she says.
She wants to be a rancher,
like her old man.
Like Bob Dace.
She's just got her little schoolgirl crush
on that hulking Bob Dace.
She's got her mind set on it.
That's what she wants.
And I, for one, am willing to sacrifice.
What do you say?
It seems we've hatched
an odd pair of fledglings.
Brace yourself.
Jordy wants to be a doctor.
He wants what?
LESLIE: He wants to be a doctor.
He's set on it.
Over my dead body!
You know what he's supposed to do.
LESLIE: Well, he's not.
He'd die for you, but he's not gonna
live his life for you. And he's right.
He'll do as we've all done.
He wants to go to Harvard first,
then Columbia premed.
You're pretty handy with those terms.
I can see who's been cooking this thing up.
Of course...
this would mean a big sacrifice
on your part.
BICK: No matter where he goes to school...
he comes right back home and runs Reata.
LESLIE: I guess you were right
about one thing.
BICK: Me?
LESLIE: On one thing.
We are getting old.
BICK: Who?
LESLIE: We are, Jordan.
We are the older generation.
Aren't we?
Suddenly?
BICK: I guess so.
"...unless oil or gas shall have been struck
at a lesser depth."
JETT: Is that about Vashti Hake's ranch?
Yes.
Good.
How about Reata?
No. That Benedict is a hard guy to crack.
Let's just keep punching, boys.
[lndustrious instrumental music]
BAWLEY: Hospital!
What's he covering up now?
He'll overstep the mark one of these days.
Give him enough rope.
Give him enough rope, and he'll hang you.
[Phone rings]
I'll get it.
Hello.
No, this is her daughter.
You'll have to find out for yourself.
Take your social life on the other phone.
LUZ II: It's for you.
I think he's nice.
BICK: Who's nice?
LUZ II: Jett Rink.
I don't want to talk to him.
What do I tell him?
Let me talk. I'll tell him.
I'll talk to him.
You've heard from me before on this, Jett.
Judge Whiteside told you, and I told you.
This is a cattle ranch, not an oil field.
That's the way it's gonna stay.
BAWLEY: That's the most expensive
phone call you ever made, Bick.
It'll cost you a billion dollars a year
for the next 50 years.
Couldn't we have just one little, itty-bitty
oil well, so I can get a private phone?
[Clock chimes]
[Romantic jazz music]
REPORTER: [Over radio]
After reporting to the President...
the Naval Secretary told the press...
that the battleship Arizona
and five other warships were lost...
in the Japanese air raid
on Pearl Harbor a fortnight ago.
He reported that 91 officers...
and 2,638 enlisted men were known dead.
That only makes me realize I'm losing you.
[Seductive jazz music]
[Singing Christmas carol]
Here they are.
LUZ II: When did you two sneak in?
The honeymooners!
Judy, you're gonna get it.
You know Mom wanted a big wedding.
That's not true, Luz.
Not quite true.
[Lighthearted instrumental music]
POLO: We came for you to see ngel.
He's the first soldier from Reata.
BICK: Merry Christmas, Polo.
VASHTI: Merry Christmas.
Isn't he a fine-looking soldier?
Just a minute.
Merry Christmas, ngel.
NGEL: Thank you.
Today the wish of all of us is
that the war ends quickly...
and that you, ngel,
return safely to Reata...
and to all of those who love you very much.
BAWLEY: I'll drink a toast to that.
Come on, now, and open it.
-Hello, Dr. Guerra.
-Hello, Dr. Benedict.
Just a little premature.
I know, it takes time.
Jordan, this is Juana.
She's been training out at the hospital.
It must be that darn north wind static.
DR. GUERRA: Haven't you learned that
dry wind, friction, and a heavy carpet...
are not the only means of creating
electricity between human beings.
[Excited indistinct chatter]
Thank you.
Could you stay and give me the lowdown
on what it's like?
-Very nice to meet you.
-Nice meeting you.
-Goodbye.
-Adis.
-Let's get some Christmas cheer.
-You talked me into it!
Friends, we're gonna have
a mighty triumphant Christmas.
I'm gonna drink a toast
to two young men of Reata.
My two sons.
Thank you, Mr. Benedict.
Better take it easy on the bourbon, Dad.
It's not good for you.
I'm not kidding you.
I hate to see ngel go.
BICK: That boy is the best dang man
on the place.
It's time for you to take your place here,
to produce beef for the war.
They need doctors, Dad.
They need doctors in war, too.
I want to finish medical school if I can.
You are being bull-headed.
I never would be any good
at running this place.
Any man on Reata can do it better.
You're the one.
You're the one with a responsibility
to Reata.
Your blood pressure is going up
just while we're talking here.
Please, it isn't good for you. Just relax.
Don't you get fresh with me.
We're talking.
Yes, I heard.
It's Christmas morning. Isn't this
something you could discuss tomorrow?
There's nothing to discuss.
When I come home,
I'll work with Dr. Guerra in Vientecito.
I love Texas as much as you do.
I want to work here.
I just want to work in a different way,
that's all.
LESLIE: Come on, Jordan.
BICK: Work with Guerra!
Here's to you, Mr. Benedict.
You look beat, Mr. Benedict.
Here's to you.
It's pretty good stuff.
Did you make that yourself?.
Yes, I make it every year.
It's my Christmas special.
BOB: No, I mean the liquor.
Did you make the liquor yourself?.
If not, it's about the only thing
you don't produce on Reata yourself.
Come here and sit down.
I've got some serious talk
to make with you.
I've been watching you pretty close
for a lot of years.
You're a ranchman.
And you're smart.
You're wondering why I'm talking to you.
Bob Dace...
look me right in the eye.
You could never be anything but a rancher,
could you?
-No, sir.
-That's my boy.
But somebody else thinks I could.
Not my Judy.
-No, sir, it's not Judy.
-Who?
President Roosevelt.
Listen to this:
"To Robert Haskell Dace.
"Greetings from the President
of the United States."
Let me see that.
"You are hereby notified to report
on December 28...
"5:00 a.m. for induction."
BICK: It don't matter.
Your job won't let you leave this place.
It'll make you stay right here.
This is just as important as carrying a gun.
I appreciate your confidence, sir.
But this is one thing
I'm not gonna try to get out of.
Have it your way. You might as well...
everybody else does around here.
I'll show you my heart's in the right place.
When you come back
after the war is over...
the job's yours.
It'll be waiting for you.
I couldn't take it, sir.
Papa, Bob and I have plans.
We want a place, just our own.
BICK: You crazy kids, you!
Can you imagine you'll ever have
anything like this? Like Reata?
Gosh, no, sir. We just want a little place.
Just a little place that'll allow us time
for experimentation and progress.
See, sir, big stuff is old stuff now.
Big stuff is old stuff?.
Bob didn't mean to upset you.
He just wants to be honest, that's all.
We just want something little
that's our own. That's all.
Just ours.
You see, Dad?
Yeah, honey, I see.
See you, Daddy.
BICK: Keeping it together all my life
for them!
I battled mesquite, dust, and the wind...
to keep it this big.
And for who?
I might just as well give it back
to the dirty Comanches!
LUZ II: That's the Christmas spirit.
Give it all back to the poor old lndians.
LUZ II: Don't tell me, I know.
You're Jett Rink.
You're Judy.
LUZ II: No, I'm Luz.
That I am.
Come on in.
LUZ II: Dad's over at the bar.
Feel free, it's Christmas.
Everybody gets one.
Christmas?
I thought that was next week.
Somebody ought to have told me.
Christmas greetings
from Mr. Jetexas himself.
Sit down.
I guess Christmas is as good a day as any
to talk business.
Run along, Luz.
We've got business to talk about.
'Bye, now.
'Bye, Mr. Rink.
Everybody calls me Jett, honey.
Bye-bye.
What's on your mind?
JETT: The country needs petroleum.
I'm going to Washington, Bick.
The reason I'm going
and the reason I'm here is oil.
I figured.
You want to talk a little business?
I'm ready.
It seems that every time we made a deal,
me and you...
it just turned out pretty lucky...
for somebody.
[Exciting instrumental music]
All this oil around here hasn't made
a lot of difference.
We live pretty much like we always have
here in Reata.
BAWLEY: Just like we Benedicts found it.
The Lord was good to you, to set
the swimming pool in your own front yard.
Hey, come on in.
BICK: Not now, Luz.
It's good for the young folks.
We'd have made improvements
around here, oil or no oil.
But that 27.5 percent tax exemption
on oil helped, didn't it?
Bale, I'll tell you what old Pinky thinks.
What?
That oil tax exemption is the best thing
to hit Texas since we whooped Geronimo.
One of the finest laws ever passed
in Washington.
And all joking aside, Bick...
we're not adverse to accepting
a share of the credit for it.
Not at all.
How about an exemption for depreciation
of first-class brains, Senator?
WHITESIDE: Whose? Yours?
My father's, for instance. He spent his life
saving other people's lives.
How about some tax exemption there?
Leslie has always been a real sharp talker,
ain't she?
Fair enough, Judge. You've always been
smooth enough for two.
PRIEST: "Do you take each other
for better or for worse...
"for richer or for poorer...
"in sickness and in health, until death?
"Jordan Benedict, wilt thou take...
"Juana Villalobos here present...
"for your lawful wife, according to
the rite of our Holy Mother the Church?"
I will.
PRIEST: "Juana Villalobos, wilt thou take...
"Jordan Benedict here present...
"for your lawful husband, according to
the rite of our Holy Mother the Church?"
I will.
PRIEST: Join your hands and kneel down.
[Lively band music]
[Square-dancing music]
What did they say?
Friends and neighbors...
I want you all to meet my wife.
Mrs. Jordan Benedict III.
Congratulations!
He was the first Reata baby I ever saw.
I remember it as if it were yesterday.
He had a fever.
I didn't think he was going
to live the day out.
[Priest reciting funeral rites in Spanish]
[Train whistle blows]
On behalf of the U.S. Army, I am proud
to present to you the flag of our nation...
which your son defended so gallantly.
[Trumpet playing taps]
[Gunshot]
[Choir singing the National Anthem]
LUZ II: Everyone in the world's
gonna be there.
I'm gonna fly up to Dallas,
and I'm going to Neiman's.
I'll buy myself
a starlight-white evening dress.
Very plain and simple and deadly.
Before you get so elaborate and simple...
you'd better hear
what your father has to say.
We're certainly going. I promised Jett.
Jett! What are you talking about?
He likes me. He likes my family, too.
He's always talking about you.
My dear, darling Luz...
if I didn't know you had a level Benedict
head on those immature shoulders...
I'd prescribe a good spanking.
He's dreamy. Ask the Snythe girls.
Ask anyone.
He's just a rough diamond.
He's a rough rhinestone.
He's old enough to be your father.
What are you six evil men up to now?
BAWLEY: Honey, it's a coronation.
Jett plans to get himself crowned king.
You got to have $10 million
to be on the guest list.
The most important people
in the country will be there.
Coast-to-coast broadcast.
Jett's gonna make a magnificent speech.
I know.
I'm going to write it for him.
lt'll be heard across the nation
by everyone.
Eliminating one. That's me.
If you people stay away, Leslie, you'll be
the only folks in Texas who ain't there.
You'll be roped in with the herd.
You'll be putting on your pink shoes and
dancing to Jett's fiddles like the rest of us.
If we go then we'll do it right.
We're oil rich, like the rest of them.
We'll go like the rest of them! Only better.
Now you're talking like my father.
BICK: The old Benedict spirit.
You set up one of your great weekends.
lnvite everybody.
We'll take them all with us.
We'll show that so-and-so
who's top people around here.
I'll even buy the four-engine Douglas.
Fly in some orchids from Hawaii.
We'll fly in low and shake the tiles
off that hotel roof.
[Bick mimicking a plane engine]
[Plane engine roaring]
There's Lola Lane!
I bet even Hollywood isn't this exciting.
-Isn't this something?
-It's perfectly fabulous!
Jett always tries to do things
in a bigger way...
and spend more money than anybody else.
Really? What does he do?
BAWLEY: To some folks, he's
a no-good wildcatting so-and-so.
[Drum roll of marching band]
[Marching band plays lively song]
There he is.
[Crowd cheering]
There's the emperor himself.
Isn't this terrific?
Look at Luz, she's queen of the parade.
You didn't tell me.
Did you know about this, Leslie?
No, I didn't.
My daughter, queen of Jett Rink Day!
What is this?
I don't know, Jordan.
BICK: She's done things before
I haven't agreed with, but this....
She's never been sneaky.
It's not exactly sneaky,
appearing in a parade.
BICK: Don't try to be funny.
LESLIE: I'm not.
I'm just as upset as you are.
But Luz is intelligent enough
not to be imposed on by him or anyone.
Give me the desk.
It's Bick Benedict.
Did my daughter Luz Benedict come in yet?
Get this. As soon as she comes in,
have her call me.
[Languid instrumental music]
You know what I think I'll do?
I'm going to keep it just like this.
I'll keep all those people, send them home.
I'm not even gonna open up this place.
Some girls might like a hotel
all to themselves.
Me, I like company, Jett.
I like lots of people.
All right.
You want lots of people?
I don't see any problem there.
If there's anything you want,
just say it, and you've got it.
All right, I'd like a Coke.
No, that's impossible.
That's just impossible.
You know as well as I do, Cokes are taboo.
All soft drinks.
You make the rules.
You like things your own way, don't you?
Let me ask you something.
Do you like things your way?
Not many people have things their way.
No, I don't get them my way very often.
And you won't either,
until you get married...
and get your man
to give you what you want.
So?
So if I was you,
I'd start thinking about getting married.
You know, that's an idea.
You looked like a queen
in that parade today.
That was my job.
It's just what you are.
Luz Benedict ll.
You could be the head lady
of this part of the whole country...
if you wanted to.
If you married the right man.
That's a sweet idea.
Why don't I just announce it tonight...
with all them thousands
of people listening?
The whole of Texas.
Wouldn't that blow the roof off?.
Jett, tell me something.
Is this a proposal?
Does it sound like one?
After a fashion, but not quite.
You want me to say something
you can laugh at?
No.
I just think you're a wonderful girl.
And I do think you're beautiful.
You're fascinating to me.
I've always been looking for...
a girl like you.
Sure would blow the roof off, wouldn't it?
You've got a long way to go tonight.
I'm very flattered. Any girl would be.
You be a good boy now.
I'll see you later.
[Wind howling]
CLERK: I hope this storm
doesn't louse up your party.
JETT: A slip-up, boy. I just forgot
to order the right kind of weather!
CLERK: I heard a twister hit Waco.
[Guard speaks Spanish]
[Juana responds in Spanish]
What's wrong with you?
Can't you talk United States?
You're talking to my wife.
I'm Jordan Benedict,
if that means anything to you.
I'm just following orders.
Mr. Rink said he'd have my neck
if I let any of the wrong people in.
You Benedicts are all close together.
They've got the Coronado suite.
You're in the Filando suite.
I'm a mess. I must go to the beauty parlor.
Hurry before they close.
ANNOUNCER: [Over radio]
Grand opening of the Jett Rink Airport...
and Emperador Hotel...
is the latest milestone in the dramatic
life of this virile son of Texas.
Howdy, everybody!
ADARENE: It's time you arrived.
VASHTI: Where are the boys?
Where's Pinky, the old bat?
Filando suite for Mr. Benedict, please.
HAIRDRESSER:
Beauty salon.
Can you take me?
HAIRDRESSER:
Yes, if you can come right along.
Thank goodness. I'll be right in.
HAIRDRESSER: Who's calling?
JUANA: Mrs. Benedict.
HAlRDRESSER:
Come on along, Mrs. Benedict.
Thank you.
Keep everybody freshened up, will you?
We'll be quick.
We're anxious to see old Jett come out
in that suit.
Why couldn't they ride with us
like other people's kids do?
Luz had to fly her own plane
and Jordy and Juana had to drive.
JUANA: Is anybody here?
We're all booked up.
JUANA: I just called. I'm Mrs. Benedict.
I'm sorry, but we're busy.
I'll wait a little.
LESLIE: They're driving. It takes time.
BICK: I know it takes time.
I made the trip myself 400 times.
But don't worry about the children.
Their behavior is odd,
but their manners are beautiful.
LESLIE: Listen here, boy!
I've taken enough from you!
I didn't want to come here!
I wouldn't be here unless you let them
bully you into it.
Now, for heaven's sake,
let's make the best of it.
Cool down, go on with your shaving, finish
dressing, and I'll go downstairs with you!
Otherwise, you can go alone!
You know, honey...
you're awful cute when you get riled.
Hurry on in there.
Your ma and pa are sure having a battle.
Hello, honey.
Where have you been?
We got tied up in traffic.
LESLIE: Where's Juana?
She's in the beauty parlor.
LESLIE: Hello, sweetheart.
JORDAN: He's all right.
He just didn't get his nap.
[Baby crying]
BOB: How's my child?
JUDY: Is that Judy crying?
CUSTOMER: I hope I'm not too late.
No. Come right in.
Yeah?
Hello, Juana.
Yeah, he's here. Jordy, it's for you.
Yes, dear?
Stay right there, honey.
I'm coming right down.
Don't you folks wait on us, we'll catch up.
Son, you're way behind.
Howdy, everybody, look what we found.
There you are.
We were getting worried.
You'd better get dressed, Jett.
You wanted me to go over
the speech with you, too.
Come on, we'd better hurry.
I'm sorry, but it happens to be
Mr. Jett Rink's orders, himself.
I'm just working here.
Everybody's orders. Same all over town.
The young lady should have gone
to a place where they do her people.
BAWLEY: If it isn't the queen herself!
-Are you having fun?
-We're making out.
-How are you doing?
-Good.
Where are Mom and Dad?
Don't trifle with your luck.
There you are.
You wanted to talk to me, Dad?
If you can spare me a moment,
I'd like to talk to you, young lady.
LUZ II: Dad, must we now?
Jordan, we must hurry to be in time
for the grand entrance.
Luz, darling, you look just beautiful!
Help me round everybody up.
I'm sorry I'm so late.
All right, people....
[Resounding clap of thunder]
Did some of you boys change this around?
We haven't changed a single comma.
Changes tend to throw you.
"Columbus discovered only the shell
of this country. Agassiz came...."
Where's Rink?
He went thataway.
[Crowd hooting]
Looks like I just come in for a root beer.
That, my friend, is a Texas range.
VASHTI: What're you doing
sitting up there?
"You've heard of Paul Revere?"
The Texan said, "Paul Revere?
"Oh, yes. Ain't he the fellow
that had to ride for help?"
[Hooting and applause]
MC: In just a few moments,
Mr. Rink himself...
will be here at the microphone.
Come on, let's go.
Jordy is looking for Jett Rink.
What?
Where we had our hair done. Jordy wants
to fight Jett because it was his orders.
On account of Juana. The girl said
they didn't take wetbacks.
[Band plays lively song]
[Crowd sings along with band]
Stay here, honey, I'll be right back.
You invited me here to insult my wife.
You're gonna answer for it!
Ain't you the one who married the squaw?
What's the matter, boy?
Not having a good time?
Get them up, Rink! Everybody knows
you got this coming to you!
Jordy, no!
You want it in front of everybody,
or you want to come outside?
I don't care much whether it's here
or outside...
so long as I get one punch
at that stuck-up face of yours.
Sit down.
Governor.
How are you this evening?
MC: And now, to introduce our guest
of honor, we hear from a man...
known from the rocky coast of Maine
to the Golden Gate in California.
Ladies and gentlemen, our own...
Senator Oliver Whiteside.
[Audience applauds]
[Begins his speech]
[Cat squeals]
BICK: Get them up.
You had this coming to you for a long time.
You'll get what you gave my boy.
Get them up.
Get them up!
WHITESIDE:
...proud, friendly...
warm-hearted, successful.
Yes, successful I am sure....
You ain't even worth hitting.
You want to know something true?
You're all through.
WHITESIDE:
I'm going to ask you
to come with me tonight...
as I turn back the pages
in my book of happy memories...
and I recall the first time
I saw young Jett Rink.
BICK: Where's the boy?
LESLIE: Juana took him upstairs.
Let's get out of here.
LESLIE: I'll go get Luz.
Come on, Luz. We're leaving.
Excuse me, please.
WHITESIDE:
The years passed quickly...
as the years have a way of doing.
And now I see Jett Rink...
[Bottle breaks]
afraid of neither opposition nor hard work...
his eyes set on the far distant...
goal toward which he's ever working...
planning, striving.
And now we come to Jett Rink, the man.
Texas has been kind to Jett Rink.
And Jett, never forgetting this kindness...
is ever ready to devote his resources...
to the greater glory of the state
which reared him...
which, in turn, does honor to him tonight...
in this great gathering here present.
And now, my friends, here...
and to the thousands of you
listening across the nation...
I have the privilege, yes...
I have the great honor to introduce
a legend in his own time...
a great Texan...
an outstanding American!
Yes, my friends, a man!
I give to you Jett Rink!
[Band plays lively song]
JORDAN: You can count on me.
All right, goodbye.
How bad?
It hit pretty hard in Vientecito.
Dr. Guerra set up an auxiliary hospital.
He needs help. I've got to go there.
You'll make better time
if you wait till first light and fly.
I hate to spend the night under Jett's roof.
Me, too. If we weren't transporting
a circus, we'd all hightail it out of here.
[Juana singing a lullaby]
I hope she doesn't let this
upset her too much.
This business tonight...
it's just one of those things.
The best thing to do is forget about it.
Go ahead and forget it.
Me, I'm going to remember it!
Now look, Jordy.
Take it easy.
We've had just about enough excitement
around here for one night.
Yeah, I guess so.
You've always had a mind of your own
and used it.
You've done things your own way.
You knew what you were doing
when you married in that direction.
I told you myself the morning
after you broke the news, remember?
I told you then that I knew
Juana was a mighty fine little gal...
but that marrying her was asking
for trouble. Remember?
I told you that.
Lots of folks in these parts
get pretty jumpy about that sort of thing.
Jett's only one of them.
I know those people. We've run
into this before. We're doing fine.
I'm concerned it has to do with the people
that ought to know better.
Like my own father.
Just the simple truth. That's you.
That's the way you think.
I don't care about Jett Rink,
but you, Papa, that's different.
Now you look here, Jordy!
You can't talk to me like that.
No man can!
I'm a fair man. I've been fair all my life,
with everybody!
And you, my own son,
can't tell me that I'm not a fair man!
Look, Jordy...
there's ways of living,
and there's ways of doing things...
that folks abide by when they want
to live right and happily...
in the comfort of their own people.
I always say that Juana is
a mighty fine gal, but--
Don't sit there and prove what I say!
I don't like to hear it!
You're not being fair!
When that ruckus started,
who went after Rink?
Your old man.
-Who took him to account? Your old man.
-And why?
Because of my wife?
-Yes!
-No!
Because your son, Jordan Benedict...
descendant of the long, proud line
of Reata...
got knocked flat on his back
in front of all of Texas. That's why!
Forget it. Don't worry yourself about it.
Mom, you made a mistake when you got
yourself mixed up with us rowdy Texans.
LUZ II: I'm shocked at you! I'm shocked
at all of us! I'm just so ashamed!
I'll never forget the sight of my brother
barging into the grand ballroom...
with all of our friends, disgracing us!
Then my father made it a bigger brawl!
How can I face people again?
JORDAN: Keep seeing Jett and
you won't have to face me.
LESLIE: Children!
How about that anyway, Mom?
LESLIE: I haven't been asked.
It seems that my family
just can't tolerate his success.
My darling, Luz.
LUZ II: Tonight meant a lot to Jett.
Really. I know.
If I only knew how to apologize to him,
I'd go to him now.
But I can't face all those people.
The party is over. They've all gone home.
He passed out like a light
in front of the whole crowd.
Oh, no!
That's what we heard, Luz.
He must have been ill.
Weak with shame or something.
He was plain drunk, if you'll forgive me.
I don't believe you.
The party broke up early,
but not a minute too soon.
Give me Mr. Rink's penthouse, please.
You're not going up there,
even if I have to sit on you!
It's important. Do you know where he is?
Luz, it's not like you
to make a fool of yourself.
I know where he is, honey.
Come along with Uncle Bawley.
LESLIE: All right, Luz. If you must go.
I must.
I've always held a strange power
over your mother.
I'm sorry, Mother.
What do you say, doll face?
About ready to come along with me?
It's time we hit the hay.
[Jett drunkenly babbles]
I give up.
Can we go to work now?
Leave him alone.
He owns the place, let him enjoy it.
JETT: Shut up.
Shut up!
Ladies and gentlemen
and distinguished guests.
I just want to count the blessings...
that this great domain
has bestowed upon her humble son.
My friends...
this is a man.
Old Mother Texas!
What did she give to me?
Not a goddamn thing.
You've got to work and sweat
and steal it from her.
But I got mine right out of the ground.
Poor Jett...
fighting for what's good.
Flunky!
Flunky for Bick Benedict...
her husband.
Poor Jett!
Poor pretty Leslie!
Pretty Leslie....
Pretty Leslie.
Wonderful, beautiful girl bride!
Poor boy.
Rich....
Rich Mrs. Benedict.
She's beautiful.
Lovely.
The woman a man wants.
A woman a man has got to have, too!
[Melancholy instrumental music]
LUZ II: Thank you, Uncle Bawley.
Governor...
you know what you can do?
[Family singing to popular 1940s song]
[Bick honks horn]
As soon as it lands, I'll sell it.
Good.
This is for me, boy.
The simple life.
No more of this highflying nonsense.
[Honks horn]
Juana, how does a hamburger
and a piece of pie sound to you?
Sounds very good.
No more of this highfalutin stuff.
Let's stop at this drive-in
and have us some chicken.
Then we can eat it with our fingers.
[Military band song]
Nice place you have here. I've been
intending to stop every time I drove by.
Thank you.
What do you recommend?
How is the fried chicken?
Little Jordy wants ice cream, Grandpa.
Grandpa?
Ice cream it shall be.
Give the little fellow some ice cream.
SARGE: Ice cream?
I thought that kid would want a tamale.
Give them what they want.
What do you say? Is this all right?
It's good.
BICK: After all that fancy food
and high living.
This is the life.
SARGE: Hey, you.
The plane should arrive in Benedict
around 1:30.
You're in the wrong place.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Your money is no good here.
Come on, let's go.
You, too.
BICK: Hold on a minute.
SARGE: Yes, what do you want?
Look here, Sarge. I'd sure appreciate it
if you were more polite to these people.
SARGE: You would, eh?
I'm Bick Benedict.
Your neighbor, you might say.
SARGE: Does that give you
special privileges?
The name Benedict's meant something
to people around here for a long time.
That there papoose down there...
is his name Benedict, too?
Yes. Come to think of it, it is.
SARGE: Forget I asked you.
Go sit down,
and we ain't gonna have no trouble.
But this bunch's gonna eat
somewhere else.
All right, come on. Let's go.
Come on, you, too.
You're out of line, mister.
[Sound of punches being struck]
[Military band song starts again]
[Organ music playing]
Is that the best that old horse thief can do?
He's feeling your mood, darling.
There's a lot of
Clair de Lune
in both of you old fire-eaters.
You're both rather gentle creatures.
How awful!
Those kids....
Look at them.
Those kids, in their infinite wisdom,
are smarter than we are.
They know I'm a disgrace.
And they don't hesitate to say so.
[Mooing]
Even the calf's got my number.
[Baaing]
I don't have to take it from a sheep!
LESLIE: Now, Jordan!
[Telephone rings]
Hello, Vashti. We're all fine.
How'd you make it back?
-They all made it back in one piece.
-Jolly.
Yes, all our guests have finally gone.
Thank goodness!
But more have left than we bargained for.
Luz has gone on to Hollywood with Lola,
whatever the name was.
She decided she would like to see
how she liked Hollywood.
We never had one in the family.
Good Lord, an actress!
All you can do is raise them.
You can't live their lives for them.
Judy and Bob are out looking at a ranch.
A small one.
Jordy and Juana are gonna move
into Vientecito.
And we, we're home minding the babies.
BAWLEY: The sun's going down.
When are you going to open up the bar?
Anytime. Go ahead.
Remember, one of these days
that bourbon's gonna kill you.
Okay. lt'll be me or it.
One of us has got to go.
I'm going to stay right here.
It's coming onto spring.
Roundup time is no time
to be away from Reata.
BICK: Honey, everybody's on the move.
The strays are leaving the herd.
I wouldn't mind it too much if you wanted
to pack up and go back home for a spell.
Home?
Where do you think I've been
this last breathless quarter of a century?
Home.
Look, boy, I belong here!
You really want to know
what's gotten my goat?
My own grandson doesn't even look
like one of us.
He really looks like a little wetback.
Little muchacho fires up, don't he?
I'm sorry, Jordan Benedict IV.
There's times when a man
just has to be honest.
You know something, Leslie?
There's no use kidding.
I'm a failure.
Nothing has turned out like I had planned.
I just feel like my saddle's turning
right out from under me.
Do you want to know something?
I think you're great!
Don't ask me why.
Some things are difficult to explain.
You know all that fine riding
you used to do, and all that fancy roping...
and all that glamour stuff
you did to dazzle me?
It was impressive.
But none of it ever made you
quite as big a man to me...
as you were on the floor
of Sarge's hamburger joint.
When you tumbled rearward...
and landed crashing
into that pile of dirty dishes...
you were at last my hero.
That's what you always wanted to be.
Could be.
LESLIE: When we went into that place,
before the fight started....
What a fight! It was glorious!
Before we went in,
I was feeling like you are now.
I was thinking to myself:
"Well...
"Jordan and l, and the others behind us,
have been failures."
And then it happened.
You wound up on the floor, on your back,
in the middle of the salad.
And I said to myself:
"Well...
"after 100 years...
"the Benedict family...
"is a real big success."
BICK: You want to know something, Leslie?
If I live to be 90...
I'll never be able to figure you out.
[Lullaby playing]
[Lively band song plays]