Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network,
Dentsu, Hakuhodo DYMP, Walt Disney Japan,
Mitsubishi, Toho and KDDI present
THE WIND RISES
The wind is rising!
We must try to live.
Here it is.
May I borrow it?
- It's in English.
- I have a dictionary.
- Very good. Give it a go.
- Thank you.
- Knock it off.
- Butt out!
Better get going.
Jiro...
No more bullying, okay?
You look quite the hero.
I slipped and fell.
- Fighting is never justified.
- I know.
Go have your snack.
Thank you.
Big brother, you're back!
I was waiting for you.
Let's pick bamboo grass.
Big brother!
I want to pick bamboo grass.
You promised to go with me.
I've got homework.
That's not homework.
It's an English magazine.
What a stupid moustache.
He's a famous Italian aircraft designer.
His name is Caproni.
It says he's a count.
- Your face is scratched.
- Leave it alone.
I better put some iodine on it.
Would you be quiet?
Big brother, what are you doing?
You're not allowed up here.
You're not wearing glasses.
Focusing on the stars
should improve my eyesight.
- Mother will scold you.
- A shooting star!
There's another one.
They're pretty.
See? Like that.
There's so many of them.
I'm a Japanese boy.
I think this is my dream.
This is my dream, you know.
It's mine too.
Your dream?
Listen, Japanese boy.
You think we are sharing this dream?
It's strange.
You're Count Caproni, aren't you?
I'm very glad to meet you.
Interesting. Yes, this is a dream.
This world is a dream.
Welcome to my kingdom.
I'm honored.
Look at them.
They will bomb the enemy city.
Most of them won't return.
But the war will soon be over.
Climb up, Japanese boy.
This is my dream.
When the war is over, I will build this.
Magnificent, isn't she?
Let's fly.
Instead of bombs,
she'll carry passengers.
Of course we can't climb up here...
but dreams are convenient.
One can go anywhere.
Come, join me.
You can walk along the spar.
Take a look.
- She's beautiful, no?
- Yes, incredible.
She'll carry a hundred people
across the Atlantic.
Mr. Caproni?
I have a question.
Do you think I could
design airplanes?
I'll never be a pilot.
I'm too nearsighted.
Listen, Japanese boy.
I'm not a pilot.
I don't even know how to fly.
To fly airplanes is simple.
But I am a creator of airplanes.
An aeronautical engineer!
Yes!
Listen to me, Japanese boy.
Airplanes are not tools for war.
They are not for making money.
Airplanes are beautiful dreams.
Engineers turn dreams into reality.
Yes!
Arrivederci. We'll meet again.
Jiro, you should go to bed.
You startled me.
I heard you talking to someone.
Mother, I'm going to be
an aeronautical engineer.
Really? That's a wonderful dream.
Airplanes are beautiful dreams.
That's what he told me.
I want to design beautiful airplanes.
You, there.
Come, take my seat.
Pardon me.
Please.
The wind feels wonderful.
Miss, you'll lose your hat.
Don't worry, Kinu.
Watch out!
Are you all right?
Safe!
Nice play.
Thank you.
"Le vent se lve."
"Il faut tenter de vivre."
"Le vent se lve.
Il faut tenter de vivre."
"The wind is rising.
We must try to live."
Earthquake.
The boiler's going to blow!
- What's wrong?
- Her leg.
Show me.
It hurts.
Kinu, be brave.
It's broken.
She can't walk like this.
Miss, the boiler.
Please save yourself.
That's nonsense.
Nothing's going to explode.
My suitcase.
Now, try to relax.
She can't walk.
Where do you live?
- In Ueno.
- I'll get you there.
- Fire.
- Let's go.
- What about your luggage?
- It's not important.
I'm so sorry.
Hang on!
We'd better hurry.
One of my shirts.
It's brand new.
You must be thirsty.
The well's almost dry.
What about you?
Thank you.
The fire hasn't reached Ueno.
I'm heading for the university.
What about you?
I'll bring someone from home.
I'll go with you.
- Look after this, Kinu.
- I will.
We'll be back soon.
Don't worry.
Watch my suitcase.
- Thank you.
- I'll leave her to you.
But what's your name?
That was some guy.
Don't you think, Kinu?
Jiro! You picked a great day
to come back.
How bad is it, Honjo?
The whole east side is burning.
That's everything we could carry.
Got a smoke?
A flying door? That's just great.
They'll never stop the fire now.
Tokyo's finished.
He really built it.
Caproni has giant dreams.
Stop the camera!
The wind's shifting.
It's coming this way.
Is the wind still rising,
Japanese boy?
Yes, it's a gale.
Then you must live.
"Le vent se lve."
"II faut tenter de vivre."
Hey Jiro. Ready?
All the new buildings
are old-fashioned.
The streets are wider.
Even the airplanes haven't changed.
Welcome!
Mackerel again?
It's great.
Every day's the same.
Same lunch, same lectures.
Can I get an egg?
The Western powers
are building all-metal aircraft.
Try the pork sometime.
We're more than ten years behind.
What?
Beautiful, isn't it?
Look at that wonderful curve.
You eat mackerel
to look at the bones?
Come on, finish up.
We're going for coffee.
Jiro sure is working hard.
Fish bones.
Is Mr. Horikoshi back from lunch?
Jiro!
Honjo, listen to this.
The NACA has a standard
curve just like this bone.
Do Americans eat mackerel too?
Jiro, package for you.
A lady brought this for you, sir.
You were out,
so she left it with me.
I see. Thank you.
Present from your sweetheart?
Got a smoke? Gimme one.
- Jiro!
- Let him go.
- Hello, Mr. Horikoshi.
- Back from school.
Your guest is waiting.
A young lady.
Oh, right.
Honestly, where were you?
Kayo, I'm sorry.
I completely forgot.
Really!
- Where's Mother?
- At Uncle's.
- Is she staying there?
- Just for one night.
You've grown, Kayo.
And gotten very pretty, too.
You're so mean.
You never ever come home.
Oh, it's almost sunset already.
I'll tell them I kept you.
Let's take the penny steamer.
She must really like you.
Come on, it's been two years.
Didn't you try to see her again?
Of course.
I went back once.
The fire stopped at her street.
See? There's the dock.
Are you cold?
I'm fine. I never dreamed
Tokyo would recover so quickly.
Can I stay with you, Jiro?
Father won't let me
live here by myself.
I'll probably be in Nagoya
by the time you come.
- With an airplane company?
- Yes.
Men have it so good.
I want to study medicine in Tokyo.
A doctor? I think
you might be a good one.
I think so too.
I'll talk to Father
next time I'm home.
Thanks. I'm counting on you.
Jiro!
There you are.
- You made it.
- Finally.
- We're on our way.
- Yes, we are.
They must've been
heading for the city.
There were hundreds of them.
There's no work in the countryside.
Another bank failure.
Which one is it this time?
- Are those the customers?
- Looks like it.
There were rumors.
The economy's in the tank.
So is our new employer.
MITSUBISHI INTERNAL
COMBUSTION ENGINE CO.
We've been waiting for you.
What took you so long?
I was told to come
anytime in April.
Then you should've come in March!
I've got an assignment for you.
It's the design for the wing strut fitting.
I need it right away.
We're behind schedule already.
In here.
The data's ready.
This way.
This is your desk.
It's imported,
but no one likes it.
Data here, hat goes there.
Listen up! The Falcon Project
has a new engineer.
He's the genius we've all
been hearing about.
Introduce yourself.
Jiro Horikoshi.
Now get to work.
Jiro, come on.
It's lunchtime. Let's go.
- The assembly plant?
- Yes, I'd like to take a look.
Asking a green engineer to design
that fitting is practically hazing.
Two.
Excuse me.
Could we ask a favor?
Look, it's really coming along.
Sorry to bother you on your break.
Not at all. You young engineers
should visit us more often.
Honjo, the strut's already installed.
I knew it.
Kurokawa's just hazing you.
Is his fitting better than yours?
Mr. Kurokawa's always hard
on new employees.
Honjo, get up here
and take a look.
I need your opinion.
- What do you think?
- Looks strong enough.
This is no good.
It's just like my design.
Then it must be bad.
Foreman, lunch break's over.
Quiet.
Fascinating! Aircraft are fascinating!
Maybe they are, but we're late.
I'm Hattori.
Mr. Hattori is our chief engineer.
Is this his first assignment?
The strut fitting for the Falcon.
That's no fitting.
Explain yourself, young man.
Yes sir. This leaf spring
will absorb stress from the wing.
The wire expands
and contracts automatically.
It runs through the strut
to an anchor on the fuselage.
But we'd have to
redesign the wing!
You're right.
I haven't done the calculations yet.
You're wasting your time.
Where's the assignment I gave you?
It's finished.
That looks like
a very clean design to me.
It's perfect.
Submit your work
as soon as you finish!
- I'm heading out.
- Me too.
What about Kurokawa's homework?
Just finishing up.
Oxen!
They haul prototypes
to the airfield.
The latest aircraft, hauled by oxen.
That's how backward we are.
But they're wonderful creatures.
Here she comes.
Get ready!
Approaching the mark.
Damn it!
- Did you get it?
- 13.3 seconds. 145 knots.
Too slow.
We need ten more knots.
She's too low.
The engine's not performing.
Kurokawa!
Representatives from the Army.
An audacious design.
- Another coup for Mitsubishi.
- Your Falcon is quite impressive.
Power dive.
She's trying to break 200.
- Parachute's open.
- Go get him!
Mr. Kurokawa, we'll investigate
the cause when the weather clears.
- What about the pilot?
- He's okay.
That's good.
Mr. Kurokawa, let's go.
We'll build Falcon Two.
Do you think the strut fitting failed?
No. I think the problem
is deeper and more complicated.
I'll never forget what I saw today.
It's like an endless road is
opening up before my eyes.
There won't be a Falcon Two.
The Army has decided
to go with a competing design.
Today was our last chance
to change their minds.
We're going to build a bomber
with help from Junkers.
No more fighters for now.
This is your chance to see Germany.
I've already approved it.
- Still open?
- Ah, welcome back.
You're later than usual.
- Two slices of the usual.
- Coming up.
There you are.
Isn't anyone looking after them?
Their parents work late.
They wait there every night.
I feel bad closing the place up.
I see. Well, thanks.
Come again.
You must be hungry.
Here's something to eat.
It's sponge cake.
I just bought it.
Go ahead, take it.
Come on!
You here, Jiro?
Too bad about the Falcon.
I heard they axed it.
Sponge cake? You have
some strange eating habits.
What did you expect?
Did you think she was going to
smile and say thank you?
Of course not.
Well, maybe I did.
There are dozens of hungry kids
right here in this neighborhood.
The cost of one fitting would feed
that kid's family for a month.
Why is Japan so poor?
Jiro, do you know what we're paying
the Germans for their technology?
Enough to feed every kid in Japan,
with sponge cake for dessert.
Still, I plan to make the most
of this opportunity.
They're sending you too?
They told me today.
Really? That's great news.
Poor countries want airplanes.
So they pay us a lot
to design them. It's ironic.
I'm leaving for Tokyo tomorrow.
Getting married.
Married?
To work hard at the office,
you need a family at home.
More irony.
Tight-fisted Germans.
They're hardly showing us anything.
I don't see any oxen.
The airstrip's
next to the plant.
Everything's so big.
It's the G-38.
Is this what we're buying?
For conversion to a bomber.
It's top secret.
Who's the Army planning
to bomb with this thing?
America, probably.
Not that they could.
Still, it's quite something.
Amazing.
Passengers can sit in the wings.
This would be wasted as a bomber.
Who cares? We need
their all-metal airframe technology.
You're kidding.
We can't go inside?
Beautiful.
Stop it.
Take your hands off him.
Is this how Germans
treat their guests?
You Japanese copy everything.
This technology belongs to Germany.
Oh, come on. Japan has
lots of planes like this.
Honjo, let it go.
We have a license
to your technology.
We signed an agreement.
We have the right to be here.
Your bosses never said
we couldn't inspect this airplane.
I'm sure you're only
trying to do your job...
but we won't tolerate this treatment.
The agreement is between equals.
Our orders were not to let
you Japanese wander around.
That's Dr. Junkers.
What an engineer.
You can go inside.
Dr. Junkers has agreed.
I'm surprised we got a demonstration.
There's more vibration
than I expected.
Our bosses are getting giddy.
Let the Army officers sit here.
Just a moment.
This is truly a stupendous aircraft.
Look, a corridor through the wing.
This is amazing.
It's like being inside a power plant.
Guten tag.
Dr. Junkers gave us permission.
Please show us your work station.
This is the flight engineer's station.
This aircraft is marvelous.
Japanese, do not go further.
Of course, my friend.
- This is incredible.
- Yes, it's fantastic.
A triumph of
German industrial technology.
Dr. Junkers is my hero,
but his company is sneaky.
Got a cigarette, Jiro?
Jiro!
A cigarette.
No. We're out.
It looks cold outside,
but this room is cozy.
I thought Germans used fireplaces.
Junkers makes radiators too.
This almost looks like that plane.
It's beautiful.
And our technology is primitive.
That's what you mean, right?
You think we'll never figure out
all-metal construction on our own?
We can't learn anything from this.
These are just pretty equations.
"This technology belongs to Germany."
Maybe we don't even
need their technology.
Wood and canvas
could be as good as metal.
Then we'll never make it.
We're already 20 years behind.
Let's take a walk.
My brain is boiling.
We're Achilles, chasing a tortoise
with a twenty-year lead.
If we close the gap
in five years...
he'll be five more years
down the road.
We'll always be chasing him.
Someday we'll overtake him
and move ahead.
I wonder if we
can be the tortoise.
What?
Listen to that.
Schubert's "Winter Journey".
It's perfect for us.
- What was that about?
- We saw him in the hangar.
Jiro?
I'm done. Go have a bath.
Dead to the world...
with a face like he's carrying
the future of Japanese aviation.
There's a telegram from headquarters.
- Come in.
- Not necessary.
Some of us are returning immediately.
You're staying behind.
Jiro will continue west
and return to Japan.
- West?
- They want him to see the world.
All by himself?
Mr. Caproni.
Is the wind still rising?
Yes, it is.
Then I invite you to join me
on my final flight. Come.
You're retiring?
It's a big jump.
Jump!
Hurry. We're taking off.
There's a hatch under the fuselage.
Hurry!
Let me through.
Up here!
- Full power!
- Fly! Fly!
My workmen's families and relatives.
Practically the whole village.
We're taking a private jaunt...
before we deliver this bomber
to the Air Force.
- What do you think?
- It's incredible.
It's like a building
out of ancient Rome.
This plane is too large
to be used for war...
but the Air Force
likes everything big.
Japan is poor and backward.
We could never build
something like this.
The important thing
for an engineer is inspiration.
Inspiration unlocks the future.
Technology will catch up.
My wife and family.
We Italians are also poor.
Too many mouths to feed.
Hey, settle down.
The bottom will fall out.
Come.
Be careful. This may be a dream,
but you can still lose your head.
Which would you choose, a world with
pyramids or one without them?
Pyramids?
Humanity dreams of flight,
but the dream is cursed.
Aircraft are destined to become
tools for slaughter and destruction.
I know.
But still, I chose a world
with pyramids in it.
Which world will you choose?
I want to create beautiful airplanes.
Like that?
Very graceful.
I have a long way to go.
I don't even have the engine yet.
Bravo! A beautiful dream.
I'm retiring.
This is my last design.
Artists are only creative
for ten years.
We engineers are no different.
Live your ten years to the full.
Jiro, we need to talk.
- I've got a meeting.
- Cancel it.
- This is a tall order.
- They're always tall.
How long have you
been with us, Jiro?
Jiro?
- How long?
- Five years.
You should be ready, then.
We want you to lead the project.
It's the Navy's design competition
for 1932. A carrier-based fighter.
A plum assignment.
Well, Jiro?
What do you think?
Leave it to me.
Good.
I'd like Honjo on the team.
Bad idea.
You'd end up competing.
Friendship's more important.
Relax and finish your coffee.
Check, please.
We've got other plans for Honjo.
Damn these Japanese engines!
And damn this short flight deck.
Fresh uniforms!
Oh, thanks.
Thanks for your help.
Those jerseys suit you.
Close the flight deck!
Stop!
We did it!
She's airborne!
Father!
Bravo! Nice catch.
That was kind of you.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. Here you are.
Thank you.
It belongs to the hotel.
Well, goodbye.
Father, I'm afraid
I was rude to that man.
Don't worry.
He's staying at our hotel.
You'll have a chance
to say thank you.
What is it?
Nothing. Just that man
who caught the parasol.
He seems to be here by himself.
I'm sorry. I'd better go.
No, please stay.
I was giving thanks to the spring.
I asked it
to bring you here, to me.
You haven't changed at all.
You're just like you were then.
We were so grateful
for your help after the earthquake.
I wanted to see you
again and thank you.
Oh, now I remember.
My name is Nahoko Satomi.
Jiro Horikoshi.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Kinu got married two days after
she dropped off your shirt.
She cried for joy
when we found you.
You were our knight
in shining armor.
Your knight?
You were like a knight on a
white horse that day.
This umbrella sure does leak.
It's all right.
I've got to tell Kinu.
She just had her second child.
It's such a cute baby.
Your painting is all wet.
Yes. I'll keep it this way
in honor of today.
Look, it's clearing up.
The rain stopped here.
Oh, look at that.
I'd almost forgotten
what rainbows look like.
Life is wonderful, isn't it?
We'd better go.
Father's probably worried sick.
There's my father.
Father!
Come, I'll introduce you.
You're soaking wet.
Don't worry, Father. I'm fine.
Mr. Horikoshi saved me again.
Jiro Horikoshi.
Satomi. I'm afraid my daughter has
caused you trouble again.
May I sit here?
Certainly.
German tobacco. Last one. Too bad.
I know how you feel.
The same thing happened to me.
You visit Germany, yes? To Dessau.
You must be Sherlock Holmes.
You are an engineer.
You read German magazines.
Magazines about airplanes.
All Japanese engineers visit Dessau.
You're exactly right.
- Dr. Junkers is in trouble.
- What kind of trouble?
He fights the government.
He will blow up.
Mr. Hitler's government?
The Nazis are a gang of hoodlums.
This is a good place.
No mosquitoes.
Not hot. Good watercress.
A good place to forget bad things.
Cigarette? I'm afraid they're Japanese.
Thank you.
It is a nice night.
Hier ist der Zauberberg.
"The Magic Mountain"
by Thomas Mann?
A good place for forgetting.
Make a war in China. Forget it.
Make a puppet state
in Manchuria. Forget it.
Quit the League of Nations. Forget it.
Make the world your enemy. Forget it.
Japan will blow up.
Germany will blow up too.
- Will Germany go to war again?
- Yes. They must be stopped.
I'm sorry to keep you
waiting so long.
Nahoko has a fever.
I'm afraid we'll have to
cancel our dinner plans.
I'm sorry. Please tell her
I hope she feels better.
I must go.
The doctor will be here soon.
"Who has seen the wind?"
"Neither I nor you."
"But when the leaves hang trembling,
the wind is passing through."
Let the wind carry...
these wings to you.
Jiro?
Nahoko!
Be careful!
Nice catch.
Bravo!
Is the young lady feeling better?
Yes, she's much better.
Congratulations.
This is the magic mountain.
It cures everyone.
I think you're right.
At first, this young man
was very gloomy.
Now he is very happy.
He has fallen in love.
That's true.
Summer love is soon forgotten.
You will go down the mountain.
You will forget what happened here.
Not me.
This person you're talking about
wouldn't be my daughter, would it?
Yes, it's Nahoko.
Please give us your permission.
But...
Father!
I would like to accept.
What a beauty.
But first, there's something
I have to tell you.
Yes?
Two years ago,
my mother died of tuberculosis.
I contracted it too.
I've loved you since
that day you rescued my hat.
I've loved you since the wind
brought you to me.
Please marry me.
I will.
But I want to get well first.
Can you wait for me?
Even if it takes
a hundred years.
Congratulations.
He is a nice young man.
Your daughter is wonderful.
This is a good summer.
- Jiro, over here!
- Honjo!
- When did you get back?
- Two days ago.
Hot, isn't it?
Come take a look.
She's beautiful.
Good clean lines.
It's a radical design.
They gave me free rein.
But we won't know
until she flies.
She'll fly.
I feel the wind rising.
You're the Japanese Achilles.
You've closed the gap.
My plane was just a tin duckling.
I have an idea for you.
I haven't tried it yet.
Use flathead screws
on the access hatches.
They'll reduce drag.
Maintenance will be easy
with a hinge on one side.
A spring about this stiff
should be fine.
That's a great idea,
like Columbus and his egg.
You should use it.
Thanks, but not this time.
I'll keep the plans.
After you use it,
I'll use it too.
Okay.
Hurry up, I'll be waiting.
Jiro! Are you here?
Jiro, it's Mr. Kurokawa.
It's an emergency.
See you.
Visit the house next time.
Jiro, you pedal.
The Special Police
are looking for you.
The thought crime boys.
Why me?
I told them you were
away on business.
Pretending to leave?
We won't fall for that.
You'd better work here.
We'll bring your things.
What's going on?
Why are they after me?
They arrested some of my friends.
None of them understood why.
Come in.
Here's your stuff.
Sorry for the bother.
Need anything else?
- Just leave it and go.
- Jiro, it's here!
The prototype flange.
It looks great.
Wish we'd had it last year.
Jiro, what do you think?
Our next plane will be
a full-grown duck, not a duckling.
A full metal duck.
How about it, Mr. Kurokawa?
Extruded aluminum alloy.
Very light. What a luxury.
All right, back to work.
- The coast looks clear.
- Okay, Jiro.
Better lie low for a few days.
We'll smooth things over.
I'll put you up.
Let me stop by my apartment.
I'm expecting a letter.
Is it something sensitive?
Yes, very sensitive.
The police will be opening your mail.
It's from my fiance.
Such things shouldn't happen
in a modern country.
You're engaged?
- Jiro's human after all.
- Splendid.
You think Japan's a modern country?
It's not funny.
Of course it's not funny.
The police are waiting for you.
Let them read your love letters.
The Navy's next design
competition is in your hands.
The company will protect you.
That is, as long as you're useful.
Just keep your mind on work.
I miss you terribly.
And "Mr. Castorp" left so suddenly.
Why are they looking for him?
I pray that he managed to
leave Japan safely.
Jiro, telephone for you.
Coming.
- The telephone is there.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
- Jiro? You have a telegram.
What?
Your landlord brought it.
It came two days ago.
Please read it.
Are you sure?
"Nahoko... has had
a lung... hemorrhage."
"Please come at once.
Satomi"
Hello? Are you there?
I understand. Thank you.
Wait, hold on!
What is it?
What's the fastest way
to get to Tokyo?
To Tokyo?
I have to be there
as soon as possible.
Let me see.
If you take the noon bus,
you can catch the express.
I'll send someone
to hold the bus for you.
Jiya!
Darling!
I wish I could've
come sooner.
You'll catch it.
You're beautiful.
I love you.
Jiro? Through the garden?
Come in.
Father, Jiro came to see me.
But he has to leave right away.
- Next time I'll use the front door.
- Use the garden, it's more fun.
All right, I will.
Take care, darling.
You too.
Goodbye.
I'll see you out.
The last train?
You'd better hurry.
Is it that serious?
I wish I could look after her.
The way to do that is
to focus on your work.
Now you'd better go.
He's gone.
Are you crying, dear?
I'm going to the sanatorium
the doctor recommended.
But it's so lonely.
You'll be all by yourself.
I want to get better.
I want a life with Jiro.
You're just in time.
The board is waiting.
So, are you ready?
I'll do my best.
Now the Navy.
They're the client.
I'll do my best.
- You weren't even listening.
- Right.
So I gave up on that idea.
- Everyone's here rather late.
- Jiro's holding a design seminar.
The next design uses
all the latest technology.
- Take a look.
- Retractable undercarriage!
We'll need it for 270 knots.
270 knots?
That's 500 kilometers an hour!
I thought the Navy
requested 220 knots.
We're designing for the future.
Wing loading is 120 kilos
per square meter.
We'll minimize drag
and push the limits of technology.
She'll have split flaps
and leading edge slats.
We can do it!
When do we start?
But then weight becomes a problem.
If we leave out the guns,
we should be okay.
I decided to set
this idea aside for now.
This is delightful.
Lucid and logical.
Almost had it.
Our engines are underpowered.
To compensate, we need
a light, strong structure.
We'll cut excess weight
and minimize drag with a smooth skin.
We're going to build
an all-metal fighter...
like nothing the world's ever seen.
I have a question!
Mr. Hirayama, please.
Mr. Hirayama is our production engineer.
Thank you.
He's going to tell us
about the new rivets.
It's technically possible to build
strong structures with flush rivets.
What's he talking about?
A way to cut drag.
We're going to skin
the whole aircraft with flush rivets.
- Question!
- I have a question!
I must say, that was interesting.
It was inspiring.
Today's letter, Miss Satomi.
Thank you.
Phone call, Chief.
- I'll call back.
- I think it's an emergency.
Hello? Mr. Satomi?
What?!
Jiro! Jiro!
Thank goodness.
I worried I wouldn't find you.
I'm here now. Can you walk?
Let's go.
I just had to see you.
I should go right back.
Don't go.
We should be together.
- What a charming companion.
- My name is Nahoko.
- So you're Nahoko.
- Jiro, is that you?
We've come to you
with a request.
Why not, dear? It'll be fine.
We've got plenty of room...
but I can hardly approve of
an unmarried couple living together.
We'll get married right away.
Mr. Kurokawa, Mrs. Kurokawa,
please be our witnesses.
Here? Tonight?
It sounds lovely, dear.
Nahoko was very brave
to leave the sanatorium.
My father's given his permission.
I've already told the doctor.
Please help us.
The bride and I have
preparations to make.
Come with me, Nahoko.
Don't worry, he's always like that.
If you care about her,
you'll send her back immediately.
I can't do that.
I'd have to give up my work.
Is that your heart
or your ego talking?
We don't have much time.
We've made our decision.
I see.
All right.
We'll have a real ceremony!
Here they come.
She's coming!
Hear me! This lovely maiden
has traveled far to join her beloved.
She's given up everything
in the world for him. What say you?
Hear me! This man is
an insensitive simpleton...
without a home
of his own.
If that's... uh, okay with you,
please come in.
Then they shall exchange
the marriage vows.
You look beautiful.
Mr. and Mrs. Kurokawa.
No words can express
our gratitude for your kindness.
We will never forget our debt to you.
Come now, we're delighted that
Jiro's found such a wonderful partner.
Aren't we, dear?
Of course. This is wonderful.
You're both very courageous.
You must be tired.
I feel like I'm dreaming.
The room is spinning.
Better get some rest.
Come here.
But your condition...
Come.
Do you always
get home this late?
Kayo, I completely forgot.
You're so insensitive.
Congratulations on becoming a doctor.
Congratulations on your marriage.
I came on behalf of the family
to thank the Kurokawas.
Are they still up?
They've gone to bed.
- Did you meet Nahoko?
- Yes.
What are you going to do?
She's alone in that room all day.
Her condition is
much worse than you think.
I'm an intern.
I know something about this.
Did you notice she uses rouge
every morning so you won't worry?
I really like Nahoko.
She's such a good person.
How can you do this to her?
Does she really have to stay here?
Yes.
Each day is very precious to us now.
Get some rest.
I'm glad you came to visit.
I'm home.
- I was waiting.
- You should sleep.
- Should you be up?
- Kayo came today.
We're already best friends.
She's like the sun,
with such a bright future.
She said next time,
she'll come as my doctor.
And your mother made me
a chemise and a nightgown.
Look, they're so warm.
Too bright?
It's all right.
I have to finish
the design by tomorrow.
For your mackerel bones?
You remembered.
I think it could
be a little lighter.
Come a little closer.
Give me your hand.
I like to look at you
while you work.
In a one-handed slide rule contest,
I'd win first prize for sure.
I think I can make each rib
half an ounce lighter.
Really? That's good.
Thirty ribs makes about a pound.
That's too much.
Half a pound is enough for two.
I could eat a pound
of mackerel by myself.
I'll keep holding your hand.
You should sleep.
- You won't let go?
- No, I won't.
I need a cigarette.
Can I let go for a minute?
No. Smoke it here.
- It's not good for you.
- I don't care.
Hey, Honjo.
Can I take a look?
- Sure. How's your bomber?
- Coming along fine.
This is avant garde.
You went all the way.
So this is flush riveting.
Feels pretty rough.
We're still learning the technique.
You've left the Germans behind.
I'm still stuck with them.
This design is you,
right down to the mackerel bones.
Jiro, let me use flush rivets too.
And your spring-loaded hatches.
Sure. Why not?
A redesign?
Yeah, but they're only letting me
modify the fuselage.
And leave the wings alone?
That's where the fuel tanks are.
One hit, and boom.
To save weight, we're not even
shielding the fuel tanks.
It's Japan's first advanced bomber.
The Navy's over the moon.
She's got to fly 3,000 kilometers
with a big payload.
More horsepower alone won't be enough.
Who are they going to fight?
China. Russia. Britain.
The Netherlands. America.
Japan will blow up.
We're not arms merchants.
We just want to build good aircraft.
You're right.
See you. Get some sleep.
Sure. You too.
I'm leaving now.
Good night.
Night.
Welcome home.
It's finished.
Now we'll see how she flies.
Congratulations.
You worked so hard.
She's on her way to the field.
I'll probably spend
a few nights there.
You must be tired.
A little.
I'm sure it will fly beautifully.
Yes, she'll fly.
I couldn't have done it without you.
I love you, Jiro.
Nahoko...
I'm off.
Good luck.
Why, Nahoko. You're up.
I'm feeling much better today.
I'm going for a walk.
Just be careful
not to tire yourself.
The room's still a mess.
I'll straighten up when I get back.
All right. Enjoy yourself.
Kayo's coming today.
That will be nice.
Yes. I'll be back soon.
Please come in.
Oh, no.
Look, she left letters!
One of them's for me.
She's going to the sanatorium!
I'll bring her back.
No! Let her go.
We shouldn't do anything
until her train leaves.
She wants him
to remember her as she was.
This is wonderful.
Just think, that's one of ours.
How's her speed?
Sorry, the numbers are too high.
We're checking them again.
How fast?
- 240 knots.
- Two forty!
- Fantastic!
- What a fighter.
Hey, Jiro.
Jiro!
She flies like a dream.
Thank you.
We meet again, Japanese boy.
Mr. Caproni...
This is where we first met.
Our kingdom of dreams.
Or the land of the dead.
Not quite. In some ways, yes.
Those ten years in the sun,
did you live them to the full?
Yes. Things fell apart
toward the end, though.
That's what it means to lose a war.
There's your Zero fighter.
Beautiful. A masterful design.
Not a single plane returned.
There was nothing
to come back to.
Airplanes are beautiful dreams.
Cursed dreams...
waiting for the sky
to swallow them up.
Someone is waiting for you.
Nahoko...
She's been waiting here
for a long time.
Darling, you must live.
You must live...
She is gone.
She was beautiful, like the wind.
Thank you.
You must live.
First, shall we drop by my house?
I have some excellent wine.
A Tribute to Jiro Horikoshi
and Tatsuo Hori
Voices
Hideaki Anno Miori Takimoto
A white sloping path
Runs up into the sky
A gently swaying, misy haze
Surrounding and holding
Unnoticed by anyone, all alone
Soaring upwards
Not afraid of anything
Dancing up
Longing to be in the sky
Speeding through the sky
A whole life, a vapor trail
Even before dying
From that window, up high
Watching the sky
Now no one understands
No one would understand
All they could think was...
"Too young"
Yet... happy
Longing to be in the sky
Speeding through the sky
A whole life, a vapor trail
Longing to be in the sky
Speeding through the sky
A whole life, a vapor trail
Theme Song Yumi Arai
Music Joe Hisaishi
Dialogue Translation by
Jim Hubbert & Rieko Izutsu-Vajirasarn
Subtitles by Aura
Executive Producer Koji Hoshino
Producer Toshio Suzuki
A Studio Ghibli Film
Original Story and Screenplay
Written and Directed by Hayao Miyazaki
The End