[SUBTITLE FEATURES:
Idiomatic English, real slang...]
[translated on-screen text,
punctuation incl. dialogue markers...]
[short linelengths,
optimized for fast reading and...]
[true meaning without distracting
from the video.]
[English subtitles by Huy Zing
& Wanessa Papillon]
Despite possible coincidences,
this film is fictional.
Rio de Janeiro
present time
We'll wait behind the hospital.
Tell us when he comes out, ok?
He's going to the parking lot.
Attention. He's coming out.
This may look like an
American movie cliche
but it's when facing death
that we understand life.
I beat up a lot of junkies.
I took down many crooked cops.
I sent a ton of
thugs into a ditch.
But it was nothing personal.
Society prepared me for this.
And a mission assigned, my friend,
is a mission accomplished.
Elite Squad 2: the Enemy Within
Special Ops. (BOPE)
You'll never be one of us!
Talk, talk! Who's the killer?
Tell me!
- Tell me you want out!
- No, sir!
If not, you're out!
...that I'm about to have a son.
She has two kids!
I tried to save my family...
I left a guy I trusted
in my place.
Didn't work out,
and I came back.
I was with BOPE many years.
I commanded the unit.
Fought until the end.
I'd still be with BOPE,
if not for what happened...
at the Penitentiary Larcio
da Costa Pellegrino...
better known as "Bangu One".
(Bangu One, 4 years earlier)
- Big Curi.
- Hey! How you doing?
- All good?
- Quiet.
Enough work there?
This is where the drug lords
ended up...
Hey, partner.
...the guys that the police
caught and didn't execute...
because they had a lot
dough to lose.
- All good here?
- All good.
Each drug gang was put
in its own isolated wing.
If left to mix,
these punks would kill each other.
You know what they did inside?
The same as outside.
They were at war, vying for
control of trafficking in the city.
If up to me, I'd lock them up,
throw away the key...
and let them slaughter
each other inside.
But there are liberal
intellectuals...
who make a living
defending these punks.
What's worse is that they get
into the heads of many people.
...the craziest thing we've been
discussing is that prison today...
is a place that costs enormously...
only to make people worse.
And look what more and more...
Fraga lived to call me
a fascist
but didn't have the courage
to tell it to my face.
When we spoke face to face,
he pretended to respect me.
And the fucked-up thing is
I had to do the same.
...Just to give you an idea,
in 1996...
the Brazilian prison population
was 148,000 prisoners.
Today, 10 years later,
the prison population...
is over 400,000 prisoners.
It's more than double.
It's almost triple.
I made a calculation.
It's perverse, I have it here.
Obviously, doesn't make sense.
Picture this, a history professor
doing math. What a disaster.
But this one I must make sure
to share with you...
which is that I noticed...
that the Brazilian
prison population...
doubles, on average,
every 8 years.
While the Brazilian population...
doubles every 50 years.
If we continue this way,
in 2081...
the Brazilian population will be
570 million...
in other words, your kids,
grandkids, and great-grandkids,
while the Brazilian prison
population...
will be 510 million.
Your children, grand-children,
and great-grandchildren!
In other words, 90% of Brazilians
will be in prison.
Can you picture it? Huh, Jlia?
Is this the retirement
you had in mind?
But listen, don't worry,
don't worry...
because this situation here
gets better.
In 2083, all Brazilians
will be living here.
In a gated community
like this one here.
Bangu One,
our first maximum
security prison.
- What's up, Curi.
- Hey, how's it going?
I'm gonna fix a
problem with Beirada...
- but it's all good, ok?
- That's cool, partner.
Here inside,
ladies and gentlemen...
are the 40 guys
considered the most dangerous...
in Rio de Janeiro. 40!
Ali Baba is outside.
He's at the palace.
But the 40 are inside,
guaranteed.
Waddup.
Yo, Curi.
What you got for us?
What's up, Beirada.
Here, as we agreed...
- Gimme.
- Here are the pieces.
Here, hold this.
All good, right?
Yo, I'm checking
it's all here.
Tie him there.
If you pay attention,
Bangu One will remind you
of reality today in our city.
Rio de Janeiro today
is, let's put it this way,...
divided into 3 criminal factions
in constant conflict...
and Bangu One is exactly
the same thing ...
- Tie him there.
3 criminal factions feeding
the hatred...
and rivalry among them.
Goddamn it, Beirada,
what the fuck?
"What the fuck" is a shitload.
Shut up, shut your mouth.
You're getting a shitload of dough.
Real quiet. Kids,
quiet, ok. Quiet.
A miserable bunch...
who never had a chance
at education...
who never had any chance
in life...
locked and forgotten in the worst
conditions imaginable...
and controlled by police...
with strong tendencies toward
corruption.
Beirada is out.
Notify the authorities
Bangu One's blowing up.
Oh, and bring me coffee.
Hard bread sucks.
- It's Qual that I want!
- Easy, easy!
Out of the way, move, move, move.
Move, goddamn it.
Sit down!
So you were gonna kill me?
You gonna die.
You gonna get it in the ass.
- I'm just a soldier, yo.
- That's the fucker.
- I'm just a soldier.
- He's the boss.
Yet, some folks still
open their mouths to say...
Brazil's the
country of inpunity.
It may even be, for one
particular sector of society.
Because for the others,
for the working classes...
for mere mortals,
there's hell to pay.
Put this shit in.
Put him in the oven.
- Come on!
- Go to hell, cocksucker.
The guy's gonna die!
Hey, man, you fattened the pig,
now we're gonna roast it!
There, get the mattress there.
Bring it, bring it.
Go in, go in. Rap, soak him.
- Our time, boss.
- Soak him. Now you'll...
Our time.
Bath time.
...learn how to roast pork,
motherfuckers.
- Bath!
- Soak him.
Now let's go to the Third.
Let's get that motherfucker
over there.
You're surrounded.
You can't escape.
Sons of bitches.
- Red assholes.
- I'm going to shoot.
Pieces of shit.
Whoever fears death,
homes, shouldn't be born. Got it?!
We're at war!
- Open this shit there, son.
- Let's fucking go!
What, bro?
Go fuck yourself, son!
I don't negotiate with police.
Go to hell.
If you come in, everyone will die.
Negotiate my cock!
Call Fraga,
call Fraga...
I don't negotiate with police.
Open this shit, kid.
I asked you to turn off
your phones and I left mine on.
Just a moment.
Real quick.
It's guys like Fraga who thugs
need when they start shit.
Right now?
And the shit that Beirada started
changed Fraga's story...
and Rio's story...
and my story.
The punks set fire to Qual.
He's on fire, but everyone's
in the main hall already.
- Can you hear me?
- Affirmative.
From here, I think it's
one long and two short.
I think it's a twelve-gauge
and two pistols.
The guards are tied to the bars,
close to you there.
They want to break thru.
What door is that?
- Third Command.
- Zoom in on that door.
The guys want to enter
the wing of the Third.
They want to kill everyone there too.
They want in,
we'll let 'em in.
We'll let them in.
Andr, get the squad
in position...
but do nothing until
I give the order, understood?
We're gonna let these guys
go in there.
- Understood? Do you copy?
- Affirmative, Colonel.
Zero One, in position.
- Show me the squad.
- Monitor 4, Colonel.
Confirm...
Andr, confirm it's a twelve-gauge
in that punk's hand.
Where's the Third?
I wanna go into the fucking Third.
Affirmative, Colonel.
Do you copy?
Copy.
Commander, we have a
good opportunity here.
Nascimento, one minute...
I need authorization
from the Governor.
Just a minute. Pardon me.
The Red Commandoes killed
the heads of ADA.
Nascimento wants authorization
to enter and finish the job.
Could be a good idea, Governor.
It solves the problem completely.
The public will support it.
Nobody tolerates these
assholes anymore.
No. I don't want
another "Carandiru."
- Where's the guy from human rights?
- I already sent him.
He should be there soon.
Tell Nascimento to buy some time.
Does the Governor realize
the opportunity...
we have right here, Commander?
- And you'll let this guy go in?
- The man's here, Colonel.
He's already here.
Open this shit now.
I want the fucking Third, man!
Sup, bro? Wassup?
Nascimento, let's deal
with this problem and...
- not make it personal. Cool?
- Cool, Fraga.
Unfortunately I cannot
authorize your entry.
If I don't go in,
there'll be a bloodbath.
- It's already started.
- I know.
- I know, I know.
I don't want to pull
your body from there.
Colonel, you have to understand...
my entry's already been
authorized by your boss.
I'm going in.
Fraga!
- The vest, Renan.
- No need.
- No need. I won't use it.
- Wear the vest, Fraga.
If I go in with a vest, Colonel...
they won't trust me.
Andr, Che Guevara here is
going in without a vest.
Beirada, what the hell is this?
What's going on here?
This fuck isn't coming close?
He's right in front of you,
Andr. Can you hear me?
With all due respect...
- Affirmative.
- With all due respect...
we're solving our own problem,
understand?
Solving your problem?
This way?!
Beirada has a pistol in his hand.
We gotta do what we gotta do,
you feel me, Fraga?
- Let me tell you something...
- With all due respect.
BOPE is outside and is coming
to kill everyone.
Fuck 'em! We'll kill all
these fuckers here.
They're not even here for
these people.
Think! BOPE doesn't give a
shit about these guys.
They haven't come in yet
because I'm fucking here.
He's doing well.
Hold, stay calm.
If I leave, you're fucked.
Release these guys.
- You guarantee?
- I guarantee. Let them go.
- You guarantee, Fraga?
- Do it, Beirada.
- Man to man.
- I'll stay. Let them go.
Think, damn it.
Let these guys go so I can come
in and talk with you. Do it.
Do it. Let them go.
- Let these guys go, Beirada.
- You guarantee, Fraga?
If I leave, you're fucked.
Let's end this
as quickly as possible.
Let them go and
let's get this over with.
Enough damn killings.
Let's end this.
- Do it. Let them go.
- Paulinho, let these guys go.
- Let them go.
- Ok.
Let them fucking go.
He's untying the hostages, Andr.
He's untied one.
The man's in control of
the situation, Andr.
Hold. Stay put.
He opened the door. Ok?
He opened the door,
he's letting them go.
One's out, two's out,
Fraga went in.
Easy, he's in charge, Andr.
Stop, Andr! Stop, Andr!
Fuck.
Don't shoot, damn it!
Don't shoot!
- He's gonna die, son.
- Lower your gun, Beirada.
Lower my gun, fuck that.
Lower your gun,
he won't shoot.
- He will, bro.
- Do you hear, Captain?
- Let the hostage go.
- He won't shoot anymore. It's over.
No one will shoot anymore,
do you hear, Captain?
- Lower your gun, Beirada.
- Lower my gun, my ass.
- Shit.
- No more shooting, Captain!
Lower your gun. Lower your gun
coz it's over. It's over, Beirada.
- Listen, Beirada, it's over.
- Let him go.
- You can trust me.
- It's a trick, son.
Trust me, Beirada. It's over.
Lower the damn gun.
Lower your gun,
trust me. Lower it.
Matias seized his chance.
He did as trained in BOPE.
He killed the punk to
protect the hostage.
The problem, my friend,
is that a .762 bullet makes...
a small entry hole...
but the exit hole is
the size of a tangerine.
The team entered and in
less than a minute...
we had the problem resolved.
Matias eliminated
the toughest guy...
- in the history of Red Commandoes.
- Hands on your head!
There was just one detail
that spoiled everything.
That fucking T-shirt.
"Human Rights" written
in English and covered in blood...
That shit turned into
headlines the world over.
A massacre, total carnage,
that's what happened inside.
The Governor will have to explain how,
after he promised me...
that there would be no massacre,
immediately after...
Colonel Nascimento
and Captain Matias...
executed the prisoners
in cold blood.
Because it was an execution.
It was an execution.
Give us more details.
Was there a negotiation?
No. No time for negotiation.
The bullets from Captain Matias, on
orders from Colonel Nascimento...
got there first.
BOPE entered only and exclusively
to kill and they killed.
In fact, they did what they're used to
doing in the slums of Rio.
Ethnic cleansing.
Social cleansing.
That's what they do.
And that's what they're paid for.
To be cowards.
BOPE today were cowards
in that prison...
just as they are cowards
in our community.
I'd like, just one time,
to see BOPE invade
and arrest a drug dealer...
in a luxury condo.
But it's not what they do, right,
Mr. Secretary of Public Security?
There, the Skulls don't go in,
do they, Mr. Chief of Police?
So you think that BOPE
acted with excessive force?
Is this what doomed
the operation?
What we can't admit is that
a representative of the State...
is more violent than those
that we want...
in prison for violent crimes.
It's absurd.
This is becoming routine.
This is becoming normal.
And no one thinks it's odd?
To have a police force
whose symbol is a skull?
whose symbol is death?
I find this inexplicable.
Mr. Governor.
I'm perplexed.
Sir, you will have to give
an explanation.
And it won't do to say that
Colonel Nascimento...
ignored your orders.
Yes, Colonel Nascimento
was a coward.
Yes, he led the entire massacre.
But the one who orders
the police is the Governor.
It's all his responsibility.
Fuck, I did everything to save
Fraga and the guy bashed me.
I never butted into Rosane's life
after we separated.
But marrying him was a low blow.
The guy went around filling
my son's head with bullshit.
It's best you don't come in.
Did you read the paper today?
So why isn't Formoso here
talking to me now?
Why can't I talk to Formoso?
So when...
So when he comes to talk to us...
we'll speak to the press, Pinheiro.
Cheers.
Commander, the decision to
go in was mine.
I'm the one who killed.
Let me take responsibility alone.
The responsibility is mine, Andr.
The responsibility is mine.
I'm in command.
Colonel, you'll excuse me...
but if we're gonna go down,
better to go down shooting.
Our unit is being thrown
to the dogs.
Let's call the press
and let the shit hit the fan.
Let's fuck these bastards, sir.
Andr, you heard what I said?
You heard my conversation
with Pinheiro just now?
- Were you listening? You heard?
- Yes, sir.
So you want to fight
with the Governor? Now?
In the press? You want to fuck
the Battalion over?
You don't want this.
Lupe, did you find
the Commander-General?
No, he went to lunch.
Then find out where
and let me know.
These guys are afraid
to talk to me.
I'm not afraid
to talk to them.
After the accusations from
the representative...
of Human Rights AID that
reverberated around world...
Guanabara Palace said
that they will relieve from duty...
the BOPE officers involved in the
occupation of the Bangu One prison.
True.
But if not Otavio...
who will you put, Guaracy?
Who it'll be, or who it
won't be, matters little.
The Governor wants that son a bitch
Nascimento discharged tomorrow.
- Ok.
- End of story.
Let's resolve this quickly.
We'll quickly put,
promote the subcommander?
- Renan?
- Quickly.
- Good idea.
- Yeah. Renan.
Later we'll see who to put
in his place and done.
True.
Oh shit.
Don't look now...
but that asshole
is coming in right now.
- Who?
- Fucking Nascimento. Look.
The Governor needed a scapegoat.
He put Beirada's death on me.
But for the public, my friend,
a good thug is a dead thug.
Well done.
Go talk to him.
Go hug him.
Colonel! Welcome.
What a pleasant surprise.
Welcome.
Now I'd like to ask for a
little of your attention...
gentlemen,
and your attention ladies.
Queixada, close in.
Open up, Imperador.
Governor of this wonderful
state...
of Rio de Janeiro,
pay attention.
Do you know what this is, Governor?
Big steps.
It's what's happening
to our city...
which is taking big steps
toward barbarism.
Governor, do not discharge
Colonel Nascimento of duty.
Because if you do,
it'll stink.
Stink with a capital S.
Because you would be giving
the green light...
for them to return to the streets,
prowl the bars...
the plazas, the schools, offering
drugs to our sons...
to our daughters.
Governor, you would
be turning our city...
into an enormous pool of blood.
Is this what you want?
To transform our city...
into an enormous pool of blood?
No!
Don't do that.
Do this right now.
Close in, Queixada.
Close in, Imperador.
"Dagger in the Skull"...
and strike these thugs.
Release the steel.
Finger on the trigger.
The man's show has a
a rating of almost 30 points.
They get tons of letters
from the audience.
- The tide will turn, Governor.
- Now I'm a fan...
I know what I'm doing.
- of Colonel Nascimento...
- Nascimento is out of BOPE.
my wife is a fan,
even my dog Diana...
is a fan of
Colonel Nascimento.
Don't transform our city
into a pool of blood.
Combat trafficking now.
And that's how Fraga toppled
me from the command of BOPE.
Only, I didn't fall down,
my friend.
- I fell up.
- Good morning, Mr. Subsecretary.
I'm Valmir Magalhes,
coordinator here of SSI.
The Secretary asked me to
welcome you. Please.
If voters were saying
that I was a hero...
who was the Governor
to say otherwise?
Renata, please send me
the report.
If you'll be so kind...
in a while, we'll need to
record your fingerprints.
The first day I was almost lost.
- Hell, I never had a computer before.
- The room.
How could I be
Subsecretary of Intelligence?
How could I be responsible...
for all the wiretaps of
Rio de Janeiro?
- This is all wiretapping?
- That's Monitoring.
You can see we have
cameras there...
we have access to all
the cameras in the city.
This is the Watchdog,
where we log...
all phone interceptions.
It would be difficult...
but I had landed where
no Skull had ever been.
In the Secretariat of Security,
I wouldn't be fighting only drugs.
I'd be able to fight the system.
Commander, this Skull
will fuck up our scheme...
in our unit, goddamn it.
Put him in an operation,
let him take a shot...
friendly fire and done...
- bury him with military honors.
- Captain.
You have been very well
commended in this battalion...
but I'm in command,
goddamn it.
You're gonna fuck up
our scheme.
- Fuck our scheme.
- This is fucked.
- What, Mrio?
What the fuck is "this"?
I'm telling you. We can't lay
a finger on a Skull, goddamn it.
It's an order. He's my friend.
He saved my life one time.
I'll put him in a corner
out of the way.
Forget this fucking shit.
Fuck up my battalion here.
Tell the Captain to enter.
Then it's on you, ok, Commander.
It seemed all was going
to end well.
But things were beginning
to crumble.
The Governor, who wasn't
an idiot at all...
decided to please the left.
Someone had to pay for the blood
on the shirt of human rights.
Permission to present myself,
Colonel.
What a pleasure, trainee.
The mere thought of Matias
wearing that blue uniform...
gave me hives.
Mr. Secretary, I'd like
if you could intercede...
with the Governor
in relation to the situation...
of Captain Andr Matias.
It's not fair for him
to be in that unit.
Matias is one of the best
cops we have.
It's not right for him to be there,
it's not correct, it's not fair.
I was in command of the
operation at Bangu, Mr. Secretary.
I'd like you to take this...
as a personal request from me.
Well, Colonel, I think your
position is commendable.
I think your request is fair.
I will speak to the Governor,
touch on this subject.
I'm sure he will understand.
Matias, I knew that Nascimento
was an asshole, partner.
He thinks he's got the biggest cock.
But betrayal, I didn't expect that.
That's bullshit.
The guy there in the government
and you expelled from BOPE?
- Son of a bitch.
- Fbio, don't meddle in this shit...
- It's not your business.
- What's wrong?
- Don't meddle.
- Relax, Matias.
Stay out of this.
I'll make you relax.
I'll put you where you can relax.
Trust me! You're going
to relax big time, partner.
- This is where you'll be.
- Fucking hell, Fbio.
Central Archives. It's important!
Organize this shit for me, ok?
I tried to help Matias, but
he couldn't stand the humiliation.
He called Clara Vidal, the most
controversial journalist in the city...
May I record what you're saying?
You may. I'll repeat.
...and let the shit hit the fan.
It's cowardly for the Governor...
to blame me for the prison deaths.
BOPE has been abandoned
for long time.
Cops go into the streets to
kill thugs every day.
I can't accept this cowardice.
Especially from a government
that only thinks about politics...
and only thinks of themselves.
The Governor was furious
and Matias was completely fucked.
On top of being in a unit
of corrupt cops...
he got 30 days in jail.
May I come in?
How can I get you
out of here, Andr?
"BOPE Officer
Blames Governor"
What are you trying to
accomplish by stirring shit up?
- I don't get it.
- Stirring shit, Colonel?
You mean, telling the truth,
defending the Battalion...
is stirring shit up?
Watch your tone with me.
- I was telling the truth.
- Show respect!
Watch your tone with me.
Don't talk to me about
defending the Battalion.
You defend the Battalion
doing what I taught you.
Not giving interviews
to papers.
You're in jail, Andr.
You'll defend what from here?
You're in jail, old friend.
If there's anyone here...
here in this room who can
defend the Battalion...
excuse me, but it's not you.
I can defend the Battalion
from the SSI.
- I can do...
- Colonel...
for the unit what no one
has ever done for the unit.
- Colonel...
- I can.
Colonel, with all due respect,
these sons of bitches
that you're mingling with...
only care about politics.
The only thing that'll change
with you inside the Secretariat...
is yourself.
Unless you've already changed, huh?
- Good evening. How are you?
- Good evening.
To make things worse, Fraga
turned his 15 minutes of fame...
into a candidacy
for state representative.
...campaign proposals...
what I'd like you...
Of course, all the intellectuals
on the left...
and all the potheads
would vote for him.
Hi, how are you? Some
proposals from my campaign.
I don't want you
stuck in front of him.
I want you circling.
Circling.
Don't stop in front of him.
This armchair Che Guevara
already pissed me off...
as NGO head,
imagine what he'd do...
if he held public office.
It would be fucked up.
And my family would be
caught in the crossfire.
Grab the kimono with
both hands, Rafa!
The kimono with both hands, Rafa!
I won't deny it,
I like fighting.
For me, only those who can
fight can live in peace.
I only wanted to teach
this to my son...
without worrying about
the opinion of others.
Come on, Rafa. Come on, come on!
Sit up! Good, good, good.
Good, Rafa. Good, Rafa.
Good. Good.
Watch the sweep,
the sweep.
All good. All good.
You know the only thing
I didn't like?
Your hand loose.
You have to grab here...
Both hands on the kimono,
No hand loose.
- I didn't want to fight.
- Didn't want to fight?
You pestered me all month
long to come fight.
Why didn't you want
to fight, son?
We're here, let's fight
to win now.
We won't lose.
Fight to win.
I'm not like you,
beating people up.
How are you?
Have you calmed down?
Beto, the problem isn't what
Rafa does or doesn't hear.
It's what you do.
The man tells my son
I'm a murderer...
- and the problem is what I do?
- He didn't.
He spoke on TV
and Rafa heard.
Ah, right. On TV, he can?
On TV, it's ok?
Did he lie?
I'm a cop, Rosane.
I'm not, I'm not...
A coffee.
I'm not gonna argue
this with you.
A coffee, please.
I'm not gonna argue with
you either...
the definition of murderer.
I just won't hide the
truth from my son.
If you don't want
to lose Rafa...
- That's what you think?
- speak to...
That's what you think I am, now?
Doesn't matter what I think.
If you want to be
close with Rafa...
you'll have to tell him the truth.
I won't lie to my son.
You'll have to find
a way to explain to him...
what you do for a living, Beto.
Battalion. Attention!
Battalion. At ease!
My son was afraid of me...
...Rosane considered me
a fascist...
...Matias considered me
a traitor.
I should have been
depressed, my friend.
But I wasn't.
My mission was more important...
than my personal problems.
Gentlemen, BOPE is a
fundamental part...
of our mandate of
public security.
I have total confidence
in your abilities.
- Together always.
- Skulls!
I dove into my work, my friend.
I exorcized my demons...
in Rio's Secretariat of
Public Security
Skulls!
Go and defeat.
Know no defeat.
- Special Ops!
- Bravo, well done.
Bravo!
I did what I told Matias I'd do.
I turned BOPE
into a war machine.
With me in the Secretariat
of Security...
BOPE got up to 390 officers...
and 16 tactical teams.
Before, we had 8 cars.
Now, we had armored cars
and a helicopter.
For some, war is cure.
War acts as an escape valve.
When pressure mounts at home,
vent it on the streets.
With me, it was always like that.
There! Hit there.
Pinheiro, can you hear me?
Concentrate fire at the top,
they're gonna come down.
Look there. Keep it there.
Let's go!
You can go in, Pinheiro.
Send everyone up.
Do you copy, Pinheiro?
After I arrived at the
Secretariat of Security...
the thugs no longer had peace.
The war machine I helped set up...
busted trafficking in Rio.
It was only a matter of time.
With trafficking out of the game,
the corruption spree would end.
Finally, I would fuck up the system.
In theory, my plan had
everything to succeed.
The less pot and cocaine consumed...
the less return from trafficking.
Hey, Marcinho, what you got
for us, son?
Hey listen. We ain't got
nothing for you.
Ah, don't give me that, Marcinho.
I came here, bro, you
gotta lay some eggs.
...your buddies killed...
If the dealers broke,
the dirty cops would break too.
Sup, buddy?
We're choking, can't
sell nothing, Rocha.
Marcinho.
Come on, buddy,
let go the loot, son.
Listen, we only got
500 bones from cable TV.
You make me come up here
for 500 fucking bones?
- Beat it, son.
- Shut up, pothead.
- Go fuck yourself.
- Go fuck yourself, bro.
Come on, Rocha.
Give my hood a break, man.
Don't sweat.
When the scratch is light,
my friend, the love is gone.
Let's go, Santos.
Check it out, Gonalves.
Yay, there's already 20 here.
Check the wallet, check
his backpack too.
Take the watch. Good.
Leave them there.
Without their cut from drugs, the
crooks wouldn't get along anymore.
Damn, took Marcinho out?
You want to fuck me.
30 per week? What is that?
Wanna fuck the unit over?
Wanna fuck me out of my command?
Colonel, every dog licks
his own dick.
And another thing...
Who said you're in command?
- Commander, your subordinate...
- Fbio!
...challenging me,
disrespecting me...
- ordering around...
- Easy, Fbio.
I'll hold him 30 days,
then run him over.
Captain Rocha is key
to the administration.
But he's demoralizing me.
I have to satisfy
a lot of interests, Fbio.
I'm in command, Formoso!
Colonel, what do you want?
You want another post?
You want to switch unit?
I'll switch you.
But you'll be fucked, ok.
A suggestion.
You won the lottery, Fbio.
Don't throw it away.
With all due respect,
listen to me.
Dismissed, Colonel Fbio.
And I was gonna kill two birds
with one stone.
Son of a bitch.
That would have been the
first step in the clean-up...
of the Military Police of Rio.
Except, in practice,
everything went wrong.
The guys are coming up there.
These guys, fuck.
What, faggot?
Don't start with that.
What actually happened was
not what I had planned
What you got for us, son?
Here's the deal, bro.
I only have 500 Reals to
give you, Rocha.
Where's this dough coming from
if you can't sell?
- You're selling your ass now?
- Fuck that!
That shit's from cable TV,
Rocha.
That shit ain't from drugs, bro.
From cable TV?
Talk to me!
This shit here, each resident's
gotta give us 12 Reals.
Got it? That's nothing.
Just so that each resident
can have a TV at home.
Yep, nothing like an economic
crisis to trigger innovation.
It only took the loss of drug bribes
for the crooked cops...
to see the obvious.
Each poor neighborhood in Rio...
is much more than
a place to sell drugs.
Come on, Rocha.
Give my hood a break, man.
Don't sweat.
Who said this is your hood?
Rocha realized,
by eliminating the middleman...
the system grossed more.
It was obvious.
It was simple math.
Hey, Irineu? Selling
many subscriptions?
Hey, boss. Soon, there
won't be enough poles!
No. We'll arrange poles.
Just continue.
Slum folks like cable TV.
Hey, Valdir.
Slum folks drink water.
Slum folks get online.
People connecting?
...Damn!
Everyone's plugged in!
Here, Santos.
Slum folks cook with gas.
Pops, I'm confiscating this.
I'm gonna leave it there.
You'll go down the slope,
take the first left.
Go to Danilo Baiano, there
you'll buy gas.
Hurry, it's closing.
- Slum folks take out loans.
- Go, pops!
We're not like just any
bankers, Mrs. Severina.
We're fair. But here,
you have to pay.
- I know.
- You have to pay.
Aranha, I'm outta here, ok.
I zeroed the register.
- No worries.
- Ready?
I just need your name...
Every slum is
a huge market...
of purchases and sales.
Rocha figured out it was better
to tax the whole slum...
than a bunch of fucked-up
drug dealers.
Each time money changed hands,
Rocha took a tax.
The crooks' own Robin Hood tax.
Motherfuckers robbin' the hood.
Pretext? To defend the
hood from trafficking.
The truth was quite different.
This fucking van doesn't
make much, dude.
Barely enough for one, man.
How can I split with you, Rocha?
You won't split?
I'll give you a break.
It's 90% for us and
10% for you, ok?
What? Are you crazy, dude?
I have a family to feed.
10% ain't enough for anyone!
Marreco, take over this shit.
Beat this bitch,
Marreco, fuck him up!
- Bring him here.
- Fuck him up!
Leave him to me.
You don't wanna pay the tax,
huh, bitch?!
Good.
My turn.
- Let's take a walk!
- Let's take a walk, yeah. Yeah!
Santos, Santos.
Shake him well to jiggle his head.
You gotta pay the tax, kid.
Fuck him up.
Whereas Fbio pulled in
30,000 every month...
Rocha pulled in 300,000,
tax-free.
In 4 years, the system
took over almost all...
the West Side of Rio.
In the past, we invaded and
the dealers came back.
But when the dirty cops
started occupying the slums...
the dealers didn't come back.
For a while, I thought the
system was helping BOPE.
But really, it was BOPE
helping the system.
Yeah, I helped create the monster
that was going to devour me.
(Present time)
What's worse is that only
one person realized this...
Representative Diogo Fraga.
You know what I found
about homicides...
in the areas of the militia?
Many witnesses started dying.
It was Rocha's gang.
They killed my brother.
More than 20 shots,
in front of everyone.
And before dying, these same
witnesses gave new statements.
- Then who was it?
- Who it was, I don't know, ma'am.
I know who didn't do it.
It wasn't Rocha.
You can put that down.
Wherever there's militia,
there's profit and death...
fostered by public agents
in charge of security.
In practice, the militia is the
mafia.
You pay them to protect
you from them.
With the growth of militias...
Fraga found another cause...
in the name of human rights.
And like all good politicians,
he exploited it to the fullest.
Because, on top of the violence
that you can see here...
they talk as if they're legitimate.
Of protection, of self-defense
against trafficking...
but, in reality, they want control.
Damn! That's a lot of bullets,
huh, Fraga.
Yeah. What we're dealing with
is the mafia, Mr. President.
Because that's what it is.
The militia is the mafia.
True organized crime.
Permission to speak,
Representative, President.
You may speak,
Representative.
Fraga, for the love of God.
You're talking about the mafia,
son? Nonsense.
The mafia are Italians who
love pasta, rondelli, gnocchi.
- Rep. Fortunato, I...
- We love rice and beans.
I'm a huge fan of your sense
of humor, you know that.
But I think it fits better
on your show.
In Italy there's no trafficking,
you know that.
- No trafficking?!
- This is hood self-protection.
Yes, but folks are dying
in these hoods.
- Hood self-protection.
- Self-protection?
That's what you call it?
Pay them to protect from them.
- Go there, see if...
- I go there!
You have any idea
how many people...
die in these neighborhoods?
- They're protecting themselves.
- Any idea?
- Decorum! Decorum, please!
- Forgive me, Mr. President.
Listen. Let me tell you
something, Fraga.
We're in an election year.
Everyone's in campaign mode.
- You have your own campaign.
- Election year?
It's like any other year for me.
- What! Don't say that.
- You know very well that...
a CPI inquiry in an election year...
- turns into campaigning.
- No, Mr. President...
I just think that this matter
is more important...
than whatever election year.
That's my position.
Look, Fraga, I'm not saying
you're wrong...
nor that he's right.
What I'm saying is this:
in an election year...
I will not accept your CPI.
Clear your head,
think about something else...
Fraga's strategy was to fight
the government head-on.
He loved provoking us to
see what came out in the media.
Fraga wanted to be a federal
representative...
and a CPI would be his
ticket to the capital, Brasilia.
But 4 years later,
everyone still believed...
that my plan had worked.
Guaracy was cashing in from
my blows on trafficking.
Good morning, Mr. Governor.
Good morning.
It was so successful...
that he ditched the
Secretariat of Security...
and left to be a federal
congressman.
- How are you? Good?
- I already went ahead.
The Governor in the center,
please.
Vermont, I'm not convinced
about this tie. Yellow?
- It's great!
- Gold.
- Yellow's nice, Governor.
- It's nice.
Even the Governor was
reaping the fruits of my labor.
His reelection was guaranteed.
The problem was, the more
votes Guaracy won...
the more Fraga criticized me.
And the more he criticized me...
the more my son distanced
himself from me.
Rafael, if you want a ride,
I'm leaving.
Ok.
This is for Fraga.
- Fraga.
- Thanks, kid.
Julia is leaving now.
Can I go with her?
- Of course. You can go.
- Thanks.
Thanks for today.
Ready to go?
Let's go.
Yeah, my friend, just when
things couldn't get worse.
After Fraga became state
representative...
I couldn't even look
him in the face.
Here it is, Representative.
She just needs to sign this
document...
appear in court and that's all.
Understood. Here, Julia.
Read carefully,
don't rush, then sign.
- Barata, how's it going?
- Colonel, how are you?
- Good.
- What happened here?
- Nothing, it's all resolved.
- Can I see the statement?
- Of course.
- Beto...?
I was going to tell you.
Can I read?
He's my son.
Rafa had nothing to do with this.
Can we remain civil?
Tell him not to talk to me.
Calm down, calm down.
100 grams, Barata?
You were buying for the
entire office, miss?
A moral lecture, now?
Barata, look,
my son is 16.
Nowadays, that's
corruption of minors.
And 100 grams, nowadays,
that's drug trafficking.
Beto, stop it.
I said, don't talk to me.
- Folks, please.
- I told you...
to shut your mouth and
not speak to me.
- Shut your mouth!
- Dad!
The pot was mine.
You can put that down, sir,
the pot was mine.
His father is right.
100 grams of pot
is no joke.
Hey, you shouldn't have
taken the blame.
Yeah? And let her get arrested?
Because of your argument?
That has nothing to do
with it, Rafael.
By the way, you
have to fire her.
Why would I fire her?
For exposing Rafa.
She took responsibility,
didn't she?
Rafa is right. If there's
a problem here...
it's not her.
Ok, if you don't...
Rafa won't work there
anymore.
That's what he wants.
Exactly what he wants.
He wants us to fight,
to push Rafa rom me.
That's exactly it.
You think this was normal?
No, not normal, Rosane.
Just like it wasn't normal
how he acted.
He was deciding the kid's life.
He didn't decide. He arrived
at the station...
and his son was there with
100 grams of pot.
Right in front of us.
He wants what's best
for his son.
At no time did he ask us...
I'm tired.
I lost my appetite.
You're acting just like my father.
Of course, I didn't want
to hear what Fraga...
was saying about the militias.
It was hard separating things.
That's why I couldn't see
what was happening...
in Rio.
The system was changing, evolving.
Before, politicians used
the system to make money.
Now they depended on the
system to get elected.
You understand?
The sports center is
already open...
the kids are playing sports.
The renovation of the
public square...
is on its way,
trash collection...
You know you have our support.
The Governor is here
so I can't lie.
You can be sure that
one of our priorities...
- is the support of the community.
- Governor, speechless.
Sincerely. Just a moment.
Just a moment.
Just a moment, godfather.
Paquito, take a picture,
Paquito, damn it.
You're too slow.
Relax, folks, today
it's in celebration.
It's in celebration.
I'd like to thank you all in
the community for being here.
We're very happy for you.
But I coudn't begin this
without honoring..
3 people very important to us.
First, the honorable
Governor Gelino...
up for reelection.
Thank you, Governor.
You will be reelected here
by the community.
You can count on that.
Thank you, Governor.
I'd also like to note
the presence of...
the Secretary of Public Security
in Rio, Guaracy.
Thank you, Guaracy.
Guaracy who is now a fed.
Thanks to us as well.
And our eternal godfather,
Representative Fortunato.
Thank you, Representative.
- I'm your fan.
- We're with you.
- Thank you, thank you.
A blessing.
Today is a celebration
of 4 years...
of our Community Center
of Rio das Rochas!
It's all ours!
Let's do some samba now
and tear this shit up.
Waddup. Yeah, baby.
Beautiful.
Oh, lovely.
"A new leader is born
in the hills of the flagpole."
Remember what I told you before?
In the slums, cash flows,
deals are closed...
and the system levies a tax?
Well, yeah, but I skipped
one thing, my friend.
In Brazil, elections are business...
and votes are the most valuable
commodity in the slums.
Didn't take long for Guaracy,
Fortunato, and Gelino...
to realize the militia expanded
the Governor's constituency.
The more slums the militia controlled,
the more votes they got.
Hey, Fbio? You like the boat?
Fuck, you gotta appreciate
me more, Rocha.
- I'm at the front lines.
- Shit, you got balls.
You're already bitching?
Hey, Santos.
- Why you bitching?
- Shit, Fbio, listen...
I didn't bring you here for this.
Here's the deal.
We're taking the whole West Side,
Tanque will be ours.
You're gonna help me.
Fuck, bro, that's
gonna be a bitch.
There's more guns there
than in my unit.
- Just a moment.
- Fbio, take it easy, man.
Something's happening right now
that'll change our lives.
(Police Station, Tanque area)
Go, go!
Come on!
- Don't fuck with me!
- Why you looking at me?
- On the ground.
- Let's go.
- Come on!
- Come on, goddamn it.
- Game over.
- I'm gonna fuck you up!
- Face the wall.
- Wait!
Easy, easy!
Don't fuck around, so no one
gets hurt, all right?
- Are you the Chief?
- Yes, sir.
The key for the reserve arsenal!
- Take it easy.
- The fucking key quickly!
Face on the fucking floor.
Here, the rifles are here.
Hello. Yeah, Sem Alma.
Good, son, good.
Scratch them but
don't bury them, ok.
Don't bury them, we'll need them.
Thanks. Speak, Fbio.
What's your question?
- Something I don't understand.
- Speak, damn it.
We wanted the Skull
out of the way.
We did, but not anymore.
- Why not?
- To take Tanque...
who am I gonna entrust?
The crooks in your battalion?
Are you fucking kidding me?
He's such a joker, isn't he?
Romance your woman,
Fbio.
- Shit, relax.
- Shit, I'm annoyed.
Militiamen are primitive
but not stupid.
You love me.
Tanque was the last stronghold
of trafficking on the West Side.
Let's go, Mariguela.
Ready?
Lots of money there
and lots of votes.
But lots of guns too.
Let's record, ok. Roll VT.
Rolling, 4, 3...
The militia could never take
Tanque alone.
What's happening to
our city Rio de Janeiro?
our wonderful city?
Thugs come into a police
station and steal weapons.
Weapons from inside
a police station!
This isn't crime, no sir.
This is terrorism!
Don't talk to me
about human rights...
because terrorists,
to me, aren't people.
It's because of "blah, blah,
blah, human rights".
Can't touch the thugs
Don't touch the thugs.
Give candy to the thugs.
Send roses to the thugs.
This is a circus, man.
Here, close in on me, Imperador.
Governor...
you know what this is?
This is a little dance.
This is what will happen
to your administration.
Your administration will dance
if you don't respond...
because these thugs
will take these guns...
to take on your government.
We can't let that happen.
What is this, people?
What is this?
They want to fight
the administration...
that best cleaned up this city...
of narcotics trafficking.
Governor...
Destroy them!
Secretary, I have to admit that
this asshole can speak.
I agree, Governor...
- I'm talking to Guaracy.
- He's right.
If we play weak now,
we'll lose votes.
We have to strike...
to guarantee these elections.
Listen, bystanders could
end up dead...
- with this kind of operation.
- Excuse me.
Governor, the campaign
materials are in.
I decide these things, Formoso.
Sure.
Let's go see the campaign
materials.
- Goddamn, I don't believe it.
- You like it?
- Vermont...
- It's very good.
- Very good.
- You've outdone yourself.
- Great, isn't it?
- Don't you think?
It looks like shit.
Look at this gold tie.
I told you it wouldn't work.
It won't connect with the
public. It's not popular.
Look at Fortunato's tooth,
that broken tooth.
This speaks to the people,
you understand?
All the campaign material
must be redone, ok?
- Redo it?
- Do it.
Governor, we already owe
a ton of suppliers.
You owe? Pay with this.
You can't vote for an administration
that can't even protect a station.
Either the Governor would respond
or the press would eat him alive.
How many? You remember?
And that's what the militia
was betting on.
...or 8.
7 or 8.
And they assaulted you?
They came in here,
beat everyone.
They cleaned everything out.
Could you identify any
dealer from the area?
Turn that off.
It's off.
What I'm about to tell you,
you didn't hear from me, ok?
They weren't dealers at all.
They came in with combat boots...
Show us where the
reserve arsenal is.
They referred to the
"reserve arsenal".
That's not the
vocabulary of dealers.
Cops? So it was the militia.
He said that?
That it was the militia?
No, he didn't say that.
Because he was afraid
to say anything.
But think about it,
the guy's Chief of Police...
he heard them speak.
He understands, right?
The language.
Sure. Of course.
Yeah, it's possible.
It's very possible, in fact.
You know what I think
about the militia?
I know. That's why
I came straight here.
- Rafa! Do me a favor?
- Yeah?
Bring a complete copy of
the file on the militias...
to give to Clara, please.
- Ok.
- Thanks.
- You're giving me the militia file?
- This is very serious, Clara.
- I know.
- What we're talking about...
is the worst problem in Rio.
It's the mafia.
Thanks, Rafa.
I have no doubt that the
militia is involved.
You have no idea what the
militia is capable of.
Look, this is the file with
the main clues on all...
we've been talking about.
If you help me expose this...
I'll serve the CPI.
Take it, read it with care.
I'll read it and speak to my
editor, all right?
- Excuse me, Colonel.
- Close the door.
Yes, sir?
The Governor wants to
take Tanque.
- I know.
- A massive operation.
He thinks the weapons are there.
- Are you getting feeds from there?
- Yes, I am.
So mobilize everyone,
I want to hear everything, ok?
- Got it.
- We have little time.
That's right.
The militia was so sure...
that the government would
rid Tanque of the dealers...
that they were already recruiting
people to keep them out.
And to scare dealers, my friend...
nothing better than the Skulls.
Ah, he's here.
Sup, Fbio.
Hey, buddy.
Sup, Rocha.
Sup, Matias. How you doing, man?
A beer, please.
Good?
- Cool, mate?
- What do you want with me?
What I want is simplicity.
Look at the neighborhood, partner.
Just look.
A mother can walk with
her son peacefully.
The vans are working.
Look at the MP there.
No one has to hide their wallet
to go to work anymore.
It's not like before.
It was a fucking mess, partner.
And there's no more theft.
The slum is damn good to live in.
- What's that got to do with me?
- Shit, Matias.
I learned that the police will do
a massive operation in Tanque.
If the MP invades, it'll
be easy for us to occupy it.
And I don't know anyone
better than you to...
- manage this here.
- Me?
Fucking Skulls, man.
Someone the thugs fear.
Aren't you a Skull?
You'll understand what I'm saying.
Godfather, can you hear me?
- Talk to me.
- Godfather, listen.
What can we do to return
a friend to BOPE?
- Help him out.
- Is he solid? Can I trust him?
More than solid, godfather. 100%.
The best Skull we got.
He's going to help us with the project.
Get his ID and tell him
to show up Monday.
So, Matias? You going
back to BOPE or what?
Hey, boss...
No one got that shit
and they're already calling...
No one wants to show
these guns.
Poke Moleira coz this shit's
about to get hot.
I already talked to Moleira,
he thought it was you too.
He said to stay alert coz the
cops are pissed.
I joined this meeting
to say that the taps...
proved that the dealers
didn't know shit...
- about stolen arms.
- Secretary.
- Good afternoon.
- I know what to do.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Nascimento.
But when I came in,
I couldn't utter a word.
I was reviewing the intel.
Secretary, our opinion remains
the same...
there is no reason
to justify an invasion.
Subsecretary, the Governor
gave the order to invade.
And we have reliable info
from Colonel Fbio's informant...
- Right, Colonel?
- Affirmative.
That the arms are there.
Plus I think the dealers...
are deceiving you on the phone.
Secretary, excuse me,
with all due respect...
but I have 300 hours
of phone recordings here.
That's 300 hours of recording
against the word of one informant...
that only Colonel Fbio knows.
Secretary, with all due respect,
my informant is reliable.
Colonel, can you tell us
the name of your informant?
- Nascimento!
- My informant is reliable.
Can you tell us...
- who your informant is.
- Nascimento!
This operation is wrong,
Formoso.
The arms aren't there.
This operation is wrong.
Secretary, if the intel is correct...
then there's no reason to invade.
Let me consult with the Governor,
just a minute.
Telephone for Dr. Guaracy.
Come in.
- Telefone, sir.
- Thank you.
Hello?
Formoso, I won't
speak to the Governor.
He's for invasion. Invade
that shit and pronto.
Right.
The Governor ordered us
to proceed.
We're invading.
Excuse me.
Valmir, take this to the car
for me.
Can I speak to you for a minute?
- What, sir?
- I want to know...
how you got back into BOPE.
If you don't know...
then, clearly, it wasn't
you who helped me, sir.
Permission to leave?
Permission granted, Andr.
The cops in Tanque were
so corrupt that not even I...
could get rid of the thugs there.
To take Tanque, only a massive
operation would do.
Check out those guys.
But the Governor didn't want that.
In an election year, there
could be no dead bystanders.
And that's when Matias
had a genius idea...
but dangerous as hell.
He entered Tanque in broad
daylight and rolled in slowly...
right in front of the thugs.
Zero One, check that guy, there.
Hey, what's up.
There were guns everywhere.
If anyone suspected a thing,
Matias was fucked.
But Matias was disguised as
a dirty cop...
and the thugs thought
they were among friends.
- All good, partner?
- All good.
You can go.
Ok, thanks. Good job, guys.
Quiet?
Boco, Moraes, do the rounds
below for me?
Going.
The team spent the night
in the outpost...
at a strategic point in the slum
waiting for daybreak.
Waiting for us to invade.
Shoot them!
Go, go, go!
Go, go, goddamn it!
Whenever we tried
to invade Tanque...
Felpa's gang escaped
the same way.
The MPs would land...
the thugs would jet.
Go! Hurry the fuck up!
The armored car followed
as far as possible.
When the convoy hit
Felpa's alleys, he resisted.
He held everyone up until
his posse spilled toward the outpost.
The MPs there wouldn't
even see the punks pass.
It was a game with marked cards.
But that day, my friend...
it wasn't the paid-off MPs
that were at the outpost.
It was the Skulls.
- Going for it, Zero One.
- Wait.
- Going for it.
Fire!
Die, you fucks!
- Go, go!
- Die.
Go, let's go.
Let's go!
Attention, Boco!
Let's check the weapons.
One by one the dealers
of Tanque would die.
The whole West Side would be
in the hands of Rocha...
and join the constituency
of the administration.
Zero One, I think that's all.
Call the Colonel?
- Call him.
- Show the weapons, Boco!
Ask him to show the weapons,
Valmir.
Hey, Zero One, show them.
- Hey, Azevedo?
- Those aren't the arms.
Those aren't from the station.
- Are you recording this, Valmir?
- Yes, sir.
You know what this operation
should be called?
- No, sir.
- Operation Iraq.
The strategy of the system
was well thought-out.
The drug lord of Tanque
could even escape...
but he'd never have
the courage to return.
Check the punk there.
The punk! Felpa.
It's Felpa.
Let BOPE take him out, Fbio.
- Tatu! Boco!
- What?
- There!
- Where'd he go, Zero One?
- There, in the alley.
- There.
Didn't I tell you BOPE
would go get him. There.
Move! Fucking move!
Give up!
I give up. I give up, fuck!
Just one problem.
Rocha called for Matias
to work with him.
- I surrender.
- Tie him up, Boco.
And I'm the one who trained
Matias, my friend.
He wouldn't stop until
he had found those arms.
- It wouldn't be pretty.
- You're the boss?
I am.
So here's what you'll do...
you'll tell me now where
the police weapons are.
What police weapons?
Dunno shit about no weapons, man.
- You don't, huh?
- Dunno shit about no weapons.
- Where are the guns?
- Dunno about guns.
- I'm telling you!
- Where are the guns?
What guns? I dunno!
Let's work it out...
- I dunno about no guns!
- Listen, punk.
This ain't a negotiation.
I want to know where
the fuck those guns are!
- I dunno about no fucking guns!
- Talk!
- I dunno
- Talk, you fuck.
- Fucking talk.
- I don't fucking know.
I don't fucking know!
Let's work him over,
Zero One.
Put him in the bag.
Fuck, this is taking forever.
Let's check this shit out.
Come on, Nunes.
Marreco, come.
- Check it out?
- Take over, Gonalves.
Let's go.
He's fucked up, Zero One.
He doesn't know anything.
Look at me, cocksucker.
You're gonna tell me...
where the police weapons are
right now, got it?
- I don't got 'em.
- You don't got 'em, huh?
You got 'em. Tell me now
where they are!
Talk, motherfucker.
I don't got 'em. I don't...
- Don't want to cooperate?
- I already told you...
- I don't got 'em...
Put him in the bag again,
Boco.
What the fuck, Rocha?
Are you fucking nuts?
He was the boss!
He was gonna give me the arms!
Well done. Excellent work by
BOPE, Captain.
That's who we were after.
Right, Commander?
- What's going on, Fbio?
- Sad for the thug, Matias?
Boco! Tatu! Take the boss down...
so I can have a litle chat
with Fbio.
What the fuck, Colonel?
What's going on?
I smell bullshit.
- Who's the informant?
- I'll find out and let you know.
Who's X9?
Here's what you'll do,
you'll call me...
later, you'll give me
the name and number of X9.
And I want this today!
Understood, Major?
Stop! What the fuck, Russo?
What the fuck, Marreco?
What the fuck?
You fucking killed him!
Fuck, didn't you want
him out of the way?
He's out of the way.
What you want?
You're gonna light a candle
for this fucking Skull?
Marreco, mark 15 minutes...
inform the superior of this shit...
say the bullet came from
who the fuck knows.
And say that me and
Commander Fbio...
were not on location.
Right, Fbio?
Let's go, Fbio.
Let's get the fuck out.
Let's go, Fbio!
You won't investigate
his death, Secretary?
We're waiting on
Ballistics, Colonel.
The ballistics are this,
Formoso:...
Andr died from a bullet
in the back...
far from his squad,
and the arms weren't there.
Nascimento, I understand your pain...
I know this is difficult...
but you must understand
the public supported the operation.
11 dealers dead and
15 weapons seized.
Major Matias was a casualty.
Could have been anyone.
Matias wasn't just anyone.
Salute.
Fire!
Attention!
Colonel Fbio? Can I speak
with you for a minute?
Colonel. A terrible loss
to our organization.
My condolences.
Excuse me.
I will investigate his death.
And I will find out what
happened to Andr, Fbio.
If you know something,
you'd better tell me now.
Nascimento, Andr was
also my friend.
And I believe in my men.
If you find out anything,
let me know.
This is gonna go to shit.
- Go to shit, why?
- Because it will.
What did you want me to do?
The guy gets in my face and...
- I just stand there?
- So what?
And Nascimento's on my ass.
- Who's on your ass.
- Nascimento!
Fuck Nascimento.
- Kojak, coffee, please.
- Water for me.
- Hey, Nunes?
- Major. Commander.
Listen, buddy.
Nascimento doesn't have
anything on us.
And another thing, partner.
If I'm in deep shit,
you're in deep shit.
You should remember that.
And you should know that
now everything's 50-50.
50-50, no fucking way, Fbio.
Fucking way.
The "I know" tax, Rocha.
The what tax?
Are you out of your mind?
You forgot?
If you wanna giggle,
you gotta tickle.
Motherfucker.
Kojak, hold that shit.
- I'm off, Nunes.
- It's all on his tab now, Kojak.
- Ok, commander.
- Nunes, how's everything?
Like an ocean, boss.
Salty, ain't it?
Took me a long time to realize
my work in the government...
had nothing to do with
public security.
Valmir, we're not going to
renew the requests...
for the wiretaps of the
operation in the Tanque.
Excuse me.
Colonel Nascimento said...
That's all, Valmir. Thank you.
It was all a stategy to get votes.
To them, Matias' death
meant nothing.
In the media, the operation
had been a success.
That was all that mattered.
You called Rafa?
- No.
- What is it, Beto?
- What happened?
- They killed Andr.
I heard.
Are you taking care of yourself?
I don't know what's happening.
I'm going to find out.
We haven't been talking...
for some time.
- Beto...
- He was right.
- Andr was right.
- Beto, I want to know about Rafa.
I'm sorry about Andr...
but I want you to call your son.
You're alienating yourself,
Beto.
Don't do this to your son.
He was only protecting
his friend.
You should be proud.
Don't waste time...
don't wait for him to
want to talk to you.
Call Rafa to have a chat.
You're gonna trade your
neck for your arm?
Breathe.
Relax.
Come. Come. Mount.
Get on.
Son!
You think I believed
that weed was yours?
Julia must be pretty hot
for you to take the rap...
for 100 grams of weed
right in front of me, huh?
I'm not afraid of you.
I don't want you to be
afraid of me.
I want you to know
that I'm your father.
I know.
- Do you?
- I do.
- You really know?
- I know.
Wow, I'll even let you grab
my arm again.
Grab it.
You only grab it when I let you.
Wait, wait.
Yes, Valmir.
I know... You know why
this will go on, Valmir?
You know why this will go on?
Because what they want
are votes, Valmir.
I don't want votes, I want
to know who killed Andr.
I appreciate it, then.
I'm with my son,
we'll talk later, ok?
Ok. Thanks.
Thank you.
Your friend died in the operation?
Something to do with the militia
that stole the guns?
Who told you this?
I bet a year's salary that
it was the militia...
who stole the guns and
will invade the slum...
I'll accept it, but only
as an investigative report.
Investigative?
- More than...
- I need deeper.
I need documents,
photos, statements.
Infiltrate. Disguise yourself.
Figure it out.
Camelo, wait.
Give me the cover then.
Bring me the goods, all right?
You'll give me the cover?
Tap the landline now.
Today.
The mobile, put it on
account of some probe.
I want to hear everything
Fraga says...
- to this journalist, got it?
- Colonel...
- he's a representative.
- I take full responsibility.
What time do you get off?
Hey partner, can't hear you
well. Still hissing.
I'll check the signal.
- Ok.
- Beautiful.
Preparing to record.
Recording.
If it were up to Rocha...
the militia would enter
Tanque real slow.
No one would even notice.
Look here, Clara, here.
You see the scratch there?
You see?
- Where? The white bit?
- That's it.
What about it?
I think it's the coat-of-arms
of the police.
They scratched it out
to disguise themselves.
But the election was coming up.
They were pushing...
and Rocha set up camp
in the house of a widow.
- I have to go in somehow.
- Easy, easy, easy.
- I have to go in.
- Easy!
And gas?
Gas got us 8,600.
This here keeps sadness at bay.
A beautiful thing, my friend.
As soon as the media
forgot Tanque...
the militia would probably
microwave her.
Mrs. Olga, first month
in advance.
Her house would become HQ
for the police patrol...
and Rocha would
terrorize the slum.
An almost perfect plan.
Look.
I think they're leaving.
Easy, easy, Clara.
Easy, Clara.
Forget easy. Let's go!
Hide the camera.
Come on.
The photos were already enough
for the cover.
Say that we're a couple
looking for a rental.
But journalists, my friend,
are curious.
Clara wouldn't rest until
she discovered...
what was in that house.
How's this thing here?
Twenty. Aranha, have a ball.
Keep an eye out,
they're fuckers.
When they get more,
it's fucked...
- Hey, godfather.
- Fucking around?
- We did the collection.
- Goddamn it.
I told you not to walk around
with these guns in Tanque.
We went quickly
and came back.
- Who stayed at at the base?
- Who's at the base?
- No one.
- No fucking one?
Didn't I tell you to call...
Are you fucking kidding me?
Shit, Nunes. 20 years
in this shit, huh.
Like I told you,
the price is 700.
Ok, deal.
When a journalist smells a scoop,
get out the way.
It's a bit messy...
but take a look,
and I'll be back, ok?
Ok, thank you.
- It's great.
- Clara sweet-talked the widow...
promised her the world and
the widow was as high as a kite.
Hello. Hi, Mrs. Olga, yes?
No, I'm not gonna pay more
than what we agreed.
What couple, Mrs. Olga?!
- That's how people are...
- Clara...
they only care about themselves.
Check this out.
- Whoa.
- Hello.
Get the camera.
Fraga, it's Clara. Fraga,
I'm in the Tanque neighborhood.
Doing what, Clara?
I found the guys who stole
the guns from the station.
Now I'm certain
it was the militia.
Clara, listen to me.
Get out now, Clara.
These people are very dangerous.
No, it's ok.
It's all ok.
No, I went in the house.
You won't believe this.
I found the Governor's
campaign materials.
There's posters, banners,
everything.
No, it's full of
photos of the Governor
with Fortunato and Guaracy.
Clara, who are you with?
Are you alone?
Calm down...
Who's on the phone, bitch?
- Give me that.
- Take it easy.
- What are you doing here?
- Take it easy...
- Clara? Can you hear me?
Hello? Clara?
- What's wrong?
- Where are the car keys?
- What happened?
- The militia's got Clara.
There's at least 20 years
of jail for us here.
- Oh yeah? You're X9? You're what?
- No.
You scared? You scared?
Motherfucker.
You scared?
Stop it!
Take this bitch to
the living room.
- Get the fuck up.
- Give me the keys.
Let the police take care of it...
The police are exactly
the problem.
Honey, give me the keys.
Call me then, please.
Diogo, for God's sake. Diogo!
Rep. Fraga.
Who else knows you're here?
You want to get a
beating then?
Don't do that, boss.
She's fine.
Let me play with her first.
Finish with her, then, and
then clean up the mess.
No!
- Take off your clothes.
- No.
- Take off your fucking clothes.
- No!
Chief.
Nothing? Well, Representative,
that's it.
Without evidence it's hard,
you know?
No witnesses, nothing.
Look, if we find a body,
any clue...
you'll be the first
to know, ok?
She was telling me
on the phone...
she had found the stolen weapons,
before she was interrupted.
Obviously, she was surprised
by those guys.
You have to publish this, Camelo.
I've got nothing to publish,
I have no proof.
Proof, Camelo?!
The government is our partner.
My hands are tied.
What you have on your hands
is a missing employee.
Obviously, the militia killed Clara
and ditched her body.
What body, Fraga?
She was working for your paper.
All this came with the job.
To be or not to be,
that is the question, partner.
What would be more noble
for the militia?
Kill the vermin that
enter our lives...
or live to enjoy the
buzz of a beer?
Tell me, Gonalves.
Enough with the bullshit!
You're quoting the bible,
now?
Bible? It's a novella,
you dumbfuck.
- Hurry. Pull those teeth out.
- This shit stinks.
But are you sure the
journalist called Fraga?
Guaracy, there's a 3-minute
call here.
You think for a bedtime story?
She opened her trap.
Goddamn it. This is very
serious, huh, Representative.
What are we gonna do?
"We"?
What are YOU gonna do?
Fraga is your problem.
Representative, easy,
Fraga is our problem.
And we take care of
our problems.
Farewell, Guaracy.
I found the guys who stole
the arms from the station.
Now I'm certain
it was the militia.
Clara, listen to me.
Get out now, Clara.
These people are very dangerous.
You won't believe this.
I found the Governor's
campaign commitee.
There's posters, banners,
everything.
No, it's full of
photos of the Governor
with Fortunato and Guaracy.
Clara, who are you with?
Are you alone?
Who's on the phone, bitch?
- Hello? Clara?
- Give me that.
- Take it easy!
- Play the end, Valmir, just the end.
You won't believe this.
I found the Governor's
campaign commitee.
There's posters, banners,
everything.
No, it's full of
photos of the Governor
with Fortunato and Guaracy.
Clara, who are you with?
Are you alone?
- When was this, Valmir?
- 11 p.m.
- Is it in the system?
- Not yet.
It's here, in my recorder.
It's like I got punched
in the face.
In one blow...
I had discovered
it wasn't just the militia...
that was behind the
arms robbery,...
Clara's disappearance,
and Andr's murder.
The militia wouldn't
campaign for the Governor...
and Guaracy for free.
The hole went a lot deeper.
I was surrounded by enemies.
Real enemies.
The Secretariat of Security
was the core of the system.
Public security in the State
of Rio de Janeiro...
was in the hands of crooks.
- And I could trust no one.
- Nascimento.
Perfect, I'll deliver it.
The arms robbery
and Matias' death...
meant nothing for the system.
The system is ruled by politics...
and politics only respects the media.
Only this time, the militia
had killed a journalist.
The system would have to catch up.
- Valmir.
- Secretary.
Valmir, tap this number for me.
This is the phone of Rep. Fraga?
Tap it.
- It was already intercepted.
- How's that?
Colonel Nascimento ordered
its interception.
Fine, give me a copy...
and you can delete the file.
He just took it with him.
The evidence had been microwaved.
There were no witnesses.
It was right in my face.
The system was going to kill Fraga.
And soon.
- Did you like it, son?
- Fraga was next.
Goddamn it, Rosane.
Rosane, it's Roberto again.
I'm on your street...
I'll wait for you at the
door of your building, ok?
When you get this message..
I'll be at your building door,
you'll find me there.
- Your dad called, Rafa?
- Why?
Nothing... just to know.
- Mom, there's Dad!
- Your Dad?
No! Stay in the car!
Rosana.
Rafa!
- Get in the car!
- Talk to me, Rafa!
Drive! Drive!
Go! Go! Go!
Oh my god!
Go!
What did the doctor say?
The surgery will take
7 to 8 hours...
because he was shot
in the kidney.
He said he will be...
he will...
- Beto...
- I'll be back, I'll be back.
Even by chance...
the system ends up hurting us
where it hursts most.
It's going to take 7 to 8 hours...
I spent my entire life...
believing that the police
could do the right thing.
It'll be fine.
One hour to the next, all
that conviction was gone.
I had no alternative.
I'd have to hit
the system head-on.
Doctor, there's a checkpoint
in front of your condo.
How's that, Braddock?
There's a checkpoint
in front of your condo.
Can I stop, Doctor?
But, in Brazil, it's hard
to arrest authorities.
Pull over, so I can
straighten them out.
So a politician, forget it.
Stop the fucking car.
Imagine how fucked up it'd
be if BOPE worked over
a corrupt representative
just like a dealer.
Lower your weapon, son.
Who's in charge here?
I am.
Wait... What's this?
What's this?
You motherfucker. Look at me.
Look at me!
If anything happens
to my son...
if anything happens to
anyone in my family...
if my son dies,
I will kill everyone.
You understand?
Look at me!
And the first to die will
be you, you motherfucker.
Your honor.
You opened the CPI,
your honor?
- What's this?
- What's this?!
Have you read the paper?
Dead journalist, Fortunato!
- People die everyday!
- What a mess.
You subpoenaed Colonel
Roberto Nascimento!
- I did.
- A CPI during elections...
- helps this gentleman!
- Cynical.
You're a punk!
- Calm down, Fortunato!
If there's a CPI,
I'll be the narrator!
Narrator, my ass!
In this CPI, Representative,
you're under investigation.
- Punk!
- You're the punk.
- Calm down.
- I'll see you in session.
- Punk!
- Calm down, Fortunato.
Fortunato, calm down!
First, I'd like to say
that this administration...
supports the establishment of
the CPI and hopes...
that our representatives will
help us discover the truth.
I'd also like to say that
the search for the...
whereabouts of the
journalist and photographer...
was transferred to
the kidnapping division...
as there are no bodies,
and no clues...
I repeat, no evidence
that they were murdered.
The only evidence we have
until now...
is the electronic recording
of Rep. Fraga...
which was obtained illegally
via a wiretap...
ordered by Colonel
Roberto Nascimento...
in the house of his ex-wife
to spy on her.
The Governor, obviously...
has relieved Colonel Nascimento
of his duties and the military police...
has initiated the process
of his expulsion.
The politicians were not
interested in my dying...
before I testify.
I'd become a martyr of human rights
in the middle of a CPI...
and Fraga would turn the
Governor...
into a murder suspect.
But the system doesn't have
central planning...
nor a board of directors,
my friend.
The system is an inhuman
mechanism...
an expression of twisted
interests.
Let's go, folks. It's time.
- Sup, boss.
- Sup.
I told you to hide the
shirt. Come on.
Pull in the front, Nunes.
The Governor did
what was best for him...
he smeared my name and
ended my police career.
I have to go, ok?
Call me if there's anything.
The tactic of the militia
would be different.
Rocha knew if someone had
to go down in the CPI...
the politicians would
dump it all on him.
Aranha, see where he is.
Where are you, partner?
I'm in front of the pub.
We'll wait behind the hospital.
Tell us when he comes out, ok?
For the militia, the sooner
I died, the better.
He's going to the parking lot.
Attention. He's coming out.
He's at the door.
Pull out, partner.
Pull out.
Let's go,
get that cocksucker!
Luckily, I discovered...
my true enemies in time.
When they came,
I wasn't alone.
- You ok?
- Skulls.
He's on the ground.
I'm in,
I'm in, I'm in.
Behind the fucking car!
Go! Go! Get the other one
get the other one!
Let's go. Go!
The motherfucker escaped...
but my war on the system
was just beginning.
Now it was personal.
And I would keep fighting,
but in a different way.
Silvio, please.
The last page of the
document is missing.
Tell them I need
a xerox to distribute.
Excuse me, ladies
and gentlemen.
May I have your attention...
so that we may hear
the testimony of...
- Colonel Roberto Nascimento.
- One moment, please.
I'd like to utter a few
words before this circus.
Representative, please.
This CPI was opened on
the eve of elections.
This is just part of an
electoral campaign.
You are a clown!
You're plotting against
the city of Rio de Janeiro.
You do not have the
right to speak.
I'm cutting your microphone.
Rep. Diogo Fraga, you are a clown!
You're plotting against our city.
You're plotting against us!
Gentlemen, please.
- Let's get to the questions.
- A circus!
Colonel Nascimento, are you ready?
Can we start with the questions?
If you'll allow...
I would like to say a few words...
before answering questions.
You may. Take all the time
you need.
My name is Roberto Nascimento.
I am Lieutenant-Colonel
of the Military Police...
of the State of Rio de Janeiro.
I've dedicated 21 years
of my life to the police.
It is thus not easy,
what I'm about to say...
but the truth is that the
MP of Rio needs to be abolished.
Please.
When my son was 10...
he asked me why my job
was to kill.
My son Rafael,
who is now in the hospital...
victim of a gunshot.
And I couldn't answer him.
I've been a cop 21 years
and I couldn't say...
for what and for whom
I killed.
But what I can say,
without a doubt, Representatives...
is that a cop doesn't
pull the trigger alone.
Rep. Fraga, half of your
colleagues in this house...
should be in jail.
Gentlemen, please.
I request silence for
the testimony. Please.
- Half is low, Representative.
- Let's maintain silence!
Please. Please.
Half is low, Representative.
There are only 6 or 7
with a clean sheet.
Gentlemen, let's maintain silence
for the testimony.
Please.
Rep. Fortunato,
you are the leader...
of one of the largest criminal
organizations in this city.
Please! Let's maintain
silence, please.
You act in concert with
the Commander...
the ex-Commander of the MP
of the State of Rio...
and ex-Secretary of Security,
Guaracy Novaes...
one of the worst crooks that
I've had the displeasure of knowing...
in my life as a police officer.
And I can affirm here,
Representative...
that the Governor of the
State of Rio de Janeiro...
is directly involved in
the crimes...
under investigation here
in this house.
I affirm that the Governor
of the State is involved...
in the crimes investigated
by Rep. Diogo Fraga.
Rep. Fortunato, you
are responsible for...
more than 20 murders
in the West Side of the city.
Among which, you are responsible
for the murder of my friend...
Captain of the Military Police,
Andr Matias.
Gentlemen, please!
Let's maintain silence,
please. Let's refrain...
I went to Fraga's CPI
to detonate the system.
I went to speak the truth.
To say what I felt.
I told everything I knew,
I acknowledged my errors...
and spoke for over 3 hours.
And knocked down a lot of people.
I put many corrupt
politicians in jail.
Thanks to my speech,
there were fuckers...
who ended up in a ditch
long before I had hoped.
It was the biggest paper-
shredding in Rio's history.
And even then, the system
remained standing.
Take his gold and put the anchor
on that piece of shit.
The system cuts off its hand
to save its arm.
The system reorganizes,
entertains new interests.
Creates new leadership.
Gentlemen, four more years!
Congratulations!
- Congratulations!
- Congratulations, everyone!
As long as the conditions for
the system's existence remained...
it would resist.
We all know that Rep. Guaracy...
was elected with money from crime,
with money from the militia.
If you confirm him as
president of this commission...
you will certify that
you are like him...
crooks dressed up as
representatives of the people...
I request to speak.
...the source of injustice!
Calm down, Representative.
You do not qualify to be
a congressman.
- I will not accept...
- Do not quality
your challenging my
competence...
- A representative of crime...
- and that of my colleagues.
cannot be a representative
of the people!
I was democratically elected
president of this council.
- Democratically!
- With the evidence...
- it's irrefutable!
- I was elected...
and you will have to swallow
your defamatory accusations.
What I can't swallow is
your criminal record!
Because I will assume
my duties here...
whether you like or not.
Now answer me this...
who do you think sustains
all this?
Yeah... And it costs.
It costs a lot.
The system is much bigger
than I thought.
There's a reason dealers,
cops and militias...
kill so many people in the slums.
There's a reason
the slums even exist.
There's a reason for all the
scandals in Brasilia and...
regardless of administration,
for corruption to continue.
Change takes a long time.
The system is fucked up.
A lot of innocent folks
will keep dying.
Rafa!
[English subtitles by Huy Zing
& Wanessa Papillon]
[huyzinho @ gmail]