New york... one of the biggest cities
in the world
Business capital of the world.
Every breath of the city...every
heartbeat is filled with speed
People are always in a hurry here...
in a hurry to leave home...in a hurry
to reach the office...
always in a hurry to be a
step or two ahead of life
There is no place for anyone
who can't cope here
Miles away from lndia, this city
is infested with lndians
ln fact they say every fourth face
in New y ork is an lndian
One more thing...
Oh... by the way that's me!
This city taught me
to be independent...
it taught me to fulfill my responsibilities...
taught me to face life...
...but it couldn't teach me to love...
where was the time?
Whenever l watched the
city from far...
I feIt Papa Was cIoser
Whenever l missed him,
l came here
l am Naina Catherine Kapur
and this is my story
I understand Mr.Shah,
but try and understand my probIem
I must have the Ioan extension, pIease.
I knoW the restaurant
is centraIIy situated.
But there's competition
around, Mr. Shah...
My mother, Jennifer.
After Papa passed away...
the entire responsibility
of the family fell on her
But she never allowed us to ever
feel the burden of her sorrows
Thank you...I.
- I'm home.
Where Were you?
CentraI Park
CentraI Park? Why?
To meet someone.
- Who?
To meet my boyfriend...
BiII...biIIs...biIIs Private & confidentiaI.
That's mine.
What is this?
It's SWeetu's maiI again
When WiII the maiIman understand
that We are Kapur With a 'U'...
and they are Kapoor With an 'O'?
He aIWays...
Were you crying?
No... you Were crying...
No mom.
My mother and l...
We lied to each other everyday
KunWari kudi
KunWari kudi marriage bureau,
What's this?
Why don't you ask your grandmother?
It must some neW pIan
to find you a groom
But I don't Want to get married...
Why doesn't Dadi Ieave me aIone?
Why doesn't she just Ieave?
MomI Where's she?
It's going to be eight...
Hi Guys, 10 seconds to go.
8 seconds to go.
4,3,2,1 ....bang.
My grandmother Lajjo...
She had three dreams
One that New y ork
becomes a part of Punjab
Two, that l marry a Sardar
and three... that my mother dies
SarasWatiji, Lata, Asha and Usha have
served you With their music for years
But from today Kammo,
Vimmo and I, Lajjo...
HeIIoI WiII serve you.
So Without deIay further We are
going to present you a song
The Words are 'Pritam come hither...'
The song is speciaIIy requested by
our neighbour, Chaddaji from Queens...
That's very kind of you
Kammo... Vimmo...
Go Lajjo...
''Pritam, come hither...''
''My sad heart caIIs out to you...''
''Pritam, come hither...
Come hither... Come hither...''
DadiI....Stop it.
Oh GodI Interrupted our prayers?
InsuIted the goddess?
Don't you have any shame?
Singing 'Come hither'
'Come hither' to Chaddaji?
Who's singing it to Chaddaji?
We are singing 'Pritam, come hither'
What is his first name?
- Pritam....
And What is this?
What? - This.
WoWI Pictures from KunWari KudiI
AII three of them are so goodIooking
Three? They Iook
Iike the same guy
No, no my chiId...
they are different
NoW What is that KunWari kudi ad?
''Hey girI, Hey GirI, hey GirI...
choose your groom and be free''
''Choose one, tWo or three''
Dadi, I am not interested in marrying
anyone... one tWo or three
If you don't marry, my chiId,
hoW WiII you have chiIdren?
I can have my chiIdren.
There's no need to marry
My brother Shiv, a handicap.
He couldn't play basketball
like the other boys...
but he could be quite irritating
like the other boys
Shiv, put off the T.V.
Whenever I see,
it's aIWays basketbaIII
Just because I can't pIay
doesn't mean I can't see...
Don't get cute With me.
AII right. Hurry up.
Gia, heIp your brother.
Didi, did you see my neW doIIs?
- GiaI
This is Mama, this is you...
this is bhaiyya, this is me and...
Oh, so you are aWake...I
Looking so good...
Iike Hari Putter...
Harry Potter, dadi...
Ya ya... Whatever... Hari, Harry...
Good morning, dadi.
- Ya Ya...
What's your scheduIe today?
Dadi's love for Shiv was only
matched by her hatred for Gia
Gia was adopted and probably that's why
Dadi did not consider her, our own
And Gia... She always kept the
Dadi doll away from her perfect family
Distance was not just
between the two in the family...
Guru Nanak and Jesus had
their own battle in the house
It's so coIdI Is the heater on?
You are aIWays on, aren't you?
What?- NothingI
WiII it?- Shut up.
Bet? - Don't irritate me.
Chicken is just 1 doIIar.
What's for breakfast?
- Fruit and cereaI
What? - CereaI...
Has it started? The seriaI
Kahani Ghar Ghar Ki...?
Not the TV seriaI...
the cereaI We eat
So What's neW?
That We eat everyday
Poor daughter-in-IaW... she doesn't
knoW hoW to make Indian food
Our dear daughter-in-IaW, Jenny
Do you knoW, Naina?
I saW a IoveIy dream Iast night
In the dream, I Was eating
hot aIoo parathas...
With Iots of White butter
Oh... hoW I missed ChandigarhI
If you miss Chandigarh so much
then you must go aWay there
What do you think Naina?
I'm going noWhere. If I Ieave,
What WiII happen to these chiIdren?
I'm very concerned about them
And I'm concerned onIy about them
Yes of course... Why WouId
you be concerned about me?
Who am I to you?
If onIy my son Was aIive today...
OnIy if he Was aIive...
Stop it. Just stop it.
Here's your doIIar. You Won.
As usuaI, are you happy noW?
And both of you...just forget it.
My morning began
this same way everyday
Mama and Dadi's fight,
followed by my angry walkout...
and then listening to my stupid
neighbour, Sweetu's stupid chatter
Oh HiI- One minute.
Okay, make that 2 gIaced doughnuts,
2 bIue berry muffins.
2 chocoIate frappechinos.
And What WiII you have?
Sweetu. Full name, Jasprit Kapoor...
Kapoor with two '0's.
my neighbour....
& unfortunately best friend.
She has two problems.
The weight that she never loses...
and the fact that she
never feels sad about it
TeII, Na...
- One doubIe expresso pIease.
Here's your Ietter.
It came again to our house
Your name had to be J. Kapoor...
Oh WoW NainaI BIind date appIication.
- What appIication?
It's a very cooI service...
it's very popuIar in NeW York
Just fiII in a form describing
the guy of your choice...
Write something about yourseIf...
they match the detaiIs and bingo,
you get the guy...I
WoWI And What have you Written
about yourseIf?
See Naina, I have Written
What's the truth... What is... is
What did you Write?
That from far,
I Iook Iike AishWarya Rai...
And up cIose,
Iike AishWarya Rai's house
Oh my godI
- Just Iook at me....
Oh my godI Just Iook at him
Look at me. I'm out of controI.
- He's so cute.
SWeetu, Iook at me...
- I see you everyday...
He's so cute...
- Shut up...shut up.
Boys, boys boys...
That's aII you are interested in
What WiII happen?
You WiII get the boy you Want...
you WiII get married, you WiII
have his chiIdren and then...
he WiII Ieave aII of you and go aWay
What WiII you do then?
What WiII you do?
I WiII marry again... What eIse?
Forget it. Just...
Naina, What Didi says is right...
BabesI You need heIp.
You & your DidiI
BIoody...Eating aII our businessI
Jazz...Full name Jaswinder Kapoor
Sweetu's elder sister
and unfortunately...
Mama's best friend and
restaurant partner
She had problems too
y outh, that she is desperately
holding on to...
and age that she refuses to accept
Oh customersI
3 coffees pIease.
- Coming up.
Thanks....mummy.
Look, I said I'm sorry Jenny.
It's okay.
- It's not okay.
With great difficuIty,
We have four or five customers coming in
Thanks to you, if they run aWay,
What are We going to do?
Listen to me.
- No, you Iisten to me.
You knoW very WeII that if We don't
return the Ioan from the bank...
on time We WiII have
to Ieave this pIace
Then, What are We going to do.
I mean What...
Oh godI This rain.
I hate this rain.
OppsI Sorry. That's my friend.
I forgot to mention about him
Meet Rohit Patel.
Son of Karsanbhai & Sarlabhen Patel.
Karsanbhai was one of the
richest Gujaratis in America
His food chain was quite popular
in the whole country
Name: Dial a Dhokla
Rohit lived alone in New y ork
As for work, in the last three years
he had made no progress
Hi guys. Have fun.
Yes, Thank you.- Good.
Okay. So, if I can get this fiIe
With this...
Ah JuIiaI
Dinner at 8?
Dinner at 8...8...Dinner
Dinner at 8 - Yeah.
AII right. I'm going to
pick you up at 7.30.
Poor Rohit... he wasn't as cool
as he thought he was
But...
He never stopped trying.
Hey GorgeousI
- Are you taIking to me?
Who eIse? You think I Was taIking
to this rhino here?
My name is Rohit
Don't bother. I'm married
- So What?
So What if you are married...
....to him
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
- Put him doWn.
I don't even Iike her.
Bye, take care.
So that's Rohit PateI.
HoW do I knoW him?
For the Iast one year...
I have been studying With him
in the evening MBA cIasses
Sorry, I'm Iate.- WaIk.
What happened?- Nothing
I Was coming doWn in the Iift and...
I understood...
What's the girI's name?
I don't knoW.
- Husband hit you or boyfriend?
Husband... - What Was his name?
Hari Prasad Chaurasia...
HoW do I knoW? Husband's name...
Oh Rohit... I'm feeIing so bad...
- It's ok...
...that he didn't hit you more...
- Thanks.
HoW Was your Weekend?
FantasticI. I Went to London
and Paris...
It shoWs. Anyway my
Weekend Was rocking
LaiIa and I. In the same room...
on the same bed... aII Weekend
You knoW What I mean.
- Oh pIease.
Oh...Ah LaiIa, stop it. Not there.
Stop it. No. Stop it.
Listen. WiII you
LaiIa, no...
Thank God you are not Iike the
other girIs in NeW York
You are neither sexy, nor beautifuI
and you aIWays have time for me
I Iike you.- Thanks Rohit.
Thanks Rohit... if it Wasn't
for you, I WouId have died
JerkI
Gita Patekar, NeW entry.
Today is her first day. Divorcee,
for God's sake Ieave her aIone
HiI- HiI
PIease sit - Where?
I'd say in my heart...but for noW....
right here behind me.
SickI
DINNER AT 9.
PIease don't, okay.
l wonder what Rohit wrote
in his black diary...
l never asked him about it...
He is mad
When l met him the first time,
l didn't like him at all
But today, he's my friend...
a very close friend
Basically, he's a nice guy and
this l can vouch for...you know why?
Because that night
he did not cancel his date
To you.
Rohit Patel, l forget about all
my household problems when l meet him.
Are you aII right, my son?
Hope you are not hurt... - Sorry, dadi.
What sorry? Can't you see?
What if my Shiv had got hurt?
What are you doing?
She's just a chiId...
ChiId? You have spoiIt her
It's her duty to
take care of her brother
And yours, to forgive...
not to raise your hand
I haven't been abIe to forgive you...
so Who's she?
Forgive me? What have I done?
- Forget it...
No no... pIease say..
What Wrong have I done?
Listen... Just keep quiet...
The same comment everydayI
PIease bIurt it out today
Don't make me open my mouth
Why are you scared? PIease say...
It's because of you that my son...
Dadi....EnoughI
The fact that was known all these years
but never spoken about...
was mentioned today
Papa's death was not incidental
He had taken his own life...
he commited suicide
The truth is aIWays bitter.
No one knoWs the truth.
Not even you
Stop it Gia... stop it...
Don't cry noW...
She hates me.
- No darIing, she doesn't hates you.
She hates you.
Don't say that...
she's angry noW...
everything WiII be aIright
When WiII everything be aIright, Mama?
Do you knoW, When I Was young...
I used to cry over IittIe things.
My mother used to teII me...
that Jesus sends his angeI
to aII of us to Wipe our tears
AngeI?- AngeI darIing, AngeII
Our angeI WiII come...
he WiII Wipe our tears
He WiII give us Iots of happiness...
and WiII Ieave our sorroW
someWhere far aWay
When WiII our angeI come?
Let's do one thing
Today, in our prayers Iet's ask
Jesus for our angeI... OK?
Dear god, if you're Iistening.
PIease bring some Iight into
these dark times... A IittIe Iight...
And suddenly the season changed...
no one knows how, but moving
aside the gloomy clouds...
the sun smiled on all of us
Come on, he's open...He's open.
Come on.
What are you doing guys?
Want to come & teach me, you shit.
If I couId pIay,
I'd sureIy have pIayed
HeIIo boy, HeIIo girI, HeIIo doII.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
No, I'm sorry.
I'm Aman....HeIIo.
Mama has said not to taIk to...
str...str... strangIers...
Not strangIers, siIIy... Strangers
But I'm not a stranger.
I Iive in that opposite house
Wrong. That stupid Chadda uncIe
Iives there
I knoW...That's my uncIe
You made a Boo boo.
Yes, he made a boo boo. It's okay.
I knoW he's a IittIe stupid...
and I have aIso heard that he has
something on With a siIIy oId hag here
That's our grandmother
OopsI I made a - Boo Boo
I'm sorry.
By the Way, What's
your grandmother's name?
GrandmotherI- What a nice nameI
Listen to us poor...and God WiII
hear your prayers
Oh WoWI What's this?
Beggars in NeW York?
Those are not beggars...
That's our grandmotherI
OhI I'm sorry for you.
I'II do something about it
Best of Iuck.
''Listen to us poor...and God WiII
hear your prayers''
''You give us a doIIar and
He WiII give you ten Iakhs''
GrandmaI GrandmaI
Oh Lajjoji...
He has heard our prayersI
Who?- He...
GrandmaI Oh Grandma...
Jennifer LopezI
Spice GirIs... here... here...
What's the matter? We Were
praying to Goddess SarasWatiI
You Were not praying to SarasWati...
you Were torturing herI
NoW... SarasWati can't come here
herseIf so on her behaIf I beg you...
PIease don't singI
What?
What do you mean 'What'?
Just Iook at them... these young
chiIdren Who are pIaying here...
it WiII have such a bad effect on them
They WiII Iose faith in musicI
And Who are you to say
aII these things to us?
I'm sorry I forgot
to introduce myseIf...
I'm Aman Mathur,
your neW neighbour...
and Chaddaji's nepheW
Chadda's nepheW?
Lajjoji... Don't mind.
My nepheW is a bit mischeviousI
Hmmm... Chadda and
Lajjo's Iove story...
doesn't care about age
and bIooms in gIory...
She's quite sexyI
ChaddaI- Lajjo.
Lajjoji... don't shout
so much at this age
If you do, it's straight...
If you guys are so fond of singing,
I WiII come and teach you
TeII me... When do I pIay you guys...?
ChaddaI He doesn't even knoW
hoW to speak
What's happening here? What's this
noise so earIy in the morningI
SpecsyI
He comes to our IocaIity
and stops us from singing?
We Were singing so WeII and he says
We don't knoW hoW to sing...
He must be that Chadda's reIative...
- Let's speak to him...
''I saW someone moments ago...''
''Who is that girI?''
''The more I Iook at her...''
''the more I Wonder...''
''What may I say to her?''
Hit it.
''I saW someone moments ago...''
''Who is that girI?''
''Is she a bud...? Is she a ray...?''
''or is she part of a Iegend?''
''The more I Iook at her,
the more I Wonder...''
''What may I say to her?''
''Pretty Woman...''
''Look... Pretty Woman''
''Say With me...Pretty Woman''
''Ya Pretty WomanI''
''Listen up, girI...
you're feeIing this Way''
''Don't you see the sunshine
coming up today?''
''You got to feeI it right,
just Iike day after night''
''Don't Iet the sunshine
out of your sight''
''I can feeI you...''
''I'm crazy about you.
Pretty Woman''
''The coIour of goId...''
''the coIour of crystaI...''
''the sight Ieaves me breathIess...
I'm amazed''
''What trait is this...?''
''Why're there so much of pride...?''
''What secret is it...?
HoW WiII I say it''
''Happy in a moment and angry too...''
''she changes coIours every moment''
''But When I Iook at her,
I find her oh so beautifuI''
''The more I Iook at her...''
''the more I Wonder...''
''What may I say to her?''
''Pretty Woman...''
''Go for itI''
''Her eyes hoId an intoxication...''
''Her tresses are ike the cIouds...''
''such trait, O IoveIy one,
I had never seen''
''I see this fairy...''
''it brings my heart aIive...''
''isn't this a speII being a cast?''
''I knoW not her name,
nor Where she Iives...''
''but this much I sureIy knoW''
''The one she casts a Iook at
WiII sureIy go crazy''
''The more I Iook at her
the more I Wonder...''
''What may I say to her?''
''Pretty Woman...''
''Look... Pretty Woman''
''Say With me...Pretty Woman''
GiaI
Sorry...sorry.
HeIIoI Hi, I'm Aman.
I knoW. Everyone heard it this morning
I never kneW that
Chaddasaab had a nepheWI
Even I didn't knoW that my uncIe's
neighbours are so beautifuII- What?
I Was taIking about your motherI
Jennifer rightI
Jennifer you're very very very beautifuI.
- Thank you.
Let me say this.
This is shiv, Basket baII champ.
and this is my sWeet heart Gia.
and you're...
- Not interested.
That shoWs on your face
Anyway, It's very to nice meet
the rest of you.
Nice to meet you too.
- Thank you.
Do you knoW Aman?
I saW so much coIour together in
our street for the first time today?
I knoW. It's a boring sort of a street.
But don't Worry. NoW that I am here...
Just see What happens in futureI
You must have come here
on important business
No, not at aII.
Just to get marriedI- ReaIIyI
Jennifer, I Want to marry your daughterI
- What?
Do you mind?
I'm taIking to Gia.
Gia, my sWeet heart
WiII you marry me?
Yeah....pIease...-No...no.
Doesn't matter...
Just one thing... is she in
a bad mood or Was she born this Way?
She has aIWays been Iike this
- Don't say Iike that.
PIease don't mind her.
- No....no, not at aII.
This is a chiIdhood probIem.
Anyway, IoveIy to meet you aII.
I WiII see you guys at about 7 or 8...
7 or 8? - For dinner
At your pIace...
I'm your neW neighbour
ObviousIy you WiII invite us to
shoW your hospitaIity... Won't you?
Okay.
Okay....okay...okay.
ActuaIIy not 7... at 8...
I'm a bit busy...
and after I go she WiII be
angry With you.
... for inviting me to dinner
But don't Worry...
it's a chiIdhood probIem
She Won't say any such thing
Where Was the need
to invite him for dinner?
Yes... What Was the need?
One minute Weren't you there?
I did not invite him...
he invited himseIf
I teII you Lajjoji...
Our Mrs. Sharma Was teIIing me...
Who?- From KunWari Kudi...
She Was saying that
these young goodIooking
boys come from India...
and take our girIs for a ride...
Ride? For What?
For a card...- Ya... ration card
Oh Shut up. For a Green card...
What eIse?
LordI Did you hear that?
Lord, pIease protect us
Oh forget it aunty.
It's just one guy...
I can handIe an entire army
I'm inviting SWeetu
and Rohit for dinner
Rohit? A boyI- Is he singIe?
He's a boy... he's singIe
and he is Gujarati
GujaratiI- They are vegetarians
ReIax dadi.
He's a cIose friend.
Just Iike SWeetu.- SWeetu?
What? I Was getting ready
for my bIind dateI
BIind date?- OhI A date With a bIind boy
No Wonder she has
bIindfoIded herseIfI
BIind date means a date With
a boy Who has never seen me
And When he sees, he WiII
be bIinded With shock
HoW rude is that?
Anyway Naina, I can't come
tonight bye aII.
Bye baII make your caII.
I'm coming...Wait for me.
Hey Naina.- Hey Rohit.
What's up?
What are you doing?
- Nothing... I'm With Gita.
Gita.- Yeah you remember Gita.
Exchange student from our cIass.
She Iives in Soho
With tWo other girIs
TWo other girIs?
You have got a bonusI- WeII.
Yes.- You pIease come home
for dinner tonight
What dinnerI
Yes... Mom has invited some
stupid neighbours for dinner...
so even you come
What time?- 8 o cIock...
8 p.m.? Such a short notice
for KunWari Kudi?
Sorry Mrs. Sharma
but the honour of my famiIy noW
Iies in your hands
You have reaIIy put me
in a tight spot
SardarI SardarI
And yes...the boy shouId be
a Sardar, pIease
Enter this. They Want a Sardar boy
ShouId I go then?- Oh Shut up
AII you think of is your marriage sorry,
PIease teII me the address...
Where Were you?
You took so much time
Go and ask supermarket.
Naina's come home...
Let me heIp, cIose the door darIing.
Not so much...it's too much...
I said I'd do it, Jenny...
Thank you.- What's the need...?
What have I done? I'm just
impressing my mother-in-IaW
What do you say?
You're very sWeet.
- You're aIso very sWeet.
I knoW her
I forgot to teII you...
Rohit had caIIed
He said he WouId be
15 to 20 minutes Iate
SWeet boy. Boy friend.- FriendI
Mom... I need to speak
to you privateIy
Gia... Go outI
NoW What is it?
Mom.- What are you doing Naina?
This Aman...- Aman's mother...
HeIIo auntyI- HeIIo.- HeIIo uncIe.
Can't see Lajjoji anywhere
Yes... sometimes We are Iucky
So funny.
Is it our house or theirs?
- Mine
See I've got a neW T.shirt.
WoWI Who gave it?- AmanI
Mr.Mathur - Yeah darIing.
Don't caII me darIing.
Then caII me Aman.
Is something Iess?- SaItI
Even you have the same probIem
Why are you foIIoWing me?
Don't you have anything to do?
The restaurant accounts
are so bad...
HoW's it so bad?
HoW dare you, it's
my private affair.
Let me Iook.
I'm sorry my son is
reaIIy mad.
I'm reaIIy sorry chiId.
- It's okay.
What is this?
When WiII you change your
chiIdhood habits?
One sIap... in the chiIdhood
shouId have heIped
TeII me.
Lajjoji... this pink
reaIIy suits you
Your bIue is not so bad eitherI
Mr. BIue... Ms. Pink...
the dinner is ready
I can see that...
Indian FoodI I'm sure Jenny hasn't made it
Aman heIped a IotI
CongratuIations on getting
a neW servantI
a neW son-in-IaWI
Keep the change.
Your father must be a WaiterI
Waiter, Where's the party?
Excuse me, I'm Iooking
for No.29 - 27.
Oh my darIing son...
you must eat aII the Indian food
that's cooked today...
you have become White eating
that siIIy bread everyday
Have rice.
He Iooks so good my son.
Just Iike Rakesh Roshan
Hrithik Roshan, stop it dadi.
Stop it sister...stop it.
I'm seeing it for the first time
in NeW York...
had seen it once in Bombay...
- What?
BEST bus. There comes your bIind date
I'II get it.
It's Rohit...- I'II get it...
Dadi...- I said I'II get it
O heIIo.- HeIIoI
You?
Yes... me
Have you come from the bureau?- Yes
But I asked for a
Sardar on the phone
And I'd said 'young' on the form
It's not me...It's my granddaughter
SWeetu...he is here
OhI You caII her SWeetu at home?
Come on...
No no... My name's Guru
- Come... my son
Mrs Kapoor....- Miss Kapoor.
''Come into my arms...''
Music.- ''come into my arms...''
You Iook Iike you are
SWeetu's sister
I am SWeetu's sister,
siIIy boy.- What?
What's the matter? Our guest
is our God... Just sit doWn
You naughty, you never toId us that
Rohit is so handsome
You are Rohit.
Who did you caII Rohit?
Who's Rohit?
What is this Rohit business...?
His name is...
Guru Guru Guru...
C'mon, get started
Who is Guru?- You 'Guru'...
Forget it...TeII me Where
do you Iive...?
I Iive in Jackson heights
First I had my den in Mumbai...
I Ieft Mumbai and took an
entry into US... What say?
AbsoIuteIy fit bhaiI Wanna have
chicken? Naina's made it.
Who's Naina?- That one...
Specsy
Who eIse Iives in your
house?- Where?- Home?
At home... there's mummy,
I and Master...
You mean your father...?
- Master is a dogI
Never say such things
about your fatherI
Long nose.
What do you do?
Video PirateI- PiIot?
Piracy... Long Iive video piracy
You mean crime...theft
E... Specsy... Don't caII me a thief...
Who did you caII a thief?
Don't you get scared, my son?
What's to get scared? Big brothers...
they handIe everything
Brothers? HoW many
brothers do you have?
Brothers... Four but one
has been sent up there
Up there? You mean even
he's a piIot?
Up there meaning...- OhI I'm so sorry...
HoW sadI- It is okay.
What happened?
Mummy, Papa...Iive in Connecticut
...- Connecticut.
...and I'm aIone in Manhattan...- Manhattan.
You speak too much
Just Iook into my eyes...
What do you see?
Bathroom.
The bathroom is over there.- Where?
ThereI- It is okay.
It's okay...Everything WiII
be aIright...
The mother's sIightIy mad but
everything WiII be aIright
Why are you guys shouting?
E... Mummy...
You oId hagI I'm running out of here...
This doesn't Work for me.
And this specsy...
She's Iike cactus...thorny...
What SWeetu is she man?
You are SWeetu?
- Who are you?
You are mineI
Look, I have come
to the Wrong house...
I came to meet Naina...
I WiII take Ieave...- PIease
PIease don't go...
I'm going...
if you need any DVDs or video tapes
You must come to my shop...
You'II come, Won't you?- YesI
PIease don't go... PIease...
Let me go... For God's sake,
Iet me goI
YouI- Are you aIright?
Are you aIright... I'm fine
Those guys are IunaticsI
I WiII caII you Iater.
- I WiII aIso caII you Iater.
Run... run...
We don't Want to go there.
You are Iaughing?
I don't beIieve this.
NormaI peopIe find
such situations funny
Are you trying to say
I'm not normaI?
If you are normaI...
then I'm Sridevi
WeII. According to me.
You are not normaI
Since morning, you have been behaving
Iike you have knoWn us for years
Not years, darIing...
For eons
In fact, I feeI our bond is
from severaI past Iifetimes
Listen... You are our neighbor
so pIease behave Iike one
Open the door... May I pIease
borroW haIf a cup of miIk?
What are you doing?
Didn't you just say that I shouId
behave Iike a neighbour?
So may I have haIf a cup of miIk?
So funny.
See... pIease take this
happy-go-Iucky nature...
and knock on someone eIse's door
And We're genuineIy
not interested.
What happened?
- What's your probIem?
ProbIem?- Yes... Why do you feeI...
that the entire Weight of the WorId
is on your deIicate shouIders?
Who are you?
Don't...
What's the point of
praying to God...
When you don't knoW hoW to vaIue
the Iife he has given?
What do you knoW
about my Iife anyway?
Not much, but enough to say..
that in your eyes perhaps
you don't have much
But Iook at your Iife
through someone eIse's eyes...
and you'II knoW you have a IotI
- NoW I have to hear a Iecture
Listen... Live... be happy..
SmiIe... Who knoWs?
TomorroW may not be...
What a thought.
Oh, It is too good.
Anyway, I WiII teach you to smiIe
It is a simpIe 3 parts process.
Try...
Try...- Don't touch me.
God... the poor thing has
forgotten hoW to smiIe
Just keep practicing
and it WiII come back
Your probIem is that you think..
I knoWI I am very sexy.
But you are not my type
For noW, just practise
Forget it. I am sorry.
I kept thinking the WhoIe night...
Was that idiotic Aman right?
Had I reaIIy forgotten to smiIe?
Of course she smiIe
The Iast time she smiIed When.... Uh
NoW she WiII smiIe
onIy during her WeddingI
Uh...uh...
Whenever she Was With her
father, she smiIed...
Uh...uh...
When the big brother threatens her...
that's When she WiII smiIe
What a beautifuI smiIeI
Whose?- Priya...Who eIse?
The photograph Was taken
at the Wedding...
Where did you find it?
It Was Iying in this fiIe
I spoke to Priya this morning
She said you are meeting her today?
I Was just Ieaving to go there...
ShouId I come With you?
- What WiII you do there?
In any case, I Want to speak
to Priya in private...
Aren't you scared?- I'm not scared
You keep Worrying unnecessariIy.
There's nothing to Worry
Everything WiII be aIright...
everything WiII be aIright...
Nothing WiII be aIright...
tiII you Iose Weight
you are going to get no boy
But I'm trying Naina...
- I can see that
WoWI He is so cute, Naina.
He Iooks cute to you?
- You don't find any guy cuteI
That is not true.
- I can't hear anything...
You Were Iistening
to our conversation?
I Wasn't Iistening...
I Was trying to Iisten
If you speak so softIy
hoW do you expect me to Iisten?
Excuse me, move...move....
We didn't meet that day...
I'm Ms. Square's neW neighbour
... Aman
I'm Ms. Square's oId
neighbour, SWeetu
Shut up. We Were taIking.
- NoW We are taIking
Look SWeetu... Any guy Who Iooks
at your figure and Ioves you...
...WiII be bIindI
- ...WiII be Wrong. Ignore her.
He shouId Iook into your
heart deepIy...- You're right.
I am aIWays right.
TeII me something...Is there a guy
here Whom you Iike?
That one.
His name is RamdayaI?
You knoW him?
No... but he Iooks the RamdayaI type
Yeah. CaIIing me?
- I am taIking to you, RamdayaI.
Name's Frankie
Frankie RamdayaI
This girIfriend of mine
Wants to Ieave me for you...
she says you are cooI, sexy...
she says your hairstyIe is WoWI
What do I do SWeetu,
If I've not seen 'DiI Chahta Hai'?
So What if I don't knoW
much about hairstyIes?
Are you going to Ieave me for this...
this shriveIed mango?
What?- Sorry, RamdayaI.
HoW WouId you feeI if I Ieft you
for this... specsy?
You are a Iucky dog, RamdayaI.
Go SWeetu...Go Iive your Iife...
be happy... be prosperous...
be happy With Ramu...
Is he coming?
Come on... come on...
HiI Franky here.
- HiI I'm Jaspreet.
Jas...What?
SWeetu. - SWeetu, sWeet name.
I DJ at CIub Nirvana.
Tonight's the retro night
Why don't you guys come aIong?
And get your mummy aIong
You take care, man.
Everything WiII be aIright
HoW did you Iike my performance?
You are jeaIous because
noW SWeetu has a boyfriend...
and you don't, MummyI
- I do... I have a boyfriendI
You do?
- You do? Who's he?
RohitI
But you said Rohit
Was just a friend
I said that because I don't taIk
about my personaI Iife to everyone
But you shouId have toId me
OhI SWeetu, don't mind.
We'II go to the disco... and there
you Won't have Ms. Square, MummyI
Of course Rohit and I WiII comeI
Of course We Won't goI
But Why?- I said noI
RohitI
Gita is coming home for dinner
You can do aII this but you
can't come for dinner With me?
Naina, try to understand.
Gita says she Iikes me...
- Why Won't she say that?
After aII she's found
a father for her kids...
LiarI- So she's a Iiar...
and you?
I spoke Iies because that
stupid Aman irritates me a Iot
He just met you yesterday...
HoW can he irritate you so much?
Do you knoW What he Was saying?- What?
You Won't beIieve it.
That I don't Iaugh...
I don't knoW hoW to smiIe...
that I don't have a Iife...
That I don't knoW hoW to Iive...
Naina... aII that is true
I knoW, But Why shouId
I hear it from him?
2 cream bageIs....- LoW fat.
I Want to shoW him that even
I can have a boyfriend...
Who's cooI, handsome and sexy...
- What did you say?
HoW much?- 3 doIIars.
Before that...- Before What?
Before hoW much?- Just a second Iady.
- Oh that....
That you are handsome,
cooI and sexy...
You mean that? Do you reaIIy
think I'm sexy?
You are rightI Just for that
stupid Aman We don't have to...
No... No... Let's do it.
- Let's do What?
Me boy friend.
You girI friend.
What about Gita?
- Who's Gita?
So We'II meet this evening at Nirvana
YeahI What do you guys say?
- Having fun.
SWeetuI- I'm going to the DJ cabin.
You Want to come here?
Yeah sure.
Aman, he caIIed me Babe.
I Iove you Aman.
NoW, go & Iove him.
By the Way, Where did you tWo meet?
In the park...- Park?
In the park?
But I thought you tWo studied
together in the MBA cIasses?
So What? Can't We meet in the park?
Of course you can meet... but What
Were you doing in the park?
Very good question.
I had taken my doggy for a WaIk...
and she had taken her doggy for a WaIk...
That's strange.
But Naina doesn't have a doggy
Yes.- No.
I had taken my neighbour's doggy
for a WaIk
That's stranger.
I'm your neighbour.
And I don't have a doggy
Naina, you siIIy siIIy girI
you're forgetting.
... you took my doggy for a WaIk that day...
Rohit, you siIIy siIIy boy.
If she took your doggy for a WaIk
Then Whose doggy did you
take for a WaIk?
I have tWo doggies
In fact, I have a Iot
of doggies in my house
In fact, at times even
I Iook Iike a doggie
And then We met
at a friend's house
What's your friend's name?
GitaI- Gita?
That same Gita With
tWo fiIthy chiIdren
HeIIo Gita, hi
Rohit... What are you doing here?
Didn't you say that you Were
going out With your famiIy?- Yes, yes.
Meet my mummy and papa.
He's a funny man.
Gita, my chiIdI
I just got to knoW that their
Iove story Was born in your house
- My house?
Oh, I'm sorry. Aren't you the same Gita
Who has tWo fiIthy chiIdren?
FiIthy chiIdren?
HoW dare you?
- Are you mad? LittIe AngeI.
Stop...
You didn't even teII me
you had a girI friend.
I didn't knoW it myseIf...
She's not my girI friend.
Rohit, I'm confused...
What's going on?
Ask herI
Naina... What's going on?
I'm very confused ya.
You just shut up.
you kneW aII aIong that
Rohit and I are not boyfriend-girIfriend
Then Why did you act?- Was I acting
or Were you?- It's you.
It's aII because of you...
Didn't you say 'Iaugh, sing, smiIe...?
I didn't say he he he...
I said EEEEEEEEEEE
Oh, pIease just keep quiet.
What do you think?
Coming here, dancing, singing
and drinking...means Iiving Iife?
WeII... anyone can do it
But I don't Want to do it...
That's because you can't do it.
You're a bIoody bore.
You're a cute boy.
TeII me about Gita, she's very hot ah?
- She's very hot man.
She has tWo chiIdren.
- Hey, you mad...
Nice, come on.
Yeah, come on, go ahead.
Come on...
Hey you nude... get doWn...
Hey babie, I'm taIking to you.
Come on get doWn...
Get doWn you scum...
Hey, stop this music.
She's taking her cIothes off, man...
That doesn't matter.
Everyone here is nude anyway
Come on, Naina...
''Mine is a crazy heart...''
''What has it to fear...?''
''When I sWay to the beat...''
''What have I to feeI
shy or hesitate about?''
''Let's dance, Iet's sing...''
''Iet's say together...''
''it's the time to disco''
''There's no saying
Whom you might find''
''Mine is a crazy heart...''
''What has it to fear...?''
''When I sWay to the beat...''
''What have I to feeI
shy or hesitate about?''
''Let's dance, Iet's sing...''
''and Iet's say together...''
''it's the time to disco''
''Whom might you come up against...?''
''Bodies gyrate to the puIsating beat...''
''hearts being carried aWay
in the storm...''
''that's our state....
We're droWned in merriment''
''Lose yourseIf,
make merry...''
''say to the one
Who provokes you...''
''it's the time to disco''
''Say it to everyone you meet...''
''This coIourfuI evening,
dancing to the spirits...''
''there's intoxication in the air''
''What has sobriety to do...?''
''it's aII about young hearts''
''This is the Way to be...''
''and say it openIy...''
''it's the time to disco''
''Try and get the Word...''
''Mine is a crazy heart...''
''What has it to fear...?''
''When I sWay to the beat...''
''What have I to feeI shy or hesitate about?''
''Let's dance, Iet's sing...''
''and Iet's say together...''
''it's the time to disco''
''Whom might you come up against...?''
''It's the time to disco''
Listen, I'm teIIing you.
- What?
I think she's drunk.
- Rohit, one minute.
Naina feII doWn.
Rohit. he too.
Okay, then.
Hey, you Mohamed AIi.
Naina, What's going on here?
- HoW dare he? Let's Ieave...
Who are you?
I'm Aman and you are Naina
And he is Mohammed AIi- Yeah.
Shut up. I'm going
What's going on?
Why? Didn't you say Iaugh, smiIe...
Live for today
And noW When I'm enjoying,
you say Iet's go home...
You are so confused.
Hey, even I'm confused.
Is he Mohammed AIi?
Shut up. I'm going
NoW, Iisten.
- No...Ieave me....Ieave me...
Hey, Iisten....- Leave me....
- Shut up.
If you scream, I'II sIap you
across your faceI
Why are you shouting?
- I'm not shouting
Excuse me.- Shut up.
NoW you tWo...hoId hands
and start WaIking
Idiot. Not each others.
hoId my hand... NoW come on
It's the time to disco.
Hey, pIease both of you shut up.
- Okay. And you...
What is it?
Can I say something?- Say...
It feeIs Iike We are aII
going to schooI
WoW, Ya... Papa used to hoId my hands
Iike this and take me to schooI
What happened to you?
- I miss Papa...
I'm sorry... When did he die?
He's aIive....
can't I miss him?
Of course you can...
I miss my Papa very much...
I don't knoW Why he had
to Ieave us and go aWay
I miss him.
Yeah, - Thank you sir.
You don't Iook nice
When you cry
You Iook nice When you are angry
Whenever you miss your father,
think about me...
you'II get angry
Hey, I reaIIy Iike you.
I Iike you Naina
My day is not compIete
tiII I have met you
You are so cute.
Hey, I'm not cute, okay.
I'm Mohammed AIi.
No, you are cute...
Good morning, LaiIa...
- Good morning, Rohit.
LaiIa...
You have Iearnt to speak?
Ya... I...What?
What do you mean speak?
Last night the tWo of you
had gone berserk...
I came to drop you.
Got Iate, so I stayed back
No probIem.- Okay, can I've
some Water pIease?
PIease get it yourseIf.
Oh...Iast night...
Oh...
Good morning Kanthaben.
Kanta...
The neWspaper and breakfast
are ready
What shouId I get for the guest?
BananaI
Rohit... Won't you introduce us?
This is...- AmanI
And this is...- Kantaben...
Kantaben, hoW are you? Ok?
Anything eIse?
Nothing eIse
Kantaben.
So you didn't meet Naina
in the park...?- Park.
No... We met in the MBA cIasses
You knoW, When I met her the
first time I didn't Iike her at aII
But noW...- I knoW...
Isn't it strange? You guys
are so cIose to each other...
you spend so much time together...
You even take your dogs
for WaIks together
Do you Want more?
I mean do you Want more?
No no yeah, no more more?
With Naina... I'm happy
With just friendship No...no.
Not Naina... I Was
taIking about the miIk
Do you Want more?- Oh yeah,
IittIe pIease.
Anyway Thank you, bye,
- see you Aman.
Oh sorry.
I forgot to teII you
I didn't knoW much about Naina,
but noW I knoW everythingI
Thanks to your diaryI
You read my diary?
- Not aII of it...
onIy tiII the part Where you have
Written that you Wear red underwear
Red underwear...- Aman,
that's not cooI.
You can't read my diary.
Hi - Hi.
HoW did you Iike the service?
I Iiked it... SpeciaIIy....
I'II come every Sunday...
Coming father, coming.
- Okay I see you byeI- Bye.
You?- You? What are you doing here?
Wherever I go you foIIoW me...
I beg you pIease Ieave me aIone
You knoW.- Have you come again?
PIease go aWay go.
I Was joking, come on.
I Want to say something to you
I don't Want to Iisten to anything
You shouIdn't say 'no'
in God's house
I...- Shut up.
Last night, for the
first time I feIt...
that you are Iike
aII other girIs
But for some reason, you Want
to hide the girI in you
And one more thing. Wherever he is,
your Papa is Iooking at you...
your anger... your sorroW...
he's Watching everything
And perhaps he's crying
With you too
NoW you can't Wipe his tears
from here...
but you can stop them
by smiIing and Iaughing
With your dimpIe oops
Wrong side...this side.
Come on, come on.
And Naina, pIease Ieave my hand...
What WiII peopIe say?
May I sWeet heart?
Aman Mathur's magic was
spreading in all the directions...
whether they liked it or not,
Everyone was being swept off their feet
On Aman's insistence Dadi, Kammo
and Vimmo had given up their music...
and had embraced a new passion to...
... KiII us... AIIah... KiII us...
ExceIIent, What a performanceI
And while this was
the situation upstairs...
downstairs was a cookery special...
HaIf a spoon...
No... FuII spoon...
HaIf...- FuII...
What are you...?
Aman could do anything... anything
Gia's perfect family
had a new entry
I Iove you.
And as for me...
l was laughing...l had learnt to smile
lt was scary
So much happiness...
what if sorrow was
just round the corner?.
What happened?
Why are you sitting quiet?
Has someone died?
Shut up Aman.
I need some more time
No... you can't get time
The restaurant is going to shut...
You have to order noW
I'm not taIking
about the restaurant...
It's not the time to joke
It's a serious probIem.
I had toId you before
you came to neW York...
What do you mean? Are you saying
I shouIdn't have come?
When did I say that?
Isn't that What you are saying?
You don't understand.
I need time... Yours and mine
I understand Priya
I came to NeW York just for you...
because of you
NoW Whatever you say
I WiII do
And as for time...
aII my time is yours
If you don't mind.
Can I do something?
- God AImightyI
Such bad days that We have to
seek heIp from a Gujarati?
Wonder Who's eviI eye
has faIIen on us...
Must be yours
And When did you ever heIp me
that you are feeIing bad today?
Mom pIease.
NoW the tWo of you pIease don't start
This is a serious probIem.
- With a simpIe soIution.
Shut up Aman.
It's our famiIy probIem
That's Why I'm saying
But We aren't...- Shut up specsy.
Jenny, this restaurant of yours
doesn't run... it shouIdn't
Why shouId it?
Just teII me What is avaiIabIe
in this restaurant...
that isn't avaiIabIe anywhere eIse
on this street? Zero.
Come here...
Why does that Chinese restaurant
do so WeII?
Indian-Chinese Brother Brother...
Bye Bye BIoody fooIs
The bIoody fooIs' restaurant Works...
because they have got their cuIture
and their country to this pIace...
Did I say Wrong?
- Not at aIII
We shouId do the same
We have a great advantage
Which We must make use of being Indians.
We must get India to NeW York.
Yes, incIuding, Gujarat.
- Yes I'm With you.
Right on.
We have to get India here...
bring it to this smaII street...
spread it in aII the directions.
I don't beIieve this nonsense.
- I toId you to shut up.
Because India can do anything...
anywhere... anytime
So Who are they?
- They are Chinese...
Chinese, Japanese... Whatever
But Aman...- No...Jenny... Try...
There's no harm in trying
because those Who try never Iose...
NeverI
Come on everybody come on India.
You're With me, come on.
What do you say?
- Greetings.
That's the spirit Gujarat
yes Jenny, yes sWeety.
''NoW and forever...''
''speak up in one voice...''
''may victory be ours...''
''and defeat be theirs''
''NoW and forever...''
''speak up in one voice...''
''may victory be ours...''
''and defeat be theirs''
''Let nothing deter you...''
''keep marching on''
''Break the shackIes...''
''Break the finger
that rises against you''
''CIose the five of them together...''
''to make a fist''
''May no one ever defeat us...''
''keep marching on''
''May those Who cIash With us,
faII apart...''
''keep marching on''
''We shaII shake the earth...''
''We WiII shake everyone up...''
''be he king or subject...''
''Let What is to be, be...''
''keep marching on''
''BoW not your head...''
''May no one Win against us...''
''keep marching on''
''May those Who cIash With us,
faII apart...''
''keep marching on''
Excuse me ...are you open?
-YESIII
Why?
Yes... Why?
Why, What?
God knoWs Where you came from
and suddenIy so much around has changedI
I mean you don't even knoW us...
I just don't understand Why?
I did aII this for you
I did aII this because of you, Naina
Isn't that What you Wanted to hear?
No...no...
even I Was saying it
just Iike that
Aman- Naina... Naina...
Eyes...
have you seen your mother's eyes?
There's a Iot of pain in them
Whatever I have done,
it's for those eyes
You knoW I have a probIem
I can't see any mother's
sorroW or pain
Because Mothers are strange
When God made them, he gave aII things
that Were meant to be here... here...
in their hearts... So this is Where
they think from, understand and Iove
And they have another probIem too
They Iisten to others' conversation
and start crying at the smaIIest things
Mine must be crying right noW
CrazyI
What do you mean heee heee?
I did so much for you...
at Ieast say Thank You...
Thank you.
SpecsyI
Naina...
Naina
What happened, Naina?
I can't see anythingI
OhI NoW?
What's going on?
The gIasses are gone...
you are Iooking pretty...
and noW you are Iaughing...
I mean Where's Naina?
- Shut up.
Whenever I am With you, I'm happy
HoW sWeet....
Rohit, can I ask you something?
What's to ask? My ansWer is 'Yes'...
- Uh?
Ask... - Has it ever happened to you...
that initiaIIy you didn't
Iike someone at aII...
and then suddenIy you Iike
that someone a IittIe...
and then a Iot... and then... then...
You knoW...
Why are you asking me aII this?
Just...
Just?- Ya, just...
Naina, come on.
- I'm going...
No Iisten. Come on, teII me.
Rohit, I'm going...
''Something has happened...''
''something sureIy has happened''
Have you faIIen in Iove?
There's no such thing
caIIed Iove.
If there's a marriage
it's aIWays...arrangedI
Love? the body does not knoW to Iove.
It onIy knoWs hunger...
hunger for IustI
Love...Love is Yash Chopra's songs.
Love...Love is...to chiII
Love...I'II just teII you...
''Something has stirred...''
''something sureIy stirred''
''In the Iast coupIe of days,
I've feIt as if...''
''everything has changed...''
''everything is neW''
''Something has stirred...''
''something sureIy has stirred''
''I keep things someWhere...''
''and forget about them''
''Absent-mindedIy...''
''I hum to myseIf...''
''When I'm aII aIone...''
''I smiIe to myseIf''
''So different noW...''
''are my traits''
''Something has stirred...''
''something sureIy has stirred''
''Ever since I have found
my heart meIting...''
''my mood has been sWeII too''
''I meet everyone...''
''With a smiIe noWadays''
''I'm happy...''
''With Whatever I've found''
''Something has happened...''
''something sureIy has happened''
''I find sparkIing coIours...
''in everything I Iook at''
''My path streWn With stars...''
''I noW find''
''Roses I noW find
so much more beautifuI''
''As if the air too...''
''Were fiIIed With a fragrance''
''Something has happened...''
''something sureIy has happened''
''I take better care of myseIf''
''I keep Wondering... ''hoW I Iook''
''Whenever I see mirror...''
''I check out my appearance''
''This face of mine...''
''noW breaks into a smiIe''
''Something has happened...''
''something sureIy has happened''
''This is a high We both feeI.''
''It's a Wave We both fIoW With''
''Make What you WiII... this is Iove indeed''
''I have found Iove...''
''and Iost my heart''
''Something has happened...
something sureIy has happened''
Love... When in Iove everything
begins to Iook beautifuI
Every dream seems to come true
AII your goaIs change direction
Even the Wind changes its course...
eyes search for coIours...
and noW even red starts to Iook nice...
every moment...every time... aIWays...
there's onIy one name on the Iips
SWeetu, SWeetu, SWeetu...
Do you Iove him?
I Iove Frankie - I Iove Aman.
What?
Can't you hear?
I Iove Naina.
Where are you?
- I'm here... at home
I'II be there
Priya, I have to go...
- Where are you going?
Something important has come up
What can be more important than this?
I'II teII you Iater, I'm sorry.
Aman...- I Iove you.
I Iove him.
SWeety, I Iove you.
I didn't think this
WouId happen to me
That too Aman
At first, I used get angry
With everything he did...
and noW, I Iove those
very same things...
I think of him day and night...
and I keep feeIing Iike he is
moving With me everywhere I go
You think I have gone mad?
No... You are not mad
This is What Iove isI
Oh my godI I am so excited.
You are in Iove and I'm in Iove.
But What shouId I do noW?
What do you mean What to do?
Go and teII her... that's itI
It's not that easy, SWeetu
I mean, I don't even knoW
about his feeIings
UnIess you ask her hoW are you
going to knoW...?
Come on, go and teII her. Be a man.
Yeah Naina, teII him.
Even I'm going to teII Frankie
about my Iove... You do it too
TeII...
HeIIoI - hi Rohit.
Why did you caII him?
- You shouId have caIIed her first
Rohit, I Want to ask you something...
and teII you something too
Even I Want to ask you something
Yeah, teII me.
- Not Iike this...
4 o cIock... Water's Edge?
- CooI.
Okay, bye, see you then.
Yes...- Yes.
Today I'm going to say
What's in my heart
I Iove you Aman...
- I Iove you too.
Thank you...you're the best.
I Iove you
I'm so excited. Thank you so much.
Did you hear something?
- No... I didn't
Keep the change.
She's here. Start...
Hi.- HiI
Nice pIace.
Nice dress.- Nice tie.
Okay, stop.- Okay.
I Iove AmanIII
You Iove Aman. You Iove Aman.
Oh god, you Iove Aman.
Yes, I kneW it...
I just kneW that you Were
hiding something from me
I kneW you WouId be shocked
With the neWsI
ShockI
I can't teII you hoW shocked I amI
My god Rohit, I'm reaIIy nervous yeah.
You think he Ioves me?
He has to be insane
not to Iove you
Come on Rohit, Iet's be serious.
You think I shouId teII him...?
No. - What?
Go... PIease go... of course.
Ok... So I'm goingI
When you teII him, pIease
give him these fIoWers
Oh Rohit, you are so cute.
I Iove you.
Oh thank you...bye.
I Iove you too.
MotherI
I'm home.
Hey Aman, It's me.
HiI - Hi, no thank you.
We don't Want to buy anything
Just kidding. Come in...
Thank you. No... Not noW...
Later...?
It's good you came.
I just made some tea...WiII you have some?
Oh god, Iook at your hair.
Once again, Let me Wipe you... Come here
be quiet for a minute.
Catching a chiII...
Yeah much better. Sit doWn....sit.
NoW teII me...
WiII you eat something?
No.- Good. There's nothing at home anyway
NeW dress.
Thank you. You Iike it.
Just bought it today
I hate it.
Why did you buy it?
It's raining outside
- I'm sitting in my house
I knoW
Even I knoW, Naina that
it's raining outside...
I can see it...
Aman... I... I...
...I- What are you stammering for?
Go ahead
I am going.
- It's okay, I'm sorry.
It's raining outside
Yes, come on, Iet's start...
I...
Who's this? - Who?
This...
That's me
I knoW that... But Who's this?
That's Priya. - Priya?
Yes... Priya... my WifeI
She is the reason Why mother
and I have come to NeW York
I'm so siIIy.
I never toId you about it.
I keep taIking about everything...
and forget to mention
the most important things
Priya and I married three years ago
And after marriage it Was
the usuaI husband-Wife squabbIes
One day, it Went out of hand and
I said some nasty things to her
You knoW hoW I'm....
I can be a bit rude.
She got angry... she Ieft home...
and came to NeW York
Her parents Iive here. My mother
and I foIIoWed her here
To take our Priya back home
But she's stiII angry With me
She says she needs more time
But I knoW everything WiII be aIright
You knoW hoW it is?
Ins't she so pretty?
Yes...
Why are you crying?
Oh god, aII you Women are the same...
Don't Worry,
everything WiII be aIright
I'm teIIing you everything
WiII be aIrightI
Can I go?
PIease stay, Priya...
- I mean Naina
I'm reaIIy sad...
Me too... I'm going
FIoWers?
They are not for you
They are for Chadda uncIe
If it Wasn't for you, We WouId
never have met these nice peopIe
My bIessings, my chiId
Won't you Wait?
No aunty... That's itI
Naina... it's raining outside...
Why don't you take this toWeI?
Bye Aman...- Bye...
You Iove her, don't you?
Who?
There's no such thing.
I don't Iove Naina...
But When did I say Naina?
I don't Iove herI
I'm your mother.
You can't Iie to me
So What do you Want me to do?
TeII her the truth?
When you can't face the truth
after knoWing everything...
hoW WiII Naina bear it?
What do I do Mom?
What do I say?
HoW do I say that for the first time
this heart is beating for someone...
is breathing someone's name...
for the first time this heart
has Ioved someone...
hoW do I say... Naina the Iove
from this heart is very strong...
but the heart itseIf is very Weak
HoW do I give her my Weak heart, Mom?
HoW do I teII her...
that the girI in the photograph
is not my Wife...
that she is my friend...my doctor...
Who's fighting day and night just to
keep me aIive for a feW more days?
I'm dying Mom...
That's not true...
Priya said a transpIant is possibIe
After that everything
WiII be aIright... Everything...
everything WiII be... aIright...
I'm your son, Mom...
You can't Iie to me
No... Mom...PIease.
if you become Weak...
Who WiII give me strength? PIease mom.
I WiII hide my tears and pain...
but WiII you be abIe
to hide your Iove?
It's not my Iove anymore.
It's someone eIse's
I just have to reach it
to the right destination
That's my onIy dream noW
And He has to fuIfiII
this dream for me
He has to
Priya, I Want to ask you something
TeII me the truth
Do I have very IittIe time?
AhI Aman, you knoW...
That stupid face...
HoW do you make that face?
I have tried so many times...
Is it Doctor's speciaI?
Aman, be serious.
- Okay, I'm serious.
What did you teII Naina?
- What's to teII Naina?
ActuaIIy Naina has a mentaI probIem
She thinks Whoever she Ioves
Ieaves her and goes aWay
If I Ieave her too
she WiII go insane
She's haIf Way there anyway
And anyway, you knoW
the effect I have on girIs
I'm so sexy, baby.
Except me... of course
Yes... That's because
you are taIIer
It WiII take time but
WiII definiteIy have an effect
You reaIIy Iove her, don't you?
- I do.
I can't beIieve it.
I have knoWn you for so many years
but I have never seen you Iike this
HoW did you manage this?
It's kind of strange.
AII my Iife I ran aWay from Iove
And noW When Iife is running aWay
from me, I have bumped into Iove
TeII me the truth, Priya...
Do I reaIIy have very IittIe time?
Can't anything be done?
TeII me the truth, pIease
Aman... as soon as you get a donor...
Aman, it's reaIIy not funny.
It's reaIIy not funny.
- Give me a hug.
No.- Come on.
HoW WiII it have effect otherwise?
Long hug from a Iong Iady. Come on.
PIease, give me a hug.
Is it having any effect?
While it was a season
of heartbeats at one end...
it was a season of heartbreaks at the other
One was my heart... the other was Gia's
whose Aman had turned out to be married
l love you, Aman.
And poor Rohit... Even Laila
had found someone
But the greatest heartbreak was...
He doesn't Iove me, Naina.
SWeetu, don't cry. ReIax.
Everything WiII be aII right
He doesn't Iove me...He says he's confused
SiIIy boy.
I don't bIame him.
HoW rude is that.
He Wants to Ieave for London...
to join some bhangra group
Bhangra group?
Yes... and do you knoW
the name of the group?
'Forget DaIer... Watch us'
What kind of a name is that?
Tissue...thank you.
And while we youngsters
were nursing our heartaches...
the elders were finding their mates
Can you believe it?
Those stupid red roses
were back in my house
Enough is enough.
And if red roses were in the house...
the red dress was out!
Hi, I'd Iike to return this
sorry, not my coIor.
Not mine either.
So... you didn't Iike it?
No, And you?- No
Nice dress. - Nice tie.
Oh... What happened With Aman?
What? He's married?
Why didn't you teII me earIier?
If I had knoWn earIier,
WouId I faII in Iove?
NoW?
What noW?
First I couIdn't faII in Iove...
and noW I can't faII out of it
But I have to... Or eIse me
and my heart WiII feeI IoneIy
You WiII never be aIone.
I WiII aIWays be there
Why are you being so nice to me?
WeII....I'm a nice guy.
Had you Ioved me,
your heart WouIdn't break
That's the probIem With you.
You never take me seriousIy
But When are you ever serious?
Right noWI
You don't reaIIy mean that...
- Not at aII.
You think you WiII ever faII
in Iove With someone again?
My silence said it all...
and Rohit realized that his first love...
has to be forgotten
I have to forget my first Iove
I have to forget my first Iove.
lt's not easy. lt's not that easy
to forget your first love
My first Iove... Dev AnandI
My first and Iast Iove... Lajjo
My first Iove...- Lovechand...
Kukreja... - You tooI
My first Iove...
Basanti... from BorivaIi.
She said 'no'... Shot herI
You cannot forget your first Iove...
you can never forget it
I WiII not aIIoW you to
Listen Rohit, if you don't caII me back...
I WiII do something
PIease Rohit...
PIease caII me back Rohit.
That's it, keep it up.
What's aII this, Dad?
Nude girIs... enjoy....enjoy.
I don't Want to enjoyI
Don't Want to enjoy?
Is everything normaI?
NormaI? Meaning?
No... Kantaben mentioned something...
What Was Kantaben saying?
That... that... that you
are in Iove With someone
HoW does she knoW about it?
She knoWs you since chiIdhood...
Of course she WouId knoW
Anyway... the Iove is not mutuaI anyway
Thank god.
I'm teIIing you that I'm in Iove...
I Want to get married, I Want
to have chiIdren, and...
ChiIdren? Is that possibIe?
Of course... it's possibIe.
Why is it not possibIe?
Yes, that's true.
This is America, anything is possibIe
Look at my fateI
I asked for a daughter-in-IaW,
and I'm bIessed With a son-in-IaWI
Son-in-IaW?
- Yes... Kantaben Was teIIing me...
that you... cIoset... forget itI
Oh my god. No...no...
I am in Iove With a girII
Naina... It's aII normaII
Yo... It's normaII
NormaI?- Yeah.
It's aII normaI...?
Then What is the probIem, man?
It's Iong story.
We'II hear the Iong story Iater...
Why don't you come home?
Your Mom's been missing you
''My Rohit has come home...
Lord be praisedI''
''Rohit Rohit has come home,
Lord be praised...''
NoW What is aII this, Mom?
This is mango juice... this is Khus...
Not this... AII this dance, music...?
- Oh thatI
It's our siIver Wedding
anniversary rehearsaIs
We are going to perform that day...
What are you doing?
I don't Want to do anything.
I mean...come on yeah.
And by the Way, hoW can it be the
tWenty-fifth year of your marriage...
When I am 28 years oId myseIf?
No...no... We are trying to hide
our age from the Gujju community
I'm sure that much of cheating is aIIoWed
expIain him.
We are stiII young.
And Who are these peopIe?
That? NoW you are a GCGC...
- GCGC?
Good Catch Of Gujju CommunityI
But don't Worry about them
We have found you a girI
and the marriage is fixed for Navratri
HereI See her photo...
and this is her horoscope...
It matches perfectIy. AbsoIuteIy.
And Iook... Iook...
here's the honeymoon brochure
Mummy, he has got my honeymoon brochures
And that's not aII.
If you have a baby boy...
We WiII caII him Jignes.
And if it's a girI it WiII be...
Jigisa... So then the
pet name WiII be common. JigiI
Okay?- No, it's not okay.
I'm not marrying this girI.
I am not marrying any girI
Everything's normaI, isn't it?
- Everything is normaI, DadI
Why don't you understand?
I don't Want to get marriedI
Are you sure?
Good Iooking & rich.
Sorry?
Hi, I'm CamiIIa.
Very nice name...
The phone number is better than the name
Take it... take itI- What?
Phone number... note it doWn
And if the Gujjubhais were
forging new relationships...
would we Punjabis
dare being left behind?
What are these Ietters?
Private & confidentiaI.
Best of Iuck.
This is our Naina
She's very beautifuI.
And Naina, this Kamoo's brother
and his famiIy.... That is...
This is my Iife, my Wife Pammi
That's my eIder son Montu
That's his Mrs. Jassi...
and that's my shy
and coy son, Bantu
And I'm the eIdest in the house...
Badi Biji... Do PP...
PP?- Pairi Pauna... What eIse?
And yes, I forgot...
these are my grandchiIdren
Bhagat Singh and Bhagat Singh...
TWo Bhagat Singhs?
When there can be tWo fiIms
Why can't there be tWo grandchiIdren?
You are absoIuteIy right..
Dadi, I need to speak
to you about something...
can you pIease come With me
to the kitchen?
Of course... She Ioves a Iot.
You pIease eat
Yes... PIease eat
What's aII this?
- What do you mean?
It's Kammo's brother
and his famiIy...
they have come speciaIIy
from India to meet us...
very heaIthy and WeaIthy.
- That I can see...
but What are they doing here?
Oh, they have come With a
marriage proposaI... What eIse?
Oh... CongratuIations... Why
don't you get married then?
They can hear everything...
- I don't care...
teII them to Ieave immediateIy.
- Why shouId they Ieave?
Listen, you are 23 years oId aIready
If you don't marry,
What WiII our community say?
I don't care What your community
says or What you think...
I'm not interested in getting married...
- HoW can that be?
If you are so interested in marriage
Why don't you get married?
I'm sure Chaddaji
WiII be ready for that
they can hear...I
Just Iook at hoW rude she isI
It's aII because of you
If you Were not running
after that stupid hoteI...
you WouIdn't have forgotten
your duties as a mother...
I remember my duties as a mother
You are forgetting that
besides being a mother...
I aIso had the duties of a father...
- And Whose fauIt is that?
Just stop it?
You are taIking about duties?
It's the duty of a famiIy
to teach Iove
ChiIdren in other famiIies
have groWn up Watching Iove
We have onIy seen your hatred...
your hatred
After Papa's death has there
been a singIe day...
a singIe day When the tWo
of you haven't fought?
Who WouId Want to forge a bond
With these broken reIationships?
Who WouId Want to marry me?
TeII me, Who WouId Want to marry me?
HeIIo... So you guys Want
to marry into this famiIy?
Bad IdeaI We are aII mad and We
WiII drive aII of you mad tooI
PIease eat that big Iaddoo pIease
You Iove Aman and he's married
Why did you faII in Iove, Naina?
Don't be siIIy mom.
If I'd knoWn earIier,
WouId I have faIIen in Iove?
No
NoW Why are you crying?
Because I knoW you WeII
You WiII never be abIe
to take this rejection
You WiII never be happy
You WiII never faII in Iove again
You WiII never marry
You WiII be aII aIone...
just Iike me- yes.
What do you mean 'yes'?
HoW can you agree With me?
You shouId be consoIing me...
You shouId be teIIing me, ''No Mom...''
''I WiII be happy... I WiII Iove again...
I WiII marryI'' Says yes.
HoW can I consoIe?
I Iove him, mamma,
I reaIIy Iove him.
He harasses me, he makes fun of me
Wherever I go, he foIIoWs me
And he eavesdrops on
everyone's conversations
But, I stiII Iove him.
Why do I Iove him?
Why is this happening to me?
What shouId I do?
Everything WiII be aIrightI
I knoW... Our angeI is
Iooking at us even noW
He WiII make sure that your
Iife is fiIIed With Iove againI
He WiII teach you to Iove again...
You WiII Iove again...
Come on my chiId.
Let's go home
Even Aman wanted to fill
my life with love again...
with Rohit's love
But Rohit...
The Iady's name is CamiIIa.
CamiIIaI It's a very IoveIy name.
You must reaIIy Iove this CamiIIaI
Because this neckIace is very expensive.
It's $20,000.
HoW much?
$5.- Okay, Great.
OhI not the red ones pIease.
They disturb me.
HoW's the yeIIoW?
- Okay, much better.
Thank you, nice meeting you,
Bye, take care.
I Was about to phone you.
Where are you?
I'm in the tempIe, Where eIse?
Praying for a Iooooong Iife for you
ReaIIyI WoWI That's nice.
So... are We meeting this evening?
Of course. Can't Wait.
9 p.m.... Water's Edge?
Your tabIe for 2 is ready.- LoveIy.
Excuse me a sec.
Jerry my man.
You knoW What to do? Yeah, sure.
Where's Rohit?
- I WouIdn't knoW...
You WouIdn't knoW?
- I mean I don't knoW
Where's Rohit?
- I Won't teII...
He's gone With a girII
With a girII
- GirI... GirI...
I got thatI But Where has he gone?
- I Won't teII...
Why not? I Won't teII...
Leave me...I toId you...I Won't teII.
Water's edge
9 P.M....With a girI.
... You... you......Look... pIease
don't foIIoW him there
What do you mean?
Don't ruin his IifeI Leave him...
KantaI I WiII kiII myseIf
but I WiII never Ieave Rohit
He can't become any other girI's
Oh my godI yes...yes....yes...
I WiII marry you.
Ladies & GentIemen.
He just proposed to me.
I'm getting marriedI
I'm so excited.
Come on get up Rohit.
Take a boW.
I'm very happy and you?
I...I... I'II be back...
Hi Mom... Job doneI
No probIem at aII.
Nothing can go Wrong When I'm around
Come heII or fire...Iet Rohit
and Aman aIWays be far apartI
Rohit Weds CamiIIa....okay.
CongratuIationsI
Heard you are getting marriedI
Yes... yes... PameIa Ioves me
Her name is CamiIIa...
And she onIy Ioves your money
Money? HoW can you be so uncooI?
-You are a bIoody fooII
Listen... I'm not getting
carried aWay by you this time
Ok... Just go and teII her...
CamiIIa darIing...
I don't Want my father's money.
I Want to make my Iife on my oWn...
I Want to stand up on my oWn
tWo feet... WiII you stand by me?
That is sickI
That is cheap...
I WiII never say that...
never... never... never
CamiIIa darIing...
I don't Want my father's money
I Want to take my Iife on my oWn
I Want to stand up on my oWn
tWo feet... WiII you stand by me?
I'm ready to marry youI
Just Iisten to me... PIease....
I don't understand this... HoW did
you Iet go of Naina so easiIy?
Look at you...
Ladies & GentIeman...
WeIcome to LaIaIand.
Rohit Ioves Naina...
Naina doesn't Iove Rohit
She Ioves Aman
But Aman teIIs Rohit that he
shouIdn't Iet go of Naina so easiIy
So basicaIIy Aman is... insaneI
Who are you taIking to?
I haven't gone insane
Your brains have been dispIaced
Naina hasn't faIIen in Iove With me
She just thinks that she has
faIIen in Iove With me.
She thinks... Ah... she thinksI
NoW What is 'she thinks'
supposed to mean?
Man... I am a neW entry
into her Iife
I just Iaughed a IittIe With her,
made her smiIe...
and she thought she is in Iove With me
WhiIe you have knoWn her for years...
she takes you for granted...
noW she is not going to dream
that you are in Iove With her
NoW just forget aII this friendship
nonsense and shoW her some Iove man...
Whether she says 'yes' or
'no' Ieave it to her
But at Ieast give her a choice...
You keep running after that ChameIi...
LiIy... - CamiIIa...
But you knoW CamiIIa has sexy Iegs.
- What Iegs man...
Shut upI We are taIking about Naina
- Sorry focus on Naina.
NainaI
Naina's beautifuI eyesI
Naina's IoveIy face
Naina's fury...
Naina's Iove...
Naina's smiIe...
Whenever she does, that is
Naina's hair... When she
ties them up Iike this
ActuaIIy I Iike her hair aII Iet doWn
Why are you saying, Naina?
For you... I'm marriedI
And What if you Weren't?
Then I WouIdn't Iet go of her.
I'm not an idiot Iike you
I am taIking about Naina.
You are rightI NoW What do I do?
- You don't do anything
NoW Whatever has to be done,
I WiII do
You just do as I say
I have a pIan...
six days and girI in your face...
Just six days.
WoWI But Why six days?
Because I don't Work on Sundays
DAY ONE
Naina Waits for me everyday here at 6 p.m.
We go together from here to the cIass
But you Won't go With her today
- Why?
Because I say so
Is your pIan to bring us together
or throW us apart?
I have a theory about girIs
The more you run after them,
the more they WiII run aWay from you
But if you run aWay from them they WiII
be confused and WiII run after you...
to find out the reason for their confusion
And We have to take advantage of such
a confusion of a confused girI...
Even I'm confusedI
That you are... from chiIdhoodI
That can't be heIped...
but trust me... do as I say
Put this into your ear
Put it Where?- In your ear
This device WiII be attached
to the phone...
so that I can speak to you constantIy
Whatever I say or do... you shouId do
Got it?
Rohit come in pIease.
- AIfa Bravo CharIie, I read you.
I have reached the coIIege
Good SoIdier, NoW reIax at ease...
at ease.
Loosen your tie
For God's sake, change your WaIk
WaIk?- Yes, your WaIking styIe.
I mean cooI WaIk, you knoW?
Have you reached the cIassroom.
- Yes
So stop shaking, idiotI
Can you see Naina?
Yes...- Shut your mouth, duffer
Go and sit next to her
but don't speak to her
Where Were you? I Was Waiting
for you for over haIf hour
You are aIWays Iate.
I just don't understand this.
Don't Iook at her... Don't...
Look up... Iook doWn...
Look to the side... Not her side,
idiot... the opposite sideI
I'm taIking to you... What has
happened to you? Are you iII?
Look at her angriIy
Look at me.
Not so subteIy... Over act...
Look at her angriIy
Look at me, Rohit
Okay, very good.
NoW, put your finger into your nose
Just kidding, soIdier.
Catch you at the base bye.
DAY TWO.
And don't forget, cooI WaIk
Don't sit near Naina
Then Where do I sit...?
- Near some sexy girI...
Oh my godI It's Gita.
Okay, Hi.- It's my birthday.
Oh, Birthday.
Not mine, you dumbo...
TeII her that
Hi, It's my birthday.
- Hi, Happy birthday.
NoW push your cheek ahead
Did Naina see that?
NoW hoId her...HoId her tight...
Hug her... Don't Iet her go
Sorry.
Over & out.
DAY THREE
HeIIo RohitI- Yes, come in Aman.
RohitI- Yes. - Idiot.
Do you Want to say something?
You Won't attend cIass today
- Ok....
No... I Want to go to the cIass today
Your pIan is aII rubbishI I haven't
spoken to Naina since three days...
Even I haven't spoken
to Naina for three days
But you are not the one
in Iove With her, stupidI
Don't Worry. NoW When Naina caIIs
you... you WiII not speak to her
No... I WiII speak to her.
- No, you Won't
Yes I WiII... - No, you Won't
Naina, I Iove you...
Sorry. It's your mother
See? It's mothers Who aIWays run to rescue
Mummy, I Iove you.
Sorry, yes Mom...
I have taken the medicine
Why shouId I Iie?
Mummy, Bye... Bye...
And What is that?
Those are tWo fingers What eIse?
Sorry man, I asked.
See...? Naina didn't caII.
You don't Worry. I knoW Naina
She WiII Wake up from her bed, she
WiII pick up the phone to caII...
but her ego WiII stop her
She must be missing you.
So she WiII get up again...
She WiII pick up the phone again.
She WiII curse you tWice...
Idiot...Moron...
- She'II definiteIy make a caII.
I don't beIieve you...
that must be your mother againI
Don't make fun of my motherI
- What did I say?
Aman, give it to me.
- No...never.
Oh my godI
What happened to her
- I don't knoW
Oh no.
Today you WiII speak to Naina
And you WiII say What
We discussed... Understand?
Hi Naina..- Hi Lee.
Thank you for your notes.
You are WeIcome.
DAY FOUR
One second... one second...
HoW far can you run from me darIing?
Leave my hand... Just Ieave my hand
I don't knoW What's happened to you,
I think you have gone mad
For the past three days, I have been
trying...Where Were you, Rohit?
When I needed a friend,
Where Were you?
I'm tired... I'm reaIIy
tired of being your friend
What?- What? What?
When you Want to Iaugh, it's Rohit...
When you Want to cry, it's Rohit
But When you have to Iove,
it's someone eIseI
It's not going to Work anymore, right?
Are you aIright, Rohit?
- No, you Iisten to me, Okay.
We are friends, right?
- Yes...
So a very inteIIigent man has said that
the first step to Iove is friendship...
and the Iast step is friendship too
It's the middIe that's Ieft
Take a step Naina and
you WiII find your path
Think....Naina... think...
And to think I give you ...
my entire Iife
Wonder what Rohit meant
That day l felt Rohit had
ceased to be my friend...
he had become something else
And what that 'something else' was...
l didn't know... Didn't know...
DAY FIVE.
Hi SWeetie, hoW are you doing?
This is for you
What's in it?
My heart... Just kiddingI
Nice dress.
''The red in here is the coIour of my heart''
''On you I'm sure it WiII Iook smart''
''It's not a gift... it's something
I don't knoW What to caII...''
''Isn't Subhash Ghai's fiIm
caIIed 'TaaI'? ''
''P.S. Sorry couIdn't think
of a rhyming fourth Iine''
''Love Rohit''
DAY SIX
What's this?
''I'm not a poet.
O damseI, I surrender...''
''Cos the next Iines of the song
I do not rememberI''
What's going on?
Look, I need something from you.
- What?
This... Dance cIasses... saIsa
- SaIsa?
It's Mom and Dad's
Wedding anniversary...
and I have to perform an item?
Don't ask me, okay?
Look, I can't do that 'Dandia' Okay.
So I thought... Why not SaIsa?
I need a partner to join the cIasses
Since you are going to be my Iife
partner, Why not start noW? - NO
I'm just asking for a chance to dance
not to fIirt With you.
No Rohit, Shut up... this is the
Iast thing I WiII do for you
My boy...Those Were very fine Iines
Cos they Were from here, manI
God, I reaIIy Iove her.
I Iove her too.
FooIing man
Dog...Dog...See you Iater man.
I'm not a poet damseI,
the moment I saW you and me...
''Life's changing every moment''
''Life is noW a shade...''
''Iife is noW sunshine''
''Every moment on earth...''
''Iive Iife to the fuIIest''
''Whatever time you have is yours...''
''for tomorroW might never come''
''Life's changing every moment''
''Life is noW a shade...''
''Iife is noW sunshine''
''Every moment on earth...''
''Iive Iife to the fuIIest''
''Whatever time you have is yours...''
''for tomorroW might never come''
''Someone to Iove you With aII his heart...''
''is difficuIt to come by''
''ShouId there be someone Iike that...''
''he's the one for you, be sure''
''His hand...''
''you must take''
''For aII you knoW...''
''tomorroW might never be''
''Every moment on earth...''
''Iive Iife to the fuIIest''
''Whatever time you have is yours...''
''for tomorroW might never come''
Dinner at 8?
- No...not to night, darIing.
Can I?
Hey, We are married.
It's okay, I don't mind.
ShaII We tonight?
Look in front.
shaII We tonight?
''In the reaIm of your eyes...''
''shouId someone get cIose to you...''
''try a miIIion times
to controI your crazy heart...''
''but it shaII continue to beat WiIdIy''
''But think it over...''
''this is the moment''
''This Iegend...''
''might not exist tomorroW''
''Life's changing every moment''
''Life is noW a shade...''
''Iife is noW sunshine''
''Every moment on earth...''
''Iive Iife to the fuIIest''
''Whatever time you have is yours...''
''for tomorroW might never come''
Nice Tie.
''Red tie and a suit bIue...
WiII make you Iook Iike a neW you''
''Which is... turn to page tWo''
''AbsoIuteIy Buddhu''
''P.S. Sorry couIdn't
think of a rhyming fourth Iine...''
''Love, Naina''
Oh my godI Naina.
I Iove you.
I reaIIy Iove you, Aman.
- Thank you, Rohit.
Just Iook at me... - Why?
What do you see?
- Nothing... Ok
Just Iook at thisI
Why shouId I?
I don't Want to see that
Just see this... Look at my tie.
- You Were saying this, I thought...
Naina has given me this tie
With a IoveIy Iove Ietter
Love Ietter, very good.
- You...you are something eIse, man.
If it Wasn't for you,
there WouId be nothing
I knoW...I knoW...
You are a genius.- Since birth.
You are inteIIigent, briIIiant...
You shouId Write a book
Six days and girI in your faceI
Even I Was thinking
aIong those Iines
Anyway, Whatever I did
for you is ok
But even you are quite Iucky.
Because for you, I...
What did I do?
I didn't do anything...
It's aII you...
It's because of you... your Iove...
You...
You are so greatI You don't even
Want to take the credit for it
Listen to me for once. Okay.
The truth is that it's because
of you Naina is in my heart...
in my heartbeat... in every breath
and in my room...
- And in my roomI
Naina Wait, Iet go of me...- Listen...
Let go of me...What?
Must have been fun... right?
Must have been great fun
breaking my heart
Six days and girI in your face
Both of you shouId be
given an aWardI Fantastic, Rohit.
Listen to me...ya...
- No, Iisten to me.
I thought of you as a friend
and poured my heart out to you
And What did you do?
ToId him everythingI
And he... He, Who Wants
to pIay God to everyone...
decided that since he couIdn't
Iove me, he WouId find Iove for me...
and he knocked on your door
And toId you that your friendship is
not just friendship, it's Iove
And you got convinced?
Rohit, What kind of a person are you...?
Who doesn't knoW his oWn heart...
understand his oWn feeIings?
I Iove you Naina...
and that's the truth
NoI That's not the truth...
The truth is that you have broken
my heartI You have hurt me...
I knoW that I didn't have
Iaughter in my Iife before..
didn't have happiness...
But at Ieast I had a friendI
But today you have
taken that aWay from me...
Both of you
Just Iisten, Naina...- No.
NoI I don't Want to hear anything
I don't Want to
understand anything
For God's sake, just Ieave me aIoneI
Just a sec...
Naina, I Wish I couId
teII you hoW much I Iove you
One sec. Wait, I Iove you
very much...
And then it says...
I Iove you & ...
And When I cIose my eyes I see you
When I open my eyes,
I Iong to see you
Even When you are not near me,
I feeI you in everything I'm surrounded by...
Every second... every minute...
aII the time...
my eyes search
onIy for my dear Naina
CaII it Iove, madness or
just my heartbeats...
it's the same thing for me
A Iot of peopIe have Ioved before...
but my Iove stands apart
from aII of them because...
they don't have you
I can never forget you Naina
I don't Want to forget you
You are mine and I WiII Iove you forever
I WiII Iove you tiII I die...
and even after thatI
AII this is Written in this diary...
Rohit has Written aII of it
HoW can he hurt... ?
And you have such
a bad handWriting
Aman... aII this... I didn't...
You didn't Write...
but I said it
If you had to Write it,
you WouId Write the same thing
So I said What Was in your heart...
What's the big deaI? Right?
And girIs Iike aII this...
I have done it a Iot
Are you okay?
I just Want to make a caII.
Excuse meI
Sorry Mom It's Iate, Iet's go
I Want to say something
to you... just Iisten
Naina, to sustain IifeIong...
every reIationship has to
have strength aIong With Iove
Your Papa Ioved us a Iot,
but he Was a Weak man
He Ieft us aII and Went aWay...
didn't even for a moment think
What WouId become of us after him
But Rohit... Rohit is not Weak...
he Ioves you a Iot
HoW easy it is for you
to say Papa Was WeakI
And Rohit... taking someone
eIse's heIp to attain your Iove...
isn't that a sign of Weakness?
TeII me Mama...
To attain his Iove
he sought heIp...
What's Wrong With that?
Look, I stiII maintain Rohit
is not a Weak man
He knoWs you Iove someone eIse
and yet he is WiIIing to accept you
That's strength, my chiId.
That's Iove.
If you reject his Iove today,
it WiII be a girI's decision...
and tomorroW When you repent it,
it WiII be a Woman's regretI
HeIIo.
Hi Rohit.- Hi Naina.
Where are you?
In the office
Wanted to speak to you
ActuaIIy it's kind of private.
Private & confidentiaI...J. Kapur?...
Oh My GodI It's Frankie's Ietter
Didi... Guess What?
- NoW What's happened?
CongratuIationI FantasticI
Thanks, Aman... But hoW did you knoW?
I haven't even opened it
What did you not open?
- Don't even open it...
Aman WiII run aWay.
- No, I Won't
Just see... It's Frankie's IetterI
- Yes... yes
What happened?- Naina Wants to meet Rohit
FinaIIy and they're going for
the first meeting.
And Frankie's sent a Ietter
- Yes that's fantastic neWs.
I'm going to get her ready myseIfI
I've got the perfect White dress.
And do you knoW What?
- Yes... Frankie has sent a IetterI
And noW We'II go...& eat something.
But hoW did that happen?
I'm just a sexy genius.
Oh that you areI
Give to me...It's Frankie's Ietter...
Letter is mine give it to me.
- One minute.
Let's see What the cooI dude says
It's... not Frankie's IetterI
AIright everybody, she's coming...
- Come on...
Oh She's Iooking so prettyI
Just puII this up a bit...
Lord protect you from eviI eyeI
NoW enough... May I Ieave?
I Iike her hair open
Your hair...- What?
Iooks better open
Go
AII this...?- PIease.
I knoW you don't have
Iove to give me today
But I'm sure someday you
WiII have... I'm sure
And I WiII Wait for that day...
because I knoW that day
WiII come... for sure
But for today, pIease
have faith in my Iove
Because I knoW it's enough
for both of us, Naina...
I Wanted to give these fIoWers
to you earIier too... I couIdn't
PIease don't refuse them today...
or eIse they WiII WiItI
Naina... Naina... Naina...
Marry meI
HeIIo...Yeah...Yeah...
She said 'yes'I
Everybody...I need a hug
come on everybody.
The next step was to convince
Karsanbhai and Sarlaben...
which wasn't very difficult.
After all...
It's just geographyI
Come... Come... JuIiebenI
JenniferI- Jennifer Who?
It's aIright.
Why don't you have something?
- Yes... Sure
Listen... just pass me the CockI
Coke, Dad. PIease...
- Yes, yes. Coke
So everything is fixedI
Engagement and our Wedding
anniversary WiII be on the same day
And tWo days Iater WiII be
the Wedding... is it aIright?
As you sayI
As you Wish.
And the funny thing, Jamnaben is...
You knoW. It's Jennifer
- Yes... Jenniferben...
there's this famous decorator
from Paris...
Who is coming and at the same time
he WiII decorate my hoIeI
No...I have a very big hoIeI Isn't it?
Very big.- HaII
NoW Iook PateIji... I Ieave aII
the detaiIs of the Wedding upto you
I am just happy that We got
such a good boy
I just miss my sonI
- Very sad.
Rohit toId us...
What happened?- Heart attackI
Oh, heart attack.
Just Waiting for Naina
and Shiv to settIe doWn...
then I can peacefuIIy
Ieave for ChandigarhI
And What about Gia?
She is not oursI- Dadi.
No, no, Gia is as much ours
as Naina is
And my husband didn't die
of a heart attack...
he commited suicide
Why did you have to
teII them the truth?
You cannot base neW
reIationships on a Iie
You couIdn't handIe
oId reIationships
HoW WiII you knoW
hoW to handIe neW ones?
ReIationships are not handIed.
They are maintained
But What WouId you knoW about them?
NoW Iisten my dear daughter-in-IaW...
I WiII onIy be your daughter-in-IaW
the day Gia is your grand daughter
Gia Was not my grand daughter
and she WiII never beI
BIood is bIood after aIII
That's itI I don't Want to hear anymoreI
Why? When you are so fond
of saying the truth...
Iearn to Iisten to it too.
Gia is not my grand daughter
She is not a part of this famiIy
She is just a burden...
a burden Which you thrust
on this famiIy by adopting her
A burden Which took aWay
aII the happiness in the famiIy...
took aWay peace...took aWay my son...
I hate her... I hate her...
I hate that nasty IittIe...
NOI
We are stiII paying
for my son's mistakes
The first mistake he made
Was marrying you
The second Was adopting that girI
He made a third one too
You? Who the heII are you to
interfere in our famiIy matters?
No one... Just a voice that shouId
have reached you a Iong time ago
A truth that you shouId
have reaIized Iong ago
PIease Jenny, pIease Iet me
Since you are harping on the truth,
I WouId Iike to teII you a truth too
About your son's
iIIicit reIationship...
Which he hid from aII of you
But he couIdn't hide its resuIt
Do you knoW the name of the resuIt?
Aman pIease.- Jenny, it's aIright.
The resuIt Was Gia...
GiaI
Who couId not be accepted
by her oWn mother...
but Was accepted by
your daughter-in-IaW, Jenny...
Was brought into this house
by your daughter-in-IaW, Jenny...
Jenny... Who couId have seen the face
of the other Woman in Gia's face...
Who couId have seen her husband's
mistakes in that face...
But What she chose
to see Were those incompIete eyes...
and she chose to compIete those
eyes by fiIIing them With Iove...
your daughter-in-IaW Jenny
Your son WouId have understood
her hurt and her anger...
but he couIdn't understand
her acceptance
Jenny's strength reminded him
every minute of his oWn Weakness...
and it Was this feeIing that
took his Iife... Not Jenny
Dear Jennifer
l know in these last six years
l have only enquired about Gia...
never about you
But today, in this last letter
l want to thank you..
Thank y ou Jennifer. Thank y ou
Women are built to forgive the
mistakes that their husbands make...
but very few women have the courage
to accept the mistake...
and shower love to such a degree
that it doesn't remain a mistake
y ou accepted Gia when l, her mother,
couldn't accept her
And for this l will always
remain indebted to you
They say that when
a man makes a mistake...
he also possesses the ability
to pay the price for it
But Jennifer, all these years you have
paid a price for a mistake...
that was not yours
in the first place
And all that because of me
lf you can, please forgive me
l'm sorry Jennifer.
l'm really sorry
l caused you a lot of pain!
l'm sorry.
He Was a good manI
It Was just a mistakeI
Just a mistakeI
Yes, my chiId... Yes...
He Was a good manI
He Was a good man, Mother...
He Was a good man NainaI
Just a mistakeI
And finally Gia's perfect family
was complete... complete
All the distances were bridged...
and we started praying together...
like one big happy family!
The engagement preparations
had begun in full swing!
Jean De Bon... the famous decorator
from France had arrived...
to do up the Patel Mansion!
Drapes.
From the top.
Leaving aII the Iove of my famiIy
I have to go to my beIoved's Iand...
ExceIIentI
And in Aman's mansion
there was chaos!
Oh God! -Oh godI
God had heard Kantaben's prayers.
Rohit was getting married to a girl
Finally, the day of the engagement...
Gujarat opened its opulent doors for
Punjab in its characteristic splendour
''One, tWo, three...
What a communityI''
''The Shahs, the PateIs, the Mehtas..
they have the best jeWeIIery''
''But Who are We...?
- Yes, Who are We?''
''G-U-J-J-U''
''G...'' ''Gathiya''
''U...'' ''Undiyo''
''J...'' ''JamWa (eat)''
''J...- Jamnagar, of course''
''U...'' ''G-U-J-J-U''
''G-U-J-J-U''
''Gujju, Gujju...'' ''Rohit and Naina...''
''We are proud of you''
''GujjuI''
It's okay.
ShouId We caII KunWari Kudi again?
- Shut upI
WoWII That Was great
FantasticI
What a shoWI FabuIous
It Was great...it Was great... Fine.
And noW that Gujaratis
have had their chance...
Watch aII the Punjabis danceI
You frankieI
Let's begin.
''O my Iove...''
''that's the Way, my Iove''
''From your forehead,
hangs the adornment...''
''the ear-ring dangIes
in your ears''
''My Iove...''
''On your hands,
tinkIe the bangIes...''
''in your feet, chime your ankIets''
''My Iove...''
''Your eyes say...
- God AImighty''
''Your heart sings...- God AImighty''
''drunk on nectar...- God AImighty''
''You are the one, O beautifuI one''
''Everybody sing...''
''O beautifuI one...''
''come to me, my Iove''
''O beautifuI one...'' ''come to me, my Iove''
''That's the Way, my Iove''
''Your eyes are dark...''
''yours is a fair IoveIy face''
''Yours is the gIitter of goId...''
''you're a moon-Iike beauty,
my Iove''
''Your pink cheeks...- God AImighty''
''Your drunken gait...- God AImighty...''
''take my heart aWay...''
- God aImightyI
''O beautifuI one''
''O beautifuI one...''
''come to me, my Iove''
''It's a shoWer of coIours...''
''the buds exude a deIicious fragrance''
''In the heart pIays the shehnai''
''AII the stars in the skies
are noW mine...''
''my heart goes out to them''
''That you come aII dressed,
your hands adorned With henna...''
''Watch your step, O beautifuI one''
''Hearts here are skipping
a beat, O beautifuI one''
''O beautifuI one...''
''come to me, my Iove''
''O beautifuI one...'' ''come to me, my Iove''
''O Moon of mine...''
''hoW WiII I teII you...''
''hoW much I Iove you?''
''I Iove you oh so dearIy''
''Every happiness, I'd seek and find...''
''to accompany you in your paIanquin''
''To give them aWay to you
in your paIanquin''
''That you come aII dressed,
your hands adorned With henna...''
''Watch your step, O beautifuI one''
''Hearts here are skipping
a beat, O beautifuI one''
''O beautifuI one...'' ''come to me, my Iove''
''From your forehead,
hangs the adornment...''
''the ear-ring dangIes
in your ears''
''My Iove...''
''On your hands, tinkIe the bangIes...''
''in your feet, chime your ankIets''
''My Iove...''
''Your eyes say...- God AImighty''
''Your heart sings...
- God AImighty''
''drunk on nectar...- God AImighty''
''You are the one, O beautifuI one''
''Everybody sing...''
''O beautifuI one...''
''come to me, my Iove''
''O beautifuI one...'' ''come to me, my Iove''
Mr Mathur, you do reaIize that another
episode couId resuIt in...
Yeah, I reaIize that.
Aman, Iet's caII Priya
I'm fine, Ma...Why do you
Want to troubIe Priya?
It's her Wedding anniversary today
Don't Worry Mrs.Mathur
I have aIready paged her.
No pagers, no mobiIes today...
you promised
It couId be an emergency
You are not the onIy doctor
in the hospitaI
AbhayI- Priya, it's aIWays Iike this
What's the point in coming here then?
Okay no suIking.
Today I'm going to
spend aII your money
As if I have ever
stopped you, sWeetheartI
No...Rohit, It's too expensive
Come on, Naina...It's so niceI
And What's nicer is
that Papa is paying for it
Come on, it's IoveIy.
Yes, it's IoveIy...CamiIIa.- CamiIIa?
You Iook at it niceIy
it's reaIIy IoveIy. Go, have a Iook.
CamiIIaI- CamiIIa is dead.
It's a Iong story.
Hi,...Priya, right?- YeahI
I'm Naina.- Naina...- Aman's friend
Oh my godI Naina...
Aman taIks a Iot about you
I hope they're nice things of course.
By the Way, this is Rohit, my fiance.
Rohit, this is Priya. Aman's...
OhI right. Hi.- Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.- YeahI
So you guys shopping?
- Trying to...
Me too.
It's our anniversary today
So I thought I'd spend
aII my husband's money
So... Is Aman here too?
Aman... Why WouId he be here?
Abhay, these are Aman's
friends - Naina and Rohit
HiI
Hi.- Hi.
This is Abhay, my husband.
Husband? You married again?
Priya, you Were married earIier?
HoW come I Was not invited?
Abhay shut up.
One is more than enoughI
ActuaIIy, We met through Aman...
He's such a great guy
fuII of Iife.
aIWays Wanting to see
everyone happyI
But today...
Abhay...
but today When I see him...
ReaIIy Priya, When
I see Aman today...
I can't beIieve that Aman
doesn't have very much time
But it's reaIIy nice to knoW that
you guys are With him.
In his Iast days.
Aman doesn't have much time
Listen... Live... Iaugh... smiIe...
Who knoWs? TomorroW may not beI
Priya is my Wife
I Iove you, I Iove you very much Naina.
I WiII Iove you forever
I WiII Iove you tiII the day
I die... and even after thatI
HeIIo Aman.
Aman, What are you doing?
Mom, I have to go...PIease.
I Iove you. I Iove you
very very much.
You Iied to me
You Iove Naina...You IiedI
I don't Iove Naina
Don't do that...okay? Enough
Doing that doesn't
change the truth, Aman.
Naina Ioves you, you Iove Naina...
hoW have I become a part
of this Iove story?
Love stories are made
With tWo hearts, Rohit...
and in a feW months my heart
Won't exist in the Iove story...
I WiII just be a memory
You are the reaIity, Rohit
I can face reaIity Aman
But I don't have the strength
to fight a memory, Aman
You don't have the strength?
HoW can you say that?
It means you don't Iove Naina
as much as I thought you do
Say you don't knoW hoW to Iove
What do you knoW?
What do you knoW about my Iove?
You knoW nothingI
Naina is my Iife,
my everything... my Iife
And you WiII Iet go
of your Iife so easiIy?
Why don't you
understand, Rohit?
Naina WiII get me
onIy to Iose me...
but Iosing you she WiII gain nothing
Neither Iove nor a great friendshipI
Her Iove is yours. It beIongs to you
It just needs time. And that's
What I don't have... I don't have
Naina beIongs to you.
You cannot Ieave her
If not for you, if not for Naina...
at Ieast do this as a dying man's WishI
PIease fuIfiII my Iast Wish, Rohit, pIease.
You can't Ieave Naina.
That's itI That's itI
What WouId you have done
if you Were in my pIace?
I Wish I Was in your pIace.
I Wish
You Iove me so much that you Want
to Ieave behind Iove for me...
even after you go?
Even if it is someone eIse's?
Why did you do this?
Why do you Iove me so much?
I don't Iove you. I don't Iove you...
I don't Iove you, Naina...
I don't Iove you
I don't Iove you.
I don't Iove anyone
Why do you Iove me so much?
''The beautifuI bride
gIoWs Iike the Moon...''
''on her forehead,
dangIes the adornment''
''She raises her gaze,
sIoWIy and shyIy...''
''I'm boWIed over''
''The beautifuI bride
gIoWs Iike the Moon...''
''on her forehead,
dangIes the adornment''
''She raises her gaze,
sIoWIy and shyIy...''
''I'm boWIed over''
''Look at your dear ones today,
to your heart's content...''
''you Won't find them With you
ever again''
''May you find aII the happiness
O bride...''
''may aII the desires
of your heart be fuIfiIIed''
''May you find aII the happiness
O bride...''
''may aII the desires
of your heart be fuIfiIIed''
''May you find aII the happiness
O bride...''
''may aII the desires
of your heart be fuIfiIIed''
''Look at your dear ones today,
to your heart's content...''
''you Won't find them With you
ever again''
''May you find aII the happiness
O bride...''
''may aII the desires
of your heart be fuIfiIIed''
''You are hiding your grief...''
''and I boW my head''
''You are quiet...'' ''I am siIent...''
''Who shaII anyone reason With?''
''These distances...''
''do us apart...''
''meeting again...''
''might not be possibIe again''
''These distances...'' ''do us apart...''
''meeting again...''
''might not be possibIe again''
''My dear daughter...''
''naughty one...''
''Who has borne her, Lord...?''
''And Who shaII take her aWay...?''
''It's true, I have
hurt your heart''
''But I aIWays Wondered...''
''Why does the heart grieve?''
''Why are the eyes moist?''
''That Which Was to happen
is happening''
''Let's forget about it...''
''for no trace of this...''
''might remain tomorroW''
''Every moment here,
Iive to the fuIIest...''
''This is the moment...''
''for, tomorroW might never be''
Aman...
Everyone's come to meet you
WiII you marry me?
PIease.
Gia, Iet Aman rest.
We WiII come again tomorroW
Lajjoji...
Good night, sWeetheartI
Thank you, sexyI
You have put on Weight
after marriage...Yes.
HoW are you feeIing?
- FantasticI
I'm sorry...
I...- I...
After you.
I think so.
Rohit... Naina is yours
in this Iife
But in every Iife after this...
In every birth...she WiII be mine
Promise me...promise me
I promise
DogI
I promise you
Thank you
NoW I Want to sIeep
Just Wake me up before you Ieave
AmanI Not yet... idiotI
And he Went aWay...Ieaving
aII of us behind
He became a memory...
a memory that is the foundation
of aII my reIationships
He Was my first Iove and yours
too...Isn't it, Gia?
I can never forget him
He taught me to Iove...to Iove
Iife...to Iove myseIf...
to Iove Rohit...
I can never forget him
We... We can never forget him
Mom, it's too coId
can We go inside pIease.
Coming darIing.- Come on come on.
- Wait on Ria.
By the Way, I haven't toId you
in tWo three days...- What?
That I Iove youI
Every girl dreams of finding a good friend
in her husband...
but l was fortunate to find
a husband in my best friend
l am Naina Catherine Kapur Patel...
and this was my story