I want to get in.
Sorry but without girl you can't enter.
- My wife is in there.
I don't give a fuck.
- You don't? - Yea.
Fuck you!
- Hey, fuck you. - No, no.
Hold on.
That's my husband.
Ok, that's your husband.
But calm down.
Don't make a riot in there.
- ok.
It's ok guys.
Peace!
Sibel!
I'm sorry that I ran away.
It's ok.
I've gone crazy?
Everybody does.
Hey babe. Are you all right?
- What do you want? - Can't you see I want you!
Piss off!
- Hey, keep cool babe!
Hey, that's my wife.
- What? - Cahit!
What Cahit...
Hold on!
Your face isn't blessed that much.
I just try to look good.
Bastards.
Why? You are one of them.
I know so little from you.
Then get to know me better.
Stop!
Stop it! Stop!
I can't! I can't!
If we do it you are my husband
and I am your wife.
Do you understand?
I'm in love!
In love!
She bewitched me.
Stop it boy!
I say stop it!
Forget your love.
Look how you look like!
Do you even know what love is?
Love is a carousel!
Always in a circle,
but you only have a wooden horse!
You don't understand!
She was called Katharina.
A very happy person.
Like a kid.
She always smiled.
Everybody liked her.
I really liked her.
What did she do?
- She painted.
Did Cahit love her?
Yes, a lot.
What a strange relationship
do you have to him?
He is my husband and I am his wife.
Do you love each other?
You wouldn't understand that.
Yea I guess I'm too stupid.
I don't even understand it.
Cahit and I fuck
from time to time.
Sibel!
- What are you doing here?
I wanted to see you.
- Why?
Niko, listen. We slept together.
I wanted to know how you are in bed.
Now I know it.
You step aside and I do, ok?
What's this? - Get your fingers off me!
I'm a married woman.
I'm a married Turkish woman and if you come to close
my husband kills you. Understood?
When did she marry?
Tell me, what a bad
husband are you!
Your girl hangs out
and you don't care.
Do you even fuck her?
Ah?
You are a pimp right?
Fuck you!
- Niko, you talk to much.
Do you earn enough money with her pussy?
Tell me...
How much would it cost to
fuck her in the ass?
50 Euros are enough?
In the brothel it's called 'Greek'?
I want to fuck a Turk
in the Greek way!
Niko!
Call a doctor!
ACT OF JEALOUSY IN ST. PAULI
Listen,
you cant stay here.
You have to leave tomorrow morning.
Without being seen.
Otherwise they tear me to pieces!
Did you understand me?
Yes.
Isn't there anybody you could go to?
Give me an answer!
No.
Holy shit!
And what do you want to do now?
They will kill me.
Who?
- My family.
Your family!
What do you expect?
You mess up all the time and then:
"My family..."!
There must be someone in Turkey?
Yes I do...
- Go there.
And what about Cahit?
What does Cahit bother you?
Can't you see what you
have done to him?
You ruined his life!
"And Cahit"!
Listen,
you really love Cahit?
Yes.
Then do him a favor:
Go!
Why do you cry,
black haired beauty?
Everything the appears
disappears again. Don't cry.
Even if your lament
climbs up to the sky.
Everything the appears
disappears again. Don't cry.
What ever happens,
after every winter there comes spring.
Everything the appears
disappears again. Don't cry.
Please do not hand over or
take over things.
Please don't talk about the
actual case either.
Please close the door.
I will wait for you.
Fasten you seatbelt, Sibel.
Your hair looks beautiful!
Are you hungry?
No.
What do you want to do now?
Can you get me a job?
In a hairdresser's salon?
I don't care.
We will see...
Smile!
How is it going?
Fine.
Sibel, don't worry.
It's just for a short while.
I'm waiting for barber
Ahmet's reply.
As soon as there is a job
needed you're in.
Take care!
I'm right there!
Do you like the hotel?
Shall I tell you a secret?
One day I will be
responsible for all this.
In a few years I will
manage the hotel...
Then you can work here.
!
How do you like that?
You can only trust yourself
Can I get a Raki?
Do you miss Cahit?
Go for it, Sibel!
I go to that date and
enter the elevator.
That's an old building with
elevators from the 80ies.
You reach the top but you can't open the door.
There is a wall...
You are not from here right?
How do you know?
l just know it.
Listen guys...
Where can I get drugs?
You are crazy?
Where have you been?
Hanging out.
- Where?
My business.
- Sibel!
My dear husband,
A few weeks have passed
since I'm here.
Istanbul is a colorful city.
Full of live.
The only one who isn't alive is me.
All I do is trying to survive.
Allah is testing us. Allah?
Allah? I don't know how to believe in him
after everything that has happened.
You got the harder lot
But prison is the only thing that I can
think of if I think of my live here.
I'm working as maid at the Marmora hotel.
Selma got me the job.
Selma, who I admired so much.
Now there's only contempt.
I hope you are fine.
Hugs and kisses. Sibel
Are you looking for somebody?
I'm looking for drugs.
What drugs?
Doesn't matter.
What's that?
- Opium.
You want to try it out?
Give it to me.
Hit...
You can work for me...
You can live here too
if you want...
What's up?
- Im moving.
Where do you want to go to?
- I met a few people.
What kind of people?
Just people...
- Sibel. Don't go.
To become like you?
Working, sleeping, working...
That's why you got divorced!
Sibel!
Yes...
Go!
Hey, babe!
What are you doing on the
street at this time?
Did you get lost?
Do you need a man?
Hold on!
Go home and fuck your mothers!
Stop laughing!
Bitch!
That's enough! That's enough!
Son of a bitch!
That's all you got?
Girl, piss off!
I fuck you now!
Who do you want to fuck?
Enough? Is it enough now?
Fuck you and your families!
What was that?
Fags!
Son of a bitch!
Come here!
Holy shit!
Oh my God I killed her!
Damnit, shit!
Did you want that, did you want that?
Run brother!
Get away!
Does it taste good?
very good!
- Isn't it?
They have good skewers here.
That's why I come often.
Cheers!
Cheers, Seref!
What do you want to do now?
I'm going to Istanbul.
To Sibel?
Yes.
Didn't you learn anything?
Hasn't she caused you enough pain already?
Without her I wouldn't have made it.
Made what?
Stay alive!
Good.
Take that!
What's that?
- Take it!
I saved it for you!
Take it and got to Turkey!
I can't!
- Take it now!
No.
Im sorry I can't.
- Stop that bullshit!
I'm your uncle. Do you remember?
Let's go to Turkey.
Thank you!
Brother-in-law?
Where is your sister?
I don't have a sister.
But you have the same mother?
How does your mother deal with it?
We had to protect our reputation.
You see.
And?
Did you protect you reputation?
Where to?
I dont know.
If you don't even know it how should I know it?
- Go straight ahead!
Okay.
Where are you from?
Hamburg.
- You are from Hamburg?
Yes. - Hey, I'm from Munich!
- Oh my god you are Bavarian?
Well in my last life I used to.
But now I'm here.
They deported me.
Deported, you know!
Why?
- Drugs.
Oh yea.
How shall I continue? Right, left?
Say something.
Get me to a cheap hotel.
There is... Ehm!
Exactly the right thing for your,
"Grand Hotel London."
Under friends...
There are ghosts in this house.
The set up is ok.
You placed the logo at the right place,
But in this sample it's too little.
I want it larger.
I don't like the font.
We have to choose one of those.
Do you have another sample?
There's somebody who wants
to talk to you. - Who?
Could we continue later?
- Sure.
Hello Selma.
Welcome.
Thanks.
Take a seat.
Yes please.
I hope you came out of
it alive! - Thanks.
How are you?
Good. And you?
As you can see...
I'm still single...
Could I have a glass of water?
- Pardon.
A glass of water for the gentleman please
and red wine for me.
That's for you.
That's not necessary.
- It's not worth to be mentioned.
Thank you. Where do you live?
At "Grand hotel London".
A nice hotel.
- It's not bad.
Thanks.
Where is Sibel?
She is here. In Istanbul.
I want to meet her. Please.
That's not possible.
- Why?
She has a new life.
She is happy.
She has a friend.
She has a daughter.
She doesn't need you.
I got lost long time before.
Do you understand?
No.
I am not.
Hello?
Cahit?
Sibel?
I can't talk at the moment.
How long are you in town?
Until I have seen you.
Hello?
There's is a call for you.
Cem is in Zonguldak for 2 days.
I don't come home tonight.
Could you take care of Pamuk?
Sweetie, are you staying with me?
Maybe I won't be back tomorrow either.
But you come back some time right?
I hope you know what you do.
No, I don't.
I wish you all the best.
What do you want to do?
Do you want to stay in Istanbul?
- Me in Istanbul? Of course not.
I go to Mersin. Where I am born.
I don't worry.
Good.
Come with me?
Let's go back.
It's me.
Fine.
What is Pamuk doing?
I want to talk to her.
How shall we do it?
We meet tomorrow at the bus station.
From there we go to Mersin.
You,
your daughter and I.
When?
- 12 o'clock.
Over there on the mountain.
There is a light fire.
Falcons are flying over its glimmer light.
Is everyone who is missing his darling
insane like I am?
I'm endlessly sad.
May my enemies get blind.
I got mad.
May the mountain rejoice instead of me.