Subtitles by: Hecko X
Member of: DKSubs
For Danish subtitles, please visit:
http://dksubs.rdwsubs.com
HOWL'S MOVING CASTLE
Sophie.
We just closed the shop,
you've done enough work.
Why don't you come out
with us this time?
No, I'd better finish this,
you go and have fun.
All right, suit yourself.
Let's go, girls.
- Wait for me! - I'm ready - Do I look okay?
- Look, it's Howl's castle!
- Wha'? - Where? - Howl? - Where?
I've never seen it so close!
You think he can see us?
You think Howl is going to town?
He's gone...
No, he's just hiding in
the fog from those plains.
Did you hear what happened to that
girl, Martha, from South Haven?
They say Howl tore her heart out.
- Now I'm too scared to go out...
- What?
Don't worry, he only
preys on pretty girls.
All right, let's go.
You guys are mean...
Hey, looks like a little
mouse lost its way.
Oh, no... I'm not lost.
This little mouse looks thirsty,
We should take her for a cup of tea.
No thanks, My sister's expecting me.
She's pretty cute for a mouse.
How old are you, anyway?
You live around here?
Leave me alone!
You see? Your moustache
scares all the girls.
So? I think she's even
cuter when she's scared.
There you are sweetheart,
sorry I'm late.
I was looking everywhere for you.
Hey, hey, we're busy here.
Are you really?
It looked to me, like the two
of you were just leaving.
- Can't... - Stop... - Stop.
Don't hold it against them.
They're actually not all that bad.
Where to? I'll be your
escort this evening.
Oh, Im, uhm, just going to the bakery.
Don't get alarmed,
but I'm being followed.
Act normal.
Sorry, looks like you're involved.
This way.
Hold on.
Now... straighten your legs
and start walking.
See? Not so hard, is it?
You are a natural.
I'll make sure to draw them off.
But wait a bit before
you head back outside.
'Kay.
That's my girl.
There you go.
Do you have any Lettie shaped cookies?
I'd buy some of those.
Here.
What time do you get off?
She was?
Hey, I'm over here, where're you going?
Sophie!
Lettie.
What's going on? Someone just told me
that you floated down onto our balcony.
So that did happen,
it wasn't a dream...
Lettie, would you like
to use my office?
I should really get back to work.
Thank you though.
Wow! He must have been a wizard then.
But he was so kind to me...
He rescued me, Lettie...
Of course he did, he was
trying to steal your heart.
You were so lucky, Sophie.
If that wizard were Howl,
he would've eaten it.
No, he wouldn't, Howl only does
that to beautiful girls.
Don't give me that.
You need to be more careful,
it's dangerous out there.
Even the Witch of the Waste
is back on the prowl.
Are you listening?
Huh?
Argh...
Lettie, the chocolate
clairs are done.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Thanks.
All right, I'd better get going then.
I just wanted to make sure
that you were doing okay.
Hello, Lettie
Hi, how are you doing?
Now, Sophie, do you really want to spend
the rest of you life in that hat shop?
The shop was just so important to father
and I'm the eldest, I don't mind.
I'm not asking what father would've
wanted, I want to know what you want.
Well...
See you later, Lettie.
Good seeing you again.
You too.
I'd better be going.
It's your life, Sophie, do something
for yourself for once, will you?
Bye Lettie.
I'm sorry, but the shop's
closed now, ma'am.
I could have sworn I locked
that door, must've forgotten.
What a tacky shop.
I've never seen such tacky, little hats.
Yet, you're by far the
tackiest thing here.
I'm afraid you will have to leave now.
The door's over here, ma'am, we're closed.
Standing up to Witch of the Waste,
that's plucky.
The Witch of the Waste?
The best part of that spell, is
you can't tell anyone about it.
My regards to Howl.
Tha-that's really me, isn't it?
I've got to stay calm.
Now, there's no use panicking, Sophie.
It's a bad dream, that's all,
just go inside, go to bed.
You're gonna be fine, Sophie.
You're gonna be fine.
I've got to stay calm.
Look who's here!
- You're back!
- Welcome home, Ma'am!
- Look at you!
- What do you think?
- It's all the rage in Kingsbury.
- It's beautiful.
- It's gorgeous.
- I know. Our customers will love it.
Sophie!
Sophie?
I'm afraid your daughter hasn't
come downstairs yet today, ma'am.
That's strange, I wonder what's wrong.
Sophie?
Sophie!
Don't come in here.
I've got a bad cold.
I don't want you to catch it.
You sound ghastly...
Like some 90 year-old woman.
I'll stay in bed all day,
so you go on.
Well... If you insist.
Up we go...
This isn't so bad, now is it?
You're still in good shape, and your
clothes finally suit you.
But you can't stay here
like this for long.
Ouh, ouh.
Being old is worse than I thought.
- They say their prince is missing.
- And they're blaming us.
Unbelievable
Yeah, yeah, it sounds like they're
gonna start a war.
That's what I heard.
That's terrible, nobody
needs to be at war.
Let's hope the prince
turns up soon.
Excuse me, could you use some help?
I'll be fine, but thanks for offering.
That was really kind.
Sure, there's room in the back if you'd
like, but where are you headed?
Just a little way's farther than
where you're going.
You're crazy if you do this, grandma!
There's nothing but witches
and wizards out there.
Thank you, I'll keep that in mind.
She's going to the Waste by herself?
Says she's looking for her younger sister.
I'll never get there with these legs...
At least my teeth haven't worn out yet.
That would make a nice cane.
Up we go.
Might be too big.
This is one stubborn branch.
You're not getting the best
of this old lady.
Just a scarecrow! I was afraid you
were one of those blob men.
But how are you standing on
your own, like that?
Your head's a turnip.
I've always hated turnips,
ever since I was little.
At least you're not
upside down now.
So long.
It's too cold.
And I can still se the town,
I've barely moved.
Go away, quit following me, there's no
need to thank me, you don't owe me a thing.
I'm sure you have some
kind of spell on you,
and I've had more than enough
of witches and spells!
So just go find some field
and stand in it!
Thank you, this cane is perfect,
it's just what I need.
If you'd like to do me one more favour, you
could run off and find me a place to stay.
I seem to become quite
cunning in my old age.
A battleship.
Why do you get so cold,
when you're old?
I'm fatter than ever, yet the
wind blows right through me.
Someone's got a fire going,
maybe there's a cabin nearby.
You turnip-head, that's Howl's castle.
That is not what I meant when
I asked for a place to stay!
Look at that.
They call this a castle?
Is that the way in?
Slow down.
For heavens sake!
Make up your mind, are you gonna
let me in, or not?!
Oh, my shawl!
It's nice and warm in there,
so I'm going in.
Oh, my shawl, thank you.
I'm sure Howl won't eat the heart of a
shrivelled, old lady, like me.
It's been a pleasure meeting you.
Even if you are my least
favourite vegetable.
Take care, Turnip-head.
What a dump... When I think "Castle",
this is not what I picture.
Well, one nice thing about getting old
is nothing frightens you.
I don't envy you lady,
that is one bad curse.
Curses are tough, you're gonna have a
very hard time getting rid of that one.
The fire spoke.
Let me guess, the curse won't allow
you to talk about it, right?
Are you Howl?
No, I'm an extremely powerful
fire demon named Calcifer!
I just like to do that once in a while.
A fire demon? Well then, you should
be able to break my curse.
Maybe, maybe not.
Listen, if you can find a way to
break the spell that's on me.
Then I'll break the spell that's on you.
You got it?
If you're a demon, how do I
know I can trust you?
You promise to help me, if I help you?
I don't know lady, demons don't make promises.
Then go find someone else.
Come one, you should feel sorry for me.
That spell keeps me stuck in this castle
and Howl treats me like I'm his slave.
It burns me up. You gotta keep the water
hot, the rooms warm...
- ...keep the castle moving. Come on!
- Uh, that's rough.
You ever tried to move a castle?
If you figure out how to break this thing
I'm in with Howl, then you can break my spell.
After that, I can easily break
the spell that's on you.
All right.
It's a deal.
Hey. Lady? Lady!
Hello! Lady!
Hello! Hey, hey, hey.
Lady! Lady!
Hey, let me get over there...
Some big help you're gonna be...
Hey, who's this lady?
Porthaven door!
How'd she get in here?
Stand by.
Mister mayor, good day.
Good afternoon, sir, would the great
wizard, Jenkins, be at home?
I'm afraid that my master
is out at the moment.
I speak for him in his absence.
An invitation from His Majesty, the King.
The time for war's upon us.
His Majesty requires that every witch
and wizard aid our homeland.
Wizard Jenkins must report to the
palace immediately. That is all.
I can't believe it's come to this.
And what do you think you're
doing here, grandma?
Calcifer said that I could come in.
I did not, she just wandered in
here from the Wastes.
She's from the Wastes?
How do we know that she's not a witch?
Do you really think I'd let a witch in here?
Porthaven door again.
Must be a customer.
Stand by.
Yes, my dear child?
My mom sent me to pick up a spell.
- Ah yes, do come in.
- Okay.
Just keep quiet and does cause
any trouble, grandma.
It's not the Wastes.
Excuse me, granny, are you a witch, too?
That's right,
I'm the scariest witch of them all.
Dust your ship with this powder
and the winds will favour it.
Thanks.
Farewell, child.
Quit telling lies to our customers.
What about you?
You're wearing a disguise.
I have to.
I'm practicing my magic.
It's the Kingsbury door.
Stand by.
Good day, would this be the residence of
the great wizard, Pendragon?
It is.
I bear an invitation
from His Majesty, the King.
Please inform Mister Pendragon, that all witches and
wizards are required to report for duty at the palace.
I will inform him right away.
This is the royal city, isn't it?
Move it grandma, or you'll lose your nose.
And stop wandering around.
Leave it alone grandma,
I'm getting angry.
This is a magic house, isn't it?
Orh!
So tell me, where does the black one lead?
Only Master Howl knows that.
I need some breakfast, I'm starved.
Don't you want to have some bacon and eggs?
Yeah, but we can't use the fire.
Master Howl's not here.
Don't worry, I can cook.
It doesn't matter if you can cook.
Calcifer only obeys Master Howl.
That's right lady,
I'm not taking any orders from you.
Oh, there's my hat.
That's better.
All right, Calcifer,
let's get cooking.
I don't cook!
I'm a scary and powerful fire demon.
How would you like a bucket
of cold water in your face?
Or maybe I should tell Howl about our bargain?
Uh! Stupid me, I NEVER should have let her in here!
So, what'll it be?
That's right, that's a good fire.
Here's another curse:
May all your bacon burn.
Calcifer is doing what she says...
I think I'd like some tea, too.
Do you have a kettle?
Sure.
Hey, hey, hey, what are you doing?
Don't get the kettle.
Whose side are you on anyway?
- Ma-Markl? Markl? What are you doing?
- Huh?
Master Howl, the Kings messengers were here.
They said you have to report to the palace.
As both Pendragon and Jenkins.
Calcifer, you're being so obedient.
Not on purpose, she bullied me.
Not just anybody can do that.
And you are... who?
Ah, y-you can just call me, Grandma Sophie.
I'm your new cleaning lady,
I just started work today.
Give that to me.
Hand me two more slices of that bacon
and six more of those eggs
Yummy.
So then... who hired you to clean?
Calcifer did.
He's disgusted by how dirty it is in here.
Hmm.
Markl, get the plates.
Wait a second, you're all gonna
eat while I do all the work?
Come have some breakfast, Sophie.
Take a seat.
Which do you want?
You only get one, 'cause the rest are dirty.
Looks like I've got my work cut out for me.
Bread, Markl?
Thanks.
Sophie?
Yes, thank you.
So friends, enjoy, bon apptit
Bon apptit
I can't remember the last
time we had a real breakfast.
Even the manners are a mess in this house...
So, what do you have hidden in you pocket, Sophie?
Huh?
What is this?
Give it to me.
Scorch marks. Howl, can you read them?
That is ancient sorcery.
And quite powerful, too.
It's from the Witch of the Waste?
"You who swallowed a falling star,
oh heartless man"
"Your heart shall soon belong to me."
That can't be good for the table.
Wow, it's gone!
The mark may be gone,
but the spell is still there.
Excuse me, my friends, please continue your meal.
Calcifer, move the castle
60 miles to the west.
And while you're at it, make hot water for my bath.
Fine, like moving the castle wasn't hard enough.
You're not working for the
Witch of the Waste, are you?
I would never work for that witch,
she's the one who...
Actually...
If I ever get my hands on that witch,
I'm gonna wring her fat neck!
Finish your breakfast!
I've had enough of this.
You bugs better run,
before I bite your heads off.
I'm sick of being treated like
some timid, little, old lady.
Hello sir, is my potion ready?
Come back later.
There's a witch on the rampage in there.
Sophie, please.
Sophie, please help me, I'm going out.
Please, get me some firewood quick.
Quick, come on.
Hey, please help me.
Hey, wh-what are you doing? No, don't, don't,
I'll fall! You crazy lady with tongs!
- You'll be fine.
- I'll fall, help!
I'm just sweeping out the ashes.
No, I'm not fine.
Please, I'm... I'm going out.
Please...
Please... I'm falling...
Help! Fall, I'm falling.
Sophie, hurry up, please. Hurry, please.
I'd appreciate it, if you didn't torment my friend.
Master Howl, are you going out now?
Markl, make sure the cleaning lady
doesn't get carried away while I'm gone.
Sophie, what did you do now?
She almost smothered me.
If I die, Howl dies too, I hope you know.
Argh, be quiet, you're alright.
Now quit bothering me, I've got a job to do.
Wait, you can't come up here!
Whatever you don't want me to clean,
better hide it now.
Save my room for last, okay?
These little outbursts seem to be
giving me some energy.
What a mess!
Incredible!
Calcifer, Calcifer!
Are you the one moving the castle?
Of course I am, no one else
does any work around here.
I am thoroughly impressed.
You're a first class fire demon,
I like your spark.
She likes my spark!
Hah, not ready, not ready!
- It's beautiful.
- Yeah, it's called Star Lake.
Hey, what's that stick doing in there?
Oh, dear.
Give me a hand, Markl.
It's a scarecrow.
Yep, I've been calling him Turnip-head.
Somehow, he always manages
to get stuck upside down.
He keeps following me everywhere.
Seems to have taken a liking to me.
That's weird.
Are you sure you're not a witch, Sophie?
Oh yes, I'm the worst kind of witch ever;
the kind that cleans.
Quit pulling so hard, Turnip-head.
I think he likes doing the laundry.
Looks like he'll have it dry in no time.
I bet he's some kind of demon.
Calcifer doesn't seem to mind him at all.
You're right, he probably is a demon.
But he led me here,
so maybe he's the good kind.
We got all the laundry put away, Sophie.
Oh, thank you, Markl. When you're old,
all you want to do is stare at the scenery.
It's so strange.
I've never felt so peaceful before.
You okay? I mean, you smell terrible.
You shouldn't keep flying around like that.
Soon, you won't be able to turn back into a human.
Isn't this great? Sophie put these here for me.
This war is terrible.
They've bombed from the southern coast to
the northern border. It's only flames now.
I cant stand the fire in gunpowder.
Those dopy guys have absolutely no manners.
My own kind attacked me today.
Who? The Witch of the Waste?
No, some hack wizards, who turned themselves
into monsters for the king.
Those wizards are going to regret doing that.
They'll never change back into humans.
After the war, they won't recall they ever were human.
Hey, aren't you supposed to report
to the king too?
I'm tired.
Make some hot water for my bath.
What? Not again.
- Is Howl back?
- Yes, he's wasting all my hot water again.
I don't know why we're doing this.
Master Howl hardly eats anything.
Too bad.
- Good morning.
Don't you love early morning markets?
And just look at the water.
I've never seen the ocean before. It's beautiful.
It always looks like that.
I hate potatoes.
Pay up.
Thanks, have a nice day.
Thank you, come again.
All our fish were caught fresh this morning.
I hate fish.
One of our ships is in the harbour!
It looks like it's on fire!
Looks like there's been a serious battle.
What happened? Sorry lady, we're closed.
- It's our flagship!
- The ship, it's sinking.
Come on Sophie, let's get a better look.
No, I've seen all I can take.
Let's go home.
I can't believe this, that's our most advanced battleship.
- The Witch's henchmen are here.
- What?
Quiet down!
They're only a few feet away.
He's gone.
I don't understand why no one else seem to notice him.
Look! There they are!
- That plane! That's what dropped the bombs!
- Look up there, Sophie, it's the enemy's airship.
Sophie, wait up! Sophie!
Ignore the flyers,
they're enemy propaganda!
Sophie, are you okay?
I just need a glass of water.
I'll get it.
Sophie, you... you sabotaged me! Look!
Look what you've done to my hair! Look!
What a pretty colour.
It's hideous!
You completely ruined my magic potions in the bathroom.
I just organized things, Howl,
nothing's ruined.
Wrong! Wrong!
I specifically ordered you not to get carried away.
Now I'm repulsive...
I can't live like this...
Come on, it's not that bad.
You should look at it now, this shade is even better.
I give up...
I seek no point in living, if I can't be beautiful...
- Howl! Cut it out! Howl, no, stop it! Howl!
- He's calling the Spirits of Darkness.
I saw him do this once before, when a girl dumped him.
Now Howl, you're all right.
We'll just dye your hair back again. Okay?
Fine! So, you think you've got it bad?
I've never once been beautiful in my entire life!
I've had enough of this place!
Thank you, Turnip-head.
How did you get to be so kind?
Sophie, get back inside, we need your help.
Howl's in trouble!
Howl, cut it out, cut it out, I'm gonna drown,
I'm drowning here Howl!
Sophie! Sophie, help him, please.
Sophie, do something!
Such drama.
Is he dead?
No, he's fine, he's just throwing a tantrum.
Come on, give me a hand.
Okay.
- Get the hot water running.
- Right!
Come on, Howl, you can still walk.
Get him cleaned up, Markl.
I will.
Now I have to mop again.
This says they've landed on the coast already.
- Where?
- North.
Howl, I'm coming in.
I've brought you some warm milk.
Want a sip?
I'll leave it here for you then.
Try to drink it, before it gets cold.
Sophie, wait...
Do you want some milk?
The Witch of the Waste
is trying to find my castle.
I saw her henchmen at the harbour.
I'm such a big coward, all I do is hide.
And all of this magic is just to keep everybody away.
I can't stand how scared I am.
Howl, why is the Witch of the Waste
trying to hunt you down?
She was once quite beautiful,
so I decided to pursue her.
Then I realized she wasn't,
so as usual, I ran away.
I can't run much longer though,
I have to report to the palace.
As both Pendragon and Jenkins...
How many aliases do you have, anyway?
As many as I need to keep my freedom.
Just refuse the King's invitation.
See that?
That's the oath I took,
when I entered the Royal Sorcery Academy.
I must report to the palace whenever summoned.
You know, Howl?
I think that you should see the King.
What?
Give him a piece of your mind.
Tell him this war is pointless
and you refuse too take part, huh?
You obviously don't know
what these people are like.
But he's our king. He should want to hear
what all his citizens have to say.
I got it!
Why don't you go to the palace for me?
Just say that you're Pendragon's mother.
And your son is such a cowardly wizard,
he's too afraid to show his face.
Maybe then, Madam Suliman
will finally give up on me.
Who's Madam Suliman?
You're wearing that hat?
After all the magic I used
to make your dress pretty...
Take care of him, Markl!
Good luck!
This charm will guarantee you your safe return.
Don't worry, I'll follow behind you in disguise.
Now, off you go!
Why do I feel like this is not going to work?
I wonder what Howl disguised himself as,
surely not a crow!
Can't be a pigeon,
he's too flamboyant for that.
That could be him...
Look how far I still have to go...
Howl?
You disguised yourself as an old dog?
You couldn't think of something a bit more useful?
Do you know how hard it is to do things,
when you're old?
Look who's here,
the tacky, little girl from the hat shop.
The Witch of the Waste!
Thank you for handing my
scorching love note to Howl.
How's he doing, by the way?
He's acting like a big baby.
And he's working me to the bone as his cleaning lady.
How delightful.
So tell me,
what business do you have here at the palace?
Job hunting.
I'm sick of working for Howl.
And what about yourself?
I received a royal invitation.
That idiot, Suliman,
finally realized how much she needs my powers.
If you're so great, why don't you
break the spell you put on me?
I'm sorry, dear.
My talent lies in casting spells,
not breaking them.
Bye, granny.
Now, just wait a minute.
You get back here right now!
If I didnt have you to worry about,
I would have clobbered her.
What on earth is wrong with you two?
Sorry Ma'am, vehicles are prohibited
beyond this point.
You must continue on foot.
That Suliman...
Using her magic to force me
to climb all those godforsaken stairs.
Come on Howl.
We can do this, just act natural.
Howl, why are you so heavy?
Wait... Help... I can't make it.
What you say?
You suddenly... remembered...
how to break the spell you put on me?
I told you...
I don't know how.
Then start studying!
I don't get it.
Where does she get all that energy?
I have to rest a bit.
Why don't you just give up?
You're killing yourself.
I've waited... for 50 years now,
to be invited here...
Ever since that Suliman banished me
to live in the Wastes.
Well, good luck then.
Too bad I'm not younger,
or I'd lend you a hand.
Come on, Howl.
You cold-hearted, old hag.
Next time I'll turn you senile too.
Almost there!
Honoured guest, please follow me.
You should go help her get up these stairs.
I'm strictly forbidden to offer such assistance.
Why, that's so rude,
the King himself invited her.
Come on! Let's go!
Don't give up now!
Are you a witch or aren't you?
Just shut up.
What happened?
You look so much older.
Mrs. Pendragon and
the Witch of the Waste!
Pull yourself together.
Isn't this what you've been waiting for?
Mrs. Pendragon and
the Witch of the Waste!
Your name's Pendragon?
Why does that name sound so familiar?
Uh, because that was the name of my tacky hat shop,
don't you remember?
Is that what it was?
Wait in here, please.
A chair!
It's mine!
Howl, get back here.
This way please, ma'am.
Thank you, madam Suliman.
So, you are Howl's mother, are you?
Yes, I'm Mrs. Pendragon.
You must be tired,
please have a seat.
Thank you.
I am madam Suliman, His Majesty's head sorceress.
That's not your dog, is it?
His name is Heen.
He's my errand dog,
I had him escort you here.
I take it Howl won't be joining us?
He's such a lazy son, he sent me instead.
I'm afraid the King would find him completely useless.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
Howl was the last apprentice I ever took on.
I've never seen such a gifted student.
I was thrilled to have finally found someone
talented enough to replace me.
Then on day, his heart was stolen by a demon,
he never returned to complete his apprenticeship,
and from that day forward, he has been using his magic
for entirely selfish reasons.
- Mrs. Pendragon.
- Yes?
That boy is extremely dangerous.
His powers are far too great
for one without a heart.
If he stays selfish, I'm afraid he'll end up
just like the Witch of the Waste.
Send her in.
What on earth happened to you?
I just restored her to the age she actually is.
All her powers are gone now.
Once, she too was a magnificent sorcerer
with so much promise.
But then she fell prey to a demon of greed,
who slowly consumed her body and soul.
Our kingdom can no longer afford to turn a blind eye
to these disreputable witches and wizards.
If Howl reports to me and vows to use his magic
to serve the kingdom,
I will show him how to break from his demon.
If not, I'll strip him of all his powers,
just like her.
That is enough!
Now I understand why Howl was so concerned
about coming to see you.
It's a trap!
You lure people here with an invitation from the King
and then you strip them of all their powers.
Howl would never be so heartless!
He may be selfish and cowardly
and sometimes he's hard to understand,
but his intentions are good.
He just wants to be free.
Howl won't come here, he doesn't need your help.
He can fix his problem with his demon on his own.
I am certain of it!
Now I understand,
you're in love with Howl.
Howl...
Did you say Howl's coming?
I want his heart, his heart belongs to me.
Stop that, just calm down.
Howl is not coming here, okay?
Oh, I think he will.
I now know his weakness, Mrs. Pendragon.
Your Majesty.
As you were.
So then, how are you feeling?
I'm fine, thank you.
Thought I'd drop by,
rather than sit through a dull war meeting.
What an honour.
Who are your guests?
- This is Howl's mother, Mrs. Pendragon.
- Ah.
Thanks for coming, but I've decided not to use magic
to win this war.
We have tried using madam Suliman's magic
to shield our palace from the enemy's bombs,
but the bombs fall on civilian homes instead.
That's the problem with magic.
Right, Suliman?
You're so eloquent today, Your Majesty.
Suliman!
I've got a new battle plan!
This time, we're gonna beat them to a pulp!
Suliman, that's the best double you've made of me yet,
keep up the good work!
Your Majesty.
- Get my generals assembled!
- Sir.
So nice to see you again, Howl.
You're looking well, madam Suliman.
Rather weak disguise, didn't I teach you better?
I'm not trying to outwit you, I kept my oath,
I reported when summoned.
Now "mother" and I will go.
I'm afraid not.
Now, whatever you do, don't look down.
It's time to show your "mother"
what you really are, Howl.
Stop, Howl! It's a trap!
Hold on!
Sophie, sit up here!
Did you have to bring those two with you?
Nice doggie.
I can't believe you work for Suliman.
I guess it's too late to toss him.
Sophie, take the wheel!
What?! I can't fly, are you kidding?!
They're gaining on us.
I'll distract them. Then, you can fly this thing
back to my castle in the Wastes.
How? I don't know the way!
Hey, don't worry.
The ring that I gave you will guide you back home.
All you have to do, is summon Calcifer with your heart.
Calcifer?
It's glowing.
Just keep following that light
and you should be there before dark.
I can't do this!
Why did you make me come here, if you were coming yourself?
Knowing you'd be there gave me the courage to show up.
That woman terrifies me,
I can't face her on my own.
You've saved me, Sophie.
I was in big trouble back there.
Don't let go!
- Wow, you're good.
- Are you nuts?!
We've got a good lead now.
I can give you 5 minutes of invisibility,
so use it wisely.
Howl!
Good luck!
No, not now.
Thank you.
That was the most fun I've had in ages.
I suppose Howl thinks he's evaded me.
I bet his "mother" can help me find him.
Almost there,
that's my hometown below us!
Don't try to be cute, dog,
I'm still not going to trust you.
The castle is coming to meet us.
Sophie! Here!
Markl, help me!
How am I supposed to land this thing?!
Sophie.
Nice doggie.
Markl.
I'm home.
Are you hurt?
I missed you!
I missed you too,
thanks for coming to meet us.
Oh, this is bad, you've gone too far, Howl.
I wonder if Howl's back home.
Howl?
Howl? Is that you?
Are you in pain?
Tell me what's happening.
Go away.
No, I'm not going away.
I'm going to help you break
the spell that you're under.
You... you can't even break your own spell.
- But you don't understand, I love you!
- You're too late.
Howl! No!
Calcifer, did Howl just get in?
Yeah, and he looks terrible.
You better figure out, how to break the spell on us, quick.
Howl is running out of time,
I hope you realize that.
You mean he'll become a monster, is that it?
I can't tell you the details of the curse, lady,
you should know that by now, c'mon.
Do you know what madam Suliman said?
She said that Howl's heart was stolen by a demon.
- Tell me now, what do you know?
- I'm so sorry, but that would be confidential information.
What if I dump a bucket of water on you?
If you drown me,
then Howl will die too.
Hi Turnip-head.
This isn't gonna be easy.
'Kay! Ready!
All right! Calcifer, open it wider.
Here we go!
I said move...
If I just hang a little curtain here,
maybe Howl won't notice.
Come on in, it's time to eat!
Here, want some more?
Don't feed her, that's the Witch of the Waste.
Oh, she's all right.
She keeps staring at me,
it's freaking me out...
What a pretty fire.
- Howl, hello.
- Good morning, everyone.
- Glad you're home.
- Master Howl, we can keep this dog, can't we?
The Witch of the Waste and Suliman's dog at my table?
What possessed you to let them in my house, Calcifer?
I didn't let them in!
Sophie crash landed her plane into my face!
I knew she'd make a great pilot.
Looks like we have yet another addition to the family.
You've got a quite nasty spell on you too, huh?
Seems everyone in this family's got problems...
What a handsome man.
So! We've got a lot of work to do.
We're moving!
Moving?
That's good. I'm sick of being stuck out here,
in the middle of nowhere.
Madam Suliman is hot on our trail,
so we're gonna have to hurry.
I'm afraid your spell is too strong for this move.
You're gonna have to stay behind.
There, all done.
All right, Calcifer, line her up!
There, that should do it.
Sit tight for a second.
Be gentle with me, please...
On my mark.
Moving's done,
you can get down now.
This is great, master Howl,
it's huge.
Oh, what a pretty fire.
But this is...
I added on a bathroom,
since our family seems to keep growing.
Come over here, Sophie!
I added another bedroom, too.
Have a look.
Why'd you... do this?
So we'd have a room that suited you.
Do you like it?
Of course.
It's perfect for a cleaning lady.
I got you some new clothes, too,
but you can open them later.
Come on, Sophie!
Look at this!
All Right! A courtyard!
That shop's ours, too.
Heen, c'mon!
See that new colour on the dial?
There's a new portal.
It's a present for you.
Come see.
You like it?
It's my secret garden.
It's incredible.
Did you use your magic to make this?
Only a little, just to help the flowers grow.
This place is gorgeous, Howl!
It's like a dream.
Sophie?
It all seems so familiar,
yet I know I've never been her before.
I feel so at home.
- Come with me.
- 'Kay
Look there!
- What a cute cottage.
- That was my secret hideaway.
I spent a lot of time here, by myself,
when I was young.
You were alone?
My uncle, who was a wizard,
gave me this place as my private study.
And now you can come here whenever you like.
What's the matter?
It's...
You're scareing me,
I have this weird feeling that you're going to leave.
Howl, tell me what's going on.
Please, I don't care if you're a monster.
I'm just setting things up,
so that all of you can live a comfortable life, Sophie.
With all the flowers you've got in this valley,
you could easily open up a flower shop.
Right? I'm sure you'd be good at it.
So you are going away...
Please, Howl, I know I can be of help to you.
Even though I'm not pretty
and all I'm good at is cleaning...
Sophie! Sophie, you're beautiful!
Well, the nice thing about being old
is you've nothing much to lose...
What is that thing doing out here?
- A battleship?
- Still looking for more cities to burn...
- Is it the enemy's or one of ours?
- What difference does it make?
Those stupid murderers...
We can't just let them fly off with all those bombs.
What's happening?
What did you do?
Just messed with it,
it won't crash though.
Howl!
Uh-oh... Here they come.
Those things are Suliman's henchmen.
Let's go!
Faster, we need to take off!
All right, you're going in!
No! Don't let go!
Sophie? What happened?
I'm too old to be treated like this!
Good night, Sophie.
Good night, Markl.
Don't worry about Master Howl, Sophie.
Sometimes, he likes to go away for days on end.
Thank you, that's good to know.
- Need anything else?
- No, I'm fine.
Well, good night then.
You're in love.
Don't deny it,
you've been sighing all day.
Just as I thought.
Have you ever in love before?
Of course I have.
I'm still in love.
Strapping, young men are so difficult to deal with,
but their hearts I just adore.
You're terrible.
And they're so cute, too.
What's that?
It's an air raid siren.
Air raid?
It's a long way's off,
but you better not go outside tonight, dear.
I'm sure Suliman's henchmen are looking
everywhere for this place.
What a good fire.
He keeps this house so well hidden.
Sophie, there's a strange lady in here!
Mother?
Sophie!
Thank goodness you're here!
I searched everywhere for you!
Oh my, look at your face, you're so old!
Everyones saying it's my fault that you left.
You'll forgive me, oh won't you?
Oh, Sophie.
Mother...
I barely recognize the place.
Who is that woman?
Huh? The landlady?
Oh, I forgot to tell you,
I got married again.
He's such a nice man and he's filthy rich, too,
so we can all live together again.
You won't have to work as a cleaning lady anymore.
That's all right, mother,
I actually like living here.
Really?
I forgot.
I've got a car waiting,
I've got to run.
Sophie, I'm so glad I found you.
A peeping-bug?
Can't Suliman do better than that?
Open wide, Cal.
I hope you and your new husband will be very happy.
- Thank you, Sophie. Bye.
- Bye, mother.
I did what I was told,
now take me to my husband.
Yes ma'am, I'm sure Madam Suliman
will be very pleased with your.
Forgive me, Sophie...
Oh, look at all of them.
If they keep leaving at this rate,
the town will soon be empty.
- Do you want to leave, too, Sophie?
- What?
That lady said she wants you to live with her now.
Yes, well...
At least she cared enough to visit.
Don't leave, Sophie!
I love you,
you have to stay...
I love you, too, Markl.
I'll stay.
Really?
'Cause we're a family now.
Yes, we're a family.
Thank you, Sophie.
I will never let Suliman
get a hold of Howl.
But the newspaper says we won.
Only idiots believe what they read in the paper.
That's so strange,
I can't get Calcifer going.
Do you have to keep smoking that?
It smells terrible.
Don't deny an old witch her pleasures, young lady.
Markl, will you crack a window, please?
I wouldn't open that window if I were you, dear.
Calcifer's too weak right now
to protect this place.
Suliman's henchmen could get in.
Markl!
Markl, get back inside,
I'm gonna check on the shop.
There are bombs falling on us,
why won't you put out some fires instead?
Howl, no!
This is exciting.
Howl!
I'm sorry, Sophie,
I should've gotten here sooner.
You're alive.
Oh, thank goodness.
Master Howl! Sophie!
You're okay!
Calcifer, you hang in there now!
Tell me... Was that cigar a gift from Madam Suliman,
by any chance?
Howl, she fed me something gross, I feel sick.
Why, if it isn't Howl.
I think you and I need to have a nice,
long, heart-to-heart chat.
There's nothing I'd like more than that,
but right now there's a war going on.
How unlike you, Howl,
not running away anymore.
Until later, then.
Stay here,
Calcifer will protect you from the henchmen.
I'll stand guard out front.
No, wait, Howl!
Don't go out there!
It's too dangerous.
Another wave's coming
and Calcifer is too weak to stop the bombs.
Let's run,
don't fight them, Howl.
Sorry, I've had enough of running away, Sophie.
And now, I've got something I wanna protect.
It's you.
Come back!
There's where we are at the shop.
Looks like Howl's in trouble.
Howl, look out!
What's going on?!
Turnip!
Markl, I need your help!
Are you crazy?
I can't move the portals without Howl's help.
You have to try, if we don't break away,
Howl will keep protecting the hat shop.
I preferred him as a coward.
Okay, we have to go now.
Are we going for a stroll?
We can't do that,
it'll make us too vulnerable.
We already are! And if we don't move quick,
Howl doesn't have a chance.
Sophie!
They're about to bomb the hat shop!
Quick! Help her get outside, okay?
You coming with us,
hop on.
I can't! It's impossible,
no one, but Howl, can take me out of this hearth.
There's no time to lose, Calcifer,
we have to try something.
Don't do this!
No! No! No! Help! Help! Help! Help!
Crazy lady with a shovel! Don't!
If you take me out that door,
the castle could collapse!
Good!
- We're ready!
- Okay, step back.
Make sure I go out last, Sophie.
I don't know what's gonna happen...
but I'm sure it won't be good.
I told you it would collapse.
Rain! Rain! Rain!
That ship's headed for town!
Markl, look after her, okay?
Turnip-head, help me find a way back in.
Don't you worry now, ma'am,
I'm gonna take good care of you.
Markl, here's a way in.
Please, oh ple-, uh, watch, the roof is leaking,
don't make it wet.
- Please, don't make it wet.
- Hold on for a second.
It's wet here, Sophie!
Too damp, too damp, damp, very damp here,
hu-hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, please.
Markl, hurry, get inside.
The castle's a wreck.
Told you we should have stayed put,
Howl and I could've handled it.
We have to tell Howl,
we're not attached to the hat shop now.
Move the castle and take us to Howl.
What?
I know you can do it,
I've never seen a fire with more spark.
But there's no chim-,
but there's no chimney here,
and I keep getting dripped on
and the wood's all damp...
They say that the best blaze brightest
when circumstances are at their worst.
Yeah, but no one really believes that...
Come on, let's be honest...
Uh, what a pretty fire.
Why don't you have a seat?
All right, I need something of yours, Sophie.
Why is that?
I can't do it by myself.
How about your eyes?
Huh?
How about this?
Thanks, Calcifer!
You're fantastic!
Imagine what I could have done with
your eyes or your heart.
That's it! You've got Howl's heart!
I found it!
I can see Howl down there.
Looks like he's trapped.
Calcifer, hurry!
No!
Put it back!
Let go!
Howl's heart, it's mine!
Put it back, now!
- It's hot, hot! Burning me!
- Let go!
You're catching on fire!
No, it's mine! It's mine!
It's mine!
Sophie!
Sophie ruined it.
My heart's ruined.
Heen, what've I done?
I poured water on Calcifer.
What if I've killed Howl, too?
It's moving...
Is Howl still alive?
Can you lead me to him?
The front door...
Heen?
That's Howl...
I know where I am,
I'm in Howl's childhood.
Howl!
Calcifer!
It's me, Sophie!
I know how to help you now!
Find me in the future!
Sorry, Heen,
I'm trying to hurry.
I just can't seem to stop crying.
Howl.
I'm sorry...
Did I come too late?
I didn't mean to make you wait this long.
I need you to take me to Calcifer, if you can.
He's dead?
No, Markl.
Howl needs that back now.
Don't look at me, I don't have it,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Please.
Please give it back.
You really want it that badly?
Yes.
- All right then. You'd better take good care of it.
- 'Kay.
Here, dear.
Thank you, you have a big heart.
Calcifer.
Sophie, I'm so tired...
If I give Howl back his heart,
what will happen to you?
I'd be okay, if you do it, I think...
I mean, you dumped water on me
and Howl and I both survived.
I'd better try then.
Its so warm and fluttering like a bird.
It's still just the heart of a child.
Please... Help Calcifer live.
And please help Howl take back his heart.
I'm alive!
I'm alive! Look! I'm free! Free!
I'm alive, I tell you!
He moved! See?
I can't steer without Calcifer!
Turnip!
His pole snapped.
Are you all right?
We'll get you a new pole, okay?
You saved us, Turnip.
Thank you, Sophie.
I'm the prince,
who's been missing from the neighbouring kingdom.
Somehow, I got that blasted spell put on me.
I know that spell.
A kiss, from your true love, breaks it.
That's right.
If it weren't for Sophie, I would've been
a scarecrow for the rest of my life!
My, what a stunning, young man, you are.
What's going on?
What am I doing here?
I feel terrible,
like there's a weight on my chest.
A heart's a heavy burden.
Wow, Sophie, your hair looks
just like starlight.
It's beautiful.
You think so?
So do I!
Looks like your true love
is in love with someone else.
You should go home anyway,
and tell your king to stop this dumb war.
Yes, that's exactly what I'll do.
One thing you can always count on,
is that hearts change.
So as soon as this war is over,
I shall return.
I love it, when you talk like that.
I'll look forward to your return, big boy.
There you are.
You should've checked in earlier.
What on earth were you up to?
Howl found his true love.
You little traitor.
The game is over.
Get me the Prime Minister and
the Minister of Defence.
- It's time to put an end to this idiotic war.
- Yes, ma'am
Hey, it's Calcifer!
You didn't have to come back, Calcifer.
I kind of missed you guys,
and it looks like it's gonna rain...
I missed you too, Calcifer.
Subtitles by: Hecko X
Member of: DKSubs
For Danish subtitles, please visit:
http://dksubs.rdwsubs.com
DKSubs are sponsored by:
www.rdwsubs.com
Thank you for watching :)
The End