Subtitles By Rajanee
The world is full of complainers.
But the fact is:
nothing comes with a guarantee.
I don't care if you're the Pope,
President of the United States,
Man of the Year.
Something can all go wrong.
Go ahead and complain,
tell your problems to your neighbor,
ask for help,
and watch them fly.
In Russia they map it out so that
everyone pulls for everyone else.
That's the theory anyway.
But what I know about is Texas.
And down here,
you're on your own.
He gave me a pearl-handled 38
for our first anniversary.
Think I better leave
before I use it on him.
I don't understand
how you can use it on him.
I'm only an employee.
I ain't married to him.
It's just...
I don't know.
Sometimes I think
something's wrong with him.
Maybe he's sick?
Mentally?
Or is it maybe me, do you think?
Listen, I ain't a marriage counselor.
I don't know what goes on.
And I don't wanna know.
But I like you.
I've always liked you.
What're you gonna do in Houston?
I'll figure something out.
How come you offered to drive me
in this mess?
I told you I like you.
I never knew that.
Well, now you do.
Hell!
Stop the car, Ray!
You know that car?
No.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
I just think maybe
I'm making a mistake.
What was that back there?
Back where?
That sign.
I don't know.
A motel.
Did you mean what you said?
Were you just being a gentleman?
Abby, I like you.
But there's no point
starting anything now.
I ain't a marriage counselor.
What do you wanna do?
Hello.
- Having a good time?
Who is this?
- I don't know. Who is this?
You still there?
- Yeah, I'm still here.
Who was it?
Your husband.
I know
where you can get those framed.
Why'd you take these?
What d'you mean?
Just doing my job.
I knew they were there.
Why'd you take 'em?
I don't know.
Call it a fringe benefit.
How long were you watching them?
Most of the night.
They'd rest every few minutes
and get started again.
Quite something.
You know, in Greece
they'd cut the head off the messenger
that brought bad news.
Now that don't make much sense.
No.
It made them feel better.
First off,
Julian,
I don't know
what the story is in Greece,
but in this state
we got very definite laws about that.
Second,
I'm not a messenger,
I'm a private investigator.
And third, and most important,
it ain't such bad news.
I mean, you thought he was colored.
You're always assuming the worst.
Anything else?
Don't come around here anymore.
If I need you,
I'll know what rock to turn over.
That's good.
"What rock to turn over..."
Very good!
Give me a call
whenever you wanna cut off my head.
I can always crawl around
without it.
We'll be back
after a short intermission...
Hold it!
Where was I?
You were telling me
about the ring of fire. - Right.
You got all these volcanoes, right?
Now every time one goes pop,
you got the equivalent of...
...20, 30 megatons of TNT.
- Meurice!
I know, Marty. Pour 'em short.
Is Ray in yet? - No, it's his night off.
Where was he last night?
I don't wanna know where he was.
Didn't he call?
This is
an old friend of mine, Debra.
Debra, this is Julian Marty.
Deuce in the corner needs help.
- Right.
How long you know Meurice?
- About ten years.
10 years?
What are you doing tonight?
Going out with Meurice.
Tell him you have a headache.
He'll pass.
We don't seem
to be communicating...
Look, you wanna hustle me?
I don't wanna be hustled.
- Oh, you don't?
It's as simple as that.
- Oh, as simple as that.
I'm not here if they come, okay?
- Right.
Nice guy.
- Not really.
What's your last name?
Good old boy.
Let's get outta here.
You get what you wanted?
- Yeah. Let's get outta here.
Drive me to a motel?
- You can stay at my place.
I'll drop you there.
- Where you goin'?
See a guy.
Don't go to the bar.
I know him. It ain't a good idea.
I just gotta see a guy.
So what's the deal?
None if your colleagues could harness
this volcanic energy?
And I just sit back and watch
these shit kickers go broke.
Sorry about last night.
- No sweat. Wasn't too busy.
But you missed a good one.
A white guy walks in and asks
do we have a discount for alcoholics.
I tell him to get lost.
But Marty's sitting here
thinking that maybe ain't a bad idea.
Well?
What?
What, what?
- Am I fired?
You wanna hit me or what?
I don't particularly
want to talk to you.
Well!
If you aren't gonna fire me,
I'll quit.
Fine!
Suit yourself.
Having a good time?
I don't like this kind of talk.
- What'd you come here for?
You owe me for two weeks.
Nope.
She's
an expensive piece of ass.
Who else has she been sluicing?
I want money! You gotta talk? Fine.
- Are you a fucking marriage counselor?
What're you smiling at?
I'm funny? I'm an asshole?
No.
That's not what's funny.
What's funny is her.
And that I had you two followed.
If it's not you she's sleeping with,
it's someone else.
And what's really gonna be funny is
when she gives you
that innocent look and says,
"I don't know
what you're talking about, Ray.
I ain't done anything funny."
The funniest thing
for me right now
is that you think
she came back here for you.
That's what's fuckin' funny!
Come on this property again
I'll be forced to shoot you.
Fair notice.
I thought you were dead.
You goin' home?
No.
I'm stayin' right here in hell.
Kind of a bleak point of view,
isn't it?
I don't want the asshole
near my money.
And I don't want him in the bar.
You get a lot of assholes in here.
Hello.
Who was it?
What?
On the phone.
Was it for you?
I don't know. He didn't say anything.
How did you know it was a "he?"
You got a girl?
Am I screwing something up
by being here? - No.
Am I?
I can find a place tomorrow, and I'll
be outta your hair. - If you want to,
then do it.
You want the bed or the couch?
Well...
The couch'll be all right.
You can sleep on the bed.
I'm not putting you outta your bed.
- You wouldn't be putting me out.
I'll be all right here.
Opal?
Lover boy oughta lock his door.
Lot of nuts out there.
Let's do it outside, in nature.
I'd like to have seen his face
when he found the dead end.
Hey, mister!
How'd you break your pussy finger?
I want it! I want it!
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
My date's here.
She saw me rollin' a cigarette
and thought it was marijuana.
Thought I was a swinger, I guess.
Isn't that wild?
Stick your finger
up the wrong person's ass?
A friend of mine broke his hand,
and it was put in a cast.
Next day he falls,
protects his bad hand,
then he breaks his good one.
He breaks that one, too.
So now he's got two busted flippers,
so I said to him,
"Creighton, I hope
your wife really loves you,
'cause for the next five weeks
you can't even wipe your own ass."
That's the test, ain't it?
Test of true love.
I got a job for you.
If the pay's right and it's legal,
I'll do it.
It's not strictly legal.
If the pay's right, I'll do it.
It's in reference to that gentleman
and my wife.
The more I think about it,
the more irritated I get.
Could you tell me what you want me
to do, or is it a secret?
This is no joke.
You want me to kill 'em.
Well?
Well, what?
What do you think?
You're an idiot.
So, this wouldn't interest you, huh?
I didn't say that. All I said was
you're an idiot.
You've been thinking about it so much
it's driving you simple.
I'll give you 10,000 dollars.
I'm supposed to do a murder,
or two murders,
and trust you
not to go simple on me
and do something stupid.
I mean
really stupid.
Why should I trust you?
For the money.
The money.
That's a right lot of money.
In Russia,
they make only fifty cents a day.
I want you...
to go fishing.
What?
- Go down to Corpus for a few days.
Get yourself noticed.
I'll give you a call when it's done.
You just find a way
to cover that money.
I'll take care of the money.
You make sure
those bodies aren't found.
There's a big incinerator
behind my place.
Do you want
like a townhouse?
Or your own apartment?
I'll show you around.
Are you sure this apartment is vacant?
Yes! I was just explaining to him
that he moved out yesterday.
Don't mind Mr. Garcia.
He used to be my brother-in-law.
Looks like the state legislature
is out of session.
I thought this was where they met.
- You're gonna help me.
I am? - Keep an eye on Mary and Ray.
Make sure nothing happens.
Let's show our appreciation
for Lorraine.
A registered nurse from Bolton, Texas.
How about it, gentlemen?
Alright, see you, Meurice.
Any time.
You don't have to worry for a while.
Marty went down to Corpus yesterday.
He's in the house!
He's in the house.
What's the matter?
I could have sworn I heard something.
- Door's locked.
Nothin' there.
Well,
we wouldn't have heard anything,
if it'd been him. He's real careful.
Fact is...
he's anal.
He told me himself. He said,
"In here,
in here I'm anal."
I'll be damned!
I couldn't believe it myself.
Me, on the other hand,
I got lots of personality.
Marty always said I had too much.
He was never big on personality.
He sent me to a psychiatrist
to see if he could calm me down.
Yeah?
What happened?
- Psychiatrist said
I was the healthiest person
he ever met. Marty fired him.
I don't think
you can fire a psychiatrist.
I never saw him again,
I can tell you that. I said,
"Marty, how come you're anal
and I gotta go to the psychiatrist?"
What did he say?
Nothing.
He's like you. He doesn't say much.
Thanks.
Except when he doesn't say things,
they're usually nasty.
When you don't,
they're usually nice.
You ever get tired?
- Oh yeah, I guess.
Hello?
- Marty?
Catch any fish?
What?
What kind of fish?
- Listen, is it done?
Yes, sir. You owe me some money.
If you're fucking with me,
you'll regret it.
They look good.
Why? You want a couple?
Just the 10,000 will be fine.
You got something to show me first?
Dead?
So it seems.
What'd you do with the bodies?
- Taken care of.
The less you know about it,
the better.
Jesus!
I don't believe it.
I'm gonna be sick.
I'm gonna want that picture back.
You did say something about the money.
Yeah, the money.
Something I gotta ask you.
I've been very, very careful.
Have you been very, very careful?
Of course.
- Nobody knows you hired me?
Don't be stupid.
I'm not about to tell anyone.
We have to learn to be discreet.
Trust each other.
For richer, for poorer.
Don't say that. Your marriages
don't turn out so hot.
How did you cover the money?
- It's been taken care of.
The less you know about it,
the better.
I made a call.
It'll be all right.
I must've gone money simple.
A murder like this...
...too risky.
You shouldn't have done it.
Can't have it both ways.
Count it
and go.
I trust you.
Who looks stupid now?
Damn!
What's the matter? You deaf?
You home?
What night is tonight?
What night is it?
Tuesday?
- Tuesday night is ladies' night.
What?
All your drinks are free.
...increased over 80%
in the last three years.
What's more,
in two years' time we'll be
experiencing the Jupiter effect.
Then all the planets in the universe
will cause this unbelievable...
...and these will be the sons
of which we shall know.
Although real good people
disagree with me,
I believe
that this Antichrist
is alive today
living in the ten nation alliance
I was talking about...
This is WKLJ,
"Through the Night."
I'm John Lievsay.
I'll be with you till six this morning
when Mike Miller will be stepping in.
Here's a request
we really had to dig for.
Abby, you all right?
Ray? What time is it?
I don't know. It's early.
I love you.
You all right?
I don't know.
I better get off now.
I'll see you.
Thanks, Ray.
Shit!
Why didn't you get into bed?
I didn't think I could sleep.
I'm surprised you could.
You called me this morning.
I wanted to let you know
that everything was all right.
I took care of everything.
All we have to do is keep our heads.
What do you mean?
- I know about it.
I went to the bar last night.
- What happened?
Was Meurice there?
- Yeah.
But he didn't see me though.
Nobody saw me.
Is it cold in here?
What happened?
I cleaned it all up.
But that ain't important.
What we do now is important.
We can't go around half-cocked.
We need time to think about this.
Figure it out.
We got some time now,
but we gotta be smart.
Never point a gun at anyone
unless you mean to shoot him.
And if you shoot,
make sure he's dead.
'cause if he ain't,
he's gonna kill you.
It's the only thing we learned
in the service that's worth a goddamn.
Where the hell's my windbreaker?
Tell me what happened.
That ain't important.
What's important is that we did it.
Only that matters.
We both did it for each other.
That's what's important. - Don't know
what you're talking about.
I mean,
what are you talking about?
I haven't done anything funny.
What was that?
You're not even acting like yourself.
First, you call me at 5 a.m.,
saying all kinds of nice things,
then you come chargin' in, scaring me
half to death without telling me why.
I mean,
if you two had a fight...
I don't care,
just as long as...
Pick it up.
What?
Well, it's him.
Who?
What's going on with you two?
All right.
You can call him back,
whoever it was.
I'll get out of your way.
You left your weapon behind.
Hi, Meurice, this is Helene Trend.
What the hell does that remark
you made about Sylvia mean?
She says you're full of shit.
I believe her, and I love you, too.
Call me soon, 'cause I'm goin'
to South America tonight, to Uruguay.
Listen, asshole, it's Marty.
I just got back from Corpus Christi.
A lot of money's missing.
I'm not saying you took it,
but the place was your responsibility.
I told you to keep an eye
on your asshole friend.
Don't come to the bar tonight...
What is this?
The bar's gonna be closed tonight.
I got business to do. But tomorrow
I wanna have a word with you and Ray,
if you can find him.
I hope you're planning
on leaving town.
You got a problem?
No, but you do, cowboy.
- Have you been to the bar? - Why?
You shouldn't have taken
the fuckin' money! Look at me!
I'm serious! You broke in the bar
and ripped off the fuckin' safe!
Abby warned me about you.
Know what your problem is?
You're too fuckin' obvious. Only you
and me know the combination, and Abby,
maybe.
These fuckin' things are coffin nails!
Hey, look.
I don't give a shit. Marty is
a hard-on, but you gotta do somethin'.
Say you're sorry. Give the money back.
Get the fuck outta here... something!
Shit!
It's very humiliating
preaching about this bullshit!
But I'm not laughin'.
So you know it's no fuckin' joke!
Damn!
Lover boy oughta lock the door.
I love you.
Stupid thing to say, right.
I love you, too.
No.
You're just saying that,
because you're scared.
You left your weapon behind.
He'll kill you, too.
Where is everything?
In the trunk.
In the car.
You leavin'?
Isn't that what you want?
Wanna come with me?
I gotta know what happened first.
What d'you wanna know?
You broke into the bar.
You wanted to get your money.
You and Marty had a fight.
And something happened...
I don't know...
Wasn't it you?
Maybe a burglar broke in...
- With your gun.
Nobody broke in.
I'll tell you the truth.
Truth is...
I've been feelin' sick
the last couple of days.
Can't sleep.
Can't eat.
When I try...
Truth is,
he was alive when I buried him.
Yeah, just a second!
What's the matter? - I think
Marty's dead. Can I come in?
That's bullshit! Marty called me
after he was jacked up.
I don't know where Marty is,
but he's not dead.
You relax, and I'll go find him.
And stay away from Ray.
The guy's gone nuts.
Turn it off.
Just turn it off!
Why?
No curtains on the windows.
So?
I think someone's watchin'.
- So what'll they see?
Leave it off!
If you do anything
the neighbors'll hear.
You think...
I meant it...
when I called.
I love you, too.
You're scared.
All right.
You got some of my personal property.
One of you do.
I don't know what the hell you two
thought you were gonna pull off.
I'm not afraid of you, Marty.
Well, ma'am.
If I see him,
I'll sure give him the message.