Excuse me, can you tell me this
where Delmare Berry lives?
He ain't here.
Go on inside.
He's a friend of mine, he wrote
this address down, right here.
Here.
You can see that's Delmare's writing.
I sure had a hard time finding this place.
- That's his writin'.
- Like I said, he's a friend.
My name is John Rambo.
We served on the same team together in 'Nam.
I don't know if he ever talked about me.
I've got a picture of us together.
Somewhere.
This junk in my pocket!
Here... here it is.
That's me, that's Danforth,
Westmore, Bronson, Ortega,
and there's Delmare, right in the back.
Had to put him in the back because he's so big...
if we didn't, he'd take up the whole picture.
- Delmare's gone.
- What time will he be back?
- He died.
What?
Died last summer.
Died how?
Cancer. Brought it back from 'Nam.
All that orange stuff
they spread it around.
Cut him down to nothing.
I could lift him off the sheets.
I'm very sorry.
Morning Amy! How are you doing, girls?
- Great, thanks. - Alright this morning?
- Andy!
- Howdy, Will!
Good morning, Dave. - Hi, Sheriff.
- Gonna take a bath this week?
Morning!
You visiting someone around here?
No.
You know, wearing that flag on your jacket,
looking the way you do...
You're asking for trouble around here, friend.
- Headed north or south?
- North.
Jump in, I'll make sure you're
headed in the right direction.
- Where you heading?
- Portland.
Portland's is South, you said you were headed North.
You got some place I can eat around here?
There's a diner about 30 miles up the highway.
- Is there a law against me getting something to eat here?
- Yeah, me.
Why are you pushing me?
What did you say?
I said why are you pushing me,
I haven't done anything to you.
First of all, you don't ask the questions
around here, I do. Understand?
Secondly, we don't want guys like you in this town.
Drifters.
First thing you know we got a whole bunch
of guys like you in this town. That's why!
Besides, you wouldn't like it here,
This is a quiet little town.
In fact you might say it's boring.
But that's the way we like it.
And I get paid to keep it that way.
Boring.
Portland, straight ahead.
If you want some friendly advice...
Get your hair cut and take a bath.
You wouldn't get hassled so much.
Hope this ride helped you out.
Have a nice day, huh?
Where the hell do you think you're going?
I'm talking to you, goddammit!
Let's see some I.D.!
All right, you're under arrest!
Put your hands on the car.
You put your hands on the car,
and you spread them.
You're going to put your hands on that car,
How you do it you decide, right now!
Legs back.
Back!
You try to be nice to some people!
Well, what do we have here?
- Why would you be carrying a knife like this?
- Hunting.
Don't be a wise guy!
What do you hunt with a knife?
- Name it.
Hi, Will.
- Lester.
Buzz us in, will ya.
- Hey, talk about your sorry looking humanity.
Just another smartass drifter.
Morning, Arthur.
- Morning, Will. What do you got?
I want you to book this gentleman for vagrancy,
resisting arrest carrying a concealed weapon.
- He says he uses it for hunting.
- Huntin'? What do you hunt, elephants?
See if you can clean him up a little.
Smells like an animal.
Hey, Mitch.
- Escort this young man downstairs.
- Yes sir, Mr. Galt. Right this way, partner.
OK, here we go.
You know it looks like it'll take
old Leroy 10 years to paint this hall
- Why don't you paint it your damned self!!
Come on, Leroy, sling that paint, boy.
- Mr. Ward,
Take these.
- Thank you.
Name?
Your name
If you're looking for trouble,
you came to the right place, buddy!
Wait.
You got three seconds before I break your face in.
He means it.
Yeah, I do.
What do you know about that.
Old Harry here is a soldier
Rambo.
John J.?
You're gonna talk to me.
I promise you're gonna talk to me, soldier.
I'm starting to dislike you.
A lot.
I'm gonna run a make on him.
Put his name in the Teletype.
Just roll it across.
Roll it across!
- Push it.
- It won't work that way
it'll only smear. Now, roll it across!
Look, you son of a bitch, if you don't put your
god damned hand down there, I'm gonna break it off!
Put it down, god dammit!
- What the hell's going on down here?
Nothing I can't handle.
He won't let us print him well.
Leave the ink on the hand!
Just what is your problem?
As things stand right now, you're facing
the ass end of a 90 day incarceration!
Plus a 250 dollar fine which you don't
look to me like you can pay.
At 10 o'clock tomorrow morning you're going up
in front of that judge. And you think we're tough!
We're going to make you more presentable
for your courtroom appearance.
Between now and then, you can just impress
the hell out of me by doing exactly as you're told.
Clean him up.
Preston, go over there
and get that hose ready, alright?
Holy shit, look at this!
What the hell's he been in to?
Who gives a shit?
Hands above your head and turn around.
Oh Christ, we should report this to Teasle.
Look at that!
You just do what I tell you.
Galt, what the fuck was that?
The man said 'clean him up'.
Clean him up!
Hey, Preston, don't forget
to get him behind the ears!
How'd you like that, huh?
What's the matter, Mitch,
don't you like water sports?
Hurry it up, it's time for my coffee break.
Alright, sit down.
Sit down!
Damn it, boy's hard to get a hold of!
That's OK, Ward, don't worry about the soap, he's tough.
Just shave him. Dry!
How blind are you? Can't you see he's crazy?
- Can't you see I don't give a shit?
Yeah, I can see that.
- That's better.
See there, I knew that you..
We're just going to shaving you partner, take it easy.
- Take this, Mitch.
Don't move...
I don't want you to cut your own throat.
You asshole!
What the hell...
I'll kill the asshole!
- Art, don't shoot!
There's people down there!
Get help! I'll go after him!
Get out of the way!
Son of a bitch!
Lester, this is Will. I'm right on his tail.
He's just east of Smith's farm,
headed towards Chapman Creek.
I know you can hear me!
You're finished!
You're gone as far as you're going to go!
D'you hear me?
He's up there behind the draw.
Mitch, get Orval on the radio. Tell him to get out
here with his damned dogs right away.
Tell him to bring the Dobermen! lt's gonna rain,
we need dogs that can hunt on sight.
Lester, tell Paul to get out to the
lumber camp to get the helicopter up here.
If they give him any shit, tell him to site
him for obstruction right on the spot.
We'll get him.
No problem.
Go on, Hooch! Thunder, lets get him!
Come on sweethearts
We'll get him!
Won't be long before he's stuffed and mounted.
- make him into a bear rug.
Didn't we go hunting here last year?
Ya I got a couple of bucks last year.
Mitch, up the hill!
Get these hounds away from me, Orval!
I don't trust those bastards.
Keep moving, my dogs can eat
and run at the same time!
He's going straight to the top.
- Isn't that supposed to be dangerous? - He's just dumb!
Hey, you're spoiling the scent.
Let my babies do their job!
This is no good.
- Why?
there were three of us in the cell block down there.
He went through us like we weren't even there.
Come on!
We've got him, he's trapped!
- Art, he's heading for Chapman's gorge.
Head him off!
There he is! On the cliff!
Son of a bitch!
What the hell's going on?
What are you doing?
We're just supposed to spot him!
Hold it steady.
- I can't, we're in a thermal draft.
He's stuck there, he can't go any place.
If you don't ride this thing right
I swear to God, I'll kill you!
Sheriff to Galt! Come in Galt.
Hold it steady, you son of a bitch!
Galt, come in, God damn it!
Get closer and hold it steady!
- Galt, talk to me! I want to know what's going on.
I got him... easy now.
Over there, dummy! Come on!
Hey, soldier boy!
Galt, get on this radio! What's going on up there?
I don't want him dead, Galt, I want him alive!
You hear me? Art, come in!
Art Galt, come in!
Helicopter, come, dammit!
Christ, look!
Jesus Christ, give me the binoculars!
Oh no! Shit!
- I can't figure it. How did fall out?
- Does it matter?
Let's nail this sucker's ass...
he can't be far.
Look!
Looks like he wants to turn himself in.
There's one man is dead. lt's not my fault.
I don't want any more hurt.
Freeze!
Stay there and give yourself up!
But I didn't do anything!
I'm warning you, boy, don't make a move, I'll blow your head off!
I didn't do anything!
Cease fire!
Ward, God damn it, cease fire!
I think we hit him.
Let's get down there. Move
Sheriff to base, come in.
Go ahead, Will?
Lester, we're down in the gorge. Galt's dead alright.
Where the hell is that god damned chopper?
He won't come, Will. Says there's a storm heading your way.
I don't give a god damned what's on its way.
I want the chopper back here right now!
I don't want Galt's body out here all night.
You sure picked one hell of a guy to mess around with.
Just came over the Teletype a few minutes ago.
John Rambo is a Vietnam vet,
A Green Beret, Congressional medal of honor.
Guy's a war hero.
- Jesus, that freak?
- I knew there was something about that guy!
I double checked it, Will.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to do what told you to do.
Dod damn it. Get that chopper back here now, out.
A Green Beret!
War hero!
- That's great! That's just great!
- Shut your mouth!
What the hell's the matter with you guys?
He's one man... wounded.
Those Green Berets... they're real bad asses.
Why don't you let the State Police handle this?
Look at him! Goddammit!
Look. Look at him!
That's Art Galt, boy!
He and I were friends when your momma
was still wiping your nose!
Now he's dead. Because of that psycho out there!
Now you listen good:
I'm gonna get that son of a bitch and I'm gonna pin
that Congressional medal of honor to his liver.
And I'm gonna do it with you or without you.
We're closin' in, the scent's getting
stronger. - Keep your eyes open.
It's going to storm, that's all we need now!
Will, let's get out of here before it gets dark.
What's the matter, you afraid of the boogie man?
You god damned pansy.
Put your gun down, I'll show you who the pansy is.
Knock it off! Ward, move out! The fight is out here!
He's out there waiting for you.
Mitch, get on your feet and move!
Go find this guy for Chrissakes!
Keep your eyes open!
See you later, Ward!
- Shut up, Mitch.
There he is!
Let them dogs loose, Orval!
Go get em sweethearts!
There's your dinner!
Cease fire!
Goddammit I'm hit!
Jesus, he's got a gun.
That's not him, it's a God damned scarecrow.
No scarecrow that shot Orville, he's close.
Kill him! Go get him!
Go get him, Maggie!
Mitch, Ward, come here!
Shingleton, you cover us.
Look at his leg! - Mitch, get your belt. Make a
tourniquet around that.
We got to get this guy to a doctor.
- Get your belt on that fast! Where's the first-aid kit?
I left it in the car. Shit! Where did he
get that gun? - It's Galt's gun.
He's out of ammo.. - How do you know that?
- Because whatever killed that dog was no bullet.
Orval, listen. You have to stay awake.
You have to release the tourniquet every 15 minutes.
We got to get him. He's out of ammo.
He had no right to shoot my babies.
Get the son of a bitch!
OK, listen up.
We're right on top of him. We're going to form
a skirmish line, 50 feet apart.
Keep moving, there's no way out of here, except through us.
OK, let's do some huntin'.
Huntin'?
We ain't huntin' him, he's huntin' us!
Spread out, dammit!
I said 50 feet!
I hate this!
Will, it's Mitch!
Who is it?
What's up here?
- Shut up!
He's got Ward.
Spread out, I'll go this way.
Who's firing?
Who's firing there?
- I got him!
Shingleton, follow me!
I got him!
Help me!
Help me, Will!
Balford? Where the hell are you?
Shingleton, over here!
Easy now.
- Get me out of here!
Shingleton, where the hell are you?
I could have killed them all.
I could have killed you.
In town you're the law, out here, it's me.
Don't push it.
Don't push it, or I'll give you a war
you won't believe.
Let it go.
Move back.
How bad is the situation? Captain...
That's the only good thing about this business,
is the business you're doing in town.
Reporters are drinking the place dry.
You look like you're ready to keel over, Will.
Why don't you go home. It's my problem now.
Your problem? Listen Dave, don't give me any of your horsehit
about jurisdiction in this one, you understand?
- Would you like me to step outside?
- Finish up what you're doing.
Somewhere in this rugged mountain countryside,
possibly above the snow line,
shrouded in mist,
the fugitive, John Rambo, is hiding.
Units of the state police along with local members
of the national guard are now being mobilized.
What still remains unexplained by the local authorities
is just how and where the former green beret
came into possession of the weapons
former Green Beret got the weapons
with which he allegedly killed one deputy sheriff
and tried to kill 6 others. Only their skilled training
in police enforcement techniques saved their lives.
And word now is that the fugitive will be
in custody an a matter of hours.
Maps Will.
Will, there's something you ought to know.
Talk to you later, OK?
What is it, Lester? Spit it out!
I was just talking to Mitch.
and he was saying that Galt and a couple
of deputies were a little hard on the guy.
Assholes!
Doesn't make one god dammed bit of difference.
Dave, and you know it!
If one of my deputies gets out of line with a
prisoner then the prisoner comes to me with it!
And if I find out it's like he says,
I kick the deputy's ass!
Me, the law!
And that's the way it's gotta be.
People start fucking around with
the law and all hell breaks loose.
- Whatever possessed God in heaven to make a man like Rambo?
- God didn't make Rambo,
I made him.
Who the hell are you?
Sam Trautman. Colonel Samuel Trautman.
We're a little busy this morning, colonel,
what can we do for you?
- I've come to get my boy.
- Your boy?
I recruited him, I trained him,
I commanded him in Vietnam for 3 years.
I'd say that makes him mine.
I wonder why the Pentagon would send
a full bird a colonel to handle this?
The army thought I might be able to help.
I don't know in what way. Rambo's
a civilian now, he's my problem.
I don't think you understand.
I didn't come here to rescue Rambo from you.
I came to rescue you from him.
Well, we all appreciate your concern, Colonel.
We'll try to be extra careful.
- I'm just amazed he allowed any of your posse to live.
- Is that right?
Strictly speaking, he slipped up.
You're lucky to be breathing.
Great! Colonel, you came out here to find out
why one of your machines blew a gasket.
You don't want to except the fact that you're
dealing with an expert in guerilla warfare.
With a man who's the best. With guns,
with knives, with his bare hands.
An man who was trained to
ignore pain, ignore weather,
To live off the land... to eat things
that would make a billy goat puke.
In Vietnam, his job was to dispose of
enemy personnel, to kill... period.
Win by attrition.
Well, Rambo was the best!
OK, Colonel, now you've got us all scared to death, what do you
and the special forces think
we do with the psycho out there?
- Let him go.
- Do what?
- For now.
Defuse the whole situation, defuse him.
Provide a little gap and let him slip through it.
In a couple of weeks you'll pick him up in Seattle or someplace,
working in a car wash.
There'll be no fight and nobody else will get hurt.
I do my own work. I don't figure the best way to do that is
to close my eyes and hope he gets picked up in Seattle!
If you send your people in there after him, they'll get killed.
We're just a small hick town sheriff's department,
colonel, but we're expected to do our duty
just like our heroes in the special forces.
- In Special Forces, we teach our people
to stay alive in the line of duty.
- No shit, I never thought of that!
- You want a war that you can't win?
- You telling me that 200 men against your boy
is a no win situation for us?
You send that many, don't forget one thing.
- What? - A good supply of body-bags!
Trautman...
I don't know which side you're on, Trautman,
I still think you came out here just to cover your ass.
But if you're serious about taking Rambo clean, follow me.
State police calling John Rambo.
Acknowledge.
Come in please. Acknowledge!
If you're listening, Rambo, here's
your situation: you are surrounded,
Every possible exit has been blocked,
every highway, every road, every fire break.
You have our word that your services
to your country will be taken into consideration.
And you'll receive fair treatment.
- Just respond, we can work everything out... over
- Anything?
- He took a radio off one of my deputies.
- Then he has to be listening.
If I was in his position, I would try to pick up
some information. Maybe catch some cross talk.
- Of course he's listening!
- He's not going to break radio silence.
- No, not for us, but he might do it for you, Colonel.
He's your boy, isn't he?
maybe you can talk him into sparing
all our lives by giving himself up.
I can try.
At least we'd get a radio fix on his position
if you don't mind setting him up for us.
Setting him up for you?
That's like bringing the pigeons to the cat.
- Thanks for bringing your people out.
- Any time, Will.
Come on, Bobby, put the magazine away and pay attention.
We may only get one crack at this.
Company leader calling Raven.
Come on Raven.
Company leader to Raven,
talk to me, Johnny.
Company leader to identify Baker Team:
Rambo, Messner, Ortega, Coletta,
Jorgensen, Danforth, Berry, Krakauer.
Confirm.
This is Colonel Trautman.
Talk to me, Johnny.
They're all gone, Sir.
- That's him, get on it.
- Rambo. Are you alright? Over.
Baker team, they're all dead, sir.
Not Delmare Berry, he made it.
Berry's gone too, sir.
How?
Got himself killed in 'Nam...
Didn't even know it. Cancer ate him down to the bone.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
I'm the last one, sir.
It's good to hear your voice, Johnny,
it's been a long time.
Look, John, you've done some damage here, but they
don't want any more trouble. - He's North-west.
That's why I've come.
I'm gonna come in and fly you the hell out.
Just you and me. We'll work this out together.
Is that fair enough?
- Where'd you come from, Sir?
- Bragg.
I tried to get in touch with you but the guys
at Bragg never knew where to find you.
Well, I haven't been spending much time there lately,
they've got me down in DC. I'm shining a seat with my ass.
I wish I was back in Bragg now.
- We'll talk about that when you come in.
- I can't do that, Sir.
Well, look, John, we can't have you running around
out there wasting friendlies and civilians.
- There are no friendly civilians.
- I'm your friend, Johnny.
I was there with you, knee deep in blood and guts.
I covered your ass more than once.
Seems like bailing you out of trouble
is becoming a life long job for me.
There wouldn't be any trouble
if it wasn't for that king shit cop.
All I wanted was something to eat.
- But the man kept pushing sir.
- You did some pushing on your own, John.
They drew first blood, not me.
Let me come in and get you the hell out of there.
They drew first blood.
Rambo, are you still reading me?
Company leader to Raven!
Rambo, acknowledge!
He's finished, Colonel
We've got a real good fix on him though. Come first light,
I'm gonna put every man I got up on that ridge.
Then we'll get him my way.
Dammit.
God dammit!
Come on move it!
Does this guy got a gun?
There's the guy the cops are shootin' at.
- I see him! - I'll get him.
Don't shoot!
This way! Let's go!
There he is! Come on!
Now we got him!
Yes, I know exactly where it is.
Now listen to me very carefully!
Surround the area with every man you got, but don't move in.
Don't do anything till I get there!
And no shooting! I don't want him dead, I want him alive!
Keep firing!
Go on, guys, shoot!
Come on!
You guys are great!
Steve. I want you and Bruce, head around
these trees go to the front of that mine.
Screw that, Clinton, I ain't goin up there!
- No way!
Brandon, I want you to go into that mine.
- Not me.
What do you mean, not me?
- I do this part time, I didn't come here to get killed.
He's probably waiting for us.
What's wrong with you, Clinton?
Rambo?
This is Lieutenant Clinton Morgan.
National Guard leader.
I'm giving you just 3 zero seconds
to come on out.
Who's got the rocket launcher?
- I do. - Come here, Earl.
Rambo. This is your last chance to come out!
Maybe we should wait.
Earl, this creep is a killer! Besides,
I'm in charge and I say we blow it up.
Now fire that thing!
Just let me get out of the way first.
Give that man a cigar!
Bull's eye!
- Where the hell are they?
- Up the hill about 500 yards.
Move in a little closer just like Iwa Jima.
I don't believe it! Idiots!
One more for "Soldier of Fortune"!
What the hell do you think this is... some kind of circus?
Get the hell out of here!
Clinton, Jesus! Didn't you get the word, Clinton,
I told you people to wait until I got up here.
Well, he was shooting at us, Will!
I wasn't taking any chances.
What a mess.
We have to dig his body out of there right away.
You can't get a dozer up here,
you have to find somebody to dig him out.
- lt's your mess, Clinton! You clean it up.
- Will, come on... I gotta be back at the drug store tomorrow.
You'd better get started right away, Clinton!
Buried in a hole by a bunch of
God damned weekend warriors!
Thought you said he was the best you ever trained.
However he may have ended up, there
was a time when he was very special.
'Special' my ass. He's just another drifter that broke the law.
- Vagrancy, wasn't it?
That's gonna look real great on his gravestone
in Arlington: ''Here lies John Rambo,
winner of the Congressional medal of honor.
Survivor of countless incursions behind enemy lines,
killed for vagrancy in Jerkwater, USA''
Don't give me any of that crap, Trautman!
You think Rambo was the only guy
who had a tough time in Vietnam.
- He killed a police officer for Christ sake!
- You're god damned lucky he didn't kill all of you.
This character! He comes waltzing in here
full of all kinds of good advice.
I wish we'd let that god damned maniac go loose...
so we could save our own asses!
Well, we saved our asses, Colonel.
And we didn't let him go loose.
The best man lost!
And he doesn't like it!
- How are you doin', Will?
- Hold my calls.
Have a seat.
Miss, can you do this again, please.
- Sure. - And for my friend...?
A shot of wild turkey.
If I was out of line before,
I just want to apologize.
None of that makes much difference now, does it?
No, I guess not.
I suppose...
I just feel...
Like you were cheated out of your chance?
I wanted to kill that kid.
I wanted to kill him so bad, I could taste it.
Doesn't sit well with that badge.
It can get confusing sometimes.
In Vietnam you can bet that Rambo and I got pretty confused.
But we had orders.
When in doubt, kill.
But what the hell, you're a civilian. You can go home
to your wife, your house and flower garden.
You're under no pressure to figure all this out.
What about you colonel,
what did you figure out from all of this?
What would you have done with him if he came in?
Would you wrap your arms around him
give him a big sloppy kiss?
Or would you have blown his brains out?
I couldn't answer that until I met him face to face.
Well, there it is.
Just as well we never got a chance to find out.
Drive!
Don't look at me, look at the road.
That's how accidents happen.
What's your name?
- Cathcart, Robert A.
- What do you got in the back, Robert A.?
- M16s
OK, Robert A., get out of the truck.
- I don't got no beef with you.
- Go home!
Want to turn that up?
What's your story, Steamboat?
Looks like somebody pulled the plug too soon.
That Rambo guy? He's on the loose again.
Hey Will, it's Rambo! He's still around
- Holy fuck!
- Get out there right away. Move!
What the hell's going on?
Watch yourselves!
- They're all gonna blow!
Attention, all civilians!
For your own safety
please evacuate the streets immediately.
Remain indoors until you receive further instructions. I repeat:
This is a police emergency.
Please evacuate the streets immediately.
They found Rambo's body.
lt stole a truck and blew up a gas
station on the other side of town.
The kid is resilient.
Why don't you forget what you're thinking
and clear out while you can.
- Get the fuck out of here Trautman
and take your advice with you.
When I talked to earlier,
you knew he was still alive, didn't you?
I suspected it.
Sure, that's why you stuck around.
You trained him.
You taught him how to get out of places like that cave.
But he's not going to get out of this place.
Teasle, you and all your men couldn't handle him before,
what makes you think you can handle him now?
Because God knows what damage he's prepared to do.
You're going to die, Teasle.
Everybody dies!
There's only one man in this room that has a half a chance.
That's not because I'm better than he is.
But it's because he trusts me.
See, I'm the closest thing to family that he has left,
and that may be all the edge I need.
Jesus Christ, where do you people come from?
This is my job, Trautman,
this is my town!
I'm not giving it up to you,
or to Rambo or anybody else!
You just stay the hell out of my way!
- Get a little closer!
- I can't...
It's too God damned hot!
Will, it's Lester, do you copy, over?
Come on, let's go!
Will, this is Lester, do you copy, over?
We've got some serious problems.
The highway's been cut off.
The truck's out here,
but we couldn't find the body.
I repeat, no body, lt's totally burnt out.
Preston, get those people out of here...
Move them back to the south side.
We don't know how many gas tanks
there are under the pumps...
Go ahead, go ahead!
- Go ahead you crazy son of a bitch!
- Rambo!
Rambo, don't do it!
Listen to me, Rambo!
You have no chance.
Drop your weapon.
We're going to order a chopper in
and fly you back to Bragg.
Hold your fire!
- Yeah?
- Hold your fire!
Think about what you're doing.
The building's perimeter's covered.
No exits.
There's nearly 200 men out there and a lot of M16s!
You did everything to make this private war happen.
You've done enough damage!
This mission is over, you understand me?
This mission is over!
Look at them out there.
Look at them!
If you don't end this now,
they're going to kill you.
Is that what you want?
lt's over, Johnny. lt's over!
Nothing is over! Nothing!
You just don't turn it off!
lt wasn't my war.
You asked me, I didn't ask you!
I did everything I had to do to win,
but someone wouldn't let us win.
Then I come back to the world and I see all those
maggots at the airport protesting me, spitting.
Calling me baby killer and all that vile crap!
Who are they to protest me? Who are they?
Unless they've been me and been there and know
what the hell they're yelling about?
It was a bad time for everyone, Rambo,
it's all in the past now.
For you! For me, civilian life is nothing.
In the field, we had a code of honor.
You watch my back, I watch yours.
Back here, there's nothing!
You're the last of an elite group,
don't end it like this.
Back there I can fly a gun ship, I can drive a tank,
I was in charge of a million dollar equipment.
Back here I can't even hold a job parking cars!
Where is everybody?
I had a friend who was there for us.
There were all these guys, man.
Back there were all these fuckin guys!
who were my friends!
back here there's nothing!
Remember Dan Forest?
Wore this black headband.
I took one of his magic markers, and I said "if found...
mail this to Las Vegas",
because we were always talking about Vegas.
And this fucking car. this fucking 58 Chevy convertible
he was talking about his car
he said he would cruise till the tires fell off.
In one of these barns a kid came up
this kid carrying a shoe shine box.
"Shine please, shine?"
He kept on asking. Joe said ya.
I went to get a couple of beers.
And the box was wired. He opened up the box...
Fucking blew his body all over the place.
He's laying there and he's fucking screaming...
there's pieces of him all over me!
And I'm trying to pull them off, you know...
my friend! it's all over me!
I got blood and everything and...
I'm trying to hold him together, I put him together
the fucking entrails keep coming out!
And nobody would help!
They only go "I want to go home!"
just calling my name.
"I want to go home, Johnny!
I want to drive my Chevy!
But I couldn't find his legs.
"I can't find your legs!"
I can't get it out of my head.
It was seven years.
Every day it hurts.
Sometimes I wake up and don't know
where I am. I don't talk to anybody.
Sometimes a day.
Sometimes a week.
I can't put it out of my mind.