Darling, don't be difficult.
Let's take our sweet...
Iovely children on an outing.
You can't do this.
I know my rights.
I have the authority to close
you down, and I'm doing just that.
This exhibit degrades everybody who
sees it and the creature himself.
He is a freak!
How else will he live?
Freaks are one thing.
This is entirely different.
This is monstrous
and should not be allowed.
These officers will see to it
you're on your way soon. Good day!
Move along please.
Hold it there, sir.
Come this way.
On the move again...
my treasure.
We'll be seeing a lot more
of these machine accidents...
- Mr. Hodges.
- Yes, sir.
Abominable things, these machines.
You can't reason with them.
What a mess!
Pull on the rope.
Irons, please.
Who is it?
- Excuse me, Mr. Treves, sir.
- Yes, what is it?
- I found it.
- Good. Did you see it?
All right. I'll see you
in a moment. Thank you.
Who's that?
- A friend of mine.
- Oh, yes.
- What are you up to?
- Nothing.
Come on, Freddie!
Nothing of any importance.
Can you tell me
where Cleeves Street is?
'Round back, to the left,
then to the right. Straight through.
Thank you.
Are you the proprietor?
And who might you be, sir?
Just one of the curious.
I'd like to see it.
I don't think so.
No, sir, we're...
closed.
Now, I'd pay handsomely
for a private showing.
Are you the proprietor?
Handsomely?
Who sent you?
- I beg your pardon?
- Never mind.
I'm the owner.
Life...
is full of surprises.
Consider the fate...
of this creature's poor mother...
struck down...
in the fourth month
of her maternal condition...
by an elephant,
a wild elephant.
Struck down...
on an uncharted African isle.
The result...
is plain to see.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the terrible...
Elephant Man!
- Stand up.
- Stand up!
Turn around.
Turn around! Turn around!
Yes...
you'll bring him to me
tomorrow morning at 10:00, Mr... .
Bytes.
He'll be there.
Good.
Here's my card,
and I'll send a cab.
All right?
We have a deal.
We understand each other.
More than money has changed hands.
We understand each other
completely, my friend.
Yes, well, thank you, Mr. Bytes.
Tomorrow.
Cor! What a stink!
I'm looking
for Mr. Frederick Treves...
please, ma'am.
Very well.
I'll-I'll send for him.
Nurse...
Oh, Mr. Treves, sir, this...
- This...
- Yes. Thank you.
Yes, I was expecting him.
- Yes, are you the cab driver?
- Yes, sir.
- Anyone else with you?
- No, sir. Just this gentleman.
- Thank you for your troubles.
- Not at all, sir.
My pleasure.
Thank you.
Will you come this way, please?
Mrs. Mothershead, I'll be in my
room, and I'm not to be disturbed.
- All right?
- Of course, sir.
Will you come with me, please?
You heard what the doctor said!
Go on.
My name is Frederick Treves...
and I'm a surgeon here
at the London Hospital.
And...
I lecture in anatomy
at the medical college.
I'd like very much
to examine you so that...
Would that be all right?
Please.
First I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
Would that be all right?
Your owner tells me... I mean the man
who looks after you tells me...
that you're English
and your name is John Merrick.
John Merrick.
Is that right?
I tell you what.
I think I'll ask you a question...
and you shake your head
like this for "no."
Have you always been
the way you are now?
Are you in any pain?
Are your parents still alive?
Do you understand me?
Your father and your mother,
are they dead?
Freddie, what are you doing for...
Oh, I'm dreadfully sorry.
I had no idea you had...
Freddie, what the hell
have you got in there?
You'll know soon enough,
at the meeting of the Society.
Until then, I beg of you
not a word to anyone, please.
All right, if you insist. But you
must have quite a find in there.
- I don't know what I've got.
- Nothing of any importance, eh?
Not a word, please, Fox.
Not a word.
All right.
Thank you.
It's all right.
I think I'll examine you now.
I'll leave the questions
till later.
All right?
Will you take
your hat off now, please?
Don't be frightened.
I simply want to look at you.
Take your hat off.
Don't be frightened.
Thank you.
Good afternoon.
Mr. Thomas, Mr. Rogers.
Pull the curtains aside.
He is English...
he is 2 1 years of age...
and his name is John Merrick.
Gentlemen, in the course of
my profession I have come upon...
many lamentable deformities of
the face due to injury or disease...
as well as mutilations...
and contortions of the body
depending upon like causes.
But at no time have I met
with such...
a perverted or degraded version
of a human being as this man.
I draw your attention to the
insidious conditions affecting him.
- Can you see over there?
- Yes.
Note, if you will, the
extreme enlargement of the skull...
right upper limb,
which is totally useless...
the alarming curvature
of the spine.
- Would you turn around, please?
- Turn around, please.
The looseness of the skin...
and the varying fibrous tumors
that cover 90% of the body.
And there is every indication that
these afflictions have been...
in existence and have
progressed rapidly since birth.
The patient also suffers
from chronic bronchitis.
As an interesting side note...
in spite of the
aforementioned anomalies...
the patient's genitals remain
entirely intact and unaffected.
Thank you.
And his left arm is perfectly
normal, as you see.
So then, gentlemen, owing
to this series of conditions...
the congenital skull exostosis,
extensive papillomatous growth...
large pendulous masses
in connection with the skin...
the great enlargement
of the right upper limb...
involving all the bones, the massive
distortion of the head...
and the extensive area
covered by papillomatous growth...
the patient has been called
the Elephant Man.
Thank you.
You never mentioned
his mental state.
Oh, he's an imbecile,
probably from birth.
The man's a complete idiot.
I pray to God he's an idiot.
Where have you been?
Out.
How can I eat
with a noise like that?
Bytes, don't!
Where have you been?
What did you do?
- Our man is sick. Come right away.
- What is it?
Like this.
What did you do with him?
He's been like this all night.
He was fine when he left here.
Now look at him.
Yes, I intend to.
- What happened?
- He fell!
He falls.
Looks like he's had
a very severe fall.
He's a clumsy soul.
Never looks where he's going.
But that's all right.
He has me to take care of him.
Why is he sitting up like this?
He needs rest.
Well, that's how he sleeps.
If he lies down,
he'll kill himself.
His head's too big.
All right. This man
belongs in a hospital.
Can't you treat him here?
Listen, he's my livelihood.
We're business partners,
he and I.
He's the greatest freak
in the world.
Yes, now you listen. You won't have
much of a livelihood if he dies.
Now, stop wasting my time.
I'm going to fetch a cab.
I truly, truly appreciate this,
my friend.
Listen. There are a lot of things
I could do for you.
You see, I move in the proper
circles for this type of thing.
In fact, anything at all...
if you take my meaning.
Everything will be taken care of.
It's good to do business with you.
Here we go.
All right.
Can I have a bowl
of oatmeal, please?
Yes, sir.
Breakfasting with the patients
this morning, Mr. Treves?
Yes. No, it's for a patient.
There you are, sir.
Thank you. Morning.
Morning.
Oh, Treves! Just come here
for a moment, will you?
What's that?
Good heavens! You haven't acquired
a sudden taste for this, have you?
- Yes, sir. It's quite nutritious.
- Possibly.
Not quite the diet
for a grown man.
Nurse!
When you have a moment...
take this up to the patient
in the isolation ward, will you?
Yes, sir.
Don't be frightened.
He won't hurt you.
Won't he indeed!
Just a minute, Treves.
Something I want to say to you.
Come in.
A hospital's no place for secrecy,
you know, Mr. Treves.
Doctors spiriting hooded figures
about is apt to cause comment.
Why wasn't this patient
properly admitted?
Why is he in the isolation ward?
He's not contagious, is he?
No, sir. He's got chronic bronchitis
and he's been badly beaten.
Why isn't he
in the general ward then?
Well, sir, he's quite
seriously deformed...
and I fear the other patients
would find him rather shocking.
Deformed? Is that it?
Am I to assume then
that he is ultimately incurable?
Yes, sir.
But you must be aware that this
hospital doesn't accept incurables.
The rules are perfectly clear.
Yes, sir,
I'm well aware of that...
but this case
is quite exceptional.
I quite appreciate your problem,
Mr. Treves.
Why not contact the British Home or
the Royal Hospital for Incurables?
They might find a place for him.
I'll look into it.
Would you like to meet him?
Excuse me.
The Elephant Man.
Sorry.
I should have warned you.
Please forgive me.
- You all right?
- Yes, sir.
Please ask Mrs. Mothershead
to come up here.
Tell her to knock on the door
and wait for me.
I'm sorry about that. L...
We'll bring you another breakfast.
You must be very hungry.
And I think you'll be quite
comfortable here for a while.
I'll see to it that you have
everything you need.
Cor blimey!
So, this is the Elephant Man.
I ain't seen nothing
like you before.
What the bleedin' hell
happened to ya?
Dumb, eh?
I like people
that can keep quiet.
Here, have a drink.
Go on! No?
You should be more sociable, mate.
You'll get yourself disliked.
You and I are
gonna be good friends...
and I've got a lot of friends
who'd like to meet you.
And they will, mate.
Believe me, they will.
I've brought your breakfast.
What are you doing down there?
Come on, up on the bed.
All he understands
is a good smack.
He's had his share of smacks. That's
what drives him under the bed.
You have to treat him
with kindness and patience.
Perhaps you've got time for that
sort of treatment, Mr. Treves.
But I haven't.
I've got a hospital to run.
Now, don't you waste your time
with him, sir.
It's like talking to a brick wall.
Now, I don't mean to be harsh but...
he doesn't belong here.
Honestly, sir, honestly,
what can you do for him?
Oh, and by the way,
Mr. Carr Gomm said...
he would like to see you
when you can spare a moment.
- Yes.
- Right.
I can't help you
unless you help me.
You see, I believe there's something
that you want to say to me.
Something back there.
I can't help you unless
you help me, you know!
I believe you want to say something
to me, don't you?
I've got to understand what you're
feeling, what you're thinking.
Do you understand me?
All right, just nod your head
if you can... Can you understand me?
Just nod your head
if you understand me.
All right.
You do understand.
I want to hear...
I want to hear you talk.
We're gonna show them that
you're not a wall. Understand?
I want you to talk to me.
All right, now,
I want to hear you say it.
I've got to hear how
you say things.
I won't hurt you. I've got to hear
and understand how you say things.
Very slowly,
I want you to say, "Yes."
Say, "Yes."
Yes.
Yes!
Good.
All right, now, just once more
say it again. "Yes."
Yes, I can understand that.
That's good.
That's very good.
All right now.
I'm going to say some words to you,
and I want you to repeat them.
Do you understand?
Say, "Hello.
My name is..."
Hello.
My name is...
"John Merrick."
No. John... That's very good.
Say, "John Merrick."
"Hello. My name is John Merrick."
Hello.
My name is...
John Merrick.
You can speak.
How did you get up here?
I want my man back.
- Just a moment. How did you get up?
- Never mind that. I want my man.
He's still very sick.
Please, come downstairs with me,
and I'll explain the situation.
Don't!
Don't.
You've had plenty of time to...
cure him.
And now he's leaving with me.
Do you understand me now,
Mr. Treves?
We made a deal.
You misunderstood.
This man has suffered a severe fall,
if you take my meaning.
He's my patient now.
Pull the other one,
why don't you?
Mr. Bytes, I'm sorry.
But all you do is profit
from another man's misery.
Do you think
you're better than me?
No, I never said that.
You wanted the freak...
to show to those doctor chums of
yours, to make a name for yourself.
You, my friend.
I gave you the freak on trust...
in the name of science...
and now I want him back!
You do not own this man!
Now stop it!
I want him back!
So you can beat him?
So you can starve him?
A dog in the streets
would fare better with you!
I shall go to the authorities.
Go to the authorities then!
Go to them by all means.
They'll be very interested
to hear your story as well as ours.
Now...
I think we really do understand
one another.
All right.
Singularly unattractive character,
I must say.
Well, Treves, it seems to me I might
as well meet this patient of yours.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Shall we say in a few days then?
Shall we say 2:00
tomorrow afternoon?
Yes. Well, whatever's
most convenient for you, sir.
2:00 then, tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
2:00!
Morning, Mr. Treves.
Early again, I see.
Yes.
With these early habits of yours,
you'd have made a good milkman.
- I'll keep that in mind, Charles.
- Okay, sir. Good morning.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me into paths of...
for His name's sake.
Righteousness. Righteousness.
He leadeth me in the paths
of righteousness...
for His name's sake.
Good. That's very good. Good.
When your visitor comes today, say
it exactly the way you've said it.
So when I introduce him to you,
say the words that you've learned.
If you have trouble with any words,
I'll help you, so don't worry.
I will introduce him to you
and say...
"Please meet Mr. Carr Gomm."
And you will say?
Hello. My name is John Merrick.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Good! Good.
I'll go and get Mr. Carr Gomm.
It is only a physical problem.
He has trouble with certain sounds
because of...
the constrictive deformity
of the mouth, but he can talk.
Talking's one thing, but is he able
to understand what's said to him?
Yes. Oh, yes! Except...
Except he's so anxious to make
a good impression on you...
that he might seem a little nervous.
Come in.
John...
may I introduce you
to Mr. Carr Gomm?
Mr. Carr Gomm,
this is John Merrick.
Hello. My name is John Merrick.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
How are you feeling today?
I feel much better.
Are you comfortable here?
Everybody's been very kind.
How is your bronchitis?
Mr. Merrick likes the food here,
don't you?
Much better than what
I'm used to.
Oh, yes?
Yes. And what was that?
Potatoes.
I understood
that you'd been flogged.
I feel much better now.
That's splendid.
How do you find Mr. Treves?
As a teacher, I mean.
Everybody's been very kind.
How long did you and Mr. Treves
prepare for this interview?
Everybody's been very kind.
Yes, of course, I understand.
Well, it's been a pleasure
meeting you, Mr. Merrick.
Good day to you.
Very good, John.
It was very good.
I'll be back in a moment.
The Lord is my shepherd...
I shall not want.
He maketh me lie down...
It was a brave attempt, but the man
was mouthing words taught by you.
Yes. Well, I'm sorry
to have wasted your time.
He restoreth my soul.
He simply doesn't belong here.
He'd be better off somewhere where
he can be constantly looked after.
I'm sorry things have turned out
this way. Good day to you.
Yea...
though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death...
I fear no evil...
for Thou art with me.
Thy rod and staff, they...
Mr. Carr Gomm!
Yes, what is it?
It's that.
I didn't teach him that part.
Surely goodness and mercy...
will follow me all the days
of my life...
and I'll dwell in the house
of the Lord forever.
How did you know the rest of it?
I didn't teach you the rest of it.
It's very strange.
Tell me, how did you know
the rest of it?
The 23rd Psalm.
I used to read the Bible every day.
I know it very well...
and the Book of Common Prayer.
The 23rd Psalm is very beautiful.
It's my favorite.
Treves, come and see me in my office
when you're through up here.
There's something important
I want to say to you.
Good-bye, Mr. Merrick.
I do hope we shall meet again.
Well, why didn't you tell me
you could read?
I was frightened.
I see.
I was afraid to talk.
Please forgive me.
Can you imagine the kind of life
he must have had?
Yes, I think I can.
I don't believe so.
No one could possibly imagine it.
I don't believe any of us can!
"Terrible though
his appearance is...
so terrible indeed that women
and nervous persons...
fly in horror
from the sight of him...
and that he is debarred from seeking
to earn his livelihood in any way...
yet he is superior in intelligence.
He can read and write,
he's quiet, gentle...
not to say even refined
in his mind."
I should very much like
to meet this gentleman.
Have you seen this?
Listen to this.
Hey up! Hey up!
Now listen.
This is a letter
to the London Times...
from the governor of the hospital.
"There is now in a little room
off one of our attic wards...
a man named John Merrick.
So dreadful a sight
that he is unable...
even to come out by daylight
to the garden.
He is being called
the Elephant Man...
on account of
his terrible deformity.
His appearance is so terrible
that women and nervous persons...
fly in terror
at the sight of him."
And how do you get tickets
to see him?
Your very own Sunny Jim.
- Let's go and see him then!
- All right, keep your shirt on.
The time must be right.
Right now he's in the attic.
But tomorrow they're moving him to
Bedstead Square right into my lap.
Then, for the right price...
you will see something you'll
never ever see again in your life!
Well, don't look so glum, girls.
Enthusiastic volunteers
should be more cheerful, hmm?
Put your collar straight, girl.
And remember...
that under no circumstances...
whatsoever...
are any mirrors to be brought
into this room.
Yes, Mrs. Mothershead.
Yes.
All right.
- He's so ugly.
- Ugly or not, you're gonna help me.
Feeling better now, Mr. Merrick?
Yes.
You look very nice
in your new clothes.
Thank you very much.
If there's nothing else,
I suppose we'll be leaving you now.
No, there's nothing.
You ready for tea?
Please go in, John.
Make yourself comfortable.
Come along, meet our guest.
Mr. Merrick, I'd like you
to meet my wife, Anne.
Anne, this is John Merrick.
I'm very pleased to meet you,
Mr. Merrick.
I'm...
I'm very pleased...
What is it?
What's the matter?
It's just that l...
I'm not used to being...
treated so well by...
a beautiful woman.
Would you like a cup of tea,
Mr. Merrick?
That's a good idea.
Would you like to come and see the
rest of the house? I'll show you.
How's your tea?
It's very good!
I'm enjoying my visit here
very much.
It's so kind of you to invite me
into your own home.
I'm sorry that I...
made a spectacle of myself.
No, not at all.
I like the way...
you arranged your pictures
on the mantelpiece.
Oh, thank you.
Is that the way they do it
in most houses?
Yes, I'm sure they do, yes.
Who are they of?
These are relatives,
and these are our children.
Children?
Oh, may I see?
Yes, of course.
Where are the children?
Well, um, well,
they're out with friends...
at the moment.
Friends.
And here is Frederick's mother.
Oh, how lovely.
And these are my parents.
They have such...
noble faces.
Yes, I've always...
I've always thought so myself.
Would you...
Would you care to see my mother?
Your mother?
Yes, please.
Oh, she's...
Mr. Merrick, she's beautiful.
Oh, she had...
She had the face of an angel.
I must've...
been a great disappointment to her.
No, Mr. Merrick.
No son as loving as you
could ever be a disappointment.
If only I could find her...
so she could see me...
with such lovely friends here now.
Perhaps she could...
Iove me as I am.
I've tried so hard to be good.
I'm so sorry.
Please.
Please. Here.
What's that you're doing?
What is it?
I see.
It's St. Phillips.
Why, that's very good.
I mean, you got the windows
and arches just right.
I wish...
I could sleep...
like normal people.
- Mr. Treves?
- Yes?
There's something that...
I've been meaning to ask you...
for some time now.
What's that?
Can you cure me?
No, we can care for you...
but we can't cure you.
I thought not.
Come in.
- Good morning.
There's someone here who'd like
to meet you, if that's all right.
May I introduce you
to one of the bright lights...
of the English stage,
Mrs. Kendal.
- Mrs. Kendal, Mr. John Merrick.
- Good day, Mr. Merrick.
Good day.
I've brought you some things.
I hope you like them.
I hope you don't
think it too forward.
I knew you'd understand.
I'll leave you together.
Here.
I want you to know, I don't go about
giving my picture to just anyone.
Oh, no.
I wouldn't think of it.
It's beautiful.
You're so...
I'll... Well, I'll...
I shall put it in a...
in a place of honor.
Here, next to my mother.
She's very pretty, your mother.
Oh, yes.
I see you're constructing a...
church?
Oh, no.
It's a cathedral.
You see?
Only, I have to rely...
on my imagination...
for what I can't actually see.
Mr. Treves tells me
that you're in the theater.
Do you live there?
Oh, no, Mr. Merrick.
I just work there.
Well, it must be...
wonderful just to work there.
- Is it beautiful?
- You've never been?
I'm afraid not.
Oh, Mr. Merrick.
You must go.
The theater's the most
beautiful place on earth.
Of course, I am a bit partial.
The theater is romance.
Romance.
Which reminds me,
I've brought you something else.
- Thank you.
- Have you read it?
No, but I certainly shall.
Romeo and Juliet.
Yes, I've heard of this.
"If I profane
with my unworthiest hand...
this holy shrine...
the gentle fine is this...
My lips...
two blushing pilgrims...
ready stand to smooth
that rough touch...
with a tender kiss."
"Good pilgrim,
you do wrong your hand too much...
which mannerly devotion
shows in this.
For saints have hands
that pilgrims' hands do touch...
and palm to palm
is holy Palmer's kiss."
"O, then dear saint...
let lips do what hands do.
They pray, grant thou...
lest faith turn to despair."
"Saints do not move...
though grant for prayer's sake."
"Then move not...
while my prayer's effect I take.
Thus from my lips...
by thine, my sin is purged."
Oh, yes.
And then it says they kiss.
"Then have my lips
the sin that they have took."
"Sin from thy lips?
O trespass sweetly urged.
Give me my sin again."
Oh, Mr. Merrick.
You're not an elephant man at all.
You're Romeo.
"Mrs. Kendal, always at the
forefront of fashion and form...
was seen leaving the London
the other afternoon.
No, dear readers, the most
facile actress of our day...
has not been taken ill, but rather
said she was visiting a friend.
And who was the lucky recipient
of this attention?
Quick inquiries proved it to be
none other than Mr. John Merrick...
the Elephant Man, with whom our
readers are undoubtedly familiar.
After a chat of
three quarters of an hour...
Mrs. Kendal was kind enough
to leave Mr. Merrick...
with an autographed portrait
of herself."
I saw it in his room.
"Owing to a disfigurement
of the most extreme nature...
Mr. Merrick has never been properly
presented to London society.
But knowing that
wherever Mrs. Kendal goes...
others inevitably follow,
the question arises...
'Will London society
present itself to him?"'
This walking stick is so...
is so dashing.
Much more elegant than my old one.
More tea?
You see, I don't go out
as often as I would like...
because naturally...
some people do find
my appearance disturbing.
If you have a chill,
I could close the window.
No, I'm fine.
Please...
I mean, thank you.
Thank you.
You see...
people are frightened...
by what they don't understand.
And it is hard to understand
even for me...
because, well, my mother...
she was so very beautiful.
Mrs. Mothershead, I don't think he
should have any more visitors today.
I have to lecture at the college,
so I'll be back this evening.
Excuse me, but if you have the time,
I would like a word with you.
- I'm awfully late. What is it?
- Well, sir, I don't quite...
I don't quite understand...
why it is you allow
that sort of people in there.
Why? Because he enjoys it,
and I think it's very good for him.
Yes, but sir, you saw
the expression on their faces.
They didn't hide their disgust.
They don't care
anything about John.
They only want
to impress their friends.
I think you're being
rather harsh on them, don't you?
I beg your pardon, sir.
You yourself hardly showed him
much loving kindness...
when he first arrived, did you?
I bathed him, I fed him and
I cleaned up after him, didn't I?
And I see that
my nurses do the same.
And if"loving kindness"
can be called care...
and practical concern...
then I did show him loving kindness
and I am not ashamed to admit it.
I didn't mean it exactly that way.
Now, please believe me.
Now, of course
I appreciate your concern.
I appreciate everything that
you've done for Mr. Merrick.
But I am the physician in charge
and I must do what is best for him.
- Please, now, I'm also very late.
- If you ask my opinion...
he's only being stared at
all over again.
Thank you.
Night time.
What's the matter, Freddie?
I've been thinking about Mr. Bytes.
What on earth
made you think of him?
Well, I'm beginning to believe that
Mr. Bytes and I are very much alike.
That's absurd.
It seems that
I've made Mr. Merrick...
into a curiosity all over again,
doesn't it?
Only this time in a hospital
rather than a carnival.
My name is constantly
in the papers...
I'm always being praised
to the skies.
Patients are now expressly
asking for my services.
Of course they do,
because you're a very fine doctor.
John Merrick is happier
and more fulfilled now...
than he's ever been
in his entire life...
and it's completely due to you.
What was it all for?
Why did I do it?
Freddie, what are you trying to say?
Am I a good man...
or am I a bad man?
Steady on, Treves.
Steady on, my dear fellow.
Come sit down, won't you?
Gentlemen, I know we usually
open these proceedings...
by reading the minutes.
But on this occasion,
in the interests of urgency...
I think we should first conclude...
the matter
previously under discussion...
the case of Mr. John Merrick,
the Elephant Man.
One moment, Mr. Chairman.
As far as I'm concerned...
this creature has no business
being here at all.
l, for one,
am sick and tired...
of this competitive freak-hunting...
by these overly ambitious
young doctors...
trying to make names for themselves.
To parade them about in front of the
pathological society is one thing...
but to waste this committee's
valuable time...
with requests for shelter for these
abominations of nature is another.
You must be more careful.
In the light of these facts,
our course is clear.
The question is not whether to
accept this creature as a patient.
The question is, when will
those rooms be vacated for use...
by better qualified,
more deserving cases?
I move that this Elephant Man...
be removed from
the premises immediately.
We have a sacred duty
to cure the sick...
not care for circus animals.
That is my last word on the subject.
Mr. Chairman, shall we vote?
I take it, Mr. Broadneck, your mind
is quite unshakable in this matter?
Mr. Chairman,
do you not have ears?
I am unalterably opposed!
My mind is made up on this!
You shall not sway me.
May we now vote, Mr. Chairman,
at long last?
Yes, Broadneck.
I think the time has come.
Gentlemen, Her Royal Highness...
Alexandra, Princess of Wales.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I hope I am not disturbing you.
On the contrary, ma'am.
Your presence here...
is always greatly appreciated.
We were just taking a vote
on Mr. Merrick.
Her Royal Highness has shown
the greatest interest in his fate.
Indeed I have, sir,
as has the queen.
I have a brief communication
from Her Majesty...
which she has requested
that I read to you.
"To the Governing Committee,
London Hospital.
I would very much like to commend
you for the charitable face...
you have shown Mr. John Merrick,
the Elephant Man.
It is laudable
that you have provided...
one of England's
most unfortunate sons...
with a safe and tranquil harbor,
a home.
For this immeasurable kindness...
as well as the many
other acts of mercy...
on behalf of the poor...
of which Mr. Carr Gomm
has kept me informed...
I gratefully thank you.
Signed, Victoria."
I'm sure I can count on you
gentlemen to do the Christian thing.
Thank you very much, ma'am.
I'm sure we shall all try.
Gentlemen, I wish to move
that Mr. John Merrick...
be admitted to this hospital
on a permanent basis...
provided the hospital receives
a yearly sum...
equal to the cost of
the occupation of one bed.
All those in favor?
Thank you, gentlemen.
The motion is carried.
Yes. Come in!
Good afternoon.
Mr. Carr Gomm has something
he wants to say to you.
Mr. Merrick,
I have very great pleasure...
in being able
to welcome you officially...
to the London Hospital.
This morning, the governing
committee unanimously voted...
that you should be provided with
these rooms on a permanent basis.
This is your home now.
I'm so very, very glad for you.
Welcome home, lad.
This is...
my home?
Yes.
Please, will you thank
the governing committee for me?
I will do my utmost...
to merit their kindness.
This...
is my home?
Yes. This as well.
Your dressing case.
Oh, thank you.
Thanks, all my friends.
Thank you.
- You like it?
- Oh, my friends.
Oh, my friends.
Oh, thank you.
- Who's next?
- I say.
- What, you again?
- Yeah, but...
But these young ladies
have never seen it.
You're on, mate.
Okay, that's it
for this performance.
- Jim, can I go tonight?
- Sit down, Charlie.
There's always tomorrow.
Don't worry.
Room for one more?
At the right price.
There's room.
All right, all right!
Keep the noise down!
We don't want
to frighten him, do we?
Hello. My name...
is John Merrick...
and I'm very, very pleased...
to meet you.
I think you are...
very beautiful...
Curtain time!
You look beautiful, darling.
I wouldn't change a thing.
You look like
the bleedin' Prince of Wales.
Here, my friends...
is the Elephant Man!
I told you he was horrible.
Just horrible.
Perhaps the ladies
would like a closer look?
- Yeah, yeah.
- No, Jack!
There.
He's quite a ladies' man, isn't he?
Come on. Give the ladies' man
a little kiss, eh?
Come on.
Give him a kiss.
Here, here, here!
That's enough romance.
Time for beddy-byes.
All right, all right.
Keep the noise down.
Now, keep it quiet.
Quiet! Hey!
Keep it quiet.
Now, watch this.
Okay, that's enough!
That's enough!
That's it.
The show's over.
I'll see you back
at the Peacock.
Get out of here.
Here.
Come on.
There you are.
That's better, isn't it?
I've done well tonight.
Here. Buy yourself a sweet.
My treasure.
- I know what happened last night.
- What?
Dear God.
Boy!
Where is he?
Where's Mr. Merrick?
- I don't know what you mean, sir.
- Don't lie to me!
I know all about it.
You were seen.
You're involved with Bytes,
aren't you?
You've taken him.
Where is he?
Now, wait a minute.
I haven't taken him anywhere.
I don't know no Bytes.
We were just having a bit of fun.
We never hurt him.
You know, just having a laugh,
that's all.
You bastard! He's gone!
When I left him,
he was in bed safe and sound!
You bastard!
You're not listening to me!
I told you, I don't know no Bytes!
I ain't done nothing wrong.
People pay money to see
your monster. I collect it.
You're the monster!
You're the freak!
Now, get out!
You're finished!
You don't frighten me,
you and your bleedin' Elephant Man.
I'm glad what I done,
and you can do nothing about it.
Only Mothershead can sack me now!
Done.
There's something
I'd like to tell you, Treves.
You know, I felt as deeply
as you did about John.
Well, now he's disappeared...
very likely to the continent.
There's no question
of your going after him.
You're desperately needed here
by your patients.
You did everything
in your power.
Remember that, Treves.
Everything in your power.
Get the stool.
Get up, you bastard.
Look at all these
beautiful animals.
What a lot you have.
That sly bastard.
He's doing this to spite me!
You're doing this to spite me...
and it's got to stop!
Bytes, he's sick!
Let him die!
But don't think
I'm going to bury that...
bag of flesh!
Wrong!
As a matter of fact...
- Bytes, no!
- As a matter of fact...
Bytes, stop, please!
Bytes, please, don't!
We've decided...
we're gonna get you out of here.
All right?
Good on you, mate.
Good on you.
Luck, my friend.
Luck. And who needs it
more than we?
Hey, mister.
Mister, why is your head so big?
Why is your head so big, mister?
Why is your head so big?
Why won't you answer me?
Why is your head so big, mister?
Stop him!
I am not an animal!
I am a human being!
I am...
a man!
Excuse me, sir.
Out of the way, sir.
Excuse me.
Mr. Treves, sir!
They found him!
I think they found John!
Thank you.
- Keep still, girl.
- Sorry.
That was very nice of Mrs. Kendal
to give me this dress for tonight.
It's so beautiful.
Does Mrs. Kendal know
that John is dying?
Yes, she knows.
How do I look?
Splendid.
Now, you will not look out of place.
You look absolutely splendid.
- Oh, splendid. Shall we go?
- Yes.
Again...
I can't tell you how sorry I am
for what happened.
You see, I had no idea, really.
Please, you mustn't blame yourself.
Mr. Treves, don't worry about me...
my friend.
I am happy every hour of the day.
My life is full
because I know that I am loved.
I have gained myself.
I could not say that...
were it not for you.
Well, and l...
You've done so much for me as well.
Thank you.
So...
I'll fetch Mrs. Mothershead
and Nora...
and be back in a few minutes.
Very good, my friend.
My friend.
Mrs. Kendal.
Thank you.
Your Royal Highness...
ladies and gentlemen...
tonight's performance
was very special to me...
because it was very special
to someone else.
A man who knows the theater
and who loves the theater...
and yet this is the very first time
he's ever been here.
I wish to dedicate...
The whole company wishes to dedicate
with all their hearts...
tonight's performance...
to Mr. John Merrick...
my very dear friend.
Stand up.
They want to see you.
Go on. It's all right.
Just stand up.
They want to see you.
I really did believe that...
the ogre would never
get out of the dungeon.
Good.
So you really enjoyed yourself?
It was wonderful!
Good. Then we must
go again some evening.
Oh, yes.
Oh, I hope so.
Yes, we will.
We will.
Good. I'm pleased.
Well, I ought to go.
You must get some sleep.
Good night, and sleep well.
- And you too, my friend.
- Yes.
I'm so pleased
you enjoyed yourself.
Good night.
It's finished.
Never, oh, never
nothing will die.
The stream flows,
the wind blows.
The cloud fleets,
the heart beats.
Nothing will die.