The summer I was 8 years old,
5 hours disappeared from my life.
5 hours... Lost.
Gone without a trace.
I remember sitting on
the bench at my Little League game.
It started to rain.
But what happened after that
remains a pitch black void.
Brian ?
You dork.
What the heck are you doing in there ?
You're bleeding.
- lt is terrible out there.
- Mom !
Hello, sweetheart.
What happened to you ?
Brian got a bloody nose
hiding in the cellar.
What were you doing down there ?
Are you okay, sweetheart ?
Poor little baby.
They had me all night
in that mailroom.
l didn't even know
it was raining.
Hold still.
Did another mom
give you a ride home ?
- Goodnight.
- l hope you're happy.
l knew he'd get hurt
playing sports.
When l was a kid,
l wasn't a star player either.
But at least l wasn't a quitter.
Sorry, dad.
Goodnight.
l told your father
Little League was a stupid idea.
Hold your nose.
Mom made me
quit baseball the next day.
This was when the nightmares began.
And the nosebleeds.
I wet the bed several times.
And then there were the blackouts.
I'd feel my eyes
roll back in my head.
I'd crumple in the floor
like a dropped puppet.
Darned thing's
not even a year old yet.
Maybe it's screwed up
from all the lightning last week.
Your father will be overjoyed.
- What time's Dad getting home ?
- Not for another hour.
Mom. Deborah.
Come look.
lt's a UFO.
lt's just a weather balloon.
Look what it's doing to the TV.
lt's flying over the house.
Let's go up on the roof.
No, wait !
Children, be careful !
That summer,
those were
the two things I'd never forget.
The cramped,
stale darkness of the crawlspace.
And, equal in power and mystery...
..that UFO,
out there somewhere...
..traveling across the universe.
The summer I was 8 years old,
I came for the first time.
I was watching my Mom going at it
with her current boyfriend,
Alfred, in my old swing set.
Alfred was all Marlboro man,
dumb as a fucking rock,
what I would years later,
come to call my type.
Only stupid things
ever came out of his mouth.
But seeing him like this,
whimpering,
crying like a helpless animal...
I couldn't take my eyes off of him.
I'd been masturbating for years.
But it was that summer that
jizz first squirted out of my dick.
Couldn't wait to show Coach.
I should start at the beginning.
My Mom signed me up
for Little League.
It was Alfred's idea, so they
could fuck without paying a sitter.
Are you excited ?
Coach Heider ?
Desire sledge-hammered me.
He looked like the lifeguards,
cowboys and firemen
I'd seen in the ''Playgirls''
my mom kept under her bed.
I didn't know
what to do with my feelings.
They were like a gift
I had to open in front of a crowd.
- Hello.
- Hello, l'm Ellen McCormick.
And this is my son, Neil.
Hello, Neil.
Honey, won't you
say hello to your coach ?
Don't worry, it takes him a while
to warm up to strangers.
I quickly became team star player.
Which wasn't saying much considering
the other kids were all spazzes.
Our first game, I whacked
a triple with bases loaded.
The crowd went fucking nuts.
But I didn't care about that.
All that mattered was
it made Coach proud.
After that first victory,
Coach called my Mom to tell her
he was taking the team to a movie.
Hey, big guy. Ready to go ?
Where's everybody else ?
lt's just you and me today.
- Really ?
- Yup.
Cool.
I picked ''Blood Prom'' , an R-rated
flick with cool gore and murders.
When this annoying blonde chick
got her head chopped off, I cheered.
Then we picked up a pizza
and headed back to Coach's.
Coach's house was awesome.
He had a giant TV, an Atari with
Donkey Kong, Asteroids, Frogger.
All my favorite games.
You exploded. My turn.
- Sure your mom's not expecting you ?
- No, she works.
She's probably got
a date with Alfred afterwards.
- You spend a lot of time alone.
- Yes, but l kind of like it.
l just ride my bike and watch TV.
lt's cool.
Shit ! You made me mess up !
Sorry !
Hold on.
Come here for a sec.
Bring one of those bottles.
This might seem
a little weird at first.
But l need to record
my team's voices,
especially my best players.
Okay ? Take this.
Now just speak into it
using your normal voice.
What should l say ?
Whatever you like.
Start with your name.
Now take a big sip of pop and belch.
- Shit.
- Good.
- Say that again.
- Shit.
Again.
Shit. Hell ! Damn !
Now, look up into the camera.
Now stick your tongue out.
Make a funny face.
Good.
Open your mouth wide.
Neil, that's perfect.
July second.
We had a 7:30 game
against Taco Hut.
l know you'll kick
their butts tonight.
Do it for
your poor hard-working mom.
- Getting a ride home with Coach ?
- Yeah.
You're mine and l love you
and don't you ever forget it.
Boy, were you on fire tonight !
lt's the best you've ever played !
Thanks, Coach.
Can we play more games tonight ?
Sure, but let me
show you something first.
l look stupid in this one.
No. You look perfect.
Your expression.
Like you're having a wonderful dream.
Neil, l've been thinking
a lot about you this week.
l'm hungry.
Sure.
You want a pizza ?
l might have something you'd like.
- What'll it be, little buddy ?
- My mom never buys these things.
- She says they're a waste of money.
- Let's eat then.
Which one do you want ?
- What are you having ?
- Corn pops.
Then l'll have...
Cocoa Krispies.
Shit.
Sorry.
Here we go.
l like you, Neil.
l like you so much.
When l really,
really like someone...
..there's a way l show them
how l feel.
Angel.
There's nothing wrong
with kissing someone like this.
Don't ever let anyone
tell you that it's wrong.
It happened.
That's what I told myself.
It just happened.
And after it was over, I looked
down at the mess on the floor.
It was like a kaleidoscope
had shattered.
And when I swallowed, the taste
of Coach's tongue seared my mouth.
You liked it.
lt's okay that you liked it.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Do you know him or something ?
I met Wendy when I was 1 0 and
she was 1 1 and a grade ahead.
What are you doing ?
- Damn. No razor.
- You're insane.
If I wasn't queer,
we would have had sloppy teenage sex
and contributing more fucked-up,
unwanted kids to society.
But instead,
she became my soul mate.
One true partner in crime.
Let's kidnap him.
His mom says
we're supposed to take him home.
- Where are you taking me ?
- A house with lots of candy.
Goody.
Beware !
These are the eyes
of the Axe Murderer's victims.
- Come on, Satan.
- Hurry up, chicken.
Never much cared for Halloween,
but this particular year...
...I couldn't shake the feeling
something horrible was gonna happen.
And there was nothing
I could do to stop it.
Wait outside for me.
l'll be done in a minute.
You hold him
while l get something.
- What are we doing ?
- Having fun.
- What's the matter, ''Satan'' ?
- What did you say, punk ?
Loser !
Brian ?
I thought that was you.
Lie down.
Lie down, retard.
- What are you doing ?
- Shut up !
Shut up, or we'll kill you.
Point the beam over here.
Open your mouth.
l said open your mouth.
Keep these in your fucking mouth.
Do what we say or l'll kill you.
l swear.
Give me the matches.
Give me the damned matches.
Shine the flashlight on him.
Neil, he's going to tattle !
Don't worry. There are things
we can do to get him on our side.
That's it.
Just lay still for a minute.
You're my little green buddy
and there's this cool thing
to show you.
When l was little,
a man used to do this to me.
You're really gonna like it.
There. That's it. That's my boy.
Wendy never looked at me
quite the same after that night.
Sharing this part of myself
I'd never shown anyone else...
I knew we'd be bound together.
Forever.
I woke up not knowing where I was
or what had happened to me.
Deborah said
I'd been missing for over an hour.
But I couldn't remember a thing.
But I knew it was
linked to the other time,
when I woke up in the cellar.
And I also knew
no matter how long it took...
..I had to find out what happened.
I had to find
an answer to the mystery.
When I was 1 5, I overheard kids
at school talking about a place.
A place you could find even in
a hicktown like Hutchinson.
Bingo...
Here we go.
How's it going ?
Okay.
l'm Charlie.
Wanna go for a ride ?
Sure.
You got cash ?
l'll pay 50, no higher.
You've got to be careful out here.
The cops patrol this whole area
and they know what's up.
l'm in Hutchinson on business.
l supply snack foods
to the local markets.
Go ahead.
Take whatever you want.
Hungry ?
We've only got an hour,
so we'd better get busy.
Wait.
Let me.
Beautiful.
So, what do you like to do ?
Tell me what you want me to do.
Whatever.
You like older guys ? Tell me.
Yeah.
That feels nice.
You are such a beautiful...
..beautiful boy.
l'm gonna come.
l know what you're thinking.
That wasn't safe.
But we're in Kansas, thank God,
not some big city
full of diseases.
Plus, you're only a kid.
Maniac. You scared me !
Thanks for meeting me.
This better be good.
My mom'll kill me if she finds out.
l have something l wanna show you.
FRlDAYS & SATURDAYS 3 TO 4
YOUNG AND WlLLlNG
Yeah. So ?
That's me.
You're such a liar.
l don't believe you.
- l'll prove it.
- Okay. How ?
Oh, my God, what're you...
Put that back in your pants,
exhibitionist.
- Look.
- No way, pervert.
Look what the guy did to me.
Are those bruises ?
Fucker gnawed on my dick
like it was a candy cane !
Didn't know he hurt me
till l blew my load.
Well, you better watch out.
Next time someone
might chomp the whole thing off.
Seriously.
Even Hutchinson has freaks.
You could end up dead.
Okay, ''Mom''.
l wish there was
a movie showing right now.
Me too.
A film about our lives.
Everything that's happened so far.
And the last scene
would just be us standing right here.
Just you and me.
Yeah.
l hear something.
lt's the voice of God.
l hear him.
Mom !
- lt's about to begin.
- Alright, l'm coming.
- VCR on ?
- l checked it twice.
lt's probably going to be silly.
The commercial showed
an old man...
..claiming aliens beamed him up
right out of his bathtub.
lf you're going to make fun,
l'll just watch it by myself.
lt's starting.
Tonight on ''World Of Mystery'',
..we investigate
the terrifying world of UFOs.
Is it mass hysteria
or something all too real ?
They kept me prisoner for hours.
They examined me like
I was a frog in biology class.
And then they stuck a probe
in my stomach.
I still got the scar here
to prove it.
Look at that.
I always got scared anytime
I watched movies about UFOs.
Even ''E. T. '' scared me.
Poor thing.
She looks so homely and sad.
Avalyn Friesen lives in
the ordinary town of Inman, Kansas.
lnman ? That's only 30 miles away.
32 years old, she is unmarried.
Lives with her father
and works as a secretary.
But there is something
unusual about Avalyn.
For as long as she can remember,
things have happened to her,
things she cannot explain.
I'd heard about people
who've experienced missing time.
Whole chunks of their lives
they couldn't account for.
Under hypnotic regression,
I learned I'd been abducted
more than 20 times.
- Oh, please !
- Quiet.
The first time I was 6.
I was on my way home from
a picnic with my grandparents.
It was dark and we got lost,
driving down a dirt road.
Grandpa lost control
and we went into a ditch.
There was this blinding white light.
But the aliens weren't interested
in my grandparents.
They floated me up out of the car
using a gravitational ray.
That's it. l've had enough.
l'm gonna get some ice cream.
Want some ?
No, thanks.
I remember lying on a table.
It was cold,
smooth and shiny.
The aliens surrounded me.
They were bald.
With marshmallowy heads
and tiny arms.
But the worst part was their eyes.
The only way I can describe them
is big, black diamonds,
all liquidy and jelly-ish.
l'm finally getting out
of this fucking nowhere town !
You better let me know
the second you're settled.
Or else.
You better come. Or else.
New York City. You're so lucky !
Hey, assface.
What're you gawking at ?
Faggots !
Shit, go, go, go !
Fuck you !
Remember the guy l told you ?
White Camaro ?
That's him. Parked by those trees.
l've fucked every john in this park.
Except for White Camaro.
So it's time for you two
to get lost.
Stop scaring my business away.
You want us
to pick you up later ?
lf you want.
l'll be done by 7.
We'll meet you.
l gotta get home
and start packing.
Alright. Call me tonight.
See you later.
- You'd better be careful.
- Of what ?
l'm serious,
you're not in Modesto anymore.
l see the way you look at him.
He's so beautiful.
l can't help it.
He's like a god.
You don't have to tell me,
l was infatuated with him too once.
But l know all Neil's secrets and
there's shit you don't want to know.
Once l'm gone, you'll be all Neil has
and you have to understand one thing.
Where normal people have a heart,
Neil McCormick's has
a bottomless black hole.
And if you don't watch out,
you can fall in and get lost forever.
- Brian, you home ?
- Yeah, Mom. ln here.
No class today ?
l've got English Comp
discussion group at 7:30.
You have mail.
Looks like one from your sister.
And one from A. Friesen ?
l can't believe she wrote me back.
- Who ?
- Avalyn Friesen. The woman on TV.
She didn't have to dump
a whole gallon of perfume on it.
What did she say ?
She wants me
to visit her in lnman.
Thanks for the ride, Preston.
Later.
You just missed it, sweetie.
This little old lady
just won both showcases.
- What did she get ?
- She got a trip to Scotland...
A beautiful living room set.
A brand new car.
l can't remember the name of it
but it cost over 27 grand.
Are you wearing cologne ?
ls work okay ?
lt's the pits.
When is our ship
gonna come in, baby ?
Soon, Ma.
Soon.
Oh, Neil, don't forget.
Tomorrow's my date.
That hot ltalian.
The guy who always
comes through my checkout lane.
l'll be at work.
The last tournament of the season.
Vincenzo.
Patches ! Patches, down.
Sorry, she gets a little excited.
Hi, you must be Brian.
l'm Avalyn, obviously.
Dad ? lt's okay, Daddy.
lt's that young man
l was telling you about.
Don't mind him.
He's just a little wary of strangers.
l'm so glad you're here. Come on.
lt isn't showy, but it's home.
Here, have a seat.
l was in the middle of lunch.
l hope you don't mind.
No, go ahead. l ate earlier.
So, you saw the show ?
Several times,
l videotaped it.
They left some stuff out, but
they got the major points across.
l think l was taken too.
You mentioned that in your letter.
You're where l was a few years ago,
just starting to remember.
There are many of us and
we need to know what happened.
So you think
that's what happened to me.
Considering
about the missing time and...
l'm sure of it.
Feel like going on a walk ?
What's that you're carrying ?
lt's a Dream Journal.
l keep a log of all my dreams.
Whatever bits and pieces
l can recall at least.
l feel like
it's slowly helping me remember.
That's a really good idea.
Your subconscious is where
all your memories are buried.
For you and me
and people like us
almost every single thing we do
stems from our being abducted.
l want to show you something
they wouldn't allow on TV.
l've been tagged.
Part of their experiments.
Touch it.
When l was taken,
my leg was bleeding,
but l didn't remember being cut.
Under hypnosis l discovered
that's where
they implanted the tracking device.
Now everything l do, they know.
ln fact, l wouldn't be surprised
if they were spying on us right now.
When l was found that night,
my nose was bleeding.
The old up-the-nose trick,
so the scar can't be seen.
Don't forget to write.
Don't you forget what l told you.
You better come see me soon, asshole.
l will.
Stay out of trouble, you two.
Bye.
l can't believe it's so late.
My mom's gonna worry.
You still live with your mom ?
My dad moved out 7 years ago.
- l don't see him much.
- Read me one of your dreams.
l just scribble
them out in the middle of the night.
- Sometimes l can barely read them.
- That's okay.
This is from 2 nights ago.
''There's a blue light.
l'm in my Little League uniform
and a tall alien
is hovering over me.
Someone else is with me.
Another boy.
Also in uniform.
A Panther ?''
That was the name
of my baseball team.
Let's see...
''The alien has big black eyes.
He's touching my face.
l want to cry out for help, but...
..l can't.''
You're on your way
to uncovering the truth.
Think of yourself as a detective.
Concentrate on the other boy
in your dreams,
he could help you find
the answers you're looking for.
Two outs.
Third baseman Jackson up
with Hinton on deck.
Jesus. Check out that Jackson.
Hubba hubba.
Are you joking ?
l'd fuck him for free.
Please return all foul balls
to press box, thank you.
You don't think Jackson's hot ?
Dude, he's fat and bald !
Different folks,
different strokes.
My Daddy hit this.
Well, come here. Collect your prize.
Thank you so much.
One second.
What will it be, big guy ?
Cash or bubbles ?
You can't decide.
Alright, come on, hold out your hand.
- Thanks !
- You're welcome.
See you later.
What ? When kids do good,
you gotta reward them.
Christ, it's Hinton,
a.k.a. Ass of the Gods.
l am so fucking wasted !
Oh, shit !
Where's your mom ?
She's probably out with
her new boyfriend, Vincenzo.
l've got a wicked headache.
- Do you have any pot ?
- Yeah. Come on.
Here.
Knock yourself out.
There's a porno in the VCR
if you wanna jack off.
Thanks.
You got a lighter ?
Yeah. Here.
- You like that ?
- It tickles a little.
That feels good, doesn't it, Neil ?
Should we put the blanket
over our heads like last time ?
Here we go.
Find what you were looking for ?
- Yeah. Thanks a lot.
- Glad l could help out.
l used to write for
my school paper too.
This will really make
a big difference to my article.
- Maybe you'll win a Pulitzer Prize.
- Maybe.
Just let me know if
there's anything else you need.
Thanks so much.
You done already ?
l'm on kind of a tight deadline.
Well, good luck.
That's two outs.
Garfield the batter, Heim on deck.
Scoot your chair back
a little further.
That's better.
Wait. Hold on a sec.
The score is
Hutchinson First National Bank, 3...
Wichita Coleman Industries, 0.
Okay. Go on.
- Where have you been ?
- Sorry.
l should've called.
l didn't realize the time.
- Well, your dinner's cold as ice.
- That's okay.
Brian, what's going on ?
You've been acting so strangely.
- Disappearing for hours.
- lt's just school, Mom.
- College is different.
- Did you ever call your father back ?
l've been busy.
l'll get it.
You finish your dinner.
He's eating his supper right now.
- Who is it ?
- lt's that UFO woman.
l'll get it in the hall.
Got it.
l was just going to call you.
l found a photo of the boy.
The one from my dreams.
That's amazing.
What are you doing right now ?
Nothing.
l need to show you something.
Can you come out here ?
Sure.
- Hi, honey. How was work ?
- Fuck you.
l'm so fucking sick of this stinking
little buttcrack of a town !
Patches, shhh, quiet !
You'll wake Daddy.
- Thanks for coming.
- No problem.
l stole this from
the Chamber of Commerce.
That's him.
The boy from my dreams.
Look at his face.
You can tell he knows something.
What are you doing ?
Start looking for him tomorrow.
Maybe he still lives in Hutchinson.
l have to show you something
only you would understand.
l've fucked every single guy and
his ugly uncle in this podunk town.
Twice.
You want one ?
One of us has to drive.
l got a postcard from Wendy.
l think she's mad at me
because l owe her 3 letters.
Yeah, her last P.S. is
''Tell Fuckface to write me.''
So you wanna hear what she says ?
''Hey ass. So New York is insane
and crazy in the best possible way.''
Pardon me.
Can we help you ?
l was wondering if
l might buy you boys a drink.
Fuck off.
You heard me, fag. Fuck... off.
Stuck-up little pricks.
Harsh.
Wasn't he kinda your type ?
No, l hate when they look like Tarzan
and sound like Jane.
Let's get out of this shithole.
But we just got here ?
Patches, get away from there !
Farmers have been finding mutilated
cattle around here for years.
l told ''World of Mystery'',
but they conveniently edited it out.
Dad says it's ''Satan worshipers''
going around chopping up cows.
Come here. Let me see your hand.
Feel that ?
Sex organs. They're gone.
The aliens experiment on cows because
the poor things are so defenseless.
Us, on the other hand,
they can't kill us.
They just leave behind
hidden memories.
Which in a way is almost worse.
Notice anything else strange ?
There's no blood.
They took that, too.
Here we go.
Oh, my God. Brian !
Tell him you like it.
Are you okay ?
Oh, God.
Neil. What are you doing ?
Come on. lt's 2:30 in the morning.
You called me your fucking...
..angel.
Wendy's going to meet you
at the station ?
l don't want you getting lost
in that crazy city.
- You don't have to worry, okay ?
- Call me the minute you arrive.
Promise me, Neil.
We should've at least gotten you
a decent hair cut.
l gotta take a piss.
We'll be right back.
- What's the matter ?
- l don't know.
My fucking dick itches
like motherfucking fuck !
What do you want me
to do about it ?
Just look down there.
Preston, come on,
help me out here.
What's wrong with me ?
Dude. You've got crabs.
l mean, it's no big, man.
You just go to the drug store
and get this stuff called ''Rid''.
You'd better be playing safe.
l stay in control.
Honey, your bus is boarding.
Alright.
My baby.
You're all grown up.
You'll be careful ?
Yeah, l will.
You're mine and l love you.
Don't you ever forget it.
Come on. l'll buy you Dairy Queen.
So what now that Neil's gone ?
- l'll kill myself.
- Eric, that is not funny.
Well, l start
Community College next week.
Really ? That's so wonderful.
Pathetic is more like it.
You can always come over
even without Neil around.
Thanks, Mrs. M.
l may just take you up on that.
You better.
Who the hell is that ?
lncognito Boy Scout ?
Can l help you ?
- ls this your house ?
- Yes.
Sorry to bother you, l got
your address out of the phonebook.
l've been checking every McCormick in
Hutchinson and you're the last one.
Anyway, l don't mean to babble...
What do you want ?
- l'm looking for an N. McCormick.
- Are you FBl ?
Sorry honey,
you are shit outta luck.
You mean there's
no N. McCormick living here ?
l mean we just put him on
a bus headed for New York City.
l'm Neil's friend, Eric,
and this is his Mom.
His name is Neil.
Yeah.
l'm Brian.
Brian Lackey.
So you still haven't written.
Big surprise.
But Wendy says you're doing okay,
which is cool.
I've been wanting to tell you about
this strange guy I met 3 weeks ago.
No, we're not fucking.
Get your mind out of the gutter.
He's not even gay, I don't think.
In fact, his vibe
is kind of weirdly asexual.
His name is Brian Lackey.
He lives in Little River
and, like yours truly,
attends Loser Community College.
Anyway, the day you left,
your mom and I found him
on your doorstep, looking for you.
He says you played Little League
together 1 0 years ago.
He was the worst player
on the team,
He's full of questions about you.
But I haven't told him much,
i.e. about your ''line of work''.
I did say you were queer like me,
I figured you wouldn't care.
But now,
are you ready for the good part ?
He thinks that when you were little,
you were both abducted by aliens.
How brilliant is that ?
But he was completely serious.
You should've seen
the look in his eyes.
So, what's the story, dude ?
Were you abducted by a UFO or what ?
P.S. Are your crabs gone yet ?''
Yeah ?
- You have a visitor.
- Hi Brian.
l was in the neighborhood
and l thought l'd stop by.
l'll be in the front room
if you need me.
Thanks, Mom.
Didn't care for that film.
That, l didn't see.
Your Mom doesn't like me very much.
She thinks
l'm trying to steal you away.
Any luck in your search
for ''N. McCormick'' ?
l met his mom and his best friend,
but he's in New York right now.
New York. Really ?
Here. Sit down.
Had any more of those dreams ?
Yeah.
But they seem to be slowly evolving.
And maybe it's just because
l've been spending time with Eric,
Neil's friend.
But it's becoming
clearer and clearer that he...
..Neil that is,
is a key figure in all this.
Like he was there with me
the night it all happened.
l can't. Don't.
No. l can't.
- l can't.
- lt's okay.
- No. No. Don't.
- lt'll feel good.
Don't !
- l'm sorry.
- You better go.
- Please.
- l'm sorry, Brian.
l pay 1 20. Not a cent more.
Okay.
Shall we ?
Fuck me !
Fuck me up the ass
with your hot, teenaged cock !
Wait !
What the fuck are you doing ?
Okay. Whatever.
l'll put it on for you.
There.
Well, come on, stud.
We're on the clock here.
We're not in Kansas anymore, Neil.
You have got to be so careful.
- l know.
- Don't ''l know'' me, Neil McCormick.
This is New York City.
You do the wrong thing with
the wrong person and you die.
Period. End of story.
Just promise me you'll be safe.
Here.
Are these the only kinds
of movies you watch ?
Why ? You don't like it ?
No, it's cool.
So, has Neil gotten back
to you yet ?
Let me explain
The Universe of Neil McCormick.
He's like a planet, Saturn, say.
And we're all like
little moons orbiting around.
Now, do planets write letters ?
But l do know he'll be
in Hutchinson for Christmas.
His mom told me
she sent him a ticket to fly home.
So l'll introduce you then.
- Yeah ?
- How about a study break ?
Thanks, Mrs. Lackey.
Thanks, Mom.
lt's 1 1 :30.
lf it's Avalyn...
tell her l'm not here.
No, l'm sorry, Avalyn,
he's out with his friends.
No problem.
- l thought you kinda liked her.
- l just... l don't know.
l think l just need
a little space from her right now.
l always thought
she was a freak anyway.
l'm off to bed.
Good night, boys.
l'm Zeke.
From L.A.
What are you doing
in New York City ?
That's a Vermeer.
Well, it's sort of a Vermeer.
You are exquisite.
l guess it's my turn, huh ?
Hope...
these don't frighten you too much.
They have a habit of popping up
in the most inopportune places.
l know. Don't be worried.
This is gonna be the safest encounter
you've ever had.
lf you could just rub my back.
Really, l need to be touched.
Make me happy.
Make me happy...
You were 1 00 percent safe, right ?
Yeah. l told you
l just jerked off,
he watched from across the room.
lt was the first time in my life
l'm bothered by it.
Maybe you should try and find
another safer way to make money.
Like everyone else.
Yeah, maybe.
You are the only one
l've ever told.
l know.
l never told Eric, or told my Mom.
l know some people might think
it's fucked up, or terrible.
But what happened that summer
is a huge part of me.
No one ever made me feel that way,
before or since.
Like l...
l was special.
Neil, you were 8 years old.
Yeah, but he really loved me.
l mean, there were
other kids sometimes, but...
l was his prize.
l was his one true love.
Happy birthday.
You didn't have
to get me anything.
lt's just a little something
l picked out.
Cool.
l thought it'd go great
with your hair color.
lt's so cool. Thanks.
You alright ?
l'm drunk.
l've never been drunk in my life.
l'm corrupting you.
At last !
That's pretty good.
Yeah, sure.
No, really.
You have definite artistic talent,
my boy.
That's an interesting touch.
What's the ''deep meaning''
behind the baseball cleats ?
l have no idea.
- How was work ?
- Fucking boring.
- You need a hand ?
- Sure.
l've got news for you.
- Well, me too.
- Okay. You first.
Look what my Mom sent me today.
She wants me
to come home for Christmas.
Your mom is the coolest.
- Mine would never do that for me.
- That's weird.
l hate Hutchinson
more than anything.
But l'm kind of looking forward
to going back, just for a short visit.
- Plus you get to see Eric.
- Yeah.
So what's your news ?
l think l found you a job.
What ?
l was talking to this friend
at work about you.
lt's only minimum wage
at a stupid sandwich place, but...
- But ?
- You're not into it, it's cool.
No, tell me more about it.
- Really ?
- l want to hear more about it.
- You do ?
- Yeah.
You sure you're gonna be okay ?
l'm just glad
my Mom's working late.
Thanks for everything.
This has been
the best birthday ever.
You're welcome.
Shit.
Who's that ?
lt's my Dad.
Dad ?
Son.
l caught you.
Your Mother said she didn't know
whether you'd be home or not.
Happy Birthday.
What are you doing here ?
l'm not allowed to wish
my son a happy birthday ?
Dad, l haven't seen you for what,
2 years ?
Well, maybe if you called back...
Maybe l don't want to call back.
Maybe l just want you
to leave me alone.
Brian, don't be like this.
l drove all this way.
Just to see how you're doing.
Well, let me tell you
what l want to know.
Something happened to me
when l was little.
Do you know what
l'm talking about ?
When l woke up bleeding
in the cellar ?
Where were you that night ?
God, l can tell
you don't even remember !
- You're drunk.
- Quit avoiding the subject !
l was bleeding,
l kept passing out.
l wet my fucking bed
and you never asked why !
And what about that Halloween ?
Something happened to me
both those nights !
What do you know about it ?
Tell me !
l'm sorry, Brian. l...
l can't help you.
May l help you ?
- Redecorating ?
- Sort of.
- How have you been ?
- Good.
- How's Berkeley ?
- Hold on, you two.
Let's continue this
in the front room
over the peanut-butter peach pie
l baked.
- Good to see you, little brother.
- You too.
Need a lift ?
Sure.
- Where we going ?
- My place.
Don't worry, l'll pay.
- lt's Christmas Eve tomorrow.
- No more talking.
- Where are we ?
- Brighton Beach.
Bedroom's this way.
Do it.
Again.
Strip.
Open wide and suck it, slut.
What are you waiting for, slut ?
Suck it !
You like that, don't you, slut ?
Take it deep.
Moan for me.
Slut knows what's coming next.
- l'm giving slut what he wants...
- There're some things l don't do.
Wait. l gotta take a piss.
l'll be right back.
You're getting fucked, slut,
whether you like it or not.
Slut !
Are you ready ? Here it comes.
Mom.
Today is the day.
- Now where are you off to ?
- l'm going out with Eric.
You don't want to stay
and talk with your sister a while ?
- l'll be back soon.
- Don't be late, young man.
Christmas Eve dinner's at 6 sharp.
Here we are.
- Do l look okay ?
- Okay's a relative term.
l'm kidding.
You look fine.
- Excited ?
- Yes.
And nervous.
Don't worry.
l'm sure you guys will hit it off.
l hope you're right.
- Oh, hi, Eric.
- Mrs. M., Merry Christmas.
- You remember Brian.
- Of course l do.
- Hi, Brian.
- Merry Christmas.
- So where's the Man of the Hour ?
- l was going to call you.
- What happened ?
- There's been an accident.
Neil got mugged
on the way to the airport.
ls he okay ?
He's going to be fine.
He's asleep in his room.
- Maybe we should come back tomorrow.
- Maybe.
Or you stay if you'd like,
have some cookies and see if he's...
Honey, you're up.
The fuck
are you staring at, Preston ?
Brian says you both
were in Little League together.
So how long has it been
since you two last saw each other ?
1 0 years...
..5 months and 7 days.
You must have
a lot of catching up to do.
Turn right off Main
by the fairgrounds.
- So what the fuck happened ?
- Long story. l'll tell you later.
Just drive for now.
lt's nice to see New York
hasn't hardened you one bit...
So you're the legendary Brian.
- We have a lot in common, don't we ?
- l think so.
Make a left at the next stop sign.
ls this starting to look familiar ?
Pick us up in a half hour.
You ready ?
Blue.
No one's home.
Let's go round back.
We have to get in.
l know a way here.
Voil.
You were the best player
on the team, weren't you ?
That's what he always told me.
Help.
This was his bedroom.
At least
the ceiling's still the same.
l used to get lost for hours
staring at all the patterns.
Whirls, speckly sparkly things.
Come on.
What's up with these people ?
He used to keep
these things stocked.
This is it, right ?
Why now ?
Why did you search me out ?
l'm tired of it.
l want to dream about
something else for a change.
''Away in a Manger''...
lt took till l actually laid eyes
on you today to remember you.
When Eric wrote me, l only got
the vaguest picture in my head.
Like a staticky TV.
Same here.
But seeing you here...
..in this room...
l feel like
he's watching us right now.
l have no idea
what happened to him.
After that summer,
he just disappeared.
l don't know
if he's even alive or what.
Maybe it's his ghost watching us.
Tell me everything you can.
l was his favorite.
Out of everyone, he picked me.
l know it sounds
kind of weird, but...
..when it first started happening...
l felt honored.
Go on.
This is where the big TV was,
all the cool video games.
That's the kitchen.
The first time happened there...
lt lasted that whole summer.
Just me and him.
l saw him one other time.
On Halloween,
a couple years later.
l was lost.
He said my name.
Brian ?
I thought that was you.
The game had just started.
l was sitting on the bench
as always.
lt started to rain...
Sprinkles at first, then a downpour.
The ump called the game.
And no one came to pick you up.
My Mom was working and my Dad,
who knows.
Everyone else drove off
with their parents.
l was left there all alone.
Then you were in the dugout
with me and you said...
We'll take you home.
And we got in Coach's
station wagon, remember ?
He brought us here.
It's alright, Brian.
We're going to have a little fun.
And he didn't want you in the bedroom
because that was just for us.
So it all happened here,
in this room.
Keep going.
Don't stop until
you've told me everything.
When there was another boy,
it was always the same.
The Coach used me as a prop
to pull you in.
He'd undress me and
and l had to make it seem fun.
Like it was a really cool game.
Go ahead, show him, Neil.
Alright, here are the rules.
I kiss you, then you kiss me back.
And then it's his turn.
Are you ready ?
Here we go.
My God...
You want me to stop ?
So l put my tongue
in your mouth,
getting it all wet and shiny.
Then it was his turn.
Watching his big lips
sucking your face,
l remember thinking
he's going to swallow his head whole.
So, we took off your clothes
and you made
this whimpering puppy sound
that Coach always loved.
Coach and me had this thing
where he would wrap
his mouth around my dick and balls.
He did that to me
and l tried to do it to you
but couldn't
because my mouth was too small.
Then, he went down on you
for what seemed like
a really long time.
Now your eyes
were closed mostly
but every now and then
they would flutter open,
and had this glassy,
faraway look.
And then...
l leaned in and whispered...
It's fun right ?
Tell him you like it.
We're almost finished.
Can you be able...?
Yeah.
Then we played the 5 dollar game.
When Coach would ask me
to do things, crazy sex things.
And if l could do them,
he'd give me a 5 dollar bill.
It's okay. Go ahead, Neil.
He made us fist him.
Do you know what that is ?
l went first, of course.
And on that night,
the 5 dollars was mine
if l could ram my fist up his ass
all the way to the elbow.
And goddamn it, l did it.
l'll never forget how it felt.
lt felt like his body
was trying to suck me into it.
Devour me.
And then l did it too.
And then
we drove you back to Little River
and left you in your driveway.
The End.
And my nose was bleeding.
How did that happen ?
When it was over and
we were getting you dressed,
your face looked like
you'd been erased.
And you were just empty inside.
And you just fell.
Face first on the floor.
And when we pulled you up,
your nose was bleeding.
Like this ?
Stop.
- No one's even home.
- No, someone's there.
- l can see them.
- Where ?
- l don't see anything.
- Now l see them too.
What's going on ?
l think someone's in there.
And as we sat there
listening to the carolers,
I wanted to tell Brian it was over
and everything would be okay.
But that was a lie.
Plus I couldn't speak anyway.
I wished there's some way for us
to go back and undo the past.
But there wasn't.
There was nothing we could do.
So I just stayed silent and tried
to telepathically communicate
how sorry I was
about what had happened.
I thought of all the sadness
and suffering in the world.
And made me want to escape.
I wished with all my heart we
could just leave this world behind.
Rise like two angels
in the night and magically...
..disappear.
Subtitles:
Laser S. Film s.r.l. - Rome