{\ Fs50 \ fad (1000,1500) \ c & # 008008 & \ 3c & FFE87C & \ 4c & GREEN & \ fnArabic Typesetting \ fs40} translation
{\ fs50 \ fad (1000,1500) \ c & H000000 & \ 3c & H00FFFF & \ 4c & H0060ff & \ fnArabic Typesetting \ fs40} Islam Geez! Wei
:: correct spelling ::
:: Video Said WhatsApp 7 6 9 849 245 0 Taif ::
"Advertising material"
What happens in this city?
Smoking ashes of cigarettes here and there
"advertising material"
"Advertising material"
Why I shall silence?
"No Smoking"
Why do you claim cigarette smoke
applied on your breath?
It became unbearable
Let's put an end to this bad habit
"No Smoking"
Let's put an end to this bad
habit
Smoking is prohibited in public places
"No Smoking"
Otherwise offered yourself to fine
"Smoking is not allowed here."
Smoking violation of the law and only offered yourself to fine
Smoking illegality
Do not smoke
"smoking is not allowed here."
Smoking illegality
Do not smoke
Do not let someone else smokes
Smoking will cost you your life
"Advertising material"
Who does not want to be happy?
But, what the price of this happiness?
Smoking will cost you your life
Smoking harms your health
The health of both love
Smoking will cost you your life
use any type of tape recorders Hall cinema to try to copy the content
offense punishable by law under the terms of the Indian intellectual property rights law
goods (1957) or which provides for the death three years in prison and a fine of up to two thousand of Akash
All characters, names, places this fictional film
If there is any similarity between them and the fact
is a matter of pure chance, and unintentional never
"T U"
the visuals and recreational items
: audio album of the film is on
Forest "Music"
: shareholder action and voice album
"My seen in"
"film industry"
: multi-contributor
"Radio City"
: shareholder distribution channels Radio
Media to Win
Direct Access
Oraaz me - Tex
: Brands Contribute
Banac Parlour "Advertising"
: Contribute
agencies  (Company (Aamir Khan
Production
Do you returned broadcast?
No
And now?
! No
No longer
And now?
! Face pickup signal dreaded in the Sui
Hello you Circuit wrestling
Olympics "Seoul" to North Korea
We are on the threshold Show MP
I see an exciting day
Broadcast
has returned  Do you revealed?
No, you have stay holding him
The last game in this Olympics
weight category of 72 kg
"Between the wrestler" Russia "and another" America
! What a sad
Olympics
b "Seoul" GS (1988) or
! What a sad
Olympics
b "Seoul" GS (1988) or
Although wrestling
, "wildly popular" India
Olympic Games as the "Seoul" GS (1988) or
Olympics
b "Seoul" GS (1988) or
"However, the wrestlers" India
was a disappointing performance at the Olympics Olympics
b "Seoul" GS (1988) or
"However, the wrestlers" India
was a disappointing performance at the Olympics
"Village" Balalaa "state" Haryana
G (1988) or "
but the wrestlers" India
was a disappointing performance at the Olympics
"Village" Balalaa "state" Haryana
G (1988) or
So our children can win medals for our country
But where the necessary support?
No money is not backed by
institutions trains
How to win a medal if our children?
If you can win a medal
, once you talk
I would have won one a long time ago
Are you new here?
! That's what I thought
, Try to tread bullring days
Stafr and escape before the start of the game so
You seem to have done this much
I mean escape
If there is a bullring here
we were to see who escape Sever
The need for circuit wrestling?
This is Allahth we have been waiting all
The ring ready for the big game
And enthusiasm is widespread atmosphere
Both Almassaraan Akhtoan the ring for the match
(You're right, without a doubt, my (Tom
seems it will be a great match
Audience seems enthusiastic
Almassaraan and standing face to face
To see how the game will be
Usual greeting hands
Launched the referee whistle
! And start the game
! I drop it to the ground
! Drop it to the ground
Early fall of the Russian wrestler
"Overconfident may be fatal."
If you want, we try again?
Now, Almassaraan preparing for the next round
Already O (Tom), this game
does not look so easy that we thought
! Let's see what will happen now
Almassaraan been testing both the power of each
! Direct attack, offset by excellent defense
! This was an amazing movement
! What a wonderful movement
Opponent does not know what it gets
Here is attacking
! What a counter-attack
! Match
! The match
And (David) is the victor game
Victory and became an ally of (David) here
(Well said, my (Tom
no one expects this rapid defeat of the Russian wrestler
! What a game
Wrestling match of high style
You really Maher
I have defeated local hero Talk
Do not overburden yourself Baltonab, oh Rfifi
Lost in front of a national hero for Talk
, Met my uncle
(Mahvir Singh Fujat)
I left wrestling years ago
Wrestling but never
leave  Presents: Disney
wrestling but never
Inc. (Aamir Khan) Production
Competition
I'm here to control my
Defeat for the best and Azfar
From the womb of your mother and even your grave
wrestling with you and will not Tvarqk
Competition competition Haya
Win lose ground floor Bakdrick
Vnujomh heaven fighting for you
Competition competition Haya
Vibrates when your heart is fearful and calm him down shops
Knead your back, your courage will be prepared to the fullest case
If every challenge in front of you as Phil berserk
Kabbaltk standing, staring your fears you results
Stand across from him, Spend it
These Aftrtk what I was born
Competition, competition, come on, come on
Win lose as much ground
Vnujomh sky battling for You
A, come on
Competition, competition, come on, come on
Competition competition
little boy will win
Younger boy will win
! Here is a
The victory was the standard flesh "
" the elephant was defeated ASDA
! Come here, my son
Wrestling conducting blood
It's instinct generated by
Prefer, buy yourself some milk
! Bless the Lord
"National Wrestling Championship in India"
When they do not find a piece of bread to eat
Allam Stngzy? The medals?
Does not care about a wrestling
Accept the job that you subjected her and by
Why retired from wrestling?
What I had a choice
Omdtna wrestling fame sweeping
But not necessary Tmdna
money  For this, I looked for other work
Dream of every wrestler
bring a medal for his country
But if your country did not provide support to struggling
Vlmty bear this wrestler?
It was not your fault that you did not win a medal for your country
How long to make these memories
Tthaglk two?
What I could not achieve our son would achieve
Would win the gold medal for my country
And will fly my flag aloft
Remember my words
This day was my uncle utmost tension
as "High school student" awaits outcome
Do not worry, my brother
Everything would be okay
Gave birth to a girl
Was hoping that my uncle alive Bold
But Rizk girl
Do not you
(You have become my cousin (Oomkar
you really
happy  As for my uncle, was a fake happiness
Then everything started
suddenly become all of the village, the author of a book
"How Thablan Bold"
Given black cow candy
made of white
sesame  Wrapped cornmeal bread
and Otamiha left hand before sunrise
Stnajabin and a boy without a doubt
This is a prayer for a special kicking Bold
I call it a day
! Come on, eat this
! Eat This
! Stop it, come on
(Mahvir)
Tjama not your wife only a few days only Sunday
The rest of the days of holding back yourself
I made to understand?
People did not stop giving advice
Prefer, my son
My uncle and my aunt did not stop them from listening
Solution on the birth
Taking half the village combined
To receive their credit that gave birth to a son
Jetta) you will have a brother)
You can play with him
! It's a girl
But did not get my uncle's son
And did not garner the villagers credited
! Despite all attempts
Must be implemented and that ye Okhtotma
Must and they fed the black buffalo
instead of a black cow
"Look for my cousin, who as" Rothek
I have fathered three children fullest wellness
It must have been a mistake to read
pray for this outcome flipped
One can not restrain himself
I've told him that there is no intercourse
! Only a few days Sunday
"It must have been considered the" Sunday
all days of the week
Not be able to have a child you
's Not your fault
Not get me mistaken
Jetta) and (Babita) Azizatan to my heart)
But the boy, according to
Who can fulfill my dream
Years passed
Uncle and did not leave his desire never
I wanted a boy
But, perhaps the Lord did not want to meet his wish
Third born was a girl
The fourth child, also a girl
Then Livni also grief
"Gold medal national championship"
Food is ready, Dad
! Ready
Aqlp otherwise burned
Would you like more?
Then my uncle despair of having a son
and despair of achieving his dream too
(Hello, oh (Mahvir Singh
Why him?
Static to watch the wrestling match
this evening?
No, you've seen
(Hello, oh (Mahvir
I've given birth Bold
prefer some candy
What happened?
See how they were beaten
! Say something
! Yes, see how they were beaten
Tatlehma bruises and wounds
Yes, Tatlehma bruises and wounds
Why did you beat them?
! I'm not the actor, my uncle
! Jetta) and (Babita) of Dharbihama)
Two Avcala quarrel Dad
Natani Balkhasrh
and called her a witch
So, Guenihama lesson
Oasah that Tdharbihama
this way for such a trivial reason?
No, what they had to beat them in this form
Please Samehoheme, are still two girls
Snsamhama because they not only Fattatak
! Movement
! Tdrbakma two girls
! Come here
Would not quarrel with a dad again
First, he told me how Tmkintma
Who did this?
First, we take care of Balkhasrh
but I remained quiet
But when called (Babita)
witch we beat
Caught him and beat him so
After the other boy tried to attack us
I grabbed his hair and I delivered to the ground
And then hit him on the back Bmrfiqi
"They say that" the drowning respect straws
The uncle was found on
Qstein not one
All this time and I hope
, Zafar was born until
To have a gold medal for my country
But unless I catch that winning remains the victory
both achieved boy or girl
(From now, you will not Tqoma (Jetta) and (Babita
never any household work
Wrestling taking place Bdmaihma
From now on will not only wrestling Tqoma
Wrestling for boys, according to
Do you think that girls less than boys in something?
I've never seen a girl struggling with throughout my life
Why will tell the people of the village?
How long will be long to talk?
What if this caused
a broken hand or a foot girls?
What we will break
Where is our money for that?
I do not know
Do not spoil the lives of the two girls
To want you
Omhlaina years I'm trying to do
Throughout this year
Oagafla your feelings inside you
, But it turns out I was wrong
I Soagafl on my dream all my life
Ottaghza Bavh dawn tomorrow
Why, Dad?
I Ataamkma "Jawljbas" which Tvdilanha
"cake rich Balbhar hot potato"
Bavh am, okay?
Why committed now?
I thought you committed the mistake
! Addressed
What Roakma?
Is not too hot, dad
Well, make it more
lane  Addressed as much as Chaian now
Because from now on
Stlazeman life wrestlers
X! O Aldnas
And not allowed to eat Gladiators
spicy or salty or fried
food  Almost every food that Tvdilanh
Considered the latter Thalitkma
X! O Aldnas
(From calculated by (Moses), find him eventually (Pharaoh
(Come on, HURRY O (Babita
O my father, do not carry us all this torment
(From calculated by (Moses), find him eventually (Pharaoh
Dad, it's very difficult to run these clothes
O my father, do not carry us all this doom
not endured all this doom
! O our father
! Oh and DNA
O and DNA, cause damage to our health
! Aaakma stop
! Aaakma and stop
O our father, we are damaging our health Monday
Accompanied us please, we are still two girls
Tons of discipline
Tons of discipline, we prefer the dreaded death
O my father, do not cause damage to our health we are Monday
Accompanied us please, we are still two girls
Tons of discipline
Tons of discipline, we prefer the dreaded death
O our father, we are damaging our health Monday
No and find someone such punishment by
meeting hit a pair of boys
I've humiliates me
Why did you beat him?
! Teach guilt Ali now
Prevent us from any tidbit, do not eat until the dough
This torment gm really, like you jailer We prisoner
Prevent us from enjoying Btfultona, we are still small
Prevent us from any tidbit, do not eat until the dough
This torment gm really, like you jailer We prisoner
It's fun and enjoy Btfultona time
Why are calculated minute fun we have here?
Luck is like a disrupted
, And our father
The driver of this car Oaldana authoritarian
O our father, we are damaging our health Monday
Prevent us from any tidbit, do not eat until the dough
This torment gm really, like you jailer We prisoner
Ask the two girls Rgiqtin, to be strongly lions
Sentia all your orders, Mom
Onqvena of wrestling is that, according to
Lancia for one year Dikma that either
Hey! Oncima so quickly?
(This is nonsense really, oh (Mahvir
Circuit girls wrestling?
Ostdjalna committed such an offense
this age?
Destroyed our childhood, withered flowers jasmine
What would you do us too, to become one of the gladiators?
Day and night screaming, tears streaming down from the eye
I still also Ttzmr, my dreaded dictator
No hope for us, and our situation does not accept any improvement?
We are better than you, O chaff
Better than you, O wicked dreaded
movies  O our father, we are damaging our health Monday
! (Babita)
Hla my feet massaged please?
! I will ask you the same thing
! Oh and DNA
! O our father
Ahterma the soil of this land always
, The more Ahtramkma
have greater respect for others as
! O our father
(My uncle was able to bring (Jetta) and (Babita
to wrestling
But there was something less
(so that's (Jetta) and (Babita
, well-rehearsed
were needed to practice with the Gladiators skilled
Oomkar)?)
My son (Oomkar)?
Yes
This is not exaggerated, my brother?
Pain was not enough to force you to two girls on
incision coached wrestling?
Now wish them wrestle boys?
OK or not?
Not Othaly bold for approval
Nor courage also Othaly
rejected  Sent if
Besbbkma Talna the flames of this
! Stop complaining
If the flames of this Talk
central his fire entirely
! Continued ran
Why DNA and forced him to train with us
?
This boy softwood does not represent a challenge for us
Seems "K.a.q.a" For me
What does this mean?
"Much talk, little action"
K.a.q.a ", is not it?"
On your slow on
I am your sister a small
! Yes, yes
Not Taakhzna by saying
however, are weak little Fattatek
Tqatlna Would I like that?
I will return immediately
! I do not understand your style treating them
I can not be their father
and Mdrihma at once
, When he takes up the coach
For Father viewing from afar
"I apologize for Natk to" K.a.q.a
! I said I apologize
Do you think this a joke?
The Balqaik
land claims and do it all the goodwill?
When they attack you from left
Why not Taatmaskin and Tdafien?
Sorry, Dad
My daughter, this wrestling
Three lapses and end up
Come on, try again
Where did you go to your strength?
Trained on the two girls wrestling
and did not say a word
But I will not allow you to cook chicken Bmtbouka
"religion forbids eating animals"
! Try Fahmi
Wrestlers need protein
! I do not like this
The meat was cooked Bmtbouka
I will refrain from food completely
Otoda be Fattatak
Massarotain are weak?
! No income me all this
! Shops that are cooked chicken Bmtbouka
Oomkar)?) -
Yes? -
Can you cook?
No, my uncle -
know if -
We do not have the budget to continue
cook food such
How we will bear the price of chicken
buy now?
Would I like to give you a hen
at 20 rupees instead of 100 rupees?
What is the benefit accruing to?
Did not explain to me your destination?
Jetta) and (Babita) will become eventually)
Massarotain Mshahurtin
When people discover that they
, touch upon the chicken from you
Where Tznhm will buy chicken?
This seems logical
! But 20 rupees for a chicken?
There are shops others -
! Slow down, listen -
To make it 40 rupees per hen
Will not give you more than 25 rupees
I Hmrt onions
I would not use this pot again
Now, place the chicken vasa
And let cook over low heat
Be eaten with rice
But it can be eaten with bread also
My uncle is his duty
The people of the village do their duty
Girls're not good only for cooking
! And not wrestling
(I've Jen (Mahvir
not reap even went with him modesty
It leaves
girls wearing shorts and Tsaraan boys
When Bdotma wrestling
Osubhtma enjoy the qualities of men
I wonder what will happen to as well?
What will happen next
fists that will deliver the greeting on your face
Something were to happen this
! The bore him a son
Did not object to their mother on the matter until
People of the entire village made fun of us
Of this case is going to marry my daughter?
, I will raise your two daughters down to the point
That the boys will not Akhtaroheme
but boys will stand a description of the two of them Takhtara
I'll tell my father today, that this wrestling thing would not work
I am well
And - for -
d "means" born
S - i - of
"means" cat
Dad, this wrestling thing would not work
(With (Babita
, yes, Dad
Jetta) hit fatigue)
so that she sleeps dismissal
Can not study
focus  Body (Babita) strongly Distressed
Baltooh continue throughout the night
(School and harassing girls (Jetta
"and call it a" man
alas! True?
No problem with all this
told me that there was a real problem
Haya
P - Z - for
Dad, we felt Baltqcef
continue due to mud wrestling
Even lice hit
Eight of them killed this evening
Now, this is a real problem
Well, Ottaghza Bavh dawn tomorrow
Please, Dad
We do not have any problem
In fact, it utmost pleasure
Please, do not enlighten felt
We will do whatever you say
Mom, say something
Otren Why does Dad?
Please, Dad, do not enlighten felt
We will do whatever you want
Will wake early in the morning
and do everything without complaint
But please, do not enlighten felt
Please, Dad
Story
Cut it?
Can you increase growth?
Story if
Quite Bajabbarhma on wrestling
but the cruelty of their hair cut
! Eventually they were girls
No matter what I do, it is in their interest
Anything Seshetthma for wrestling
! Get rid of it
"Is the sun emerging, or that the moon reflected"
I am astonished, must
Monday Bzga together today
(Let him O (Babita
! It is our destiny no objection
, Enough wrestling
Now it's time real quarrel
Since then, a small village
"called" Balalaa "state" Haarana
Stemmed real revolution
(Althairtan (Jetta) and (Babita
(against the dictator (Mahvir Singh
All weapons uncle have been revoked
one after the other
Cleverly disabled the alarm clock
What happened, Dad?
Delayed waking day
Aging and Ovailh
No problem
I've finished training today
(Come on, O (Babita
been eliminated a lot of bulbs
How lamp that Antefo every day?
Bad quality, Dad
impress them to escape injury from exercise
The fight were Tstsalman
without a fight even
Do should I strike you?
Despite the fact that my uncle, has condemned the iron
But he felt powerless
Kfar detainee trap
! Stay away from here
I do not understand how I became
! This force suddenly
But my uncle understand why Omsata
Jetta) and (Babita) this weakness)
Thinking (beta) and (Babita)
triumphed in this war
! Ye
Omahbtan for a wedding (Soonati)?
Um... j
Othaolan causing Baharaja?
Choose one
This
Invited me Orakma
Finally Vtataa seem like the other girls
! Do not tell your dad
Promises of the house before eight in the evening
! Ha has come, Arostna Rhodotorula shame
! Fill modesty, to shame
! I saw a lot of my life wacky
! But I have not seen the strangest of Arasa following
! But I have not seen the strangest of the following Arasa
! Virgin married a marriage to an old breaker
! Hey, it Arasa loser
! It Arasa loser
! Asked Arasa help me to recover
! Bring me a toothbrush, no need for surprise
! But he came to me with sugar, what a cheat
!! What a loser
! It Arasa loser
! Leisurely, my brother
! It's crazy
I've missed the exercise for one day
Why provokes all the fuss?
What kind of parents are forced
Fattatah on Aldo Massarotain?
Makes them wake up in the morning Bavh
to Icoma ran?
Iemlhma like slaves?
Kafattaan make them?
! If objected, cut their hair
! Oh God, not anyone doing such a
father ! I pray the Lord for such a Ablaney
father  At least indifferent to the faith of
, And was only natural Meserkme
, And the moment of birth
Almaha cooking and cleaning
Feltqom every home business
Once you are fourteen years
Zojoha complacency
The offers have anyone, do Aqublo
And Sazojok
from a man who did not show him before even
And then conceive and raise children
This is all serve him
At least Iatbarakma Aldkma
and his two daughters really
Do anything to Ogelkma
Abandon everything that craves to Ogelkma
Why?
So that both of you live better
life  What's wrong with doing?
I'm here to control my
Defeat for the best and Azfar
Luck when it gives you a chance to prove yourself
Mamo several days to equip no doubt
Encounter every drop of sweat you Taatsbb
Make sure that you will win it for yourself
Luck will be subject to meeting your efforts this
! Competition, competition, come on
Bmak day it became very evident to me
(I do not know what about (Geeta) and (Babita
but I'm not talented wrestling
! Look at the state of
give him more of butter, my mom
has become weak
I lost on purpose to make you happy
"Shut up you, the" K.a.q.a
! He lost deliberately said
Do not worry
Will keep this secret between us
After all, we are a family
Reputation of our reputation
Taatfajra not much
witness what I'll do tomorrow
Not going to do this tomorrow
No, my uncle
certainly I will tomorrow Nzala fierce
We will go to the "Rotak" Tomorrow
For wrestling contest
But, I'm not ready to compete after wrestling game
It has Bzkirk?
Would fight boys?
Will stand for two minutes, my uncle
Why?
Evil has Hzmtk defeat
Are not striking?
I have not seen a lot of my life wrestling competitions
But today I was on a date with one
Competition not seen "Haryana" by
Became inevitable
! Mahvir Singh Bujat), hello)
Increases our honor you came to watch our contest
I also subscribe to a famous
wishes  Name, please
(Geeta Kumari Bujat)
Why?
Ostdjal girl wrestling?
Yes, what's the problem?
Type
Sir, when I organize a competition for cooking
Sostdei Miss (Jetta) gladly
! As this contest Wrestling
We came from as far away
distance  Will not go back without subscribing to fight
(Either fighting (Jetta
! And either we fight you and I
First utter drivelling
! And then insists on what it says
What do you mean?
I would like to wrestle girl boys?
Probably do not care about your reputation
we were indifferent to our reputation
! Samsh your reputation earth now
Please, sir
Sir, we really
Nhtermk  But we can not do the asking
We can not do this, sir
! Let Us
! How dare by this
Brings you the opportunity until your doorstep
and rejects them in this way?
What do you mean?
How long have you run
wrestling contests?
Five years -
How many of those who came to watch? -
Little by
If?
Dimit), think about it)
Town has never see a girl wrestling
When wrestle Boy Girl
How many people will come to watch this?
We will achieve the proportion Show Unusual
But what if you are broken by a girl or presented? -
Feltenksr -
Not heal the wound your competition
Even if offered a ticket Brobbetin
Expenses will be covered by Massaraeink for months
(Syed (Mahvir
Ladies and gentlemen
Vtiyanj and Aftiata
Probably seen the girl walk on fire
eat a snake or a girl
"But today, for the first time on" Rothek
You'll see a girl struggling with feta
"After half an hour Circuit" for Ashok
Ticket Brobbetin
Ticket Show girl struggling Brobbetin
! You win
Even made Massaraeik struggling Asda
what you are half that audience even
What do you think?
You again will endure?
O my companion, as soon as the end of this bout will be normalized land
Will fight wearing clothes like this?
! Shut up -
! I wish this -
Where are they?
Look sexy -
I hope that is not torn her shirt -
! I wish I could be torn
! (Come on, (Jetta
! Come
! He has lost his mind, and her father
Do you know the rules of wrestling Circuit like?
If, choose from would you like to teach you the loss
Notices do you think?
! Ftana lean
! O Lucky
win for the first time in your life
My God! (Gassi) Sahzmha defeat evil
Get out of the three of you here
Daughter has lost her mind
There is still time, I was stopped by
Else will come out on a stretcher
To beat your opponent, you defeat your fear first
At least, my daughter has to defeat her fear
! Attached to them, she's a girl
! Do not commit such a mistake
! You Thrzina
! Jetta), well done)
! Wow
! Ended her
! What a movement
I have fought well
! Well done
(And winner of the contest prize, (indurativa
an amount of Rs. 20
(And the guest of honor (Carter Singh
special award for (Geeta Kumari) Rs 50
sorry, Dad
not you
Haya
You was lucky
otherwise you went back to your home on a stretcher
= =! Dad
what time of the next bout?
Wearing a T-shirt and shorts
Tell the hurricane Welcome
Hold a telephone, telephony everyone
wary fierce coming
"Whether you are a" Hinghar "or" Delhi
will Txueq ground
Oossalk and will be kept absolutely fall apart
The response attacked'll find them absolutely
Stxueq land, a land Stxueq
It's the power of the not insignificant
Out to be reckoned
It is the power to be reckoned with
Significant
Start tomorrow, you'll also vaporized
! What a girl
Watch ye Gladiator Vsthrq G'rourk
fist ignite a fire
You will know your weaknesses will be received mass
Will not pick yourself a moment
will not depart hit you glance
Stxueq land
Oossalk and will be kept absolutely fall apart
The response attacked'll find them absolutely
Stxueq land, a land Stxueq
It's the power of the not insignificant
Out to be reckoned
Again people started talking
(about (Geeta) and (Babita
"These two girls had come in from the village" Balalaa
and Tshakan boys crushed
This boy lost girl
Do not Penzalha did not you?
But the solution time and it changed its
words ironic applause
Some people did not want to wrestle a girl
And some did not call the girl struggling
of the foundation
! Please left
It was not (Jetta) and (beta) Journalist
and wrestling competitions by
But people also love Tkspan
It's the power of the not insignificant
Ruby (14.900) of, Ruby (15.000) of
Ruby (15.150) of
Wrestling has become a big
Did not bring (Geeta Kumari) pride for our school and by
brought to our village, but the whole
I assure you it will increase our village pride
national championship for beginners as well
Vacation? For two months?
Osttzoj daughter?
Ali preparation (Jetta) to play
national competitions sir
My brother, let alone this
If she is going to marry may put this into account
I do not understand your decisions sometimes
What I had a choice
I would leave my dream
So, left the job
What do you do now?
I will continue to cultivate our land
Work hard yes, but at least
I will have time to train two girls
Tito) Place the drive)
Wait, go
(Yes, oh (Mahvir Singh
What did you say?
If I take a loan
This will help me a lot
I've got my daughter to the local level
, so
What great tragedy
access the local level women's wrestling?
If the individual competition, will override the first place
What is the reason you need for this loan?
Sir, I would like to buy a rug to train them
Plays well
The supported today
someday will raise the head of the country
(Listen, O Lord (Mahvir Singh
We have limited funding for sport
less wrestling and financing
After wrestling men
training and travel and equipment funds and etcetera
Left so much to the ladies wrestling
And for so little
I bought my candy Fund
But our moral you always
Why he did not win medals India
that people like you reluctant seated
Well, I'll stand if
Tito), bring me lunch)
Master (Mahvir Singh) Would I like to Mchatrta lunch?
Sports Federation This looks like termites
I have spoiled the whole sports
As long as does not support talented athletes
it not Ttzmr when they do not win medals
Think not of glory Tamara you eat "
" will not reach the glory even licking Sabra
I love what you do, your job Drudge
Bchgvk by
And these bastards are not helping
! Priceless rug until training
What are the rug training, my brother?
Carpet industrial fragile trained by
wrestler without being hurt
! And its teams for any other rug
Committed the silence?
Discharged something a mistake?
Acts uncle, make you dream at night
Now, do not Evarqk asleep or awake
Wrestling on the mat wrestling
quite different from mud wrestling Circuit
Now we wrestling on the mat wrestling
And wrestling on the carpet
be harvested win points
You can either make a point or two
or three or five points
(Oomkar)
Hold
The grabbed an opponent from his waist
and I delivered on his knees
Vsthsalin on one point
It is this situation that Qlapth on the back
Vsthsalin two points
There are several ways to do this
! My uncle
Thus
Or the status of the knee, so
The opponent was thrown on his back from a standing position
Vsthsalin three points
! Please, my uncle
So altogether, three points
From a standing position
to fall on his back
The get five points
is difficult, but not impossible
The overturned
opponent from a standing position
From above your head inflected
And fell on the ground, his back
Vsthsalin five points
! Witness -
No, no, my uncle -
Come here -
No, please -
Carpet
real wrestling is not so
It's so
You stay within the yellow
PART  Red zone is the danger zone
If you lose out by a point
There are three rounds of two minutes each round
Three rounds, two minutes each round
From won two rounds of the three have
victory
Sir, your daughter less than required
weight  If?
Take my advice does not provide for competition
A wedding
Make fatter next year promised
That fought in this case will break their bones
Told me that it was permitted
Balenzal or not
Allowed, yes
! Come
"National championship for beginners"
! Good movement
I've defeated (Jetta) boys stout
What chance these girls in front of her?
Is this a girl or a storm does not subside?
"Gold medal national championship for beginners"
"International tournament for beginners"
Is it less than the specified weight?
! Yes, but how important is this?
! Aqlbhe
"Gold medal championship (International) for Beginners"
"" Jetta), the state, "Haryana)"
Over time
Turned (Jetta) from beginner to professional
, And my uncle
Of the citizen, to an old
citizen  (Come on, (Jetta
I and (Babita) increased Toulna after
Palace Qamtna
! Oskotaiha land
! Going to give aside
! (Jetta)
! "Victory for" Haryana
"Winning the national championship for professionals"
Finally achieved the dream of my uncle
Now we can relax
No
Not fulfill my dream after
Every year we see a national hero
Achieved my dream
If Tjelba gold medal for yourself and by
but also for your country
You can celebrate the day
But starting tomorrow we will prepare for a higher purpose
Dad
I want to talk to you
Talk
, Dad
..alan, And since I won the national championship
Why?
..la, I mean
All national heroes have to go
to the state of "Patiala" to better training
Bokadamih to join the national sport
Where are you going to Bhdazq?
Tell me about it directly
Have to go too, Dad
From now on
to train there
Under the hand of an international coach
"National Academy of Sports in India"
(Geeta Kumari Bujat)
Wrestling Section
... Geeta Kumari)
"Nothing but the best"
Sounds good place
Hope to be a good coach also
"India"
Hey girls, come on
Must and nor are Mbottaghat
Because the idea of training our developer
Well, Dekn of training
Now, You just have to learn to forget
Forget all the wrong education
which Tgaytamonh
Diet erroneous
exercises wrong and erroneous methods
After forget all this
True Tdrebkn
begin  (With the International Coach (Eut Kadamkizat
And you will learn what Oalmkn According to him
Is that clear? -
Yes, sir -
Good
! Abdin warmed up
! Bring me tea
! Come on, girls
Energy, more energy
Yes, so completely
Astmrn Thus
Good -
Greetings, sir -
(Sir, I am (Mahvir Singh Bujat
(father (Jetta
Well
I was trained
Well, good
It's clever, sir
Very strong and bear much
Where his tea?
! Come on, Thrkin
Sir, request one
The got (Jetta) the proper training
Win international medal without a doubt
! (Jetta)
Must be angled 90 degrees
between the leg and thigh
Any fool he teach you?
Is this how Stvosen international medal?
I came to reaching, right?
I've done what I came for him
Now, let me rest
! Do not waste my time
Translation Islam Geez! Wei
"break"
Why my heart beats so fast?
I do not know
These new colors, these sounds fresh
Why my days suddenly become different?
I do not know
Why my heart beats so fast?
Osnkrj later tonight?
Is the atmosphere different?
Or that spiritual happiness wrappers?
One will not make a difference
This taste of freedom, of the utmost magnificence
I do not know
Why my branches were opened flowers?
Why my heart beats so fast?
I do not know
! Yes, so completely
Remember one mistake will cost you the medal
New friends made up
Recorded up to the sky
Ground ignites jealousy
Accuse me that I Otdallal
Days after the day of this life
It seems to be tired of counting
Began asking questions, what will be next?
Yes, dad
training applies well
I'll go, coach awaits
! Goodbye
I left behind me all the questions
what is right and wrong
Without his feet or longer tread
Why my heart beats so fast?
! (Jetta)
Come here
Let alone style and your dad
I do not want to see only what taught him
understand?
Hello?
(Sorry, I went out (Jetta
For years and I have lost deliberately Ogelkma
! It is the truth
!
Otren you out?
Creates Gladiator The style was right
I will win international medal also
and you also
Yes, when it will come back to the house?
I'll come next week
Othtegen something?
No, I do not need something
Well
Like?
Really?
I've overlooked your hair
Looks good
Your father will not like this
Now, will not apply everything
also want my father
Coaches has no problem with such a qualified instructor
Doin what you wish there
Diligence analysis a little -
! Mom -
Real training that included an succeed
some freedom
Not frequently ultraviolet rays
Watch movies and eat abroad also
Did our performance despite this
affected  I am the best the Academy wrestling
I went back to your house, O wrestling?
How are you? -
Okay, Dad -
What news workouts?
Go to "Sydney" to fight Nzala
Apply well, Dad
You have seen it yourself
Learn new things
New strategies
movements and new methods
Very good
I thought about teaching her a few things as well
After all, they have to win the national medal also
I've lengthened your hair
Dad -
not -
It's good
Not Thajma According
You also defense
Hold Me
How Sthrran yourself now?
Hold the hand of an opponent and so on
Avthiaa Hajma
It's an old style
View
Hold Me
Strongly more
My thumbs in this way
Not the forefoot, both sides
unfasten the hands of an opponent and Hajma
What's wrong with my style?
What's wrong with it?
No, not a mistake, Dad
But this healthier
taught me coaches
method  Have become an expert now?
International wrestling?
... Dad, I've been
I would like to know what your knowledge of this manager
did not teach you and your father
Does not show her, show me I
Come
Place your thumbs so
So, that's what you taught your coach
Is this how Stvosen international medal?
! I was not ready, Dad
If Astaadi
That's what I tell you, Dad
! Style free of the defense
What happened today was not true
What is this that was not true?
Was inevitable that happening
Someone has to tell the father that his methods
weak
Methods is not weak
But is has become weak
And remember that, if you can win the national medal
except his ways "weak" This
You can win the national medal
(his ways are these, my (Babita
Rather than international medal
Whenever Obakrt Absorb this, the better
, OK
Keep faith Bosalepk
and I will keep my faith in my father
I pray the Lord that Tqatlin well
national competition
I call upon the Lord to fare well
cycle of international games
This world lie apply
The pain it real
Everything mirage, my dear
Only bond of my family
These eyes
Dreamed a beautiful dream heart buried
Tears streaming down to Vrackm in stillness
These eyes
Remain vigilant throughout the night eyelids
Refuses to bloom am mad
Differentiate my way, it is definitely Covenant
To stay together from the cradle to the grave
Now secured a joint grief and by
These eyes
After that we requested from the window of hope
Choked frustration, even ml
Breath burdened with ideas, what a torment
Why is this spirit frustrated suspicious?
Why is this frustration, why our situation for this Al?
Why riven heart a million questions?
These eyes
The shine as the stars of the sky
Now in the dark folds of the disappearance
These eyes
Which used to enjoy the warmth of the sun
Tired now and would like to indulge shade
Differentiate my way, it is definitely Covenant
Stay together from the cradle to the grave
Now secured a joint grief and by
These eyes
After that we requested from the window of hope
Choked frustration even ml
"" World Championship as "Sydney"
"" National championship as the "New Delhi"
! (Come on, (Babita
! Going to give
! Well done
What are you doing O (Jetta)?
(Come on, O (Jetta
! Aqlbhe, come on
What are you doing O (Jetta)?
! Payers
! Hajma
! Good movement
Tdafien this how?
Next round
Hajma directly
! Do not look happy, Dad
Pain fight is good?
But I did my dear
I've fought quite as
expected  (I, I can not imagine (the Jetta will fight like you
Now, you also won the National Medal
You also are you going to Academy professionals
And you will have a new coach
Age and your father will grow again
No, Dad
Never forget my dear
how I got to this level
Hello  O heroine
Hello, my sister
Are you still upset me?
! Come
Why put this bag? -
Let me carry with you -
It's too heavy
(Hello, oh (Jasmit
(This my younger sister (Babita
! Wow! Family of wrestlers
Messy situation here
Here we spend our free time
This is a place to relax
Here we watch TV
Where training headquarters?
Not so Taathmsa
Relax today and tomorrow Strenh
Can I say something?
Without feel offended
Tell me
I have a lot
changed  I remember the first time you lose a match
Taatmkny not sleep tonight
... And now, even though you lost caps
I mean, it does not appear the impact of
on your facial features
Do Guenk your father tell me this for him?
I remember my father well trained
seems you have to forget
Focus Pettmarenk
You and I will take care Pettmarini
Why teach the lecture?
I lost one match
"Moscow"
Geeta Kumari) compete in the second round)
of
Alambarayat also "Moscow"
Geeta Kumari) compete in the second round)
from Alambarayat also
It is fighting well, but does not control the situation
Trying (Jetta) full capacity
But  (Kasha) is making a point
! The tour ended
Out (Geeta Kumari)
early qualifying World Championship Wrestling
! "What a disappointment for" India
Another defeat representative of India
(Geeta Kumari Bujat)
"Jakart"
Qualifier "Jakart" also came out
(Jetta) in the first round
"Jakart"
Qualifier "Jakart" also came out
(Jetta) in the first round
(Ignominious defeat for (Jetta
qualifier "Istanbul" for the World Championships
"Istanbul"
(ignominious defeat for (Jetta
qualifier "Istanbul" for the World Championships
(do not lose your hope, O (Jetta
We have done our best
has provided a good match
Taatmkny did not win not only
That does not mean you're a bad wrestling
This happens sometimes
Some people do not share them
in winning the World championships
Otcharin also ashamed?
Because it has been left out of the world championships?
I do not know this
, But all I know
You're the girl who broke
boys Circuit mud
You are the girl who, despite the lack of weight
won all the junior tournaments
I gained all the confrontations
national championship for three consecutive years
Taatmkny but did not win the gold medal
I do not know a girl others to "India" may do
Your great faith
But my faith water point
Sea faith of your dad
Talk to him for once
Meet him in any way?
It is DNA
What the worst that could happen?
Give you a slap in the face?
Tqublaha of his mind
Always helped us
criticism is not it?
Medication
(I talked to (Babita
Told me that exercise is going well
And?
Jetta) is not okay)
Talked to them for once
Hello
! (Jetta)
! Well, wait
(She (Geeta
sorry, dad
Left over six months to start
ninth session of the tenth World Games
"The biggest sporting event to" India
We have no choice but to keep up the extent of the readiness of our players
To face the fiercest competitors around the world
This time cycle World Games
I would like to Nkinz three medals
Either from you three
Or three of you
you  I do not care of this
Left over six months
Abzln do your best
Concept?
!Come on
(Jetta)
Come here
You will get a medal of them -
Yes, sir -
Not a category that you lose out
Category, but you can win them
Concept?
Harder for you to compete
category 55 kg
You must be a Atsuspt this now
As the 51 kg category
You can survive and win if possible
Strakabban diet of each individual are strictly
Without corrupting -
! Sir, -
Sir, I would like the competition the 55 kg category
If you competition category 55 kg
will not Tbarahi loss
Them to lose 4 kg
Changed her diet food
Starting from tomorrow, Stbdoan
training for competition the 51 kg category
! Come on, girls
Did not Tvose the 55 kg category?
No need for your loss weight
Stnavsin the 55 kg category
and also Stvosen
"I am coming to the" Patiala
"We do not know which one to" Patiala
How do you want to sit there for six months?
Rented an apartment
And food?
I Sotha
! Sotha I, my uncle
I was thinking to come with you
What do you do there?
Well, the past Oblja Well
when I trained with me
... So, that trained with me now also
Honestly, I think I am lucky necklace theirs
I mean, that's what I think
And will buy vegetables you
and I'm going to Finely chop for you
I meet your requests and Odlk feet
Sobad compress secondary things perfectly
As you can see, it's the World Games
cycle  We can not take any chances
! Get ready to win gold
"Patiala"
Room above
Haya
Is there not room is this
the same price?
It is a beautiful
It's beautiful without doubt
! You passed this
"International Academy of Sport in India"
Prefer?
(We father and cousin (Jetta) and (beta
! Ahhh
Uncle, does not it look this place the utmost magnificence?
What you doing, O heroine?
You? -
Okay, Dad -
Why are you here?
Uncle insisted on my coming
Said they Global Games
and we can not risk never
"Shut up you, the" Q.a.k.a
, Training (Jetta) the 51 kg category had begun
and diet as well
Keep Ptdrebathm and diet
I am I will command the rest
Tdrebkma when to start?
Balsabah am
Well
Ottaghza Bavh dawn tomorrow
I'm here to control my
Defeat for the best and Azfar
Stuck Bhelmk well, beware of abandoned
Let alone all the cynics, and their talk Feltrno
This day, their day by saying Vdahm Ankazhok
Day will come tomorrow, and prove your ability in front of their eyes
Lion's roar silent enough to defeat
A dog howls
! Competition, competition, come on, come on
Win, you lose ground Bakdrick
Vnujomh heaven fighting for you
! Competition, competition, come on, come on
Pause, pause
Direct attack would not work
Both of you manipulate with an opponent
Falsely certain movement and carried out the dispute
! Sidi
Sir, I have a specific diet Okhaddatha
system  But I do not know why they do not bear fruit
The mother are planning  O (Jetta)?
Do uttered something
mother wept?
Sir, based on their actions
think they do not need anything Academy
The decision you
Do you have something to say?
Recognize Bouktohma If
Sir, we do not have only one mistake
That their father crazy
Crazy to win a gold medal for his country
Btefolthma Obadahma for Oabhma
and forced them on wrestling
When intercepted, cut their hair for them
To improve skill wrestling
imbedded Issaraan boys
Receptive to all harassment of the villagers
hoping to raise the head of this country days
See, sir
See
"These 50 rupees I've earned the" Rothek
"I've earned this and to" Heyzar
"This is the" Chandeara
This, and this
all of these, sir
I've definitely come a long way to Asla here sir
Tjbarhama not to return now, sir
It's my fault
I deeply apologize
Presence of the coach would like
won three medals
It does not matter if even a bronze
But I want my country to gain the gold
And this girl can this sir
Waited outside all, if you allow
I made a mistake to waste your time
(Category 55 kg, did not qualify (Jetta
to represent the "India" until the World Cup match
that rivaled the 51 kg category
was to win a medal
had to win a medal
category 55 kg, a long time ago
! You're in charge about this
WPM I missed?
Jetta), attack by nature)
Bnglepk style on the nature of one's
, you change the whole matter
It's like a tiger to tell you not only know the attack
perfectly elephant style of defense
"Will not impair mussels" Sham
"will not taste the grapes" Yemen
Why did not you tell me if
! How to fight to win medals
If you allow me the opportunity, I will do gladly
Here and Now
Atalbounkm inside
What happened was a mistake
But the Commission decided to give them another chance
Thank you sir
But, as of today
You are not allowed to enter the Academy
and not allowed them to get out of them
Well, sir
Pour me a glass today, my uncle
Sorry
Thank you
We came to do our part led things
The Academy spent all our efforts
Promise to immediately
(No, O (Oomkar
Can stop me from entering there
But no one can stop me
(of training (Jetta
! Cheer up, my uncle
faced three of them, dad
but Hzmtna defeat the evil of
Me was shorter and not too strong
Do you have a recording of this game?
Yes, Dad, it's the library
Make a copy to me
Left only three months
"on the World Games held as" Delhi
We sense of enthusiasm here
"National Academy for Sport to" Patiala
To where you are going, my uncle?
, The only thing I hated uncle
atmosphere of thrill-made
It's killing me angrier
"Site" mixing untamed
"My aunt Sensuality"
If you would like to watch movies
"Lets go to the" Amar Mahal
They do not offer a decent films here
! Come down
"My daughter unbridled"
Yes?
A ticket next show?
Any movie would like to watch?
We brought the film with us
! Stopped
! His job
Do Antheetma? -
Be happy -
Snhdz next promotion period also
What are you doing, my Rafiqaa?
I mean, from any country of this film?
"Atlanta" with "Indonesia"
Is it the importer of the film? -
Yeah -
Can I take a copy of it?
I'll give you 50 rupees
How can they win if they fight like this?
! My uncle
I have known defect and trying to resolve it
But how will lead as a result of what you did?
Academy has hung a banner
kills, upon seeing "for you"
! Ride
Again, more thrill
Tqatlin this how?
Kalqth thin?
If you Stqatlin this form
do not you go to the still of the foundation
What happened to you, my father?
I have seen all your matches
! So what you Tsaraein undoubtedly
Do you have a copy of this film
that you gave me?
Yes, Dad
Can you act and watch it on your own?
Sostaar a laptop
Well
Should you prepare Bavh dawn tomorrow
Been a long time since listened to my father
Was a wonderful feeling
(Nzalk with my job (the first round of Jakarta
filled by Dad
Go to 3:58
minute was in front of you grab two points
but you preferred to defend
Chglah and View
left the opportunity of your hand
When your opponent brawling
you foot
How did you do this?
And it is quite the opposite, when you have to defend
Tljoan attacked and Tahedran points
Will never benefit you attempt to profit Points
You direct your mind first
Matches I've lost you to easily Trlakenha
! Come on, my sister
"" Preliminary qualifying as "Patiala"
Each round of two minutes
120 seconds in front of you any full
Thina second mistaken her opponent
It's ingenious, is not it?
Yes, sir
! Utmost dexterity
Now, you look ready, my sister
Do I told my father Pfozk?
What was his response?
"! No need to over-excited"
"World Games goods (2010) or"
Large festive ceremony
declaration of the start of World Games goods (2010) or "
World Games commodities cycle (2010) or"
Large festive ceremony
declaration of the start of World Games goods (2010) or
"And the host country for the event" India
provides reviews highlights the ancient culture
! It's moments where pride undoubtedly
filled with  The Rivals "India" Login
Welcome their large
Let us remind you that the most powerful
athletes from 72 countries are participating the event
Will return tomorrow to the lack of tape
to start Games
Until tomorrow, the night of carefree
The (Jetta) tense before the first Nzalha
This was expected
Vodaiha international competitions
yet very bad
Despite this there is still hope of the nation
This was often an opportunity (Geeta) Recent
to prove itself
The first game the sport of wrestling women
, of the 55 kg category between
"Geeta Kumari) from" India)
"and (Melissa Anderson) of" Wales
! (Come on, (Jetta
(apparently the tension on the features (Jetta
To see if she is going to break this jinx
which the concomitant loss first tours
Would like to remind our viewers that the game
three rounds and each round of two minutes
From prevail two rounds
extracted victory
The game begins
Both Almassarotain Taatqldan caution
Trying not to lose any points
Here are stuck her foot
and (Jetta) a big problem
(One point for (Malasa
Malasa): 1)
Jetta): 0)
It seems that (Malasa) stronger
(Three points in favor of (Malasa
What are you doing O (Jetta)?
Malasa): 4)
Jetta): 0)
The abandoned (Jetta) for another two by two points
Will win (Malasa)
this round according to the law supremacy full
Trying (Jetta) constipation foot
but Al_khasmh directed the movement of anti
And (Malasa) extracted by two points
What happened exactly Khchinah
Malasa) won the first round to take complete control)
(six points versus no point for (Jetta
What are you doing, O (Jetta)?
! Tekhsary not miserably so
To see if (Jetta) is able to return
the second round after a huge loss in the first round?
Here are a swift counter
(and overridden (Malasa
(two points for (Malasa
(another point for (Malasa
It seems that this game tensile
(of the hands (Jetta
! (Not Tekhsary O (Jetta
! Come on, O (Jetta), Haya
Jetta) the last three points in this round)
it has to make points with the utmost speed
Trying (Jetta) disposed
and make points quickly
Jetta) is trying her heart)
(and two points for (Jetta
Malasa): 3)
Jetta): 2)
Jetta) is trying to make more points)
But the referee whistles
Round nearing completion
And still (Jetta) backward point
! Come on, my sister, come on
Jetta) is trying with all its might)
epilepsy rival territory
! Jetta) problem now)
And (Jetta) to capture the three points
Jetta): 5)
Malasa): 3)
Left over a few seconds
On (Jetta) that does not make them any points recorded
! (Yes, O (Jetta
! Hurrah
returned (Jetta) match
round for the benefit of both
Proved (Jetta) that it will not accept defeat so easily
It's the last round, okay?
Assuming Defense
I made to understand?
! Assuming the attack
Begin another round
Jetta) are attacking in full force)
(And a point in favor of the (Jetta
Jetta): 1)
Malasa): 0)
Jetta) are attacking in full force)
He's attacking, trying to rival the heart
(And two points in favor of the (Jetta
Jetta): 3)
Malasa): 0)
You be able to continue the progress?
Done, taxpayers now
Here's the (Jetta) attack again
Rival is a brilliant anti
almost beyond (Jetta) Red Zone
And (Malasa) holds a three-point
I told you to stand up
! No problem
Keep attack
Score tied at three points for both of them
! Come on, (Jetta), come
May tend tip the match for either of them
The (Jetta) was poised to win
but lost provided
To see who will prevail
Jetta) problem)
! Wow !, what a movement
(And three points in favor of the (Jetta
(I keep it to the ground, O (Jetta
it is trying with all its might to keep rival
ground
Jetta) won the match)
(Represented by "India", (Geeta Kumari Bujat
proved wrong all the doubters capabilities
(It's moments of pride for parents (Jetta
(Mahvir Singh Bujat)
Has every right to have his daughter gained
fair
So far India has won five gold medals
, 13 silver and seven bronze medals
Back to Department of wrestling women
(and represented "India" (Gita Kumari
Qualified for the semi-finals of the 55 kg category
(Face (Jetta
(Nigeria (Naomi Edward
world champion twice
What do you think?
Naomi) very strong wrestling)
and extremely violent and prone to attack
Do not give any chance to the opponent to
attacked
It will not be easy on the
(Jetta) this time
Today played on the breeze You
Now, Give ear to what I say
The only shops that Trlake
It's a very difficult adversary
But not impossible to defeat
You must comply with attacking style
This time stick to the defensive style
Try and collect points by
Let alone collect points
You will have many opportunities
Do not give her any chance
because they will not give you one
Oagafla them tightly every time
Although not making points, Vsimlkha frustration
and then give you a chance to attack
! This moment Thajman
First game
final half of the 55 kg category
(Hindi (Geeta Kumari
(against Nigeria (Naomi Edward
Naomi) to start the attack from the start)
Unlike the usual nature
(Jetta) defense
Naomi) attack again)
Jetta) problem)
Jetta) constitute a strong defense)
and (Naomi) overburden attack
Jetta) is trying to stop it)
The referee called Whistle
Tried (Naomi) strongly failed
Jetta) addressed well)
! Hajmiha directly
! Leisurely
It's a match burning
and (Naomi) deal harshly
It seems to be frustration owned
(Naomi) trying my wrist (Jetta)
The referee gives a warning
Called the referee whistle again
Receive (Naomi)
warning so as not to exclude
! (Cohesive O (Jetta
game continues again
Jetta) defend with all their strength)
and (Naomi) are attacking in full force
Naomi) stuck out)
(and three points for (Naomi
The (Jetta) addressed well
<font color = "# 40bfff" What a great effort
But  (Naomi) penetrated the defenses
and grabbed three points
On (Jetta)
act quickly or lose round
Naomi) attacking furiously)
and (Jetta) is committed to the defensive style
(Jetta), fall (Naomi)
(A point in favor of the (Jetta
and still trying
this time (Naomi) problem
! (Asuraei O (Jetta
trying to take it out of the red zone
! Tour ended
Jetta) play in good)
but it lost first round
What are you doing O (Jetta)?
Why do not Thajman?
Begin the second round
! (Come on, O (Jetta
Naomi) attack as usual)
Do will succeed this time?
(Good maneuver (Jetta
! (Come on, (Jetta
Get rid of the rival Movement
Here are attacking
Naomi) ducking and is a brilliant counter)
Turned out Walker provided
those who will prevail?
(Try (Naomi) Heart (Jetta
but (Jetta) defends well
Both sides trying to implement his style
Naomi) used all its strength)
But  (Jetta) does not give her room
It's exciting
match ! Come on, my sister
Naomi) was trying its best)
But  (Jetta) does not give her room
Naomi) attack again)
And (Jetta) defends
Here are (Naomi) paid
(All attempts fail (Naomi
(gorgeous and defense (Jetta
Naomi) stuck out)
but is trying to invalidate the movement
Outs this way, Lzimaiha
Whenever you try (Naomi) application traffic
overridden (Jetta) with ease
Referee called whistle
Second round it ended goalless
Must (Naomi)
ask themselves how Sochterq defenses (Jetta)?
(And (Naomi) pay (Jetta
If you can not make points
Seetmlkha frustration
And then give you a chance to attack
Naomi) attack)
and (Jbta) problem
This moment Tguetnasin opportunity
And (Jetta) inspired anti
(Three points for (Jetta
and (Jetta) win this round, three points behind
Naomi), Look at)
This girl, it's a smart
but you smarter ones
Okay?
Do not allow them to easily Bagdhabk
How Tqatlin?
Sir, I also learned to fight
Third and final round
begun  It's interesting to see
Naomi) plays this diligence)
Here are (Naomi) go for the feet
Naomi) grip controller)
and (Jetta) problem
Jetta) does not remain, defense)
and insisting it
Naomi) trying to do a brilliant counter)
And (Jetta) stuck her feet
Naomi) is trying with all its might)
But  (Jetta) stands a lookout
It's the status of the lock again and yellows
sentence
Stop the match referee in this situation
And continue the game again
Naomi) attack again)
Jetta) stuck to her back)
Do will be recorded (Naomi) any points?
(Cohesive O (Jetta
outcome is still goalless draw
trying (Naomi) attack in the strongest
Jetta) vulnerable to attack here)
but she stuck to her back
And (Naomi) are trying to complete its offensive
but (Jetta) prevent this
(A confrontation between the burning (Naomi) and (the Jetta
Jetta) was somewhat hair)
from the red line and the referee called whistle
Left only 12 seconds
Still score goalless draw
From scoring first win
! And (Jetta) attack
And (Naomi) are trying to evade
! But fail
Jetta) proprietary reins)
As the final score goalless draw
It has been able to make points
Now, draw
will take place  The draw will take place now
"This so-called" stand decisiveness
Choose each competitor's position either attack or defense
And the success of the nines with 30 seconds
That landed on the Red will face
(Naomi) attack
But fell on the blue face
(the attack of the share (Jetta
99%, from the attack of its share
winning the whole match
Much the same might not like
(to be victorious (Jetta
Not to mention the impossibility of defense against attack
(Naomi) for 30 seconds
any feet do you choose? -
Right -
chose (Naomi) feet ( Jetta) right
Jetta) take the defensive)
And (Naomi) Avlah trying its option
Now, in front of (Jetta) options
Either do not allow for (Naomi) logged
points within 30 seconds
Or making the points
and command the game
(This situation confronting (Naomi
, impossible to achieve any of the variants
launched the referee whistle
(try (Naomi) Drop (Jetta
but resist with all its might
've brought up, (Jetta) problem
Jetta) is trying to fall parked)
! Here is the counter-attack
And (Jetta) is making a point
Did not expect a win (Jetta) this match
I have defeated the first candidate
Gold Medal
B "position to resolve" the most fabulous
Intervened directly to the finals
(Let us hope that the rest (Jetta Bujat
World Cup match this constitution also
! (Jetta)
Hla went my uncle?
To watch the next game
To discover the face (Jetta)
Australian World Cup match or Scots
I am proud of b (Jetta) very
I followed my plan strictly
The result lies before you
Here's to come
Look utmost magnificence
! I mean Kmassarah
Uncle, not this, we saw the video?
(Angelina Watson)
've Defeated (Jetta) twice
They play pretty good so far
Will also fare well World Cup match
(For as long as they have confidence (b Jetta
they sooner or later will win an international medal
! Silver guaranteed now
will not be final never easy
(Miss (Jetta
has changed the style of your play 180 degrees
How did this happen?
... Credited with all this back
for my parents
never stopped believing in my abilities
(Syed (Mahvir
(hello Mr. (Shamin
(Congratulations, Sir (Mahvir
fought (Jetta) nicely
all the people (Balalaa) utmost pride
I have insisted, we will see (Jetta)
stadium and only abstain from food
What do you think the game?
I have insisted, we will see (Jetta)
stadium and only abstain from food
I loved her very
Give her this
What are these? -
Luck amulet -
Valenhaia tomorrow
! Bless the Lord
How can we allow this, sir?
Mahvir Singh) taught (Jetta) instructions)
among viewers
Poor girl stands perplexed
any of us eavesdrop
Style to play
does not seem to be perplexed never
In addition to that, how can we prevent the public from
talk?
Not a coach?
Them to listen to you
No, sir
I listen to
That's why winning -
Where is the problem then? -
I wanted the bronze medal, right?
It is very possible that holds the gold medal tomorrow
Not?
I am amazed because it arrived so much
but happy for her
Must be that it will be a final
summit in excitement tomorrow
Face a gamer Indian
and in front of an Indian audience
! I overcome it and, of course,
Angelina), Otcharin any pressure)
before the final game?
Yes, I'm sure of it lies under pressure g
It has defeated twice
One of the first round? -
Yes -
Yes, from the first round
So, thank you
! Greetings to you and
"Hindi"
What is the game plan tomorrow
dad?
No alternative to a single plan for tomorrow, my daughter
You have to Tqatla
way people remember you by always
If I won the silver, your memory will go forgotten "
" But if I win the gold, you will be a role model over time
And set a good example olive tree, my daughter, "
" do not grow quickly, but stay long
! Look for these two girls
If I win tomorrow will not Tvose alone
Millions of girls-appointed Sifuzn you
Will be a victory for every girl
they consider less than a boy thing
Imposed on them from household chores
Married to Icomn of raising children is not only
Match tomorrow's most important game of your life, my daughter
Because tomorrow will not Tusbanda such as the Australian and
But you will encounter both downplayed of your business days
"Hello Welcome Stadium Wrestling"
It's Wrestling Ladies Finals
the World Games goods (2010) or
Category of 55 kg, which is about to start
Hindi (Jtaa Kumari) against
(Australian (Angelina Watson
We would like to remind all of us
that he had never competed wrestling Indian women
Department
India did not win the gold medal before
these games
Between all this we see the crowd
high hopes and a lot carries the national flag
"India"
Jetta
Are not (Mahvir Singh)?
Father (Jetta)?
Yes
Moment, please
President of Wrestling Federation would like to meet you to talk
something important
Sokablh later
matches my daughter
It's a man would probably feel offended
Minutes and by
You go and prefer Sowatik
! "Credited with all this goes back to my father"
Go, and take the credit if
How far is it?
We are nearly reaching, sir
Brought me to where?
! My brother
What are you doing, my brother?
Warm applause for (Jetta), while intervention
Is there one here?
It's the ultimate
Diligence analysis
Angelina Watson) enter the stadium)
"No signal"
Begin final
! (Gold O (Jetta
called whistle initially
behave (Angelina) violently from the beginning
Here are attacking
Trying (Jetta) to get rid of its grip
Jetta) defends)
and (Angelina) trying to attack
Angelina) attack, and here is a swift counter)
(And three points in favor of the (Jetta
Jetta) begins a great start)
Topping round
Jetta): 3)
Angelina): 0)
! Well done, well done
Usual attacking Australian
and (Jetta) addressed
Jetta) obliges the defense)
Here are a swift counter
(Another point for (Jetta
Jetta): 4)
and (Angelina): 0
Jetta) play excellently so far)
On (Angelina) act quickly
Jetta) advanced by this tour)
Here are attacking
Jetta) attack, and (Angelina), a brilliant counter)
(And a point in favor of (Angelina
! Well done
Trying to (Angelina) control
Trying to (Angelina) Arjah Kvtha
scoring more points
And (Jetta) defends well
Referee called whistle
Jetta) leads the tour with four points for one)
On (Angelina) to make points in the course
Here are attacking
And (Jetta) inspired anti
(Another point for (
Jetta Jetta) and 5 (Angelina): 1)
Here are (Geeta Kumari) won the first round easily
(Probably starting to realize (Angelina
that this is not (Jetta) faced by earlier
and begin the second round
Do wins (Jetta) this tour
and make history?
(Mutual maneuvers, and stuck out (Jetta
(Drop excellent point in favor of (Jetta
Jetta): 1)
and (Angelina): 0
! (Come on, O (Jetta
Jetta) stuck her foot)
And (Angelina) problem
Jetta) is trying to volatility)
(and two points in favor of the (Jetta
Jetta): 3)
and (Angelina): 0
And (Jetta) raining (Angelina) all of its
Jetta) attack)
(Another point for (Jetta
bendy two points and by
and preference will win the round and the tournament also
Jetta) do everything they can)
Do you win (Jetta)?
(And whistle saved (Angelina
(No problem, O (Jetta
look (Angelina angry)
Jetta) are trying to stay away from them)
Jetta) is trying to make the first point)
(And a point in favor of (Angelina
Jetta): 4, (Angelina): 1)
Jetta) are still at risk)
(And two points in favor of (Angelina
Jetta): 4)
and (Angelina): 3
And (Jetta) resort to defend
! No problem, come on
Still (Jetta) advanced point
Retained a little after
Do you retain (Jetta) Besdartha?
Our gospel) trying to attack quickly)
almost time runs
Jetta) defends well)
Angelina) is doing its best)
Jetta) progress on the attack)
(and three points for (Angelina
Angelina): 6)
and (Jetta): 4
Delayed (Jetta) after they had advanced
Ended this round
Angelina) have shown that they are made from metal heroes)
What are you doing?
You can win the match
Regained (Angelina) enthusiasm again
! Come on, my sister
Will not be an easy tour
(For (Jetta
attack (Angelina) violently from the beginning
and (Jetta) is trying to address them
! Ahezmiha, my sister
Jetta) problem now)
(And three points for (Angelina
and made three points last round
! Come on, my sister
Angelina): 3)
and (Jetta): 0
Jetta) upset their balance)
while (Angelina) fixed
Jetta) Press)
and (Angelina) brilliant counterattack
Jetta) problem now)
(Another point in favor of (Angelina
Angelina): 4)
and (Jetta): 0
(And turn the game in favor of (Angelina
If it wants (Jetta) back for the game
it must make points quickly
But, do you have the opportunity?
Jetta) Press I.)
(Skilled movement (Jetta
she is about to make a point
(and a point in favor of the (Jetta
Angelina): 4)
and (Jetta): 1
Referee called Whistle
On (Jetta) more focus to make a point
But because Ahtersa (Angelina) could attack again
It is impossible to return to the game now
! Stflleha my sister, Stflleha
Jetta) are trying to act quickly)
Here are Thahm
But  (Angelina) is making a point
Angelina): 5)
and (Jetta): 1
(It is impossible to go back (Jetta
match now, it's the problem of serious
Remember my daughter
Your father will not be present every time
to save you
I can let you know the fighting, according to
But must Tqatla
Abzli extra effort yourself Onqve
Left over 22 seconds, according to
And (Jetta) the last four points
This stage, almost impossible
reduce the deficit in this period
, Progress has five points is very difficult
But not impossible
Jetta) trying)
And (Angelina) adheres to the defense for the last moment
Left only a few seconds
And "India" to accept the silver
You manipulate with an opponent
Zeevi you a certain movement and its opposite Take Action
Amazing movement (Jetta) God wills
Ostsagtha on its side?
(Gold medal went to (Jetta
Jetta) has achieved the impossible)
It is the first ever Indian wrestler
And the first to win the gold medal
cycle World Games
Who would have imagined that such a girl
, from a small village in India
You will be able to make their mark in this world
(Well done (Jetta
It's a proud moment for "India" without doubt
! O heroine
Where is my father?
I do not know
Came together despite this
Gold medal went
(Hindi (Jetta Bagot
and now, according to tradition
National anthem of the winner will be his playing
! Victory to India
Hey, what are you doing here?
(Come O (Jetta
media wait
! Come
Come on, everyone is waiting
! Come, come
Finally my uncle uttered those magic words
Nthrq that we were longing for
heard throughout the 10 years
! I'm proud of you
Translation Islam Geez!
Wei during the song finally there is information I recommend reading
Name: Mohammad Aamir Hussain Khan
Age: 51 years
"Has increased his weight so first lead role of" Father
, and after he had finished watching the entire cap of two girls
shooting  Has done severe diet to return again
body of the young man and the young period ended Sightseeing
The film won a very positive views of cash and evaluation 5 /
4.5 hailed by most of the artists, directors and even rivals
Hold a telephone, telephony everyone wary fierce
coming won the film a very positive views of cash and evaluation 5 / 4.5
praised by most of the artists, directors and even rivals
The film won a very positive views of cash and evaluation 5 /
4.5 hailed by most of the artists, directors and even rivals
"Whether you are a" Hinghar "or" Delhi
eclipse Txueq Oarzas film won a very positive and evaluation 5 / 4.5
views monetary praised by most of the artists, directors and even rivals
Said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love you personally hate professionally
"Whether you are a" Hinghar "or" Delhi
will Txueq ground
Wearing a T-shirt and shorts
Tell the hurricane Welcome
he said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love you personally hate professionally
He said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
Hold a telephone, telephony everyone wary fierce
said to come against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love you personally hate professionally
Stxueq land, a land Stxueq
said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love I personally hate professionally
He said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love you personally hate professionally
It's the power of the not insignificant
said against him (Salman Khan): "My family has to watch your movie night
" and they told me it was the best of my film "Sultan," I love you personally hate professionally
It is the power to be reckoned with
And reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
himself again for the fourth time in its history it
force to be reckoned with
Out to be reckoned
and reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
himself again for the fourth time in its history
And reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
It is the power to be reckoned with
and reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
himself again for the fourth time in its history
And reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
It is the power to be reckoned with
and reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
himself again for the fourth time in its history
And reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
It is the power to be reckoned with
and reap huge profits and the film is expected to break his record
himself again for the fourth time in its history
It is the power to be reckoned with
Unfortunately not overlooking us, but next year as a guest of honor of the film production
next film with giant (Amitabh Bachchan) two years from now it
force to be reckoned with
Unfortunately not overlooking us, but next year as a guest of honor of the film production
next film with giant (Amitabh Bachchan) two years from now
It's the power of the not insignificant
unfortunately not overlooking us, but next year as a guest of honor for a film of its production
next film with giant (Amitabh Bachchan) two years from now
Unfortunately not overlooking us, but next year as a guest of honor of the film production
It's the power of the not insignificant
unfortunately not overlooking us, but next year as a guest of honor for a film of its production
next film with giant (Amitabh Bachchan) two years from now
It is the power to be reckoned with
"Film is coming some (2018) or the name" cutthroat India
(based on the famous "Confessions of a serial killer" for the novel (Philip Taylor
They force to be reckoned with
"Film is coming some (2018) or the name" cutthroat India
(based on the famous "Confessions of a serial killer" for the novel (Philip Taylor
! What a Girl
"The film is coming some (2018) or the name" cutthroat India
(based on the famous "Confessions of a serial killer" for the novel (Philip Taylor
"Film is coming some (2018) or the name" cutthroat India
If you do not see the films before I advise him of these films
Pk - 3Idiots - Ghajini - Taare Zameen Par - Dhoom 3 - Fanna
Watch ye Gladiator Vsthrq G'rourk
fist ignite a fire if you do not see the films before I advise him of these films
Pk - 3Idiots - Ghajini - Taare Zameen Par - Dhoom 3 - Fanna
You will know your weaknesses will be received mass
If you do not see the films before I advise him of these films
Pk - 3Idiots - Ghajini - Taare Zameen Par - Dhoom 3 - Fanna
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez!
Wei will know your weaknesses will be received mass
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Will not pick yourself a moment
will not depart hit you glance
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Stxueq ground
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Oossalk will be kept and they fall apart pieces
I wish I could be gained satisfaction translator
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
The response attacked'll find them absolutely
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
! What a Girl
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
! What a Girl
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's the power of the not insignificant
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's the power of the not insignificant
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's the power of the not insignificant
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's the power of the not insignificant
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's the power of the not insignificant
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
It's utmost speed, and you do not have Nada
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Soon as it prepares to become (Jetta) leopards
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Before the fruit to fall from her tree
will have Obrank beat
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Eliminate all inevitably discount
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Blink of an eye, your order will end immediately
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Until the bullet is not in the speed of something
I wish I could be a translator gained satisfaction
.ooouselt part of the splendor of the film, Islam Geez! Wei
Until the bullet is not in the speed of something
! What a Girl
! What a girl
Wearing a T-shirt and shorts
Tell the hurricane Welcome
Hold a telephone, telephony everyone
wary fierce coming
It's the power of the not insignificant
It is the power to be reckoned with
:: Video Said WhatsApp 8 4 9 7 6 9 2 4 5 0 Taif ::
videoo_happy: to follow up on what is new follow us on: Alanstaqram
the seller and the translator is Msaliyn what you see, please be careful