Shashi... tea!
Sapna!
Give me my phone.
No...
What no... have your breakfast first...
Why don't you stop this white bread...
why can't you get brown!
Give it to me...
I like white blue red... anything.
No Maaji...
your porridge is ready.
Can I eat one parantha at least?
Mom... you've had enough
paranthas all your life...
it's time you had porridge now.
Shashi where's my parantha?
Hurry up please...
Sagar... your bournvita.
It's too white... make it brown!
Everyone wants only brown brown...
Mom look... thief!
One sweet ladoo mom!
OK my darling... have one.
You're sick...
you are going to
become a ladoo very soon.
Eat eat... eat more...
you all are going to die very soon.
Sapna quiet
you should eat what you like.
Exactly.
This new fad of brown bread...
egg whites...
all started since you
joined this new dance class...
that... that jhaaaz dance!
What's so funny?
I can't control it... it's too funny...
Mama... say... what dance? What class?
Which class?
Eat your omelette.
Where's the omelette?
There's only toast and parantha here.
Come on Dad...
let's do the jhaaaz dance!
Sapna... your omelette.
Mom it is not jhaaaz dance...
it is jazz dance.
Jaazz...
J...Jhazz...
Jaazzz... Jazz...
Aye careful... pack properly...
Ma'am... It has to be gipt packed?
Not 'gipt'... it's GIFT...
Gipt... gipt...
Never mind...
Satish... is the car free?
I have a lot of
orders for sweets today...
Why do you need to go? Send Ramu...
I need to go for a meeting...
Nice to see you Shashi...
The ladoos were
excellent the last time!
Thank you.
Come in...
Will need more ladoos
next week as well.
Give me one ladoo before she sees.
Next, Modern Colony.
Yes madam.
Hello... come in.
Sorry I'm a little late.
No problem at all.
Come... let's all taste the ladoos.
They are really excellent!
You've done a great job!
Excuse me.
Satish...
the ladoos were a super hit today!
Everyone loved...
I'm busy right now...
can we talk later please?
Sagar...
how many times have I told you...
not to do this.
What are you doing!
Where's Sapna?
First do that Michael Jackson thing.
Tell me.
First do!
First do! First do!
OK?
Where's Sapna?
She's gone to Rupal's house...
to study.
What exam?
Must he some test vest...
No test vest mama...
Cafe Coffee Day!
You've let out the secret...
what will Sapna do to you now?
She's gone to Cafe Coffee Day
with her friends...
she's having cold coffee.
Aren't you gotten angry?
Not 'gotten'...getting...
I am not getting angry...
what to do?
She's worn a really short skirt...
At least she has worn a skirt!
There are hoys with her too!
Lucky hoys!
You don't have a problem
with any of this?
I can't hear anything.
What?
There's some cold coffee
on your skirt.
Where have you been?
Studying.
With whom?
With Rupal.
Can't you study at home?
You think you can teach me...
English Literature?
Wow... great curry!
Thank god I didn't eat out...
Give me that chilly pickle...
Shashi...
you should stop making
those ladoos vadoos
I have just one passion...
you want me to give that up too?
Then give me...
one Shashi Special Ladoo!
Only I should eat your food...
why should others enjoy it?
If I didn't cook well...
you wouldn't even
bother to come home, right?
I've important
meetings to attend to...
these talks take time.
Talking to me is not important right?
Oh I forget...
'important talks'
happen only in English.
Why waste time talking?
No! No! No!
Dad how could you do this? Please!
Sapna...
What happened?
Hello.
Satish... What happened?
Why is Sapna yelling?
Shashi... I won't he able to go
to the PTA meeting.
How can you do this?
No wonder she is angry...
Told her you will go with her...
Me?
How can I...
What do you mean by how?
Aren't you a parent too?
What will I say there?
Don't be silly Shashi...
you're not going into a jungle...
it's a school...
they're not going to eat you up.
Now I have to go... bye
I will come with you...
There is no need...
I will tell them you're
ill and Dad's not in town.
Why ill? Tell them I'm dead.
Don't he dramatic mom.
Do you even know what PTA means?
No...
I may not know the meaning of PTA...
hut I certainly know
the meaning of a parent.
Now before I get really angry...
go get ready.
Which one is your classroom?
7A... this one?
Which one is your seat?
Not seat... desk... second last row.
You sit so far back?
It doesn't make a difference...
come on...
That's really far back...
Hi Sapna...
Hi Rupal!
Hello hello!
I'm Neelam...
commonly known as
Rupal's mother these days
I'm... Sapna mother... Shashi.
How nice to meet you Shashi.
But I have a hone to pick with you.
Every time that Rupal
comes to eat at your house
she comes back home and tells me
I have to learn how to cook from you.
No aunty... even your food is...
fantabulous!
What a sweet little liar.
But you must invite
me home soon Shashi...
then you and I can sit and
gossip about these Siamese twins.
Yes... yes aunty...
please come... anytime!
Mom, you wanted to use the loo right?
So nice to meet you Shashi.
Bye... see you soon.
What loo?
Come come come...
please sit inside...
I'll be just a minute...
Is this your English teacher?
Yes... Father Vincent...
my class teacher...
Yes Sapna...
How are you?
Mrs Godbole right?
Pleasure to meet you.
How's Mr Godbole?
Fine... very fine.
So... Sapna...
what should we start with?
As I had discussed with
Mr Godbole at the last PTA...
Sapna's performance
continues to be excellent...
Sir... sorry... father...
my English not good.
If you don't mind...
can we talk in Hindi?
Of course Mrs Godbole...
Hindi is our national Language...
we should all speak in it...
hut... my Hindi not very good...
is that okay?
No problem!
I am from Kottayam district you see...
Kottayam... that's in Kerala right?
It's famous for its
banana wafers right?
Do you like them?
Very much!
Next time I go I...
I'll bring back a big
packet of chips for you.
Is she doing well in her studies?
Of course...
she is one of the top
5 students of our class.
She could rank first...
if she showed more interest in Physics.
But is her English good?
Her English is excellent.
Mrs Godbole...
she is one of our brightest students.
But is she respectful?
Does everyone like her?
Sapna... you haven't told
your mum about your fan club?
Bu Mrs Godbole,
I wanted to talk to you about...
this inter-school quiz competition.
Sapna has been chosen...
Sapna has 'choosen' for the school...
been 'choosed'...
Has been chosen!
I warned you about my Hindi.
She will need to stay back
an extra hour in school...
for practice sessions...
Sir... I have already
spoken to my dad about this...
and there is no problem.
Yes hut you haven't
spoken to your mum...
Ma'am, I need your permission please.
Not a problem father...
our school must win.
Although the Coffee Day
business will suffer a hit.
Thank you Mrs Godbole...
I'll see you at the next PTA meeting?
And don't forget the banana chips.
Of course not...
Thank you sir.
Everything went well right?
Banana chips!
Is Father Vincent your uncle?
Father Vincent was so kind...
so polite...
he said something in jest...
and I went along with it.
He didn't seem to mind at all...
he made me feel so comfortable...
by talking in Hindi.
And you made him
feel so uncomfortable...
by talking in Hindi.
"Is Sapna a good girl...
does everyone love her"...
And why joke about Cafe Coffee Day...
Dad should have been there...
and you were talking in Hindi...
even to Rupal's mother.
Each time I had to answer for you.
What happened?
Failed her exams?
I'm the one who's failed.
Meaning?
I have embarrassed her today.
All teenagers feel their mom
and dad are an embarrassment.
Not mom and dad...
just mom.
Why are you so upset?
Tell me...
why did you marry me?
What can I say...
one look at you and I was hooked!
Isn't there any water?
Why didn't you marry a modern woman?
If I gave it so much thought
why would I get married at all...
It's a joke Shashi... come on...
What's come over you?
No matter how hard I try...
I just can't seem to please anyone.
Sapna's just a child.
And you?
Hello...
Manu!
Hi... how are you?
Yes I know you
sisters chat regularly...
but what about me.
So how is New York?
When are you coming to India?
Last time when you
came along with Radha...
what a wonderful time we had.
So how is...
Meera...?
What!
The date's been fixed?
Wedding in New York!
Speak to Shashi...
I can't believe it...
We're going to New York!
Can't sleep... so much noise...
Aye dumbo... wake up...
we're going to New York!
Manu aunty is
sending tickets for us...
so sweet of her... right mom?
Sorry mom...
forget about it please...
just forget it...
we are going to New York!
Not going to school?
Cousin Meera is getting married.
To an American in New York...
how cool!
It must be very cold there.
Mom... even it if was hot,
you couldn't come.
Why?
You don't have a passport.
You have to make a passport?
Yes you have to...
Tomorrow I'll start
the visa procedures...
first is yours...
since you need to leave before us.
And us?
We will go later.
Why?
I've told you...
I don't want to go alone
I'll come with you...
on the plane.
What's this alone valone?
You, Sagar and me
will travel together.
We will have great fun...
let mummy go ahead.
She needs to help
Manu aunty with the wedding...
really boring work.
We'll join them
later and just have fun.
What... no Dad!
What about your quiz competition?
You want to let your team down?
I don't have any quiz competition
I can go with mummy.
Fine... you'll he
thrown out of school...
you can sit at home and make ladoos.
What?
I've never travelled alone...
how will I manage?
What alone!
A hundred people will he
with you on the flight.
Let me take Sagar...
No it's not a good idea...
you won't be able to manage.
Don't I do it here?
But that's America...
it's a foreign land...
you can't even speak English well.
Will you he happy...
3 weeks without me?
Shashi If I was you...
I would he at the airport right now.
Maaji... how do I go?
It's a matter of a few days...
everyone will join you anyway.
She is your only sister...
she's all alone there...
first wedding in the family...
who else will she turn to for help?
And I'm here anyway...
Problem?
Yes... a really big problem.
Will you manage without me?
Yes... few Beyblades...
that Tron game...
Ben 10...
and many Hot Wheels cars...
if I get all this I will manage.
And how do you do that thing?
O my dear...
my heart doesn't heat without you.
My heart... it feels a twitch.
How do I go to a foreign land?
My heart...
My heart trembles... quivers
I am afraid.
O my dear...
my heart doesn't heat without you.
My heart... it feels a twitch.
How do I go to a foreign land?
Do you embrace
all your colleagues so fondly?
It was a hug Shashi.
Are the two of you very close?
That's just a way of saying hello...
it doesn't mean we are close.
Everybody hugs... it's normal!
We are close right...
maybe that's why we never hug!
Sometimes my heart heats faster.
My left eye flickers.
Will you forget me... I wonder
I know you through and through
I know you more than you.
Will your eye wander... I wonder.
So ma'am... what do you do?
Making... making snacks...
Snacks?
You know you are not
allowed to bring food articles
into the United States of America?
Food... food articles...
My English... weak...
So ma'am how will you
manage in our country...
if you don't know English?
Like you are managing in our
country without knowing Hindi!
These nights these days.
Your words and ways
I will miss them so...
Your slights and spite.
The way you hold me tight.
Makes me pine for more...
Why don't you stop me?
O don't let me go!
One mention of you...
I worry... I'm wary...
I think of you...
Mama come fast... it's late!
My heart...
My heart trembles... quivers
I am afraid.
Mom...
not possible to say goodbye
without crying in India, right?
She's crying so much.
Shashi...
when the immigration guys ask you...
"What is the purpose of your visit?"
what will you say?
"I am going to sister's
place to attend wedding."
Good!
And "What's the duration of
your stay?"
I am going to...
I am going to stay in
my sister's place...
Looks like you'll be sent right back!
Why?
Didn't I tell you... DURATION!
DURATION!
Sorry sorry...
5 weeks...
Let's go!
What are you doing?
If I hug it's a problem,
if I don't it's a problem!
New York...
window seat?
Don't they have this form in Hindi?
I can fill it out for you
America?
Yes... my niece is getting married.
All the best.
Open your hag...
no water allowed.
But it's a long journey...
You will get water inside.
Eatables are not allowed either.
Just one box?
Sorry ma'am...
Alright?
Satish... they took away
my water bottle...
I'm inside the plane...
is Sapna asleep?
Excuse me ma'am...
can you please turn
off your cell phone.
Sorry.
No it's fine... you can keep it.
Water...
You can ring the bell.
Can you get the lady
a glass of water please?
The next 18 hours...
this button is at your service.
You can...
confidently, definitely, surely
absolutely shamelessly
press this button again and again.
See... magic!
Ma'am, veg or non-veg?
Veg... veg...
Would you like some
Chardonnay or Merlot with your meal?
One glass of wine is good for health.
Cheers!
It's good stuff.
What's the matter?
Just one Hindi movie here...
I've seen it on TV.
And 50 English channels...
Here... look...
same picture...
same film...
there's no need for that
I need to talk to my father.
Captain, who bombed the train
I don't know who bombed the train.
Then go back and try again.
No! No! No!
Stop this cow dung...
Let's start with the bomb...
Excuse me...
are you a terrorist?
We are trying to sleep here...
I will go hut...
I am going to sister's
place to attend wedding...
Passport please...
Immigration form...
Please look into the camera ma'am.
Please look into the camera...
What is the purpose of your
visit to the United States?
What?
What... is... the... purpose... of...
your... visit... to the United States?
My sister is attending my wedding.
What?
Ah you're here to attend a wedding!
Yes.
Thank you.
- What is the purpose...
- To help the United States of America.
Sorry?
Yeah... you know...
to spend some dollars...
help recover your economy.
You don't want it? I can go back...
I am going to sister's
place to attend wedding!
- How dumb am I...
- Listen...
Don't let these people scare you...
it's time for them to get scared of us.
This is your first trip to the US...
and first times happen only once.
Every first experience is special...
so enjoy...
surely, definitely, confidently!
All the best!
Shashi aunty!
Mom... you've reached?
I'm in the car!
How are you?
The kids aren't
troubling you I hope...
Hi mama!
Sagar!
Aunty...
no more worrying about Sapna,
Sagar and uncle...
you're in New York...
we're going to have a blast!
New York has really
tall buildings, right?
Saw them from the plane...
Shashi... that's Manhattan...
Man... hat... tan?
'Man' means...
aadmi...
'Hat'...means
topi.
Mom... what's 'tan' in Hindi?
'Tan'...means...
dhoop ki chaap!
Aadmi... topi... dhoop ki chaap...
Manhattan! Tomorrow I'll take you.
Thank you Shashi...
Thank you...?
OK... welcome
I know it wasn't
easy for you to come...
hut who do I have except you.
It's been 10 years
since Anil passed away
I really miss him...
selfish fellow!
I have to do everything on my own now.
Manu...
I look at you and I feel so proud...
to think of where we started...
and where you are now!
Remember our Hindi medium school?
We couldn't speak a
single word of English...
not a word!
And look at you now...
you have a great
career here in America...
taken care of 2 girls all by yourself.
Anil... Anil...
If he hadn't motivated me...
I would have remained the same
I miss him so terribly...
hut thank god you're here!
Aunty this is gorgeous!
Wonderful choice Shashi!
Hat... man... with a tan
Manhattan.
Touching heaven, oh my god!
New avenues of joy.
Shops full of dreams.
A new surprise, at every stop.
To your left is Prada.
To your right is Zara.
Giorgio Armani,
Thank God it's Friday!
Gucci and Versace,
Jimmy Choo, Givenchy,
Diesel, Dior, Hokey Pokey,
Gap and Bloomingdale
Louis Vuitton.
Moschino
Valentino...
So much to say yet speechless.
All together, still alone.
What a city! Touch wood
5,6,7,8 avenues.
Million billion legs and shoes.
Lots of colours, dollars dollars
sense of pidlee poo.
Breakfast is for all day.
Straight and gay they all sway
and Lexington, and Madison,
it's all so ooh!
Frappuccino.
Mochaccino.
Cappuccino...
You gotto say balle
balle while you do that...
Balle balle balle balle!
Aunty... you're not eating
food's not good?
This parantha is really good...
It's Mexican food... Quesadilla...
Whatever it is... it's good!
What's that? What did she say?
She just abused you.
So tell me about the dowry,
what are you giving me?
- What am I giving you?
- We are not buying you...
that's not how it works.
The hoy gives the
girls family the dowry.
And lots and lots of gifts.
So I'm going to go broke?
I don't know why
hut I'm really sleepy.
Go sleep my dear...
Is that alright?
Yes of course
I feel so had...
she must he so tired.
Must be the jet lag.
Hello Satish...
how are the kids?
Have they gone to school?
Have they taken their lunch boxes?
Please do try to get home early...
I'm feeling a bit strange here...
without all of you...
Shashi... just enjoy yourself...
I'm getting into an elevator...
will talk later.
Slept well?
Sorry... got to go to office for a hit
I'll try to be back
as soon as possible...
we'll start on the wedding plans.
Drive carefully...
Bye darling, see you!
Good morning Aunty!
Should I make you some breakfast?
No I have cereal.
What are you going to do by yourself?
We do have Zee TV Hindi hut...
I have an idea,
why don't you come with me to college!
What will I do there?
I have class for 2 hours...
and you can hang out at a cafe...
and I'll come join you.
You got cash... change?
Yes.
And don't worry...
in case you get lost...
if you do get lost just call me.
Don't worry, go now.
The parks here are so beautiful...
Washington Square Park...
Washington... Square... Park...
Good!
Wow... that's a beautiful dress
you're wearing!
Man: This lady is so rude...
must be having a bad day.
Can I get a regular coffee...
and a blueberry muffin.
Here's your receipt...
please pick up your food over there...
Okay... have a nice day.
Next!
How you doing today ma'am?
I want...
I asked how you were doing today.
Doing... I'm doing...
I'm doing...
You can't take all that time
I got a long line here.
Sorry... what to eat?
Are you kidding me right now...
please hurry up lady.
Vegetarian...
Vegetarian is fine...
what do you want to eat?
Only vegetarian...
A bagel... a wrap... a sandwich?
Sandwich.
And what kind of
filling do you want inside?
Do you want cheese...
tomatoes... lettuce...?
Lady... you're holding up my line...
this is not rocket science.
Cheese?
Yes... cheese...
Yes to cheese!
Anything to drink?
Water...
Still or sparkling?
Only water.
Coffee...?
Americano? Cappuccino? Latte?
Lady... I ain't got all day...
'Nescoffee'
What?
Yes we have nice coffee...
we have the best coffee in Manhattan
I'll just give you an Americano.
Small or medium?
Small.
Small. Is that it?
$10.20
10 dollars...
Hello... the least you could do is
say thank you...!
Sorry... thank you...
Stupid idiot!
Sorry...
I am not cleaning that up!
Don't bother...
What a stupid woman.
Madam...
your coffee...
from the coffee shop.
Cafe not good...
woman... not nice!
Aunty!
Wait... I'm coming...
Be careful... such a big bus.
Learn to speak English in
four weeks... what a con!
Can anyone learn to speak
English in just four weeks?
Joke right?
Did you have fun today?
Please check the code and try again.
Shashi... Shashi...!
Sweetheart get me
that back up panditji
and those musicians?
We have to meet
the Hindu priest tomorrow
American Hindu priest?
No... they're all our people...
American Hindu Priest...
cool idea mom.
What do they chant at weddings?
'Om bhurbuvasvaha' what else...
No way... that's the Gayatri Mantra!
- Mom!
- I tried...
Will you meet the priest tomorrow?
- Yes definitely.
- He speaks in pure Hindi.
Keep this list of
phone numbers with you...
caterers, decorators, priest etc...
and just like you dial
the city code of '020' in Pune...
you will need to dial
the code '212' here.
Fabulous!
Such good food after so many years.
House keys...
in case you feel like stepping out.
The priest is here.
This is my younger sister Shashi...
you can discuss everything with her.
Sure.
Welcome to NYLC... how can I help you?
Hello...
English tuition?
Yes English classes.
Who am I speaking to?
What is your name please?
I...Shashi...
Sha... Shaashi...?
Well Shaashi what can I do for you?
How to... join class?
Well we have a 'LSE4'
class that starts today...
an 'LSE6' class starting next week...
and an 'LSE8' class
that starts next month...
LIC...?
Oh... sorry...
'LSE' is Learn to
speak English in 4 weeks...
'LSE6' is Learn to
speak English in 6 weeks...
Madam... sorry...
slow...
Sorry.
The 'Learn to Speak English 4' class
is a 4 week class...
and it starts today.
Today!
Money?
Oh you mean the fee.
It's 400 dollars
for the 4 week class
400?
Hello?
Welcome to NYLC...
how can I help you?
I Shashi...
address...?
If you are taking the train...
get off at the 23rd street station.
It's near the Flat Iron building...
23rd station... one ticket.
Wait...
Train...23rd station?
No no... on the other platform.
16th street?
After street no. 23, comes 24...
which means 16 is on that side...
numbers numbers everywhere...
M.G. Road... Laxmi road...
why can't they just
have names like that.
Sir...250 building?
Yes, this is it
English station... tuition?
English class?
Shaaashi...?
Welcome to the
"New York Language Centre".
Come in, come in...
take a seat.
My name is David... David Fischer...
and I'm your teacher.
Hello...
OK... let's continue...
I Eva...
I...come... Mexico...
I work like nanny
I work like nanny...
to American family
I speak Spanish...
the baby... speak Spanish.
The baby mama so worry
baby no speak English.
She say to me... go...
English class...
I... go... English class!
Eva my darling...
let's pray for the baby's future,
shall we?
I Queens...
How lovely!
No... no...
I live on the Queens.
You live in Queens, New York.
What is your name?
Salman Khan
I first from Lahore...
second from Pakistan.
I...
drive taxi...
New York cab.
But no Pakistani girl
marry taxi driver...
English please!
I here... come...
English learn...
become foreigner
Pakistani girl only marry foreigner
French heard, Johnny Depp...
Salman...
I wish you a beautiful Pakistani.
Girl sir... only girl.
How boring!
Moving on...
the gentleman from France.
Hello.
My name is Laurent...
French...
I'm cook...
in hotel...
and my English not clean...
dirty
I learn English...
good.
Good good!
Thank you Laurent...
And now the lady in
the gorgeous sari...
Sit...
Sit and talk?
I Shashi...
from the India.
From India...
Yes sir... from the India...
No Shashi... not from 'the' India...
from India!
And what do you do Shashi?
I also cooking...
cooking... selling...
Are you in the catering business?
Small business...
in house only...
making snacks...
ladoo!
Ladoo...?
Ladoo... round round...
It's a sweet...
We have an entrepreneur in the class!
Entrepreneur...
is a person who runs
his or her own business.
Shashi... you are an entrepreneur!
Is that a word or a poem?
What kind of a language is this!
Entre... pre... near.
Entrepreneur!
Shashi I'm home...
Where were you?
Just for a walk...
Why are you worrying so much?
You have 3 weeks of freedom left...
make the most of it.
You're having to do so much work...
Work? What work?
I'm making all of them work...
the perks of being old.
How is it going?
You know what they call me here?
Yes... Shaaashi.
No...
Entrepreneur!
Have you been making ladoos
for everyone there?
I thought we got disconnected.
Hello...
You want water?
Thank you...
Welcome.
That day...
very very had day.
Everything went wrong...
I feel... sorry...
Bad day!
Me not forget your face.
Your face.
Class... late!
Oh, yeah..
A...E... I... O... U...
These are called vowels.
Eva... Eva!
What are these called?
Vowels.
Just like bowels.
No Rama...
not like bowels!
Sorry madam...
sir... sorry sir...
I only saying for
remembering purpose...
towels...
bowels...
and... vowels!
Correct?
Now, when a word
begins with a vowel...
like apple...
begins with a vowel 'a'...
we say 'an' apple.
'An' orange...
'An' idiot.
So I...
an Eva?
No... if it's a name...
or a proper noun...
we just say Eva...
not an Eva...
or the India.
Okay?
Just Eva... just Rama.
Yes Shashi?
Why India not 'the India'
and why America
"the United States of America"?
That is a very good question Shashi...
and we will come to that once
we do the class on
the various forms of nouns.
What a question you asked madam!
David sir had no answer...
full confusion.
Good question...
Very smart...
Sleeping again.
We are smarter than these people...
we struggle only because
of this bloody English...
else we would have blown them away.
What you say?
I say I come to your parlour...
you give me free hair cut...
and I teach you free Urdu.
You come to parlour...
I shave your head!
Spicy noodle...
just like dragon!
Excuse me...
hello...
what is good name?
What did he say?
Strange fellow... weird fellow...
Did you speak in English or in Tamil?
You ask good question.
Good?
Very good.
Thank you.
Ask question... me?
You? Me?
Yes!
OK!
Cup of coffee...
with me... now?
House...
me... coffee...
bye!
- Yeah, bye.
- See you. Bye.
Coffee-Voffee Sugar-Vugar.
Paper-Vaper News-Vews.
Clock-Vok Time-Vime.
Run-Vun Run-Vun.
Train-Vain Pass-Vass.
Late-Vate Class-Vass.
Friendship-Vendship Bonding-Vonding
I've changed my point of view.
Everything around is new
I'm happy-vappy why, oh why?
I'm busy-vusy that's why!
Slowly, slowly, steadily
I'm learning-vearning a new language.
Extraordinary!
This passion!
Morning noon!
Extraordinary!
This passion!
Morning noon!
It's all about English Vinglish!
Morning noon English Vinglish!
- Good morning.
Breakfast is ready!
I've taken the day off.
How do I go to class today?
Why did you take the day off for me?
You'll need to take leave
for the wedding too...
What do you mean?
I haven't spent any time with you...
we have so much to catch up on.
Remember the necklace
Anil's mother had given me?
I've divided them equally,
one for Meera...
and one for Radha.
What a beautiful bracelet I found...
what are you looking for?
Meera says it's too expensive...
Do you remember our aunt in Pune?
She told me to meet the Panditji...
Panditji...
I mean... catering...
you need to meet
the catering people...
they've called so many times.
Oh god I totally forgot.
Meet them today.
Let's go together.
Let's get dressed quickly...
we'll meet Radha and
do lunch after that.
What's wrong?
Suddenly got a splitting headache...
Need some medicine?
No... I should he fine
if I sleep for a hit...
why don't you go ahead?
But Shashi...
Manu... it's important...
you may not get the time later.
Please... you must go...
Only if you promise to sleep.
Say it with me...
who is the star?
I am the star...
No... I'm the star...
Sorry...
sorry sir... late...
What have you been cooking?
No cooking... late...
Come in...?
You may not...
Ask again Shashi.
Come in?
I can't see you...
are you asking me to come in?
I can come in?
You can... the door is wide enough...
hut you may not!
Why?
Shashi... you need to ask...
'may I come in?'
Sorry...
May I come in?
You may!
May I sit down?
You may.
- What is May.
- May?
May I send this back to India?
May I go home now?
May I give lift to you?
May I give slap to you?
May I have a coffee with you?
Not today...
No? OK...
May I have a walk with you?
Your food...
No...
you cooking hotel... expert...
I'm...
in house cooking...
very small.
No...
not small...
food is...
food is art...
When a man cooks, it's art...
when a woman cooks, it's her duty.
What did you just say?
I'm sorry...
Man cooking... art.
Lady cooking...
daily job... duty!
No...
Food is...
love.
You cooking with love, good food.
You make people happy.
You artiste!
Not small...
You must open restaurant here...
in New York!
No... you open.
Maybe... one day...
French-Indian restaurant!
French...
you make... pasta shaasta...?
No...
Pasta is Italian food.
Oh French, Italian not same?
No... no way!
For example...
this white thing?
That's lasoon...(Garlic)
Italian food lasoon everywhere
French food... not everywhere.
You put lasoon in ladoos?
No!
Sugar...
sweet sweet...
Dessert!
You bring me sweet ladoos?
OK!
You want ticket?
L-A-S-O-O-N
L-A-D-O-O
White ladoo.
Big white ladoo.
You stay here?
No...
Near?
This not your station?
No...
opposite side...
train... back... other side...
Back?
I go...
Bye.
Shashi...
Hope she's ok...
You're back?
How are you feeling?
Much better.
Sorry we're late.
Come let's eat something...
Indian kitchen... good evening...
Was he Italian or French?
Promise me you won't tell anyone?
What can I order for dessert?
What happened?
Mom... I saw a rat...
a really big rat...
And it went that way!
I'll just get the stick
English classes!
That's awesome!
Very very happy to meet you!
Nice to meet you.
Shashi madam...
let us all bunk and go for movie.
'A' movie...
Yes David Sir is absent today.
Even that Africa is sick madam...
bunking fellow.
Let us all go for a fine film.
No fine film... English film!
Obviously we'll watch an English film...
not Chinese.
We will all go watch English movie.
You want to join us?
No... no...
Madam you come please...
I buy popcorn
I have class.
Unfortunately my teacher
hasn't fallen sick...
I gotto go.
Aunty... you must go...
I'll see you after class... bye!
Bye Radha!
What he say?
He say... all you need is love...
everyone should love...
and kiss people on
your right hand side.
Salman...
shut up!
Wonderful movie no madam?
Good? You like it?
So much love... beautiful.
Shashi... you like the movie?
Good English practice...
Yeah...
Yeah... good English practice...
- One second.
- No problem.
Hello?
Where the hell is my scrapbook?
I'm sure you've kept it somewhere...
tell me quick.
Sapna... why are you yelling?
Where is it?
Why don't you calm down.
How do I calm down mom?
Why do you touch my things?
How many times have I told
you not to touch my things!
Check the second
shelf in your cupboard...
it's safely tucked
away under your pyjamas
so that no one reads it...
I didn't read it either.
That's because you can't read...
All ok?
What right do children have...
to treat their parents like this?
They don't even know
the meaning of respect!
Am I a trash can...
to dump in whatever they feel like?
What kind of a relationship is this?
We do our best to make them happy...
and how easily they hurt you in return.
Kids are supposed to be innocent...
what kind of innocence is this...
taking advantage of our weakness...
You can teach everything...
hut how do you teach someone...
to be sensitive to others?
I will have a cafe latte...
a double cheese vegetable sandwich
and a glass of iced water please.
And you sir?
Cappuccino please...
Small.
Shashi...
you see?
What?
You order...
perfect.
You order... correct English.
Now?
All... ice water...
Yes... you did it!
I did it!
Good to talk... without understanding!
Sometimes better.
What a feeling!
I walk carefree!
Don't ask me to stop.
Just let me go on
I have no fear
I have no worry
I hope I don't lose my way.
If I do... may the road find me!
Don't make me stop!
I've changed my point of view.
Everything around is new
I'm happy-vappy why oh why?
I'm busy-vusy that is why!
Extraordinary!
This passion!
Morning noon!
Extraordinary!
This passion!
Morning noon!
It's all about English Vinglish!
Coffee-Voffee Sugar-Vugar.
Paper-Vaper News-Vews.
Manu, I was thinking...
this buffet system...
standing and
eating with plates in hand
is so uncomfortable.
If we're doing it
all in Indian style...
then we should serve
food while they're seated.
Excellent idea!
And something for shagun...
Shagun... what's that?
A small gift for
the guests at the wedding...
Gift? Shouldn't
we he receiving the gifts?
I mean 'return gift'...
in the form of sweets
to be given to guests
I'll need to order that.
No order vorder... I'll make it myself!
Really?
What was that?
Kevin... we were just discussing
how much gold you need to buy us...
lots and lots of kilograms of gold.
You hear?
Sir David and boyfriend break up!
Sir David very sad
I know.
Nothing sad about gay
people breaking up...
drop one and pick another!
Salman... don't say that.
No making fun...
We are all different from each other.
For you...
David Sir may not he 'normal'...
for David Sir...
you may not he 'normal'...
hut feelings are all the same...
and pain is pain...
What she say?
She say David sir different for you...
you different for David sir...
hut heart pain same same.
Sorry madam...
Who is this fellow?
Who break David Sir?
Boyfriend.
Heart fracture.
Hello... I'm back.
Today we are going to talk...
communicate...
express... share...
what we think... what we feel...
about life...
about this city...
this class!
Rama... you have something to say?
Sir... I have lot to say...
I have 'a' lot to say...
Yes Sir...
My...
My deepest feeling...
is to teach them such a lesson
such a lesson...
Who Rama?
Oh sorry...
I want to teach
the office peoples big lesson.
They're thinking... no...
he's a idiot...
only knowing the software.
Making fun of my behind
of my English.
But now I will show them
that Ramamurthy is Mr Ramamurthy!
I will show them what I can do!
America big place...
beautiful place
I missing two things very terribly
my idli (rice cake) and my mother...
my mother then my idli...
Please sit down!
English class become one big family.
No border problem...
Salman bhai, Rama bhai,
we're brothers.
Aunty...
Eva my white sister...
Shashi madam, my Indian sister...
and Yu Son my yellow...
sorry.
Yu Son not sister...
Yu Son not yellow...
Yu Son pink...
Yu Son beautiful...
Yu Son my friend, my best friend.
Udum... Udumhuhke...
can we hear your voice please?
Me...?
He talks also?
I like this class
I come this class to listen English...
I don't talk much...
I want to listen people talk...
and...
I also...
gay.
Another one!
Bravo! Very good!
OK... who is next?
Laurent my love come up
here and give us a speech.
No sir...
I don't like speech...
Fine fine...
Tell us what you like about the class?
Shashi!
I agree...
but what do you like about Shashi?
She is very beautiful...
her eyes are like
two drops of coffee...
on a cloud of milk
I come to class...
so I can see her.
So Shashi... beautiful eh?
Luaro... what you're doing in
class today not correct...
Laurent... all women not French!
Indian woman! Show the respects!
We don't flirts in the open
spaces in front of publics.
What I do?
Not what I do... what I did!
He will need a two year course...
I am very sorry...
Shashi...
I'm very sorry you know.
First time I see you in
the cafe, you remember?
I think beautiful...
I say beautiful...
It's been ages since someone...
said something nice about me
I was just taken aback... that's all.
See you tomorrow.
What is the matter with you?
Why are you being so judge...
judgemental...
You're so judgemental...
mental?
Radha...
sorry Radha...
I had a doubt...
I was watching this film...
this man keeps calling
this woman 'judgemental'
She seemed fine to me...
why was he calling her that?
What does 'judgemental' mean?
Mental judge?
Aunty!
You're too funny.
'Judgemental' means...
You're wearing
a traditional outfit... a sari.
Just by looking at you...
without thinking...
without understanding...
without knowing you...
if I were to conclude...
that you are a typical
Indian conservative woman...
when in reality
actually...
you're a free thinking woman
then I would he called...
'judgemental'!
Judgemental...
Aunty...
you want to learn
so much English so fast?
I have very little time Radha...
Can I have more DVDs?
Idli (rice cakes) and chutney!
Thank you madam!
Rama... control your excitement
I am still here.
Idli also here sir.
Oh that's idli... looks delicious.
Now... we have one week left to go.
And... on the last day
you will have to take
an examination!
Each one of you will need
to prepare a 5 minute speech.
A full 5-minute speech?
English Rama please...
You have to pass this exam
before I can give you...
a certificate that
tells the world you are
qualified to communicate in English!
Don't look so sad.
You will all be wonderful
I'm sure you will all
pass with flying colours.
Good luck!
Rama bhai...
no certificate
unless you pass the exam!
Sir... when is exam?
The 28th...
28th...
28th... that's the day of the wedding!
Where is the time to
prepare for speech...
no 'the' speech.
How to do... how to do...
between waxing and hair cut?
You will have to talk very
much now Mr Udumhudum...
Udumhke.
You ok?
All ok?
28th exam...
same day wedding!
Don't know...
I didn't...!
It's ok... we go up and come down.
Wait... wait...
want to see something?
What?
Come.
Beautiful!
Yes.
You alright?
Shashi!
Errant heart.
Heart's in trouble.
There is trouble in the heart.
Errant heart.
A hit hard.
A hit of a coward.
Why do you stop at
the doorway of pain?
Why do you put
yourself on trial each time?
Why do you laugh when you want to cry?
You fail to decide
between right and wrong.
Errant heart.
Heart's in trouble.
There is trouble in the heart.
Errant heart.
Your breath is freezing cold.
Your eyes are full of smoke.
Your constant gamble of joy and pain.
Your eternal sense of hope.
Your fear of yourself.
Why do you complicate
an uncomplicated journey?
Why do you not
listen to your own advice?
Errant heart.
Mama!
Surprise!
Shocked right?
You were to come next week...
It was Manu's idea to surprise you.
We had to plan so carefully...
to keep it a secret from you.
Didn't even tell Radha...
that broadcast channel.
Everyone's been waiting for you...
where did you disappear?
Mama... I had 5 packets of chips...
7 cokes...
3 movies!
And what about your
15 visits to the loo!
Do you want coffee, Shashi?
Errant heart.
Heart's in trouble.
There is trouble in the heart.
Errant heart.
A hit hard.
A hit of a coward.
You go everywhere on your own?
Not had.
Even those who know English...
find it difficult here in New York...
hut you are managing on your own...
amazing!
You managed there on your own too...
didn't you?
Barely...
Mama... I can't sleep...
what do I do?
Come to mama.
You take care of him now...
I'm on holiday.
Sleep my darling...
my baby...
my ladoo...
Shashi... tea!
Please pose.
OK good.
See...
see over there...
Jhaaz! Jhaaz! Jhaaaz!
Not jazz... jhaaz!
And next we go to the Empire state.
Empire State! I want to see it!
I want to see Empire!
We'll all see Empire.
You people go ahead...
I'll stay here...
mama's legs are really aching.
No mama... you have to come.
It will be very crowded there.
And if your legs hurt...
not a good idea...
there will he really long lines.
We will go ahead...
you just chill.
No!
Sagar you know what...
there is this awesome ice cream place.
It's called Cold Stone.
Do you know what they do...
they take a stone and
heat up the ice cream...
then they add gummy hears and
chocolate chips and heat it up again.
Come let's go beat up the ice cream!
Come let's go!
Satish uncle let's go...
Shashi... wait
I cook French dessert...
crepe...
you try, you tell me...
Why don't you leave me alone!
Don't you know...
I'm a married woman.
I'm a mother of two children.
Do you know...
they are all waiting for me
at the Empire State Building.
So tell me...
should I sit here
with you on the sidewalk
and eat French fries
or should I go to my family?
Shashi...
What?
The Empire state building...
is this way...
French fries is not French...
it's an American concept.
This is French ladoo...
with organic chocolate 70 %
you can make it warm if you want.
Mama!
Sagar...!
What happened?!
He got in the way of the hall...
I'll go get some water...
- Mama...!
- How did it happen?
Where's mom?
Are you hurt anywhere else?
Can you please call Shashi Radha?
Mom's phone is with me!
Where is Shashi?
Where did she disappear?
OK come let's go...
let's take care of Sagar first...
and I will come back for aunty.
Brave boy... you'll be ok!
Mama... do you know what happened?
Big hall came...
and I fell
I didn't see the hall coming...
otherwise... one kick!
Liar...
Nothing happened...
just a little scratch...
and look at him now... fuss pot!
Sagar is a strong hoy
have a cookie...
drink your milk...
One magic kiss from
mama and all will be well.
How's the pain in your leg?
You must have been in a lot of
pain... to not come with us...
hut take off by yourself.
If you don't like
being with us anymore...
you should have told us...
we wouldn't have come here.
Satish... what are you saying...
What do you mean...'what'?
What's happened to you Shashi?
It looks like you were happier alone
I was just...
Thank god I didn't send
the kids earlier with you.
That's it!
Enough of this English!
What's happened to me?
English has become more
important than my children!
Aunty nothing happened...
Sagar is fine.
No Radha...
I should have come along with you all
I have become so selfish...
I have forgotten my responsibilities
I didn't come here to learn English.
Enough! I'm done with
this English Vinglish!
Aunty don't do that...
don't give up now.
Just 3-4 classes left to go...
What more will I learn in 3-4 days?
Please inform them...
I'm quitting.
Aunty... please...
just finish what you started...!
You should finish
what you started right?
I want to finish...
what I started long ago...
being a mother to my children
I am looking for Professor David.
Right here!
Hi, I'm David...
Hi... I'm Radha, Shashi's niece.
This is Shashi's niece...
so good to meet you
I have some had news for you.
Shashi's not gonna he able
to make it to class anymore.
No... she has to take her exam!
I know... her family has
come down from India...
and we're busy with
my sister's wedding...
I'll give you my card...
you have her call me.
Bonjour!
How are you?
Radha...?
Shashi here?
No she isn't here...
I came to talk to David about it...
she's not going to
take class any more...
Why? Exam very important for Shashi
I know... my sister is
getting married and...
her family has come down from India,
so unfortunately...
Can I ask for telephone number?
Ladoo sampling!
- Kevin... try one...
- Thank you...
This is incredible...
I could get married
again and again for this.
To you... to you... again and again.
Wow...! Shashi Aunty it's amazing!
You know Kevin... these are
the best ladoos you will ever eat
I totally agree.
And my wife,
she was horn to make ladoos...
I just gave you a compliment...
you were horn to make ladoos!
Manu... we can put marigolds here...
and jasmine there...
and the other flower arrangements...
Mama... Jose is calling you...
Aunty... you were not
horn only to make ladoos.
Sagar come here...
Salman why don't you tell me
the story of your favourite film.
My favourite movie is...
Sex and City.
It is story of 4 sexy girls...
talking of sex and
walking on the city.
Very pretty.
Sir... I like the Rajnikanth film
very very much.
Rajnikanth is not a actor...
he's a god!
He can remove
the underwear of the superman...
he can catch a bullet with his nose...
Granny... I will dance to
the 'dhinka chika' song.
Sagar... dance to this song instead...
What a boring song!
Sagar it's awesome!
Sapna, come with me!
My sweet pampered favourite bride.
She loves and desires the moon.
My God given blessed child.
Angelic beauty of the Gods
I hope to see
my favourite student tomorrow...
Trying... David sir...
No trying vying Shashi.
Taking an exam is not
a matter of life and death...
it's about the joy of telling
yourself that you have done it.
Shashi madam...
last day of class...
we really miss you.
Speech ready no madam?
Coming tomorrow no madam?
The wedding is tomorrow...
afternoon...
No problem madam!
Tomorrow exam morning...
1 hour exam...
like that only you come...
like that only you go!
Shashi please come
I am failing tomorrow and I am here.
Shashi you must come...
One cup of coffee maybe?
Aunty... he really likes you!
Do you also...?
It's ok... it happens...
Radha...
I don't need love...
what I really need is...
some respect!
Will you help me...
one last time?
I want to take the exam tomorrow.
O listen... take care of her.
She is delicate blossom.
She is precious.
She is a rare one.
Come all dance along.
Let's drown in joy.
To this happy song.
Her eyes... they speak.
They tease... they sneak
into the world of dreams.
All bright and gold and green!
Here goes the shy blushing bride.
She sways to her beloved's charms.
Magic in her dark kohl eyes
I come to America...
I want to learn English...
To get a better job...
I want to learn better English...
to become the better person...
I can then go to college...
I didn't know why
I wanted to learn English...
Pakistani girl Chinese girl...
No... come tomorrow
I teach all America Spanish!
Where's Shashi?
The ladoos have to be taken out...
need to he gift wrapped.
Chill mom... people are going
to love the ladoo gift pack.
Shashi aunty is amazing.
- I wish mom had some of that talent.
- Yeah right!
Who do you fancy...
American guys or Indian?
Crap it's your mum...!
Chill... she won't understand.
So what's your boyfriend's name?
I don't have one... do you?
No...
Aunty its already 8.30.
Don't forget...
we need to go to the beauty salon.
Let me help you with that.
Bring the other tray.
Manu aunty... come quickly!
Where is Sagar?
Aunty... we can buy them
on the way back...
Yes Shashi...
there's an Indian
sweet shop near by...
don't worry...
Now no one will get to
taste Aunty's ladoos!
Come here.
How many times have
I told you to behave?
Didn't I warn you?
Will you do it again?
Will you?
Stop it
I will make fresh ladoos again...
All over again?
All that trouble again Shashi!
Yes...
I will.
Excuse me...
please help me with that...
Satish... I'll get it done.
It's ok... what to do!
Aunty...
we need to leave...
What's the point
if I fail in my favourite subject...
and pass in the other?
Satish look after them...
I've heard so much about
your wife's food... Iadoos?
She loves cooking...
And I love eating!
Thank you for coming.
Congratulations!
Hi Radha!
- Hi.
- I bought flower.
Thank you.
Yu Son!
Hello!
You are looking very... correct!
Thank you very very much
for calling us to come.
Can't understand
how he got through the English exam.
Where is Shashi?
Shashi aunty is getting ready...
May I go helping?
No, she'll be here soon... thank you
God knows how she also
got through the exam.
What you say?
I say I love you.
Shashi! Oh you look so beautiful!
Shashi madam... we missed you today.
What a speech I gave...
What a speech!
I not understand one word.
Rama bhai also... superb English!
Don't call me Rama bhai...
that is my servant's name in India!
Oh Shashi you look so beautiful...
Thank you... you too!
David sir!
Thank god Radha invited
all of us to the wedding
I couldn't let you
leave without meeting me.
Thank you so much for coming.
Shashi... what are you doing?
The wedding is about to begin...
Satish uncle...
Satish... this is David Sir...
Udumhke...
Eva...
Salman... Yu Son...
- Ramamurthy...
- Nice to meet you.
Laurent...
Nice to meet you.
They are my close friends.
Shashi, it's time for the ceremony.
To my darling daughter
Meera and my dear son Kevin...
How I wish Anil was here.
When Meera was going
through her troubled teens...
she was 14...
she was only 14 years old...
when she came in
fuming and asked us...
'Why did you give birth to me?'
She was so angry with life...
that she was furious
that we gave birth to her
without asking for her permission!
I will answer that today Meera.
You were horn...
so your dad and I could
share complete happiness.
"You were horn so you could
bring happiness into our lives..."
I am so sorry I didn't
take your permission.
Love you both sweethearts!
God bless both of you always.
Son... you just got lucky!
But fortune smiles on those
who embrace it's offerings...
so... love each other.
And son...
leave me and your mother alone!
It's time for us
to focus on each other.
Shashi Aunty... your turn.
Yes... come on.
Aunty.
Sorry... my wife's English is...
not very good so...
May I?
Meera...
Kevin...
this marriage is a...
Oops sorry... I started in Hindi.
This marriage is a
beautiful thing.
It is the most
special friendship...
friendship of two people
who are equal.
Life is a long journey.
Meera, sometimes you will feel
you are less
Kevin, sometimes you will also
feel you are less than Meera.
Try to help each other
to feel equal.
It will he nice.
Sometimes...
married couple don't even know
how the other is feeling.
So... how they will help the other?
It means marriage is finished?
No.
That is the time
you have to help yourself.
Nobody can help you better than you.
If you do that...
you will return back feeling equal
your friendship will return back...
your life will be beautiful.
Meera... Kevin...
maybe you'll very busy...
hut have family...
son... daughter...
in this big world...
your small little world.
It will make you feel so good.
Family...
family can never he...
never he judgemental!
Family will never...
put you down...
will never make you feel small.
Family is the only one
who will never laugh
at your weaknesses.
Family is the only place
where you will always get
love and respect.
That's all Meera and Kevin...
I wish you all the best.
Thank you.
Well Shashi...
you don't 'return back',
you just return...
and you missed a few
'a's and 'the's...
else you passed with distinction!
Shashi aunty you were amazing!
Yes... I'm so proud of you.
Do you want me to help?
Bring the other tray.
Next time you speak in
English in front of mama...
please think...
she can talk better than you!
David Sir... ladoo!
Thank you...
I have something for you!
When you don't like yourself...
you tend to dislike
everything connected to you.
New things seem to be more attractive.
When you learn to love yourself...
then the same old life...
starts looking new...
starts looking nice.
Thank you...
for teaching me...
how to love myself!
Thank you for making me...
feel good about myself.
Thank you so much!
Ladoo...
Broke the French heart, didn't you?
Shashi...
Do you...
still love me?
If I didn't...
why would I give you two ladoos?
And...
good choice!
Her eyes... they speak.
They tease... they sneak
into the world of dreams.
All bright and gold and green!
Here goes the shy blushing bride.
She sways to her beloved's charms.
Magic in her dark kohl eyes.
What newspaper would you like sir?
New York Times please.
And you ma'am?
The New York...
sorry... do you have
any Hindi newspaper?
No, sorry.
It's ok... thank you.