sync by airsubs
The world of investing...
..can be a jungle.
Bulls. Bears.
Danger at every turn.
That’s why, we at Stratton Oakmont
pride ourselves, on being the best.
Trained professionals, to guide you through
the financial wilderness.
Stratton Oakmont.
Stabilty.
Integrity.
Pride.
One.
Two..Three!
Twenty five grand to the first cocksucker
to nail a bullseye!
Come on, let's go!
One.
Two..
..Three!
My name is Jordan Belfort.
Not him,
Me. That's right.
I’m a former member of the middle class,
raised by two accountants in a tiny
apartment in Bayside, Queens.
The year I turned 26, as the head of
my own brokerage firm,
I made 49 million dollars.
Which really pissed me off
because it was three shy of a million a week.
No..no..no, my Ferrari was white.
Like Don Johnson’s in Miami Vice.
Not red.
See that, humongous estate down there?
That’s my house.
My wife, Naomi.
The Duchess of Bay Ridge, Brooklyn.
A former model and Miller Lite girl.
Yeah, she was the one with my cock
in her mouth in the Ferrari,
So, put your dick back in your pants.
In addition to Naomi and my
two perfect kids,
I own a mansion, private jet, six cars,
three horses,
two vacation homes and a
170 foot yacht.
I also gamble like a degenerate,
drink like a fish,
I fuck hookers maybe
five-six times a week,
I have three different Federal agencies
looking to indict me. Oh yeah..
...and I love drugs.
Pull up..Pull up!
We’re gonna crash!!
For Christ's sake! Pull up!
Juuusss..Relax.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, i'm alright.
Good job.
You get in there safe, alright?
Next time, brahther.
Till next time.
Yep, on a daily basis
I consume enough drugs,
to sedate Manhattan,
Long Island...
..and Queens.
For a month.
- Okay, Mr.Jordan.
I take Quaaludes, ten to fifteen times
a day. For my back pain.
Adderall to stay focus.
Xanax to take the edge off, pot to mellow out,
cocaine to wake back up again and morphine well..
because it’s awesome.
Mornin' Blake.
But of all the drugs
under God’s blue heaven,
there’s one that’s
my absolute favorite.
See...
enough of this shit’ll make
you invincible,
able to conquer the world
and eviscerate your enemies.
And, I’m not talking about this.
I’m talking about this.
See, Money doesn’t just buy you
a better life --
better food, better cars,
better pussy --
it also makes you a better person.
You can give generously to the church
or political party of your choice.
You can save the fucking spotted
owl with money.
I've always wanted to be rich.
So, let me go back.
I'm 22 years old. Newly married
and already a money crazed little shit.
So, what do I do?
I go to the one place on earth
that befit my high minded ambitions.
JERRY FOGEL: You are lower than pond scum.
You got a problem with that?
Jordan?
No.
No problem at all.
- Good, because that is what you are.
Pond scum.
Your job is ‘connector’, which means...
that you'll be dialing the phone
over 500 times a day,
trying to ‘connect’ me
with wealthy business owners.
And, till you pass your Series 7,
that is all you’re gonna fucking be doing.
Sit. Sit!
Just so you know, last year
I made over 300 thousand dollars.
The other guy you'll be working for,
he made over a million.
A million dollars?
I could only imagine what a douchebag
that guy must be.
Jordan Belfort?
- Yes, sir.
Mark Hanna.
- A pleasure to meet you.
And, you as well. I see,
you've already met the village asshole.
Smile and dial.
And don’t pick your
fucking head up till one.
Hey, fuck him.
I'm senior broker here,
he's just a worthless piker.
Why don't you blow me, Hannah.
Now, Did you really pitched stock..
in your job interview?
I had to do something to stand out.
Right, Sir.
I fuckin’ love that!
Lunch, today.
- Yeah.
We don't start dialing at 9:30
Because,
our clients are already
answering the phone!
Three, two..
one..Let’s fuck!!
You want to know
what money sounds like?
Go to a trading floor on Wall Street.
Fuck this, shit that.
Cunt, cock, asshole.
I couldn’t believe how these guys
talked to each other.
I was hooked within seconds.
It was like mainlining adrenaline.
Fourty, Pick up the cocksuckin' phone!
- Sorry..
You're such a fuckin' deouchbag, Hanna.
- We don't give two shits about..
'How' technology works.
Because, all we care about is
getting fuckin' rich!
Jordan Belfort..
- Solid..two thousand.
Done!
Time to paint the tape.
Whooow! Two thousand, Microsoft.
Going in the hole!
C'mon.
The pole man is alive.
Alive. Hold on to that, it's hot.
Shut that motherfucker.
Shut it..shut it. Shut it!
Sold!
Tootski?
No. Thank you, though.
Mr. Hanna, what can I bring for you
on this glorious afternoon?
Well, Hector, here’s the game plan.
You're gonna nring us two Absolut Martinis,
You know how I like 'em, straight up.
And then, Precisely seven and one
half minutes after that,
You're gonna nring us two more,
and then..
two more after that every five minutes,
until one of us passes the fuck out.
An excellent strategy, Sir?
I’m good with water for now,
though thank you.
It's his first day on Wall Street,
Give him time.
Thank you.
- Mmhmm.
Mr.Hanna..
You're able to..
..do drugs during the day
and still function and do your job?
How the fuck else would you do this job?
Cocaine and hookers, my friend.
Right.
I gotta say, I’m incredibly excited
about being part of your firm.
The clients you have are absolutely..
- Fuck the clients.
Your only responsibility is to put
mean on the table.
You got a girlfriend?
- I am married.
My wife, her name is Teresa.
She cuts hair.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Think about Teresa.
Name of the game?
Move the money from your client's pocket.
Into your pocket.
- Right.
But, if you can make the clients money,
at the same time.
It advantageous to everyone.
Correct?
No.
Number one rule of Wall Street.
Nobody --
okay, if you’re Warren Buffet
or Jimmy Buffet.
Nobody knows, if a stock’s gonna go up,
down, sideways or fucking circles.
Least of all stock brokers.
It's all a Fughazi.
You know what a fughazi is?
Fugazi it's a fake..
Yeah, Fugazi, Fughazi.
It's a wazi, it's a woozi...
..fairy dust.
It doesn't exist. It never landed.
It is no matter.
It's not in the elemental chart.
It's not fucking real!
Stay with me.
- Mmhmm.
We don't create shit.
We don't build anything.
So, you got a client.
Who bought stock at eight.
And, announces it sixteen.
He's all fucking happy,
He wants to cash in, liquidate.
Take his fucking money and run home.
You don't let him do that.
Cos, that would make it real.
- Right.
What do you do?
You get another brilliant idea.
A special Idea.
Another situation.
Another stock.
To reinvest his earnings
and then, some.
And, he will. Every single time.
Cos, they're fuckin' addicted.
And, then..you just keep doing this.
Again and again.
..and again.
Meanwhile..
He thinks, he is gettin' shit rich.
Which he is...On paper.
But, you and me.
The brokers..
we are taking home cold hard cash via.
Commission, motherfucker!
Right.
That's incredible Sir.
I can't tell you, how excited I am.
- You should be.
There's two keys,
to sucess,
in the broker business.
First of all,
You gotta stay relax.
You jerk off?
Do I jerk off? Yeah,Yeah,
I jerk off..yeah.
How many times a week?
Like, uhm..three four times, maybe.
Pump those numbers up.
Those are rookies number in this racket.
I myself, I jerk off at least..
twice a day.
- Wow!
Once in the morning,
right after I work out.
And, then once, right after lunch.
- Really?
I want to.
That's not why I do it.
I do it, cos i fucking need to.
Think about it.
You're dealing with numbers.
All day long.
Decimal points..high frequencies.
Bang, bang bang. Iek, iek eik..
Fucking digits!
Ke, ke..ke ke..
All very acidic,
above the shoulders,
mustered shit.
Alright?
That kind can weaken some people up.
Right?
You gotta feed the geese.
Keep the blood flowing.
And, keep the rhythm
below the belt.
Done.
This is not a tip.
This is a perscription. Trust me.
If you don't?
You will fall out of balance.
Split the differential..
and tip the fuck over.
Or, worse shit.
I've seen this happen..
Implode.
No, I don't wanna implode sir.
- No, you don't.
I'm in it for the long run.
You know?
Yeah, implosions are ugly.
- Yeah.
Pop off to the bathroom,
work on it anytime you can.
And, when you get really good at it.
You'll fucking be stroking it.
And, you'll be thinking about money.
Second..key to sucess.
In this racket, Is this baby right here.
It's called cocaine.
It will keep you sharp,
between the ears.
It will also help your fingers dial faster.
And, guess what?
That's good for me.
Yes, sir.
Revolutions. You follow?
Revolutions.
- Keep the client on the ferris wheel.
And, it goes..the park is open.
24/7..365.
Every decade..every
goddamn century.
That's it.
The name of the game.
I'll key the key.
Thank you.
We are common denominator.
Keep that for me.
For the next six months I got to know
the 'ins' and 'out' of Wall Street.
Earning shit money,
as I geare up to take my Series 7.
Then, I was a license broker at last.
Ready to make my fortune.
My first day as a future
Master of the Universe.
They called it Black Monday.
No shit.
By four p.m. the market
had dropped 508 points,
the biggest plummet, since
the crash of ‘29.
This is not something, that
you wanna sell.
You know what happened?
A fucking Tsunami.
I think you're making a big mistake.
Yes, I will talk to your wife.
- Trust me. Do not answer the phone.
A lot of people are gonna be calling you.
Trying you to get your dirty laundry.
Holy.
Fucking..Shit!
Unbelievable!
My first shitty day as a broker.
Within a month,
L.F. Rothschild, an institution
since 1899,
..closed its doors.
Wall street had swallowed me up.
And, shit me right back out again.
We could pawn my engagement ring.
If we needed to.
Cos, I don't mind.
If we needed to, I'm saying i'm okay.
- Will you listen to me.
We’re not pawning anything. Okay?
What'd I always tell you?
- You're gonna be a millionaire.
That's right, okay?
Let me look..
We'll find something.
How about this?
- What?
- “Nobody Beats the Wiz”.
Electronic store.
Stock boy, what do you think?
- You're not gonna work at that place.
Yeah, but you know..you start off..
- Jordan you're gonna be miserable..
at that place, if you go there.
- It's sales. You work your way up..
You'd be a general manger..
- You're not gonna be a stock boy.
Why not?
- Cos, you're a stock broker.
You understand that,
nobody is hiring stock brokers right now.
You understand that?
Okay?
Ah, this place is..
What does that say?
- Stock brokers.
Long Island.
Stock brokers in Long Island.
Hey, I’m looking
for Investor’s Center?
That’s us, you wanna invest?
No.
Investor’s Center.
I’m looking for Investor’s Center?
Yeah, that's us.
This is it.
Oh, I'm Dwayne.
- You're Dwayne?
Yeah.
- Hi, Dwayne. We spoke on the phone.
I'm Jordan Belfort.
I'm the broker from Rothschild, New york.
Yes, yeah. Have a seat.
How are you?
We spoke on the phone earlier, right?
- Two hours ago.
Where..where are your quotrons, here?
- Quotrons?
- Yeah, computers.
No, we don't need computers here.
We just trade right off
the pink sheets here.
Pink sheets?
- Yeah, they're Penny stocks.
Company that can't get listed on NASDAQ,
they don't have enough capital;
..their shares trade here.
- Penny Stocks?
Yeah, this one..Aerodhyne.
is a really interesting...
Or Aero..Aerotyne?
- Aerotyne, yeah.
Very hot stock right now.
- Yeah?
They are couple of brothers,
that are making radar detectors out of a garage;
They are out of Dubuque. Maybe,
it's microwaves, I'm not sure. But..
You call the company's main line,
their mom Dorothy answers,
and she's so sweet.
Six cents a share?
C'mon, Who buys this crap?
Well, I mean..
Honestly, mostly Schmucks.
There's postmen,
there's always a postman.
Plumbers, uhm..?
They see our ads,
in the back of Hustler,
Popular Mechanics,
and our ads actually says,
they can get rich quick.
Hustler?
- Yeah..
You know, that girlie magazine?
- Yeah, nudie mag.
A lot.
- Yeah.
We're helping them finance houses,
we are helping them
buy their wife a diamond ring..
A boat..maybe.
Is this stuff regulated or you guys
what're you doing here?
ehhh..sort of..
- sort of?
Jesus Christ!
The spread on these is huge.
Yeah and that’s the point.
What's your name again?
Jordan Belfort.
Jordan, what did you get on
that Blue chip Stock?
I make one percent.
Or, I did make one percent.
Pink sheets it's fifty.
It's fifty percent?
It's fifty percent commission?
Yup.
For what?
It's our mark up for our services.
So, if I..if I sell a stock at
ten thousand dollars.
My commission is five thousand bucks?
If you sell ten thousand
dollars worth of this stock,
I'll personally give
you a blowjob for free.
And, I hope it happens.
Hello, John.
How're you doing today?
You mailed in my company
a postcard, a few weeks back.
Requesting, information
on penny stocks that had huge..
upside potential with
very little downside risk.
Does that ring a bell?
- Oh, yeah. I may've sent you.
Okay great. Well, the reason
for the call today John is.
Something just came
across my desk John.
It is perhaps the best,
i've seen in the last six months.
If you've sixty seconds,
I'd like to share this with you.
You got a minute?
The name of the company,
Aerotyne International..
It is a cutting edge tech firm
out of the Midwest,
awaiting imminent patent approval,
on a new generation of radar
detectors that have both huge military,
and civilian applications.
Now.
Right now John. The stock trades over
the counter at ten cents a share,
And, by the way John...
Our analyst indicates,
it could go a heck of a lot higher after that.
Your profit,
on a mere six thousand dollar
investment would be, upwards of..
..sixty thousand dollars!
Jesus! That's my morgage man!
- Exactly, you could pay off your morgage.
John, one thing I can promise you.
Even in this market,
Is that I never ask my clients
to judge me on my winners.
I ask them to judge me on my losers.
Because, they I have so few.
And in the case of Aerotyne,
Based on every technical
factor out there, John.
We are looking at a
Grand Slam home run.
I'll do four grand.
Four thousand, that'd be 40 thousand shares, John.
Let me lock in on that trade now,
and get back to you with my secretary
with an exact confirmation.
Sound good, John?
- That sounds good. Great.
Hey, John?
Thank you for your vote of confidence.
And, Welcome to the Investors Center.
- Yeah, thanks alot. Bye.
How’d you fuckin’ do that?
Just like that I made two grand.
The other guys looked at me like,
I’d just discovered fire.
Great! Even better!
I was selling garbage to garbage men.
And, making cash
hand over fist.
The only problem you're gonna have is,
that you didn't buy more.
Boom..Shakalak!
So, I was selling them shit.
The way I look at it,
Their money was better off
in my apartment.
I knew how to spend it better.
Excuse me.
Is that your car, in the lot?
Yeah.
That's a nice ride.
- Thanks man.
Donnie Azoff.
Jordan Belfort.
Nice to meet you.
You know, I’ve seen it around.
I've seen it around a lot.
I think, we live in the same building.
- No, shit?
Twelfth floor?
- Yeah. What floor are you on?
Fourth floor.
I have a four year old kid, ugly wife?
So, what do you do, bro?
What do you mean, what do I do?
For work?
What do you do?
I'm a Stock broker.
Stock broker?
- Yeah.
Childrens Furniture.
Oh, good for you.
It's all right.
You make a lot of money?
Yeah, I do alright for myself.
I'm trying..to put it together.
Your fucking nice car?
We live in the same building?
I'm not understanding...
How much money do you make?
I don't know.
Seventy Thousand last month.
Get the fuck..!
Get the fuck out of here.
I'm serious.
No, i'm serious too.
Seriously, how much money
do you make?
I told you,
70 thousand.
Well, technically.
72 thousand last month.
Somethin like that.
You make 72 grand a month?
- Yeah.
Tell you what.
You show me a pay stub
with $72,000 on it,
I’ll quit my job right now
and I'll work for you.
Hey, Paulie. What's up?
No, yeah..everything's fine.
Hey, listen.
I quit.
And he did quit his job,
which I thought was a little weird.
I mean, I had just met this fucking guy.
There were other things
about him too,
like his phosphorescent white teeth;
and the fact that he wore horn rims
with clear lenses to look more Waspy.
Then, there were this..rumours.
I heard this, stupid shit.
I don't know.
I didn't even wanna bring it up.
It's just...stupid.
- Is it about me?
You know, people say shit.
I don't even listen to them,
half of the time.
What do they say?
Shit, about you doing your cousin
or something like that?
I don't even listen to it.
Bro, it's not like that.
You know,
it's not like that.
I mean, like you married your cousin.
Some stupid shit.
Yeah, my wife..yeah,
my wife is my cousin.
It's not like what you think,
whatever..you know?
Is she like a...first cousin?
or is she...
Her..her father,
is the brother of my Mom.
It's not like...
We grew up together.
And, she grew up hot..you know.
She fucking grew up hot.
All my friends were trying
to fuck her. You know?
I'm not gonna let someone...
One of these assholes fuck my cousin.
So, I used the cousin thing as....
I'm not gonna let,
someone else fuck my cousin.
If any one is gonna fuck my cousin,
it's gonna be me.
Out of respect. You know..
- No..I get it. Yeah..
You're not afraid of like the
whole kid thing, right?
What? Having kid with her?
Yeah.
- No, we have two kids.
I don't mean..
I don't wanna get personal..
They're okay?
No, they're not retarded
or anything like that.
But, there'a big chance, right?
Yeah...
There is like a..
sixty percent..
You know, sixty sixty-five percent
chance the kid's gonna be fucking retarded..
..or whatever.
- That scares the shit out of me, buddy.
Look, man. A lot happen with kids. Whatever
takes biz whether you're fucking cousin or not..
What if something like that happened?
I basically, you know?
If the kid is retarted.
I would drive it up
to the country,
and just like, open the door and
i'm gonna set you free now.
You know, like run free..
You know..
I'm completely fucking with you!
That's horrible...
No. We would take it to institution
or something where it's handled like..
Raise the kid or whatever..
You know what?
If you're happy, God bless you, buddy.
No, i'm not fucking happy.
No one who's married
is fucking happy.
Well, i'm sorry to hear that, buddy.
Listen, i'm really..
I'm really appreciative
of this fucking job.
I'm really enjoying..
- I'm really happy of what you're doing..
Actually, I got you
a little present.
You got me a present?
- I got you something, yeah.
You're sweet!
-It's in the back though.
We gotta go out back.
What, it's wrapped up or something?
It's wrapped up yeah.
I don't get it.
We can do it while you're
in fucking car. Come on.
I'm not fucking doing this.
You're out of your fucking mind.
Do this shit bro.
No.
No one is fucking here bro.
Get the fuck in.
Smoke this crack with me bro.
Smoke some fucking
crack with me bro.
One hit.
That's it.
We gotta get out of here, buddy.
We gotta get out of here.
Let's go fucking run.
Let's run like a fucking
lion and tirger in pairs!
Let's fucking run!
Go..go...go..go!
You've reached Frank's auto body.
We're closed right now,
so, please leave us a message!
Hello, my name is Jordan Belfort.
My partner and I are..
very interested in renting
out your garage.
Donnie and I were
going out on our own.
And,the first thing we needed
was brokers.
Guys with sales experience.
So, I recruited some
of my home town boys.
Sea Otter.
Who sole meat and weed.
Chester..who sold tyres and weed.
And, Robbie...
who sold anything
he could get his hands on.
Mostly, weed.
This is Brad.
And, Brad's the guy I really wanted.
But, he didn't go along with us.
He was already making so much
money selling Qualutes.
He’d become the Quaalude
king of Bayside.
You get any pussy
with that thing or what?
Yeah, man. Of course man.
- Bring some chicks around here sometime huh.
Little morch...little morch.
Hey, Zit.
Tell your sister,
I was asking about her.
But you bring me a pair of her panties,
next time you come through.
Yeah, man. She said,
they don't wanna talk to you man.
Get the fuck out of here.
Hey, Ma.
We got chicken or what?
Ma?!
You listening?
It's easier than you think.
Every person
you're on the phone with,
They wanna get rich
and they wanna get rich quickly.
They all want something for nothing.
- There was this one time,
That i was selling pot to Amish dude.
You know guy's that got like the beard,
With like no mustache or some bullshit..
- Yeah..yeah.
Well, he says that he only wants
to make furniture.
What's that gotta do with anything?
- I don't understand.
What the fuck are you talking about?
I'm not putting words into
your mouth or nothing, But..
you just said that,
Everybody wants to get rich.
Holy fuck, you did just said that.
- Yeah, you said that.
What the fuck are you talking about?
- Yeah, like buddhist.
They don't give a shit about money.
They're wrapped in sheets!
They don't buy shits.
- I'm not..i'm..I'm not talking..
...about Buddhist or Amish.
I'm talking about normal people.
Working class, everyday people.
Everyone wants to get rich.
Am I crazy?
- There's no such thing as Amish Buddhist..
I am pretty fucking sure.
- No, I didn't..
Can we get some Ketchup please?
- I didn't say Amish buddhist..
Do you guys not wanna make money?
I wanna make some
fucking money, okay?
I can sell anything.
Shit, I can sell lubes to convent full of Nuns
getting horny to be fuckin' each other.
That's the attitude!
You can sell anything?
Sell me, this fucking pen
right here.
You can sell anything..
Sell that.
Sell me that pen?
Can I finish eating first?
I hadn't eaten today.
Brad, show em how it's done.
Boom. Sell me that pen.
Watch, go on.
You want me to sell this
fucking pen?
That's my boy right there.
Fucking sell anything.
Why don't you do me a favour?
Write your name down on that napkin for me?
I don't have a pen.
Exactly.
Supply and demand, my friend.
See what I mean?
He's creating urgency.
Getting you to want to buy this stock.
Gotta make it as something that they need.
That's the thing.
All nuns are lesbians.
What the fuck are you
talking about, Otter?
Yeah, think about it.
They can't keep in dudes..
Four fucking times.
Get me four times.
Look, I knew these guys
weren't like Harvard MBAs.
Robbie Feinberg the pin head,
took five years to finish High School.
Alden Kupferberg- The sea otter,
Didn't even graduate.
Chester Ming, the depraved Chinaman
thought Jiujitsu was in Israel.
Smartest of the bunch was
Nicky Koskoff.
He actually went to Law School.
I call him "Rugrat" b'cos of his
piece of shit hairpiece.
Still, give me them young,
hungry and stupid.
And, in no time
I’ll make them rich.
Omigod. Jordan.
You like it, baby?
It’s beautiful.
They’re not the biggest
stones in the world.
But, I promise
they are really high quality.
This is beautiful.
I don't...it's so beautiful.
Oh, boy.
- What?
I know that look.
What is it? Go ahead.
- I don't know, it's..
These stocks, these companies.
They are like, crappy companies?
Yeah, Yeah.
They are terrible.
Don't worry about it. I told you,
What i'm doing is, completely legal.
Yeah, I know. They're like, they're not
gonna make any money though, right?
Sometimes they do.
Sometimes, they don't.
You know, how it goes.
Wouldn’t you feel better,
if you sold that stuffs to rich people,
who can like afford to lose alot of money?
Of course.
But, rich people don’t buy penny stocks.
They just don't.
Why not?
Because they’re too smart,
that’s why not.
I mean, what person with
a college education.
Would trust this bunch of jerk offs?
But what if they didn’t sound like
a bunch of jerk offs?
What if, I can teach them
how to sell it to people with money?
Real money.
So, I decided to re-invent the company.
Gentlemen,
Welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
You snooks will now be targeting
the wealthiest.
one percent of Americans.
I'm talking about Whales, here.
Moby 'fucking' Dicks.
And, with this script.
Which is now your new 'Harpoon'..
I'm goona teach each and everyone
of you to be Captain...
Fucking Ahab.
Get it? Huh?
Captain Who?
Captain Ahab.
From the fucking...
Book..motherfucker.
From the book.
Turn you fucking brain on!
Listen to me.
We are a new company,
with a new name.
A Company, that our clients
can believe in.
A Company, that our clients can trust.
A firm, whose roots..
are so deeply embedded
into Wall Street,
That our very Founders,
Sailed over n the Mayflower,
chiselled the name
Stratton Oakmont,
right into plummet fucking rock.
Got it?
What we are gonna do is this.
First we pitch them
Disney, AT&T,
IBM, blue chips stocks
exclusively.
Companies at these peoples moan.
Once we sucker them in,
We unload the dog shits.
The pink sheets, the pennies stocks.
Where we laid the money.
50% commission baby.
Now, the key to making money
in a situation like this,
Is to position yourself now,
before the settlement.
Because, by the time you read
about it in The Wall Street Journal.
It's already too late.
And you wait.
You wait.
And, whoever speaks first.. loses.
Sorry, I appreciate the call.
I realy have to give this some thought.
and, uh..talking to my wife about it.
Can I call you back?
They don't know, right?
They gotta think about it.
They gotta talk to the fucking wives.
Or the fucking tooth fairy..
The point is it doesn't matter
what the fuck they say.
The only objection they have is
they don't trust you guys.
And, why should they trust you?
I mean, look at you..
you're a bunch of fucking
sleazy salemen right?
So, what do you say?
- You mean to tell me that..
if I put you in Union Carbide at 7
and took you out at 32..
Texas Instruments at 11 and took
you out at 47..
You're still at 16 and took you out at 41,
..you wouldn’t say Chester..
pick me up a few thousand
shares at Disney?
On the spot, right now. C’mon.
- I mean, honestly Kevin. Honestly..
Seriously?
- I don't know you.
You cold called me.
You're a total stranger..
I'm in complete agreement with you,
You don't know me, I don't know you..
..Alden Kupferberg.
- Robbie Feinberg.
Chester Ming.
- I'm Senior Vice president at Stratton
...Oakmont.
- and I plan on being one of the...
Top broker in my firm next year.
- And, I'm not gonna get there,
by being wrong, Stan.
- I do wanna say that..
you sound like a pretty sincere guy.
It's not gonna make you rich.
It's not gonn make you poor.
But, what Stratton..will do
is serve as a...
Benchmark, for future business, Kevin.
- You feel comfortable with me, Scott?
And, then you'll know for sure,
That you've finally found the broker
on Wall Street that you can trust.
And who can consistently,
make you money.
Sound fair enough?
Yeah, I gotta say,
I'm pretty impressed.
What do..what do you think?
Kevin?
You give me one shot here,
On a blue chip stock like Kodak.
And, believe me..Kevin.
The only problem you gonna have..
is that you didn't buy more.
Sound fair enough?
Shit..
My wife might devorce me.
but, yeah.. let's do it.
Excellent choice, Kevin. How much
do you wanna go for it, this time?
Let's do five..five thousand dollars.
Why don't we try eight thousand, Kevin?
All right, let's do ten.
Ten?
- You wanna do that?
Excellent choice.
Kevin, let me lock in that trade
right now and get back to you,
in a few minutes.
With the exact confirmation.
Kevin, and Welcome..
..to Stratton Oakmond.
- Thanks man, I'm gonna have a beer,
This is fun.
- Take it easy Kevin.
Thanks Jordan.
Thanks a lot.
What a fucking idiot.
- The one..
..thing I know about
in this world is Airlines.
And Kushon Airlines is the
future of Airlines.
Get in now..
- My name is Nicky Koskoff.
Chester Ming, and i'm a Senior
Vice President at Stratton Oakmont.
Truly I'm so so sorry for your loss.
When did he passed?
- Just think I'm wrong..
It's like getting in on sunlight before
there's any sunlight, you understand?
That was a very intelligent decision
I'm happy to transfer you to our sale associate.
Rhonda.
Rhonda?
Has anybody fucking seen Rhonda?
Everybody have a good week?
End of the month.
$28.7 million in gross commissions,
All from Pink Sheets Stock Boys!
And to celebrate with a weekly
act of debauchery,
I have offered our lovely sales
assistant Danielle Harrison here,
ten thousand dollars..
To shave a fucking eye!
Yeah!
You want this?
Huh? You want this?!
Let the shaving begin!
Scalp, scalp...scalp.
Scalp, scalp...scalp..scalp,
scalp...scalp.
FYI Boys, Danielle’s promised to use
This 10 thousand dollars for breast implants!
She's already got C-cups,
But now she wants fucking Double Ds!
Is this a great company or what?!
This is the greatest fucking
company of the world!
Dominic..
Blow the roof off this
motherfucker!
Word spread throughout
Wall Street.
Even in places I didn't want it to.
It wasn't long before
Forbes Magazine.
The flagship of Wall Street
called to do a 'Profile' on me.
Let me ask you, How do you see
the future for Straten Oakland.
One word..
Diversification.
That's good.
Thank you so much.
I have more than enough.
- Fantastic..fantastic.
Can we get a quick picture?
A total fucking hatchet job.
This conniving little twat!
Look at this?
“The Wolf of Wall Street”.
They call me..look.
Your hair looks good.
“Jordan Belfort,
sounding like a kind
of twisted Robin Hood
who takes from the rich
and gives to himself
and his merry band of brokers”.
Read that..read it.
- Listen.
There’s no such thing,
as bad publicity, Sweeheart.
- Read the article.
Jordan, you look great.
You're in a huge magazine.
Calm the fuck down!
What the hell’s all this?
It's the Forbes article.
They all wanna work for you now.
Hey, what did I say?!
Hey, you want a job?
You talk to me!
Forbes had made me a superstar.
Every day, dozens of money-crazed
kids beat a path to my door.
If we hired ‘em,
they dropped out of college
overnight..
and spend whatever allowance they had
on a new suit from our Straten tailor.
Are you fuckin' serious right now!
I mean, we're literally putting
clothes on these kids backs.
And here comes, this jerk off
sniffing around.
You know, everytime someone
rises up in the world.
There's always gonna be
some asshole trying to drag him down.
Within months,
we doubled in size,
moved to even bigger offices.
It was a madhouse,
a greed-fest,
with equal parts cocaine,
testosterone and body fluids.
It got so bad.
I had to declare
the office a fuck-free zone,
between the hours of 9 and 7,
but i'm telling you
even that didn’t help.
Actually the madness started
on our very first day,
when one of our brokers,
Ben Jenner,
christened the elevator by getting
a blowjob from a sales assistant.
Her name was Pam and to her credit,
she did have an amazing
technique, with this..
wild twist and jerk motion.
About a month later,
Donnie and I decided
to dowble-team her,
On a saturday afternoon while our wives
were out shopping for Christmas dresses.
Eventually Ben married her,
which was..
pretty amazing considering
she blew every single guy in the office.
He then got depressed and killed
himself three years later.
Anyway, I hired my Dad Max
to maintain order,
As the enforcer.
Stratten's very own Gestapo.
We called him Mad Max
because of his hair-trigger temper,
which could be set off by something
as innocuous as a ringing telephone.
Who the fuck
has the goddamn gall to call this
house on a Tuesday night!
Goddammit!
- You're gonna miss it.
Oh, please tell me something
I don't know.
I wait all week for the fucking Equalizer.
And they have to fucking...
Hello?... - Gene, how are you Gene?
But, as soon as he picked up the phone.
He'd affect this weird British accent.
right-eo.Gene that will be great...
Cheerio.
It was absolutely...
The fucking half-wit!
..bizzare.
You missed it!
And He's Mad Max all over again.
Alright, tell me what happened.
What happened?
Well, he discovered..
..it was his mother's sister.
- Who is he? Who?
The main guy.
You know the main guy.
It was his mother's sister.
She showed up dead.
Of course, Mad Max didn't have to know
everything we're doing at Straten.
Then, there's a big target.
They get launched and stick?
- There's a bullseye..
The bullseye is a dollar sign.
Whoever, gets closer to the dollar
sign get the most bucks.
So, if he gets hurts,
what happens?
I don't think,
he's gonna get hurt.
they’ve got, like, superhuman
strength anyway.
You can't look him right
in the eyes.
You can't look him in the eye?
- That's a fact. It's on PBS.
They get confused and
their wires get crossed.
You gotta look like at the chin.
Looks like i'm look at you
but i'm lookin' at your chin.
They're like the monalisa,
They find eye contact, like whever
you're standing at the room.
Then, they lock it..
But, there's a limit to what
we can do with him?
We're allowed to throw shit at him.
We're allowed to throw..
foods..bananas..
But, for example,
what i wouldn't do is maybe like..
tell him to pull his cock out..
and like get some of the girls
to fondle him or shit..
Let's keep that in our
back pocket.
This guy's more about thrown
at the dartboard.
The thing is...
this is their gift, okay.
They're build to be thrown.
Like a lawn dart.
Their top is heavy. Like a lawn dart,
they're build for accuracy.
Can we bowl with this guy?
That's his fucking brother, Robbie.
The brother is the bowling ball.
The brother,
you put a skateboard on him,
strapped him to a skateboard..
And, toss him down an alley
at some pins.
No, shit.
That's interesting.
Can we get that guy?
We'll get that guy too.
But, it says here..
This guy will show his cock.
They’re very ornery,
by the way.
So, you gotta be careful.
With these litle guys, okay?
Safety is first, alright?
I want some of those fucking
Tranquilizer gun ready..
to knock these fucker out.
Maze, taser guns?
A pallet gun, maybe?
No, pallet gun's gonna hurt em.
I just want em out!
I say, we stick with the 'loophole'.
Right..okay?
If we don't consider him a human,
we consider him as an act.
I think we're in the clear.
Like, you know like flying willanders,
you know a lot of those guys died,
Bu, they never sued anybody.
- The important thing..
you guys gotta keep in mind is
that these things gossip.
They get together and they gossip.
That's a good point.
- And the last thing that we need..
is them getting together
and say, ' oh, they made fun of us'..
It's gonna make Straten look bad.
- That's why I love you.
You think of shits like that.
We treat it just like
one of us, okay?
One of us,
copul gobul one of us.
We accept them one of us.
Copul gobul one of us.
- Jordan!
Your dad’s coming.
Something to do with the
American Express bill.
Get him out of here?
- Yeah, lick my twat.
No, I'm serious.
Make some shit up.
$430,000 dollars
..in one month, Jordy? Huh?
Four-hundred-and-fucking-
thirty-thousand fucking dollars..
In one fucking month!
They’re business expenses.
Just relax
Jordy, look what you got here?
Look at this.
26 thousand dollars
for one fucking dinner!
Okay, no..no..no.
This could be explained.
Dad we had clients.
We had Pfi..Pfizer clients.
Right, the portal house from argentina.
Expensive champagne, the wine..
we had to buy champange,
And you got all the fucking sides.
Tell him what the sides were.
I ordered sides, so..
- Sides?
$26,000
Worth of sides?!
What are these sides?
They cure cancer?
The sides did cure cancer.
That's the problem.
They were up there.
That's why they were expensive.
Shut the fuck up.
- I'm seriou..
Stop.
And, EJ Entertainment.
What the fuck is EJ Entertainment?!
Well..that's uh..
Yeah, Jordan.
What's EJ Entertainment?!
Jordan what is that?
It’s a fucking prostitution ring, Jordy.
That's what it is!
That is what it is.
Isn't that the perfect,
description for them?
That is what it is...but..
None of this were charged to me.
This is all of them.
Oh, it's all us?
It wasn't me though.
Fucking explain this shit to him.
These are all your fucking charges!
Right here.
The IRS they allow for T&A, that's fine.
T&E
- I said, T&E.
No, you said T&A.
- No, I didn't.
Yeah, you did. Yeah, you did.
You said T&A.
It's T&E. alright?
I know you're upset about the dinner.
And that makes sense.
B'cos, we did spend too much money.
But, I said T&E.
Don't tell me what you said.
I heard what you said.
Dad, he said T&A.
- He did.
He said T&A.
- Absolutely, no question.
I'm getting this close!
That's what i'm saying.
I want you to open up more, Max.
He's gonna fucking kill you.
Why do you hold it in?
Max, Max..Why do you hold it in?
- That's it.
That's it.
Get the fuck out of here.
What kinda hookers take credit card?
- A rich one!
In Stratton, there were three
kinds of hookers.
The blue chips, top of the line.
Model material.
They cost between $300 and $500
and you had wear a condom.
unless, you gave them a hefty tip,
which of course, I always did.
Then came NASDAQs,
who were pretty,
but not great,
They cost betweem two to three
hundred bucks.
Finally there were pink sheets, skanks.
They cost about a hundred or less,
and if you didn't wear a condom,
you'd get a penicillin shot the next day,
and pray your dick didn't fall off.
Not that we didn’t fuck them, too.
Believe me, we did.
It's that slip disc thing again.
I know what it is.
You know,
too much..with EJ entertainment.
How are things at home?
Well, not the best.
It just doesn't...
you know what i'm saying.
It's like the smell..
There's a smell,there's attraction
thing and after a while,
It just kinda fades away
a little bit..
Yeah, well..it's supposed
to fade away.
Supposed to?
- That's marriage.
You know,
your mother and I.
We've been married a long long time.
- I know.
What do you think?
We're jumping into bed every two minutes?
It doesn't work that way.
- I love her to death.
I wanna stay married, Dad.
But..uh..
It's crazy out there.
Some of these girls, you should
see them. Oh my God!
They're fucking..the things
they're doing now, Pops.
I mean..it's whole
on another level.
Really?
- And, they're all shaved too.
Get out of here!
- They're all shaven.
Are you kidding me? No bush?
- Bald as a China-doll.
No, bush.
- Oh my God!
All of a sudden, One week.
Nobody'd anything down there, anywhere.
It's a new world.
- They're bald from the eyebrows down.
Wow.
- Nothing. Not a stitches.
Like lasers.
- Wow, new world, see?
I was born too, too.. early.
I've never been a fan of bush,
to be honest.
Really?
- Yeah.
I don't mind it.
Dad..
I dont want you stressing out
about any of these.
How can I not get stressed out?
Look at the knuckleheads
you got working for you?
I know they're knuckleheads
but I need em to live like me.
You get it?
To lived like me.
Jordy,
one of these days, the chickens are
gonna come home to roost.
You're looking at me like
I'm crazy.
Crazy?
This is Obscene!
It was obscene --
in the normal world.
But, who wanted to live there?
Fucking magic!
I love this!
We got minds up here,
that's gonna take this company.
Into the fucking
stratosphere!
Jor-dan!
Jor-dan!  Jor-dan!
Fuck Merrill Lynch,
Fuck them.
Why should they be taking
all the fucking money,
all the fucking time.
It was our next big move.
Finding companies to take public.
IPOs.
It was the only way,
these Wall Street pricks..
would ever stop thinking
of us as some..
..shit kicker bucket shot.
We’ve got Arncliffe National,
See, we were a little different.
We liked to get as fucked
up as possible.
During our business pow-wows.
In order to stimulate
our free flowing ideas.
Which is why, we're popping
these ludes like they're M&Ms.
We own the fuckin' comp..
We own the company...
Don't know what a lude is?
I'll tell you.
Ah, wait.
Wait wait wait.
Looks like those ludes,
are woking their magic on
Donnie right now.
The Qualude.
or 'lude' as it is commonly referred to.
Was first synthesized
in 1951 by an Indian doctor.
that’s not feathers..
-- as a sedative..
and was prescribed to stressed out
housewives with sleep disorders.
But, pretty soon..
someone figured out..
that if you resisted the urge
to sleep for fifteen minutes,
you got a pretty
kick-ass high from it.
Didn’t take long  for people
to start abusing ludes, ‘course,
and in 1982 the U.S.
Government Schedule One’d them,
along with the rest of the world.
Which meant there was only a finite
amount of these things left.
No shit,
you can’t even buy ‘em anymore.
You people’re all
shit outta luck.
What is it?
- Steeef Maddin..
Steeef Maddin..
Steeef..
-Steeef.
You remember those ads?
Those giant headed girls
with the bunked eyes,
wearing those big clunky shoes.
My friend from school
Steve Madden.
His friend from school
Steve Madden was 'The name'
in women shoes at that moment and,
and all of Wall Street was
begging to take his company public.
Except, guess who grew
up with him?
Women shoes.
Women shoose.
My very own Vice President.
Diamond Donnie Azoff.
Jordan, you better come check
this fucking chick out.
Look.
I would fuck that girl,
if she was my sister.
I would let that girl,
give me fucking aids.
She's hot.
- Cristy.
Jordan, this is my friend Naomi.
Hi.
- Naomi.
Nice to meet you.
Naomi, Nice to meet you.
You have an awesome place here.
I don’t think I’ve ever been
in a house like this big before.
Oh, really?
- Yeah. - Beautiful beach out there..
Blair Hollingsworth.
Hi. Buddy, nice to meet you.
Name's Blair right?
- Yeah.
You like to jet ski?
I've never done it before.
you’ve never jet-ski’ed in your life?!
No, i've never jet-ski'ed.
- You’ve never been to jet-ski’ed..
No, i haven't.
- How many times you gonna ask her,
She's never been on a jer ski.
I don't know,
I might ask her a couple more times.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Hildy.
Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Jordan, Teresa needs your help.
Yeah. I'll be out in couple of minutes.
Just tell her,
I'll be out in couple of minutes.
Why don't you tell your wife that?
- How am I to do that, when i'm having a conversation?
What am I, your secretary?
- I think, we should get going.
Wait, wait.
where're you guys going?
We gotta go. We got two other parties
we're supposed to get to.
We can stay for a drink.
- Yes, stay for a drink.
No, we got two other parties
we're supposed to get to. so..
Why don't you let her stay for a bit.
Let her stay for a bit.
What's the big deal?
You like champagne?
- I do.
Donnie, what the fuck
are you doing?
You piece of shit!
You guys're gonna have
to excuse my friend.
Get the fuck out of here!
Let him fucking finish, Hildy.
That's fucking rude!
So, Bay Ridge.
That’s near Staten Island, right?
Brooklyn, across the Verrazano Bridge.
Saturday night fever, territory.
- That's right.
Guinea gulch.
We call the Verrazano Bridge
guinea gang point.
So, I presume,
You’re Italian?
On my dad’s side.
I'm also Dutch,
German, English..
-- I’m a mutt.
Oh, you're a mutt.
Yeah. Actually, I have family
over there, in London.
My Aunt Emma.
She's the best.
Very British, you know?
Classy Lady.
That explains it then.
Explains what?
Explains you. I mean..
You’re a Duchess, right.
The Duchess of Bay Ridge.
Excuse me?
Can I get a straw please?
Thank you.
So, I was umm..
...a little surprised you
asked Cristy for my number.
Why's that?
Aren’t you married?
Well..
Yeah, but..what?
Married people can’t have friends?
We're gonna be friends?
Yeah.
You don't wanna be my friend?
We are not gonna be friends.
--and at night I work my designs.
I have an entire line of lingerie..
Camisoles, bustiers, panties.
She designs panties, too?
Oh my God!
C'mon, Jordan, think of a way to get
up to her apartment?!
You wanna come up
for some tea or something?
Tea? Yeah.
Like hot tea?
- Yeah.
Sounds nice.
Tea. Fuck yeah.
I want to come up for tea.
Darjeeling..Rosettes..or
something of that shit..
Rocky.
Who's this.
Say hi, Rocky.
- Hi, sweet heart.
Why don’t you light a fire?
I’ll be right out.
Fire here.
- Sure.
I like painting here,
It's uh...
God, help me.
How do I fuck this girl?
You allright?
- Yeah, yeah. Just,
Trying to light a fire here.
That’s it, you’re leaving. Don't get involved.
Go home to your wife.
As you can probably guess,
I fucked her goddamn brains out.
For eleven seconds.
Did you just cum?
Oh, yeah. I just came.
Did you..did you come?
- No.
No? Okay.
I'm still hard.
Just give me a sec to get going.
Sure.
Oh, God!
Fuck off, Rocky!
Bad dog.
- Give him a biscuitt or something..
It's okay.
Just keep going.
Go, play Rocky.
Go..go.
You're crazy.
I couldn’t get enough.
I mean, her pussy was like
heroin to me.
It wasn't just about the sex, either.
Naomi and I got along.
I mean, we had similar
interest and shits.
Woohoo. Shit!
You, get out of the fucking car!
Sick son of a bitch.
Just relax, sweetheart. relax..
Son of a fucking bitch!
Stop, please.
What are you doing home?
- That whore from the party?
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
I thought you were at
the fucking beach..
That's where you've fucking been?
With that fucking whore
from the party?!
How could you do this to me?!
Who the fuck are you, Jordan?
You’re like a completely different
fucking person!
I made a mistake,
I don't know what to tell you babe.
I'm sorry.
I am sorry.
- Is that what you want?
Do you love her?
Answer me.
I felt horrible.
Three days later, I filed for divorce
and moved
Naomi into the apartment.
Say what you will,
but the Duchess did have style.
She brought in a decorator,
feng shui’d the place--
she even hired a gay butler.
This guy was smart, sophisticated,
professional,
i mean..really, really great.
Jasmine?
Yes, Sir. I tried to stump you
this evenning. Very good..
Very good. Great nose!
Except for that, one time.
Omigod!
Oh, hey.
Is it wenesday already?
What the fuck?
That is fucked up!
He must have thought, we're still
at the Hamptons this weekend you know..
Where were they doing, sweeheart?
In the bedroom? - They're everywhere.
There were two guys over there
on the table,
There were more over here.
They were more right here.
- Oh, God!
You're fucking serious. Right there?
Why didn't you tell me..
Baby it gets worse.
After they left,
I checked the apartment.
What?
What is it babe?
Where is my money?
I don't know where they are.
- Where's my fucking money? Where is it?
I don't know where your
money is Mr.Belfort.
I didn’t do anything.
- He's lying Jordan,
He's lying through his fucking teeth!
Let' start from the beginning.
Let' start from the beginning. Alright?
You invited friends over, right?
One thing let to another.
Things got out of hand.
We understand that, we do.
We do blow all the time.
We are fucking degenerates ourselves.
Look at us.
The money was stolen from my apartment.
Right from my sock drawer.
Alright?
- As I said,
I don't know about money..
- Just start from the begining.
Who came over?
- It's just a normal day.
I knew you're coming home
the next day.
So, everything will be fine.
It'll be cleaned up.
I got a little high, at breakfast.
I got a little happy,
I had some eggs,
I had a little bit of ice cream.
I said, who I knew that likes ice cream.
That's my frined Rudy.
So, I call Rudy.
- Who's Rudy?
Yeah, Who's Rudy?
You know, who Rudy is.
Come on.
You know who he is?
- I don't know fuck..
Who the fuck's Rudy?
I don't know any one name Rudy.
- Last month, the Lollypop Club.
You know who Rudy was, dancing.
You know...Rudy?
- I don't..I..I eh..
What do you mean?
So, he went to the Lollypop Club?
Oh, he was at the Lollypop club for sure.
On the stage, griding with everybody..
I got fucked up.
I like to dance...
Maybe, I met him. Maybe I didn't..
I meet a lot of fucking peoplel.
Fifty thousand dollars was stolen from
my fucking socks drawer.
All my girlfriend's jewellery..
What the fuck?
- Your fucking faggot friend..
..Rudy take my shit.
Did he? Answer me.
Okay, now I get it.
Now I get why.
This is a gay thing. I see.
All of you.
You think this is b'cos you're fag?
My cousin is a fucking faggot.
And I go on vacation with him and
his boyfriend. I love fags!
I will not be stolen from.
You get that?
I fucking like gay people.
But I don't like you.
Talk, you fuck. Talk!
I'm gonna drop you, fucking..
Where is it?
Chester and Toby
they went all Yakuza on Nicholas.
They got crazy.
I had to call the cops
just to keep em for killing the poor guy.
I gave 'em each a thousand bucks
and told them what Nicholas had done.
And they kicked his ass.
Thanks again, officers.
It's not like I cared about
the fifty grand anyway.
I was making that much alnost
everyday through one rathole or the other.
Now, 'rathole' is a friend.
Like, Brad here.
Who helps stock in his name from me.
I drive the price up.
Then, he'd sell and kick
most of the profit back to..
You guessed it.. me.
All cash.
None of it on the books.
A big 'no, no' of course
in the eyes of the law.
Enter our new Securities Attorney,
Manny Riskin.
700 bucks an hour,
to be the voice..
..of DOOM.
- Listen to me,
You piss on the SEC’s leg,
you’ll end up with your tits in a ringer.
Will you not worry about it.
I got the SEC in control.
What the fuck is this imbecile doing?!
Hey, hey. What're you doing?
Hey! We got the SEC in here.
The Securities and Exchange Commission
sent two lawyers down to review our files,
so, I set them  up in our conference room.
And, I had it bugged
and the air conditioning turned up so high,
that it felt like Antarctica in there.
Is it always this cold in here?
I don't know.
Then, while they were, looking
for a smoking gun in that room.
I was gonna fire off a bazooka in here.
Offering up our latest IPO.
An IPO is an initial public offering,
the first time a stock is offered
for sale to the general population.
Now, as the firm taking the company public,
We set the initial price, then
sold those shares back to our friends.
Look,
I know, you're not following what I’m saying.
Anyway, right?
That's okay.
That doesn't matter.
The real question is this,
“was all this legal?”
Absolutely, fucking not!
But, we were making more money
that we knew what to do.
What do you do, when you're making more
money than, you know what to do with?
Omigod!!
Will you marry me?
Omigod!
Is that a 'Yes'?
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure.
-  Yeah!
I held my bachelor party
at the Mirage, in Las Vegas.
The flight there alone,
was a Baccanal!
One last blowout for the Gods
before I settled down for good.
A hundred Strattonites.
Fifty hookers plus fifty more
waiting once we landed.
Oh, and the drugs..I mean,
I tell you our plane
was a pharmacy with wings.
All told,
the weekend cost me two million bucks.
Including the cost of refurbishing
the entire 28th floor.
Kiss the bride.
But, the wedding was like
something out of a fairy tale.
--with Naomi my Duchess,
me her handsome Duke..
..and The Bahamas Ocean Club
our castle.
Of course, after that bachelor party,
Me..the Duke needed a few
penicillin shots so he could..
..safely consummate, the marriage.
Hey..I’m Barry Kleinman,
filming the wedding.
A few words, huh.
For your son.
Jordan, remember what I told you.
It involves your penis..
...and her vagina.
You know, you know it.
You can do it, Jordy.
Omigod!
Aunt Emma!
Oh, God!
You came!
Jordan!
Jordan! Look, who came.
It's Aunt Emma.
Aunt Emma!
Jordan dear, how lovely.
- Hey, how're you doing?
Pleasure to finally meet you,
in person.
Into the donuts, I see.
Oh, I’m--- uh...
I lived through the 60s, my dear.
Enjoy the day.
She surprised me!
I didn't even know.
- It's huge honour.
Just one more step. Keep your eyes closed.
- Where are we going?
One, Two..three!
What is this?
It's your wedding present!
- What?
It's your wedding, sweetheart.
Are you serious?
A fucking Yacht?!
For millionaires,
who's ships have come in.
Priceless boats offers
the most fun afloat.
It's no coincidence that
this 150 feet..
..of Steel hull
is the color of cash.
Anchors Away!
Oh, my God!
Baby!
Do you like it?
You like it?
Yes!
For three weeks, we sailed the Naomi
through the Caribbean.
Eventually, taking her home
to Long Island,
where we’d bought a house.
Seven acres on the
Gold Coast of Long Island.
The most expensive
real estate in the world,
with maids, cooks,
landscapers, you name it.
We even had two guards
who worked in shifts,
Both, named Rocco.
It was heaven on earth.
Wake up, you piece of shit!
Who’s Venice?
Who?
Who? - Who?
What are you a fucking owl?!
Who's she?
Some little hooker
you were fucking last night?
What the fuck
are you talking about?!
No. No, way!
Baby.
No!
You were calling her name
in your sleep.
Are you out
of you fucking mind?!
I don't..I don't
even know who Venice is.
What the fuck does that even mean?
Venice.
That's the stupidiest shit i've ever
heard in my fucking life!
Venice?
Venice baby
where are you?
Venice?
Venice?!
Where did you go? Huh?
You're going rough huh?
Ah..! Jesus Christ!
I like it. I like it.
Wolfie..wolfie. Wolfie!
Wolfie.
Wolfie?
- Yes, it's my 'safe' word baby.
It's my 'safe' word!
- I don't give a fuck,
about your safe word.
Shut the fuck up!
Shut up, you little bitch.
You fucking dirty little birdie!
That's right!
That's right, I forgot.
I forgot baby.
Donnie and I,
we’re investing in
a condo complex in Venice.
That's why..that's why all this confusion.
- Oh, you're investing in Italy?
Not Italy.
California, baby.
Oh, California?
- Yeah.
You're a lying piece of shit!
Duchess, baby, come on.
- Don’t you fucking ‘Duchess’ me.
Don’t you ‘Duchess’ me.
I'm sorry.
- Do you really think,
That, I don’t know
what you’re up to?
You’re a father now, Jordan.
Yeah.
You’re a father now
and you act like an infant!
Fuck.
Goddamn it! Baby, you know.
You got real anger issues!
Who was the one who flew in here,
at three in the morning
on a stupid helicopter..
And, woke up Skylar?!
That was you.
How about that?
Does it even matters to you?
- Fucking bullshit!
Does it even matter to you,
that I just had that
driving range..
sodded with Bermuda..
grass, Jordan?
And, now..
you fucking wrecked it.
No. You didn't
researched the whole thing
and dealt with the fucking
golf course people!
Oh, my God! You had to deal with
the gold course people too!
What a great tragedy.
Honey, Oh my God!
You probably had to pay
them in cash..
..with your hands,
What a fucking burden.
And actually,
do some work besides,
swiping my fucking credit card
all day, huh?
Cos, I can't keep track of
your professions honey.
Cos last month,
you're a wine connoisseur.
Now, you’re an aspiring landscape architect?!
Let me get that right.
- Fuck you!
Don't fucking dare..
throw that fucking water at me.
Don't fucking dare.
All right, honey?
We can talk this out. Alright?
We'll just use our words.
You know?
Communicate. Okay?
Come on, sweetheart.
Talk to me..talk to me.
Stop flexing your muscless,
Jordan.
You look like a fucking imbecile.
Babe, come on.
You should feel..
..feel happy you got a husband..
Who's in such great shape
like this, Huh?
Come here.
C'mon, give me a kiss.
You look so beautiful
right now. C'mon!
Kiss you?
- Yeah, give me one...
Fuck You!
Ah yes..
My morning ritual.
First, I’d get up and fight with Naomi
about whatever I did the night before.
Next it was a steam,
so, I could sweat out the drugs,
still in my system.
Then. I’d assess the damage.
Drown out my eyeballs..
take my “back pills”
to get the day started,
then, seek to make up
with Naomi.
Good morning Daddy.
Where’s my kiss?
Does Daddy get to kiss
both his little girls, huh?
Ohhh, no!
No, Daddy doesn't even get
to touch Mommy..
for a very, very..
very long time.
Daddy is really sorry about
what he said in the other room,
He didn't mean any of it.
Daddy shouldn’t waste his time.
And, from now on..
it's going to be nothing but short,
short skirts around the house!
And, you know something else, Daddy?
And Mommy’s so sick and tired
of wearing panties,
Yeah?
- Yeah.
In fact..
she’s decided to throw them all away.
So, take a good look, Daddy.
You’re gonna be seeing an awful lot
of this around the house,
but, no touching.
What’s wrong, Daddy?
Look at this shit.
Mommy, likes to play games with daddy.
Mommy, have you ever notice,
anything odd about Mr.Fuzzy Bear, over there?
His eye seems to be a little
bit odd, Don't they?
Yeah, there's something a little bit
different about his eyes.
Hah! Yes,
I think it's true.Say, 'Hi, Mommy',
Say, 'Hi' to Rocco and Rocco.
Hi, fellas!
See that, huh?
Of all the fucking days,
she choose just today to give me blue balls.
Today's the biggest day
in Stratten's history.
And, I needed to be thinking straight.
Hey,Jordan.
Welcome.
- Steve here yet?
This was the day, that we launched
the Steve Madden IPO.
The troops are all here.
Everyone's rallied, excited.
Everything had to run tight.
It had to be perfect.
What the fuck is that kid doing?
What's he doing?
The biggest IPO in this firm’s history,
What the fuck is he doing?
Is he wearing a bow-tie?
Hi.
How're you doing?
- Good.
You cleaning your fishbowl?
I just..I had a minute.
You had a minute.
And, today..you needed
to clean your fish bowl. Today?
I had finished my paperwork and
I was..just had a couple of minutes.
Okay.
Nice to meet you.
On new issue day?!
On cocksucking, motherfucking
new issue day?!
This is what you do?!
Hey, everybody?!
Listen up.
This is what happens when you fuck
with your pets on new issue day!
Now take your bowtie,
get your shit, and..
get the fuck out of my office, you understand?
- Get the fuck out!
Everybody on point!
We are here, to make money.
A real wolf pit.
Which is exactly, how I liked it.
Jordan. Look what I caught in the lobby?
I caught a genius.
Enter, Steve Madden.
Red Hot ladies footwear impresario.
And, thanks to Donnie,
We were taking his company public.
Stratten Oakmont was crawling out
of it's primerial loose.
Pond scum, no more.
That's why they gotta see your face.
You get ‘em fired up so they’ll push
the shit out of this stock.
Okay?
And not only that.
Donnie and I secretly owned 85%
of Steve Madden shoes.
Which legally speaking was a big NO NO.
But, we'll get filthy fucking rich,
If our troops got behind it.
Our job was to get 'em worked up.
But, not too worked up.
Hello, if uh..
For those of you who don't know me,
..my name is Steve Madden.
Yeah, we know who you are.
Your name is on the box.
The shoes. Show them the shoes.
Show them the shoes.
This shoe..it is pretty cool.
This is the Mary Lou..
Which is the one that really
put me on the map.
Without it, I wouldn't be here.
Believe it or not.
Believe it or not, though.
The Mary Lou is actually
the same as the Mary Jane.
But, it's black leather.
All right,
let's give it up for Steve Madden
and his awesome Mary Lou!
Hold that up, hold that up.
Hold that up, proud.
Give him a round of applause.
You got that out of your system, huh?
You're having a good afternoon or what?
I wanna take a moment to
tell you why Steve is so..
Absolutely, off the fucking wall.
It’s because this man is a creative genius.
This ability, this gift that
Steve has..
it goes beyond just..
spotting the hottest shoe trends.
Steve's power, is that
he creates trends.
You understand?
Artists like Steve come along
once every decade!
I'm talking, Giorgio Armani!
Gianni Versace!
CoCo Chanel! Yves Saint Laurent!
Steve, come up here for a second.
I don't think you all realise..
that Steve Madden is
the hottest person,
in the women shoe industry,
with orders going through the roof at every
department store in North America, right now.
We have him here in our office.
We should thank our fucking
lucky stars this man is here.
We should be on our
hands and knees right now,
getting ready to suck this guy off.
Like this, okay?
I wanna suck you off, Steve.
Everyone's gonna suck you off.
This is our golden ticket to the
fucking chocolate factory, right here.
And, I wanna meet
Willy 'Fucking' Wonka. Okay?
I wanna be with the fucking
Oompa Loompas like this.
Get off this fucking stage.
Get out of here.
All right.
I want you all to focus for a second.
See that little black boxes?
They are called a telephones.
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret
about this telephones.
They're not gonna
dial themselves! Okay?
Without you...
They're just worthless hunk of plastic.
like a loaded M16 without a..
..trained Marine to pull the trigger.
And in the case of the telephone,
It's up to each and everyone of you,
My highly trained Strattonite,
My killers
My Killers who will not take
no for an answer!
My fucking warriors
who'll not hang up the phone,
until their clients either buys..
... or fucking dies!
Let me tell you something.
There is no nobility in poverty.
I've been rich, and I've been poor man.
and I choose rich every time.
Cos, At least as a rich man,
when I have to face my problems,
I show up in the back of a limo
wearing a $2000 suit
..and $40,000 gold fuckin' watch!
Now, if anyone here thinks
I'm superficial..
...or materialistic.
Go get the fuck out and get a job at McDonald’s,
because that's where you fucking belong!
But, before you depart this
room full of winners,
I want you to take a good look at
the person next to you, go on.
because one day in the
not-so-distant future,
you're pullin' up to a red light
in your beat-up old Pinto,
and that person’s gonna pull up
right along side you
in a brand new Porsche,
with their gorgeous young wife
by his side. Who's got big voluptous tits.
And who will you be next to?
Some disgusting wilderbeast with three days of
razor-stubble in a sleeveless moo-moo,
crammed in next to you with a carload full
of groceries from the fucking Price Club!
That's who you're gonna
be sitting next to.
So, you listen to me and you listen well.
Are you behind,
on your credit card bills?
Good.
Pick up the phone and start dialing.
Is your landlord ready to evict you?
Good.
Pick up the phone and start dialing.
Does your girlfriend think
you're a fucking loser?
Good.
Pick up the phone and start dialing!
I want you to deal with
your problems,
by becoming rich!
All you have to do today
..is pick up that phone..
And speak the words that
I have taught you.
And I'll make you richer
than the most powerful CEO of
the United States of fucking America.
I want you to go out there,
And I want you to ram
Steve Madden stock down
your clients’ throats
Till they fucking choke on it
till they choke on it and buy 10,000 shares!
That's what I want you to do.
You'll Be ferocious!
You'll Be relentless!
You'll Be telephone fucking terrorists!
Now, let's knock this Motherfucker
out of the park!
At 1 p.m. we opened
the stock for sale at $4.50 a share.
By 1:03 it was over eighteen dollars.
Even the big Wall Street firms
were buying.
Of the two million shares
being offered for sale,
a million belonged to me,
held in phony accounts by my ratholes.
Now, once the price hit the high teens,
You know what?
Who gives a shit.
As always, the point is this--
22 million in three fucking hours!
Can you believe it.
Jordan.
Barry Kleinman's on the phone
from Future Video.
A who?
- I don't know. He shot at your wedding.
He says, it's urgent.
Urgent? Who the fuck's Barry Kleinman?
Oh, my God. You wanna marry me?
You're in love with me?
Yeah, go fuck your cousin.
Barry, what's up?
Listen, I got a subpoena.
- Subpoena?
What the fuck are you talking about?
The FBI wants a copy
of your wedding video.
The F-B-fucking-I?
You fucking kidding me?
Listen to me,
His Name’s Denham,
he’s an agent in the New York office.
What’s his problem?
- He’s a boy scout,
..thinks you’re Gordon Gekko.
What does he want with my wedding video?
It's like invasion of my privacy,
You know what i'm saying.
It's intrusive..you know.
He's got your pictures of your
whole inner fucking circle.
Pictures, names of the people..
You know what he's trying to do.
Exactly, what's he's doing now. Look at yourself.
He's trying to rattle you.
He's trying to rattle your old lady.
So, she'll nags you to be a fuckin' witness.
Oh, He wants me to rat on myself?
He wants me to give information
about my..what?
The good fucking news is,
you know I know everybody downtown,
I called The Justice Department,
The DEA..
nobody even know you
fucking exists, so calm down.
They don't know I exist?
- No.
That's good.
You know who he is right?
- Yeah.
So, if I just wanted to get some more
information, just find out what he knows,
we could go to his house right?
Tap his phones a little bit,
..bug in get a little information..
- You don't fuck with these guys like that,
you don't fuck with him like that.
What are you nuts or something?
That's what you fucking do.
What do I pay you for?
I have a fucking P.I license you know.
I make a living at this,
I'm not a cop anymore.
They'll take my fucking license
away from me, alright?
Okay.
Okay, if I can't do that,
Can i just..can I give the guy a call?
Why is that..Jordan.
Jordan do me a favor.
The only one who calls
this guy is your fucking lawyer.
I told you, whatever
the fuck you say to him,
He's gonna used it against you.
Don't you understand?
He is smart, you are dumb.
- Fucking bullshit.
I'm not allowed to call him.
- Are we fucking talking tonight?
The last time you took these
fucking pills, you put..
your head in fucking micooven,
I'm not making it up
Okay, I won't call.
Hey, fellas! C’mon aboard!
Plank’s right down there.
Welcome.
What a nice day.
Welcome aboard.
Jordan, Welcome aboard to Naomi.
Pleasure to meet you.
I’m Agent Denham.
This is Agent Hughes.
Hi, how are you?
Let me introduce you.
This is Nicole.
Heidi, come on. Don't be shy.
What are you guys all shy for?
Don't be scared.
These are friends of Stratten.
- It's a Pleasure. - Hello.
Your message said that,
you wanted to speak privately.
Right. I do want to
speak privately.
Give us a minute, huh, Ladies.
Let me know if I can get you anything.
We'd be happy to help.
You guys hungry?
If you want something to eat.
We got some pasta, shrimp, lobster,
I got whiskey,
anykind of booze you want?
You know what, the bureau doesn't
allow us to drink when we are at sea.
Duh? Of course.
Ever been on one of these before?
A boat?
I learned to sail when I was six.
No, shit.
Is that right.
I mean, one like this, though.
I had the whole front extended
to put a chopper up there.
See that?
Anyway, this is for you.
It's a complete list of every person
that was at my wedding.
I understand you wanted
the whole wedding video,
I figured this would help expedite
the whole process, right?
There you go.
Look.
My point is that.
I know you’re investigating Stratton,
but, for the life of me
I can’t figure out why.
I know we are a little unorthodox;
We're a little...
loud in the way we do things.
You gotta understand,
trying to make a name for ourselves.
But, I want you to understand,
we don't do anything illegal.
Whatsoever.
You could talk to the SEC,
They're at my office,
fifteen times,
over the last six month, so..
I got nothing to hide.
You know, The SEC’s a
civil regulatory agency.
We pursue criminal activity.
Exactly.
You go after real criminal. Which...
makes me wonder, what the hell
you're investigating me for?
I mean, honestly. What..
What is it that you think,
that we did or do. I don't get it.
Well,
Jordan, I can’t discuss
ongoing investigations.
No, i get that.
I understand.
With that said.
This case got dumped
on my desk.
You know, by a higher up..
Who needs to make a show of
looking into the new company,
on the block. The whole press
and everything.
I end up being the smuck
who does the looking.
Exactly.
It's just..you know,
it bothers me.
We are the new guy.
we're the one that's banging
on Wall Streets door, man.
You should see what's going on
at the bigger firm.
I know all the information.
It's true.
Goldman, Leyman Brothers, Merrill.
collateralized debt obligations?
This internet stock bullshit?
I mean, it's a fucking travesty.
I mean,
I could take you step-by-step,
to what exactly is occuring.
You know, all you have to do is ask.
I'm available.
That's exactly
what I wanted to hear.
I don't see why,
a little sit down like this.
Can't be profitable
for the both of us.
It should, right?
It should be profitable for us.
It should.
- Look?
I'm gonna give you my personal line,
five days a week you just call me.
Feel free.
I'll do that.
- Great.
Are you sure you guys don't want
something to drink?
I mean, you're not hungry.
Nothing?
Oh, no.
- No?
Let me ask you.
And if you don't wanna get too personal,
just tell me to shut up at anytime.
Did you try to get your broker's
license at one time?
Did I hear that right?
Were you trying to
take a stab at Wall Street?
Who've you been talking to?
Who the fuck have you been talking to?
- Well, you're investigating me..
I hear things.
You see what I mean?
You ever think about,
what would've happened.
if you've..you know,
stayed the course?
You know what. When
I’m riding home on the subway,
And, my balls are fucking sweating.
I'm wearing the same suit, three days in row.
Yeah, you bet I do.
I thought about it, before.
Who wouldn't, right?
Right, who fucking wouldn't.
I mean, you got..
another personal question.
You don't need to answe..
- No, it's alright Jordan.
What are you pulling?
50-60K something like that, a year?
Let's put it this way.
You get a free handgun,
when you sign up for the bureau.
No. But, it fucking pisses me off.
You know what I mean.
You think about,
the people that build this country,
hardworking people like you.
You know,firefighters,
teachers, FBI agents.
End of the day, you guys get
fucking skinned to life, financially.
Fucking makes me angry.
That's the one thing about
Wall Street and this market is.
For me, I feel, it's good to give back.
You know, there's
there's situations.. where I can.
make those situations
better for people.
You know.
Opportunity, is everything.
Exactly.
Yeah, for example.
I got this one kid, right.
Went to school for environmental
science or something like that.
He was bogged down by
student's loans.
Turns out, his mother needed
triple bypass surgery.
Horrible situation.
But, we got him in at the market
at the right time.
Choose the right stock.
We gave him the right guidance.
Boom. Overnight,
changes his entire life.
You know, he got to put his mother in the
best hospital in New York city.
It didn't work out for her, granted
she passed away, unfortunately.
But, we gave him that opportunity,
you know what i'm saying.
It's just about setting up
the right team and then,
overnight, your life can change.
What is..intern..uh..
What does an intern make off
on a deal like that?
On that situation..
On that particular trade.
One trade.
North of half a million dollars.
And, I'd do that for anybody.
You know, anybody that needs
the proper guidence.
Can you say that again?
Just the way, you said it.
Just the same way.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
No..come on you know
what i'm talking about.
Just say the same thing.
I think, what Jordan just did is he..
If I'm not mistaken.
You just tried to bribe
a Federal Officer.
No, technically,
I didn't bribe anybody.
According to the US Criminal Code,
there needs to be exact dollar figure
for the exchange of services.
That would not hold up
in the court of law.
That's the truth, But..
I wanna tell you this,
- Yeah.
The same gentleman, that told me
you tried to get your broker's license,
also told me that
you are a straight arrow.
He ran a security check on me.
Well..
i'm on a boat fit for a bond villain
sometimes you need to play the part, right?
I think it's time you both
get the fuck off my boat. What do you say?
You know, Jordan.
I'll tell you something.
Most of the Wall Street
jackasses I bust,
they were born to the life.
- Is that right?
Their father was a douchebags.
Just like their fathers before them.
But you,
You Jordan, you got this way
all on your own.
Did I?
Good for you, little man.
Little man?
Good for you.
- Me, the littleman?
Let me tell you something.
Let me tell you something else.
Honestly, i'm not bullshitting here,
this is one of the nicest boat
that i've ever been on.
I gotta..I gotta tell you.
- I bet it is.
And, you know what
I was just thinking too.
The fucking hero that
I'm gonna be back at the office.
When the bureau seizes
this fucking boat.
B'cos, I'm gonna finally fuck Jordan.
It's beautiful.
And, you get the beautiful girls and everything.
It's wonderful.
Alright, get the fuck off my boat.
I'm sure we'll be seeing each other, real soon.
- I'm sure.
Good luck on that subway ride home
to your miserable ugly fucking wives.
I'm gonna have Heidi lick some caviar
off my balls.In the meantime.
Hey, you guys wanna take
some lobsters for your ride home?
You fucking miserable pricks!
I know you can't afford them.
Fucking cheap fucks.
Fucking miserable pricks!
Hey, fellas..look what I found
in my pockets. Look!
Your year salary, right here.
You know what I call them?
Fun coupons.
A fun coupons.
Switzerland?
What the fuck is in Switzerland?
Swiss fucking Banks, that's what.
It was ass covering time.
I had to hide my money.
Enter Rugrat.
He knew Swiss Banker from law school.
But, he was in Geneva.
And there was no way,
I'm gonna make that flight sober.
So, I knew if I took my drugs right.
I could sleep through the entire flight.
But, I had to take em, JUST RIGHT.
At 4 pm I popped a few more ludes.
Which started kicking in by the time
I finished my sales meeting.
My tingle phase.
By dinner I popped a few more
on top of some cocktails and a
valium or two.
My slur phase.
By eight thirty,
I popped a few more ludes.
and pretty much lost my motor skills.
This was the drool phase.
By ten I didn’t know who
or what the fuck I was--
The amnesia phase.
We boarded the plane,
just before midnight.
Wow! Look at you.
You're all beautiful.
May I see your boarding passes Sir.
- We have boarding passes.
He's got his hand on my dick again.
Oh, my God! Take it off.
Take it off.
I heard there's a treasure map,
under here.
Stop.
Please, sit down.
Go back to your seat, please.
Please, go back to your seat.
I will have to call the captain.
Please, Sir.
Please sit down.
Please sit down!
Okay, i'm going.
Okay..okay.
Fasten your seatbelt please.
We cannot take off, if you haven't
fasten your seatbelt.
Sit down, fasten it.
I will do it for you.
- What?
You gotta speak english
We don't understand Swiss language.
Christ. Fuck.
Donnie.
Donnie, this isn't funny,
untie me, buddy.
I can’t tie you.
The captain tied you.
He was fucking tasing you.
Why?
You're screaming at people.
Fuck off.
You were on the floor,
like rolling around and shit.
You called the captain the N-words.
I call the captain an N-words?
Yeah, he was very upset.
Really?
Luckily, we are in first class.
Jesus Christ, I think you have
a fucking drug problem.
Where are the ludes?
They're in my ass,
don't worry about it.
I got it.
Thank god.
Jesus Christ, what are we gonna do when
we get to Switzerland, buddy.
This is bad.
This fucking thing's pressing my chest
I can't breath.
Do something to calm
me down, please.
Okay, shut the fuck up.
Just shut the fuck up.
Help me.
Okay...shhh..shh..
That's good.
-  Go to sleep.
Rub it harder, buddy.
You're all right.
We all love you.
Shut the fuck up!
Mr.Belfort.
You're free to go.
Really?
Hey, Donnie.
- Yeah.
When we get up there.
Try not to act like yourself, okay?
Let's make Geneva an
asshole free Donnie zone, alright?
Why the fuck are you
coming at me for?
Hey, listen..the only reason
you're sitting in this limo
and not a Swiss jail is
b'cos of my friend, okay?
We are here.
Jordan Belfort!
At last!
Nicholas has told me so much.
Jordan, Jean-Jacques Saurel.
Pleasure to make your acquaintance.
- Nice to meet you.
I'm curious about your bank
secrecy laws, here.
Excusez-moi, Jordan,
Swiss custom requires
ten minutes of blah blah blah..
Chit chat.
Chit chat! Thank you.
before business can be discussed.
Of course, let’s get “down to it.”
What would you like to know?
Under what circumstances
would you be..
..obligated to cooperate with an FBI
or U.S. Justice Department investigation?
For example.
Ca depend.
Ca depend?
- Oui.
Ca depend on what?
Exactly.
Whether America plans to invade
Switzerland in the coming months.
So, check if tanks are rolling down
the Rue de la Croix?
Yes, Rue de la Croix.
What I’m asking, you Swiss dick,
is are you going to fuck me over.
I understand perfectly,
you American shitheel.
The only way the Banque
Real de Geneve would cooperate;
with a foreign legal body
is if the crime being pursued is
also a crime in Switzerland.
But, there are very few Swiss laws
which apply to your practices.
From a financial standpoint,
you are now in heaven.
See, I told you he's fantastic, right?
If the U.S. Justice Department
sent us a subpoena,
it would become papier-toillette.
We would wipe our ass with it.
Unless, of course..
it was an investigation
into stock fraud..
which is a crime in Switzerland.
If I'm correct.
Then, there’d have to be Cooperacion.
On your part,
If I'm not mistaken.
Yes, we would.
Assuming the account is
under your name.
if it were..
another name..
A friends, Comerate, Cousin..
Relatives?
Yeah.
Was that yodeling I just heard or
did you just say
what I thought you said?
Yes!  Yes!
He's telling me to use a rathole.
But, a U.S. rathole would never
get into Switzerland with all that money.
What I needed was a ratholr
with a European passport.
Jordan?
Hey! How is my favourite Aunt, huh?
Welcome, was the traffic terrible?
- No, not at all.
Thank God, Aunt Emma didn't need
too much convincing.
Turned out, the british weren't too much
different from the Swiss.
Money talks.
And, bullshit takes the bus.
How do you say 'rathole' in British.
If you get in any trouble, whatsoever.
I'll come forward immediately.
I'll say that I duped you.
That I promise.
Risk is what keeps us young,
isn’t it darling?
Sometimes, I wonder
if you let money get
the best of you, my love.
Among other substances.
It’s that obvious, huh?
It's chilly darling and you're
sweating bullets.
What can I say, Aunt Emma.
I’m a drug addict.
I really am. I mean,
Cocaine, pills..
Whatever it is,
I'll fucking do it.
That's the truth.
I am a sex addict too.
Well, there are worse things
to be addicted to than sex.
Jesus, why am I telling you all this?
I am sorry.
Because I'm very easy to talk to.
You are.
You are easy to talk to.
I suppose it's..
It's just my job, you know, it's uh...
All these people depending on me, tens of
millions of dollars at stake, you know,
Sometimes, I feel like I..
I've bitten on more than
I can chew, you know?
You're a man with large appetites.
Yeah.
Is she, fucking hitting on me?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
I suppose, I put that on
myself though, right?
My decision.
It's hard to..
Hard to learn to..
to control the anxiety
sometimes, you know?
Learn to relax, and let go.
To release the tension.
She is hitting on me.
Holy shit!
Yeah, release the tension.
Suppose we, uh.. We
all just need to learn not..
Learn to do what comes
naturally in life, you know?
Is he fucking hitting on me?
Stability, dear.
Family.
You take care of my nice, my love.
I'll take care of everything, over here.
Deal.
We had, literally,
a fuck load of money.
Aunt Emma, could never carry
all this by herself.
So, I thought to myself,
who else has European passport?
Now, Brad, as a successful
drug dealer,
spent his winters in the south of France,
which is where he met his wife, Chantelle.
A striper of Slovenian origin,
born in, of all places, Switzerland.
Well, this is fucked.
Oh, no, shit!
- Like this will take a, like, 50 trips.
- I know.
Yeah, a suicide work.
But, how about her family? Right?
I mean, they all got
Swiss's passport, right?
I mean, she's got parents,
she's got a brother.
Right, brother's got a wife,
that's five fuckin' people.
Six, seven trips, boom, right?
They're all fuckin' Swiss and it was like,
''what are you doing?'', they could do that.
At least I have a family,
you crooked nose fuck!
Hey, hey, uh, don't
forget about my money.
- I'm sorry, what was that?
- Hey, I forgot to tell you
- he's got some, he's got some money.
- My money.
- Yeah, a couple mill comin' in like a week.
- Yeah.
And when it gets here, I'll give
you a call, you come pick it up.
You give me a call?
When it gets here, I'll give you
a call, and you come pick it up.
Well, we don't fuckin'
work for you, man!
Shh..
Sweetheart, you have my
money taped to your tits.
Okay? Technically you do work for me.
Hey, Jordan, we're gonna need to talk.
If I fuckin' do this, I'm telling
you right now, I ain't goin' to him.
Okay? I'm not a fuckin' schwas, I
don't do fuckin' pick-ups, alright?
- But listen to me, when this thing placed,
- I'm gonna take care of everything.
and I fuckin' say, and you
tell that fuckin' piece of shit.
- If he comes correct.
- I will.
If he comes in, I'll fuckin' loopy and fucked up.
I swear to God, I'm a mash that douchebag's teeth.
I hear that, who's fucking cheating?
- Who's fuckin' cheating?!
- Look, may I asking..
I put the money on that
fuckin' table, not you!
I'm the reason we
have this fuckin' deal!
- I have a gun, you fucking idiot!
- What the fuck this gun.
I already told you this.
You know what? You're a fuckin' pill
deal, I got five more just like you, bro!
Keep talking, you piece of shit!
Do you know what? You dress like shit!
- So, fuck you!
- Fuck you, motherfucker!
- Jesus!
- Like that faggot. Who's the faggot?
- Enough with your shit!
- You okay?
Hey pal!
The next day, aunt Emma flew to Geneve.
Two million in cash in her carry on.
Which in a big picture was
a drop in the Swiss bucket.
'Cause the following month,
over the course of six roundtrips,
Chantelle's family and friends smugglin'
over 20 millon in cash
without even a hiccup.
- Shred it.
- And by the way..
- Here they are.
- Excellent!
- And I have some more.
- Really?
- Here.
- Oh, thank you.
- And here.
- Welcome.
[LAUGHING] Welcome?
- And yeah, like four bags of it.
- Ooh.
Are you Swiss-Slovakian
or Swiss-Slovenian?
- Slovenian. Yes.
- Slovenian? Okay.
- So you're blonde?
- Oh, stop that.
Shit.
Put the fuckin' car
parked, you dumb idiot!
Yeah, close the briefcase.
One fuckin' day, one fuckin' day
you couldn't keep it together?
I was fucked up, Brad.
- You're fuckin' kidding me!
- Fucked up.
- It's a joke!
- It's a joke?
- I'm sober.
- Jesus fucking Christ.
- It's a fuckin' joke. I'm not stupid.
- Are you fuckin' stupid?
- You fuckin' drivin' you like a fuckin' maniac.
- Do you know what..
- You know the attention
that fuckin' draws?
- You know what, I'm not stupid.
- I'm smart.
- Smart?
- I make million dollar deal.
- That's right.
We smart important people, unlike you.
People who don't sucker punch
people when they're scared, okay?
- I'm scared?
- And by the way,
- I haven't got an apology for that.
- One apology, okay.
I check my fuckin' messages everyday
- when I come home from work
- Did you?
- my answering machine
- You didn't got one, huh?
zero! I got a blinking light
because I don't have shit from you!
- Yeah right. You know, you got a big
fuckin' mouth!
- I got my wife, I got my wife
checking the messages every 45
minutes, calling the office say,
has Brad apologize? Is there any
apology message on the machine?
- Alright, do you know what..
- I don't have jack shit.
- You know what? That's
not how you treat me.
- Yeah, you got a big
fuckin' mouth. You know
I'm not gonna give you a fuckin'
pass, just give me the case.
- Oh, you're not gonna give me a pass?
- Get out of here.
Look, it's a figure fuckin' speech.
- Oh my God, the Emperor of Foxville
- Just give me the fuckin' case
came down from Foxville
to give me a pass!
Hey, what are the citizens of Foxville
doing at the day when
the Emperor's gone?
- I'm begging you.
- Is it, is it mayhem?
Or people looting and raping?
What all the little fuckhead doing?
- Why are you here?
- You go fuck yourself!
- You fuckin', alright, alright.
- Hey, you fuck the back up!
I'm fuckin' saying!
That if I ever cross you in my
life, if you come at me again,
- Just fuckin' keep it down.
- You know what?
I got it. I don't want to be avoiding
anything, but I think you like, like..
- Like, when you come at me,
- What the fuck?
- 'cause you look at me.
- what's the matter with you?
I just know I just noticed like,
you have like a fuckin', like..
- Stop that talk!
- You might twinkle.
You have like a twinkle, were
you trying to kiss me, bro?
- Jesus fuckin' Christ..
- Bro, you're trying..
- I'm.. What's with you?
- I have like a, I don't know, I just..
- I said that homophobic thing..
- Baiklah.
- You're just not the one for me, pal.
- Okay.
You know what I mean? It's not,
it's not about that for me, you know?
- You understand?
- I've heard enough, please.
I'm begging, give me the fuckin' case.
- Okay?
- I gonna give you the case.
- Gve me the case. What's that?
- You gotta do me one favour.
You gotta take this case,
you gotta drive straight home, you know.
I need you to open up the briefcase,
and you take out every single dollar,
don't leave one dollar inside the briefcase.
I want you to have it all neatly
organized outside the briefcase,
and you to take it,
I need you to shove it right up your
wife's Slatvian cunt, you understand?
- My fuckin' wife?
- Fuckin' chill!
- [GROANING] Chill, bro!
- You motherfuckin' piece of shit!
- How about that?
- Let go, let go! Come on. Fuck!
[SIREN]
Motherfucker! You fuckin' dick!
Stop! Don't move! Don't move,
I'm gonna fire your fuckin' leg!
I'm gonna fire you in your fuckin' leg!
Drop the case, put your hands in the air!
Get that!
[SCREAMING]
Get on your knees, sir!
Get down on your knees!
Motherfucker!
Fuck! Jesus!
Mother fucker!
Jordan!
Do I have a surprise for you.
20 real lemons.
Retired pharmacist friend of mine,
it been in his safe for 15 years.
You fuckin' kiddin' me? Lemons?
- [LAUGHING]
- They're gonna knock us out off our fuckin' head.
When it comes to quaalude, the
lemon 714 was the holygrail.
- Can you believe it?
- Oh my God..
I thought they were like a myth.
Three times as powerful as
anything available today.
- Look at these babies.
- Boy Donnie really knew how to celebrate.
He said he was saving
these for a special
occasion, like a birthday,
or being clapfree.
Or, my money arriving
safely in Switzerland.
We're gonna die!
[PUKE]
So that night, I cleared my schedule,
and I rid my body of anything
that could fuck with my high.
It was celebration time.
Okay.
We start off with one, see how it'll go?
My guy says all we need is one.
Here we go.
- Salute.
- Cheers.
Maybe if I pull it
again, it will go down.
Steve,Steve! I gotta get outta here.
No! I think I got it figured out.
It must be one pull for
up, and two pull for down.
Okay.
You feel anything?
No.
Been thirty five minutes.
Maybe we built up a tolerance
after all these years, huh?
Hm..
This is bullshit!
My metabolism is pumped
out, I can't feel shit!
They're old, I think
they lost the potency?
Huh?
Check the bottle!
January '81
They're fuckin' duds.
- Fuck!
- Let's take a..
- Take two more each.
- Yeah.
Jordan!
You're up, babe?
What are you two retards doing?
We're workin' out, honey.
Well, Bo Dietl's on the phone.
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay?
Hey! Bo, what's going on?
Jordan, listen to me clearly.
I can not talk to you in this
phone, and I have to talk with you.
We're gonna get outta
here. What's going on?
Listen to me, leave the
fuckin' house, Jordan!
And then call me from a payphone.
This is not a fuckin' joke, Jordan.
Yeah, yeah. Ya.
- Shit!
- What's.. What he said?
I don't know what the fuck
is going on, I gotta go!
Is everything okay, Jordan?
The closest payphone I can get to
is at the Brookvile Contry Club.
It was a real WASP stronghold.
Just a mile down the road from my house.
Hey Bo, what's up? It's me, what's going
on? I'm at the payphone,
what's going on?
Listen to me carefully.
Please, your little friend
here, Brad, your little buddy,
he's in jail.
He.. What the fuck he's in
jail for? What did he do?
I don't know what he did.
My friend in Long Island told me he got
picked up in some fuckin' shopping mall,
- he got locked up..
- Wait, did you say a shopping mall?
- Yeah, yeah.
- He, he was with Donnie
he was supposed to deliver some money,
and that fuckin' fat piece of shit.
- I'm gonna go and fuckin' kill him.
- Jordan, Jordan, Jordan. Listen to me!
Don't go! Listen to me.
That guy, Denham, that FBI agent guy,
somebody told me, he's got your phone
tapped. Your ofice and your home.
- Don't talk on that motherfuckin' phone!
- Okay. Fuck! I got it, I got it.
I got it, I got it.
Jordan.
You didn't try to bribe this
fuckin' FBI agent, did you?
No, I didn't try to
bribe that FBI agent.
You think I'm that fuckin'stupid? No!
What the fuck you said?
I can't understand.
Say that again!
I said I won't, I know what
my feeling with this FBI agent.
What the fuck are you saying?
- I said..
- Are you fuckin' high?
Are you kidding me? I
don't wanna see more FBI!
Jordan! Are you fuckin' high?
Jordan, do me a favour.
Stay where you are,
don't get behind the wheel of the car,
I'll be there in a
moment to pick you up.
Jordan, Jordan!
After 15 years in storage,
the lemons had developed a delayed fuse.
It took 90 minutes for this little
fuckers to kick in, but once they did..
Pow!
I mean, I'd skipped the tingle phase
and went straight to the drool phase.
Tell me where you are, don't fuckin'..
This little bastard was so strong,
I discovered a whole new phase.
The cerebral palsy phase.
Come on, stand up.
Oke, walking's out.
I think, think what else is there?
Yes!
I can crawl, I can crawl like Skylar.
Fuck!
The kid makes it look so goddamn easy.
Think, you motherfucker, think.
Yes!
I got it!
I've got it!
I can roll.
I can roll!
[GROANING]
[PANTING]
[PHONE RINGING]
[SHOUTING]
Jordan?
Oh Jesus. Where are you?
I'm at the Country Club.
What?
I'm at the Country Club!
I don't know what the fuck are you
saying, but you need to get home!
Donnie is out of control.
He's on the other line
with some Swiss guy,
- I don't know..
- What?!
Get him off the phone!
I can't understand you.
What the fuck are you saying, Jordan?
Can you just get home? Hurry.
Oh my God!
Oh my God..
I was less than a mile from home.
I drove as slow as I fuckin' could.
I think Jello move faster.
I just couldn't give him two million.
I'm gonna be a little late.
You ate two million?
Million!
Get off the phone, get off
the fuckin' phone, idiot!
- [CAR HORN]
- Get out of the way, asshole!
- Hello?
- Too late..
- And it's..
- You hate two million?
No, you don't hate two million, Donnie.
By some miracle, I made it home alive.
Not a scratch on me or the car.
Is that so?
Jordan?
Oh Jesus fucking Christ!
What did you take?
What is wrong with you?
Jordan!
It's fuckin' good, right?
- What the fuck are you saying?
- You fucked up.
- What were you saying?
- Get off the phone!
Get off the fuckin' phone!
What the fuck, Jordan?
You're doing this in the
house, I hope you know that!
You fucking doing this in the house!
- You two are fucking funny friends!
- Get off the phone!
- Jesus, Jordan!
- The FBI!
- Get off the phone!
- I buy the phone!
Get off the phone!
- Give me the phone!
- [SCREAMING]
Come on. We're gonna
go upstairs, alright?
Get off the phone!
Fuck you!
- What's wrong?
- What you did?
- You piece of shit!
- What?
What?
Brad!
Huh?!
You fuckin' asshole!
Gimme the phone.
What did you do?
You piece of shit!
- What the fuck I did wrong?
- Fuck you!
I wanna fuckin' do it!
I wanna fuckin' kill you!
I'll get you!
What the fuck happen?
Oh, shit!
Jordan? Jordan, are you alright?
Donnie? Donnie?!
Donnie is not breathing!
Oh, fuck! I don't know what to do!
Jordan, I don't know what the
fuck to do, I can't help him!
What are we gonna do, Jordan?
Oh my God, I think he's choked, Jordan.
Do something!
- Oh God, help me!
- I got you!
He's not breathing, Jordan.
You got to do something!
- Oh shit!
- Oh my God!
Oh my God..
I got you!
Here!
Get in me!
[GROANING]
Step aside! Oh my God!
Oh God!
Move aside, baby!
Oh, God..
Look at me! Come on!
Come on, come on!
Jordan, he's not breathing,
you got to do something!
Jordan, he's a father, he's
got fucking kids, do something!
Yeah! Yeah.
Jordan, you gotta get over
here, tell me what I'm doing.
Oh fucking God, get over here, call 911!
[SCREAMING]
You alright?
Are you alright?
Mr. Belfort?
Why the fuck you are here? Fuck.
Sir?
We need to ask you some questions.
You fuckin' kidding me? Fuck you!
Come on, get up!
Well, get the fuck outta my house!
- Let's go! Come on! Get up!
- I've been here all night.
- Let's go!
- I've been sitting here all night.
- What the fuck are you talkin'?
- Wait a minute, why you taking him?
- The fuck are you doing?
- Let's go!
Why you taking him?
- Tell him!
- We got no warn.
You just come up and
peep a house like this!
- I'm just talkin'..
- Did you drive your car that night
Mr. Belfort?
Well.
Wow!
Maybe I hadn't made at home okay.
Get out of the fuckin' way!
Fuck! Fucker!
Did you drive..
That car, tonight?
- Yeah..
- Yeah?
Right.
I'm a family man. Family man. Honey!
It was a miracle I wasn't killed.
More, you know, that I
didn't kill anybody else.
The cops took me in for questioning,
but they couldn't charge ne.
They had no proof I was even behind the wheel.
Meanwhile, Brad did
three months in jail for
contempt because he
wouldn't let Donnie out.
The result? I was scot free.
But I had eyes on me like never before.
You're a lucky man, Jordan.
You're lucky be alive,
let alone not in jail.
No, I don't believe in luck, right?
But it's time.
Please, let me call
the SEC and cut a deal,
before your luck runs out.
Wave to daddy!
Hey! Hey, sweetie.
- [LAUGHING]
- You're doing great, sweetie.
You're doing so great.
What kind of terms that
we do talking about, if I..
- You know..
- I don't know
you know you plead guilty to
handful of securities violation.
Stock manipulation, high pressure sales
tactics, ticky-tack
shit like that, you know?
Pay a couple million dollars in fine,
in exchange, SEC fucks
off till the end of time.
And Stratton, what happen to Stratton?
I mean that you,
there's no way, I mean..
You gotta walk away, right?
- Let Donnie be in charge.
- Alright, Donnie.
And the FBI is another
animal, completely.
They still be pursuing you
for criminal wrongdoing.
However, with you
stepping down voluntarily,
my guess is, that your
best friend, agent Denham,
will be standing around
with his dick in his hand.
Jordan.
Wh.. What do you have to think about?
Yo.. You beat them!
You won!
God knows you'll never
have to work again.
What you're gonna do? Spend the rest of
your life in jail? Is that what you want?
- No.
- Okay!
Okay. You got all the
money in the world.
You need everybody else's money?
- Of course not.
- Well?
- You know I built it.
- I know you built it!
You built it, so now preserved it!
[CLAPPING]
You know..
Five years ago, when I started
Stratton Oakmont with Donnie Azoff,
I knew the day would eventually
come where I'd have to be moving on.
And it's trully with a heavy
heart, that I'm here to say that..
That, that that day is finally here.
[SHOCKED]
I wanna, I wanna thank you all for your
years of loyalty and admiration, but uh,
the point is this.
Under Donnie's keadership, along with
Nicky Koskoff and Robbie Feinberg,
moving into key management posisitions,
this place really is, it's gonna be
better than ever. That
I promise you, okay?
This is Ellis Island, you people.
Okay, who you are, or where you
from, where do your relatives came
over, from the fuckin' Mayflower,
or the inner tube from Haiti.
This, right here, is the land of
opportunity, Stratton Oakmont, is America!
[CHEERING]
- All of you know Kimmie Belzer, right?
- Yes, we do.
Fuck you!
Come on, Kimmie.
Which you probably didn't know is,
Kimmie was one of the first brokers
here, one of the Stratton's original 20.
And most of you met Kimmie the beautiful
sophisticated woman that she is today.
A woman that wears
3000 dollar Armani suits.
Drives brand new Mercedes Benz.
A woman who, who spends her winters
in Bahamas and her summers in Hamptons.
That's not the Kimmie that I met.
The Kimmie that I met didn't
have two nickels to rub together.
She was a single mom on the balls of
her ass with an eight year old son.
Okay? She was three
months behind on her rent.
And when se came to me
and ask me for a job,
she asked for 5000 dollar advance just..
Just so she could pay her son's tuition.
And what I do, Kimmie?
Go on, tell them.
You wrote me a check..
For 25.000 dollars.
That's right.
Thank you.
And you know why that is?
That's because I believed in you.
It's because I believed in you, Kimmie.
Just like I believe in each
and everyone of you here today.
- I fuckin' love you, Jordan. I fuckin' love you.
- I fuckin' love you.
- I love you.
- I fuckin' love you too!
I fuckin' love you too!
And I love all of you!
I love all of you, from
the bottom of my heart.
- I love you, Jordan!
- I mean it!
It's a shame, you know, 'cause..
For years I've been telling you guys,
never to take ''no'' for an answer, right?
In order to keep pushin' and
to never hang up the phone,
until you get what you want.
Because you all deserve it.
You know this fuckin' deal
that I'm about to sign..
barring me from the securities
industry, barring me from Stratton..
My home..
The fuck is that? You know?
I tell you what it is. It's..
It's me taking ''no''
for an answer, you know?
It's them, them selling me,
not the other way around. It's..
It's me being a
hypocrite, is what it is.
So..
You know what?
I'm not leaving.
I'm not fucking leaving!
[CHEERING]
The show goes on.
This is my home.
They gonna need a fucking wrecking
ball to take me outta here!
They gonna need to send a national
guard or fucking SWAT team,
'cause I ain't going nowhere.
Fuck them!
[HUMMING]
[SHOUTING]
Jordan! Jordan!
Jordan, get back here!
Hey!
Give.. Give me that!
What a trouble in the jungle, for Christ sake!
How did he, muffle
truffle you, huh, richman?
Turn the offer, trust
Welch on the order of SEC.
He is back in the ocean, happy hunting.
[MUSIC]
It was our time to party big.
And just as Brad was
released from jail too.
I apologize, even offered to
pay him for his time in the can.
But he said no.
The day he was out,
he didn't want any part of us.
Sad thing was, two years later,
he was dead.
Massive heart attack, at 35.
Same age Mulshock died.
Not that they, have a hell
of a lot in common, but,
anyway, I don't know
why that came to mind.
Within days, subpoena started flying.
Notices to produce documents,
deposititions, you name it.
Donnie couldn't drink water fast enough.
You now say it's coming
was to get me a subpoena.
Here's how we do a subpoena
to substracting our funds.
Fuck you USA, Fuck you!
Fuck you, Fuck you..
[CHEERING]
Jordan Belfort.
Olden, that's a nice name.
Thank you very much for that.
What kind a name is that?
That is my name.
I do not recall that.
I do not recall that, okay?
Mr. Ming, thank you for coming in today.
Is it okay if I grab some danish?
- Can I have a danish?
- No, no, go.
They interogated everybody.
I got a low blood sugar,
that were I thinking.
I went on for months, it was
a total fucking harassment.
But not a single Strattonite cracked.
Gladys Carrera.
- Doesn't ring a bell.
- Sorry, I have no recomendation of that.
- No.
- No idea.
I don't recall that transaction,
do you guys have any milk?
Absolutely not.
By end of this, you
called so many times,
I just thought you might remember that.
I don't remember that.
- Would you re.. remember any of those?
- I do not recall any of that.
- This Abdul..
- I do not re.. No I don't recall.
It was a long phonecall, I just wanna
review if you have any memory of that.
Okey, you know we've talked to several
of the employee at
this firm and nobody can
recall anything about
this thieft man IPO.
It's.. I think it's odd.
- Do you recall?
- Carnage Cooperation?
- You do, you do recall it?
- No I don't recall that at all.
Excuse me, I have to ask,
is that your real hair?
Are you gonna say anything about that?
- Will you never comment
on my hair, is that
how we're doing?
- I just asking about that.
Is this personal question?
I wondering why you
wearing something like that.
I'm sure I don't recall what happened.
Can I get you anything else gentlemen?
Yes sweetheart I have rare
condition which require
me to drink one of those
every 15 minutes, please.
We were specifically adviced
not to leave the country.
So, we took our wives to Italy.
We figure that we
were safer working from
over the seas, giving orders to Rugrat.
Nobody could arrest us.
And nobody could prove I was still
running Stratton from a yacht.
Hey, Rugrats bonjour, you
bomheaded eagle, how you doing?
Donnie, Donnie listen,
we have a problem okay?
Your friend Steve Madden
is unloading shares.
What do you say? Who told you that?
- What is going on?
- He's doing it, Donnie.
He says, he says Steve
Madden is unloading shit.
Who told you that? That's bullshit.
- Gimme that goddamn phone, just..
- Don't!
- Ruggie, what's going on?
- He doesn't know what's going on..
Jordan look, I'm watching the screen and
huge chunk to Steve
Madden is being sold, okay.
It's not coming from us,
so it's gonna be Steve.
He's the only person
with that many shares.
Donnie, call me back, alright.
Donnie, your little friend is
trying fuck me, you know that?
Your little friend trying to fuck me
right now. Get him on the phone now.
Even though I own 85% of
Steve-Cock-Sucking-Motherfucker-Madden Shoes.
The shares were in his fucking name.
This motherfucker knew
I was in trouble with
the fed and he was
try to take advantage.
Donnie come on talk to me man,
how do you wanna play this?
Ruggie, I want you to get all
client on the phone right now
and having start selling
Steve Madden we gonna
try make that fucking
price down, do you hear me?
Shut the fuck up, this is your
fucking friend from highschool.
They will fuckin'
freak me, they're gonna
fuck with me and gonna turn this entire
company to a penny stock, you hear me?
- You got it?
- Yes, I got it.
Don't start jumping into conclusion
before we know what is going on.
Capitan!
Hang up your phones,
everybody! Hang up..
Turn the boat away, we're going home!
Baby, baby, what happened?
Sweetheart what's going on?
I am uhh..
- Just wait, I can't..
- Baby, baby, baby..
What is going on? Why are you crying?
- She's dead.
- Who?
I just got a call from my cousin, Betty,
- Yeah?
- Aunt Emma's dead.
- You fucking kidding me?
- No.
You serious? Oh my
God, baby, that's, fuck!
Oh sweetheart thatjust fucking..
Fucking heart attack, boom, snap, gone.
Shuffled off her mortal coil and twenty
million dollars stock
in a Swiss bank account.
She was fine.
- Oh God, baby oh God, that so fucking terrible.
- You know, she's not that old.
It is terrible to you.
Your aunt was such an
elegant, attractive woman.
My condolences to you.
Yes, yes we absolutely devastated, thank
you, thank you so much,
for your condolences.
Now where is that leave
us in regard to her
account exactly, does it
going to probate or what?
Don't worry Jordan, not to worry,
your aunt before she died, signed a
document naming you as her successor.
She did.
Fantastic, well that's a good news.
Well, not as of yet.
Wait, wait.. what is it means, not as of yet?
No [SPEAKING FRENCH]
I, I can't seem to hear you
I must have bad reception.
Aren't you speaking English?
Now.. Fast, very fast.
Fast, I have to get to Switzerland now.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Speak English, fucking speak English!
- Hey, hey.. quiet, okay?
- Okay.
Take your suit, take your dick
okay, and move your ass, please.
Okay, move my ass.
I gotta say these Swiss were
some sneaky motherfuckers.
Within minutes he had set me up with a
forger who could fake
aunt Emma's signature.
You American Shit.
I just had to get there by
tomorrow or lose 25 million dollars.
- We're going to Monaco.
- Monaco? Now?
Yes baby we're going to Monaco
so we can go to Switzerland, okay?
But her auntjust die.
I realize that but i have bussiness in
Switzerland i need to
go Switzerland right now.
Bottom line, sorry.
- We got to get to London.
- Why?
- The funeral.
- Yeah, but babe look, look.
I love your aunt, more than anyone
in the entire world i really did.
but she is dead now sweaty, she's
dead and she's not going anywhere.
She still be dead by the
time we get to London, okay.
- Captain Ted.
- Captain Ted, we go to Monaco, Monaco now, okay.
- Monaco right?
- We go to Monaco.
So we can drive to
Switzerland so we dont need
to stamp up passport take
care of business here.
We'll drive back to Monaco, take a flight
over to London to catch the funeral
be in the New york meet with him in
three business days it's a fucking plan.
I'm just wanna to inform you out
there here. Might run into some chop.
Chop? We can fucking handle chop
right, i mean it's 170 foot yacht.
No, no, we're not going anywhere
unless he said it's safe, alright.
- It's safe.
- Don't worry about the chop.
- You don't know shit about chop.
- Oww, really.
- And you two? You fucking expert on this?
- I'll chop your fucking credit cards.
Chop is fine, trust me chop is
fine, is chop fine Captain Ted?
Yeah, i mean if we take it slow.
Ya, we gonna take it slow.
It's a little uncomfortable
but tell me it's safe.
It's gonna be safe,
because.. I mean we'll have
to batten down the hatches
and we secured the deck
We're looking a few, maybe a few broken dishes.
Few broken dishes, what a few broken dishes.
Is that sound fucking awesome or what.
- Oww, not really.
- We're gonna fucking fun time.
Let's go to fuckin monaco now.
Let's fucking move let's go.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Hold on.
What the fuck is going on here?
The jet ski jus went overboard.
Jesus Christ, hold on okay.
The waves were 20 feet high building,
turn around go to that fucking way.
- We can't
- Go.
We'll get broad sided and it's game over.
I am a master diver, you hear that
I am a master diver, no
one is gonna fucking die.
I got you.. Trust me okay, i love you.
I love you, just hold on tight.
Tight.
Hold on, baby.
Donnie.
Donnie,
- What?
- hold on baby?
Get the fucking ludes!
I don't wanna die trying, i do love
that shit up to but i'm so scared.
I fucked up, i fucked up so bad.
- Get the ludes, downstairs
- What do you say?
Get the ludes.
I can't go down, They're below deck!
There's like three feet
of water down there!
I will not die sobber, get those fuckin ludes.
- Okay, okay.
- Go!
- Where he's going?
- Don't know baby.
Donnie, he fucking crazy.
Jesus Christ.
Hold on, get away from the
window, we'll gonna blown away.
Mayday! This is Captain Ted Beecham
aboard the Yacht
Naomi! This is a Mayday!
I got them, i got them.
Give me to me.
What you're gonna do right now.
This is a fucking may day.
[SCREAMING]
[MUSIK]
[CHOPPER SOUND]
Nice thing about getting rescued by Italians..
.. That they feed you,
make you drink red wine.
And you get to dance.
[EXPLOSION]
Did you see that?
That was the plane I
sent to come get us.
I shit you not, it
exploded when a seagull
flew into the engine,
three people killed.
You want a sign from God,
After all this I finally got the message.
New dream, of becoming financially indepedent.
But struggle every month just to pay your bills.
Would you like to own a home like this?
Who can barely afford to pay your rent.
My name is Jordan Belfort.
And there is no secret to well creation.
No matter who you are. No
matter where you came from.
You too can become finacially
independent in just a matter of months.
All you need is strategy.
When i was 24 years old, i made a decision.
Not to survive, but to thrive.
At first i didn't feel like
deals like this were possible.
But we have the house, and we
have 30 thousand dollar profit.
I certainly beleive now.
I think about it for second.
If you dont have guts
to attend Jordan Belfort
Straight line perssuasion
system seminar.
Then how do you, expect to make any money.
You wanna be a millionaire some day.
Have some guts make a decision.
Jordan belforth said work for
me because i work hard for it.
And if it doesn't work
for you it's because
you lazy, you should
get a job at Mcdonalds.
There is nobody holding you
back from financial freedom.
And there is nobody stoping
you from making millions.
Don't you sit in a home or the life
you dreamed will fly right pass.
I change all these people's
live and i can change yours too.
So come to my seminar, the
life of your dream is only..
- You're under arrest
- You've got to be joking..
- Don't kidding, hey.
- Turn that Camera off.
You fuckin, you fucking cocksucker.
Fuck you!
What the fuck you doing?
you fucking pieces of shit.
Hei Jordan let me give you a little legal advice.
Shut up, fuck off.
(FBI, New York)
Jordan Belfort.
I cleaned on my act, i did rehab.
I'm a Tv personality.
I'm sobber for 2 years, and this happens.
Rugrat goes and get busted down in Miami.
And Guess who the fuck with? Saurel.
- You gonna beat me? I know your country.
- No!
What the fucking odds? There had to
be ten thousand Swiss bankers in Geneva.
and Rugrat is the one dumb enough
to get himself arrested on U.S. soil.
I know.
[CRYING]
Even more fucked was he got busted for
shit that had nothing to do with me.
And nothing to fucking do with me.
Something about
laundering drug money, to
offshore boat racing to
a guy name Rocky aoki.
You know the founder of Benihana.
Benihana?
Beni Fucking hana.
Beni 'fucking' hana,why, why god.
Why would You be so
cruel as to choose a chain
of fucking Hibachi
Restaurants to take me down?
Long story, short
Saurel ratted me out, but
not before he ratted out
Brad's wife Chantalle.
Who turns out he been fuckin
everytime she went to Switzel.
No, no, no
Alright
One count engaging in conspiracy
to commit securities fraud.
Two counts securities fraud.
One count engaging in Conspiracy
to commit money laundering.
21 counts money laundering.
1 count of obstruction of justice.
Bail has set at 10 million dollars.
What up?
Rocky, how you doin?
- Wooff..
- I'm not a fucking dog.
Yeah, it's getting old to crap to
start to shit in the house again.
- Me too.
- Come here buddy.
- Good to see you pal.
- Me too.
How you doing brother?
You know, shitty pal.
But i'm hanging in there.
Piece of jewelry, check that out.
Can't leave the house, you know.
Sun to get cub and fiber already.
Fuckin Rugrat.
That wig-wearin'faggot I can't believe
that fucking guy were'nt killed..
When he got out, i want
to show on his desks.
Irresponsble prick.
I'll tell you one thing.
That you never eat Benihana again.
I don't care who's birthday it is.
What is that Naomi actually doing?
She right in the house there, say
hi she probably won't wave you back.
Naomi, sweetheart.
What's up her ass, was she mad at me?
No you know.
Probably had to mortgage
the house to make bail.
Probably ended sell a thing in
order pay for all my lawyers.
It's been a night mare
buddy, i tell you the truth.
What do you gonna do right.
Anyway how is Stratton that
more important how is morale?
You piss of cause he have
to make money legally now?
Jordan.
I got the founding partners together.
Talk to them about everything and..
I got you.
How much you got me?
The house, money, don't
worry about it i got you.
I love you buddy. You
know i do it for you right.
- I'll kiss you.
- Alright, enough, enough.
- You wanna beer, pal?
- What do you drink?
We got this non-alcoholic shit.
- What is that?
- It's non alcoholic beer.
It's got no alchohol.
- Is it beer?
- Ya, with no alchohol.
But you drink enough and you
drink a lot to get you fucked up.
No, it's no alchoholic fucking point.
I'm not a scientist, i dont get fuck target
but I can get you a beer, if you want..
I know, but i don't drink, you remember.
- I'm not drink anymore.
- Are you wanna go inside.
And blow some lime and baking powder..
Can't imagine ever not
enjoyed geting fucked up.
- Yeah.
- I loved it.
But i've been sobber.
Fucking sucks.
- Boring right.
- So boring.
Like kill myself.
There is a term and we dont like to
use it unless circumtances dictate..
.. I think they do
dictate in this case and
term is Grenada, have
you ever heard Grenada.
No i haven't.
Grenada very interesting
because it is a small
island nation that was
invaded by the United
States of America 1983 have 9000 people.
And essentially means is.
This case is unloseable.
So, you know, come in
we can have our dick
hanging out of our pants,
nobody gives a fuck.
I'm gonna win.
You Sir.
Are was known.
As a Grenada.
You're looking at real prison time.
Money laundering can get you as much 20 years.
And, our case gonna be stronger, if we
caught your shed and
cash your mattress,.
Oh that right.
Hei Jordan.
Jordan, You're rotting away in
jail, 2 your kids get out the college.
That's not our ambition here.
There's other people involve in this too.
We think, they need to see
their day in courts as well.
Why do I sense there's
an offer in the air?
He's got good sense.
What are you, Craskin?
Full cooperation, he
provides us with the
comprehensive list of all
coconspirators spanning
the last seven years and
he agrees to wear a wire.
- Did you just say wear a wire?
- A wire.
Wow, wow, is that means, you
want me to rat, is that it?
No, i want you to cooperate.
- No, you want me to rat.
- Yes, we want you to rat.
That fucking exactly what
we want you to do, to rat.
How is Christy's party?
- Fine.
- Good.
Babe, i've spoke to the lawyers again today.
There is some really really great news.
Turns out you completely
off the hook, honey.
I know that already.
Right, exactly, you never did
anything wrong in first place right?
It turns out, all the FBI really
wants for me is to a coorperate.
You know.. turns out i
have so much information
about the stock market
and the Wallstreet..
That i could save the
government years of
heartache not to mention
countless dollars.
It gets even better babe.
Because if i do to sign cooperate, i might
only be looking at 4 short years.
How much case, we could start
fresh maybe sell the house.
And any fine that i have to pay
wouldn't due till i serve term.
So, we still have plenty
money left over, you know.
You think, of course bug me out a little
bit is this whole idea for doing it.
Give an information about my friends.
Ohh, like he said, ther is
no friend on Wallstrett right.
Right.
It's exactly silver lining to that
too honey because they said eventually.
Eventually everyone gonna have to
give an information on this case.
So at the end of the day, might
not even a factor, you know.
- Well, that's a good news, right.
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm really happy for you.
What do you mean you happy for me?
- You should be happy for the both of us right?
- Yeah right.
Alright.
Come here baby.
- Gimme a kiss, sweetheart.
- Jordan.
- Let's make love. Please.
- No.
Jordan stop it! No!
Jordan stop it.
I Fucking hate you Jordan.
- Get off me.
- Ohh Baby don't do that.
You know how much i love you right.
Stop that sweetie, please.
You want to fuck me Jordan?
You want to fuck me?
Good, go ahead, go ahead and fucked me.
I want you to fuck me real hard.
I want you to fuck me like
its a last fucking time.
- Come babe, cause i need you to come for me baby.
- Oh i like that.
Come for me baby, i need you to
come for me like its a last fucking time.
Come baby.
Ohh, baby that was so fucking great.
That was a last time.
What do you mean baby?
I mean that was a
last time we had a sex.
What are you talking about.
I want to divorce.
What do you mean, you
want a divorce? What
is that suppose to
mean you want a divorce.
Get off me! i want a divorce.
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
- I don't love you any more Jordan.
You don't love me.
You don't love me anymore huh?
Well it'sjust fucking convinience for
you, now i'm under federal indigement
with electronic brace around my ankle.
Now you decide you don't fucking
love me anymore, is that right?
No, no.
What kind a person are you? Tell me.
- You married me.
- What the fuck is that suppose to mean.
Jordan, this is how it's gonna go,
i'm gonna take the custody of the kids.
If you agree to divorce right now,
i will allow you to take shift, okay
Don't try to fight it.
It will save us both a lot of money
and i got a felling you gonna need it.
You're not taking my kids,
sweetheart, you hear me.
I already talk to lawyer, he said if
you get convicted, i've got a
good chance to getting custody.
I got news for you, you're not fucking
taking my children you
vicious fucking conman.
Fuck you! You fucking bitch.
You're not fucking taking my
goddamn fucking kids, you hear me.
Fuck you! You're not takin my fuckin kids.
Fuckin bitch.
Fuckin whore.
Fucking bitch, piece of shit, fuckin whore.
Look at yourself Jordan.
Sick.
- You're a sick man
- Fuck you.
I've told you not taking my
fucking kids, you fucking..
You think i will let my kids near you.
Look at yourself.
You know what my lawyer said.
My lawyer said that you're
gonna prison for 20 years Jordan.
20 fucking years, you never
gonna see the kids again.
- You think i'm not
gonna see my kids again?
- No, i'm not letting you near my kids.
You don't get understand
what i fucking tell you, huh?
Don't you fucking touch her.
Don't you fucking touch me.
Sweetheart.. you gonna
go with daddy alright.
You cool right, you're with daddy.
Don't you fucking touch her Jordan.
I swear i will fucking kill you!
Alright baby.
Daddy will go little trip
together okay, litle trip together.
Get the key
There you go. Go inside,
put your seat belt on, okay.
Here you go, get your legs in.
I'll take her with me.
I'll told you i'll taking her
with me. You fucking bitch.
You're not gonna stop me.
Little trip.
Don't don't
Get the hell out of here.
Close the door.
Mommy!
- Get out of here.
- Open the fucking door.
No!
Naomi!
- Mommy!
- honey, It's okay.
You're alright.
It's alright.
What's the matter with you.
You alright.
Paragraph one
The defendant shall
plead guilty to all counts
of the indictment currently
pending against him
in the United States District Court
for the Eastern District of New York.
Paragraph 2
Talk normally.
The defendant shall participate
in undercover activities
Breath normally
wearing a recording device also known a wire
After 5 minutes you'll forget you having on.
Conjungtion of the investigation..
Paragraph 4.
The defendant must not commit or
attempted to commit any further crime.
Please.
Let me just sign the fucking
thing, alright, thank you.
- Just here?
- That will be good.
Thank you.
It, wasnt even a choice.
For the next 6 hour i came up with the list.
Friends, enemies, business
associates dan anybody
you ever known me or taking
so much as a stock tip
[CHEERING]
First name on the list.
was Donnie.
George do you know how good it
is to have yo back in this office.
It's not to say when you
gone, it's sad, you understand.
I fucking stiff mad now.
I can't
I can't even think about it you know.
Everytime i think about them my blood boils.
- I can't even say his name.
- I know.
You know, this is disgusting.
I grew up with these guys.
He betrayed me like that?
Do you have a.
Ever Get back, too, about um..
But um.. Account.
( Don't Incriminate
yourself i'm wearing a wire)
You remember was like 4-5 miles
or something like that right.
It was supposed a take back 4-5 million, was it?
Actually i was... I was fucked up Jordan.
Yeah right, it's stupid.
If he calls you, you make
sure you contacts me, okay?
- Of course.
- Yeah.
Are you gonna eat last piece, of your tail.
It's all yours.
I'll take it this.
So, what else is
Tell me and everything.
You know.. how it is,
she hate my fucking guts.
How she, good
She still alive, so, my life fucked you know.
No.
Mr. Jordan.
Mr Jordan You got a visitor.
What?
You got a visitor.
I need you to get dress.
What the fuck is going on.
You going to jail.
- I will get some clothes
- We'll give you hand with that.
Okay.
FBI, every body sit down,
put your hands.. Shut up.
I gave up everyone.
And in returned i got 3 years some
hell hole in nevada i never hear of.
Like my pops mad maxx said.
Chicken come home to roast.
I wanna fucked that meat.
Mr belfort has distinguished
himself in terms of his cooperation.
Mr belfort has helped the governmet went
conviction of over 2
dozen serious offenders.
And help them recover
millions of dollars he
made available for
restritution to their victims.
The sentence of the court should
be 36 months in federal prison.
Please remain the offended.
I'm Sorry.
Stratton Oakmont Belfort sentenced.
I'm not ashamed to admit it.
When we arrive at the prison.
It was absolutely terrified.
Belfort on your feet.
But i ended have been.
See, for brief leading moment.
I forgot i was rich.
And i lived in the place
where everything was for sale.
When you like to learn how to sell it.
To live In some bad
motherfucker in my life, look
at that rockstar, professional
athlete, gangstars.
I'm telling you some real bad
mother fucker but this guy.
my good friends Mr
Jordan Belfort is this
single badass motherfucker
i have ever met.
So i want you right now, to give a warm
aucland new zealand
welcome for my good friend
And The world greatest sales
trainer Mr Jordan Belfort.
Thank you.
Sell me this pen.
It's a amazing pen.
For professionals.
Sell me this pen.
It's a nice pen you
can use the pen to right
down both from your lifes
so you can remember..
Sell me this pen.
Well.. This pen works and
I personally love this pen..