Forget it. It's too risky.
I'm through doing that shit.
You always say that,
the same thing every time.
"I'm through, never again,
too dangerous."
I know that's what I always say.
I'm always right, too.
But you forget about it
in a day or two.
Well, the days of me
forgetting are over...
and the days of me remembering
have just begun.
You know when you go on
like this what you sound like?
I sound like
a sensible fucking man.
You sound like a duck.
Quack, quack, quack...
Take heart, 'cause you're never
gonna have to hear it again...
since I'm never
gonna do it again...
you're never gonna
have to hear me quack...
about how I'm never
gonna do it again.
After tonight.
Correct.
I got all tonight to quack.
Can I get anyone more coffee?
Oh, yes. Thank you.
You're welcome.
I mean, the way it is now...
you're taking the same risk
as when you rob a bank.
You take more of a risk.
Banks are easier.
Federal banks
ain't supposed to stop you...
in any way during a robbery.
They're insured.
Why should they give a fuck?
You don't even need a gun
in a federal bank.
I heard about
this one bloke...
He walks into a bank
with a portable phone.
He gives the phone
to the teller...
bloke on the other end
of the phone says...
"We got this guy's little girl.
"If you don't give him
all your money...
- "we're gonna kill her."
- Did it work?
Fucking way, it works.
That's what I'm talking about!
Knucklehead walks into a bank
with a telephone...
not a pistol, not a shotgun...
a fucking phone.
Cleans the place out.
They don't even lift
a fucking finger.
Did they hurt the little girl?
I don't know. Probably never was
a girl in the first place.
The point isn't the girl.
The point is...
they robbed a bank
with a telephone.
You want to rob banks?
I'm not saying
I want to rob banks.
If we did, it would be easier
than what we been doing.
No more liquor stores?
What we been talking about?
Yeah, no more liquor stores.
Besides, it ain't the giggle
it used to be.
There's too many foreigners
own liquor stores.
Vietnamese, Koreans, they don't
even speak fucking English.
You tell 'em,
"Empty out the register..."
they don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
They make it too personal.
We keep on, one of these gook
fucker's gonna make us kill him.
I'm not gonna kill anybody.
I don't want to kill anybody,
either.
But they'll probably
put us in a situation...
where it's us or them.
And if it's not the gooks,
it's these old fucking Jews...
who've owned the store
for fifteen fucking generations.
You got Grandpa Irving
sitting behind the counter...
with a fucking Magnum
in his hand.
Try walking into one of those
places with nothing but a phone.
See how far that gets you.
Fuck it. We're out of it.
Yeah, well, what then?
Day jobs?
- Not in this life.
- What, then?
Garcon! Coffee!
This place.
Garcon means "boy."
This place? A coffee shop?
What's wrong with that?
Nobody ever robs restaurants.
Why not?
Bars, liquor stores,
gas stations...
you get your head blown off
sticking up one of them.
Restaurants, on the other hand,
you catch with their pants down.
They're not expecting
to get robbed.
Not as expecting, anyway.
I bet you could
cut down on the hero factor...
in a place like this.
Correct.
Same as banks,
these places are insured.
Manager... he don't give a fuck.
He's just trying
to get you out the door...
before you start
plugging the diners.
Waitresses? Fucking forget it.
No way they're taking a bullet
for the register.
Busboys, some wetback
getting paid $1.50 an hour...
really give a fuck
you're stealing from the owner?
Customers sitting
with food in their mouths.
They don't know
what's going on.
One minute they're
having a Denver omelette...
next minute, someone's
sticking a gun in their face.
See, I got the idea...
last liquor store we stuck up.
Remember?
All the customers
kept coming in?
Yeah.
You got the idea
taking their wallets.
Mm-hmm.
- Now, that was a good idea.
Thank you.
Made more from the wallets
than we did from the register.
Yes, we did.
- People come to restaurants.
A lot of wallets.
Pretty smart, huh?
Pretty smart.
I'm ready. Let's do it.
Right now, right here.
Come on.
- All right.
Same as last time, remember?
You're crowd control.
I handle employees.
I love you, Pumpkin.
I love you, Honey Bunny.
Everybody, be cool!
This is a robbery!
Any of you
fucking pricks move...
and I'll execute every
motherfucking last one of you!
Ha ha ha
Jungle boogie,
Jungle boogie
- Get it on
- Jungle boogie
- Get up with the boogie
- Get up with the get down
- Jungle boogie
- Get down with the boogie
- Come and shake it around
OK, so tell me again
about the hash bars.
- OK. What you want to know?
- Hash is legal there, right?
Yeah, it's legal,
but it ain't 100% legal.
You just can't walk
into a restaurant...
roll a joint,
and start puffing away.
I mean, they want you to smoke
in your home...
- or certain designated places.
- And those are hash bars?
Yeah, it breaks down like this.
It's legal to buy it,
it's legal to own it...
and if you're the proprietor
of a hash bar...
it's legal to sell it.
It's legal to carry it,
but... but that doesn't matter...
'cause, get a load of this,
all right?
If you get stopped by a cop
in Amsterdam...
it's illegal
for them to search you.
I mean, that's a right the cops
in Amsterdam don't have.
Oh, man, I'm going.
That's all there is to it.
I'm fucking going.
I know, baby.
You'd dig it the most.
But you know what the funniest
thing about Europe is?
- What?
- It's the little differences.
I mean, they got the same shit
over there that they got here...
but it's just
a little different.
Example?
You can go to a movie theater
in Amsterdam and buy a beer.
And I don't mean just, like,
in no paper cup.
I'm talking about
a glass of beer.
And in Paris, you can
buy a beer at McDonald's.
And you know what they call...
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese
in Paris?
They don't call it
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese?
No, man, they got
the metric system there.
They wouldn't know what the fuck
a Quarter-Pounder is.
What do they call it?
They call it
a "Royale with Cheese."
- "Royale with Cheese."
That's right.
What do they call a Big Mac?
Big Mac's a Big Mac,
but they call it "Le Big Mac."
"Le Big Mac." Ha ha ha ha.
What do they call a Whopper?
I don't know.
I didn't go into Burger King.
You know what they put on
French fries in Holland...
- instead of ketchup?
- What?
- Mayonnaise.
- Goddamn!
Ha ha ha.
I've seen 'em do it, man.
They fucking drown 'em
in that shit.
Yuck.
We should have shotguns
for this kind of deal.
- How many up there?
- Three or four.
That's counting our guy?
I'm not sure.
So that means it could be
up to five guys up there?
It's possible.
We should have fucking shotguns.
What's her name?
Mia.
Mia. How did Marsellus
and her meet?
I don't know.
However people meet people.
She used to be an actress.
Oh, really? She do anything
I'd have seen?
I think her biggest deal
was she starred in a pilot.
Pilot? What's a pilot?
Well, you know the shows on TV?
I don't watch TV.
Yeah, but you are aware...
that there's an invention
called television...
and on this invention
they show shows, right?
Yeah.
The way they pick TV shows,
they make one show.
That show's called a pilot.
Then they show that one show
to the people who pick shows...
and on the strength
of that one show...
they decide if they want
to make more shows.
Some get chosen
and become television programs.
Some don't, become nothing.
She starred in one of the ones
that became nothing.
You remember Antwan Rockamora?
Half-black, half-Samoan...
used to call him
"Tony Rocky Horror"?
Yeah, maybe. Fat, right?
I wouldn't go so far
as to call the brother fat.
I mean, he got a weight problem.
What's the nigger gonna do,
he's Samoan.
Yeah, I think I know
who you mean. What about him?
Well,
Marsellus fucked him up good.
Word around the campfire is...
it was on account
of Marsellus Wallace's wife.
So, what'd he do, fuck her?
No, no, no, no, no.
Nothing that bad.
Well, then, what, then?
Gave her a foot massage.
- A foot massage? That's it?
- Mm-hmm.
Then what did Marsellus do?
Sent a couple of cats
over to his place.
They took him out on his patio,
threw his ass over the balcony.
Nigger fell four stories.
They had a little garden
down at the bottom...
enclosed in glass,
like a greenhouse.
Nigger fell through that.
Since then, he kind of
developed a speech impediment.
That's a damn shame.
But still, I have to say...
you play with matches,
you get burned.
What do you mean?
You don't be giving
Marsellus Wallace's new bride...
a foot massage.
You don't think he overreacted?
Well, Antwan probably
didn't expect Marsellus...
to react the way he did,
but he had to expect a reaction.
It was a foot massage.
A foot massage is nothing.
I give my mother a foot massage.
No, it's laying hands
in a familiar way...
on Marsellus' new wife.
I mean, is it as bad
as eating her pussy out?
No, but it's
the same fucking ballpark.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
stop right there.
Eating a bitch out and giving
a bitch a foot massage...
ain't even
the same fucking thing.
It's not.
It's the same ballpark.
Ain't no fucking ballpark,
neither.
Now, look, maybe your method
of massage differs from mine...
but you know
touching his wife's feet...
and sticking your tongue
in her holiest of holies...
ain't the same fucking ballpark.
It ain't the same league.
It ain't even
the same fucking sport.
Look,
foot massages don't mean shit.
Have you ever given
a foot massage?
Don't be telling me
about foot massages.
I'm the foot fucking master.
- You given a lot of 'em?
- Shit, yeah.
Got my technique down
and everything.
I don't be tickling or nothing.
Would you give a guy
a foot massage?
Fuck you.
- You given 'em a lot?
- Fuck you.
You know, I'm kind of tired.
I could use
a foot massage myself.
Yo, yo, yo, man.
You best back off.
I'm getting
a little pissed here.
- This is the door.
- There it is.
What time you got?
7:22 in the a.m.
No, it ain't quite time yet.
Come on. Let's hang back.
Just 'cause I wouldn't give
no man a foot massage...
don't make it right
for Marsellus...
to throw Antwan
off a building...
into a glass
motherfucking house...
fucking up the way the nigger
talks. That shit ain't right.
Motherfucker do that shit to me,
he better paralyze my ass...
'cause I'd kill
the motherfucker...
- you know what I'm saying?
- I ain't saying it's right.
But you're saying a foot massage
don't mean nothing...
and I'm saying it does.
I've given a million ladies
a million foot massages...
and they all meant something.
Now, we act like they don't,
but they do.
That's what's so fucking cool
about 'em.
There's a sensuous thing
going on where, you know...
you don't talk about it, but you
know it, and she knows it.
Fucking Marsellus knew it...
and Antwan should've fucking
better known better.
I mean,
that's his fucking wife, man.
This ain't a man with a sense
of humor about this shit.
You know what I'm saying?
It's an interesting point.
Come on.
Let's get into character.
What's her name again?
- Mia.
Why you so interested
in big man's wife?
Well, he's going out of town,
Florida...
and he asked me if I'd take care
of her while he's gone.
- Take care of her?
- No, man. Just take her out.
You know, show her a good time.
Make sure she don't get lonely.
You're gonna be taking
Mia Wallace out on a date?
It is not a date.
It's just like if you were going
to take your buddy's wife...
to a movie or something.
It's just good company,
that's all.
It's not a date.
It's definitely not a date.
Hey, kids. How you boys doing?
Hey, keep chilling.
You know who we are?
We're associates
of your business partner...
Marsellus Wallace.
You do remember your business
partner, don't you?
Let me take a wild guess here.
- You're Brett, right?
- Yeah.
I thought so.
You remember your business
partner Marsellus Wallace...
don't you, Brett?
Yeah, I remember him.
Good.
Looks like me and Vincent
caught you boys at breakfast.
Sorry about that.
What you having?
- Hamburgers.
- Hamburgers!
The cornerstone
of any nutritious breakfast.
What kind of hamburgers?
Ch-ch-cheeseburgers.
No, no, no, no.
Where'd you get 'em?
McDonald's, Wendy's,
Jack-in-the-Box, where?
Um, Big Kahuna Burger.
Big Kahuna Burger. That's
that Hawaiian burger joint.
I hear they got
some tasty burgers.
I ain't never had one myself.
How are they?
They're good.
You mind if I try one of yours?
- This is yours here, right?
- Yeah.
Mmm! This is a tasty burger.
Vincent, you ever had
a Big Kahuna Burger?
Want a bite?
They're real tasty.
I ain't hungry.
If you like burgers,
give 'em a try sometime.
Me, I can't usually get 'em...
'cause my girlfriend's
a vegetarian...
which pretty much makes me
But I do love the taste
of a good burger. Mmm.
You know what they call...
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese
in France?
- No.
- Tell him, Vincent.
Royale with Cheese.
You know why they call it that?
Because of the metric system?
Check out the big brain
on Brett!
You're a smart motherfucker.
That's right. The metric system.
What's in this?
- Sprite.
- Sprite, good.
You mind if I have
some of your tasty beverage...
to wash this down with?
Go right ahead.
Ahh.
That hit the spot.
You, Flock of Seagulls.
You know why we're here?
Why don't you tell
my man Vince here...
- where you got the shit hid at?
It's over there.
I don't remember asking you
a goddamn thing!
- You were saying?
- It's in the cupboard.
N-no.
The one by your kn-knees.
We happy?
Vincent? We happy?
Yeah, we happy.
Pbbbt.
Look... I'm sorry, uh,
I... I didn't get your name.
I got yours. Uh, Vincent, right?
But... but I... I never got yours.
My name's Pitt...
and your ass ain't talking
your way out of this shit.
No, no, no.
I just want you to know how...
I just want you to know
how sorry we are...
that things got so fucked up
with us and... and Mr. Wallace.
W-we got into this thing with
the best intentions. I never...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I break your concentration?
I didn't mean
to do that. Please, continue.
You were saying something
about "best intentions."
What's the matter?
Oh, y-you were finished?
Oh, well, allow me to retort.
What does Marsellus Wallace
look like?
What?
What country are you from?
Wh-what?
"What" ain't no country
I ever heard of!
- They speak English in "What"?
- Wh-what?
English, motherfucker!
Do you speak it?
Yes!
- Then you know what I'm saying.
- Yes!
Describe what Marsellus Wallace
looks like!
What? I...
Say "what" again!
I dare you!
I double-dare you, motherfucker!
Say "what"
one more goddamn time!
H-h-he's black.
- Go on!
- He's bald.
- Does he look like a bitch?
- What?
Oww! Aah!
- Does he look like a bitch?
- No!
Then why you try to fuck him
like a bitch, Brett?
- I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
Yes, you did, Brett!
You tried to fuck him.
- No.
Marsellus Wallace
don't like to be fucked...
by anybody except Mrs. Wallace.
You read the Bible, Brett?
Y-yes.
Well, there's this
passage I got memorized...
sort of fits this occasion.
"Ezekiel" 25:17.
"The path of the righteous man
is beset on all sides...
"by the inequities
of the selfish...
"and the tyranny of evil men.
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity and good will...
"shepherds the weak through
the Valley of Darkness...
"for he is truly
his brother's keeper...
"and the finder
of lost children.
"And I will strike down
upon thee...
"with great vengeance
and furious anger...
"those who attempt to poison
and destroy My brothers.
"And you will know
My name is the Lord...
"when I lay My vengeance
upon thee!"
No!
Let's stay together
I think you're gonna find...
when all this shit
is over and done...
I think
you're gonna find yourself...
one smilin' motherfucker.
Thing is, Butch,
right now you got ability.
But painful as it may be,
ability don't last.
And your days
are just about over.
Now, that's a hard
motherfuckin' fact of life...
but that's a fact of life...
your ass is gonna have
to get realistic about.
See, this business
is filled to the brim...
with unrealistic
motherfuckers...
motherfuckers who thought
their ass would age like wine.
If you mean it turns
to vinegar, it does.
If you mean it gets better
with age, it don't.
Besides, Butch...
how many fights you think
you got in you, anyway?
Hmm? Two?
Boxers don't have
an Old-timer's Day.
You came close,
but you never made it.
And if you were
gonna make it...
You would have made it
before now.
Good or bad
Or happy or sad
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Ooh, ooooh, ooh
Yeah
You my nigger?
It certainly appears so.
Night of the fight,
you may feel a slight sting.
That's pride fucking with you.
Fuck pride!
Pride only hurts.
It never helps.
You fight through that shit.
'Cause a year from now...
when you're kickin' it
in the Caribbean...
you're gonna say to yourself,
"Marsellus Wallace was right."
Ha ha ha.
I got no problem with that,
Mr. Wallace.
In the fifth,
your ass goes down.
Say it.
In the fifth, my ass goes down.
Yo, Vincent Vega,
our man in Amsterdam.
Jules Winnfield,
our man in Inglewood.
Get your asses on in here!
Goddamn, nigger!
What's up with them clothes?
You don't even want to know.
Where's the big man?
Big man's right over there
taking care of some business.
Why don't you hang back
for a second or two, you know?
You see the white boy leave,
just go on over.
How you been?
I've been doing pretty good.
How 'bout yourself?
All right.
So, I hear you're taking Mia out
tomorrow?
At Marsellus' request.
Have you met Mia?
Not yet.
- What's so fucking funny?
- Not a goddamn thing.
I got to piss.
Look, I'm not a fucking idiot,
all right?
It's the big man's wife.
I'm gonna sit across from her...
chew my food
with my mouth closed...
laugh at her fucking jokes,
and that's it.
Hey, my name's Paul,
and this shit's between y'all.
Then what did you fucking ask me
about it for?
Asshole.
Give me a pack of Red Apples.
Filters?
- Nah.
You looking at something,
friend?
You ain't my friend, palooka.
What was that?
I think you heard me just fine,
punchy.
Vincent Vega's in the house?
My nigger.
Get your ass over here.
You'd never do that to me
- What's up?
- I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Pack of Red Apples.
$1.40.
And some matches.
Here's what I want to do
Hey
We ought to stay together
It's as if it turns...
every part of your body
into the tip of a penis.
Wow.
I'll lend it to you.
It's a great book on piercing.
Well, you see
how they use that gun...
to pierce your ears?
They don't use that to pierce
your nipples, too, do they?
Forget that gun.
That gun goes against
the entire idea behind piercing.
All my piercing,
eighteen places on my body...
every one of 'em
done with a needle.
Five in each ear. One through
the nipple of my left breast.
Two in my right nostril.
One in my left eyebrow.
One in my belly. One in my lip.
One in my clit.
And I wear a stud in my tongue.
Excuse me.
I was just curious, but, um...
why would you wear a stud
in your tongue?
It's a sex thing.
Helps fellatio.
Vincenzo. Step into my office.
This is Panda,
from Mexico.
Very good stuff.
Now, that's Bava.
Different, but equally good.
And that is Choco, from
the Hartz Mountains of Germany.
Now, the first two
are the same...
300 a gram.
Those are friend prices.
But this one
is a little more expensive.
This is 500 a gram,
but when you shoot it...
you will know
where that extra money went.
Now, there's nothing wrong
with these two.
This is real, real,
real good shit.
But this one
is a fucking madman.
Remember,
I just got back from Amsterdam.
Am I a nigger?
Are we in Inglewood?
No. You're in my home.
Now, white people
who know the difference...
between good shit and bad shit,
this is the house they come to.
Now, my shit,
I'll take the Pepsi Challenge...
with that Amsterdam shit
any old day of the fucking week.
That's a bold statement.
This ain't Amsterdam, Vince.
This is a seller's market.
Coke is fucking dead as... dead.
Heroin is coming back
in a big fucking way.
All right,
give me three grams of madman.
If it's as good
as you say it is...
I'll come back
and buy another thousand.
Well, I just hope that I still
have some left for you.
But... I'm giving you some
out of my own private stash.
That is what a nice guy I am.
Hey, I'm out of balloons.
Is a baggie all right?
Yeah, that's cool.
All right.
I'll just get one for you.
Honey,
will you get me some baggies...
and, uh,
twistix from the kitchen?
OK.
Hey, uh,
what do you think about Trudi?
She ain't got a boyfriend.
You want to, uh,
hang out, get high?
Which one is Trudi?
The one with all the shit
in her face.
No, that's Jody. That's my wife.
- I'm sorry, man.
- Thank you.
No, I can't.
Um, I gotta be someplace.
All right. No problemo.
I'll take a rain check.
Oh.
Thank you, Jody.
Still got your Malibu?
Ah, man. You know what some
fucker did the other day?
What?
- Fucking keyed it.
- Oh, man, that's fucked up.
Tell me about it.
I had it in storage for 3 years.
It was out 5 days...
and some dickless piece of shit
fucked with it.
They should be
fucking killed, man.
No trial, no jury,
straight to execution.
Boy, I wish
I could've caught him doing it.
I'd have given anything
to catch that asshole doing it.
It'a been worth him
doing it...
just so I could've caught him
doing it.
- What a fucker!
- What's more chicken shit...
than fucking
with a man's automobile?
I mean, don't fuck
with another man's vehicle.
- You don't do it.
- It's just against the rules.
- Thank you.
Mind if I shoot up here?
Mi casa, su casa.
Muchas gracias.
Hello?
Billy Ray was a preacher's son
And when his daddy
would visit he'd come along
Vincent.
I'm on the intercom.
Where is it?
Where is the intercom?
It's on the wall
by the two African fellows.
To your right.
...was the son
of a preacher man
The only boy...
Warm. Warmer. Disco.
Hello.
Push the button
if you want to talk.
- Hello.
- Go make yourself a drink...
and I'll be down
in two shakes of a lamb's tail.
The bar is by the fireplace.
Being good isn't always easy
OK.
When he started
sweet-talkin' to me
He'd come and tell me
everything is all right
He'd kiss and tell me
Can I get away again tonight?
The only one
who could ever reach me
Was the son of a preacher man
The only boy
who could ever teach me
Was the son of a preacher man
Yes, he was, he was
- Lord knows he was,
- Ooh, yes, he was
How well I remember
The look
that was in his eyes
Stealin' kisses
from me on the sly
Takin' time to make time
Tellin' me that he's all mine
Learnin' from
each other's knowin'
Lookin' to see
how much we've grown
And the only one
who could ever reach me
Was the son of a preacher man
The only boy
who could ever teach me
Was the son of a preacher man
Yes, he was, he was
Oh, yes, he was
Let's go.
What the fuck is this place?
This is Jack Rabbit Slim's.
An Elvis man should love it.
Come on, Mia,
let's go get a steak.
You can get a steak here,
daddy-o.
Don't be a...
Oh, after you,
kitty cat.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Now, how may I help you?
There's a reservation
under Wallace.
- Wallace?
- We reserved a car.
Oh, a car. Why don't you
seat them in the Chrysler?
Throw a nickel in the jukebox
Then we start to rock
School gal, baby,
gonna tell you some news
You sure do look good
in them baby doll shoes
Well, it's one, two,
pull off my shoes
Three, four,
get out on the floor
Five, six, gonna get your kicks
Down at the corner
of Lincoln and 46th, yeah
All right
I've been waitin'
in school all day long
Waitin' on the bell
to ring so I can go home
Throw my books on the table,
Pick up the telephone
Come on, baby,
let's get somethin' goin'
Decaf!
Just a minute.
Throw a nickel in the jukebox
Then we start to rock
School's out baby,
gonna tell you some news
You sure do look good
in them baby doll shoes
Well, it's one, two,
pull off my shoes
Three, four,
get out on the floor
Five, six,
come get your kicks
Down at the corner
of Lincoln and 46th
You gotta move,
start rockin', baby
Rockin', rockin', baby,
gonna rock all night
Rock all night,
just wait and see
Ricky! Ricky!
Let's hear it for Ricky Nelson!
Fantastic job, Rick.
Thank you very much.
Vincent!
Just so that you all know...
Ricky will be back
in the second half of our show.
So we hope you enjoy your meals
here at Jack Rabbit Slim's.
Thank you.
Call for...
Phillip... Morris!
What do you think?
I think it's like a wax museum
with a pulse.
Hi, I'm Buddy.
What can I get you?
Let's see.
Steak, steak, steak.
Yeah, the Douglas Sirk steak.
I'll have that.
How do you want that cooked?
Burnt to a crisp,
or bloody as hell?
Bloody as hell, and oh, yeah,
look at this. Vanilla Coke.
What about you, Peggy Sue?
I'll have the Durwood Kirby
burger, bloody, and...
the $5.00 shake.
How do you want that shake?
Martin and Lewis,
or Amos and Andy?
Martin and Lewis.
Did you just order
a $5.00 shake?
Mm-hmm.
That's a shake.
That's milk and ice cream.
Last I heard.
- That's $5.00?
You don't put bourbon in it
or nothin'?
- No.
- Just checkin'.
I'll be right back
with your drinks.
...lonesome town
To cry my troubles away...
Could you, um...
roll me one of those, cowboy?
You can have this one, cowgirl.
Thanks.
...with regret
Think nothin' of it.
...lonesome town
I can learn to forget
So... Marsellus said you
just got back from Amsterdam.
- Sure did.
How long were you there?
Just over three years.
I go there about once a year
to chill out for a month.
No kiddin'? I didn't know that.
Why would you?
I heard you did a pilot.
That was my fifteen minutes.
What was it?
It was a show about a team
of female secret agents...
called "Fox Force Five."
- What?
"Fox Force Five."
Fox, as in we're
a bunch of foxy chicks.
Force, as in we're a force
to be reckoned with.
And Five, as in there's one,
two, three, four, five of us.
There was a blond one...
Sommerset O'Neal.
She was the leader.
The Japanese Fox
was a kung-fu master.
The black girl
was a demolition expert.
French Fox's speciality was sex.
What was your specialty?
Knives.
Character I played,
Raven McCoy...
her background was she grew up
raised by circus performers.
According to the show...
she was the deadliest woman
in the world with a knife...
and she knew
a zillion old jokes.
Her grandfather,
an old vaudevillian, taught her.
And if we would've
got picked up...
they would've worked in
a gimmick where every show...
I would've told another joke.
You know any of them old jokes?
Well, I only got the chance
to say one...
'cause we only did one show.
- Tell me.
- It's corny.
Don't be that way.
Tell me.
No. You wouldn't like it,
and I'd be embarrassed.
You'd be em...
You told 50 million people,
and you can't tell me?
I promise I won't laugh.
That's what I'm afraid of,
Vince.
That's not what I meant,
and you know it.
Well, now I'm definitely
not gonna tell you...
'cause it's been
built up too much.
What a gyp.
Martin and Lewis.
Vanilla Coke.
Mmm. Yummy.
You think
I could have a sip of that?
Be my guest.
I gotta know what a $5.00 shake
tastes like.
You can use my straw.
I don't have cooties.
- Yeah, but maybe I do.
- Cooties, I can handle.
All right.
Goddamn, that's a pretty
fuckin' good milk shake.
Told you.
I don't know
if it was worth $5.00...
but it was pretty fucking good.
Don't you hate that?
Hate what?
Uncomfortable silences.
Why do we feel
it's necessary...
to yak about bullshit
in order to be comfortable?
I don't know,
but it's a good question.
That's when you know you've
found somebody really special...
when you can just
shut the fuck up for a minute...
and comfortably share a silence.
Well, I don't think
we're quite there yet...
but don't feel bad.
We just met each other.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to go to the bathroom
and powder my nose.
You sit here
and think of something to say.
I'll do that.
OK.
I said goddamn! Goddamn.
Goddamn.
I need some hair spray.
Mmm. Don't you just love it...
when you come back
from the bathroom...
to find your food
waiting for you?
We're lucky
we got anything at all.
I don't think Buddy Holly's
much of a waiter.
Maybe we should've sat
in Marilyn Monroe's section.
Would you like some coffee?
Which one? There's two Monroes.
No, there's not.
That is Marilyn Monroe.
That is Mamie Van Doren.
And I don't see
Jayne Mansfield.
She must have the night off
or somethin'.
- Pretty smart.
- Yeah, I got my moments.
So, did you think
of somethin' to say?
Actually, I did.
However...
You seem like
a really nice person...
and I don't want to offend you.
Ooh. This doesn't sound like
the usual mindless, boring...
gettin'-to-know-you chitchat.
That sounds like you actually
have somethin' to say.
Well, well, I do.
I do.
But you have to promise
not to be offended.
No! No, no, no.
You can't promise
somethin' like that.
I have no idea
what you're gonna ask me...
so you can go ahead and ask me
and my natural response
could be to get offended.
Then,
through no fault of my own...
- I would've broken my promise.
- Let's just forget it.
That's an impossibility.
Trying to forget anything
as intriguing as this...
would be an exercise
in futility.
Is that a fact?
Besides,
isn't it more exciting...
- when you don't have permission?
All right. All right.
Well, here it goes.
What did you, uh, think about
what happened to Antwan?
Who's Antwan?
Tony Rocky Horror. You know him.
He fell out of a window.
Mmm. Mmm.
Well, that is one way to say it.
Another way to say it
would be that he was thrown out.
Another way would be was he was
thrown out by Marsellus...
and yet even another way
is to say...
he was thrown of a window
by Marsellus because of you.
Is that a fact?
No, no. It's not a fact.
It's just what I heard.
- It's just what I heard.
- Who told you?
They.
They talk a lot, don't they?
They certainly do.
Don't be shy, Vincent.
What else did they say?
Well, I'm not... I'm not shy.
Um...
Did it involve the "F" word?
No. No, no, no.
They just said that Antwan
had given you a foot massage.
- And?
- And... and nothin'. That's it.
You heard Marsellus
threw Tony Rocky Horror...
out of a four-story window
for giving me a foot massage?
Mm-hmm.
- And you believe that?
Well, I mean...
at the time I was told,
it sounded reasonable.
Marsellus throwing Tony
out of a four-story window...
for massaging my feet
seemed reasonable?
No, it seemed excessive...
but that doesn't mean it didn't
happen. I mean, I understand...
that Marsellus is very,
very protective of you.
A husband being protective
of his wife is one thing.
A husband
almost killing another man...
for touching his wife's feet
is something else.
But did it happen?
Only thing Antwan
ever touched of mine...
was my hand when he shook it...
at my wedding.
Really?
Truth is,
nobody knows why Marsellus...
threw Tony out of
that four-story window...
except Marsellus and Tony.
But when you little scamps
get together...
you're worse
than a sewing circle.
Ladies and gentlemen...
now the moment
you've all been waiting for...
the world-famous Jack Rabbit
Slim's Twist Contest.
This is where
one lucky couple...
will win this handsome trophy
that Marilyn here is holding.
Now, who'll be
our first contestants?
Right here!
Hey, all right!
- I wanna dance.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I do believe Marsellus...
my husband, your boss...
told you to take me out
and do whatever I wanted.
Now I want to dance.
I want to win.
I want that trophy,
so dance good.
All right. You asked for it.
Let's hear it
for our first contestants.
Let's meet our first
contestants here this evening.
Young lady, what is your name?
Mrs. Mia Wallace.
And how about your fella here?
Vincent Vega.
All right. Let's see
what you can do. Take it away!
Yay!
Go for it!
All right!
It was a teenage wedding
And the old folks
wished 'em well
You could see that Pierre
Did truly love the mademoiselle
And now the young
monsieur and Madame
Have rung the chapel bell
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They furnished off
an apartment
With a two-room Roebuck sale
The coolerator was crammed
With TV dinners and ginger ale
But when Pierre found work
The little money comin'
worked out well
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They had a hi-fi phono
Boy, did they let it blast
700 little records
All rock, rhythm, and jazz
But when the sun went down
The rapid tempo
of the music fell
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They had a teenage wedding
And the old folks
wished 'em well
You could see that Pierre
Did truly love
the mademoiselle
Ha ha ha!
Is that what you call
an uncomfortable silence?
I don't know what you call that.
Drinks. Music.
I'm gonna take a piss.
That's a little bit
more information...
than I needed, Vince,
but go right ahead.
Girl
Bow, bow, bow
You'll be a woman soon
I love you so much,
can't count all the ways
I'd die for you, girl,
and all they can say is
He's not your kind
They never get tired
of puttin' me down
And I never know
when I come around
What I'm gonna find
Don't let them
make up your mind
Don't you know, girl
Bow, bow, bow
You'll be a woman soon
One drink and that's it.
Don't be rude.
Drink your drink.
But do it quickly.
Say good night and go home.
Girl
You'll be a woman soon
Soon
You'll need a woman
I've been misunderstood
for all of my life
But what they're sayin', girl,
just cuts like a knife
The boy's no good
Well, I finally have found
what I've been lookin' for
But if they get a chance,
they'll end it for sure
Sure they would
Baby, I've done...
You see, this is a moral test
of oneself.
Whether or not
you can maintain loyalty.
Because being loyal
is very important.
They never
get tired of puttin' me down
And I never know
when I come around
What I'm gonna find
Don't let them
make up your mind
Don't you know, girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
Girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
Hello.
Girl
So, you're gonna go out there,
you're gonna say...
"Good night.
I've had a very lovely evening."
Walk out the door
and get in the car.
Go home, jerk off,
and that's all you're gonna do.
Now it's up to you, girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
You'll be a woman soon
Soon
You'll need a man
All right, Mia.
So, listen, I gotta go.
All right?
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ.
You f... Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, fuck me! Fuck me!
Oh, come on, girl.
We're gettin' out of here.
We gotta walk now.
Don't fucking die on me, Mia.
Silly fuck.
Answer!
Have you got the ring?
Why, certainly.
Join hands,
you two love birds.
Uh-uh.
Please. Please.
Hurry up.
Yes, yes, yes, indeed.
Hold hands, you love birds.
Fuck you, Lance! Answer!
Now, what do you say?
I give up,
I'll marry you!
Lance!
The goddamn phone's ringing!
I can hear it.
I thought you told
those fuckin' assholes...
never to call here this late.
Yeah, I told 'em...
and that is exactly
what I'm going to tell...
this fucking asshole right now.
I'll teach you a thing or two.
Don't you dare strike me!
Hello?
Lance, Vincent.
I'm in big fuckin' trouble, man.
I'm comin' to your house.
Whoa, whoa.
Hold your horses, man.
Wh-what's the problem?
I got this chick,
she's fuckin' Odin on me.
Don't bring her here.
I'm not even fucking
joking with you, man.
Don't not be bringing some
fucked-up pooh-butt to my house.
No choice.
She's O.D. In'?
She's fuckin' dyin' on me, man!
OK, well, then you bite
the fuckin' bullet...
and you take her to a hospital
and call a lawyer.
Negative.
This is not
my fuckin' problem, man!
You fucked her up,
you fuckin' deal with this!
Are you talking to me
on a cellular phone?
I don't know you.
Who is this?
Don't come here.
I'm hanging up the phone.
Prank caller! Prank caller!
What the hell was that?!
Have you lost
your fucking mind?!
You were talking about drug shit
on a cellular ph...
Lance, help me.
You crashed your car
into my fuckin' house!
Grab her feet.
Hey, hey, hey!
Are you deaf?
You are not bringing this
fucked-up bitch into my house!
This fucked-up bitch
is Marsellus Wallace's wife.
Do you know
who Marsellus Wallace is?
Yeah.
If she croaks on me,
I'm a fucking grease spot!
I will be forced to tell him
that you did not help...
and that you let her die
on your fuckin' lawn.
Now, come on, help me.
Help me. Pick her up.
Shit!
Lance!
It's 1:30
in the goddamn morning.
What the fuck's
going on out here?
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Who's she?
Go to the fridge
and get the adrenaline shot.
What's wrong with her?
- She's O.D.ing!
- Get her out of here!
Get the shot!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, too!
What a fuckin' bitch.
Just keep talkin' to her.
She's gettin' the shot.
I'm gonna go get
my little black medical book.
What the fuck you need
a medical book for?
I never had to give
an adrenaline shot before.
You've never given
an adrenaline shot?
I never had to.
I don't go joypopping
with a bunch of bubblegummers.
My friends
can handle their highs.
- Get the shot!
- I am if you'll let me.
I ain't fucking stopping you!
Well, stop talkin' to me.
Start talkin' to her!
- Get the shot!
- All right!
Hurry up, Lance!
We're losin' her!
I'm lookin' as fast as I can!
What's he lookin' for?
I don't know. Some book.
What are you lookin' for?
My little black medical book!
A little black
fuckin' medical book!
It's like a textbook
they give to nurses.
I never saw no medical book.
Well, trust me, I have one.
If it's so important, why don't
you keep it with the shot?
I don't know!
Stop bothering me!
While you're lookin' for it,
she's gonna die on our carpet.
You're never gonna find anything
in this mess.
Honey, I'm going to fucking
kill you if you don't shut up!
Get in here!
Christ.
Get the fuck out of my way.
Pig.
Quit fuckin' around
and give her the shot.
While I'm doin' this...
you take off her shirt
and find her heart.
It's got to be exact?
Yeah, exact.
A shot in the heart,
so I guess it's gotta be exact.
I don't know exactly where
her heart is. I think it's here.
- That's it.
- This it?
What I need
is a big fat magic marker.
- You got it?
- What?
A magic marker! A felt pen!
A fuckin' black magic marker!
All right.
Hurry up.
Fuck. OK, OK, OK.
I think it's ready.
- Hurry up, man. Hurry up.
- I'll tell you what to do.
No, no, no.
You're gonna give her the shot.
- You're gonna give her the shot.
- I ain't givin' her the shot.
- I never done this before.
I ain't never done it before,
either. I ain't startin' now.
You brought her here, that means
you're gonna give her the shot.
The day I bring an O.D.ing bitch
to your house...
then I give her the shot.
Give her the shot.
- Give it to me.
- Here.
Give me that.
Tell me what to do.
OK. You're giving her
an injection of adrenaline...
straight to her heart,
but she's got a breastplate.
You've got to
pierce through that.
You gotta bring the needle down
in a stabbing motion.
I gotta stab her three times?
No! You don't gotta stab her
three times. Just once.
But hard enough to get through
her breastplate into her heart.
Once you do that,
you press down on the plunger.
OK, then what happens?
I'm kind of curious
about that myself.
This ain't no fuckin' joke, man!
- Am I gonna kill her?
- No, no!
She's supposed to come
out of it like that.
All right. Count to three.
Ready?
One...
two...
Three!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
If you're all right,
then say something.
Something.
Ha ha. That was fuckin' trippy.
Ha ha ha ha.
Uhh.
Oh, man.
Mia. Mia.
What's...
what's your thoughts on... on...
on how to handle this?
What's yours?
Well, I'm of the opinion...
that if Marsellus
lived his whole life...
he don't need to know nothin'
about this incident.
If Marsellus knew
about this incident...
I'd be in as much trouble
as you.
I seriously doubt that.
I can keep a secret if you can.
Shake on it?
Mum's the word?
Cool.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
I'm gonna go home
and have a heart attack.
Vincent!
Do you want to hear
my "Fox Force Five" joke?
Sure.
Except that I think I'm still
a little too petrified to laugh.
No, you won't laugh
'cause it's not funny.
But if you still wanna hear it,
I'll tell it.
I can't wait.
OK.
Three tomatoes are walking
down the street...
Papa Tomato, Mama Tomato,
and Baby Tomato.
Baby Tomato
starts lagging behind...
and Papa Tomato
gets really angry...
goes back and squishes him,
and says, "Catch up."
Hmm. Hmm.
Ketchup.
See you around.
Oh, that Paddlefoot...
he funny, silly dog.
He think totem pole alive.
Hee hee hee!
He arctic tenderfoot.
Ho ho ho ho!
That totem pole
been here forever.
Butch?
Butch,
stop watching TV a second.
Yeah?
We got a special visitor.
Now... do you
remember when I told you...
your daddy died
in a P.O.W. Camp?
Well... this here
is Captain Koons.
He was in the P.O.W. Camp
with Daddy.
Hello, little man.
Boy, I sure heard
a bunch about you.
See, I was a good friend
of your dad's.
We were in that Hanoi
pit of hell together...
over five years.
Hopefully...
you'll never have to experience
this yourself...
but when two men
are in a situation...
like me and your dad were
for as long as we were...
you take on certain
responsibilities of the other.
If it had been me who'd...
not made it...
Major Coolidge would be talkin'
right now to my son... Jim.
But the way
it turned out...
I'm talkin' to you...
Butch.
I got somethin' for ya.
This watch I got here...
was first purchased
by your great-grandfather...
during the First World War.
It was bought
in a little general store...
in Knoxville, Tennessee.
Made by the first company
to ever make wristwatches.
Up till then, people just
carried pocket watches.
It was bought by Private
Doughboy Erine Coolidge...
on the day he set sail
for Paris.
This was your great-
grandfather's war watch...
and he wore it every day
he was in that war.
And when he'd done his duty...
he went home
to your great-grandmother...
took the watch off...
put it in an old coffee can...
and in that can it stayed...
Till your granddad,
Dane Coolidge...
was called upon
by his country...
to go overseas and fight
the Germans once again.
This time they called it
World War II.
Your great-grandfather
gave this watch...
to your granddad for good luck.
Unfortunately, Dane's luck
wasn't as good as his old man's.
Dane was a marine,
and he was killed...
along with all the other marines
at the Battle of Wake Island.
Your granddad was facing death.
He knew it.
None of those boys
had any illusions...
about ever leaving
that island alive...
so, three days before
the Japanese took the island...
your granddad asked a gunner
on an Air Force transport...
name of Winocki...
a man he had never met
before in his life...
to deliver to his infant son...
who he had never seen
in the flesh...
his gold watch.
Three days later,
your granddad was dead...
but Winocki kept his word.
After the war was over...
he paid a visit
to your grandmother...
delivering
to your infant father...
his dad's gold watch.
This watch.
This watch
was on your daddy's wrist...
when he was shot down
over Hanoi.
He was captured,
put in a Vietnamese prison camp.
He knew that if the gooks
ever saw the watch...
they'd confiscate it...
take it away.
The way your dad looked at it,
this watch was your birthright.
He'd be damned if any slopes
put their greasy yellow hands...
on his boy's birthright,
so he hid it...
in one place he knew he could
hide somethin'... his ass.
Five long years he wore
this watch up his ass.
Then he died of dysentery,
he give me the watch.
I hid this uncomfortable hunk
of metal up my ass, two years.
Then... after seven years...
I was sent home to my family.
And...
now...
little man,
I give the watch to you.
It's time, Butch.
...weighing 210 pounds...
Floyd Ray Wilson!
It's official.
It's official. Wilson is dead!
Dan,
that had to be the bloodiest...
and the most brutal fight
this city has ever seen.
Coolidge left faster than I've
ever seen a victorious boxer...
leave the ring.
Do you think he knew
Wilson was dead?
My guess would be yes, Richard.
I could see
the frenzy in his eyes...
give way to the realization
of what he was doing.
I think any man would have
left the ring that fast.
Do you feel this tragedy...
is gonna have an effect
on the world of boxing?
Such a tragedy can't help
but shake the boxing world...
to its very foundations...
but par amount importance is
during the sad weeks ahead...
the eyes of the WBA remain...
Mia.
Marsellus?
I didn't do it, man.
How you doin'?
Great.
I never thanked you for dinner.
What you got?
He booked.
His trainer?
Says he don't know nothin'.
I believe him.
Think Butch surprised
his ass same as us.
No, we don't wanna think,
we wanna know.
Take him to the kennel,
sic the dogs on his ass.
We'll find out for goddamn sure
what he knows and what he don't.
Butch's search...
how do you want it done?
I'm prepared to scour the earth
for that motherfucker.
If Butch goes to Indochina...
I want a nigger hidin'
in a bowl of rice...
ready to pop a cap
in his ass.
I will take care of it.
Mister?
Hey, mister?
What?
You were in that fight.
The fight on the radio.
You're the fighter?
Now, what gave you that idea?
No, ho, come on.
You're him.
I know you're him.
Tell me you're him.
I'm him.
You killed
the other boxing man.
He's dead?
The radio said he was dead.
Sorry about that, Floyd.
What does it feel like?
What does what feel like?
Killing a man.
Beating another man to death
with your bare hands.
Are you a weirdo?
No.
It is a subject
I have much interest in.
You are the first person
I've met...
who has killed somebody.
So...
what does it feel like
to kill a man?
I'll tell you what.
You give me one of them
cigarettes you got up there...
and I'll tell you all about it.
So...
Esmarelda...
Villalobos.
Is that Mexican?
The name is Spanish,
but I am Colombian.
That's some handle
you got there, honey.
Thank you.
And what is your name?
Butch.
What does it mean?
I'm an American, honey.
Our names don't mean shit.
So, moving right along,
Esmarelda.
What is it you wanna know?
I want to know what it
feels like to kill a man.
I couldn't tell ya.
I didn't know he was dead
until you told me he was dead.
Now that I know he's dead...
you wanna know
how I feel about it?
I don't feel the least bit bad
about it.
What the fuck I tell ya, huh?
As soon as the word got out
the fix was in, man...
the odds went through the roof.
I know. I know.
Unbelievable.
Hey, fuck him, Scotty.
If he was a better boxer,
he'd still be alive.
He never laced up his gloves...
which he never shoulda done
in the first fuckin' place...
he'd still be alive.
Yeah, well...
who gives a fuck?
It's over now.
Well, enough about the poor
unfortunate Mr. Floyd.
Let's talk about the rich
and prosperous Mr. Butch.
How many bookies
you lay it around on?
All eight?
How long to collect?
So you'll have it all
by tomorrow night?
No, I understand,
a few stragglers aside.
Oh, fuck, Scotty,
that is good news...
that is great news, man.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
No, me and Fabienne
are gonna leave in the morning.
It'll probably take us a couple
of days to get to Knoxville.
OK, my brother.
You're right.
You're goddamn right.
All right, Scotty.
Next time I see you,
we'll be on Tennessee time.
Be cool, brother.
45.60.
And, uh, here's a little...
somethin' for the effort.
Now...
if anybody asks you
who your fare was tonight...
what are you gonna say?
The truth.
Three well-dressed,
slightly toasted Mexicans.
Bonsoir,
Esmarelda Villalobos.
Buenas noches, Butch.
Keep the light off.
Is that better,
sugar pop?
Oui.
Hard day at the office?
Pretty hard.
I got in a fight.
Poor baby.
Can we make spoons?
You know what? I was thinkin'
about takin' a shower.
I'm stinkin' like a dog
over here.
Mmm. I like the way you stink.
Let me take this jacket off.
I was looking at myself
in the mirror.
Uh-huh.
I wish I had a pot.
You were lookin' at yourself
in the mirror...
and you wish you had some pot?
A pot.
A pot belly.
Pot bellies are sexy.
Well, you should be happy...
'cause you have one.
Shut up, fatso!
I don't have a pot.
I have a bit of a tummy...
like Madonna
when she did "Lucky Star."
It's not the same thing.
I didn't know
there was such a difference...
between a pot belly and a tummy.
The difference is huge.
Would you like it
if I had a pot belly?
No. Pot bellies make a man...
look either oafish
or like a gorilla.
But on a woman,
a pot belly is very sexy.
The rest of you is normal.
Normal face, normal legs,
normal hips, normal ass...
but with a big perfectly
round pot belly.
If I had one, I'd wear a T-shirt
two sizes too small...
to accentuate it.
You think men
would find that attractive?
I don't give a damn
what men find attractive.
It's unfortunate what we
find pleasing to the touch...
and pleasing to the eye
is seldom the same.
If you had a pot belly...
I would punch you in it.
- You'd punch me in my belly?
- Right in the belly.
Ah! I'd smother you.
I'd drop it right on your face
till you couldn't breathe.
You'd do that?
Yes. Yes.
Did you get everything?
Yes, I did.
Good job, sugar pop.
Did everything go as planned?
You didn't listen to the... Ow!
You didn't listen to the radio?
I never listen to your fights.
Were you the winner?
I won, all right.
Are you still retiring?
Sure am.
So, it all worked out
in the finish?
We're not at the finish yet,
baby.
Mmm.
We're in a lot of danger,
aren't we?
If they find us,
they'll kill us, won't they?
But they won't find us,
will they?
Do you still want me
to go with you?
I don't want to be a burden
or a nuisance, it's...
Say it.
Fabienne...
I want you to be with me.
Forever?
Forever and ever.
Do you love me?
Very, very much.
Mmm.
Butch?
Yes.
Will you give me oral pleasure?
Will you kiss it?
But you first.
OK.
Mmm.
Butch.
Mon amour.
L'aventure commence.
Mmm.
I think I cracked a rib.
Giving me oral pleasure?
No, retard. From the fight.
Don't call me retard.
My name is Fabby.
My name is Fabienne.
Stop it. Stop it.
Shut up, fuckhead!
I hate that mongoloid voice.
OK, OK. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I take it back.
Would you hand me a dry towel,
Miss Beautiful Tulip?
Oh, I like that.
I like being called a tulip.
Tulip is much better
than mongoloid.
I didn't call you a mongoloid.
I called you a retard,
and I took it back.
Uhh.
Butch?
Yes, lemon pie.
Where are we going to go?
Well, I'm not sure yet.
Wherever you want.
We're gonna get
a lot of money from this...
but it ain't gonna be
the kinda money...
that we can live like hogs
in the fat house forever.
I was thinkin' maybe
we could go down...
someplace
in the South Pacific.
The kinda money
we're gonna have...
is gonna carry us
a long way down there.
If we wanted,
we could live in Bora Bora?
You betcha.
And if after a while
you didn't dig that...
go someplace else,
maybe Tahiti. Mexico.
But I do not speak Spanish.
Well, you do not speak
Bora Boran, either.
Besides, Mexican is easy.
Donde esta el zapateria?
What does that mean?
Where is the shoe store?
Donde esta...
Spit, please.
Donde esta el zapateria?
Excellent pronunciation.
Mmm.
You'll be my little mamacita
in no time.
Que hor a es?
What time is it?
Time for bed.
Sweet dreams, jellybean.
Butch?
Never mind.
Ohh!
Merde.
You startled me.
Did you have a bad dream?
Shit.
What is this you're watching?
A motorcycle movie.
I'm not sure the name.
Are you watchin' it?
In a way.
It's a little early
in the morning...
for explosions and war.
What was it about?
How should I know, Fabienne?
You were the one
who was watchin' it.
No, imbecile,
what was your dream about?
I don't know. I don't remember.
It's really rare
that I remember my dreams.
Well, let's look
at the grumpy man...
in the morning.
- Mmm.
Why don't you get up
and we'll get some breakfast?
One more kiss,
and I'll get up.
Mmm.
Satisfied?
Yep.
Then get up, lazy bones.
Ohh.
God. Unh.
What time is it?
Almost 9:00 in the morning.
What time does our train arrive?
11:00.
You know what I'm gonna
have for breakfast?
What, lemon pie?
I'm gonna order a big plate...
of blueberry pancakes
with maple syrup...
eggs over easy,
and five sausages.
Anything to drink with that?
Ah, that looks nice.
To drink...
a tall glass of orange juice
and a black cup of coffee.
After that, I'm going to
have a slice of pie.
Pie for breakfast?
Any time of the day
is a good time for pie.
Blueberry pie
to go with the pancakes.
And on top, a thin slice
of melted cheese...
Where's my watch?
It's there.
No, it's not.
Have you looked?
Yes, I fucking looked.
What the fuck
do you think I'm doing?
You sure you got it?
Yes. Bedside table drawer.
On the little kangaroo?
Yes.
It was on the little kangaroo.
Yeah, well, it's not here now.
Well, it should be.
It most definitely should be,
but it's not here now.
So where the fuck is it?
Fabienne...
that was my father's
fucking watch.
Do you have any idea
what he had to go through...
to get me that watch?
I don't have time to go into it,
but he went through a lot.
All this other shit
you could set on fire...
but I specifically reminded you
not to forget the fucking watch!
Now think.
Did you get it?
I believe so.
You believe so?
What the fuck does that mean?
You either did,
or you didn't get it!
Then I did.
Are you sure?
No.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Motherfucker!
- Motherfucker!
- Aah!
Do you know how
fucking stupid you fucking are?
No!
It's not your fault.
If you left it
at the apartment...
If you left it at the apartment,
it's not your fault.
I had you bring
a bunch of stuff.
I reminded you about it,
but I didn't illustrate...
how personal the watch
was to me.
If all I gave a fuck about
was the watch...
I should've told you that.
You're not a mind reader,
are you?
I... I'm sorry.
Don't be.
It just means
I can't have breakfast with you.
Why does it mean that?
Because I got to go back to
my apartment and get my watch.
Won't the gangsters
be looking for you there?
Well...
that's what I'm going
to find out.
If they are and I don't think
I can handle it...
Then I'll split.
I saw your watch.
I thought I brought it.
I'm so sorry.
Here's some money.
Go out and get those pancakes.
Have a nice breakfast.
I'll take your Honda.
I'll be back before
you can say blueberry pie.
Blueberry pie.
Maybe not that fast...
but pretty fast, OK?
OK.
Bye.
Shit! Of all the fucking things
she could fucking forget...
she forgets my father's watch!
I specifically reminded her.
"Bedside table,
on the kangaroo."
I said the words, "Don't forget
my father's watch."
Lookin' good, Butch.
Aah!
Flowers on the wall
That don't bother me at all
Playin' solitaire till dawn
With a deck of 51
That's how you're going
to beat 'em, Butch.
They keep underestimating you.
Kangaroo
Now, don't tell me
Countin' flowers on the wall
That don't bother me at all
Playin'...
Solitaire till dawn
With a deck of 51
Smoking cigarettes
And watching "Captain Kangaroo"
Now, don't tell me
I've nothin' to do
It's good to see you,
I must go
I know I look a fright
Motherfucker.
Huhh!
He's dead.
Oh, my God.
If you need someone to go
to court, I'll be glad to help.
That guy was a drunken maniac.
He hit you, and then he
crashed into that car.
Who?
Him.
I'll be damned.
Uhh.
Aah! Aah! Uhh!
Aah!
I'm shot!
Uhh!
- Can I help you with something?
- Shut the fuck up.
Now, you just wait
a goddamn minute now.
What the fuck are you up to?
Come here, motherfucker!
- Uhh!
Uhh!
You feel that sting,
big boy, huh?
That's pride
fucking with you, see?
You got to fight
through that shit.
Uhh! Huh?
You better kill me.
Yeah,
somebody's going to get killed.
Somebody's going to get their
motherfucking head blown to...
Hold it right there,
God damn it.
This ain't none
of your business, mister.
I'm making it my business.
Toss the weapon.
You don't understand, man.
Take your foot off the nigger.
Put your hands behind your head.
Approach the counter right now.
This motherfucker's
trying to kill me.
Shut up.
Keep a-comin'. Come on.
Uhh!
Zed, it's Maynard.
Yeah. The spider
just caught a couple flies.
Nobody kills anybody in my place
of business except me or Zed.
That's Zed.
I thought you said
you waited for me.
I did.
So how come
they're all beat up?
They did that
to each other, man.
They came in fighting.
Now, this one right here,
he was going to shoot that one.
Is that right?
You going to shoot him, boy?
Huh?
Hey, is Grace all right
out front?
Yeah. It ain't Tuesday, is it?
No. It's Thursday.
She ought to be fine.
Mm-hmm.
Ahh. Well...
Bring out The Gimp.
I think The Gimp's sleeping.
I guess you'll just have to go
wake him up, now, won't you?
Get up.
Get down.
Which one of 'em
you want to do first?
I ain't for sure yet.
Eenie, meenie, minie, mo.
Catch a nigger by the toe.
If he hollers...
let him go.
Eenie, meenie...
minie, mo.
My mother said...
To pick the perfect one...
and you are...
It.
I guess that means you,
big boy.
Shh.
You want to do it in here?
No. Let's do it back there
in Russell's old room.
Sounds good to me.
Uhh. Uhh.
You keep an eye on this one.
Yeah!
Uhh!
Yeah, go!
Come on, motherfucker!
Now, motherfucker!
Come on!
Yeah!
Uhh! Uhh! Aah!
Aah!
Yeah!
Yee!
Yee-haw!
Go!
Come on, motherfucker!
Aah!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Come on!
Yeah!
Uhh!
Now, motherfucker!
Aah!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Come on!
Now!
Yeah!
Yeah, baby!
Shut the fuck up!
Fuck!
Come on!
Yeah.
Haah!
Aah!
Ohh!
Ohh! Uhh!
You want that gun,
don't you, Zed?
Go ahead and pick it up.
Go ahead, pick it up.
Come on. Atta boy.
I want you to pick it up...
Zed.
Step aside, Butch.
Uhh!
Fuck!
You OK?
No, man.
I'm pretty fucking far from OK.
Uhh!
Aah!
What now?
Uhh!
Let me tell you what now.
I'm going to call a couple
of hard pipe-hitting niggers...
to go to work
on the homes here...
with a pair of pliers
and a blow torch.
You hear me talking,
hillbilly boy?
I ain't through
with you by a damn sight.
I'm going to get
medieval on your ass.
I meant, what now
between me and you?
Oh, that what now.
I tell you what now
between me and you.
There is no me and you...
not no more.
So are we cool?
Yeah, we cool.
Two things...
Don't tell nobody about this.
This shit is between me, you...
and Mr. Soon To Be Living...
The Rest Of His Short-Ass Life
In Agonizing Pain...
rapist here.
It ain't nobody else's business.
Two...
You leave town tonight...
right now.
And when you're gone...
you stay gone...
or you be gone.
You lost all your L.A.
Privileges. Deal?
Deal.
Get your ass out of here.
Ohh!
Uhh!
Fabienne!
Fabienne.
Come on, baby, come on.
Get your shit.
We got to go right now.
I was so worried.
What about our bags?
Fuck the bags.
If we don't split right now...
we'll miss the train.
I'll be downstairs.
Is everything well?
Just come on!
No talking now.
Are we in danger?
Come on, honey!
Where did you get
this motorcycle?
It's not a motorcycle, baby.
It's a chopper.
Come on, let's go.
What happened to my Honda?
I'm sorry, baby.
I had to crash that Honda.
Will you come on now, please?
Come on,
let's go, let's go.
You're hurt?
No, no.
I might've broken my nose.
It's no biggie.
Come on, hop on.
Baby, please.
Honey, we got to hit
the fucking road. Get on.
I'm sorry.
Come here, come here.
I'm so sorry.
You were gone so long I started
to think dreadful thoughts.
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie.
I didn't mean to worry you.
- How was your breakfast?
- It was good.
Did you get
the blueberry pancakes?
They didn't have
blueberry pancakes.
I had to get buttermilk.
Are you sure you're OK?
Honey, since I left you,
this has been without a doubt...
the single weirdest
fucking day of my life.
Come on, hop on.
I'll tell you all about it.
Come on, get on. Gotta go.
Whose motorcycle is this?
It's a chopper, baby.
- Whose chopper is this?
- Zed's.
- Who's Zed?
- Zed's dead, baby.
Zed's dead.
Yes, you did, Brett!
- You tried to fuck him.
- No.
And Marsellus Wallace
don't like to be fucked...
by anybody except Mrs. Wallace.
Oh, God, please.
I don't want to die.
You read the Bible, Brett?
Yes!
Well, there's
this passage I got memorized.
It sort of fits the occasion.
"Ezekiel" 25: 17.
"The path of
the righteous man...
"is beset on all sides...
"by the inequities
of the selfish...
"and the tyranny of evil men.
"Blessed is he...
"who in the name
of charity and good will...
"shepherds the weak...
"through
the Valley of Darkness...
"for he is truly
his brother's keeper...
"and the finder
of lost children.
"And I will strike down
upon thee...
"with great vengeance
and furious anger...
"those who attempt to poison...
"and destroy My brothers.
"And you will know
My name is the Lord...
"when I lay My vengeance
upon thee."
Uhh!
Aah!
I'm fucked. I'm fucked.
Is he a friend of yours?
Oh, Vincent, Marvin.
Marvin, Vincent.
Better tell him
to shut the fuck up.
He's getting on my nerves.
Marvin. Marvin!
I'd knock that shit off
if I was you.
Die, you motherfuckers! Die!
Why the fuck didn't you tell us
somebody was in the bathroom?
Slip your mind?
You forget someone was in there
with a goddamn hand-cannon?
You see the size
of that gun he fired at us?
It was bigger than him.
We should be fucking dead, man.
I know. We was lucky.
No, no, no, no.
That shit wasn't luck.
Yeah, maybe.
This was divine intervention.
You know what
divine intervention is?
I think so.
That means that God
came down from Heaven...
and stopped the bullets.
That's right.
That's exactly what it means.
God came down from Heaven...
and stopped
these motherfucking bullets.
I think it's time for us
to leave, Jules.
Don't do that. Don't
fucking blow this shit off.
What just happened here
was a fucking miracle.
Chill, Jules.
This shit happens.
Wrong. Wrong.
This shit doesn't just happen.
Do you want to continue
this theological discussion...
in a car or in a jailhouse
with the cops?
We should be fucking dead,
my friend.
What happened here
was a miracle...
and I want you to fucking
acknowledge it.
All right, it was a miracle.
Can we go now?
Let's go, nigger. Come on.
Shit.
You ever seen
that show "Cops"?
I was watching it one time,
and there was this cop on...
and he was talking
about this gunfight...
he had in a hallway
with this guy, right?
And he just unloaded
on this guy...
and nothing happened.
He didn't hit nothing.
OK? It was just him
and this guy.
I mean, you know...
it's freaky, but it happens.
You want to play blind man,
go walk with the shepherd...
but me, my eyes
are wide fucking open.
What the fuck does that mean?
It means that's it for me.
From here on in,
you can consider my ass retired.
- Jesus Christ.
- Don't blaspheme.
- God damn it.
- I said don't do that.
Why are you fucking
freaking out on us?
Look, I'm telling
Marsellus today.
I'm through.
Why don't you tell him
at the same time why?
Don't worry. I will.
Yeah,
and I'll bet you $10,000...
he laughs his ass off.
I don't give a damn
if he does.
Marvin, what do you make
of all this?
Man, I don't even
have an opinion.
You got to have an opinion.
Do you think that God came down
from Heaven and stopped...
What the fuck's happening?
Oh, shit, man!
Oh, man,
I shot Marvin in the face.
Why the fuck did you do that?
Well, I didn't mean to do it.
It was an accident.
Oh, man, I've seen some
crazy-ass shit in my time...
Chill out, man.
I told you it was an accident.
You probably... You went over
a bump or something.
Hey, the car didn't hit
no motherfucking bump.
Hey, look, man, I didn't mean
to shoot the son of a bitch.
The gun went off.
I don't know why.
Well, look at
this fucking mess, man!
We're on a city street
in broad daylight.
I can't believe it, man.
Well, believe it now,
motherfucker.
We got to get this car
off the road.
You know,
cops tend to notice shit...
like you're driving a car
drenched in fucking blood.
Just take it
to a friendly place, that's all.
This is the Valley, Vincent.
Marsellus ain't got
no friendly places.
Jules, this ain't
my fucking town, man!
- Shit!
- What you doing?
I'm calling my partner
in Toluca Lake.
Where's Toluca Lake?
It's just over the hill here,
over by Burbank Studios.
If Jimmie's ass ain't home...
I don't know what the fuck
we going to do, man...
'cause I ain't got
no other partners in 818.
Jimmie, yo,
how you doing, man?
It's Jules.
Just listen up, man.
Me and my homeboy are in
some serious fucking shit, man.
We're in a car, and we got
to get off the road pronto.
I need to use your garage
for a couple hours.
We got to be
real fucking delicate...
with this Jimmie situation.
He's one remark away from
kicking our asses out the door.
If he does, what do we do?
We ain't leaving
till we made a couple calls...
but I don't want it
to reach that pitch.
Jimmie's a friend.
You don't come
into your friend's house...
and start telling him
what's what.
Just tell him not
to be abusive, that's all.
He kind of freaked out
back there when he saw Marvin.
Well, put yourself
in his position.
It's 8:00 in the morning.
He just woke up.
He wasn't expecting this shit.
Shit, we got to remember here
who's doing who a favor.
If that favor means
that I got to take shit...
then he can stick that favor
straight up his ass.
Nigger, what the fuck
did you just do to his towel?
I was drying my hands.
You're supposed
to wash them first.
You watched me wash them.
I watched you get them wet.
I was washing them.
This shit's hard to get off.
Maybe if he had Lava,
I could've done a better job.
I used the same
fucking soap you did...
and the towel didn't look like
no goddamn maxipad.
What if he was to come in here
and see his towel like this?
It's shit like this
that'll bring this situation...
to a head, man.
Look...
I ain't threatening you
with nothing, all right?
You know I respect you
and all...
but just don't put me
in this position, all right?
All right. Fine. Fine.
Ask me nice like that,
no problem.
Just go handle your friend.
Go ahead. I don't care.
Mmm. Goddamn, Jimmie.
This is some
serious gourmet shit.
Me and Vincent
would've been satisfied...
with some freeze-dried
Taster's Choice, right?
Heh! And he springs this
serious gourmet shit on us.
What flavor is this?
Knock it off, Julie.
What?
I don't need you to tell me
how fucking good my coffee is.
I'm the one who buys it.
I know how good it is.
When Bonnie goes shopping,
she buys shit.
I buy the gourmet
expensive stuff...
because when I drink it,
I want to taste it.
But you know what's
on my mind right now?
It ain't the coffee
in my kitchen.
It's the dead nigger
in my garage.
Oh, Jimmie,
don't even worry about it.
I don't think about anything.
I want to ask you a question.
When you came pulling in here...
did you notice a sign
out in the front of my house...
that said
"Dead Nigger Storage"?
Jimmie, you know
I didn't see no shit...
Did you notice a sign
in the front of my house...
that said
"Dead Nigger Storage"?
No. I didn't.
You know why
you didn't see that sign?
Why?
'Cause it ain't there...
'cause storing dead niggers
ain't my fucking business!
Jimmie, we're not going
to store the motherfucker.
Don't you fucking realize, man,
that if Bonnie comes home...
and finds a body in her house,
I'm going to get divorced?
No marriage counselor,
no trial separation.
I'm going to get
fucking divorced, OK?
And I don't want
to get fucking divorced.
Now, man, you know, fuck,
I want to help you...
but I don't want to lose
my wife doing it, all right?
Jimmie, she ain't
going to leave you.
Don't fucking "Jimmie" me,
Jules!
OK?
Don't fucking "Jimmie" me.
There's nothing you're gonna say
that's gonna make me forget...
that I love my wife, is there?
Look, you know...
she comes home from work
in about an hour and a half.
Graveyard shift
at the hospital.
You got to make
some phone calls?
You got to call some people?
Well, then do it, and get
the fuck out of my house...
before she gets here.
That's Kool and the Gang.
We don't want
to fuck your shit up.
I want to call my people,
get them to bring us in.
You're fucking my shit up
right now!
You'll fuck my shit up big time
if Bonnie comes home.
So just do me that favor,
all right?
The phone is in my bedroom.
I suggest you get going.
Well, say she comes home.
What do you think she'll do?
Oh, no fucking shit,
she'll freak.
That ain't no kind of answer.
I mean, you know, I don't.
How much?
A lot or a little?
You got to appreciate
what an explosive element...
this Bonnie situation is.
I mean, if she comes
home from a hard day's work...
and finds a bunch
of gangsters in her kitchen...
doing a bunch
of gangster shit...
there ain't no telling
what she's liable to do.
Yeah, I've grasped that, Jules.
All I'm doing
is contemplating the "ifs."
I don't want to hear about
no motherfucking "ifs."
All I want to hear
from your ass is...
"You ain't got no problem.
I'm on the motherfucker.
"Go back in there,
chill them niggers out...
"and wait for the cavalry,
which will be coming directly."
You ain't
got no problem, Jules.
I'm on the motherfucker.
Go back in there
and chill them niggers out...
and wait for The Wolf,
who should be coming directly.
You're sending The Wolf?
Oh, you feel better,
motherfucker?
Shit, negro,
that's all you had to say.
Is she the hysterical type?
When is she due?
Mm-hmm.
Give me the principals'
names again.
Jules.
Mm-hmm.
Vincent.
Jimmie.
Bonnie.
Mm-hmm.
It's thirty minutes away.
I'll be there in ten.
You're Jimmie, right?
This is your house?
Sure is.
I'm Winston Wolf.
I solve problems.
Good. We got one.
So I heard. May I come in?
Yeah, please do.
You must be Jules...
which would make you Vincent.
Let's get down
to brass tacks, gentlemen.
If I was informed correctly...
the clock is ticking,
is that right, Jimmie?
100%
Your wife Bonnie...
comes home at 9:30 in the a.m.,
is that correct?
Uh-huh.
I was led to believe if she
comes home and finds us here...
she wouldn't appreciate it
none too much?
She wouldn't at that.
That gives us forty minutes
to get the fuck out of Dodge...
which, if you do what I say
when I say it, should be plenty.
Now, you got a corpse
in a car...
minus a head in a garage.
Take me to it.
- Jimmie?
- Uh-huh.
Do me a favor, will you?
I thought I smelled
some coffee back there.
Would you make me a cup?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, how do you take it?
Lots of cream,
lots of sugar.
About the car... is there
anything I need to know?
Does it stall, smoke,
make a lot of noise?
Is there gas in it?
Anything?
Aside from how it looks,
the car is cool.
Positive? Don't get me
out there on the road...
I find out
the brake lights don't work.
Man, far as I know,
the motherfucker's tiptop.
Good enough.
Let's go back to the kitchen.
Here you go, Mr. Wolf.
Thank you, Jimmie.
Mmm.
OK, first thing...
you two, take the body,
stick it in the trunk.
Now, Jimmie, this looks to be
a pretty domesticated house.
That would lead me to believe
that in the gar age...
or under the sink, you got
a bunch of cleaners and shit?
Yeah, Mr. Wolf.
Under the sink.
Good. What I need
you two fellas to do...
is take those cleaning products
and clean the inside of the car.
I'm talking fast, fast, fast.
Go in the back seat...
scoop up all those little
pieces of brain and skull.
Get it out of there.
Wipe down the upholstery.
Now, it don't need
to be spick-and-span.
You don't need to eat off it.
Just give it a good once over.
What you need to take care of
are the really messy parts.
The pools of blood
that have collected...
you got to soak that shit up.
Now, Jimmie, we need to r aid
your linen closet.
I need blankets.
I need comforters.
I need quilts.
I need bedspreads.
The thicker the better,
the darker the better.
No whites. Can't use 'em.
We need to camouflage
the interior of the car.
We're going to line
the front seat and back seat...
and the floorboards
with quilts and blankets.
So if a cop stops us and sticks
his big snout in the car...
the subterfuge won't last...
but at a glance, the car
will appear to be normal.
Jimmie, lead the way.
Boys, get to work.
"Please" would be nice.
Come again?
I said
a "please" would be nice.
Get it straight, buster.
I'm not here to say "please."
I'm here to tell you what to do.
And if self-preservation
is an instinct you possess...
you better fucking do it
and do it quick.
I'm here to help.
If my help is not appreciated,
lots of luck, gentlemen.
No, Mr. Wolf,
it ain't like that.
Your help is definitely
appreciated.
Mr. Wolf, listen.
I don't mean disrespect, OK?
I respect you.
I don't like people barking
orders at me, that's all.
If I'm curt with you,
it's because time is a factor.
I think fast, I talk fast...
and I need you guys to act fast
if you want out of this...
so pretty please
with sugar on top...
clean the fucking car.
Don't be looking at me
like that, all right?
I can feel your look.
It's a 1974 Chevy Nova.
Green.
Nothing except
for the mess inside.
Mmm, about twenty minutes.
Nobody who'll be missed.
You're a good man, Joe.
Thanks a bunch.
How we coming, Jimmie?
Pretty good.
I got it all here...
but, uh...
Mr. Wolf, you got to
understand something.
Winston, Jimmie, please.
Winston.
You got to understand
something now, Winston.
Uh, no, thank you.
This is our best linen here...
and it was a wedding present...
from my Uncle Conrad
and my Aunt Ginny...
and they're not with us anymore.
I really want
to help you guys out...
Let me ask you
a question, Jimmie...
if you don't mind.
No, please, go ahead.
Your Uncle Conrad
and Aunt Ginny...
were they millionaires?
No.
Well,
your Uncle Marsellus is...
and I'm positive
if Uncle Conrad and Aunt...
- Ginny.
- Ginny were here...
they would furnish you
with a whole bedroom set...
which your Uncle Marsellus
is more than happy to do.
I like oak myself.
That's what I have
in my bedroom.
How about you, Jimmie?
You an oak man?
Oak's nice.
Oh, man.
I will never forgive
your ass for this shit.
This is some fucked-up
repugnant shit.
Jules, did you ever hear
the philosophy...
that once a man admits
that he is wrong...
that he is immediately
forgiven for all wrongdoings?
Get the fuck out my face
with that shit.
The motherfucker said that shit
never had to pick up...
itty-bitty pieces of skull
on account of your dumb ass.
I got a threshold, Jules.
I got a threshold
for the abuse that I will take.
Right now, I'm a fucking
race car, all right?
And you got me in the red.
I'm just saying
that it's fucking dangerous...
to have a race car
in the fucking red, that's all.
- I could blow.
- Oh, you ready to blow?
Yeah, I'm ready to blow.
I'm a mushroom cloud-laying
motherfucker, motherfucker.
Every time my fingers touch
brain, I'm "Superfly TNT."
I'm "The Guns of the Navarone."
In fact, what the fuck
am I doing in the back?
You the motherfucker
who should be on brain detail.
We fucking switching.
I'm washing the windows...
and you picking up
this nigger's skull.
Fine job, gentlemen.
We may get out of this yet.
I can't believe
this is the same car.
Let's not start sucking
each other's dicks quite yet.
Phase one is complete...
clean the car...
which moves us right
along to phase two...
clean you two.
Strip.
All the way?
To your bare ass.
Quickly, gentlemen.
We got about fifteen minutes...
before Jimmie's better half
pulls into the driveway.
Damn. This morning air
is some chilly shit.
Are you sure this is
absolutely necessary?
You know what you two
look like?
What?
Like a couple of guys who just
blew off somebody's head.
Stripping off those bloody rags
is absolutely necessary.
Toss them in Jim's garbage bag.
Don't do nothing stupid...
like leaving this shit out front
for Otto the Garbageman...
you know what I'm saying?
Don't worry.
We're taking it with us.
Jim, the soap.
- Vincent.
- OK, gentlemen...
you've both been
to County before I'm sure.
Here it comes.
Goddamn!
The water's fucking cold.
Better you
than me, gentlemen.
Ha ha ha!
Don't be afraid
of the soap.
Spread it around.
Get him up there
a little bit.
Vincent's hair.
Come on, do it,
God damn it! Do it!
Uh, uh...
Towel 'em.
They're dry enough.
Toss them their clothes.
Perfect.
Perfect. We couldn't
have planned this better.
You guys look like...
What do they look like, Jimmie?
Dorks.
They look like
a couple of dorks.
Ha ha ha. They're your clothes,
motherfucker.
Come on, gentlemen.
We're laughing our way
right into prison.
Don't make me beg.
OK, gentlemen, let's get
our rules of the road straight.
We're going to a place called
Monster Joe's Truck and Tow.
Now, Monster Joe
and his daughter Raquel...
are sympathetic to our dilemma.
The place is North Hollywood...
so a few twists and turns aside,
we'll be going up Hollywood Way.
Now, I'll drive the tainted car.
Jules, you ride with me.
Vincent, you follow in my Acura.
Now, if we come across the path
of any John Q. Laws...
nobody does a fucking thing
till I do something.
- Right.
- What did I say?
Don't do shit unless...
- Unless what?
- Unless you do it first.
Spoken like a true prodigy.
How about you, Lash LaRue?
Can you keep your spurs
from jingling and jangling?
Mr. Wolf, look,
the gun went off.
I don't why.
I'm cool. I promise you.
Fair enough. Now, I drive
real fucking fast, so keep up.
If I get my car back
any different than I gave it...
Monster Joe's going to be
disposing of two bodies.
Out of my way, Rex.
- We cool?
- Like it never happened.
All right.
Boys, this is Raquel.
Someday, all this will be hers.
Hi. So, what's with the outfits?
You guys going to
a volleyball game or something?
I'm taking my lady
out for breakfast.
Maybe I could drop you two off.
Where do you live?
- Redondo.
- Inglewood.
It's... it's your future.
I... I see a... a cab ride.
Move out of the sticks, fellas.
Say good night, Raquel.
Good night, Raquel.
I'll see you guys around.
Stay out of trouble,
you crazy kids.
Mr. Wolf,
I just want to tell you...
it was a real pleasure
watching you work.
Yeah, really, and thank you
very much, Mr. Wolf.
Call me Winston.
You see that, young lady?
Respect.
Respect for one's elders
shows character.
I have character.
Because you are a character...
doesn't mean
that you have character.
Want to share a cab?
I could go for some breakfast.
Feel like having breakfast
with me?
Cool.
I don't know why,
I thought he'd be European...
Yo, man, he's about as European
as English Bob.
I know that now, but...
- Was he cool or what?
- Thank you.
Totally fucking cool,
in control.
Didn't even really get pissed
when you were fucking with him.
I was amazed.
Want some bacon?
No, man. I don't eat pork.
Are you Jewish?
Naw, I ain't Jewish.
I just don't dig on swine,
that's all.
Why not?
Pigs are filthy animals.
I don't eat filthy animals.
Yeah, but bacon tastes good.
Pork chops taste good.
Hey, a sewer rat
may taste like pumpkin pie...
but I'd never know...
'cause I wouldn't eat
the filthy motherfuckers.
Pigs sleep and root in shit.
That's a filthy animal.
I ain't eating nothing
that ain't got sense enough...
to disregard its own feces.
How about a dog?
A dog eats his own feces.
I don't eat dog, either.
But do you consider a dog
to be a filthy animal?
I wouldn't go so far
as to call a dog filthy...
but they're definitely dirty.
But a dog's got personality.
Personality goes a long way.
Ah, so by that rationale...
if a pig had
a better personality...
he would cease to be
a filthy animal.
Is that true?
We'd have to be talking about
one charming motherfucking pig.
He'd have to be ten times
more charming...
than Arnold on "Green Acres,"
you know what I'm saying?
Oh, man, that's good.
That's good, man.
You're starting to lighten up.
You been sitting there
all serious and shit.
Man, I've just been
sitting here thinking.
About what?
About the miracle we witnessed.
The miracle you witnessed.
I witnessed a freak occurrence.
What is a miracle, Vincent?
An act of God.
And what's an act of God?
When, um...
God makes the impossible
possible.
But this morning
I don't think qualifies.
Hey, Vincent...
Don't you see?
That shit don't matter.
You're judging this shit
the wrong way.
I mean, it could be
God stopped the bullets...
or he changed Coke to Pepsi,
he found my fucking car keys.
You don't judge shit like this
based on merit.
Now, whether or not
what we experienced...
was an "According to Hoyle"
miracle...
is insignificant...
but what is significant
is I felt the touch of God.
God got involved.
But why?
Well, that's what's
fucking with me.
I don't know why,
but I can't go back to sleep.
You're serious?
You're really thinking
about quitting?
- The life?
Yeah.
Most definitely.
Fuck.
What you going to do, then?
Well, that's what I've been
sitting here contemplating.
First, I'm going to deliver
this case to Marsellus.
Then, basically, I'm just
going to walk the earth.
What you mean, walk the earth?
You know,
like Caine in "Kung Fu."
Walk from place to place,
meet people, get in adventures.
And how long do you intend
to walk the earth?
Till God puts me
where he wants me to be.
And what if he don't do that?
If it takes forever,
then I'll walk forever.
So you decided to be a bum?
I'll just be Jules, Vincent...
no more, no less.
No, Jules.
You decided to be a bum...
Just like all those
pieces of shit out there...
who beg for change...
who sleep in garbage bins,
eat what I throw away.
They got a name
for that, Jules.
It's called a bum.
And without a job, a residence,
or legal tender...
that's what you're
going to be, man.
You're going
to be a fucking bum.
Look, my friend, this is just
where you and I differ.
Garcon!
Coffee!
What happened this morning,
man, I agree it was peculiar.
Garcon means boy.
But water into wine. I...
All shapes and sizes, Vincent.
Don't fucking talk to me
that way, man.
If my answers
frighten you, Vincent...
then you should cease
asking scary questions.
I'm going to take a shit.
Let me ask you something.
When did you
make this decision?
When you were sitting there
eating that muffin?
Well, yeah.
I was sitting here
eating my muffin...
and drinking my coffee...
and replaying
the incident in my head...
when I had what alcoholics
refer to as a moment of clarity.
Fuck.
To be continued.
I love you, Pumpkin.
And I love you, Honey Bunny.
Everybody be cool!
This is a robbery!
Any of you
fucking pricks move...
and I'll execute every one
of you motherfuckers!
You got that?
You just be quiet!
Get the fuck down!
You, you're in a blind spot.
Take your dames to that booth
on the count of ten.
Mexicans out
of the fucking kitchen!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight!
Where the fuck are you going?
You fucking yuppie! Get down!
Hey, you, throw those bags!
Fucking wanker! Move! Move!
What the fuck are you doing?
Move!
The restaurant's ours!
Get down on the fucking floor!
Grandpa, down!
I'm the manager here...
and there's no problem...
no problem at all.
You're going to give me
a problem?
No, sir, I'm not.
I thought you said you're going
to give me a fucking problem!
You're going to give me
a fucking problem?
I think we got a hero here,
Honey Bunny!
Well, just execute him!
I am not a hero.
I'm just a coffee shop...
Get the fuck down!
The restaurant's ours!
Just take whatever you want.
- You talk to the customers.
- Yeah.
You tell them
to be fucking cool...
- and everything will be over!
- Yeah.
- You understand me?
- Yes.
Listen, everybody.
Be calm...
cooperate...
and this will all be over
in a minute.
Get the fuck down!
Well done.
All right, now, people...
I'm going to come around
and collect your wallets.
You don't fucking talk.
You just throw them in the bag.
Are we clear?
I said, are we fucking clear?
Good. Now wallets out.
That's it.
Get the fuck down.
In the bag.
In the fucking bag!
I don't have
nothing on me, man.
What am I waiting for?
In the fucking bag.
Laura? Laura, tips.
- In the bag.
- Yeah.
- Is that a cellular phone?
In the fucking bag.
Tidy up, tidy up.
That's it.
Now get the fuck
down on the floor.
In the bag.
What's in the case?
My boss's dirty laundry.
Your boss makes you
do his laundry?
When he wants it clean.
Sounds like a shit job.
Funny.
I was thinking the same thing.
Open it.
Afraid I can't do that.
I didn't hear you.
Yes, you did.
What's going on?
Looks like we got
a vigilante in our midst.
Shoot him in the face.
I hate to shatter your ego,
but this ain't the first time...
I've had a gun pointed at me.
You don't take your hand off
that case, it'll be your last.
Stop causing problems!
You'll get us all killed!
Give 'em what you got
and get 'em out of there!
Shut the fuck up, fat man!
This ain't none
of your goddamn business.
Be cool, Honey Bunny. Be cool.
It's no problem.
I got it under control.
Now I'm going to count to three.
If you don't open that case...
I'm going to unload
in your fucking face.
We clear?
One...
two...
- three.
- OK, Ringo.
You win.
It's yours.
Open it.
What is it?
Is that what I think it is?
Mm-hmm.
It's beautiful.
God damn it, what is it?
You let him go! You let him go!
Let go of him!
- Tell that bitch to be cool!
- I'm gonna kill you!
- Say, "Bitch, be cool!"
- Be cool, Honey Bunny!
- Be cool!
Tell that fuckin' bitch
to chill!
Be cool, Honey Bunny!
- Chill that fuckin' bitch out!
- Chill out, Honey Bunny!
- Let go of him!
Chill!
Tell her it's
going to be all right.
It's going to be all right.
- Promise her!
- I promise!
- Tell her to chill!
- Just chill out, Honey Bunny!
- Now tell me her name.
- Yolanda.
All right, now, Yolanda!
We're not gonna
do anything stupid, are we?
Don't you hurt him!
Nobody's gonna hurt anybody.
We're all gonna be like
three little Fonzies here.
And what's Fonzie like?
Come on, Yolanda,
what's Fonzie like?!
He's cool?
What?
- Cool.
Correctamundo!
And that's what we're gonna be.
We're gonna be cool.
Now, Ringo,
I'm gonna count to three.
And when I count three...
I want you to let go
of your gun...
put your palms
flat on the table...
and sit your ass down.
But when you do it,
you do it cool.
You ready?
One...
two...
three.
OK, now you let him go!
Yolanda, I thought
you were gonna be cool.
Now, when you yell at me,
it makes me nervous.
And when I get nervous,
I get scared.
And when motherfuckers
get scared...
that's when motherfuckers
accidentally get shot.
Just know,
you hurt him, you die.
Well, that seems
to be the situation.
But I don't want that,
and you don't want that...
and Ringo here definitely
doesn't want that.
So let's see what we can do.
Now...
here's the situation.
Normally both your asses...
would be dead
as fuckin' fried chicken...
but you happened
to pull this shit...
while I'm in
a transitional period...
and I don't want to kill you.
I want to help you.
But I can't give you this case,
'cause it don't belong to me.
Besides, I been through
too much shit over this case...
to just hand it over
to your dumb ass.
Vincent!
Be cool!
Yolanda, it's cool, baby!
It's cool!
We still just talking!
Come on, point the gun at me!
Point the gun at me!
There you go.
Now, Vincent, you just hang back
and don't do a goddamn thing.
Tell her we're still cool.
We're still cool, Honey Bunny.
How we doing, baby?
I... I gotta go pee.
I want to go home.
Just hang in there, baby.
You're doin' great.
I'm proud of you.
And Ringo's proud of you.
It's almost over.
Tell her you're proud of her.
I'm proud of you, Honey Bunny.
I love you.
I love you, too, Honey Bunny.
I want you to go in that bag
and find my wallet.
Which one is it?
It's the one that says
"Bad Motherfucker."
That's it.
That's my Bad Motherfucker.
Open it up. Take out the money.
Count it.
How much is there?
About $1,500.
OK, put it in your pocket.
It's yours.
With the rest of those wallets
and the register...
that makes this a pretty
successful little score.
Jules, you give
that fuckin' nimrod $1,500...
and I'll shoot him
on general principle.
No, Yolanda, Yolanda!
He ain't gonna do a goddamn
motherfuckin' thing.
Vince, shut the fuck up!
Shut up!
Come on, Yolanda,
stay with me, baby.
Now, I ain't givin' it to him,
Vincent.
I'm buyin' somethin'
for my money.
Wanna know what I'm buyin',
Ringo?
What?
Your life.
I'm givin' you that money...
so I don't have
to kill your ass.
You read the Bible, Ringo?
Not regularly, no.
Well, there's this passage
I got memorized.
"Ezekiel" 25:17.
"The path of the righteous man
is beset on all sides...
"by the inequities
of the selfish...
"and the tyranny of evil men.
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity and good will...
"shepherds the weak through
the Valley of Darkness...
"for he is truly
his brother's keeper...
"and the finder
of lost children.
"And I will strike down
upon thee...
"with great vengeance
and furious anger...
"those who attempt to poison
and destroy My brothers.
"And you will know
I am the Lord...
"when I lay My vengeance
upon you."
Now, I been sayin'
that shit for years.
And if you heard it,
that meant your ass.
I never gave much thought
to what it meant.
I just thought
it was some cold-blooded shit...
to say to a motherfucker before
I popped a cap in his ass.
But I saw some shit this mornin'
made me think twice.
See, now I'm thinkin'...
maybe it means
you're the evil man...
and I'm the righteous man...
and Mr. Nine-millimeter here...
he's the shepherd
protecting my righteous ass...
in the Valley of Darkness.
Or it could mean...
you're the righteous man
and I'm the shepherd...
and it's the world
that's evil and selfish.
Now, I'd like that.
But that shit ain't the truth.
The truth is...
you're the weak...
and I am the tyranny
of evil men.
But I'm tryin', Ringo.
I'm tryin' real hard
to be the shepherd.
Go on.
I think we should
be leaving now.
Yeah,
that's probably a good idea.