...from here in London, Financial Times 100 Index up 11 points
just above the key 3800 level.
As for the rest of Europe, Frankfort's DAX
gaining 9 points to 2532.
...The CAC market losing 7;
the weaker Franc weighing on the market.
Thank you, Ilsa.
Have a nice day.
If you are on time this morning
according to this...
San Francisco's freeways are...
Well tell me what
we're supposed to do.
I mean you may be perched
on majority shares...
...but we all get fucked
at the actual crash.
That old man is going to sink us.
Soon as I have Baer/Grant's
P and L report in hand...
...I will be speed dialing your number.
Is that a promise?
I'm sorry, I'm not aware of that term.
Well what do I do if Anson calls about
substantiation procedure?
Take evasive actions have your
secretary say you're in a meeting
Thank you, Jack.
- Yes, Maria.
- Invitations.
- Mm-hmm.
- The museum gala.
- No.
- The Fitswilliam botanical annual fundraiser.
- The Hinchburger wedding.
Hinchburger wedding...
...tuxedos and droning conversations,
I don' t think so, no.
I'll send your regrets.
Honestly why must I bother.
You don't know about society,
Maria.
You don't have the satisfaction
of avoiding it.
- Yes.
- I have an Elizabeth on line 3.
Your ex-wife.
I know who it is.
Take a message.
Oh, happy birthday, sir.
Thank you, Maggie.
I don't like her.
I wouldn't even mention the following,
but he was very insistent.
- It's obviously some sort of prank.
- What?
Well, a gentleman called requesting
to have lunch with you.
I tried to assure him
that you're very busy.
- What's his name?
- A Mr. Seymour Butts.
'Under the Bleachers'
by Seymore Butts.
I'm sorry?
Cancel my lunch, make a reservation
to City Club for myself and Mr. Butts.
My usual table.
Maria,
put the reservation under my name.
- You ready to order, sir.
- No, I'm still waiting.
This was ice tea?
- Boo!
- Conrad, what a surprise!
Happy birthday, Nickie.
Seymore Butts,
I'll never get tired of that one.
That's why it's a classic.
This is nice restaurant.
- They give me free jacket.
- I'm sure they're gonna want it back.
- I remember being here a long time ago.
- Yeah, I took you here once.
No, I used to buy
crystal-meth off the maitre d'.
- Oh, really?
- In college.
Which college?
Touche.
Miss me?
As much as that's possible.
- You look good.
- So do you.
Think I was worried.
Worried about me?
How long has it been since
Mom's funeral? 2-3 years?
- I thought you quit.
- I did. It didn't take.
Well, you can't smoke here.
I'm with you.
It's illegal to smoke
in restaurants in California.
Fuck California.
How are you?
Couldn't be better.
Elizabeth?
We're divorced, she remarried
a pediatrician or a gynecologist...
...or pediatric gynecologist.
Lives in, uh... Sausalito.
That's too bad.
I liked her.
And what about you?
What, you don't keep track
of me anymore?
Not since family week at rehab.
So what brings you to town Conrad?
Everything all right?
Yeah.
- Need anything?
- Nope.
Really?
No, I don't need anything from you.
I just...
...have myself laying naked
on the beach near Bisa...
...and all the sudden it click.
October 12th...
...Nickie's birthday.
October 11th.
Whatever.
This is for you.
You shouldn't have.
What do you get for the man
who has... everything?
Consumer Recreation Services.
Well, I do have golf clubs.
Call that number.
- Why?
- To make your life... fun.
- Fun?
- You know what that is, that you've seen other people have.
It's an entertainment service.
An escort service?
A profound life experience.
- Sorry, oh, put this napkin...
- No, that's all right, just...
Tell me you'd call.
- I said I would.
- No, you didn't.
You still on medication?
Why would you say that?
You gentlemen ready to order?
I didn't mean it the way it sounded.
I'm not on anything,
I'm not even seeing a shrink...
...and I feel great.
Do you mind?
I think you'll like this
I did.
That was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I'll call them.
Do it... for you.
I said I'll call, ok?
All right, I'll call.
It's just that...
uh... I hate surprises.
I know.
# Happy Birthday to you...
Happy Birthday to you...
# Happy Birthday, Mr. Van Orton...
- ...Mr. Van Orton...
# - Happy Birthday to you.
Someone's got to fly to Seattle and
drive a stake through Anson's heart...
- Have you seen the profitability report?
- You can imagine how much more unhappy I am.
- So you're gonna deal with Anson?
- That's correct.
-We're furious.
-Sleep well, Nicholas.
I will.
Good night, Ilsa.
Dinner's in the oven.
Thank you.
Oh, I saw Conrad today.
Did you? How is he?
He's okay.
I think he's in one of those...
...personal improvement cults or something.
Well, send my love,
if you see him again.
- Happy birthday.
- Good night.
From companies that defaulted
on their payments...
...the FCC expects to receive more than
500 million dollars in bids...
...as the licenses eagerly soar...
Elizabeth, good evening.
Happy birthday, Nickie.
Eleven Forty.
You almost missed it this year.
Have you had a nice birthday?
Does Rose Kennedy
have a black dress?
And went not once but twice
through the spanking machine.
Can only imagine.
How are you?
Connie asked me
the same thing today.
Connie really?
I always liked your brother.
Anyway...
I...
- ...I just thought this might be difficult for you.
- Just another birthday.
Because of your father...
That's right,
he was 48, wasn't he?
I hadn't really thought
about it until now.
Why do I call?
I honestly don' t know...
Please send Dr. Mel
and Rachel my best.
She has a little brother
on the way.
We did the ultra sound.
Offical nuclear family.
You must be very pleased.
We are.
We are very pleased.
Well, it's good to talk with you.
I guess I should let you go.
Take care of yourself.
You, too, Nicholas,
I mean that.
- I really do.
- Uh huh, be well, bye.
A proposal to encourage small businesses
to provide their employees...
...with health insurance
is now being debated...
...by Washington legislators...
...the bill which a type is
a small business help lands...
...to those of larger corporations
is receiving an initial support...
...from the number of
key Republican leaders.
However Democratic lawmakers...
...are voicing serious concerns about...
...claiming that it would under mine
local officials...
I just wanna make sure
that we understand each other...
Once you get it down on paper,
then you can count on my full support.
- We understand.
- Thank you.
We'll talk soon.
Well, you shouldn't feel
this reflects negatively on now.
- I can feel that it was negatively done on me.
- I received this...
Just a moment.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
I understand.
We hope we haven't
caused you any inconvenience.
Thank you for choosing C. R. S.
Mr. Feingold,
could you assist this gentleman?
Oh, yeah... sure.
Jim Feingold,
VP Engineering, Data Analysis.
I don't know exactly how this works,
my brother sent me this card as a gift.
Oh, here we go, yeah.
All right, excellent,
well... um, let's get started.
Yeah, I'm sorry about the,
you know all this, hullabaloo here...
We're, uh... well, we're still moving.
You mind holding that?
Thank you very much!
Thank you.
- Are you hungry? New Moon Cafe?
- No, thank you.
Gift from Conrad Van Orton.
Interesting.
- What is?
- Well, your brother was a client with our London branch.
We do a sort of informal scoring...
...and his numbers are outstanding.
Really?
- You sure you're not hungry?
- No, thank you, I'll be fine.
Now need to fill out the...
these forms.
There's an application...
...and then a...
...couple of psych-tests there,
MNPI and PAP...
Oh, uh... for the financial
questionnaire...
...don't answer anything
you don't feel like.
We'll run our TRW.
I sometimes hurt small animals,
true or false?
I feel guilty when I masturbate.
Well, I don't write the questions,
I just review the answers.
What is this for?
Well, to give us
an overall sense of your capability.
No, what is this for?
What are you selling?
- Oh, it's a game.
- A game?
Specifically tailored
to each participant.
Think of it as a great vacation,
except you don' t go to it...
...it comes to you.
What... what kind of vacation?
It's different every time.
Humor me with specifics.
We provide...
...whatevers lacking.
And what if nothing is lacking?
May I make two suggestions?
You really think that I'll participate
without knowing any...
First, admit to yourself
that it sounds intriguing...
...second, you don' t have
to decide today...
Take the silly test
fill out the stupid forms...
...one day your game begins,
you either love it or hate it, decide then.
You know we... we are like...
...an experiential Book-of-the-Month-Club.
You can drop out at any time
with no further obligations.
That was my sales pitch.
How long will this take?
About an hour for those,
another hour for the physical.
- Physical?
- It's a cursory examination...
...turn-your-head-caugh sort of thing,
you'll be out of here in no time.
Confused.
Risky.
Bloody.
Oops.
- Mr. Sutherland called about the Baer/Grant Publishing.
- Cancel it, push it back to Wednesday.
- Grants say they'll go back tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Yes.
How much longer
is this going to take?
Shouldn't be long, we're almost done.
You said that two hours ago
- All right, put it back until tomorrow.
- ...selection...
...before the following emotional responses.
You have 0.9 seconds to
continue. Your emotional...
...reaction time for the factor...
Would you make a selection
before the following emotional responses.
You have 0.9 seconds to continue.
Is this thing end?
I'm sorry to keep you here waiting.
Well, don't worry, it's been just terrific
spending my entire day with your guarantee.
Well, it's all down to this.
This is an insurance company requirement,
it states that you're aware...
...that the game exists and that you're
willing to participate in said game...
...so on and so forth our guarantee
that the payment's entirely...
...at your brother's discretion as a gift
it's dependent on your satisfaction.
Does that mean that if I'm not happy,
he doesn't have to pay?
That's never happened,
we've never had an unsatisfied customer.
I think you mean dissatisfied.
That's right, your
left-brain word fetishist.
Initials, initials
and you sign there.
...in blood.
Just kidding.
All right, now your copy will be
at the front desk in this folder.
And I'll... keep the pen.
We'll let you know.
- What about Monday or Tuesday?
- No, that's bad for me.
- Well, how about tonight?
- Well, I'm working all this evening.
Wednesday is the only possibility
right now.
- Do you wanna do dinner?
- Okay.
By the way, I went to C. R. S.
Really? What did you think?
Well, they seemed just
a little bit disorganized.
Well, when I did it in London,
they've been around a while.
Are you gonna do this?
No, I haven't decided yet.
...telling you it's the way
to getting in on the ground floor...
...for the next Disneyland.
C. R. S. won' t go public,
their family owned.
Stranger things have happened.
No, they haven't actually.
They opened here.
"The game" in San Francisco?
See?
They're doing fine without any of us.
- How are you, James? Good evening.
- Good evening, sir.
Get new members here?
Believe so, sir.
Put the next round on me.
Got you, sir.
No, no, no.
Last time I played Pebble, I swore
I'd never pick up another club again.
Speaking about games...
...couldn't help to overhear you
talking about C. R. S..
Well, the reason I mentioned is...
I took the test today
the Montgomery street office.
You did? Kudos.
So, yours hasn't started yet?
No, not yet, that was one of
the questions I had for you.
- What is it?
- Oh, what is it?
The eternal question.
You know I envy you.
I wish I could go back and do it
for the first time all over again.
Here's to... new experiences.
Hmm, if you'll excuse me,
I got to go.
Good night, Ted.
- Nicholas...
- Nice to meet you.
So, you played recently?
Oh, about a year ago.
I was working in Los Angeles.
Oh, I heard the London office
is very good too...
It sounds like lot of
fantasy role playing nonsense, though.
You wanna know what it is?
What it's all about?
John, chapter 9, verse 25.
I, um...
- ...haven't been to Sunday school in a long time.
- Whereas once I was blind...
...now I can see.
Good night, Nicholas.
Best of luck.
Good night.
If the Baer/Grant meeting...
...is not held tomorrow...
...may as well not be held at all.
When Mr. Van Orton boards
his plane on the morrow...
...he'll have every agreement and
addendum in the complete closing package...
...flawlessly revised.
So you will miss another opera
you would of have slept during anyway.
We now have an opportunity
to show our clients...
...how well we will rise
to his exhilarating challenge.
- Yes?
- Nicholas Van Orton?
- Who is this?
- This is Cynthia from C. R. S.
- How did you get this number?
- We've finished processing your...
- Look, I'm in a meeting right now.
- I'm afraid it was rejected.
- I beg your pardon?
- You shouldn't feel this reflects negatively on you...
...we hope we haven' t
caused you any inconvenience.
- Uh, this is ridiculous.
- Thank you for speaking to C.R.S.
Anything wrong?
Uh... no, no, nothing's...
...you may hang up
or press tab for more options.
Oh, this is Conrad.
Leave a message.
Yes, Connie it's Nicholas,
give me a ring when you get in.
Oh, uh... regarding your birthday present...
um... things are a little crazy right now.
I don't even know if I can
fit it in my schedule.
But we'll talk about it
at dinner tomorrow.
Thanks, bye.
Hello...
...the resulting rise
of unemployment are decline...
...into buyable small businesses.
Meanwhile Republican leaders argue...
...that this passage would be
the very stimulant...
...that a sluggish economy needs.
No one has expressed an opinion...
...as to how it will impact on
pampered existence of Nicholas Van Orton.
For one thing on which both
Democrats and Republicans seem to agree...
...is that most Americans have a serious
doubts about the Economic future.
A recent poll suggests that a staggering
57% of American workers believe...
...there is a very real chance
they will be unemployed...
...within the next 5 to 7 years.
But what does that matter to
a bloated millionaire fat cat like you?
And now for financial news.
Stock markets rose both domestically...
...and abroad today
after the announcement of...
...stronger than expected earnings
by several high tech companies...
...but dipped again reacting to report
Nicholas Van Orton has sneezed.
Are you gonna spend the rest of
the evening prying at that clown' s mouth?
I... I... I don' t...
It's frustrating for me
if you don't pay attention.
What is this?
This is your game, Nicholas
and welcome to it.
I'm here to let you in
on a few ground rules.
You received the very first key
and others will follow.
You'll never know where you'll find them
or how you'll need to use it.
So keep your eyes open.
How do you...
You can see me?
Let us save the questions to afterwards.
How does this work?
There's a tiny camera
looking at you...
...right now.
It's impossible.
You're right, impossible.
You're having a conversation
with your television.
It's miniaturized.
You know how dangerous that is?
- Mr. Van Orton?
- ...and in domestic news, sunny California...
Yes, Ilsa, what is it?
- Is everything all right?
- Fine.
...in the petroleum processing
plant yesterday...
- I finished for the evening, will you be needing anything else?
- ...in sunny California...
No, I won't, Ilsa, thank you.
Good night.
- Good night, then.
- ...under control of major that broke out...
...in a petroleum processing
plant yesterday...
Several weeks...
- Who was that?
- Never mind who that is.
- You wanna know how a camera got into you home, don't you?
- Yes, I would.
Cold.
Co... colder.
Wa... wa... warm.
Warmer.
Write this number down.
It's a 24 hour
Consumer Recreation Services hotline.
For emergencies only.
But don't call asking
what the object of the game is...
...figuring that out...
...is the object of the game.
Good luck and
congratulations on choosing...
C... R... S...
Great to have the American ambassador
expelled after the incident.
Who the State Department responded
quickly with a forward apology.
An announcement with the ambassadors
will be immediate voluntary...
May I help you?
What is it?
What?
Thank you.
Buddy?
Can you help me out?
I need some toilet paper.
I ran out.
Just... just go out to the next stall.
Come on, help me out.
Hello?
Didn't expect to see you here.
I wanted to wish you luck.
Been up all night?
I checked it...
...personally.
I appreciate that, Sam.
Why don't you go home and get some sleep?
- You're sure you don't want me along?
- No, I'll be fine.
Hmm, nice shirt.
Don't ask.
Cio!
All of these years...
...the first time ever
you stepped forward in these offices...
...it's to ask me to step down.
You promised to meet
the projections, Anson...
...a dollar sixty per shares is
what you said.
I don't think
this visit comes as a surprise.
- Projections were far too optimistic
- Admittedly, yes.
Our E.P.S. was 150 last quarter,
we're up 8 cents.
The expectations were 10 and this
case the expectations meant everything
Will you really hold me to
it over pennies?
My stock is falling,
I don' t know about yours...
...those pennies are costing millions.
Give me... give me next quarter.
If you still feel this way,
vote your shares.
Today is what counts, Anson.
You...
you intractable son of bitch.
Your father could see you know.
- What?
- Your father was a friend.
You're friends! God damn it,
I've watched you grew up.
Because you went fishing with my father,
I should sit on my hands...
- ...while you're throwing my money away?
- I...
I'm not finished.
You misspoke before
when you said you're stepping down.
I am firing you.
Action is taken,
confidence is restored...
The stock goes up.
No.
There's no Baer/Grant Publishing...
...no Baer/Grant Publishing
without...
...Anson Baer.
Where's Stewart Grant?
He's probably out there sailing...
...and enjoying his golden years,
wondering where the hell you are, Anson.
I'm sorry...
...you failed.
I have prepared severance package
that is more than...
...equitable.
Valid until...
...this evening.
I could fight you with this.
If I leave without your signature...
...this agreement begins to disintegrate...
...and if it's shrink, options narrow...
...and your compensation will be shriveled.
Think it's in your...
...best interest, Anson.
Well, I guess this is your...
...lucky day.
My lawyers will be
in touch with you.
Excuse me,
has Conrad Van Orton left a message?
- I'll check on it right away, Mr. Van Orton.
- Thank you.
- Oh, I'm so sorry. Here.
- Please, don't do that.
I'm so sorry, I wasn't even looking.
I'm really having a bad day.
How about a bad month?
You did almost exactly the same
thing to me when I was here last week.
Here.
Don't do that. Just get me some... uh...
some napkins and... uh... some soda water.
Looks like the... uh...
...cleaning's gonna mean
more than the suit.
I don't think so.
- It was an accident, sir.
- Terrific.
I said I was sorry.
Asshole.
Cristine!
Mr. Van Orton is a valued customer.
Fine, then you kiss his ass.
Don't you talk to me like that.
I apologized, I offered to help,
what do you want me to do?
Clean out your locker.
- What?
- You heard me.
I'm terribly sorry, Mr. Van Orton.
If you're not too uncomfortable...
...will this table suit you
for complimentary meal?
Be fine.
- I'll fetch your waiter.
- Thank you.
Check, sir.
- Miss, pardon me, miss?
- Oh, great, it's you.
I don't know how this works,
but you have something for me.
I... uh...
- I received this note.
- What're you about? Babbling about psycho?
I need to know
what is going on.
You wanna know whats going on?
I'm going on my second job this month now.
Looks like I'm going on unemployment.
- Maybe I should try to explain.
- Don't explain, just fuck off.
Son of a bitch!
I am... I'm trying to...
I'm apologizing... I...
Jesus, what is this?
- What's with him?
- I don't know, he just he fell down.
Can you hear me?
- Do you know what to do?
- I don't even know if he's breathing.
Move your head.
Don't stand there, get help.
Hey, hey, it's ok.
How do we know he's real?
He's pissing his pants, mister.
Is that real enough for you?
Help me, God!
He's turning blue.
Police! Police!
You will have to fill this forms out.
I don't know this man.
- Here, what do you need.
- Can't get involved in this.
- Hey, I might have to detain you.
- Detain me?
- The reports gotta be filled out.
- She can do the reports.
Ride with your wife.
We'll meet at the hospital.
- The hospital?
- Two blocks away.
She's not my wife.
Let's go.
This is insane.
10 minutes ago, I'm about to
enjoy a quiet little dinner...
...and received this note.
- He's breathing, isn't he?
- Yes.
Is the siren entirely necessary?
Let's just talk to someone
who can get this over with, shall we?
Hang on.
They need your
drivers license number.
Oh, no,
you've got to be kidding.
What is... uh...
- ...happening?
- This was what I was trying to explain to you.
This is a... uh...
...a game.
- A what?
- It's a company.
They plan elaborate pranks.
Things like this.
I don't really understand it myself.
What are you talking about?
This is a...
The lights, they went out...
...hundred people ran away.
What you mean the guy who just...
...pissed himself
and turned blue was...
Sorry about that.
You should be.
Why're they involving you?
There's gotta be a...
...a flashlight.
Oh, great.
I thought that guy was going to die
gave him a mouth to mouth.
I'll see you around.
- How do you know that's the way?
- I don't.
Where did you all go
you motherfucking frat boys?
You'd better hide.
Lobby?
My brother got me this
gift certificate to this company.
Why? I got the key out of this uh...
...out of the mouth of this... uh...
...wooden clown.
Never mind.
I didn't like this.
There's no signal.
What is the going rate
for a trapped-in-elevator-adventure?
Well, don't even think about it.
- Why not?
- Read what the sign says.
"Warning: Do not attempt to open,
if the elevator stops..."
"...use an emergency..."
- Phone?
- Phone...
If there was one.
We'll wait for help, so.
Let's just wait for help.
Okay, I'll give you a boost.
You get up, you go first.
This is not an attempt to be gallant,
if I don' t lift you...
...how are you going to
get up there?
I don't know, you pull me up.
It's easier my way,
come on, step up.
- No.
- Oh, please.
I'm not wearing any underwear.
Okay, there I said it.
Okay.
We can use this like a ladder.
My hero, let's go.
I don't think so.
Thank you.
Damn it! My briefcase!
I'll wait.
Not as if anybody can open it.
Wait a minute,
this is C. R. S.
- What's C. R. S.?
- This is the company that I was telling you about.
The one that gave me a
gift certificate.
This is their building.
We'll wait,
we'll wait for the security to come...
...and we'll just explain.
They'll love that!
Explain for both of us!
We don't wanna draw it,
don't draw any attentions.
- Just out for a stall.
- Run!
We can't fit down there!
Are you trying to ditch me?
- Hey! you're a grown man, I'm not responsible for...
- I'm not the one who started running.
Well, I'm not
the one that started this...
- Go up there!
- I'm going.
Here.
Climb.
So where's your modesty
around the pet dogs?
Hey! Shut up!
Stupid fucking dogs!
Let me guess!
I go first.
There goes a thousand dollars.
Your shoes cost a thousand dollars?
That one did.
Here.
Come on.
It's right there.
Meals Miles.
What?
It should be here.
Fire escape.
Yeah, it's classic.
Why me?
Who are you?
Nicholas Van Orton.
What are you,
a czar or something?
All right.
I think...
...if we...
...drop from here...
...the garbage will break our fall.
I think not.
Be careful!
What the fuck are you looking at?
Oh...
...shit!
Table for two please.
Where're we going?
That tall bright building.
It's right near there.
Everything okay, miss?
Yeah.
How are you doing?
San Francisco's finest...
Is there some place
I could throw this?
There's a waste basket
beside the desk.
Oh...
Think I have a fresh sweat shirt
for you somewhere.
That would be great.
You know, you've never even
asked me my name.
Well, uh... maitre d' said
you're name was Christine.
All right.
I guess I'll call you a cab.
You got a shower in your office?
Yeah.
You an athlete or something?
No, I'm an investment banker.
I move money from
one place to another.
Actually, would you mind
if I just...
...quickly rinsed off?
No.
- Is there a towel I could use?
- Yeah, it's... uh.. it's... it's behind the door.
- Oh, I'll just be a second.
- No problem.
Listen, I know the owner of the city club
and I'd be happy to give him a call...
...if you'd like.
Don't, it was a shitty job anyway.
I overreacted.
I, uh...
I have a confession to make.
Someone gave me 400 bucks to
spill drinks on you as a...
...practical joke.
Really?
And what did they say?
Well, they said 300, I said 4...
...they said the guy in
the gray flannel suit...
...I think I said the...
...attractive guy in
the gray flannel suit?
Mr. Van Orton?
- Hello?
- Mr. Van Orton, it's Maria.
- I thought I should call.
- What time is it?
It's 11 o'clock.
I took the liberty of rescheduling
your meeting with Alison and...
No, no, no,
I'll be in there in an hour.
Can you, I left my briefcase
at 1019 Montgomery Street...
Could you check with
the Losts and Founds please?
- Anson Baers in town at the Ritz Carlton.
- Really?
- He's requesting dinner tonight.
- Well, we'll see about that.
And the Hotel Niko called to say...
...they have your
American Express card at the front desk.
You left it there last night?
- Should I send someone?
- No, just give me the number.
- 555-1111.
- Call you back.
Good morning! Hotel Niko.
Yes, this is Nicholas Van Orton.
I'm told you have my American Express card.
Yes, Mr. Van Orton,
everything's in order...
...the concierge has arranged for the wine
and flowers in the room.
Has he?
And a young woman phoned
to say that she's on route...
...but running a little late.
Did the young woman
leave her name?
I'm sure I don't know.
Of course you don't.
Thank you.
Sorry, my fault.
Ah, Mr. Van Orton.
Welcome back.
Here we go.
Have we met?
I believe so.
If you'll just sign here...
...on the signature card.
Thank you.
My key?
Don't I get a key?
Didn't I give you one last night?
No, I don't think so.
Cute, that's very cute.
This way, sir.
Have a nice day.
House keeping.
Could you come back a little later?
Ah...
Shit!
Where the fuck is he?
Why are you following me?
What are you talking about?
I'm not following you.
I'm just driving it.
Hey...
- ...whatever I'm doing is none of your business.
- Is Anson Baer the game?
Is that what this is all about?
Yo, buddy, back off,
just back off, huh?
What?
Oh, that's cute,
that's really cute.
I suppose the game uses
real bullets, huh?
All right,
I'm a private investigator.
Somebody hired me
to keep tabs on you.
Who?
Who hired you?
- Mr. Van Orton...
- Maria, get hold of Sutherland.
Have him meet me at
the Ritz Carlton.
I'm on my way.
- What's happening?
- Follow me, Sam.
Ah, Nicholas!
It's unexpected.
Have you really believed...
...that just because
you publish children's books...
...people's gonna care about
my reputation?
You could have pictures of me...
...wearing nipple rings
butt fucking captain kangaroo...
...the only thing they care about
is the stock!
And whether that stock is up or down...
- Daddy?
- It's all right, it's all right.
And the fact that you bring Conrad
into this juvenile game...
...is unconscionable.
- Are you finished?
- No! I'm not finished!
I'd like you to meet
my attorney, Samuel Sutherland.
I think the two of you
have got something to talk about.
Oh, we've met this morning.
I signed the determination contract
for Baer/Grant.
I accepted your settlement, Nicholas.
You were right.
I'm going sailing,
you know, sailing.
You're welcome to join our lunch
maybe...
...we can straighten this out.
You remember my wife Mary Carol
and my daughter-in-law Kaliegh.
Please, uh...
...accept my...
...misguided, uh...
How concerned should I be?
It was a misunderstanding.
It looks a lot like you.
Well, you should see
what they do with the nightly news.
What?
Can I ask you to do me a favor?
You know you can
Find out about a company called
Consumer Recreation Services.
Sounds like they make
tennis rackets.
What do you know?
Well, they gave me a waiver...
- What is this?
- It's a...
I don't believe it,
it's invisible ink.
- Your joking.
- This is what I'm dealing with. I'm being toyed with by...
...by a bunch of depraved
children, this...
Are you ok?
Tell me not to worry.
You don't have to worry.
I promise.
I'll call you later.
Right.
Maria, the other night...
...last night...
...got a taxi for
a young woman named Christine...
What's the company that we use?
United?
- What?
- United Taxi Company.
United Taxi...
...then you call United,
find out who the driver was and...
...where they took her.
Ilsa!
I have a gun!
#...and you just had some kind of mushroom
and your mind is moving slow...
#...go ask Alice...
#...I think she'll know...
#...when logic and proportion
have fallen sloppy dead...
#...and the white knight is talking backwards
and the red queen's off...
# Remember what the doormouse said:..
Ilsa? Ilsa... Ilsa...
- Mr. Van Orton!
- Are you all right?
What do you mean?
What's happened?
The house,
you haven't seen the house?
What's wrong?
There's been a break in,
now lock your door...
- Stay inside, just lock your door.
- Oh, be careful.
- 911, emergency?
- Yes, I need the police.
- There's been a break in to my house.
- Stay on the line and give me your address.
My address is 2210, Broadway.
It's the biggest house on the street.
- Now, sir, you said it was a break in?
- Yes, yes, there's been a break in.
Are you sure they're gone?
What?
Are you sure there's not still
someone somewhere in the house?
- Nickie!
- Sir?
Are you still there?
- Meet me in your car.
- Hello?
Hello?
Sir?
- All right. What happened?
- Sssh.
Conrad, where're we going?
Just wait!
What are you doing?
With the facts...
...I can't trust
a room service in the hotel...
...I sure as hell can't
trust the fucking car.
- Who?
- C. R. S.! who do you think?
Jesus! To think what
I almost got you into.
What are you saying?
Oh, I'm so fucked.
They just fuck you! And they fuck you!
And they fuck you!
And just when you think it's all over,
that's when the real fucking starts!
All right, calm down,
just take a breath.
They won't stop, Nick.
I paid the bill.
I gave them their fucking money.
They won't leave me alone!
What're they doing to you?
Everything!
I'm a goddamned human pinata.
Calm down!
- And why're they keep playing, if you've already paid?
- I don't know.
I don' t know.
I paid them more to make it stop!
They did this.
It's a flat tire.
How do you know?!
Get a grip on yourself, will you?
We'll figure it out!
Okay, okay.
The phone doesn't work.
I can't get a signal.
Really?
- You know how to change a tire?
- No, don't you?
It can't be that hard.
I don't think we should be out
in the open like this.
Hit the teletrack
it's lift-left compartment.
You're with them.
What?
You're doing this,
you're part of it.
Whose are these?
I don't know about those.
Somebody put them in the car.
You're behind the whole thing,
aren't you?
What are you talking about?
You brought them to me.
These were in your car!
Now right there in your fucking car!
Conrad!
Listen to what you're saying.
No! You're not gonna
control this conversation!
Why would I ever do
what you're describing?
Because you resent me.
Stop being emotional.
- It kills you that I'm living my life.
- Lower your voice, Conrad!
What? You're afraid
somebody's gonna witness the scene?
Get back in there!
Get back to your fucking house!
- Will you stop it?
- I'm calling the cops.
You're just so afraid
that somebody's gonna see...
...what a manipulated
fucking control freak you are!
What is wrong with you?
What are you on?
Oh, I'm sorry, Nick...
I'm sorry I didn't
live up to your expectations.
Ah, bullshit!
I'm not you, I'll never be you,
I don't wanna be you.
There you go again!
I'm your brother!
- Always push the responsibility out on me
- For Christ's sakes! I'm your brother!
- All I ever tried to do is help you.
- I don't want your help!
- Nobody asked you to play Dad!
- No! You don't say that.
Did I have a choice?
Conrad!
What?
I don't want your help!
- Nobody asked you to play Dad!
- Did I have a choice?
Did I have a choice?
Taxi!
2210, Broadway.
Hey, buddy, you missed a turn.
Hey!
Do you hear me?
You missed a turn back...
No, no, no!
Stop the car!
Thank you.
Open the door.
Unlock the door.
Open the goddamn door!
Listen.
I... am a very wealthy man.
And whatever they're paying you...
...I'll double it.
No!
What are you, out of
your fucking mind?
It's a game.
It's game.
Here we are!
- Detective, I'm Sam Sutherland.
- Tim Folly.
You know where we're going?
It's this way.
14th floor.
Okay...
Management for the building says the space
hasn' t been officially rented yet
The county recorder has
no listing for a Consumer...
...Recreation Service
or any derivation thereof.
Divers, they're still
looking for the cab...
...as soon as they find it,
they'll pull the plates in the V. I. N.
Have you spoken to your brother?
He hasn't called me back yet.
No.
What about the house?
The graffiti was an oil-based
marine marking solution...
...illegal in the states.
It's not impossible to trace,
but it'll take time.
The photo...
...the gun...
...the clown...
...the ambulance...
...it's all pending.
Breaking and entering
we've got solid.
Malicious mischief, vandalism,
harassment...
- ...but that's all.
- Illegal surveillance...
...reckless endangerment...
Attempted murder.
Except, you said you
hired these guys.
That's irrelevant.
Now, look.
It's our job to tell you
what we've got...
...so far, we don't have motive.
What was my father like, Ilsa?
Why do you ask?
I don't know.
All the time I've known you,
you've never once asked about him.
I guess he was just on my mind.
Your mother loved
your father very much.
I think he's just worked too hard.
Was he...
...morose?
I mean...
What I remember most...
...was that his manner was so...
...slight.
You could spend time in a room...
...and not even know that he'd
been there the whole time...
No, what I mean is...
Before he...
What happened, no?
Nobody expected it.
I wonder how much of him there
is in me?
Not much, I think.
Was mother worried about him?
Nobody ever worried
about your father.
- Yes.
- It's Maria.
- I found the address you wanted from United Taxi.
- Yeah, give it to me.
It's on the Patraro Hill...
Who are you?
Christine, is she here?
She's sleeping.
Amian, who is it?
Hey!
What're you doing here?
Can we talk?
Sure.
- Hi.
Didn't think I'd ever
see you again.
What can you tell me
about these?
Is this you?
Where did you get them?
My hotel room.
Was in my hotel...
Are you telling me that this is not you?
What makes you... um...
...think this is me?
Well... um...
...the bra, the red bra.
Okay.
What I thought that...
Can I sit down for a..?
Sure.
Are you all right?
You're not all right, are you?
Is it this contest thing
that you're in still or..?
I'm sorry, I am being a nuisance.
I should go.
No, it's ok, we can talk.
I'll put some clothes on me,
I'll be right back.
Do you have an aspirin?
Can I get you something
to drink with this?
Is this you?
Oh, yeah.
That's a first communion.
Show it to me.
- What's wrong?
- Take the picture out of the frame...
...and show it to me.
All right.
They're watching.
What?
Not here.
They can see here.
Smoke detector.
What do you say, we... uh...
Let's go for a drive or something
we could...
- No, no, I am tired of this! I am goddamn tired of this!
- We'll go for a drink, there's a...
Who do you people think you are?
Who do you think you are?
Come on, out of there!
- Nicholas, please!
- Let's go, right now!
Come on,
just come on out of there right now!
Now you've done it.
So what are they going to do?
Get away from the window.
What is this?
Wake up, it's a fucking con.
Get in, get in!
You all right?
Hold on!
- Get out of the car.
- I could've handed you to them.
- And they find me now they...
- Get out of the goddamn car!
You don't have a choice!
No one else's gonna tell you
what's going on!
You wanna know,
'cause if I'm gone you never will.
I can't believe they didn't take the time
to get the fucking house right.
- Who are they?
- I don't know. Nobody does. I'm an employee.
Then what good are you?
I know things like who
you can trust and...
- ...that your brother was in it from beginning.
- That's a lie!
Yeah? I was your waitress
on your birthday.
Connie told me about C. R. S. that day.
Ever seen me in there before?
Sorry...
I mean it wasn't his fault,
I guess he thought it was his only way up.
They fleeced him real good.
But how? How did they get to him?
Same thing to him they did to you.
What are you talking about?
They checked your accounts.
That night in your office...
...I got the number to your private line...
...and modem that gave C.R.S.
remote access to your computer.
You gave him everything else.
What?
You took their tests, handwriting,
voice samples, psychyinfos...
They used it all to
figure out your passwords.
And Feingold the...
...the guy who signed you up...
...he did 5 years for hacking City Bank.
They only had to keep
you distracted...
...while they broke into your
financial network...
...transferred your holdings
into dummy accounts.
Overseas operator please
Why else would they be
willing to shoot at us?
Alamine Bank, Zurich, Switzerland.
Beause they're finished with you.
Live, dead, the same.
Long as you disappear.
Yes, blue-two-backslash 9690,
D as in David.
That's right.
The balance?
That's impossible.
They already got it, Nicholas.
They got everything.
You've reached the Sutherlands.
Please leave a message.
As you get this message, Sam,
I have checked them all, I don't know how...
...but they have drained
my accounts.
They're trying to kill me.
Now you call the cops.
I got one of them right here.
We'll make her to testify.
I know how this sounds...
...but you call me...
...on my cellular...
And you be careful.
Yeah.
Cut your card in half, so...
...my treat.
You take two sugars, right?
Never mind.
- My name's not Christine, it's, I mean, it's not my real name.
- Who fucking cares?
It is just money,
you should be glad you're alive.
I'd rather not talk
about it right now.
- All I mean is someone like you...
- How many times have you done this?
- I'm curious.
- What?
These scams.
Con games, how many?
Lots.
Well, whatever nickle dime bullshit
you pulled in the past...
...this is more than just me.
This is pension plans...
...payrolls...
...this is 600 million dollars.
Yes.
Nick, it's Sam.
I got your message.
I was disturbed to say the least.
So what are we gonna do?
I've been on the phone
for an hour already.
Nicholas, your funds are intact.
Nothing's been touched.
- What are you talking about? I checked on it myself.
- Who is it?
- I made the calls.
- Nothing's changed.
I'm telling you
not one cent is unaccounted for.
Who is it?
My attorney says that
nothing is missing.
He's in on it.
I don't know what the hell is happening,
but stay where you are.
- Until I get there.
- Sutherlands in on it
Nicholas, I have another call.
Give me your precise location.
Nicholas?
Got to get out of here.
How did they get to him?
Why did...
I wouldn't worry about it.
What do you mean?
It's out of your hands.
Cellurar calls can be intercepted.
Those calls you made...
to B of A...
...France, B of A, Switzerland.
You were talking to us.
You were talking to us
Filled in the blanks.
Access codes, passwords.
Stuff even your lawyer didn't have.
But...
...we have it now, so we're done.
Bye, Nicholas.
Things have happened.
- It's important that...
- Sh, sh, sh!
No money, no identification,
no passport.
What happened to you?
Where to begin?
- It's complicated.
- It always is.
I was on holiday alone and
I was robbed by two men.
Robbed?
And what hotel were
you staying at?
I don't remember.
Have you gone to the police?
I don't speak Spanish.
And I just need enough
to get out of here.
Oh, we'll help with the local
law enforcement if you wanted to bother.
As far as money is concerned.
Can I make a suggestion?
You say you were mugged?
And they didn't take that watch?
How much is the watch
like that worth?
A couple of hundred at least.
Man with a watch like that doesn't
necessarily have the passport problem.
Excuse me?
Can I be attentioned please?
Thank you.
Anybody here going to San Francisco,
I need a ride?
I've got 18 dollars and 70... 78cents.
For a ride to San Francisco.
Anybody?
- Keep the change.
- Thanks, pal.
Conrad Van Orton.
Could you ring his room please?
One moment please.
- Is there a problem?
- You're here for Conrad Van Orton.
- Yes.
- I'm the hotel manager.
Pleasure to meet you.
Where's my brother?
- Will you come with me, sir?
- Wait a minute, is there a trouble?
Sir, this is a private matter for you.
There were some complaints
by other guests... damage to his room...
We did the best we could
to accommodate his behavior.
- His behavior?
- Yes, sir.
There was an incident a few days ago.
A nervous breakdown, they said.
The police took him. They left
this address in case anyone came.
It's a hospital in Napa.
Terribly sorry for him.
Elizabeth...
I need to borrow your car.
Nickie...
What happened to you?
I mean...
- Look at you...
- Look at me what happened tonight?
I don't know.
I have these things I have to worry.
I need your car.
Of course you can have it,
if you need it.
Can't I get you something to eat?
You know you're the only person...
...that I can trust.
Everyone else...
If Sam Sutherland calls you...
...you don't tell him you talk to me.
You lie to him.
And whatever else happens
before he speaks...
Ok, coffee...
...English muffin...
...and your water.
This bottle...
- ...is open. Who opened this bottle?
- Yeah, I opened it.
I don't want an opened bottle.
I want an unopened bottle.
I don't want ice like this,
I want just a glass...
...please.
Nickie, talk to me.
You're scaring me.
I don't even know
what you're saying.
I'm sorry, Liz, I don't mean it.
I'm sorry.
You know I've been...
...thinking last couple of days.
I've had some... some spare time.
And I wanted to tell you...
...I understand why you left me.
And I know that I...
...resented it.
I want to apologize to you...
...for shutting you out...
...and not being there.
And I hope that you can forgive me
Yes, I...
You've been on the go
for days.
There's nothing to forgive.
Then...
...pain sets in...
...the onset of a migraine pain...
If this sounds all too familiar...
...relief...
...is here at last.
Oh, no...
...you bastards.
Battery...
For nearly a decade
doctors have been prescribing...
How did you find me here?
Taggarene strong that has...
...tags... two things...muscle pain, joint pain...
He's an actor.
So if you trust your doctor...
...trust Taggarene.
He's an actor on television.
Can't explain now.
Can I borrow your yellow pages?
Cafe, past Chinatown.
Get out of the car, fucker.
Open the door and
leave it running.
You're making a mistake here.
Now get the fuck
out of the car.
Get the fuck
I am extremely fragile...
...right now.
New Moon Cafe.
- He does commercials.
- Do you know how many customers we have?
Hundreds, thousands.
I know he ordered from you.
He went to the Montgomery Street 1019...
Is there anybody here
that can help me?
He's an actor. If I blow these people
you have here upon you...
Hey! Why are you taking my picture?
We were hoping
he would auditon today.
He'd really be perfect
for this part.
Oh, this will break his heart.
Well is there any place
we can contact him?
Well, his beepers here
on the table.
He took the kids to the zoo.
The zoo!
That's very very sweet.
- Which zoo?
- Oh, it's the one with the White Tiger.
Lyno Fisher, I love your work.
Ok, please...
Look, I... uh...
I got my kids.
Get rid of them.
Guys... uh... guys, come on,
snack time...
One more snacks.
Here, go, go, go.
It was just a job.
Nothing personal.
You know, I mean...
play my part...
- Improvise a little, I mean.
- I need to talk to who's in charge.
Nobody knows...
...and nobody gets
a big picture...
Hey, Tammy, Alex cut it out.
Damn it, why do they do that?
Offices are empty.
I need to find out where they are.
Ok.
They own the whole building.
They just move from
floor to floor.
And you work for them, right?
You can get me in.
- No, I can't.
- Oh, yes, you can.
You can tell them the police called.
You got to speak to someone.
Tell them I'm gonna
blow the whistle on them.
What whistle?
There's no fucking whistle.
This is very dangerous.
I don't think you understand.
Right now...
...I am...
...extremely...
...dangerous.
Michael, guys.
Come on, we're leaving.
Well, we're here.
Drive in.
What're you gonna do anyway?
You won't get your money back.
I don't care about money.
I'm pulling back the curtain.
I wanna meet the wizard.
He's eyeing us like Tiffany towers.
Pull in somewhere
where they won't see you.
Stand staff, Mr.
- You're not allowed to be here.
- They called me back.
I got a fitting.
He's with me.
- You don't need me.
- Shut up.
- Get in this.
- Oh, my God.
Cuff him to the rail.
What floor?
You're fucked, you're both,
they're gonna listen!
Where?
- I told you they hired me over the phone.
- Where did you pick up your checks?
- It was a different floor.
- Guess?
Like you know...
we're on this way sort of...
...I don't know.
All right, take it easy.
Say you're surprised.
Oh, fuck!
What are you doing here?
Back from the dead.
Nicholas, you're not
about to shoot anyone.
Turn around.
You're gonna come with me.
Everybody down!
Stop!
All right, what do you
think you're doing?
You tell me!
Who's behind this?
Who did this to me?
Why?
- What do you mean why? How deluded can you be?
- Who is responsible for this?
It wasn't you...
It wasn' t personal...
It could've been any asshole with
a couple of hundred million in the bank.
Get on my radio, all right?
You get your boss...
You tell them I'm gonna
shoot somebody.
Who am I gonna call, Nicholas?
They won't do it.
Oh, yes, they will!
You get somebody up here...
...because I'm gonna kill you.
They don't care about me, Nicholas.
They'll let me die...
You're not in a position
to threaten anyone.
Where'd you get that?
What?
- That gun, that's not an automatic.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
We all had an automatic.
Where did you get the gun?
This is my gun.
But we've searched the house.
Well, I guess you missed this,
didn't you?
This is fake.
It's a part of your game.
- Don't you start with me now.
- No, no, listen to me.
- Don' t you fucking start with me
- I'm telling you the truth now...
...this is all "the game".
Bullshit, all right? Bullshit!
I know what happened to that guy...
...they shot that guy, Feingold
whoever, they killed him.
- Think about it, what'd you see?
- I saw them kill him.
No, what'd you really, really see?
This whole time, special effects...
...squibs, squibs like in the movies.
Nicholas! Nicholas, listen!
Damn it, he's got a real gun
with the goddamned bullets...
...ok, ok, I'll put it down.
Feingold, Mr. Fisher,
he's on the other side of that door...
- He's an actor.
- You're trying to kill me.
No one's trying to kill you, Nicholas.
Please put that gun down.
You're about to make
the biggest mistakes of your life.
Nicholas, I mean there's always a safety net.
The taxi, there was a driver at my house...
...it's that they shot at us with blanks.
It's not true.
It is.
It's what you hired us for.
They're waiting
on the other side of that door...
...with champaign, Nicholas!
Please, goddamn it!
Conrad!
Conrad's there!
It's your birthday party.
You stop lying!
Let me show you.
Don't you move.
He's got a gun,
get back from the door!
You shot him!
Someone...
Someone call an ambulance!
He's dead.
We thought you knew.
How did you let this get
so out of hand?
He wouldn't listen to me at all.
Almost through this
it's over.
Aren't your responsibility.
Never...
Never let them mark
and take over
I'm sorry.
He could've killed us.
I had a walkie-talkie.
I used walkie-talkie.
We're going to jail.
We're all going to jail
for the rest of our lives.
Oh, God!
Nicholas!
We've got him.
We have him there,
he came on right on target.
Standby for further
medical treatments.
Keep everyone back until we
clear away the breakaway glass.
Mr. Van Orton,
don't open your eyes.
Breakaway glass,
but it can still cut you.
Just gonna take a look at you.
I'm gonna take your pulse.
Just take it easy,
it was a quite a fall.
Happy birthday, Nickie.
What is this?
It's your birthday present.
I hurt you with something really.
I'm such an asshole
Ladies and gentlemen,
my brother, Nicholas Van Orton.
Amazing, I just wanted to tell you.
This was the best ever.
Thank God, you jumped,
because if you didn't...
...I was supposed to
throw you off.
Thanks.
I have to head home.
I just wanted to say goodbye.
Rachal...
...sweet dreams.
Thanks, Mal, for coming.
I'm sorry about your car.
I left it at the zoo.
No problem.
Happy birthday, Nicholas.
I'll call you. I really will.
Nicholas, I haven't a clue
what this is all about.
Your taste in champaign
is excellent as always.
It was great entrance.
Yes and I want you to know
that what happened on Sunday was...
Oh, no, no, no, please.
I've never been happier
my whole life.
I thank you...
...and my wife thanks you.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you, Sam.
What's this?
This...
...is...
...the bill...
The bill?
Keep the pen.
Thank you...
...both.
You wanna split?
Oh, God, yes please.
I'll take you up on that.
Oh, my God!
Thank you, Connie.
What happened to that... um...
...waitress?
What was her name... um...
Christine?
She said something about
catching a plane.
I just saw her out front
waiting for a cab.
Christine?
I... um...
...I didn't have chance
to say goodbye.
Thank you. I... I... I... um...
You know, I never did ask you
your name, did I?
No.
It's...
...Clair.
So you... um... catching a plane or?
Yeah, we have a gig
starting next week in Austrailia, so...
Gonna sheer some more sheep.
Just a walk on this time.
Well, when you get back...
...maybe dinner,
we gotta have some dinner.
You don't know
anything about me.
No, I don't.
So you tell me.
- Well, what...
- Where you're from?
Originally...
...O... Oklahoma.
Colorado?
I've been doing this
way too long.
You know... uh...
Would you like to...
...have a
coffee with me at the airport?
# One pill makes you larger
and one pill makes you small...
# And the ones that
mother gives you...
# ...don't do anything at all...
# Go ask Alice...
# ...when she's 10 feet tall...
# And if you go chasing rabbits...
# ...and you know you're going to fall...
# Tell 'em a hookah-smoking caterpillar...
# ...has given you the call...
# Call Alice...
# ...when she was just small...
# When the men on the chess board...
# ...get up and tell you where to go...
# And you've just had
some kind of mushroom...
# ...and your mind is moving slow...
# Go ask Alice...
# ...I think she'll know...
# When logic and proportion
have fallen sloppy dead...
# ...and the white knight is
talking backwards...
# ...and the red queen's "Off with her head!"...
# Remember...
# ...what the dormouse said:..
# ..."Feed your head..!"
# "...Feed your head!"