HIS NAME IS JAN.
Man: I DO NOT
KNOW HIM.
HE'S FROM THE RIG.
YOU KNOW WE DO NOT FAVOR
MATRIMONY WITH OUTSIDERS.
CAN YOU EVEN TELL US
WHAT MATRIMONY IS?
IT'S WHEN 2 PEOPLE
ARE JOINED IN GOD.
Man: DO YOU
REALLY BELIEVE
YOU'RE CAPABLE
OF BEARING
THE RESPONSIBILITY
NOT ONLY FOR YOUR
OWN MARRIAGE IN GOD,
BUT ALSO ANOTHER'S?
I KNOW I AM.
CAN YOU THINK
OF ANYTHING
OF REAL VALUE
THAT THE OUTSIDERS
HAVE BROUGHT
WITH THEM?
THEIR MUSIC.
OUT YOU GO,
BESS McNEILL,
AND BE SEATED.
??
Mott the Hoople:
?? FORGOT MY 6-STRING RAZOR
?? HIT THE SKY ??
?? HALFWAY TO MEMPHIS ??
?? BEFORE I REALIZED ??
??
?? WELL, I RANG THE INFORMATION
?? MY AX WAS COLD ??
?? THEY SAID SHE RIDES
A TRAIN TO OREOLE ??
?? NOW, IT'S
A MIGHTY LONG WAY... ??
Woman: BESS.
BESS, COME ON.
DON'T BE SILLY.
HE'S LATE.
ALL RIGHT,
BUT AT LEAST
HE'S COMING.
GET THIS ON,
THEN.
YOU'RE GOING TO
RUIN YOUR DRESS.
HE'S LATE.
YOU'RE BEING SILLY.
COME ON.
COME ON.T IT?
BESS,
GET YOUR CLOTHES ON.
COME ON.
DON'T RUIN IT.
IT'S A GOOD DAY.
COME ON.
BESS, YOU'RE NOT
SUPPOSED TO SEE HIM.
YOU KNOW THAT.
YOU'RE GOING
TO RUIN YOUR...
YOU'RE LATE!
Man: HEY!
[WHISTLES]
BREAK OUT THE BOTTLES!
COME ON.
IT'S MY WEDDING.
WILL YOU PLEASE
BE UPSTANDING
FOR THE BRIDE?
Everyone:
?? THE LORD'S MY SHEPHERD ??
?? I'LL NOT WANT ??
?
?? HE MAKES ME COME TO GOD ?
?? IN PASTURES GREEN ??
?? HE LEADETH ME ??
?? AS QUIET WATERS LIE ??
AS WE STAND
IN THY PRESENCE TODAY,
IN THY HOUSE,
WE WORSHIP THEE
AS THE AUTHOR
OF EVERY GOOD
AND PERFECT GIFT.
CHRIST LOVED THE CHURCH
AND GAVE HIMSELF
FOR HER.
TO HIM.E OURSELVESIST
IF IT IS NOT
TOO INAPPROPRIATE,
MAY I SAY
THAT YOU, BESS,
HAVE SHOWN THAT LOVE
AND THAT COMMITMENT
IN YOUR OWN LIFE.
IT IS NOT ONCE
OR TWICE
THAT YOU HAVE BEEN
IN THIS BUILDING,
GIVING YOUR TIME
AND EFFORT TO
CLEANING IT.
I KNOW THAT
YOU HAVE DONE THAT
NOT SO AS TO BE
WELL-THOUGHT-OF
HERE ON EARTH
BUT OUT OF YOUR LOVE
FOR GOD IN HEAVEN.
GREAT SERMON, FATHER.
[PATS JAN]
RING THE BELLS, THEN.
OUR CHURCH
HAS NO BELLS.
THAT'S NOT TOO FUN,
IS IT?
WHOO!
OH!
YAY!
WHOO-HOO!
HA HA!
THIS IS DODO.
OH, THE SISTER-IN-LAW.
WE HAVEN'T REALLY
MET, HAVE WE?
NO. WELL, EVERYTHING
HAPPENED SO QUICKLY.
WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
I JUST MEAN...
WELL, IT DID, DIDN'T IT?
ARE YOU NOT
HAPPY FOR ME?
OF COURSE I AM.
[BAND PLAYING]
[PEOPLE CLAPPING IN RHYTHM]
COME ON, TERRY.
WHOO! WHOO-HOO!
WHOO-HOO-HOO!
YEE-HA!
HEY!
Man: YEE-HA!
GET ALONG, LITTLE DOGIES!
BESS.
[BURP]
BLOWIN' IN THE WIND]
[BAND PLAYING
[CLEARS THROAT]
"DEAR BESS,
"I'VE KNOWN YOU
FOR 6 YEARS,
"AND I CAN
DEFINITELY SAY
"YOU HAVE
THE BIGGEST HEART
OF ANYONE
I'VE EVER MET."
"IT WASN'T
EASY FOR ME HERE
WHEN I MARRIED SAM,
"BUT YOU WELCOMED ME
INSTANTLY,
AND I WON'T
EVER FORGET THAT."
"YOUR GENEROSITY
KNOWS NO BOUNDS,
"LIKE THE TIME
WHEN YOU LENT
JACK A BIKE
"BECAUSE
HIS WAS BROKEN,
ONLY IT WAS MINE,
AND I HAD TO
WALK TO WORK."
[LAUGHING]
"I WAS FURIOUS
WITH YOU THEN,
"BUT I
REGRET THAT NOW,
BECAUSE
IT'S YOUR SPIRIT."
"YOU'D GIVE ANYTHING
TO ANYONE."
"WHEN SAM DIED,
I LOST A HUSBAND,
AND YOU A BROTHER."
"WE SAW EACH OTHER
THROUGH THAT
AND PROMISED
TO LOOK AFTER
ONE ANOTHER."
"YOU ARE
THE REASON--" SORRY.
I HAVE STAYEDREASON
"WHEN I ALMOST
GAVE UP IN THIS
COLD PLACE,
AND NOW YOUR WARMTH
HAS EMBRACED
ANOTHER OUTSIDER."
"HIS NAME IS JAN,
"AND I DON'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT HIM,
"BUT I'LL ACCEPT
HIS RIGHT TO BE HERE
BECAUSE OF YOU,
BESS."
"IF HE DOESN'T
TAKE CARE OF YOU
"AND GIVE YOU
EVERYTHING YOU NEED,
I'LL KILL HIM."
"THANK YOU FOR ALL
YOU'VE GIVEN ME,
BESS.
I LOVE YOU
VERY MUCH."
[APPLAUSE]
HAVE ME NOW?
HERE?
MAYBE YOU WANTED
SOMETHING MORE ROMANTIC.
THIS IS LOVELY.
YOU SURE?
NO. HAVE ME.
WHAT DO I DO?
[UNZIPS ZIPPER]
OK?
YOU GOT BLOOD
ON YOUR DRESS.
[ZIPS ZIPPER]
SHALL I GO DOWN
AND WAIT FOR YOU?
YOU OK?
HI.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
[PEOPLE CLAPPING IN RHYTHM]
YEE-HOO!
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
GO GET HER NOW,
JAN!
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERING]
Man: GO GET HER, JAN!
Rod Stewart:
?? EVERY DAY I SPEND MY TIME ??
?? DRINKING WINE,
FEELING FINE ??
?? WAITING HERE
TO FIND THE SIGN ??
?? THAT I CAN UNDERSTAND ??
?? YES, I AM ??
?? IN THE DAYS
BETWEEN THE HOURS ??
?? IVORY TOWERS ??
?? BLOODY FLOWERS ??
?? PUSH THEIR HEADS
INTO THE AIR ??
?? I DON'T CARE
IF I EVER KNOW ??
?? THERE I GO ??
??
?? DON'T PUSH YOUR LOVE TOO FAR
CAN'T GET
THIS FUCKER OPEN.
SHIT.
?? DA DA DA ??
?? DA DA DA DA ??
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
?? DA DA DA ??
HMM.
[JAN LAUGHS]
HOW COULD YOU TAKE IT?
HOW COULD YOU
KEEP AWAY FROM THE BOYS?
I WAITED FOR YOU.
[LAUGHING]
NO. DON'T LAUGH.
YEAH.
BUT YOU MUST
HAVE BEEN LONELY.
WHO DID YOU TALK TO?
[MEEK VOICE]
I THANK YOU FOR
THE GREATEST GIFT OF ALL:
THE GIFT OF LOVE.
I THANK YOU FOR JAN.
I'M SO LUCKY TO HAVE BEEN
GIVEN THESE GIFTS.
[FIRM VOICE]
BUT REMEMBER TO BE
A GOOD GIRL, BESS,
FOR YOU KNOW I GIVETH
AND I TAKETH AWAY.
[MEEK VOICE]
WHAT? I DIDN'T MEAN IT
LIKE THAT.
YES. I'LL BE GOOD.
I'LL BE REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
[JAN SNORING]
FLY.
AAAAAWAY!
OH!
[MOANING]
Minister: HELLO, JAN.
HELLO.
BESS.
Bess: HELLO.
WHY DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY CHURCH BELLS?
WE DO NOT NEED BELLS
IN OUR CHURCH
TO WORSHIP GOD.
I LIKE CHURCH BELLS.
LET'S PUT THEM
BACK AGAIN.
HAVE FUN.
BUT NOW, FRIENDS,
THINGS HAVE BECOME
VERY DIFFERENT.
IT HURTS ME
TO HAVE TO SAY IT,
BUT THERE APPEARS
TO BE THOSE
IN THE CHURCH
WHO ARE PREPARED TO
CLING TO THE WORLD
INSTEAD
OF FLEEING FROM IT.
BUT THOSE
TO WHOM I REFER
WILL KNOW WHAT I
AM SPEAKING ABOUT.
IT GRIEVES MY HEART,
AND I KNOW
THERE ARE OTHERS
WHO FEEL
JUST THE SAME.
AMEN.
MR. DONALD JOHN BEATON,
WILL YOU RISE AND ADDRESS
THE QUESTION?
THANK YOU, LORD,
FOR THIS DAY YOU HAVE
BLESSED US WITH.
IT'S STUPID THAT
ONLY MEN CAN TALK
IN THE SERVICE.
HOLD YOUR TONGUE,
WOMAN.
[MOVIE PLAYING]
[DOG BARKS IN MOVIE]
Boy in movie:
LASSIE! IT'S LASSIE!
LASSIE
IT
I KNOW IT!
LASSIE! OH, LASSIE!
LASSIE. OH, LASSIE.
OH, WELCOME HOME.
THEY'RE BURYING
ANTHONY NOW.
GO AND LISTEN
TO THE MINISTER.
WHAT?
YEAH. YOU CAN DO THAT
IF YOU WANT.
MEN ARE ALLOWED
AT FUNERALS.
GO ON.
Minister:
ANTHONY DOD MANTLE,
WHO HAS BEEN ONE...
YOU ARE A SINNER,
YOUR PLACE IN HELL.
THE MINISTER SAID
HE WOULD GO TO HELL.
DID HE SAY THAT?
BLOODY CHEERFUL.
WILL
ANTHONY
GO TO HELL.
EVERYONE KNOWS THAT.
YOU DO REALIZE
THAT I WILL HAVE
TO GO BACK SOON,
DON'T YOU?
YOU KNEW IT
ALL THE TIME.
[LAUGHING]
"LORD, WE ARE
UNWORTHY OF THE LEAST
OF ALL THY MERCIES.
"WE THANK THEE
FOR THIS FOOD.
PARDON OUR SINS
FOR JESUS' SAKE. AMEN."
[TOGETHER]
AMEN.
WHEN ARE YOU GOING BACK?
OH, DIDN'T YOU KNOW?
JAN'S GOING TO STAY
AT HOME WITH ME--
QUIT THE RIG BECAUSE
WE'RE SO HAPPY.
BESS, COME ON.
I WISH I COULD.
[CRYING]
I WILL NOT HAVE THAT
KIND OF BEHAVIOR
IN MY HOUSE!
I'M SORRY, MOTHER.
I'M SORRY.
IF YOU CANNOT
CONTROL YOUR MOODS,
IT'S THE HOSPITAL
AGAIN FOR YOU,
MY GIRL.
I'M SORRY.
WHY SHOULD YOU
BE ANY DIFFERENT?
EVERY WOMAN AROUND HERE
HAS TO LEARN TO BE ALONE
WHEN THEIR MAN'S AWAY AT SEA
OR ON THE OIL RIGS.
EVEN YOU CAN LEARN
HOW TO ENDURE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT YOU,
AND QUITE FRANKLY...
I'M SORRY--
I'M SORRY
TO SAY THIS,
BUT I DON'T
TRUST YOU.
SHE'S...SHE'S VERY
SUSCEPTIBLE.
AND YOU COULD
GET HER T...
YOU COULD GET HER
TO DO ANYTHING
YOU WANTED.
NO. I DON'T THINK SO.
HOW AM I
SUPPOSED TO LOOK OUT
FOR HER NOW?
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO DO?
KEEP HER HERE, LOCKED UP
FOR THE REST OF HER LIFE?
SHE HASN'T
GOT THE STRENGTH.
SHE'S STRONGER
THAN YOU AND ME.
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND, DO YOU?
SHE'S NOT RIGHT
IN THE HEAD.
COME ON.
SHE JUST WANTS IT ALL.
WHAT'S THIS?
WHAT?
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S A PRESENT.
CAN I OPEN IT?
YEAH, SURE. OPEN IT.
NICE COLORS,
AREN'T THEY?
VERY CHEERFUL.
[GROWLING]
Terry: IT'S OPEN.
WE'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR YOU, BUD.
HEY.
Terry: YEAH. THAT'S FINE.
YOU WANT A LITTLE SNORT?
Jan: LOOK AT YOU.
HA HA HA!
Jan: BESS!
[BANGING]
NO!
AAH!
Jan: COME, COME, COME.
ALL RIGHT?
IT'S OK.
[MEN TALKING]
Man: WHOO!
WATCH YOUR HEAD!
WUM! HA HA HA!
Man: WATCH YOUR HEAD.
OK?
IT'S JUST
FOR A LITTLE.
I'LL CALL YOU.
Bess: JAN!
NO!
BESS!
[CRYING]
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT, DEAR.
OK? YOU'RE OK.
Dodo: IT'S ALL RIGHT,
DARLING.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
[MOANING]
IT'S OK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, DEAR.
LET'S GIVE YOU
ONE OF THESE.
ONE OF THESE DOWN YOU.
HERE WE GO.
TAKE ONE OF THESE.
THAT'S IT.
POP IT IN YOUR MOUTH.
SWALLOW.
Jethro Tull:
?? WHO WOULD BE A POOR MAN,
A BEGGAR MAN, A THIEF ??
?? IF HE HAD A RICH MAN
IN HIS HAND? ??
?? AND WHO WOULD STEAL THE CANDY
FROM A LAUGHING BABY'S MOUTH ??
?? IF HE COULD TAKE IT
FROM THE MONEY MAN? ??
?? CROSS-EYED MARY
A-GOES JUMPING IN AGAIN ??
?? SHE SIGNS NO CONTRACT ??
?? BUT SHE ALWAYS
PLAYS THE GAME ??
?? SHE DINES
IN HAMPSTEAD VILLAGE... ??
[FIRM VOICE]
YOU ARE GUILTY
OF SELFISHNESS, BESS.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN CONSIDER
FOR ONE SECOND
HOW PAINFUL
IT MUST HAVE BEEN FOR HIM.
YOU PUT YOUR OWN FEELINGS
BEFORE EVERYONE ELSE'S.
I CAN'T SEE THAT YOU LOVE HIM
WHEN YOU BEHAVE LIKE THAT.
NOW YOU MUST PROMISE
TO BE A GOOD GIRL, BESS.
[MEEK VOICE]
I PROMISE TO BE A GOOD GIRL.
[TURNS VACUUM OFF]
I'M SORRY FOR
THE WAY I BEHAVED,
MOTHER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, BESSIE.
MOTHER,
WOULD IT BE OK
IF I CAME HOME
FOR A BIT WHILE
JAN'S AWAY?
OF COURSE IT WOULD,
BESSIE.
OK.
Man: YOU GOT IT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS SHIT.
MMM.
[RADIO PLAYING]
OH, SHIT.
NICE.
HUH?
YOU KNOW, THE WAVES
ARE GETTING
PRETTY HEAVY.
JESUS CHRIST.
WHAT THE FUCK'S
WRONG WITH YOU?
JUST PISSED.
JUST GIVE ME ONE.
JUST WAIT.
NOW, BUT YOU KNOW,
THERE'S SOME NICE...
SHIT. SORRY, GUYS.
JUST THROW
THE GODDAMN RADIO AWAY.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING
IN HERE ANYHOW.
YOU AND YOUR
FUCKING RADIO.
OH, GOD! FUCK. JEEZ!
COME ON. DANCE! DANCE!
YEE-HA! YEE-HA!
YEE-HA!
FIRE! FIRE!
WET TOWEL!
JUST...SHIT!
WHOO! WHOO!
WHOO! WHOO! WHOO!
HEY!
i??BUENO! i??BUENO! i??BUENO!
DIDN'T HE SAY
HE'D CALL?
DO YOU WANT ME
TO WAIT WITH YOU?
YES, PLEASE.
WHERE THE FUCK
IS THE SECOND SHIFT?
I GOT A PHONE CALL
TO MAKE.
Dodo: I GOT TO GO
TO THE HOSPITAL.
ARE YOU COLD?
NO.
NO?
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
DON'T WAIT TOO LONG,
WILL YOU?
OH, SHIT.
PIM, GOT TO MAKE
A PHONE CALL.
GET OUT OF HERE.
[RING RING]
HELLO?
Jan: OH, IS BESS THERE?
ONE MOMENT.
BESS. BESS.
IS THAT YOU, BESS?
Bess: HI.
OH, I'M SORRY I COULDN'T
GET TO THE PHONE EARLIER.
THAT'S OK.
DON'T YOU
LOVE ME ANYMORE?
OH...
OF COURSE I DO.
SAY SO, THEN.
I'D MADE UP
MY MIND NOT TO.
EVERYONE SAYS
THAT I LOVE YOU
TOO MUCH
AND IF YOU
FOUND OUT
HOW MUCH
I LOVED YOU,
YOU MIGHT
GET UPSET
BECAUSE WE'RE
NOT TOGETHER
RIGHT NOW.
OH, BESS, NEVER STOP
SAYING YOU LOVE ME.
YOU HEAR?
Bess: YES.
NO MATTER
WHAT ANYBODY SAYS.
YES.
SAY IT, THEN.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
[BESS SNIFFLES]
I CAN HEAR YOU
BREATHING.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[TURNS ON RADIO]
PLAYING]A PLAIN
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING?
Bess:
THAT YOU'RE HERE.
AND WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
UM...I'M TOUCHING
YOUR ARMS
AND YOUR CHEST
AND YOUR TUMMY
AND...
[LAUGHS]
YOUR PRICK.
YOU'RE SO HUGE.
HA HA HA!
JAN WILL BE HOME IN
10 DAYS FOR A WEEK.
PARDON?
JAN WILL BE HOME IN
10 DAYS FOR A WEEK.
PITS.
HI.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WHERE'S JAN?
I'M THE ONLY ONE BACK.
HURT MY WRIST.
THEY SENT ME HOME.
OH.
HE SENDS HIS LOVE.
Dodo: HOW LONG HAVE
YOU GOT OFF NOW?
Pits: ONLY 3 DAYS.
OH.
YEAH. YOU KNOW ME.
I'M BACK.
OH, SORRY.
Dodo: HOW LONG
HAS SHE BEEN ASLEEP?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
CAT GOT YOUR TONGUE?
Bess: HAVE YOU TAKEN
MY CALENDAR?
HUH?
HAVE YOU TAKEN
MY CALENDAR?
NO, I HAVE NOT.
WHAT WOULD I WANT
WITH YOUR CALENDAR?
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
YOU'VE TAKEN IT.
I HAVE NOT TAKEN IT.
YES, YOU HAVE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WHAT CALENDAR?
WHERE IS IT?
BESS, YOU'VE GOT TO
STOP ALL THIS, YOU KNOW.
YOU'VE GOT
TO GO ON LIVING
WHEN HE ISN'T HERE.
I MEAN, HE'S NOT DEAD.
YOU'RE NOT DEAD.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN?
YOU'VE GOT TO STOP IT.
[SCREAMING]
Dodo: SHH. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S NOTHING.
Mother:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WAS THAT BESS?
NO. IT'S OK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
BIT OF HYSTERICS.
NO, NO.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SORT IT OUT.
WE'RE NOT TO HAVE
THIS CARRY ON
IN THE HOUSE.
I KNOW.
JUST STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
[SCREAMING]
[FIRM VOICE]
BESS McNEILL, FOR MANY YEARS,
YOU'VE PRAYED FOR LOVE.
SHALL I TAKE IT AWAY
FROM YOU AGAIN?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
[MEEK VOICE]
OH, NO.
I'M STILL GRATEFUL FOR LOVE.
[FIRM VOICE]
WHAT DO YOU WANT, THEN?
[MEEK VOICE]
I PRAY FOR JAN TO COME HOME.
[FIRM VOICE]
HE WILL BE COMING HOME
IN 10 DAYS.
YOU MUST LEARN TO ENDURE.
YOU KNOW THAT.
[MEEK VOICE]
OH, I CAN'T WAIT.
[FIRM VOICE]
THIS IS UNLIKE YOU, BESS.
OUT THERE, THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO NEED JAN AND HIS WORK.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
[MEEK VOICE]
THEY DON'T MATTER.
NOTHING ELSE MATTERS.
I JUST WANT JAN HOME AGAIN.
I PRAY TO YOU.
OH, PLEASE,
WON'T YOU SEND HIM HOME?
[FIRM VOICE]
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT?
[MEEK VOICE]
YES.
OK. GET HER UP.
BLOW OUT!
[ALARM BEEPING]
GET AWAY!
BLOW OUT!
TERRY!
TERRY! TERRY!
TALK TO ME, WILL YOU?
[MAN YELLING]
WATCH OUT!
JAN!
GO GET--GET A MEDIC!
Minister: I DON'T KNOW
WHAT KIND OF CONDITION
HE'S IN.
I THINK IT'S
VERY SERIOUS, THOUGH.
I DON'T QUITE KNOW.
IT'S JAN. THERE'S BEEN
AN ACCIDENT ON THE RIG.
[HELICOPTER ENGINE
RUMBLING]
JAN, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
OH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M HOLDING
YOUR HAND.
DON'T TOUCH ME.
DON'T TOUCH ME!
Man: JAN, RELAX.
JUST TAKE...
SIT DOWN HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
SHH.
DEEP BREATH.
HELLO. TALK
TO ME, DARLING.
TALK TO ME.
COME ON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT.
UH, THEY'RE GOING
TO OPERATE STRAIGHTAWAY.
IT WILL BE
A FEW HOURS,
SO I THINK
WE BETTER WAIT...
Dodo: BESS.
BESS, YOU CAN'T
GO IN THERE.
IT'S
NOT ALLOWED.
I WANT TO BE WITH HIM.
I KNOW YOU DO.
I KNOW.
BUT COME ON.
COME WITH ME.
COME ON.
NO. I WANT TO SEE HIM
ALL THE TIME.
BESS, IT'S NOT
A GOOD IDEA.
COME ON.
BESS. BESS, PLEASE,
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
IT'S JUST NOT POSSIBLE.
BESS!
CAN I HAVE
A WORD WITH YOU?
STAY THERE,
ALL RIGHT?
DON'T MOVE.
I WANT YOU
TO PRAY WITH ME.
Dodo: BUT...
PLEASE.
DEAR GOD,
WE PRAY THAT YOU
WILL HOLD YOUR HAND
OVER JAN
AND NOT LET HIM DIE.
[TOGETHER]
AMEN.
MRS. NYMAN,
WILL YOU PLEASE
COME WITH ME?
WILL HE LIVE?
WE HAVE STABILIZED
YOUR HUSBAND'S CONDITION
FOR THE TIME BEING.
WILL HE LIVE?
YES. YES, BESS,
HE WILL LIVE.
YOUR HUSBAND SUFFERED
VERY SERIOUS INJURIES.
LIFE SHOULDN'T ALWAYS
BE PRESERVED AT ANY COST.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
UM, WELL, THE DOCTOR
MEANS, BESS,
THAT, UM, SOMETIMES...
IN SOME CASES
WHEN LIFE ISN'T
WORTH LIVING,
THEN IT MAY
BE BETTER TO DIE.
YOU DON'T KNOW JAN,
OR YOU COULD NOT
SAY SUCH A THING.
YOUR HUSBAND
MAY NEVER WALK AGAIN.
WE THINK HE'LL BE
COMPLETELY PARALYZED.
BUT HE'LL LIVE?
YES. HE WILL LIVE,
IT SEEMS.
[MEEK VOICE]
FATHER.
ARE YOU THERE?
ARE YOU STILL THERE?
[FIRM VOICE]
OF COURSE I AM, BESS.
YOU KNOW THAT.
[MEEK VOICE]
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
[FIRM VOICE]
YOU WANTED JAN HOME.
[MEEK VOICE]
I'VE CHANGED MY MIND.
WHY DID I ASK
FOR THAT?
[FIRM VOICE]
BECAUSE YOU'RE
A STUPID
LITTLE GIRL, BESS.
I HAD TO TEST YOU.
YOUR LOVE FOR JAN
HAS BEEN PUT TO THE TEST.
[MEEK VOICE]
THANK YOU
FOR NOT LETTING HIM DIE.
[FIRM VOICE]
YOU'RE WELCOME, BESS.
?? HE SAID
"THERE IS NO REASON ??
?? AND THE TRUTH
IS PLAIN TO SEE" ??
?? BUT I WANDERED
THROUGH MY PLAYING CARDS ??
?? AND WOULD NOT
LET HER BE ??
?? ONE OF 16
VESTAL VIRGINS ??
?? WHO WERE LEAVING
FOR THE COAST ??
?? AND ALTHOUGH
MY EYES WERE OPEN ??
?? THEY MIGHT JUST AS WELL
HAVE BEEN CLOSED ??
?? AND SO IT WAS... ??
Minister: I WOULD SAY TO YOU...
THAT IF THERE IS
ONE OF THESE COMMANDMENTS
WHICH YOU DO NOT LOVE
AND DO NOT OBEY,
YOU HAVE NO PLACE
AT THE LORD'S TABLE.
[SINGING HYMN]
WHEN DID YOU
GET BACK?
I CAME BACK
WITH JAN.
OH, IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
OH, SURF'S UP!
Pits: HI.
Jan: HI, GUYS.
Terry: HOW YOU DOING,
BUDDY?
WELL, FINE.
HOW ARE YOU?
OK.
DID YOU FIND ANYTHING?
Terry: GAS.
NOTHING REALLY.
HA HA!
GUESS WHAT, NOW.
WE'RE HEADING UP NORTH.
WELL, NORTH,
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S WHERE YOU
ALWAYS SAID THE OIL WAS.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE, ANYWAY?
WE'RE MEANT TO BE
OUT DRILLING.
[OPENS CAN]
Jan:
I JUST FELT LIKE
PUTTING MY FEET UP
FOR A WHILE.
I DIDN'T TRUST
YOU 2 GUYS
OUT THERE ALONE.
[LAUGHTER]
[CANS OPENING]
OH, MY...
MY ARMS AREN'T OK, SO...
I'M NOT THIRSTY, ANYWAY.
BULLSHIT!
HEY, COME ON.
COME ON.
OH, MAN, SORRY.
[COUGHING]
OK.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT REALLY
SUPPOSED TO HAVE
ANY VISITORS, SO...
Terry: WE REALLY DON'T HAVE
THE TIME, EITHER.
HA HA HA! OK.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF, HUH?
Pits: TAKE CARE.
GET WELL SOON.
SEE YOU, GUYS.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
WILL YOU DO
SOMETHING FOR ME?
YES.
THE NEXT TIME YOU COME,
COULD YOU WEAR
SOMETHING MORE...
MORE LOOSE...
SO I, UH...
SO I WON'T HAVE TO SEE
YOUR BODY.
[SOBBING]
[DOOR OPENS]
BESS, YOU'LL
HAVE TO GO NOW
BECAUSE JAN NEEDS
TO REST.
ALL RIGHT.
[DOOR CLOSES]
YOU SHOULDN'T GET HIM
TOO OVEREMOTIONAL,
YOU KNOW.
IT'S NOT GOOD FOR HIM.
I'M SORRY.
YOU GOT TO
CHEER HIM UP.
IS HE ASLEEP NOW?
WELL, HE SHOULD BE...
THE AMOUNT
I'VE GIVEN HIM.
WOULD IT BE
ALL RIGHT
IF I WENT AND HAD
A LOOK AT HIM?
I LOVE YOU, JAN.
[IMITATING JAN]
I LOVE YOU,
TOO, BESS.
YOU ARE THE LOVE
OF MY LIFE.
BESS.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I'VE BEEN
TO THE CHURCH.
WHAT, AT 2:00
IN THE MORNING?
I DON'T WANT YOU
GETTING ILL AGAIN...
LIKE YOU DID
WHEN SAM DIED.
I SAID I'VE BEEN
TO THE CHURCH.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE CHURCH.
DID YOU HEAR
WHAT I SAID? DID YOU?
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET ILL AGAIN
LIKE YOU DID
WHEN SAM DIED.
I'VE HAD A WORD
WITH DR. RICHARDSON,
ALL RIGHT?
AND HE SAYS
HE COULD SEE YOU TOMORROW.
OH, CAN HE?
[DOOR OPENS]
BESS, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO COME IN?
[DRAWER OPENS]
DODO SAID
I HAD TO COME.
SHE HAS THIS IDEA
ABOUT ME TREATING YOU.
MY PREDECESSOR ADMITTED YOU
A FEW YEARS AGO.
WELL, WHY DID HE
DO THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
NO, NOR DO I.
YOU WERE UPSET BECAUSE
YOUR BROTHER HAD DIED,
AND NOW YOU'RE UPSET
BECAUSE YOUR HUSBAND'S ILL.
NOTHING UNUSUAL
ABOUT THAT.
AM I NOT GOING TO
HAVE SOME PILLS?
I'M PROBABLY NOT LIKE
YOUR OLD DOCTOR.
I DON'T THINK THAT PEOPLE
SHOULD BE GIVEN PILLS
JUST BECAUSE THEY DO
WHAT'S ONLY NATURAL.
MAYBE SHOWING WHAT YOU FEEL
ISN'T THE DONE THING
FROM WHERE
YOU COME FROM,
BUT IT'S CERTAINLY
NO DISEASE.
WHAT...HAPPENED
ON THE RIG
WAS MY FAULT.
HOW COME?
I PRAYED TO GOD
TO SEND HIM HOME.
WELL...
WHAT POWERS
YOU POSSESS.
DO YOU REALLY...
DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE
THAT YOU POSSESS
SUCH POWERS?
I KNOW YOU PEOPLE BELIEVE
A LOT ABOUT YOURSELVES.
BESS...
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD DO
A BIT OF GRIEVING
FOR YOURSELF
INSTEAD OF HIM.
I THINK YOU SHOULD
COME AND SEE ME
NOW AND AGAIN
IF YOU FEEL LIKE IT.
I'M SORRY.
OH. HA HA!
COME ON.
WELL, THINGS WILL PICK UP
ONCE HE GETS HOME AGAIN.
??
T. Rex:
?? WELL, SHE'S MY WOMAN OF GOLD
?? YES, SHE'S NOT VERY OLD,
UH-HUH, HUH ??
?? WELL, SHE'S MY WOMAN
OF GOLD ??
?? YES, SHE'S NOT VERY OLD,
UH-HUH, HUH ??
?? I DON'T MEAN
TO BE BOLD, UH ??
?? BUT, UH, MAY I HOLD
YOUR HAND? ??
?? WELL, SHE AIN'T
NO WITCH ??
?? AND I LOVE THE WAY SHE TWITCH
, UH-HUH, HUH ??
?? WELL, SHE AIN'T
NO WITCH ??
?? AND I LOVE THE WAY SHE TWITCH
, UH-HUH, HUH... ??
Bess and Dodo:
?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU ??
?? SQUASHED TOMATOES
AND STEW ??
?? YOU LOOK LIKE
A MONKEY ??
?? AND I THOUGHT
IT WAS YOU ??
Dodo:
LOOK AT THAT.
SPECIAL.
SHALL I OPEN
YOUR PRESENT?
YES.
YOUR PRESENTS.
CAN YOU SEE
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT IS IT?
WAIT AND SEE.
HA HA HA!
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
WHERE DID YOU
GET THAT?
I GOT IT
IN A SHOP.
[LAUGHING]
THAT IS
THE STUPIDEST THING
I'VE EVER SEEN.
OH, LOOK, IT'S NOT
DOING ANYTHING NOW.
AHEM. ALL RIGHT, GO ON.
WELL, GO ON.
[LAUGHTER]
THAT IS JUST TERRIBLE.
THAT IS DAFT, THAT IS--
COMPLETELY DAFT.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, JAN.
THANK YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
Bess: DO YOU
LIKE IT?
[DOOR CLOSES]
OH, YES, IT'S...
HA HA!
IT'S--IT'S NICE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
YOUR PILL.
OK?
OH...
ONE MORE DRINK.
OK?
YEAH. THANK YOU.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
I'M FINISHED, BESS.
NO.
YOU COULD TAKE
A LOVER
WITHOUT ANYBODY
NOTICING...
BUT YOU CAN'T
DIVORCE ME.
THEY'D NEVER
LET YOU.
BESS.
NO. NO.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU THINK I WANT?
YOU CRIPPLE!
[DOOR CLOSES]
YOU MUST MAKE UP
WITH HIM.
A HUSBAND AND WIFE
HAVE TO BE ABLE
TO TALK TO EACH OTHER.
HE'S THE ONE
WHO IS HELPLESS,
AND YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO MUST SHOW
YOU'RE STRONG.
GO TO HIM AND TELL HIM
YOU ARE SORRY
YOU WERE ANGRY.
YOU HAVE GOD.
YOU HAVE THE STRENGTH
YOUR LIFE IN GOD
HAS BESTOWED UPON YOU,
AND THAT IS A STRENGTH
HE DOES NOT POSSESS.
OH, NO.
COME ON.
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
COME ON. THAT'S IT.
THAT'S IT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S SHE THINKING OF,
GOING OFF LEAVING
YOU LIKE THIS?
YOU MUST ADMIT
THAT SHE WAS...
SHE WAS HAPPY
WHEN WE GOT MARRIED.
SHE BLOSSOMED...
DIDN'T SHE?
I CAN'T JUST
LIE HERE.
I CAN'T EVEN
MAKE LOVE TO HER.
SHE'S GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
SHE'S GOT TO GET ON
WITH LIFE.
HELP ME
SET HER FREE.
SHE'D DO ANYTHING
FOR YOU, JAN.
YOU KNOW THAT.
SHE DON'T CARE
ANYTHING ABOUT HERSELF...
BUT SHE'D DO
ANYTHING FOR YOU...
JUST TO SEE A SMILE
ON YOUR FACE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YEAH.
RIGHT.
THANKS
FOR TELLING ME.
NO TROUBLE.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO READ TO YOU?
HMM?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[FOOTSTEPS]
THEY TOOK HIM BACK
TO THE HOSPITAL.
Dodo: BESS.
BESS,
WHAT IS GOING ON?
HE WENT UNCONSCIOUS.
WE HAD TO BRING HIM
BACK HERE.
AT HOME ANYMORE--
NOT IF YOU'RE
GOING TO GO
RUNNING OFF
AND LEAVING HIM
LIKE THAT.
I'M SORRY.
WELL, IT'S JUST NOT
GOOD ENOUGH!
I'M NOT--
I'M NOT EVEN ALLOWED
TO KISS HIM ANYMORE.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
LISTENING TO WHAT
HE SAYS, BESS?
IT'S UP TO YOU.
HE AIN'T GOT
ANYONE ELSE.
YOU COULD GIVE HIM
THE WILL TO LIVE.
THAT'S MORE THAN
ANY DOCTOR CAN DO.
BESS?
I'M SORRY.
NO, IT WAS MY FAULT.
COME HERE.
HI.
LOVE IS
A MIGHTY POWER...
ISN'T IT?
IF I DIE...
IT WILL BE
BECAUSE LOVE CANNOT
KEEP ME ALIVE.
BUT I CAN HARDLY
REMEMBER
WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO MAKE LOVE...
AND IF
I FORGET THAT,
THEN I'LL DIE.
REMEMBER WHEN
I PHONED YOU
FROM THE RIG?
WE MADE LOVE
WITHOUT BEING
TOGETHER.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO TALK TO YOU
LIKE THAT AGAIN?
I'D LOVE TO.
BESS.
I WANT YOU TO FIND
A MAN TO MAKE LOVE TO
AND THEN
COME BACK HERE
AND TELL ME ABOUT IT.
IT WILL FEEL LIKE
YOU AND ME BEING
TOGETHER AGAIN.
NOW, THAT...
THAT WILL KEEP ME ALIVE.
I...I CAN'T.
THIS MORNING
WHEN I...WHEN I TOLD YOU
TO GET A LOVER,
IT WASN'T
FOR YOUR SAKE.
IT WAS FOR MY SAKE...
BECAUSE I DON'T
WANT TO DIE.
I'M AFRAID.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YES.
IT WILL BE
YOU AND ME, BESS.
DO IT FOR ME.
I...
I CAN'T.
PLEASE.
BESS?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
SURE?
HERE YOU GO.
WHOA-OH. EASY.
Leonard Cohen:
?? SUZANNE TAKES YOU DOWN ??
?
?? TO HER PLACE NEAR THE RIVER ?
?? YOU CAN HEAR THE BOATS
GO BY ??
?? YOU CAN SPEND THE NIGHT
BESIDE HER ??
?? AND YOU KNOW
THAT SHE'S HALF-CRAZY ??
?? BUT THAT'S WHY
YOU WANT TO BE THERE ??
?? AND SHE FEEDS YOU
TEA AND ORANGES ??
?? THAT COME
ALL THE WAY FROM CHINA ??
?? AND JUST WHEN YOU MEAN
TO TELL HER ??
?? THAT YOU HAVE NO LOVE
TO GIVE HER ??
?? THEN SHE GETS YOU
ON HER WAVELENGTH ??
?? AND SHE LETS
THE RIVER ANSWER ??
?? THAT YOU'VE ALWAYS
BEEN HER LOVER ??
YOU CERTAINLY NEEDED
SOME SHUTEYE.
I PUT YOUR ROSE
IN A VASE.
PERKED UP A BIT.
YOU SHOULD THINK OF
YOURSELF A BIT, TOO--
GO OUT.
GO DANCING.
I'VE SEEN YOU DANCE.
YOU LIKE TO DANCE.
WHERE'S JAN?
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO IN HERE.
[MEEK VOICE]
DON'T LET HIM DIE.
[FIRM VOICE]
AND WHY SHOULDN'T
I LET HIM DIE?
[MEEK VOICE]
I LOVE HIM.
[FIRM VOICE]
SO YOU KEEP SAYING,
BUT I DON'T SEE IT.
[MEEK VOICE]
THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO.
THERE'S NOTHING AT ALL.
[FIRM VOICE]
PROVE TO ME THAT YOU LOVE HIM,
AND THEN I'LL LET HIM LIVE.
[RINGS DOORBELL]
[DOOR OPENS]
I'VE COME TO DANCE.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
IT'S GREAT. YOU'RE GREAT.
GREAT MOVEMENT,
BUT, UM, MAYBE
YOU COULD TALK TO ME.
[GIGGLING]
Elton John: ?? AND LOVE
LIES BLEEDING IN MY HAND ??
?? OH, IT KILLS ME TO THINK
OF YOU WITH ANOTHER MAN ??
?? I WAS PLAYING... ??
BESS, STOP DANCING.
TALK TO ME.
?? BUT MY GUITAR
COULDN'T HOLD YOU ??
?? SO I SPLIT THE BAND ??
[LOWERS VOLUME]
BESS...
TALK TO ME.
GIVE ME 5 MINUTES.
YOU CAN TOUCH ME NOW.
YOU CAN HAVE ME NOW.
BESS, LISTEN TO ME.
WE'RE NOT
GOING TO MAKE LOVE.
NOW PUT YOUR CLOTHES
BACK ON.
DON'T YOU WANT ME?
DON'T YOU LIKE ME?
YOU SAID THAT
YOU LIKED ME.
YES, BESS,
I LIKE YOU.
NOW PUT YOUR CLOTHES ON.
BUT YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND. I'LL...
I'LL BE GOOD
TO YOU, AND...
[CRYING]
I WANT US TO MAKE LOVE.
LISTEN. UM, BESS,
IF YOU WANT
TO TALK TO ME,
WE CAN MEET
AT THE HOSPITAL.
NOW JUST PUT
YOUR CLOTHES ON, BESS.
[CRYING]
NO...
PLEASE. I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT, NOW JUST PUT
YOUR CLOTHES ON, BESS,
AND GO HOME.
NO.
I'M LYING
ON MY BACK, ALL NAKED.
AND...
HE COMES IN,
AND HE SEES ME.
AND HE KISSES MY BREASTS.
UM...
AND HE ENTERS ME...
AND...
AND HE'S MAKING LOVE
TO ME...
GENTLY...
AND...
HE'S COMING.
IT WAS DR. RICHARDSON.
HI.
HI, BESS.
WHERE ARE YOU
GOING, THEN?
[INDISTINCT]
JAN, WE'RE GOING TO
TAKE YOU OFF
THE RESPIRATOR
FOR 5 MINUTES
TO EXERCISE YOUR LUNGS
A LITTLE BIT
AND SEE HOW YOU ARE,
SO JUST RELAX
AND TAKE IT EASY.
OK, START TO BREATHE
BY YOURSELF, NOW, JAN.
JUST TAKE
VERY DEEP BREATHS.
SLOWLY.
THAT'S IT.
AND AGAIN.
Dodo: VERY GOOD.
DEEP BREATHS.
NOW, THAT'S IT.
BESS.
YES?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
ON THIS BUS?
WHICH BUS, JAN?
COME TO ME. COME.
I'M HERE.
I'M HERE IN THE BACK.
YES.
IN THE BACK
OF THE BUS.
YEAH.
COME.
DODO. DODO.
JAN.
GO AND GET
DR. RICHARDSON.
I'M GOING TO PUT YOU BACK
ON THE RESPIRATOR NOW, JAN.
JAN, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
ARE YOU AWAKE?
TALK TO ME.
HI, BESS.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE
A CHAT WITH YOU.
BESS.
THIS IS MY BUS--MY BUS.
[MEEK VOICE]
FORGIVE ME, FATHER.
I HAVE SINNED.
[FIRM VOICE]
MARY MAGDALENE SINNED,
AND SHE IS AMONG
MY DEARLY BELOVED.
Bess: I GO TO THE BACK
OF THE BUS...
AND YOU'RE THERE.
AND YOU'RE SO HUGE...
THAT YOU'RE ALMOST
BURSTING OUT OF YOUR PANTS.
AND I UNDO YOUR FLY...
AND I TOUCH YOU.
I'M TOUCHING YOUR PRICK.
[SINGING IN GAELIC]
[CONGREGATION
SINGING IN GAELIC]
[PRECENTOR
HAVE YOU BEEN IN
TO SEE JAN?
HOW IS HE?
BETTER.
HE'S BETTER?
JUST A BIT.
HEY, BESS,
IT LOOKS LIKE
YOUR PRAYERS
HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE
TO TAKE HIM
OFF THE RESPIRATOR.
GOOD NEWS, ISN'T IT?
DO YOU THINK...
THAT WE TURN
TO DIFFERENT PEOPLE
WHEN WE GET CLOSE
TO THE EDGE?
AND THAT WE, UM...
WE TURN BAD
WHEN WE'RE GOING TO DIE?
YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO DIE.
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT.
I PROMISE YOU.
Elton John: ?? WHEN ARE YOU
GONNA COME DOWN? ??
?
?? WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO LAND? ?
?? I SHOULD HAVE STAYED
ON THE FARM ??
?? SHOULD HAVE LISTENED
TO MY OLD MAN ??
?? YOU KNOW
YOU CAN'T HOLD ME FOREVER ??
?? I DIDN'T SIGN UP WITH YOU ??
?? I'M NOT A PRESENT
FOR YOUR FRIENDS TO OPEN ??
?? THIS BOY'S TOO YOUNG
TO BE SINGING ??
?? THE BLUES... ??
OH, LOOK.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Terry:
HERE YOU GO.
HEY, HEY, GIRLIES!
WE FOUND SOME SHROOMIES!
DON'T GET YOUR HOPES
UP TOO HIGH, WILL YOU?
DR. RICHARDSON SAYS
THAT JAN COULD GET
WORSE AGAIN.
I'M THE ONE
WHO SAVED HIS LIFE.
I CAN SAVE IT AGAIN.
BESS, WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I TOLD JAN STORIES--
STORIES ABOUT LOVE.
THAT WAS ALMOST LIKE
BEING TOGETHER, HIM AND ME.
YOU SEE,
LOVE CAN SAVE JAN.
HE MUST NOT FORGET
ABOUT LOVE.
HE TOLD ME THAT.
HE TELLS ME
WHAT TO DO.
BESS, I'M GLAD THAT
YOU LISTENED TO JAN,
BUT DON'T LET HIM GAIN
TOO MUCH POWER OVER YOU.
SICKNESS IS
A MIGHTY POWER.
I'VE SAVED JAN.
DON'T TALK LIKE THAT.
IT'S STUPID!
YOU ALWAYS SAID
THAT I WASN'T STUPID.
WELL, YOU'RE STUPID
IF YOU SAY THINGS
LIKE THAT.
WHY ARE YOU SAYING
I'M STUPID NOW?
BECAUSE I CAN SEE
THAT YOU'RE DISAPPEARING
INTO A WORLD
OF MAKE-BELIEVE,
AND IT WORRIES ME.
I USED TO GO MAD
WHEN PEOPLE
CALLED YOU STUPID,
STUPID.
BUT YOU
Dr. Richardson:
WE'RE GOING TO PUT
A DRAIN IN THIS AFTERNOON.
IT'LL BE MUCH EASIER
TO GET THROUGH TO HIM.
DON'T WORRY.
IT'S A VERY MINOR OPERATION.
Jan: ARE YOU TRYING
TO MAKE ME FEEL GUILTY?
Bess: WHAT
MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
I THINK SHE'S TRYING
TO MAKE ME FEEL GUILTY.
[JAN SIGHS]
COME HERE.
YOU LOOK FUCKING AWFUL.
WHY DO YOU DRESS
LIKE THAT?
YOU DRESS LIKE A WIDOW.
I'M NOT EVEN DEAD YET.
MAYBE YOU WISH I WAS.
NO. NO, NO.
YOU HAVEN'T DONE
WHAT I ASKED YOU TO DO.
I HAVE!
I ASKED YOU
TO BE WITH A MAN.
I HAVE DONE THAT.
YOU CALL THAT
BEING WITH A MAN?
I CALL IT A JOKE.
I LOVE YOU.
I DON'T LOVE
SOME OTHER MAN.
PROVE IT.
BESS, WHAT IS GOING ON?
ARE YOU SLEEPING
WITH OTHER MEN
TO FEED HIS SICK FANTASIES?
HE DID GET BETTER.
NO, HE DID NOT
GET BETTER!
THAT'S JUST THE WAY
IT GOES, BESS.
SOMETIMES HE'S BETTER;
SOMETIMES HE'S WORSE.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THAT'S ALL IN YOUR MIND.
HE IS MY HUSBAND,
AND GOD HAS SAID
THAT I MUST HONOR HIM.
WELL, IF THAT'S WHAT
HONORING IS ALL ABOUT,
THEN I MUST HAVE
SOMETHING WRONG.
WELL, YOU DON'T COME
FROM AROUND HERE,
DO YOU?
NO, AND I'M GLAD
I DON'T.
WITH LOCALS TALKING--
IT MAKES ME SICK.
BUT YOU LIVE HERE,
AND YOU GO
TO THE CHURCH.
YES, BUT IT DON'T MEAN
I DON'T LOOK AT THINGS
ME OWN WAY.
WHY DON'T YOU
MOVE, THEN?
YOUR HUSBAND'S DEAD.
YOU KNOW VERY WELL
WHY I DON'T MOVE.
I DON'T MOVE
BECAUSE OF YOU.
A WOMAN HAS TO CHOOSE
FOR HERSELF, BESS.
SHE HAS TO HAVE
A MIND OF HER OWN.
NOW, WHAT YOU'RE DOING
IS MAKING THINGS WORSE.
IT'S NONSENSE.
HIS HEAD'S FULL OF SCARS.
HE'S UP TO HIS EYEBALLS
IN DRUGS.
HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
AND HE DOESN'T KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
[MEEK VOICE]
AM I GOING TO GO TO HELL?
[FIRM VOICE]
WHOM DO YOU WANT TO SAVE--
YOURSELF OR JAN?
BESS.
[TURNS VACUUM OFF]
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME--
MOST UNLIKE YOU.
Minister: I MUST
WARN YOU THAT THE LORD
LOOKS WITH ANGER
UPON THOSE WHO FAIL HIM.
[TURNS VACUUM ON]
YOU'VE GOT TO LEND ME
SOMETHING TO WEAR.
[MEN TALKING]
Man: A GOOD SHOT.
Man: ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
[POOL BALLS CLICK]
HELLO.
Man: GOOD SHOT.
HOW MUCH, DARLING?
1, 2, 3, UP.
OK. GOOD.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
Man: THANK YOU.
Dodo: I CAN'T HEAR
THE BLOOD PRESSURE.
WE HAVE
A FIBRILLATION.
CLEAR.
Dodo: STILL NO CHANGE.
OK. CLEAR.
CLEAR AGAIN,
PLEASE.
GO ON.
CLEAR, PLEASE.
[MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY]
YES!
OH, YES!
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD WORK.
IT'S OK?
[BESS CRYING]
Dr. Richardson:
HI, BESS.
BESS...
BESS, I THINK
IT'S TIME WE HAD
A LITTLE CHAT.
I LOVE YOU
NO MATTER WHAT
IS IN YOUR HEAD.
[DISHES CLATTERING]
SO YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO GIVE JAN
ELECTRIC SHOCK
TREATMENT WHEN
HIS HEART STOPPED
IN THE OPERATION
YESTERDAY?
NO, WE DIDN'T.
IT WAS A PERFECTLY
SIMPLE OPERATION.
AS YOU KNOW. WELL,
I SHOULDN'T
HAVE TO SAY THAT.
YOU KNOW THAT
VERY WELL.
Mother: I WANT
A WORD WITH BESS
ON HER OWN.
THANK YOU, DOROTHY.
I'M NOT GOING TO ASK YOU
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
GETTING UP TO
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
TO HEAR YOU LIE TO ME,
BUT AS LONG
AS YOU ARE LIVING
UNDER MY ROOF,
YOU ARE TO BEHAVE
LIKE A DECENT HUMAN BEING.
I HAVE NEVER
LIED TO YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YES, MOTHER.
THIS IS VERY PAINFUL
FOR ME.
YOUR GRANDFATHER
CAN NO LONGER
HOLD HIS HAND OVER YOU
WITH THE ELDERS.
I DON'T THINK YOU REALIZE
WHAT THAT MEANS.
HAVE YOU ANY IDEA
WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE CAST OUT?
YOU WILL
HAVE NOTHING, BESS.
I'VE KNOWN
STRONG MEN AND WOMEN
WITHER AWAY
AFTER BEING CAST OUT.
NOW, YOU ARE NOT STRONG.
YOU'RE A FEEBLE GIRL.
IT WOULD
KILL YOU, BESS.
I'VE SAID ENOUGH.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Dodo: BESS. BESS.
CAN YOU COME DOWN
A MINUTE, LOVE?
DR. RICHARDSON IS HERE.
HI, BESS.
HELLO.
[DOOR CLOSES]
HOW ARE YOU?
CAN WE SIT DOWN?
UH-HUH.
BESS...
I THINK...I THINK
YOU'VE GOT YOURSELF
INVOLVED
IN SOMETHING
WHICH IS
OUT OF YOUR CONTROL.
HAVE I?
COME ON, BESS.
YOU'RE NOT
A KID ANYMORE.
LOOK,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE,
HE'S FORCING YOU
TO GET SCREWED
BY EVERY TOM,
DICK, AND HARRY.
IT'S JUST NOT YOU.
I DON'T MAKE LOVE
WITH THEM.
I MAKE LOVE
WITH JAN...
AND I SAVE HIM
FROM DYING.
WELL, I'M SORRY,
BUT YOU KNOW,
TO ME, HE SEEMS MORE
LIKE A DIRTY OLD MAN
WHO WANTS TO PLAY
THE PEEPING TOM.
SOMETIMES...
I DON'T EVEN HAVE
TO TELL HIM ABOUT IT.
JAN AND ME...
WE HAVE
A SPIRITUAL CONTACT.
GOD GIVES EVERYONE
SOMETHING TO BE GOOD AT.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN STUPID...
BUT I'M GOOD AT THIS.
GOD GIVES EVERYONE
A TALENT.
AND WHAT'S JAN'S
TALENT?
HE IS...
HE'S A GREAT LOVER.
WELL, WHAT'S--
WHAT'S MINE, THEN?
I DON'T KNOW.
HAVEN'T YOU
FOUND IT YET?
I SEE.
AND WHAT'S YOUR
TALENT, THEN, BESS?
BECAUSE, UM...
OH, SURELY IT CAN'T
BE BEING SCREWED
BY MEN YOU'VE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
I CAN BELIEVE.
ARE YOU ANGRY NOW?
YES, I AM!
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH,
YEAH, I'M ANGRY
BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T SEE THAT HE'S
MESSING YOU ABOUT.
HE'S THE ONE
WHO'S SICK.
LOOK, WHAT HE'S
DOING TO YOU
IS SICK,
AND IT'S
GETTING SICKER
AND SICKER.
HE'S BECOMING MORE
AND MORE OF A DANGER
TO YOU
THE MORE THE FLUID
RISES IN HIS...
LISTEN TO ME,
FOR GOD'S SAKE!
DO YOU ALWAYS
GET SO INVOLVED
IN YOUR PATIENTS'
PROBLEMS, DR. RICHARDSON?
LISTEN TO ME, BESS.
I CARE FOR YOU.
I LOVE YOU, BESS.
YOU'RE VERY SPECIAL.
WILL YOU MOVE
YOUR HANDS, PLEASE?
CERTAINLY.
DODO.
Bess: WILL YOU SHOW
DR. RICHARDSON OUT, PLEASE?
Dr. Richardson:
W-WHAT'S GOING TO
HAPPEN NOW, BESS?
UM, HAS HE TOLD YOU
ANY MORE
OF THE THOUGHTS
HE'S HAD?
ANY MORE SERVICES
FOR YOU TO PERFORM?
DON'T COME HERE AGAIN.
OH, HE HAS, HAS HE?
AND WHAT'S IT GOING
TO BE THIS TIME?
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO GIVE HIM TO SLOBBER
OVER THIS TIME?
[MEEK VOICE]
DEAR FATHER, WHAT'S GOING ON?
[WHIMPERING]
FATHER, WHERE ARE YOU?
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
THAT BOY SCARED ME.
HELLO.
CAN YOU TAKE ME
OUT TO THE SHIPS?
CAN'T TAKE YOU OUT THERE.
THE OTHER GIRLS
WOULDN'T LIKE IT.
BUT THEY CAN'T
DO ALL THE SHIPS.
THEY DON'T HAVE TIME.
MAYBE NOT.
WHAT ABOUT THE BIG ONE?
I DON'T GO OUT
TO THAT ONE ANYMORE.
GIRLS WON'T GO ABOARD.
WELL, THEN YOU CAN
TAKE ME. NO HARM DONE.
Dr. Richardson:
HOW ARE YOU
FEELING, JAN?
WELL, I'VE FELT BETTER.
YEAH. YEAH.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE PERIODS
IN WHICH WE CAN
GET THROUGH TO YOU
HAVE LATELY
BECOME VERY RARE.
I'LL HAVE
TO SEND YOU
BACK TO GLASGOW
FOR A WHILE,
I'M AFRAID.
I DON'T WANT
ANY MORE...
OPERATIONS.
OF COURSE,
IT'S ENTIRELY UP TO YOU,
BUT...
I HAVE TO SAY
THAT YOUR CONDITION'S
UNLIKELY TO IMPROVE
WITHOUT SURGERY.
WELL, IF YOU'VE
MADE YOUR MIND UP
ON THAT POINT,
UM, MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO CONSIDER OTHER MATTERS.
I MEAN, WE SHOULD START
THINKING ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE
THAN JUST YOU.
BESS.
I'M GLAD YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M DRIVING AT.
YOUR...YOUR CONDITION'S
BEEN--IT'S BEEN
VERY HARD ON HER.
AND I CAN'T JUDGE WHY,
BUT SHE'S SUFFERING
FROM DELUSIONS
REGARDING YOUR CONDITION.
I HAVE TO BE BLUNT.
I DON'T THINK
THAT SEEING YOU
IS GOOD FOR HER.
I GUESS NOT.
I AM CONVINCED
THAT THE BEST THING
WE CAN DO
FOR HER RIGHT NOW
IS TO ADMIT HER
AGAIN.
GET HER AWAY?
YES.
AS FAR AWAY
AS POSSIBLE.
THINK THAT'S NECESSARY?
LISTEN, IF YOU
DON'T WANT SURGERY,
THE INDICATIONS ARE
THAT WE WILL ENTER
A PROLONGED PERIOD
IN WHICH YOU WILL BE
MORE AND MORE AFFECTED
BY YOUR CONDITION.
[SIGH]
THE POORLIER YOU ARE,
THE MORE DETRIMENTAL
YOUR INFLUENCE ON BESS.
I'VE DRAWN UP SOME PAPERS
GIVING ME THE AUTHORITY
TO DETAIN HER
UNDER THE PROVISIONS
OF THE MENTAL HEALTH ACT.
I'LL NEED YOUR CONSENT.
Dodo: YOU'RE GOING
TO SECTION BESS?
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
I CAN GET HER TREATED.
TELL ME, DR. RICHARDSON,
DOES...
DOES THIS MEAN I WILL
NEVER SEE HER AGAIN?
Dr. Richardson:
TO BE REALISTIC, YES.
IT'S JUST THERE
AT THE BOTTOM.
Dr. Richardson: YOU SAID
YOU WANTED TO HELP HER.
COME ON, JAN.
Deep Purple:
?? IF YOU'VE BEEN BAD ??
?? LORD, I BET YOU HAVE ??
?
?? AND YOU'VE NOT BEEN HIT ?
?? YOU'VE NOT BEEN HIT
BY FLYING LEAD ??
?? YOU'D BETTER
CLOSE YOUR EYES ??
BOW YOUR HEAD ??
?? WAIT FOR THE RICOCHET ??
?? OOH OOH OOH ??
?? OOH OOH OOH OOH ??
[CLANG CLANG]
HOW DO I GET BACK?
I'LL KEEP AN EYE OUT
FOR YOU.
HELLO.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I WANT THAT YOU DO
IT WITH THE SAILOR
AND I WATCH.
OK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S OK.
ALL RIGHT.
COME HERE, YOU.
NO!
Sailor:
THERE WE GO, EH?
YEAH.
THAT'S BETTER.
COME ON DOWN.
YEAH.
YOU LIKE IT
LIKE THIS, EH?
OH, PLEASE.
CAN I GO HOME NOW?
NO. NO. CAN I
GO HOME NOW?
PLEASE, I DON'T WANT--
STAY STILL.
NO. PLEASE.
NO. NO. PLEASE.
PLEASE.
STAY STILL, I SAID.
[BESS CRYING]
[SCREAMING]
NO.
AAH!
BITCH!
I'M GOING
TO SHOOT YOU.
YOU WILL, HUH?
I'M GOING
TO SHOOT YOU.
YOU THINK SO?
YOU DON'T EVEN
KNOW HOW TO
USE THAT THING.
NOBODY WILL BELIEVE
A HOOKER!
Man: BECAUSE THERE IS
ONLY ONE THING FOR US,
SINNERS THAT WE ARE,
TO ACHIEVE PERFECTION
IN THE EYES OF GOD...
THROUGH UNCONDITIONAL LOVE
FOR THE WORD
THAT IS WRITTEN,
THROUGH UNCONDITIONAL LOVE
FOR THE LAW.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
HOW CAN YOU
LOVE A WORD?
LOVE WORDS.
YOU CANNOT BE
IN LOVE WITH A WORD.
YOU CAN LOVE
ANOTHER HUMAN BEING.
THAT'S PERFECTION.
NO WOMAN SPEAKS HERE.
BESS McNEILL,
THE KIRK SESSION
HAS DECIDED THIS DAY
THAT HENCEFORTH,
YOU SHALL NO LONGER
HAVE ACCESS TO THIS KIRK.
THEY WHO KNOW YOU
SHALL NOT KNOW YOU.
PLEASE, LET ME STAY!
PLEASE!
BEGONE, BESS McNEILL,
FROM THE HOUSE OF GOD.
[DOOR OPENS]
HELLO, BESS.
YOU'RE--YOU'RE
COMING WITH US.
WE'RE GOING
TO GLASGOW.
Dodo: BESS, THEY'RE
GOING TO TAKE YOU
BACK INTO HOSPITAL
JUST FOR A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S FOR YOUR OWN GOOD.
I WANT TO SEE JAN.
I WANT TO SEE
MY HUSBAND.
I KNOW,
BUT NOT NOW, BESS.
IT'S FOR
YOUR OWN GOOD, BESS.
MOTHER CAN'T
HAVE ME ADMITTED--
NOT NOW
THAT I'M MARRIED.
BESS, IT WASN'T
MOTHER THAT SIGNED
THE PAPER.
IT WAS JAN.
YOU LIAR!
COME ALONG, BESS.
JAN!
DODO, HOW
CAN YOU DO THIS?
YOU HAD
A HUSBAND,
TOO, ONCE.
YOUR LOVE COULD HAVE
SAVED HIM, IF ONLY
YOU'D TRIED!
JAN!
Bess: JAN!
[DOOR CLOSES]
OK, BESS. LET'S GO.
OH, FUCK!
RYAN,
SHE'S NOT HERE!
HELLO.
Boy: WHO'S A TART?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO'S A TART?
Boys: TART! TART!
I CAN'T OPEN THE DOOR.
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
MOTHER?
PLEASE. PLEASE, MOTHER,
OPEN THE DOOR!
Bess: PLEASE, OPEN THE DOOR!
[BESS CRYING]
MOTHER!
I'LL BE GOOD.
I'LL BE REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
I'LL BE REALLY GOOD.
OH, PLEASE, OPEN.
PLEASE GO AWAY.
STOP IT! GO AWAY.
YOU JUST GO AWAY
AND LEAVE ME!
WHO'S A TART?
AWAY WITH YOU.
STOP ALL THIS RACKET
OUTSIDE THE HOUSE
OF GOD.
COME ON! ON YOU GO.
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
BESS.
BESS!
BESS, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT, LOVE?
BESS, IT'S DODO.
OH, BESSIE.
JAN IS DYING.
I--I WASN'T TO TELL YOU.
I WASN'T TO TELL YOU.
NO. IT'S GOOD
YOU TOLD ME.
I KNOW YOU LOVE ME.
I HAVE TO GO.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
ANYTHING AT ALL?
YES.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO GO TO JAN
TO BE CUREDR HIM
AND TO RISE FROM HIS BED
AND WALK.
WILL YOU TAKE ME
TO THE BIG SHIP?
AGAIN?
ARE YOU SURE?
[MEEK VOICE]
FATHER, WHY AREN'T
YOU WITH ME?
WITH YOU, BESS.
[FIRM VOICE]
I
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
[MEEK VOICE]
WHERE WERE YOU?
[FIRM VOICE]
OH, DON'T YOU THINK
I HAVE OTHER PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO TALK TO ME?
[MEEK VOICE]
WELL, OF COURSE.
I HADN'T THOUGHT OF THAT.
[FIRM VOICE]
THERE'S THIS SILLY
LITTLE THING CALLED BESS
WHO KEEPS ON WANTING ME
TO TALK TO HER,
SO MY WORK'S BEEN
PILING UP A BIT.
[MEEK VOICE]
BUT YOU'RE WITH ME NOW?
[FIRM VOICE]
OF COURSE I AM, BESS.
YOU KNOW THAT.
[BELL CLANGING]
THANK YOU.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
UM, I'M SORRY.
DO YOU NEED ME?
NO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
STAY THERE.
BESS ASKED ME
TO PRAY.
FOR WHAT?
FOR JAN'S LIFE.
FOR A MIRACLE.
YEAH. THAT WOULD
BE A MIRACLE.
DEAR GOD,
I PRAY THAT JAN
GETS BETTER,
THAT HE RISES
FROM HIS BED AND WALKS.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
SISTER McNEILL HERE.
WE'LL MAKE YOU BETTER.
WHERE'S JAN?
I'D LIKE TO SEE HIM.
NO. NOT NOW, LOVE.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
AN OPERATION NOW.
I WANT TO SEE HIM.
NOT NOW, LOVE.
YOU NEED AN OPERATION.
NO. I'VE GOT
TO SEE JAN.
PLEASE, DODO.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT. STOP.
SHE WANTS TO SEE JAN.
I'M GOING TO TAKE HER
TO SEE JAN.
COME ON.
OUT OF THE WAY,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
HELP ME. COME ON.
MOVE, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE!
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
THERE YOU GO.
THERE YOU ARE.
YOU CAN SEE HIM NOW,
CAN'T YOU?
HOW IS HE...
HOW'S HE DOING?
Bess: IS HE NOT
ANY BETTER?
Dodo:
NO. NO, HE'S NOT.
OH. I THOUGHT HE
MIGHT BE BETTER NOW.
HMM.
MAYBE I WAS WRONG
AFTER ALL.
OK, LET'S GET INSIDE.
HERE. TAKE THOSE.
TAPE.
OK, TAKE CARE. LET'S GO.
1, 2, 3.
THERE WE GO.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
LOVE.
NOW, BESS,
DO YOU KNOW ME?
YEAH.
PULSE: 90.
WHAT HAPPENED?
DO YOU KNOW?
Dodo: NO.
Woman:
PRESSURE ON 100.
GET THE BLOOD PRESSURE.
100.
Dodo: IT WILL BE
ALL RIGHT, LOVE.
IT WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
Dr. Richardson:
CAN I HAVE A LOOK
AT HER BACK?
THERE WE GO.
OK. HAND ME
THE SCISSORS.
YES.
ALL RIGHT.
MOTHER.
OH, MOTHER.
HERE SHE IS.
BESSIE.
BESS.
I'M SORRY THAT I
COULD NOT BE GOOD,
MOTHER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
BESSIE.
YOUR GRANDFATHER'S
SORRY HE COULDN'T COME.
WILL YOU TELL HIM
THAT I LOVE HIM?
I AM GLAD THAT YOU
CAME, MOTHER.
Dr. Richardson:
BLOOD PRESSURE.
IT WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
Woman:
IT'S GOING DOWN.
2 UNITS NOW.
2 UNITS IMMEDIATELY.
2 UNITS.
OK, WE'RE JUST GOING
TO LOWER YOU DOWN
A LITTLE BIT NOW,
ALL RIGHT, BESS?
THERE WE GO.
THAT WAS EASY,
WASN'T IT?
GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
OH. OH.
DODO, HOLD ME.
HERE I AM. I'M HOLDING.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, LOVE.
I'M HERE. I'M HERE.
I'M AFRAID.
I KNOW. I KNOW.
JAN?
JAN!
SHH. NOW, SHH.
I'M FRIGHTENED.
IT'S...
IT'S ALL WRONG.
Woman: NO PULSE.
BESS?
Dr. Richardson:
STAND CLEAR. STAND CLEAR!
CLEAR. CLEAR.
WHAT?
[MONITOR EMITTING STEADY TONE]
IT'S GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S A GOOD GIRL.
COME ON.
OK. YOU CAN STOP NOW.
WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
SHE'S GONE, DODO.
SHE'S GONE.
NO.
BESS. BESS.
LISTEN TO ME.
I'M SORRY.
OH, I'M SORRY.
Dr. Richardson
whispering: Dodo.
[CRYING]
NO!
COME ON, DODO.
LET'S GO!
COME ON.
Dodo: I'M SORRY!
Elton John:
?? IT'S A LITTLE BIT FUNNY ??
?? THIS FEELING INSIDE ??
?? I'M NOT ONE OF THOSE
WHO CAN ??
?? EASILY HIDE ??
?? DON'T HAVE MUCH MONEY ??
?? BUT, BOY, IF I DID ??
?? I'D BUY A BIG HOUSE WHERE ??
?? WE BOTH COULD LIVE ??
?? IF I WAS A SCULPTOR ??
?? HA, BUT THEN AGAIN NO ??
?? OR A MAN WHO MAKES POTION
S IN THE ??
?? TRAVELING SHOW, I ??
?? KNOW IT'S NOT MUCH ??
?? BUT IT'S THE BEST
I CAN DO ??
?
?? MY GIFT IS MY SONG, AND ?
?? THIS ONE'S FOR YOU ??
?? AND YOU CAN TELL EVERYBODY ??
?? THIS IS YOUR SONG ??
?
?? IT MAY BE QUITE SIMPLE, BUT ?
?? NOW THAT IT'S DONE... ??
YOU DESCRIBE THE DECEASED
AS "AN IMMATURE, UNSTABLE
PERSON,
"A PERSON WHO,
DUE TO THE TRAUMA OF
HER HUSBAND'S ILLNESS,
"GAVE WAY
IN OBSESSIVE FASHION
TO AN EXAGGERATED,
PERVERSE FORM
OF SEXUALITY."
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO CLARIFY THAT
TO THE INQUIRY?
THAT'S WHAT I WROTE.
YES. THAT'S WHAT IT SAYS.
CAN I HAVE A GLASS
OF WATER, PLEASE?
GET DR. RICHARDSON
A GLASS OF WATER.
THANK YOU.
Man: LISTEN, MAN,
YOU HAD THE DECEASED
IN YOUR CARE.
THE COURT WOULD LIKE
TO HEAR THE MEDICAL FACTS.
IF--IF YOU'D, UM,
IF YOU WERE TO
ASK ME AGAIN
TO WRITE...
UM...THE CONCLUSION,
THEN...
INSTEAD OF WRITING
"NEUROTIC"
OR, UM, "PSYCHOTIC,"
THEN I MIGHT...
JUST, UM,
USE A WORD LIKE...
"GOOD."
GOOD?
YES.
YOU WISH THE RECORDS
OF THIS COURT
TO STATE THAT
IN YOUR MEDICAL OPINION,
THE DECEASED WAS SUFFERING
FROM BEING "GOOD"?
PERHAPS THIS WAS
THE PSYCHOLOGICAL DEFECT
THAT LED
TO HER DEATH.
IS THAT WHAT WE SHALL
WRITE, DR. RICHARDSON?
NO.
Dr. Richardson:
OF COURSE NOT.
Man: VERY WELL, THEN.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD STICK
TO YOUR ORIGINAL STATEMENT
THEN, DOCTOR.
YES.
I THINK THAT EVERYTHING
THERE IS TO SAY
ABOUT BESS McNEILL
HAS BEEN SAID ALREADY.
WE HAVE AGREED
TO SANCTION HER BURIAL,
BUT THERE CAN BE
NO FUNERAL SERVICE.
THE FACT THAT SOME OF US
KNEW THE DECEASED GIRL WELL
CANNOT BE ALLOWED TO INFLUENCE
THE FORM OF HER BURIAL.
BESS McNEILL'S FUNERAL
MUST BE THE SAME
AS ANYONE ELSE
OF HER KIND.
THE BODY WILL BE RELEASED
BY THE AUTHORITIES
SOMETIME THIS WEEK.
I'VE OBTAINED PERMISSION
FROM THE ELDERS
TO BURY BESS...
BUT...I CANNOT DEVIATE
FROM THE PRINCIPLES THAT
APPLY TO FUNERALS HERE.
I MUST SAY ABOUT BESS
WHAT MUST BE SAID.
OK. COME ON.
WHERE'S JAN?
HAS HE GONE DOWN THERE YET?
I DON'T KNOW.
HAVE YOU SEEN JAN?
Minister:
BESS McNEILL,
YOU ARE A SINNER,
AND FOR YOUR SINS,
YOU ARE CONSIGNED
TO HELL.
NOT ONE OF YOU
HAS THE RIGHT
TO CONSIGN BESS
TO HELL.
TERRY, IT'S TIME.
LET'S DO IT.
GET UP,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
COME ON, MAN.
COME ON.
TAKE GOOD CARE OF HER.
[CRYING]
COME ON, JAN.
YOU GOT TO LET HER GO.
[SPLASH]
BESS!
JAN.
JAN, HEY.
WHAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
COME ON.
I WANT
TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING.
YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO
BELIEVE IT.
WHAT?
COME ON.
PLEASE.
HERE. LET'S GO.
PIM! PIM, COME ON!
YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO
BELIEVE IT.
HA HA HA!
HEY, PIM, COME ON.
CHECK THIS OUT.
CHECK THIS THING
OUT, MAN.
YOU SEE ANYTHING?
THERE'S NOTHING
OUT THERE.
I'VE TRIED ALL
THE FUCKING RANGES,
AND THERE'S
NOTHING THERE.
I JUST WANTED
TO BE SURE. COME ON.
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING]
[RINGING]