You're not saying things
that mean anything.
It's not even a debate.
It's a better automobile!
Ain't no way you can say to me
a Lincoln is better than a Cadillac.
- A Lincoln is better. It's a better automobile.
- Forget about it.
A Cadillac's got more acceleration.
It's got more power.
It's got better handling.
It's got more legroom for your legs.
It's got more power.
- You just said that.
- Bingo.
- What?
- You just said, "More power."
- You're starting to repeat yourself.
- I said that?
- You're getting senile.
- He got me so fucking aggravated.
I'll tell you one thing,
Mercedes got it all over both of them.
A Mercedes?
A Lincoln's like driving a fucking water bed,
for Christ's sakes.
- A Mercedes.
- Yeah. It's a good car.
I'll tell you one thing, my friend.
Undisputable. The Lincoln is longer.
It's longer? Longer like what?
Longer like my dick is longer?
No, no, no. We're not talking about
a Volkswagen.
What do you mean? Yeah, Volkswagen.
Longer. Like longer.
Like in inches it's longer.
- You don't make no fucking sense.
- It's a longer car.
Two fucking cars, right?
This is a car, this is a car, right?
Right here, okay?
All things being equal,
the one's longer gonna get there first.
You don't have to be fucking Einstein
to understand this.
You know what happens
when you get there, don't you?
- No.
- You're still driving a fucking Lincoln.
I'll show you a fucking picture.
Two cars. The one's longer gets there first.
That's a scientific fact. It's a longer car.
- Can I ask you guys something?
- What?
Are you guys, you know, wise guys?
Wise guys? What are wise guys?
- You know...
- What makes you think we're wise guys?
We could be cops.
Yeah.
- You believed me. Undercover what?
- No, I didn't.
- You believed me.
- No, it's just...
- Who's that over there?
- Who?
The guy by the bar with the mustache.
That's Don, Don the Jeweler.
Jilly brought him here.
What Jilly? Jilly "Four-eyes"?
Not that fucking hump Jilly "Four-eyes."
Jilly, you know, from Queens.
- You think he's a wise guy?
- No, he's a connected guy.
Connected? If I had a thing to lay off,
he could lay it off for me?
- You got something you gotta lay off?
- Ain't the question.
I'm just saying if I had a thing,
he could lay it off. That's all.
All that fucking money you owe downtown,
you'd have to lay off a fucking Brink's truck.
- Sonny's in love.
- I think fucking Lefty's in love.
I'll see you.
Were you asleep?
- Are you okay, honey?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Go back to sleep. I'll call you tomorrow.
That's good, babe.
Okay. I'm sorry. I gotta go back to sleep.
I'm so tired.
- All right.
- Hey.
- Yeah.
What?
Put the phone on your pillow.
I want to listen to you breathe.
You Don the Jeweler?
There. That's some beautiful thing.
Why don't you give it to your wife?
My wife? How am I gonna give it to my wife?
- I ain't married.
- Got a girlfriend?
- Yeah, I got a girlfriend.
- So marry her.
Hey, you for real?
I'm asking you
to middle a diamond for me here.
- All I want from my end is $8,000.
- And I'm saying to you
is you should give it to somebody that
don't know better, because that's a fugazy.
All right?
That's a fugazy?
How do you know it's a fugazy?
- You looked at it for two seconds.
- What? It's a fake.
I know what a fugazy is.
Hey, pal, you want to see something?
I'm gonna show you something.
There you go. Ain't that something?
That's a beautiful thing.
Yeah, that is a beautiful thing,
but it's not my thing.
What about this?
What do you want me to say?
Go ahead, try and sell it,
you want to be a dumbsky. Give it a shot.
Dumbsky? You calling me a dumbsky?
You know who you're talking to, my friend?
Hey, Left. Come on, have a spritzer.
You want to go embarrass yourself
with this thing...
Embarrass myself? My family, my children...
My mother can hold her head up
in any neighborhood in this city
when she walks down the block, see?
In all the five boroughs, I'm known.
Forget about it.
I'm known all over the fucking world.
Anybody, ask anybody about Lefty
from Mulberry Street.
- You're pissing up the wrong fucking tree.
- I didn't mean no disrespect.
- It's a misunderstanding.
- Where you going? Sit down there.
You're gonna walk out on me?
You don't walk out on me.
I walk out on you.
- You got a car?
- I got a car.
Let's go get your car. Come on.
Take care.
Put that window up.
I'm gonna catch a draft.
I'm getting fucking cancer over here.
- You'll be all right.
- Where we going?
You a cop?
Don't ask so many fucking questions.
Well, well, I've got to school you, my friend.
I've got to school you.
What's the matter? You work for Jilly,
he never school you?
School me in what?
You don't talk until I talk to you.
Fugazy.
You call that ring a fugazy. You don't know
word fucking one, my friend.
I know. I look at you and I know.
You a guy
can't keep his fucking mouth shut.
Hey, I'm talking to you now.
Look, I've been in jewels five years.
How do you figure
I'm gonna earn the kind of money I do
if I can't tell a fucking zircon?
- There's good money in it?
- What?
What?
- What, jewels?
- Thank you.
Yeah. If you know what you're doing,
there is.
Let's go to 23rd and 8th. Then we'll find out
if you know what you're doing.
You owe me $8,000.
No, hold on. Wait. I gave you the diamond.
Left, who's this guy?
- He says it's a fugazy.
- What's a fugazy?
- Your diamond's a fugazy.
- What is a fugazy?
- Come on, you know.
- Don't you tell me what I know.
- You know what you did, pal.
- One of you has got to be wrong.
That's a Tiffany fucking diamond.
Left, that is my wife's fucking diamond ring.
It's a fugazy, Left.
You took away your wife's ring?
Look, you bring that ring to any kike
on 47th Street,
he's gonna tell you that that is primo.
You took away your wife's ring
to go bet on the Giants?
Hey, look, you don't want it.
Give it back to me, okay?
- Hey, Left, come on...
- $8,000.
Let me talk to this fucking guy for a second.
Just give me half a second, would you?
$8,000.
Why don't you go to the bar
and have a drink?
Let me talk to the guy for a minute.
Come on.
Hey, I got a fucking black belt, pal. So you...
Shit!
This guy is going to fucking kill you.
You understand what I'm saying?
We got about two minutes
to figure a way out of this thing.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry? Shut the fuck up.
- Sorry ain't gonna do it.
- I don't want to die.
Yeah?
- What kind of car do you drive?
- A Porsche.
Give me the keys.
All right.
- Whose car is it now?
- It's Lefty's.
Lefty's stuff. All right, good.
That's for the fucking drinks, pal.
Why'd you pay for that drink, Don?
A wise guy never pays for a drink.
- I didn't know that.
- Always on the arm.
All right.
You scared that guy, though.
That cracks me up.
I got 26 fucking hits under my belt,
and you're the one he's scared of. Fuck.
- Pull over.
- What?
Pull over. I've got to do something.
- Right here?
- Yeah. Right here, pull over.
All right. I'm cool.
Come on, give me a hand with this.
Pull this out, pull it.
- You're taking the whole fucking thing apart.
- You didn't hear nothing under the dash?
- No, I didn't hear a fucking thing.
- There it is.
I can go right up the back.
What the fuck are you doing down there?
- Just feeling around here.
- You think I got a wire in my car?
- Fuck!
- You think I'm fucking stupid?
Did I say that? Did I say you got a wire?
Say it to my face, if you're gonna do this.
Nothing for nothing,
but I think you owe me an apology.
Ain't the question. I lost a screwdriver here.
- You lost a what?
- The screwdriver fell down there.
Come on. You lost a screwdriver
in my fucking stereo?
You'll find it again. It's down there.
- So you like the DeVille?
- Forget about it.
Yeah. I got the Fleetwood Brougham.
- Is that right? With the velour?
- Forget about it.
- Are you married?
- No.
- I got a girl out there in California.
- That's good.
She should stay in California.
Keep your eye out for your balls.
- Yeah, you're right.
- I'm always right.
A wise guy's always right.
Even when he's wrong, he's right.
All the way up the line, connected guy
to wise guy to skipper to boss.
- Yeah, I know that.
- You know?
- Yeah.
- What do you know?
It's kind of like the army,
like a chain of command.
The army? It ain't nothing like the army.
The army is some guy you don't know
sends you out to whack
some other guy you don't know. Army.
- You want to check in with me tomorrow?
- Yeah, all right.
I don't know how the fuck you knew
that ring was a fugazy.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah, so long.
Don the Jeweler is a good earner.
He ain't a leech.
He keeps to himself. He's a jewel guy.
- Where's he from, Jilly?
- Florida.
- He's a jewel guy.
- But Florida where? The beach?
- No, not the beach.
I don't know.
Wherever the fuck
the Dodgers have spring training.
He's a stand-up guy?
I said I knew him, Left.
I didn't say I fucked him.
Hey, you. Come here!
Come here.
What do you say, Jilly? How you doing?
My friend Lefty's asking about you.
Don't embarrass me, capisce?
I wouldn't do that to you.
You know that, Jilly.
Because if you do,
one of us is gonna whack you out.
That's not good.
All right, Jilly. Go back to your bath.
- Take care, kid.
- Good to see you.
When I introduce you, I'm gonna say,
"This is a friend of mine."
That means you're a connected guy.
If I said instead, "This is a friend of ours,"
that would mean you're a made guy.
Capisce?
Yeah, "friend of mine." "Friend of ours."
- What do I call you? "Friend of ours," or...
- You keep your mouth shut about me.
Know what I'm saying? Hey, Don.
You got a couple of fazools?
- I got some things I got to take care of.
- Yeah.
What do you want? $100?
What are you doing?
A wise guy don't carry his money
in a wallet.
A wise guy carries money in a roll.
Like this. See?
Beaner on the outside. Like that. Come on.
That mustache.
You got to get rid of that mustache,
'cause that's against the rules.
And get a pair of pants, will you?
This ain't a fucking rodeo.
Dress like I dress. This is my family.
- More even than my own family.
- Is that right?
- I don't got a family.
- You don't got a family?
No, I'm an orphan.
I grew up in an orphanage.
Ain't the question, even if you had a family.
If this is your family,
then this is your family.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Yeah.
I'm freezing my balls off.
What do we got to be standing outside
all day in the cold for?
- Got to show the flag.
- The flag of fucking Antarctica.
- What's going on?
- Hey, Lefty.
- Lefty, what do you say?
- This is Donnie, a friend of mine.
How you doing?
The good news is
my dick is now a popsicle.
- Hi, Sonny.
- Hey, Sonny, how you doing?
Sonny Red.
- Who's this guy?
- This is Donnie, a friend of mine.
Just stand there and look dangerous, friend.
He does look dangerous, don't he?
You gonna make this week's vig? I hope so.
'Cause I don't want to have to come
looking for you. You hear me?
- Come on, Bruno.
- I just shit in my pants, right?
It's the boss, Donnie.
Okay, Joe,
the Bureau wants your autograph.
- What's that, you want me to sign it?
- Forget about it.
"Forget about it" is right.
Listen, by the way, they want you to shave
the mustache. Regulations.
How did they even know
about the mustache?
- Did you rat me out?
- I didn't rat you out.
- Show and tell.
- Yeah. Nice.
- What?
- So does he. He wants me to shave.
- Who? Ruggiero?
- Yeah.
Regulations. Here.
You know something?
I got him. I got my hooks in the guy.
Cloaked by the high grasses
of the African Savannah,
the stalking cheetah moves stealthily
towards his prey.
- How you doing?
- You're here for my dad?
Yeah. I'm Donnie.
- Tommy. How are you?
- Good.
- Merry Christmas. Come on in.
- Thanks.
- Benny's watching TV. You met Tommy?
- Yes, we met. Thank you.
Separated from the herd,
the gazelle senses danger.
Benny, Donnie's here.
Too late. The cheetah springs.
Benny loves animals.
- You see that?
- I'll be in the kitchen if you need me.
- Hunter and hunted.
- Look at that.
Predator and prey.
The endless cycle of nature repeated.
I brought this by for you.
It's a little Christmas present.
Yeah, wait a minute. Here.
I'm sorry, Left, but I'm in
a little bit of a rush here, you know? So...
- Merry Christmas.
- Thank you.
That's really nice of you.
Wow. Look at this.
Very generous of you, Donnie.
Thank you. Good boy.
- All right. So, happy holidays.
- Where you going?
- I thought you was an orphan.
- Yeah.
- So what are you gonna do?
- Left, I don't want to spoil your day.
Come on.
No man of mine is gonna be alone
on Christmas. Come on in here.
Come on.
You think I cook
like them goombahs in Brooklyn?
All they know is manicotti.
A hundred years, they'll be eating manicotti.
- You never ate coq au vin?
- No.
There we are.
Can of collagen, can of tomatoes.
- Punch of salt.
- "Punch"?
- Punch. Punch of salt?
- "Punch" or "pinch"?
"Punch," not "pinch."
- Did I say "pinch"?
- No, you said "punch."
Sometimes you don't make
no fucking sense, Donnie.
- You got all this, Annette?
- I can't cook special like Benny.
Shut up, Annette. Forget about it.
Wherever you go, the best cooks are men.
On Mars, the best cooks are gonna be men.
That's a fact.
Wait till you taste this coq au vin.
It's gonna melt in your mouth,
like Holy Communion.
What the fuck is that? Annette, get that.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Thanks, Annette.
- Sure, Benny.
She's a good woman, Annette.
One broad, that's enough for anyone.
Pop, I'm going out
for a couple of hours, okay?
Merry Christmas. Donnie, take care.
Yeah, you, too. Take it easy.
My own fucking son's a junkie.
Can you believe it?
What are you gonna do?
Give him a smack in the mouth
once in a while.
I got bruises on my hands.
You don't know the worries I got, Donnie.
A woman like Annette, I can't do right
by her. I ain't got $3 in my pocket.
I put a bet on a horse, that horse don't do
what it's supposed to do,
like every fucking thing else in my life.
I got cancer of the prick.
My ex-wife lives in this building.
Can you believe it?
I run into her in the elevator.
I got to have three spritzers afterward
just to calm down after I see her.
What are you talking about,
cancer of the prick?
It's cancer of the prick.
You didn't know that?
I'm in the medical books for that.
I got this boat, too, this Bertram.
50-foot Bertram with twin Chryslers.
I had to get rid of it
for money I owe Sonny Red.
The vig alone is $3,000 a week.
- Who's that guy with him?
- Bruno? That's his son.
- I'd like to put a dent in that guy's head.
- No, you don't do that, Donnie.
- You don't touch him.
- I know. I'm saying I wish I could.
You wish?
A guy like you doesn't touch a made guy.
You know what I did yesterday?
I went in front of all the skippers.
That cocksucker Sonny Red, all of them.
I went on the record with you.
You know what that means?
I think I do.
You do? You ain't got no fucking idea,
my friend.
Nobody can touch you now. I'm your man.
Jesus Christ couldn't touch you,
because I represent you.
So keep your nose clean, be a good earner,
follow the rules, and who knows,
maybe one day when they open the books,
you get straightened out.
Become a wise guy.
A made guy. Come on, lift your glass.
I'd die with you, Donnie.
Anything happens, I'm responsible.
- All right?
- All right.
- Salute.
All right, Don.
- Thanks a lot. It was excellent.
- Could you spot me a couple hundred?
- Yeah, okay.
- I'll get it back to you. You got it here.
Here you go.
- I'll get back to you on this.
- Yeah.
- Believe me. Call me tomorrow.
- All right.
Hello.
- Look what the reindeer dragged in.
- Merry Christmas.
I was working. Nothing I could do.
Working?
- Who works Christmas Day, Joe?
- I do.
- Where's the kids?
- They couldn't wait anymore.
Well, that's nice.
Christmas, they can't wait up
for their father.
- Is that your way of saying you're sorry?
- You know I'm sorry.
I don't need to know.
The girls need to know.
Only be sure to introduce yourself.
They might think
you're the Fuller brush man.
- If you knew what I was doing today...
- I don't have an idea
- because you don't tell me, remember?
- Because it's for your own protection.
As if any of this is for me.
You're getting the checks, right?
- I'm getting the checks.
- Good. Then don't say it like it's nothing.
- 'Cause it's not nothing.
- It's not nothing, but it's not a husband.
A lot of women would disagree with you.
Is that what you do with all your time?
- Conduct polls with all your women?
- I'm not even gonna dignify that.
Seven days a week, I'm out there busting
my ass, and this is the shit I come home to.
You said it was gonna be three months.
It's going on two years.
How do you find anything in here?
You got cereal on three shelves.
You got cereals over here.
Put stuff away for once. It's my job.
- Quit my job?
- What about my job, Joe?
Christmas Day you don't show up,
so Mommy puts on the Santa suit.
Mommy hangs the lights.
Mommy carves the roast.
- You just leave it alone.
- Joseph.
- It would be easier if you tell me...
- Just give me a break.
...what goes on with these guys,
what you do.
Just shut up, please. Leave me alone.
Terry and Kerry are at my mother's.
Why don't you go pick them up?
Where's Sherry?
Sherry is with her boyfriend.
- What?
- She's at her boyfriend's.
- Since when does she have a boyfriend?
- She's 12, Joe.
- I didn't okay this, Maggie.
- Okay it? What do you think?
You can drop out of the sky like God
and bark orders?
I am the husband and the father!
I put food on that table!
- Undercover husband!
- What do I get for Christmas?
Empty fucking house!
I'm here.
I wanted to be alone with you.
Oh, God.
What happened to your 'stache?
The B, they made me shave it off.
Can you believe that?
- They didn't.
- Yeah.
It was the only thing I liked about this job.
- So, Sherry got a boyfriend?
- Yeah, she does.
Nice kid. He's so nice.
He's on the wrestling team.
I'll bet he's on the wrestling team.
Kerry's doing the catechism. So sweet.
And they're swimming.
Coach says he's never seen nothing like it.
There's a meet Saturday.
What am I gonna do? We'll see.
You know that I wouldn't do this to you
if I didn't think you could handle it.
I'm not worried about me, Joe.
All right, what's going on, kids?
Am I getting the silent treatment?
I'll make a bet with you.
I'll bet you $20
that you can't get through this entire meal
without saying three words.
All right?
You lose.
What did she say?
Girls, come here a second.
Come here, Terry, Kerry.
Come on. Sorry, sweetie.
Come on. Let's go see your sister.
Come on upstairs.
Let's just, let's read a book.
Do what you're told.
Left, it's Donnie. I'm checking in.
Yeah, that's what I said. I'm checking in.
No. I've been out all day. What's going on?
All right. So long.
You didn't see the paper?
How come you didn't see the paper?
Every morning you're reading the paper.
What were you reading this morning?
Look at this.
Can you believe this?
The boss gets whacked. The fucking boss.
You never hear from the boss
until he gets whacked
- and then your life gets turned around.
- Want to tell me where we're going?
- I got sent for.
- So what does that mean?
- You got sent for.
- What does that mean?
What do you think it means?
You don't wanna go? You want me
to turn around? I'll turn around.
What are you gonna do?
Take a left off the fucking bridge?
- Not here, I'm saying after the bridge.
- No, I gotta go.
You get sent for, you go. Sonny sent for me.
I'm sick of this.
- You got sent for by Sonny Red?
- Did I say Sonny Red?
Not Sonny Red. Sonny Black.
Donnie, what are you doing? Put the fuck...
Donnie, you wanna kill me
with that draft?
Left, Sonny Black is your friend.
What's the big deal?
Right. We're friendly.
Ain't the question, "friend."
The whole time Sonny Black's in the can,
the whole time...
He's got a family, he's got a mistress.
He's got a mistress for the mistress.
I watched out for them, all of them.
Me, I was the only one.
Nobody else gave a fuck.
Two hundred fazools, week in, week out.
So you took care of Sonny Black.
What are you worried about, then?
Sometimes I think, in that orphanage,
they dropped you on your fucking head.
How am I supposed to know
if you don't explain it?
You think I don't know
how a hit gets set up?
You think I don't know that?
You know, what I know.
How many times have I been
on the other end of that fucking phone?
- Twenty-six times.
- Great.
You just got done saying
you and Sonny Black are friends.
Donnie, I got sent for.
In our thing, you get sent for,
you go in alive, you come out dead
and it's your best friend that does it.
Anything should happen to me,
make sure Annette gets the car.
- Spritzer, Left?
- Later, maybe.
Look at this hand. This ain't a hand.
This is a fucking deformed Creature
from the Black Lagoon's claw I got here.
Hey, Left.
- You throwing that down?
- I don't know.
Gin.
Love on the rocks ain't no surprise
- Paulie, that ain't gin.
- Ain't no fucking surprise, neither.
It's gin.
What are you talking? You got two sevens.
I had three sevens.
- Paulie.
- Nicky, I had three sevens.
I know I had three sevens.
Don't start this shit now.
You know you had three sevens?
You don't have three sevens.
I had three sevens.
From now on, I'll deal out the cards,
you say "gin" whenever you feel like it.
Fucking booths. $200 in action
and what we have we got, five?
We're taking a beating again
this week, Sonny.
Let's go for a ride. I got a new car.
Can you believe the ride on this car?
I can't understand how they lost a war,
them Germans.
- I got a date out in Jersey tonight.
- Which broad is this?
The one from the calendar.
Miss Pennzoil Air Filter of 1978.
- What's he doing looking in the mirror?
- What're you doing over there, Left?
What's it look like I'm doing?
I'm checking my lipstick.
What would I do without you, Left?
What would I do?
What about you, Donnie?
What would you do?
Have to find yourself a new goombah,
wouldn't you?
That was something about the boss, huh?
We all gotta go sometime.
What are we doing here, Sonny?
We glomming something, or what?
- No.
- You, wait in the car.
- What?
- Watch the car.
Oh, fuck!
Shit!
Christ, I think I shit my pants. What is this?
He's supposed to go
to an animal trainer somewhere.
- Fuck him.
- Left, I think he likes you.
- Either that or he's just hungry.
- What's he got to do with me?
- Sonny, what is this?
- It's for you.
For me?
I know how you feel about animals.
It's a gift from me.
- It's for me?
- Yeah.
I got the power. Now you're under me.
- What do you mean, you got the power?
- Sonny got upped.
What, you got upped?
Rusty's gonna run the whole thing
from the can.
Sonny Red's got Little Italy. I got Brooklyn.
That's why you sent for me?
Yeah, why? What did you think,
you was gonna get whacked?
Lefty thought he was gonna get whacked.
Congratulations. Come here.
Good stuff.
Grab the pussy. Let's go.
What am I gonna do with this?
He thinks they smell fear.
I'm sick of this.
You and Sonny Black are friends.
I got told to shut my mouth
about Sonny Black.
How many times I stood up
to the boss himself, that cocksucker.
May he rest in peace.
You're gonna have to...
I got...
I'm gonna need 40 of those burgers.
Hold the onions.
Sonny Black, they make skipper.
I ain't a mutt.
Thirty years busting my hump. For what?
A lion.
Five hours ago, you thought
you was gonna get whacked.
- Donnie, did I say I was gonna get whacked?
- Not in so many words.
I don't understand you.
How many words does it take?
You're right. I misunderstood.
Thirty years I'm earning.
Any work to be done, call Lefty.
I never complained.
Twenty-six guys I clipped.
Do I get upped? No, they pass me by.
Sonny Black gets upped.
I don't get fucking upped.
Sonny was probably in
on whacking the boss.
Of course he was in on whacking the boss.
Whacking the boss.
Another thing I get left out of.
It's like one of those, whatchamacallit,
you know, bureaucracy.
What bureaucracy? Ain't no bureaucracy.
What you talking about, bureaucracy?
Where the fuck do you get your ideas?
Bureaucracy.
All I'm saying, I'm saying they
don't appreciate you, is what I'm saying.
Appreciate? They appreciate you?
- Come on, Left, I'm on your side.
- You're on my side?
You're on my side
because I say you're on my side.
Hey, look. Donnie!
Don't get
on your fucking high horse, Donnie.
I don't like that.
But tell you what.
Look at that.
I wish I had that boat again, that Bertram.
I wish I had that boat.
I'd get in my car with Annette,
I'd drive down to the pier
I'd get on that boat and I'd go.
I'd go.
East, west, north, south,
nobody'd ever find me.
Look at this thing. It's a fucking insult.
Let's go! Come on.
I gave it to him!
- Come on, Sonny!
- Jesus!
- No, Sonny! Please.
- He's got the money.
- He was a friend of mine.
- Broad daylight. I can't believe it.
What kind of people are gonna take
another man's property right off the street?
Forget about it.
The whole society's going down the tubes.
We never had this kind of a problem
when Nixon was around.
Nixon? Nixon? Forget about Nixon. Nixon.
We had respect all over the world.
We stood for something.
We had law and order in the street.
We had a little different story.
Too bad he wasn't Sicilian.
He was Sicilian.
You know, last night
I'm watching Roger Grimsby on the news
and those Ayatollah cockamamie people
are marching through the streets,
and they're whipping each other on the back
with whips.
Get out of here. I never heard of that.
- Donnie, am I right?
- What?
Fucking fanatics over there.
What're you asking him for?
What was it, a ventriloquist act?
I asked him a question...
But you're talking to me. You're asking him.
He reads... What do you mean,
why am I asking him?
Fuck if he reads. You ask me.
What're you asking him?
- Did you see it?
- I'm here. You're talking to me.
You're talking to me.
What are you talking to him for?
I talk to you, then I talk to him.
I talk to everybody.
All right, all right, all right.
Sonny, come here. Bobby.
Good seeing you.
Bobby, give Sonny a good table
and a bottle of your best, on me.
Why don't you get him a tailor
while you're at it?
- What do you say, Curley?
- How's it going?
This is Dean Blanford,
he's from Washington.
- Joe.
- Donnie.
Call me Donnie.
I don't want to get confused.
I know what you mean, pal.
Sometimes you get so busy,
- even I forget my own name.
- Yeah, is that right?
Is it hard to cash checks?
Dean's up from Washington.
Yeah, you said that part already.
What's next?
Now that the operation
is beginning to bear fruit
headquarters decided to transfer me
up to Sin City here.
- What for? You want to keep an eye on me?
- No.
To make sure you receive
the proper support.
- The proper support.
- And to make sure, in all the hubbub,
- there are no missed opportunities.
- Missed opportunities? Like what?
We have an agent in Miami,
goes by the name of Richie Gazzo.
- Miami?
- His operation is potentially very sweet.
Problem is, it's starting to languish
right now and needs jump-starting.
The Bureau would like you
to go down there
and see if you could interest
some of your mob friends.
- If you vouch for Richie Gazzo...
- I ain't vouching for nobody I don't know.
I was hoping
we'd get off on the right foot here.
What's the big deal?
You just go down and vouch for the guy.
Sit in the sun for a week.
- If I vouch for the guy, I could wind up dead.
- So could he.
You're not the only one out there
risking your life, bud.
I'll let you know.
I'll get back to you.
He'll let us know?
- Good evening. How many?
- Five.
My wife says it's very in, Japanese.
She read about it in Parade magazine.
Very big now.
Have seat. Take off shoes. Please.
- What kind of food is this?
- It's fish.
- Please, take off shoes.
- Are you kidding me?
Take off your pants. What's that?
I'm afraid it's necessary.
- It's Japanese tradition.
- Is that right?
- Forget about it, I ain't doing it.
- I'm afraid it's necessary.
Forget it, I ain't taking my fucking shoes off.
- Hey, Donnie.
- What?
When in Rome...
Nicky, who won the fucking war?
- War? What war?
- We did. Do you want to fight it again?
- Take off your shoes.
- I ain't gonna do it.
- Take your shoes off.
- I ain't taking my shoes off.
I want to eat sometime tonight.
Take off your shoes,
or I'm gonna chop off your fucking feet.
What do you want me to do?
You want me to take orders
from a fucking Jap?
I grew up in an orphanage because
my old man was killed in Okinawa.
You think I'm taking my shoes off
for this fucking prick?
No, I ain't doing it.
I'm afraid it's necessary.
Listen, my friend's not gonna
take off his shoes there, Mr. Moto.
I'm afraid it's necessary.
Neither are the rest of us.
So give us a table before I smack you.
You must take off your shoes.
- You like shoes, you fuck?
- Get him down!
You like shoes?
Let me get in there.
Slant-eyed motherfucker!
- Come on. Let's go.
- Son of a bitch!
- Watch him, Donnie!
- Stupid fuck!
Kick the shit out of him, Donnie! Kick him!
Use those fucking boots!
Don't you move, you fuck.
Don't you fucking move.
You like shoes, you fuck?
Slant-eyed motherfucker!
- Come on. Let's go.
- Son of a bitch!
Watch him, Donnie!
Stupid fuck!
Kick the shit out of him, Donnie! Kick him!
Mind your own business.
Just go home! Go home!
Go home, you miserable bitch.
What you doing?
Sonny's ready to start.
He's not done yet. You want him to piss
all over the fucking floor?
...not sharing the cigars.
Up the block, they sell for $50 a box.
We could sell them for $25.
You give two or three of those to a broad,
she'll do anything you want.
Give three Quaaludes to Brenda.
Maybe she'd cook.
I doubt it.
I got a guy that's in the middle
of this load of Sergio Valentes.
A dime on the vig.
- So, what do you got on the street?
- $100,000.
That should be $250,000
by the end of the year.
I can get these real cheap
and I got a guy who can move them.
Will you fucking stop that?
How else am I supposed to open this?
Open sesame!
A score's a score.
Boss, look what I got here. It's 100 pairs.
Sonny Red's got $1 million a month
with his trucks in Jersey.
What do I get?
Steak knives and parking meters.
We ought to hijack an oil tanker.
There's a lot of money in oil.
You know something?
There's a guy I know down in Florida.
He says it's wide open down there.
- Where in Florida?
- Florida. The beach.
The whole economy's moving down there.
They call it the Sun Belt.
The economy's got to be good
for us to make any real money.
You don't think they got
their own wise guys in Florida?
Florida and Arizona
because of the energy crisis.
I heard a whole conversation
on the Long John Neville Show.
Problem up here, you got 3,000 wise guys
all chasing the same fucking nickel.
You're from down there, Florida, Donnie?
Lot of parking meters down in Florida.
You guys think this is funny?
I'm the skipper now. I gotta answer!
$50,000 a month, I kick up to Rusty.
Every month!
One day, I'm gonna die.
I'm gonna be here in this same room
with all these same fucking guys
talking about the same fucking scams
that never amount to nothing!
That's how I'll know
that I've been sent to fucking hell.
Joe, give these humps another drink.
It's all they're good for.
I tell you right now, we better start earning
or somebody's gonna get clipped.
Why did you inject that, Donnie,
with Florida?
What are you talking about?
I didn't inject nothing.
You injected that. Don't tell me no.
I know you. You don't say nothing
unless there's a reason for it.
Now, who is this fucking guy in Florida?
Nobody. He's a guy I knew
when I lived down there, that's all.
You vouch for this guy?
Hey, come on. That was bullshitting around.
Bullshitting around? What, you think
Sonny Black is just bullshitting around?
What do I know? I don't... You know...
You think he wasn't?
Yeah, well... Listen to me, Donnie,
I don't know what to swear on.
My dead father, my mother who I love,
my children.
I swear to you, Donnie, something
is going on you don't know about.
- I was making conversation with the guy.
- Mr. Smart Conversation,
you tell me what happens
if Sonny Black decides
he wants to go to Florida?
Who said he's going to go to Florida?
Donnie, don't think
you can pull the wool over my eyes.
I see you siding up to Sonny Black.
With my eyes, I'm looking at you.
You're doing it.
- Come on.
- I ain't siding up to Sonny Black.
He goes to Florida, you're responsible.
And I'm responsible
because I represent you.
Come on. I was just bullshitting around.
You think you can trust Sonny Black.
You can't trust Sonny Black.
Sonny Black is one big, fat,
fucking snake in the...
- Grass. Snake in the grass.
- You can't say that now.
Sonny Black is a skipper.
You don't open your mouth about him.
Lefty, this fucking guy Richie calls me up.
He says,
"I'm getting hassled
by a couple of half-assed wise guys."
He's looking for a partner
to give him a little peace of mind.
- He's got this nightclub to run down there.
- A nightclub?
Got a singles bar. It's near the beach.
I got two grenades in my house.
I'd blow up all Mulberry Street
before I'd give you up. You understand?
I don't know what I would do
if you did something wrong.
You understand? I'd die with you.
Come on!
Come on, Four!
Four!
- Shit.
- That was in.
Bullshit. Knocked me so far...
Don't push me!
I'll break your fucking head.
- Shit! He lives!
- What the fuck are you...
Fuck!
Jesus Christ.
Half hour.
- Where is this guy?
- I don't know, Left.
- Is that him?
- Yeah, that's him.
Don, you brought the cavalry.
Richie Gazzo.
- How you doing?
I'm late!
You guys got a chance
to work on your suntans out here.
Kings Court. Where every man is a king.
Wait until you get a load
of the banquet room. You're gonna plotz.
Ask him why this place
is such a fucking dump.
He wants to know
why it's such a dump, Richie.
I had to shut the doors.
The way these bums had their hands
in my pockets.
You know, $200 for this, $300 for that.
I got a wife who does that,
you know what I mean?
Ask him to leave, Donnie.
- Richie, step outside, take a look at the car.
- Sure. Great.
What kind of a man has a Malvole?
He won't provide for his own wife.
- I'm telling you, this guy's all right.
- You vouch for him?
- When I knew him before, he was all right...
- You vouch for the guy?
I'm just making an introduction. You got
to make the decision about the joint.
This would be something, you know,
if we had my own lounge down here,
me and you.
- You know?
- What about Sonny?
Donnie, don't tell me what to do, Donnie.
I'm asking a question.
Donnie, Sonny's down here for a vacation.
He ain't once gotten out
of that chaise longue.
He lies there like he's in fucking traction.
Yeah, I know, but he did mention
that he might wanna get something going.
Imagine Sonny Black operating down here.
The way he is?
Come on. Sonny Black belongs in Brooklyn.
I guess if everything worked out
we could send a few fazools up there, no?
Thirty years I'm busting my hump.
What do I got?
Even a dog
gets a warm piece of the sidewalk.
I ought to show something for what I did.
- You know what I mean?
- Definitely.
This ain't New York down here.
New York with the politics,
all the old beefs and the grudges.
Down here, a guy like me could sit down
with the boss.
You know what I'm saying?
Get out from under, be a free agent again.
I'm telling you, Donnie, nothing but right.
Lefty wants to ask Santo Trafficante
for permission to operate down here.
- You got to give me a boat.
- We can't afford that kind of money.
- What kind of a boat?
- I don't know. Like a 70-footer.
- I want to take him out for the day.
- You're talking $6,000 a day here, Joe.
Santo Trafficante is the boss of Florida.
- He sits on the Commission. Did you know?
- I knew that.
- A 70-foot boat?
- It's up to 80, actually.
We just picked up Lefty on a wiretap
talking to one of Trafficante's guys.
A few things to go over
to make a loan-sharking indictment.
This is important!
Ninety, actually.
I did what you asked.
I came here and vouched for this guy.
So what, I'm gonna take Santo Trafficante
out in a rubber ducky or what?
We're gonna have to
wash your mouth out, bud.
Does Sally Paintglass report to Nicky
or Nicky Cigars?
- Nicky Glasses.
- Nicky Glasses?
As I was saying,
we've got to fold Sonny into the RICO...
- I need a boat for this fucking sit-down!
- I'm a Mormon, mister. Now clean it up.
Joe, I think you got a malfunction
on your tape recorder.
Get me a fucking boat, would you? What?
I'm not getting anything here.
I'm worried. He's getting strung-out.
We're getting what we want. Fuck him.
There it is.
Just moving behind, nice and slow.
Why don't you count it, my friend?
Go ahead.
It's all there. No bullshit.
We're bueno?
Pleasure doing business
with you caballeros.
Oh, Columbia, the gem of the ocean
The home of the brave and the free
- Fuck.
- Fuck!
What are you doing? You want to
throw me in the pool? You got the balls?
He hasn't made a pick yet.
Forget those dogs.
Hey, you know,
if you took my blood pressure right now,
it'd be down 100%.
Rusty's locked up in the can
with his fucking sinuses.
He finds out you're down in Florida...
I don't punch a clock for Rusty.
Live your life like a man down here.
Forget about it, Sonny. By tomorrow,
you're gonna be crying
you miss the New York bread.
New York bread is like cake.
Hey, two weeks you're wearing
the same fucking shirt.
What does that mean?
I'm not in a big hurry
to go back to New York.
Yeah, don't worry about it. One more day,
that fucking shirt's gonna go back
to New York on its own.
That's why we don't get service in this joint.
They see you in that fucking shirt, they say,
"There's Joe Faccia Di Culo," in that shirt.
That's enough.
"That's enough?"
What does that mean, "that's enough"?
Look at him, look at him. He's mad.
- Hey, Donnie, let's go for a walk.
- Where?
- Come on, I'm gonna get a candy bar.
- All right.
Look at him, that was once yellow,
that shirt.
What are we supposed to call him now?
Sonny Florida.
Watch out, you're gonna put him
on the warpath again.
Yeah.
That shirt. That's the shirt the barber
gives you to put over your shirt.
I want to know what you're up to.
- What do you mean?
- Yesterday.
Last night?
What were you doing last night?
No, I'm saying, when yesterday?
What time yesterday?
Come here. Don't mess around with me.
Yesterday fucking afternoon.
Nothing.
Why has Lefty got such a hard-on
to send me back to New York?
Oh, come on, Sonny.
That guy's busting your balls down there.
I wanna know.
I wanna know what you got
going on down here.
I don't understand, Sonny.
You wanna know about every
half-assed scam that'll amount to nothing?
That's right.
Look.
I don't mean any disrespect.
I mean, I know you're a skipper
and I'm a nobody,
but I can't do that to Lefty.
Listen to me, you cocksucker,
I'll eat your fucking balls for breakfast.
You understand me?
Every fucking one of you.
This is life or death.
Not a fucking game, Donnie.
This is my say-so. Now, you tell me.
I can't do it, Sonny.
How about if I fucking whack you
right here and now?
Do what you have to do, Sonny.
I can't do that to Lefty.
- Mommy, I need some help.
- Hello?
- Hey.
- It's too tight.
- Here, sweetie.
- I'm in Florida.
- What are you doing in Florida?
I don't know. I'm hunting for turtles.
What do you think I'm doing in Florida?
Honey, I'm working.
It's 12 degrees here.
Excuse me, you're wearing this coat!
Young lady, you are wearing this coat.
- Bitch.
- What did you call me?
- Is everything all right?
- What did you...
What if I said no, Joe?
Would it make any difference?
- I guess not.
- So don't ask me. Come on, stand up.
"John Wayne dead. Nation mourns."
How can John Wayne die?
The fucking Indians got him.
"Old-fashioned family man.
Ruled with an iron hand."
Look at that.
Let me talk to Kerry.
I want to talk about the Communion.
My God, Joe. She doesn't want to do it.
What do you mean? She ain't got no choice.
- You are wearing this coat!
- Put her on the phone, Maggie.
I don't know when I can call again.
Does she know not to bite the wafer?
I don't know. She's acting out or something.
- I'll be back next week.
- Thank you.
Maggie, I promise I'll get back
for her Communion.
- Yours doesn't look any better.
- Don't start it with your sister.
- Joe, I got to go.
- What?
I love you. Shit.
- Who's that on the phone? Richie?
- No. What did Sonny say?
- You told Sonny about the club?
- No, I thought you did.
- Just shut up about it. Call Richie.
- All right.
Big guy like Santo Trafficante,
he's been around
since the Mustache Petes.
You gotta respect the man.
- Donnie, you get that boat yet?
- No, I'm working on it.
Don't tell me no. You got to get that boat.
I reached out already.
His man says, "Lefty, he loves boats."
I told him a 100-foot boat.
I'm on the clothesline now.
I told you, I'm working on it.
- Don't disappoint me again, please.
- Again? Since when did I disappoint you?
Forget about it. What's this?
Look at that. Same thing we call each other.
Friend of mine, friend of ours. Good.
But there's the double meaning. You get it?
- Know what I mean?
- Yeah.
- A boss appreciates a thing like that.
- The irony of it.
- Yeah, irony.
Forget about it. Put a beaner inside here,
then he knows these are men of men.
You see, if I work out the strategy right,
you got to hold up your end now.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Yeah, I know.
You got to hold up your end now.
You know what I'm saying?
How much is this?
Donnie, you got something on you?
- What are you doing there?
- How about here's $5?
- You're doing an amazing job, you know.
- What?
- I mean, we all think so.
- Yeah. Absolutely.
For crying out loud. Fuck.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
What's "forget about it"? What is that?
"Forget about it" is like
if you agree with someone.
Like, "Raquel Welch is one great
piece of ass." "Forget about it."
But then, if you disagree, like,
"A Lincoln is better than a Cadillac?
"Forget about it."
It's also like if something
is the greatest thing in the world.
Like "Minghia, those peppers!
Forget about it!" You know?
It's also like saying, "Go to hell," too.
Like, "Paulie, you got a one-inch pecker."
And Paulie says, "Forget about it."
Forget about it. "Paulie, forget about it."
Sometimes it just means, forget about it.
All right. Thank you very much. I got it.
Let me tell you something.
I don't get this boat for Lefty...
- Forget about it?
- Fucking forget about it.
You know that sting operation?
What do you call it?
Where the agents dress up like Arabs
and try to bribe congressmen?
- They got a boat down here.
- What?
- Abscam.
- That's right. It's Abscam.
Yeah? Could we get it?
Forget about it.
Son of a bitch!
Come on, son of...
Fucking Donnie.
Hey, Lefty,
you're not gonna fucking believe this.
- You think this is some joke, huh?
- What?
- You think this is funny, huh?
- What are you talking about?
It's fucking cold. Why is it so cold in here?
Hey, Donnie. Listen to me, Donnie.
I know you know, all right?
And I know you know I know you know.
- Right.
What the fuck are you talking about?
I'm telling you, I'm freezing
to my fucking death, Donnie.
Yeah, fucking Greenland in here.
There's no knob. Where's the knob?
Thank you.
Well, did you call the maintenance guy?
They gotta have a...
Maintenance. I'm not gonna call
a maintenance guy. What are you, crazy?
Who knows a maintenance guy comes in,
what if he's an agent? Come on.
Come on, he's not an agent.
He's a fucking janitor.
Janitor, come on.
I don't want him touching it.
Put his hands on it. Who knows what
he puts in the goddamn air-conditioner.
Here, look at this. Here, look, look.
I got it up to 120, here. Come on.
Ain't no fucking...
I'm not gonna have anyone going in here.
You know something?
That's a fucking practical joke.
- That's what that is.
- It's a joke?
- Yeah.
- Where's the joke? I don't see the joke.
Come on, you know Sonny's
sense of humor. It's Sonny fucking around.
- You think this is Sonny?
- Yeah.
- Sonny?
Sonny did this to me?
This is not Sonny Black, my friend.
No. This is you, Donnie.
You fucking cocksucker, it's you!
Whoa, you don't fucking call me that, Lefty.
- Don't call you what?
- Don't you fucking call me cocksucker.
Cocksucker. I'll call you anything I want.
I'll call you cocksucker.
Yeah, I'll call you cocksucker.
I'll call you motherfucker!
Yeah, you're a fucking cocksucker.
- You calling me a cocksucker?
- Yeah, you like that?
- I'm a what?
- Cocksucker.
- I'm a cocksucker?
- You're a cocksucker.
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna kill me over a fucking draft?
- Yeah.
- Let me tell you something.
You'd better fucking kill me.
Because you don't kill me tonight,
I'm gonna come in here,
I'm gonna chop you up and then...
I'll sneak in here and fucking kill you.
Oh yeah, you don't call me cocksucker.
Here.
Oh, yeah, go ahead.
- Cocksucker.
- Go ahead. Take it back.
- Kill me.
- Take it back, Donnie.
Fuck you, I'm getting my own room.
I'll see you tomorrow.
You're not gonna see me tomorrow,
for your information.
I got news for you, Donnie.
You won't see me tomorrow.
Tomorrow is Mother's Day,
and wise guys don't work on Mother's Day!
You're a cocksucker.
Go ahead!
No!
Give me a break! No!
Are you trying to get me killed
with that fucking suit?
Fucking car. That purple, fucking car.
Don't say the word "plotz."
You understand?
Get in the back.
Wait a minute. I'll be there.
Mr. Trafficante, this is Lefty,
a friend of ours.
I don't know what to say.
To me, this is like a great moment in my life.
It's like meeting Mickey Mantle.
That's the boat I arranged for you,
Mr. Trafficante.
It's got everything.
Got a full bar, any kind of music you want.
You want to make a telephone,
it's got telephones.
- Any questions, you ask me.
- Where's Sonny Black?
- Sonny Black?
- Yeah.
Everybody, out. Come on, baby.
- It's beautiful!
- What did I tell you?
You brought the family.
Hey, Paul, what do you know?
- Nice boat.
- What do you say, Paulie?
Where's Gilligan?
Now, that's what I call a boat.
Yeah, I would be... Yeah.
Here.
Sure, you can operate here.
You got to show a little respect.
Hey! Over here.
I don't even want to look at you.
- You know what the bow is?
- What did I do now?
You stabbed the wrong guy
in the back, my friend.
What are you talking about?
You think I said something to Sonny?
Go to the bow. I'm gonna stay in the stern.
Go to the bow. Stay there.
I'm so disgusted with you, you know that?
- You just said it.
- Just so you know.
- How you doing?
- That Trafficante is something else.
- Is that right? Is he a good old guy?
- Forget about it.
That motherfucker had this all to himself
for 50 fucking years
and it's still a cow town.
This could be like Vegas down here.
Forget about Sonny Red
and his trucks in Jersey.
This is all I want. Florida.
Tell you something. Sonny Red
is freezing his nuts off right now.
That's for sure.
All I need is the start-up money from Rusty
and then we all get rich.
Are we heading
back to New York pretty soon?
Not you. I want you to represent me
down here, Donnie.
I want you to be my man in Florida.
Get that club going. You know, Kings Court.
You didn't think I knew about that, did you?
I think I'll send the lion down here with you.
Keep that big pussy in the parking lot.
You know, Sonny, I really appreciate
the offer and everything,
but I got a lot of things going on
in New York.
- I'd like to keep them...
- Lefty's a dynamite guy. No doubt about it.
He looked after me when I was in the can.
That's something I don't forget,
something that I will never ever forget.
He's a stand-up guy.
He really cares about you, too.
Yeah, I know he does.
The problem is that
you think that he's helping you,
but he's hurting you.
He gets those two or three wines in him...
You know what I'm saying.
I don't want to be
stepping on nobody's toes.
- If it wasn't for Left, I...
- That's it. Look.
You belong to me now.
That's it.
Mr. Trafficante's leaving.
- You believe that?
- Ulcers, Christ, they're killing me.
Come here.
Santo, this is Donnie.
- He's a friend of ours.
- Hi, Donnie. Nice to meet you.
- This is Donnie.
- Hi, how you doing?
- Give my best to Joe, will you?
- I will.
Snowed in. Can you believe him?
Right. His daughter's First Communion,
and he gets stuck at an airport.
That's for his own protection.
I'll see you later. Okay?
- I hate flying.
- I know you do. Be safe.
Oh, sweetheart.
Honey.
Your father is so proud of you.
I'm going upstairs.
God damn it, Joe.
The number you have dialed
has been changed.
The new number is unpublished
at the subscriber's request.
Hey, Left, get us checked in over there,
will you?
- Stick around. I'm going to get a paper.
- All right.
Jesus, Joe. That's Hollman, US Attorney,
coming at us.
The guy on the right.
Christ, Joe, what are we going to do?
Why don't you just shut the fuck up?
I'll take care of it.
Anything goes wrong down there,
you have their people call your people
in New York, understand?
I don't want to come down here
and iron anything out.
- You got your plane tickets?
- Joe Pistone.
Remember me? Southern District...
What kind of fucking shit...
- What are you doing?
- Grabbed my cock.
What the fuck!
Shut up. He's working.
Keep your mouth shut.
Fucking degenerate bastard.
What a sick fuck. Grabbed my cock.
I want that club up and running.
I don't care how long it takes.
Here comes a fucking cop.
Get the hell out of here.
Have a safe trip.
You have the tickets and everything?
Listen to me.
Get on the phone.
Get me on the next flight back. Understand?
Don't call me Joe again.
I'll cut your fucking throat, understand?
You piece of shit.
- Daddy?
- Hi, baby.
- Who made you?
- God made me.
- Why did God make you?
- God made me to show his goodness
to make me happy with him in heaven.
- Where is God?
- God is everywhere.
Sweet dreams, angel.
I want a divorce.
He comes home at all hours of the night
without announcing when, why, or where
he's been for the last three months.
And you know what he does?
He rearranges the cabinets.
He remakes the bed.
He vacuums the entire house.
Do you know another man that vacuums?
It's abnormal.
- It's abnormal behavior.
- Well, you know,
changing the phone number and
not telling your husband is pretty normal.
- I don't exist, you don't exist.
- So now I know how it feels.
No, now I know how you feel.
I'll tell you something. It felt good.
Now I do know how it feels
to be so in control.
Now I know how it feels to be strong.
- You love control, don't you?
- Oh, my God.
Please, Joe, just listen.
Otherwise you just play out
the old pathology.
Maggie, you were saying Joe leaves.
Yes, he leaves.
He leaves me with the house
and the kids and the bills,
but not a husband.
I want my husband.
What do you think you're running from?
- I ain't running from nothing.
- "I ain't running from nothing."
You hear yourself?
The man I married was a college man.
Being the distancer
forces Maggie into the role of the pursuer.
This gives you a feeling of power.
Simultaneously, you resent Maggie
- for fulfilling her intimacy needs...
- I'm an undercover agent for the FBI, Doctor.
You and your Mafia faggots
can go screw each other.
I'm not gonna do it anymore.
I really hope that you can help her out
because obviously she's very sick.
You can see that.
Obviously, I'm the sick one.
- You.
- Now,
Monday, Wednesday, and Friday
are Joe's intimacy days.
Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday
are Maggie's.
Now, on your day,
you make an intimacy request.
"Rub my back," or
"I have a problem with the kids.
Could you help me out?"
You sit around in
your safe little fucking house
with your safe little fucking station wagon,
and your safe little friends.
You dream up the next $100 head fuck.
- "Will you rub my back?"
- You're an animal, do you know that?
- Just get in the fucking car.
- Do you know that?
You know what my intimacy request is
for that guy?
It's very intimate.
He can take the bill he's gonna send me
and shove it up his ass.
You want to know why we went to him?
I was hoping he could come up with
one good reason for me not to leave you
because I don't have one anymore.
What? You gonna leave me?
You gonna leave me, Maggie?
You don't leave me.
- Hello.
- Hey, Annette.
Donnie.
- What's the matter?
- Where are you?
I'm in New York. I had to come back. Why?
- It's Tommy.
- Why, what's going on? What happened?
Can you give your sister
some vegetables, honey? Thank you.
Not with your fingers, sweetie.
What else do you need?
We did fractions with Miss Greenberg today
in class, you know?
Did you? Fractions?
- I got my test back and I got a 95.
- Of course you did.
- What's going on?
- Donnie, what are you doing here?
You belong in Florida.
I checked in with Annette
and she said something...
- You called her from Florida?
- I was up here. I had a few things to care of.
You got to go back. Come on.
What happened to him?
Is he gonna be all right?
Do I know?
They got 12 fucking diplomas on the wall,
and they can't tell you a fucking thing.
Forget about it.
Tommy gets out of this fucking Bellevue,
he's going right back to fucking up.
- What did he do? Did he overdose?
- That ain't the question.
A plastic pipe in his mouth.
About five million tubes.
They have a machine breathing for him.
Where's the fucking doctor?
You want me to go talk to this guy for you?
Talk to the doctor?
You gonna break his legs?
I'm saying, you want me to do something?
I'm here.
I want you to go back down to Florida.
You belong to Sonny now. Believe me.
I came here to be with you.
I want to help you out.
- You're my man. I'm here for you.
- I don't want you here, Donnie.
You and Tommy is both
peas in a fucking pod. You don't listen.
You got your own ideas.
You do what you want to do
up on your high horses. Everything's a joke.
You go to La Guardia and you get back.
- Get back to Florida. Get on a plane.
- I ain't going.
- Forget about it.
- Go on!
I'm gonna stay here with you.
You want to kick the shit out of me?
I'm gonna be right here. All right?
Twenty eight years.
You can read it on his birth certificate.
Bellevue Hospital. Now he's back, in there.
And I'm out here,
worried to my fucking death.
And he's asleep in there,
same as 28 years ago
with the same expression.
He's made no progress.
He ain't got no fucking respect.
He's my son.
His heart stopped like a watch.
That's what the doctor said.
Just like a watch.
They had to wind it back up.
Who knows? Maybe next time,
they can't.
He's gonna be all right. He'll be all right.
I love you, Donnie.
Hey, Joe.
What?
You know the U.S. Government?
Yeah.
The U.S. Government you swore an oath
and dedicated your life to?
Yeah. Why?
We got audited.
Hey, let's make a toast to Sonny, huh?
To Sonny and our new Florida business.
Hey, Sonny, how you doing?
- What's going on, Red?
- You know the boys.
I hear you was in Florida.
Yeah, it's nice down there. Take the sun.
You got friends down there?
Everybody's nice down there.
The people, they're very friendly down there.
Nice color.
Thank you.
I'm not talking to the Bureau.
There is no Bureau.
There's a bunch of assholes
and the I.R.S. Is another bunch of assholes.
So what I'm asking you to do
is to place a phone call, asshole to asshole.
- Please calm down.
- You want me to calm down?
You tell this fucking auditor
that I'm coming to D.C.
And I'm gonna whip the shit out of him
with his calculator, you understand?
Let's face it, bud,
they don't audit you for...
Okay, I'm gonna hang up now.
Wait, I'm a GS-15. You can't...
Fucking cocksucker.
All right!
How you doing, Nicky?
Hey, Sonny!
Look at this place. It's unbelievable.
- Beautiful.
- I feel lucky tonight.
Look at it. Opening night.
This place is a goddamn palace,
for Christ's sake.
Terrific, Sonny. I love it.
- It's a fucking palace!
- How you doing?
How you doing? Having fun?
Let's try another one. Again.
I like it.
I like it bigtime.
- I need a steak, medium rare.
- Couple bowls of chili, extra hot.
Okay, Donnie, this is the take.
- Put this bag someplace safe.
- All right.
Chicken taco.
Just turn real slow.
Is there a problem, Officer?
- What's your name, boy?
- Donnie Brasco. What's yours?
What are all you New York guineas
doing down here?
Your missus invited us.
Gentlemen, we're running
a charity event here.
- We have a permit.
- You got a permit for the lion?
Break it up! Break it up!
You fucking pigs!
I guess you didn't ever think
of paying these guys off, did you?
Where the hell am I gonna get money to go
bribing cops? Nobody authorized that.
You know how fucking embarrassed I am?
The old man's people down here.
A year now, I got to be in my house
with the shades drawn.
Where's that bag?
They got it. They got everything.
That's Rusty's money.
- Sonny, I'm sorry...
- Shut up.
You shut up. Sit down.
Shut the fuck up.
Like this, I got to go back to New York.
Make this right with Rusty.
Face that cocksucker Sonny Red.
You know, I got to say something.
Usually the cops are so fucking dumb.
It takes them three months
just to get wind something's going on.
Then they got to go get a warrant.
They got to go through them pictures.
What are they?
- Surveillance.
- They go to surveillance.
Three months taking pictures.
All this time,
how do these cops know so much?
- We just opened the fucking doors.
- What are you saying?
There's got to be a snitch here.
All right.
So there's a snitch.
We find him. We cut his prick off.
Leave it in his mouth.
Leave him on the street.
Okay?
What are you,
a silent partner all of a sudden?
- Get me the fuck out of here!
- Hey, knock it off in there!
Shut up! Fuck you!
Keep it up, boy,
I'll send you out of here in a box.
- Did you bust it up good?
- Yeah, we busted it up.
He's out of business. You understand?
Yeah, I'm listening.
That punk is finished down here. That's it.
That's great. I can't believe it.
- All right, look, I'll talk to you later.
- Okay.
Give me some of that cheese
with that salami, please?
- He busted up the club.
- Good.
- Take this taste out of my mouth.
- There you go.
Now he has to answer for what happened.
You gonna send for him?
He sits down with us.
Bing-bada-boom, it's done.
The whole fucking crew. All of them.
I'll dust off the guns.
Napkins and tablecloths, $500 scoot.
$500 scoot?
Down in Florida, it's $500 an hour.
You like it down there so much,
why don't you go buy some oranges?
- What do you got there, Bullfrog?
- Dime on the vig.
I'm doing the best I can, Sonny.
What do you got, Nicky?
I got a guy boosted 30 tickets
to Chaka Khan at the Garden.
What about Florida?
I thought we weren't supposed to talk
about Florida.
So you never got nothing going on?
No. Nothing ever panned out for me, Sonny.
I couldn't catch a break.
- You never got nothing going on?
- What did I just say?
Sonny.
Paulie, I got a truckload of razor blades.
What the fuck am I gonna do
with razor blades?
You know how many razor blades
fit in a truck?
I got a guy on the inside,
works in a warehouse.
Has the art collection of the Shah of Iran.
A sit-down where?
Yeah.
That was Sonny Red's guy.
Wants to have a sit-down in Little Italy.
I got sent for.
Donnie, come on.
Paulie, we'll take your car.
That cocksucker Sonny Red,
he rubbed my nose in Florida
because of a fucking rat!
Forget about it.
Donnie, you ride up front.
You know what to do
when you find that rat, right, Left?
Could be I found him already.
So where we headed, Sonny? Little Italy?
Our guy says they got a little stop
to make first. You know what I mean?
Let's go.
Where are you going? Wait in the car.
All right. Come on.
We still got to get downtown.
- How long is this gonna take?
- I got them in the drain in the laundry room.
- The.22s?
- Bruno said you want the 9mm.
- Meanwhile, where the fuck is he?
- Yeah.
In bed with some broad with more hair
on her lip than he's got on his head.
- He's your kid.
- Don't remind me. Come on.
You think that's funny?
I don't think that's so funny.
All right.
- You don't want to listen.
- I don't think that's funny.
- A son should respect his father, capisce?
- Answer me. You think that's funny?
Shit, the bulb is out. Watch your step, guys.
Big fucking surprise from a fucking spider.
Yeah, nothing like the surprise
Sonny Black is gonna get.
- You can say that again.
- Put one right here.
He'll never know what hit him.
- Goddamn right.
- He's never gonna know what hit him.
- I'll blow his brains right there.
- Jesus! No!
Bruno!
Okay, come on! Get him off!
- Sonny!
- Get him off of me!
Take my arm. Take my hand.
Jesus Christ.
Paulie, go get Donnie.
What's going on?
- Is everything all right?
- What?
Is everything all right?
Get out.
Get down there.
The meek want to inherit the earth,
they're gonna have to get in fucking line.
Look what I found.
Them or us.
Nicky, you got Big Trin.
- Trin? I'll get a hernia.
- Shut the fuck up.
Donnie's gonna help you.
Come on, Donnie.
Help me fillet this fat fuck.
All right, all right. Come on.
We got work to do.
There was a rat in Florida, Donnie.
Nicky wasn't a rat.
You don't mention his name, all right?
That's what we said.
We don't mention his name.
Yeah. Tell yourself
whatever you have to, Left.
I'm not telling myself.
- You was down there. You have eyes.
- Twenty years you know a guy.
You fuck him, whack him out,
just like that? Over a lounge?
- That's beautiful.
- The man held out.
He held out on a coke deal.
What does one thing
got to do with the other?
He could have got whacked out just for that,
for your information.
- There wasn't a rat in Florida.
- There was a rat.
There was not a rat in Florida.
Richie fucked up paying off the cops.
What do you mean Richie fucked up?
That's why the club got busted.
Richie didn't pay off the fucking cops.
Nicky didn't have anything to do with it.
You don't mention his name.
That's the rules.
- Fuck the rules.
- That's the rules, Donnie.
Say his name.
- Come on.
- Say his name.
Come on. Nicky.
Say Nicky.
You can't say his name
because you know that I'm fucking right.
Say it! Say Nicky!
Say his fucking name!
Nicky was a rat because
Sonny Black says he was a rat.
Who the fuck am I?
Who am I?
I'm a spoke on a wheel.
And so was he, and so are you.
Quit riding the fucking brake.
You the boss. You the boss, Boss.
- He looks good, huh?
- Sonny Black.
Congratulations, Sonny!
Boss!
- Sonny. Congratulations, Sonny.
- Congratulations.
- Oh, God!
- No, everything's okay, Maggie.
Yeah? If everything's okay,
what are you doing here?
Mind if we come inside, Mrs. Pistone?
I'm not sure. That depends.
At that point, he became hysterical.
As if the Bureau were responsible
for this audit.
- Whereas, well, self-evidently...
- Did you ever think of giving him a raise?
The only way to give him a raise
would be to upgrade him.
Yeah.
GS-14 is a supervisor, Maggie.
So he's a supervisor.
But he's undercover.
He's not supervising anyone.
The point is,
that's the last time we heard from him.
Standard procedure is that
he is to check in with us every day.
Maybe he might miss a day or two
here and there, but...
- It was three weeks ago.
- I want you to tell me
where my husband is.
I demand that
you tell me where my husband is!
- We can't tell you because we don't know.
- If he gets in touch with you,
you have got to try to talk sense into him.
Mrs. Pistone, please help us here.
- You want me to help you out?
- Yes.
You want me to help out the FBI
that used my husband and sucked him dry,
so that a bunch of supervisors
could become SACs
and prosecutors could become judges
and assholes like you
could get promoted to GS-16?
Maggie, come on. You don't mean that.
Let me tell you something.
I hope he crossed over.
Mrs. Pistone, there is a war going on
in the Mafia family where Joe is undercover.
Three leaders of a rival faction
have been murdered.
He's right in the line of fire.
Not because he's one of us,
because he's one of them.
Who he's with and who he's close to,
they're all the top dogs now.
It's just not a problem we anticipated.
We have got to pull him out.
You have got to talk to him.
He'll listen to you.
You think so?
He was here a week ago.
He snuck into the house after I was asleep.
And he didn't even wake me up,
didn't even say hello to me.
He came to get his sport coat.
- Let's take a walk.
- All right.
Left, what are we doing?
We're gonna walk and talk.
We got too many eyes around here.
Here it is, Donnie.
Sonny Red's kid, Bruno. He's disappeared.
Now, as long as he's on the loose,
ain't none of us safe.
- Right?
- Yeah.
You got no idea where the guy is?
He's got a nickel-a-day coke habit.
He's gonna turn up somewhere.
Anyway, we got the contract.
Now, this thing gets done right,
when the books open up,
I'm proposing you for membership.
- You know what that means?
- Yeah.
Yeah? What?
- It means I can't fuck it up.
- You read my mind.
- You read my mind. You can't fuck it up.
- No, I won't fuck it up.
You're gonna be a made guy, Donnie.
Capisce?
Yeah. All right.
Come on. Let's go back inside!
- Left.
- Yeah, what?
What? I'm freezing here!
You know that boat you used to have,
that Bertram?
- Boat? What about it?
- Yeah, boat.
How much is it? A boat like that?
How much? What do you think?
You could get a sports fisherman
for maybe 300, used.
Why are you asking me
about boats, Donnie?
I was just wondering.
I was curious, you know.
- You're curious about boats?
- Yeah.
It's 10 degrees out here. I'm freezing.
You're asking me about boats,
after what we just said?
You losing your marbles on me or what?
- No, I'm all right.
- So don't ask questions like that.
- That's crazy, okay?
- Yeah.
You hit this cocksucker,
and you leave him in the street. Come on.
- You want to tell me what's going on?
- Nothing. Go back to bed.
I'm looking for something, all right?
I'll be right in.
That's not gonna work anymore.
Where is it?
There's $300,000 in that bag.
How do you know what's in that bag?
I counted it.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You counted it?
What do you mean, you counted it?
It's none of your business.
Not my business? It's in my house.
Who'd ever believe it wasn't my business?
I want that fucking bag, Maggie.
FBI men do not walk around
with $300,000 in a bag.
- Joe, you could go to jail for this.
- Shut the fuck up. Nobody's going to jail.
Did you think about your children
for a second?
- You have no idea what you're talking about.
- I don't?
- The bag belongs to somebody else.
- Does it? Who?
- Whose bag is it, Joe?
- One of my best... Just some fucked-up guy.
- A fucked-up guy needs $300,000?
- Yeah, right. Where's the goddamn bag?
You're becoming like them, you know that?
Did you ever once ask yourself
how I make it through my days?
I pretend I'm a widow
with medals and scrapbooks and memories.
I pretend you're dead.
That's how my life makes sense to me.
Just go away. Stay away.
God, why do you hate me
when I love you so much?
You think I hate you?
I don't hate you.
This job is eating me alive.
I can't breathe anymore.
And if I come out, this guy Lefty dies.
They're gonna kill him,
because he vouched for me,
because he stood up for me.
I live with that every day.
That's the same thing as if I put the bullet
in his head myself, you understand?
I spent all these years
trying to be the good guy.
You know, the man in the white fucking hat.
For what?
For nothing.
I'm not becoming like them, Maggie.
I am them.
Left? Donnie.
Donnie? Where you been?
Yeah, look...
- I gotta see you.
- You're right, you gotta see me.
- We found Sonny Red's kid.
- Bruno?
Yeah, he's on a boat on Staten Island.
- I'll pick you up.
- We don't have time, Donnie.
- You meet me there.
- Okay.
Bruno's here. He's down the end of the pier.
We'll wait here a minute
while he has his drink.
Let him get a little sleepy.
- I'm getting a little sleepy myself.
- How's his boat?
- The boat?
- Yeah.
Nice.
Forget about it. One thing I know is boats.
I'd like to pop him, throw him in the water,
take the fucking boat.
Remember you said a couple of times
how if you had that Bertram again,
you'd drive down to the pier with Annette
and just go?
Remember you said that? North, south,
east, west, nobody'd ever find you.
That was before.
Don't remind me about that now.
- Yeah, but I'm just saying...
- I don't want to think about that.
Did you mean it?
Mean it?
Who am I? Rockefeller?
I'm gonna go buy a boat?
- I'm saying, what if, Left?
- What if.
What if...
I mean, I got a couple of things
going on the side. A couple of jewel things.
Maybe I could get that kind of money
for you.
You're gonna find money
for me to get a boat?
- Maybe.
- Yeah?
That would be real generous of you, Donnie.
What if I could hand you
a bagful of money right now?
You know what I'm saying?
You could leave this life.
You said it yourself, if you don't move up,
every day you're looking
over your shoulder.
You don't know what's gonna happen.
- Donnie, listen to me.
- No more bullshit.
Get out of this life is what I'm saying, Left.
- I'm gonna show you something, Donnie.
- What?
I want you to look at it very carefully.
And then I want you to think very carefully
about what you say to me.
That's a Federal boat, Donnie.
- I really don't think that's the same boat...
- That's the same boat.
It's got the name on it, The Left Hand.
It's like my name.
That's that Abscam boat.
You think I knew that was a Federal boat?
You think I'm a fucking rat?
How many times I have you
into my own house?
Twice a week, at least. Why?
There it is, "At least."
- I cook for you.
- Yeah.
If ever I had any money, I'd give you.
I never had any money. But if ever I had...
$100 in my pocket, I gave you $50, right?
- Yeah, you did.
- If you're a rat...
If you're a rat, then I'm the biggest
fucking mutt in the history of the Mafia.
Even if this thing is a Federal boat, Left,
they scam all these other people.
They didn't scam us.
You know what I'm saying?
We went. We had a great party.
We walked away from it.
How do you know
that we walked away from it?
We're sitting here, right?
So they tried to outsmart us,
but we outsmarted them.
We beat the agents.
You gotta believe me.
Okay.
Let's go do this work.
Get this over with.
Two in back of the ear.
Like pushing a button.
Bing, bing. That's it.
- Yeah.
- Don't freeze up.
- You gonna freeze up?
- No.
- A lot of guys freeze up.
- I'll be all right.
Did I say you was a rat?
I can't believe you brought that up.
Come on. Forget about it, Left.
I never said you was a rat.
I'm your best friend.
Come on. Let's go do this thing.
Come on, Donnie. Come on.
Gotta do it, Don.
Come on, Don.
Now!
Come on.
FBI! Freeze!
Shit!
Don't say nothing, Donnie.
Don't say nothing to them.
Don't tell them nothing, Donnie!
Donnie, don't say nothing!
- It's over.
- Fuck you, it's not over. I'm not coming out.
There'll be a mouthpiece there in 24 hours!
Donnie, you're all right!
- Shit!
- It's over, man!
Don't say nothing to them, Donnie!
It's over, Joe.
You've known this guy as Donnie Brasco.
That's not his real name.
Truth is, he's been an FBI agent all along.
You can contact me here if you want to talk.
Can you believe those fucking guys?
There's no way Donnie's an agent.
It's a nice fucking bluff, huh?
That boat was a set-up.
They set the boat up.
See? Then we think Donnie's a rat.
Almost had me going,
if you didn't know Donnie.
Right, if I didn't know Donnie.
Hyenas kill many young cheetahs
and more than one could overpower
the mother and turn on the cubs.
Yeah?
Yeah. All right.
All right. Okay.
Was that for me?
No. It was a guy I got to go see.
- So late?
- What am I gonna do?
Who knows with these people?
- Honey, don't wait up for me tonight.
- No?
I don't know how long I'm gonna be.
And listen to me.
If Donnie calls
tell him
if it was going to be anyone,
I'm glad it was him, all right?
Look how beautiful you look.
- Goodbye.
- Bye, Ben.
Excuse me, Mrs. Pistone.
Have a seat.
- "To Special Agent Joseph..."
- Thirty seconds, sir.
"Joseph D. Pistone, in grateful recognition
for meritorious service."
Allow me to present you with this medal
and this check for $500.
Hold the check up.
- Congratulations again, son.
- Congratulations, Joe.
- Ma'am, take good care of him.
- I will.
Mrs. Pistone.
It's over.
Come on, honey. Come home.