- Allora, come stai, Leone?
- Bene
Okay, okay. Let's talk business.
This fat bastard is trying to move
in on Morizio's business.
And you know, Morizio
is a reasonable guy.
He just wants
a little conversation.
But this guy,
he don't wanna hear about it.
Maybe he'll listen to you.
He comes to town every Tuesday.
Are you free Tuesday?
Yeah, I'm free Tuesday.
Nice to see you again,
Mr Jones.
Remember, neatness counts.
You got one half hour.
One hour.
Yeah, what?
It's Tonto, downstairs.
There's a guy who wants to talk to you.
What's he look like?
Serious.
- Tell him I'm coming up.
- He's coming up.
Somebody's coming up.
Somebody serious.
Mickey, open your eyes.
We got company.
Come on.
Stop, stop, man!
Tell the driver to wait for us
out back, and hurry up.
- Hey sweetie, what's going on?
- Don't worry, baby.
It's cool. Take a nap.
Oh, my God.
Those fuckers blocked
both the exits.
Check the terrace!
- 911 emergency.
- I need help.
- Somebody's trying to kill me.
- Alright, just stay on the line.
I'll just be off a moment.
Sir, I'm gonna connect you
with an officer.
Detective Jefferson.
May I help you?
I'll call you back.
Relax, man. I got half of Bolivia
sitting in them suitcases over here.
Ain't been cut yet. Go ahead, take it.
It's yours.
Dial this number.
I'll talk to you later,
sweetie, okay?
Bye.
- Hello?
- It's Morizio. Remember me?
- I see you're back in town.
- Yeah. No, I mean, no.
Just for today.
Aha, so it's safe to say
today's your last day in town...
and we'll never see
your fat fucking face again.
Yeah. Right.
Let me speak
to our mutual friend.
He wants to talk to you.
Make sure he understands,
and let him go.
Do you understand?
- So say it.
- I understand.
Good.
Jesus.
Hola! Qu tal amigo? Two milk as usual, eh?
Why did you hide the cigarette?
This building's full of rats.
I didn't want my old man to find out.
Got enough problems.
What happened?
I fell off my bike.
Don't tell my dad
about the cigarette, okay?
- Why are you doing this to us?
- I don't know-
People got memory problems these days.
It must be the sun.
- Know when to come out of the sun.
- I don't know how it happened.
What's my job? I'm just a holder.
I hold the stuff you give to me.
I don't look at it, I don't touch it.
- I don't even know how to cut it.
- Try to follow me, alright?
In June, we gave you the dope.
It tests 100 percent pure.
Now it's July, we pick up the dope,
and it tests 90 percent pure.
Somewhere between June and July,
ten percent turned to cut!
I don't know. It's none of my business.
You give me the stuff, I hold it.
- That's all I know.
- You know I'm trying to help you out here...
but if you're gonna be
a hard-ass about it...
I gotta disturb him.
When he's into his music,
he hates being disturbed.
I'm telling you the truth.
I hope so, because he's got a talent
for sniffing out a lie.
It's scary.
It's almost like a sixth sense.
Are you gonna change your tune
or I gotta bust into his?
I'm telling you the truth.
All right.
Stan.
I'm sorry.
He said he didn't cut the dope.
Of course he didn't.
Just do me a favor.
Find out who did by tomorrow.
Noon.
Malky, wait.
I didn't cut your shit.
Find out yourself!
What are you doing out here?
Get inside and do your homework.
- I did it already.
- Get inside and help your sister...
clean up the goddamn house!
And stop smoking cigarettes!
One!
Two. Take a deep breath in.
Take a deep breath out.
- Take a deep breath. Inhale.
- Time's up. My turn.
Change the channel,
and I'll smash your face.
Ready for the legs.
And down.
Sorry, sweetheart.
Squeeze. Release.
Good morning.
Hi, honey.
Sweetheart, turn that down.
Mama's got a headache.
- She took my turn.
- She wants to watch goddamn cartoons!
It wouldn't hurt her
to move her ass.
I'm not the one
with a fat ass around here.
Two and up.
Can someone who's doing nothing
all day but watching cartoons...
move a little ass
and go get some food?
- Legs. Beautiful.
- I dare you to say that again.
- Margie, I think I screwed up.
- It wouldn't be the first time.
You always come up
with something, right?
I think I went too far this time.
You're going too far right now.
I'm gonna be late for work.
How about working
at home today?
Really feel it.
That's it, stomach in.
- One-
- Now it's my turn!
Shit!
She's gonna hit me!
- Daddy, she's-
- Shit! Shut the goddamn door!
Please don't shoot!
Fucking bitch.
- Megatron!
- Firm up the whole body.
When you use the Quadra-Step,
your thigh muscles-
- Can somebody answer the phone?
- I'm busy!
- Hello?
- This is Marguerite McCallister...
headmistress at the Spencer School
in Wildwood, New Jersey.
Is Mr. or Mrs. Lando home?
This is she.
Mrs. Lando, when your husband
enrolled Mathilda at Spencer...
he told us she had problems
As you know, we pride ourselves
on turning troubled girls...
into healthy,
productive young women.
But if they are not here,
there is very little we can do.
Mathilda left school
without permission nearly two weeks ago.
I know your husband paid tuition
in advance for a year...
but if you will refer to the rules
and regulations manual we sent you...
you will see that unless there is
a valid excuse for prolonged absence...
your tuition will be forfeit.
She's dead.
Tell that fucking kid to do
a little work around here!
Clean up!
I'm tired of this fucking mess.
Hurry up!
Why am I feeling
When things could look black
That nothing
could possibly go wrong
This has been
A most unusual day
Love has made me see things
In a different way
Is life always this hard,
or is it just when you're a kid?
Always like this.
Keep it.
I'm going grocery shopping.
You want some milk?
One quart or two?
It's two, right?
I like these calm little moments
before the storm.
It reminds me of Beethoven.
Can you hear it?
It's like when you put your head
to the grass...
you can hear it growing.
You can hear the insects.
- Do you like Beethoven?
- Couldn't really say.
I'm gonna play you some.
Daddy!
You better stay here.
We said noon.
I've got one minute past.
You don't like Beethoven.
You don't know
what you're missing.
Overtures like that
get my juices flowing.
So powerful.
But after his openings,
to be honest...
he does tend to get
a little fucking boring.
That's why I stopped!
Toss the apartment.
You're a Mozart fan.
I love him too.
I love Mozart!
He was Austrian, you know.
But for this kind of work,
he's a little bit light.
So I tend to go
for the heavier guys.
- Cool.
- Dude, what the fuck are you doing?
Man,
keep your bombacut mouth shut.
Check out Brahms.
He's good too.
- What the fuck do you know about music?
- Man, knock it off!
- You check the mattress?
- Nope.
Wow.
Oh! Fuck!
He's dead.
Jesus. Look what you did.
Stan, you all right?
What are you doing?
- He's dead!
- But he ruined my suit.
Yeah, I know,
but he's dead.
He's a piece of meat.
Forget about it. Calm down.
I'm calm.
Stay there, all right?
Benny!
Jesus fucking Christ, Benny!
It's Malky and Stan!
Take it easy, all right?
Come on.
Come on,
let's get a cigarette.
Benny, we're coming out!
Benny, don't fire!
Get in there!
Jesus fucking Christ, Benny!
You wear something new and-
Got a light?
Take it easy.
What's happening out there?
It's all right, ma'am.
D. E. A. Police.
Leave that poor family alone.
- Everything's all right. Just calm down.
- I am calm. I'm calm.
Why don't you
leave them alone?
He said go back inside.
Stan, I think it's better
if we go inside.
Benny, turn that kitchen upside down!
Find that shit!
Willy Blood, look what you did!
You killed a 4-year-old kid!
Did you really
have to do that?
Please open the door.
Benny,
there are three kids here.
I think Stan killed this girl.
Willy, that asshole,
shot the little boy.
The third one's missing.
Find her.
Shit. We missed
the little girl, man.
I'm gonna find the fucking super
in this goddamn building.
- Don't you recognize me?
- Me, Grimlock. Know you!
Shit.
- Yo! I found it!
- Bingo!
- They found it.
- I know.
There it is.
There's cops outside.
We better go.
It's the cops outside.
We better go. You stay here.
What do I say?
Tell them...
we were doing our job.
- What's your name?
- Mathilda.
- Sorry about your father.
- If somebody didn't do it...
one day or another,
I would have probably done it myself.
Your mother, she-
She's not my mother.
My sister wanted to lose some weight.
Bet she never looked better.
She's not even my real sister.
Just a half sister.
Not a good half at that.
If you couldn't stand them,
why are you crying?
They killed my brother.
What the hell did he do?
He was four years old.
He never used to cry.
He just used to sit
next to me and cuddle.
I was more of a mother to him
than that goddamned pig ever was.
Don't talk like that about pigs.
They're usually nicer than people.
But they smell like shit.
Not true.
As a matter of fact,
right now I have one in my kitchen...
that's very clean...
- and smells very nice.
- You don't have a pig in your kitchen.
Yes, I do.
I was just in there,
and I didn't see any goddamned pig.
Don't move.
I'll get him.
Piggy, where are you?
There you are.
Hi, Mathilda.
Hi, piggy.
How are you today?
I've seen better days.
- What's your name?
- Leon.
Cute name.
You have anyone to go to,
any family anyplace else?
I'm gonna get some more milk.
Holy shit.
Don't touch that, please.
What do you do for a living?
Cleaner.
You're a hit man?
Cool.
- Do you clean anyone?
- No women, no kids. That's the rules.
How much would it cost to hire someone
to get those dirt bags...
who killed my brother?
- Five grand a head.
- Wow.
How about I work for you...
and in exchange,
you teach me how to clean?
What do you think?
I'll clean your place.
I'll do the shopping.
I'll even wash your clothes.
- Is it a deal?
- No, it's not a deal.
What do you want me to do?
I've got no place to go.
You've had a rough day today.
Go to sleep,
and we'll see tomorrow.
You've been really great
with me, Leon...
and it's not always like that.
You know?
Good night.
You sleep well?
Good.
- After breakfast you gotta take off.
- Where to?
Not my problem.
Read it.
You don't know how to read.
I'm learning, but I've had
a lot of work lately...
so I'm a little behind.
What's it say?
I've decided what to do with my life.
I wanna be a cleaner.
You wanna be a cleaner.
Here.
Take it. It's a good-bye gift.
Go clean, but not with me.
- I work alone. Understand?
- Bonnie and Clyde didn't work alone.
Thelma and Louise didn't work alone.
They were the best.
Mathilda, why are you
doing this to me?
I've been nothing
but nice to you.
I saved your life yesterday,
right outside the door.
Right.
Now you're responsible for it.
If you saved my life,
you must've saved it for a good reason.
If you throw me out now,
it's like you never opened your door...
like you let me die
right there in front of it.
But you did open it. So-
If you don't help me,
I'll die tonight. I can feel it.
I don't wanna die tonight.
You're just a little girl.
Don't take it badly,
but I don't think you could do it.
I'm sorry.
How's that?
Don't you ever do that again
or I'll break your head.
You got that?
I don't work like that.
It's not professional.
There is rules.
And stop saying okay
all the time!
Good.
You expect to use that
in this hotel?
Mister, I have to use it...
because I have an audition
at Juilliard next month...
and I have to practice.
Okay, but not after 10:00.
- I promise.
- All right.
I'll put you
at the end of the hall...
so that you
don't disturb anyone.
Fill those out, please.
Daddy, can I please fill them out?
I like to check in to hotels.
Thanks, Pop.
I'll bring these back in a minute.
Fourth floor!
Thanks, mister!
You're lucky to have a little girl
that's interested in things.
I have a kid, 17,
does nothing all day long.
Can I leave my plant here
while I take my stuff upstairs?
Of course.
I'm putting in a name of a girl
in my class who makes me sick.
If things get hot,
she'll take the heat.
There. Finished.
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
- Eighteen?
- Want to see my license?
No. You just look a little young.
Thanks.
Leon, I want you to teach me
how to be like you.
I want to be strong and smart
like you.
I know I'm not
strong enough yet...
but I could learn the basics,
the theory.
What do you think?
Just the theory.
I need this, Leon.
I need time
to get my head together.
Yeah, and I need...
a drink.
Don't move.
I'll go get one.
When you told me
to get this baby out for you...
I thought my hearing was going.
I says to myself, Leon's a pro.
Nobody uses that except beginners
I like to stay in shape.
Sure.
Always stay on top of it.
It's like me. I gotta know
where everything is all the time.
I never leave this place,
except to go from here to there.
Change ain't good, Leon.
You know?
Check it.
- Make sure it's the right thing.
- I trust you.
One thing's got nothing to do
with the other. Remember that.
I will.
The rifle is the first weapon
you learn how to use...
because it lets you
keep your distance from the client.
The closer you get
to being a pro...
the closer you can get
to the client.
The knife, for example,
is the last thing you learn.
Position.
Never take it off until the last minute.
It reflects light.
They can see you coming
from a mile away.
And always dress down.
Never brighter
than the floor, okay?
Let's practice now.
It's the best way to learn.
Who should I hit?
Whoever.
I'll be with you in a second.
Give me a few minutes. Thank you.
You guys get lost.
I don't want to see you.
- Is everyone in position?
- This has to look natural.
- No women, no kids. Right?
- Right.
Jogger in the yellow and orange?
Keep calm.
Don't take your eyes off him.
Breathe easy.
Watch his movement.
Pretend you're running with him.
Try to feel his next movement.
Take a deep breath.
Hold it.
Now.
Oh, my God!
- I'm all right. I'm fine.
- Get down! Where'd that come from?
One shot. Not bad, huh?
- Who the hell fired?
- I just can't breathe! Get off me.
Can we try
with real bullets now?
Not today.
Let's pack up.
Like that.
- No, thanks.
- No discussion.
It seemed...
to Socrates-
I'll do it.
Leon, all we do is work.
We need a break.
Let's play a game.
- What kind of game?
- I have this great game.
It makes you think and helps your
memory. It's exactly what you need.
Like a virgin
Touched for the very first time
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, Mr. President
I don't know.
Moustache.
I'm singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
- What a beaut-
- Gene Kelly?
Good.
Your turn now.
Okay, pilgrim.
Clint Eastwood?
- I don't know. I give up.
- John Wayne.
I was just about to say that.
I swear. It's amazing.
Leon, really brilliant.
Amazing.
- You love your plant, don't you?
- It's my best friend.
Always happy.
No questions.
It's like me, you see.
No roots.
If you really love it, you should
plant it in a park so it can have roots.
You should be watering me
if you want me to grow.
You're right.
Wait!
They gotta be jumping out of the plate.
They gotta be alive.
It's been a long time, Leon.
I missed you.
- And you missed some nice jobs too.
- Been training.
Training's good,
but don't overdo it.
Training don't pay
as good as working, Leon.
Tony...
all the money I make,
that you keep for me-
You need some money?
Just curious.
I've been working
a long time...
and I haven't done anything
with my money.
I thought maybe
someday I could use it.
You met a woman.
You gotta be careful
with women.
Remember when you arrived
in this country?
When I took you in, you were still wet
behind the fucking ears...
and, already, you were in deep shit
because of a woman.
- Don't forget that, Leon.
- I wish I could sometimes.
You know, about my money-
Maybe I could give...
a little...
to someone.
You know, to help out.
It's your money. I'm just
holding it for you, like a bank.
Except better than a bank
because banks always get knocked off.
No one knocks off old Tony.
Besides, with a bank...
there's always tons of forms
and all that shit.
But old Tony, nothing to read,
nothing to write. It's all in his head.
I know how to read now.
That's good, Leon.
Your money's here.
Whenever you want it,
you just ask me.
- Here's a grand. Come on.
- It's okay. I don't need it.
- Take it. Have some fun. Go ahead.
- Thank you.
All right.
Now let's talk business.
Don't move.
I'll go get the file.
Manolo, a glass of milk
for my friend Leon here.
Listen, Mathilda,
you gotta be careful.
You can't just speak
to any guy off the street.
Leon, get a grip.
What's the big fucking deal?
I was just smoking a butt
while I was waiting.
I want you to stop cursing.
You can't talk to people
like that all the time.
I want you to make an effort
to talk nice.
And I want you to stop smoking.
It will kill you.
Stay away from him.
He looks like a weirdo.
I'll be out in five minutes.
Stand where I can see you.
Leon, I think I'm kinda
falling in love with you.
It's the first time for me,
you know.
How do you know it's love
if you've never been in love before?
'Cause I feel it.
Where?
In my stomach.
It's all warm.
I always had a knot there,
and now it's gone.
Mathilda, I'm glad you
don't have a stomachache anymore.
I don't think
it means anything.
I'm late for work.
I hate being late for work.
How's the practicing going?
- How are we today, miss?
- A little sick of practicing.
I understand.
But you're doing all right.
I haven't received
any complaints.
I put a cloth over the strings
to lessen the noise.
That's very smart.
- Not everyone loves music.
- I know.
What does your father do?
- He's a composer.
- That's wonderful.
Except he's not really my father.
He's my lover.
Think I'll go for a walk.
- What are you doing Saturday night?
- What about dinner?
- Where you going?
- Visiting friends at 6J.
Go ahead.
What about Saturday?
- About 8:00?
- I don't know.
You got plans?
Meet you here?
We know you're a busy man.
We'll make this short.
If you'll just take us step-by-step
through exactly what happened.
The guy was here.
He went for his gun.
Bang, we shot him.
- Where exactly were the kids?
- I don't know!
They should have been at school,
don't you think?
Your statement said
you were the first man in.
- Didn't you see any kids?
- The door was broken.
What happened?
Did you follow the procedure?
I lost a good man here.
What the fuck do you want with me?
Cooperation.
I haven't got time
for this Mickey Mouse bullshit!
You want cooperation?
Come up in my office, room 4602.
Kids should be at school.
Come on, that's my ball!
Give that back.
Where you going?
Damn! Where you going, man?
That's my ball!
Follow the blue car.
You want me to blast the music
and go through the lights?
No, drive slowly.
Take the hundred bucks,
and shut the fuck up.
I do not want to fight you,
but you leave me no choice.
Boy, you just gave me
a great idea!
- I mean a big one!
- Welcome back to E! News Daily...
our 30-minute look at the latest
in entertainment news.
I'm Bianca Ferrar.
It's for you.
A present.
Do you want me to open it?
I'll open it.
How do you like it?
Nice, eh?
Mr. McGuffin?
Can I have a word with you?
Here. It's for a contract.
Twenty grand, right?
His name is Norman Stansfield,
and he's in room 4602...
in the D. E. A. building,
26 Federal Plaza.
- I'm not taking it.
- Why not?
- It's too heavy.
- Well.
Will you rent me your gear
for the day?
I never lend out my gear.
But...
you still have your gun.
Use it.
Just do me a favor.
Don't shoot out the window.
Why are you so mean to me?
Wildly killing people
you don't give a shit about...
but you won't get the bastards
that killed my whole family?
Revenge is not good
once you're done. Believe.
- It's better to forget.
- Forget?
After I've seen the outline
of my brother's body on the floor...
you expect me to forget?
I want to kill
those sons of bitches.
Blow their fucking heads off.
Nothing's the same
after you've killed someone.
Your life is changed forever.
You have to sleep with one eye open
for the rest of your life.
I don't give a shit
about sleeping, Leon.
I want love...
or death.
That's it.
I want death.
Get off my case, Mathilda.
I'm tired of your games.
There's this really great game, Leon.
Makes people nicer.
Starts them thinking.
The kind of game you love.
If I win...
you keep me with you...
for life.
And if you lose?
Go shopping alone, like before.
You're gonna lose, Mathilda.
There's a round in the chamber.
I heard it.
So what?
What's it to you if I end up
with a bullet in the head?
Nothing.
I hope you're not lying, Leon.
I really hope that deep down inside
there's no love in you.
Because if there is...
just a little bit of love in there
for me...
I think that in a few minutes
you'll regret you never said anything.
I love you, Leon.
I win.
I took a hit.
I need a hand now.
I know she's young,
but she learns fast.
Kids need to be shaped
into something, right?
I know. I taught you that.
But ain't there an age limit?
She's 18.
Really?
How about something to drink, Tony?
Sure. Manolo, glass of milk
for Leon.
Nice tattoo.
Manolo, make that two.
- What's that for?
- Can't afford to catch cold.
First you find out
where the chain is.
You can't see it,
but you can feel it. Here.
- I'll ring, you start talking.
- What do I say?
Whatever you want.
- Yes?
- Hi.
It's Susan.
I'm sorry. You must have
the wrong door, little girl.
I don't know any Susan.
Move back a little.
I can't see anything.
The light's out.
It's all dark out here.
- Mister, I'm scared.
- Okay.
What the fuck are you doing?
Open up.
If it leaves your mouth,
I'll pull the trigger, capisce?
Here's okay.
Let it go.
I said, Let it go.
Move. Move over.
Easy. Easy.
Easy. Careful.
You want me-
Go ahead. Your turn.
Help me.
Please don't beat me.
Sir?
Sir, it's not my dope.
Sir, look I-
A little left, please.
Before- Ple-
Now, the security shot.
No, the second goes
higher on the chest.
Aim for the heart and lungs.
There. Right there.
You see?
The first shot takes him
out of order.
- The second finishes him off.
- What are you fucking doing?
Never in the face.
If they can't recognize the client,
you don't get paid.
You could take out anybody
and said you did the job.
- Got it?
- Got it. Never in the face.
- Now you can put the tools away.
- What are you fucking doing?
What the fuck is going on?
Hey, mister!
What are you fucking-
You see, when you use
the silencer a lot...
you have to put
a piece of cloth here...
because it gets very hot
and could burn it inside.
A damp, black cloth is the best.
What you doing?
We said no women, no kids.
Who do you think this is gonna kill,
junkies and monkeys?
Now it's clean.
Let's get out of here.
I thought we don't have
the right to drink.
I know, but we're making
an exception for your first time.
Well, if we're making exceptions
for a job well-done...
how about a kiss,
like in the movies?
Yes.
What you doing?
- I'm going to kiss you.
- I want you to stop, please.
Come on. Just a kiss.
Stop. Everyone is watching us.
Go sit down.
Enjoy.
- You don't believe me, do you?
- How's that?
- When I say I'm in love with you.
- Mathilda, please drop it.
- Just change the subject, okay?
- Okay. Sorry.
So, how old were you
when you made your first hit?
Nineteen.
Beat you.
- What you doing?
- Can't afford to catch a cold.
- There's no doorbell.
- So knock on the door.
- Yes?
- Hi.
I'm looking
for Mr. Reuben's apartment...
but it's all dark out here
in the hall, and I'm lost.
Just a second.
You want more? Come on.
Show your fucking face.
You think you're going to
get me that easily?
When it's tough like this,
you know it's gonna be ugly.
Better make it quick or else
we'll be all day listening to his crap.
Asshole! Come on, show me
your fucking face, faggot!
- Come on, gum trick.
- Hey.
What about the ring trick?
You know that one?
Ring trick? Come on, asshole.
I'm waiting.
Show it to me, motherfucker.
That's the ring trick.
Mario, go back to the barbershop.
We'll finish later.
Leon, what's up?
All done already?
Nicer than people, eh?
I told you that.
You got a problem?
Get the chair. Sit down.
I was thinking.
If something happens
to me someday-
Hey, Leon,
nothing's gonna happen to you.
You're indestructible. Bullets
slide off you. You play with 'em.
Tony, I thought about my money.
You remember the girl
who came here the other day?
Her name is Mathilda.
If anything happens to me...
I'd like you...
to give her...
my money.
You can count on me, Leon.
Thank you, Tony.
I won't be long.
- Did I do something wrong?
- No.
This one is too big.
Yeah, and I only get the leftovers,
is that it?
Mathilda, since I met you...
everything's been different.
So I just need some time alone.
You need some time
to grow up a little.
I finished growing up, Leon.
I just get older.
For me it's the opposite.
I'm old enough.
I need time to grow up.
Shit.
Come on! Hustle!
- Good shot.
- Come on.
You're new, aren't you?
Fifth floor, right?
- You can't sit here like that.
- Really, why not?
Nothing's free.
Like a parking meter.
When you stop, you pay.
It's the law.
- Only on T. V.
- What'd you say?
- Forget it. How much is your meter?
- Ten dollars...
a month.
Got change?
Don't worry about it.
We'll do ten for twelve.
I'll pay now for
the rest of the year.
Okay, a year.
Does paying rent here mean
I have to put up with you guys?
So go play somewhere else.
I need to think.
Stand up.
Don't you like your job?
Food.
- Where you going?
- Special delivery, room 4602.
Sign here.
Come here.
- Have a nice weekend, girls.
- Thanks.
I'm gonna go
to the restroom.
Special delivery?
Let me guess.
Chinese?
Thai, maybe?
I've got it.
Italian food.
What's your name, angel?
I want you to put the sack
on the floor.
Good.
Now I want you to tell me everything
you know about Italian food.
Don't forget the name of the chef
who fixed it for me.
Nobody sent me.
I do business for myself.
So this is something...
personal, is it?
What filthy piece of shit...
did I do now?
You killed my brother.
I'm sorry.
And you wanna join him?
It's always the same thing.
It's when you start to become
really afraid of death...
that you learn
to appreciate life.
Do you like life,
sweetheart?
That's good.
Because I take no pleasure...
in taking a life...
if it's from a person
who doesn't care about it.
Stan, I've been looking
all over for you.
- I checked upstairs-
- What? I'm busy.
It's Malky, man.
He's dead.
Malky was making a buy for us
from the Chinaman.
But they got nothing
to do with it.
They told me this guy came
from the outside. He was a pro.
He was fast.
He fucking came out of nowhere.
Boom, shoots the Chinaman dead
in two seconds.
Easy, man.
I'm a cop.
Then turns around,
says something to Malky like-
No women, no kids.
I think
it was something personal.
Death is whimsical today.
Blood, do you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you, Stan.
Just chill out, man.
Would you take her
up to my office?
All right.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Leon, my love.
I know where to find the guys
who killed my brother.
Their boss is Norman Stansfield.
He's in the D. E. A. building, room 4602.
I'm gonna do them myself.
If something goes wrong,
I left you 20 grand on the table.
It's for a contract.
Five grand ahead, right?
I know I'll feel better
after I do this.
I love you.
Wait. I won't be long.
I can't park in front like this.
It's a federal building!
He's gonna do the same exact thing
that I said.
A nine millie.
Bullets.
Another nine millie.
What'd you plan to do
with all these guns?
Maybe she was planning on
taking out the whole building.
Holy shit!
What's this? Lunch.
Careful, Blood,
might be poisoned.
There's no anchovies on this.
Is that what you call I won't be long?
I been here for ten minutes.
I did my best.
Do you like it?
Yes.
So say it.
I like it.
Not thirsty?
You know, a girl's first time
is very important.
It determines the rest
of her life sexually.
I read that once in one
of my sister's magazines.
My girlfriends told me
they hated their first experience.
That's because
they didn't love the guys.
They just did it to show off.
Afterwards, they started liking it,
like cigarettes.
Will I like it the first time?
Mathilda, no.
Why not?
I just can't.
- You love someone else?
- No.
I mean-
There was someone a long time ago.
Before I came to the States.
Her father didn't want her
to see me.
She was from
a very respectable family.
Mine was...
you know...
not so respectable.
Her dad went nuts every time
she'd take off to see me.
She still snuck off
to see you, right?
Right.
See, nothing can stop love, Leon.
He killed her.
One shot through the head.
They kept him in jail for two days,
and they let him go free.
They said it was an accident.
So...
one night I...
waited for him.
Five hundred feet with a lens.
He also had an accident.
The same night I took a boat
and came here...
to meet up with my father
who was working for Tony.
I was 19.
Since then I've never left
the city, and...
I've never had another girlfriend.
You see, Mathilda...
I wouldn't be a good lover.
Okay.
Would you do me one favor?
What?
I'm sick of watching you
sleep on your chair.
We're gonna share the bed.
I don't think it's a good idea.
It's okay.
Put your legs up on the bed.
Yeah. That's nice.
Put your head down.
It's okay. Relax.
Good night, Leon.
Good night.
I want a piece of cake first!
Manolo, take the kids
in the kitchen.
I have a lot of respect
for your business, Tony.
When you've killed for us
in the past...
we've always been satisfied.
That's exactly why today
is going to be very hard for me.
I hope you'll excuse my mood.
My man was killed
right here on your turf.
The Chinks tell me
that the hit man...
was kind of the Italian type.
So we figured that Tony
might know something.
Wait. There's more.
You're gonna love this.
A few hours later, a little 12-year-old
girl comes into my office...
armed to the teeth, with the firm
intention of sending me to the morgue.
Do you know who came and got her
right there in my building?
The very same...
Italian hit man.
I'm dying to meet him.
Relax. Everything's fine.
Sleep well?
I never really sleep.
Got one eye open always.
Yeah, I forgot.
I never saw someone with one eye open
snore so much.
- I snore?
- Like a baby.
I'm gonna get some milk for breakfast.
I won't be long.
Don't forget the code
when you come back.
Two knocks, then one,
and two knocks again. Right?
Right.
Hola seor! Ring these up.
I'm gonna go get some milk.
From here on out,
you don't make a sound.
You answer my questions
by nodding yes or shaking your head no.
Is he alone?
Does he expect you?
Do you have keys
to the apartment?
Is there a code, a way of knocking,
so he knows it's you?
Alpha team.
- Final position. We're ready to go.
- Be careful.
What up? Move! Fuck.
Shit.
Alpha team. Man down.
I told you.
- Bring me everyone.
- What do you mean, everyone?
Everyone!
Take this.
Go take a look.
- Don't move.
- Do you see anything?
It's the guy. He's here.
He's got a gun to my head.
Nobody moves.
- Let the girl go.
- Take it easy, man!
Okay, the girl's coming out.
Let the girl go.
Grab the axe off the wall.
Over there. Go!
You're coming with us.
Christ, he shot him!
Bastard!
Move!
- Shut the fucking water off!
- Got it.
Come!
We're in a bad way here.
Send the cats.
I don't know what happened.
I didn't see 'em coming, I swear!
I just went shopping and I came back,
and they were everywhere.
Stay away from the window.
Come here.
Snipers.
Okay, now, get this fucking asshole
out of there.
- How are we gonna get outta here now?
- Leave it to me. We're checking out.
But it's not big enough for you.
It's barely big enough for me.
- We said no discussion.
- No, I'm not letting-
- I'm not going! I won't go!
- Listen to me.
We have no chance together.
But if I'm alone, I can do it.
Trust me.
I'm in good shape.
I know I've got a lot
of money with Tony.
We'll take it and leave together,
just the two of us.
Go.
You're saying that
so I won't worry.
- I don't wanna lose you.
- You're not gonna lose me.
You've given me
a taste for life.
I wanna be happy,
sleep in a bed, have roots.
You'll never be alone again.
Please, go now, baby. Go.
Calm down.
Go now. Go.
See you at Tony's. I'm gonna
clean them all. Tony's in an hour.
I love you, Mathilda.
I love you, too, Leon.
Hey, what is going on up there?
Take the guy out, not the building.
We've got one breathing here!
Get a medic on the horn!
Clear the hall!
Let him through!
- We've got a wounded man. Make way!
- Down those stairs.
Let's go! Move!
Get that guy off the stairs!
- Get your team back out there!
- I got him!
We've got two men coming
down the stairs. Let's hurry!
You okay?
Hey, I need a medic over here!
Move your fucking asses.
Squad Number One,
what's the status on the apartment?
Can't see shit. Too much smoke.
Give us five minutes.
You got it.
What? Two hundred men can't find
one man and a girl?
Did you find the girl?
How are you doing?
Take your mask off, quick.
Let me see you. That's deep.
Right. And this one here-
You're from the 3rd Precinct?
Let's open up
his sleeve a little bit.
All right, fine. Put it down.
This one.
You stay there for two minutes.
I'll be right back.
Let me put the mask back on.
I breathe better with it.
You're all right.
Sit tight.
Come on, everybody out!
Let's go! Out!
Clear the way, men.
What are you doing here?
Get out. Come on.
Stansfield?
At your service.
This is from...
Mathilda.
Shit.
Get out of here!
Leon asked me
to help you out...
if something happened,
and I think something happened.
He put aside
a little cash for you.
So what I'm suggesting
is that...
seeing as how
you're still so young...
I should hold the money for you
until you're older.
Like a bank, you know, except...
it's better than a bank
'cause banks always get knocked off.
No one knocks off old Tony.
But it's your money.
In the meantime...
all you gotta do is come here
every once in awhile...
and I'll dish it out
so you can have a little fun.
Here.
- Here's a hundred bucks to start.
- Can't I get a job instead?
A job?
What the hell can you do?
I can clean.
I ain't got no work
for a 12-year-old kid...
so get it out
of your goddamn head!
It's over!
The game's over!
Leon's dead!
You hear me?
Come on. You think
I ain't hurting too?
But he's dead.
You're gonna forget all this craziness
and get your little ass back to school.
Now take this money
and get the hell outta here.
Don't let me see your face
till next month...
'cause something tells me
I'm about to lose my famous kind streak.
My parents...
died...
in a car accident
four weeks ago.
It was terrible.
We didn't have the time to get to know
one another when you first came here...
but I want you to know I'm not the kind
of woman who'd let down a child...
whatever her situation,
whatever her mistake.
So I'm going to help you and do my best
to welcome you here again.
But on one condition:
You have to stop lying to me,
Mathilda.
I want you to take a chance...
and trust me.
Tell me what happened to you.
My family got shot down
by D. E. A. officers...
because of a drug problem.
I left with the greatest guy on Earth.
He was a hit man, the best in town,
but he died this morning.
If you don't help me,
I'll be dead by tonight.
- You know her?
- I've never seen her.
I think we'll be okay here, Leon.