O, my old friend! Thy face is
valanc'd since I saw thee last,
comest thou to beard me in Denmark?
What, my young lady
and mistress! By'r lady,
your ladyship is nearer to
heaven than when I saw you last,
by the altitude of a
chopine. Pray God, your voice,
like a piece of uncurrent gold,
be not cracked within the ring.
Masters, you are all welcome. We'll
e'en to't like French falconers,
fly at anything we see: we'll
have a speech straight. Come,
give us a taste of your quality.
Come, a passionate speech.
- What speech, my good lord?
- I heard thee speak me a speech once,
but it was never acted. Or if it
was, not above once, for the play,
I remember, pleased not the million,
'twas caviar to the general, but
it was, as I received it, and others,
whose judgments in such matters
cried in the top of mine,
an excellent play,
well digested in the scenes, set
down with as much modesty as cunning.
I remember, one said there
were no sallets in the lines
to make the matter savoury,
or no matter in the phrase
which might indite the
author of affectation,
but called it an honest
method, as wholesome as sweet,
and by very much more
handsome than fine.
One speech in it I chiefly
loved: 'twas AEneas' tale to Dido,
and thereabout of it especially
where he speaks of Priam's slaughter:
if it live in your memory, begin at
this line, let me see, let me see:
The rugged Pyrrhus, like th'
Hyrcanian beast, it is not so...
- It begins with Pyrrhus.
'The rugged Pyrrhus,
he whose sable arms,
black as his purpose,
did the night resemble
when he lay couched
in the ominous horse,
hath now this dread and
black complexion smear'd
with heraldry more dismal,
head to foot now is be total gules,
horridly trick'd with blood of
fathers, mothers, daughters, sons,
bak'd and impasted with the
parching streets, that lend
a tyrannous and a damned
light to their vile murders:
roasted in wrath and fire,
and thus o'ersized with coagulate gore,
with eyes like carbuncles,
the hellish Pyrrhus
old grandsire Priam seeks.'
So, proceed you.
'Fore God, my lord, well spoken,
with good accent and good discretion.
Anon he finds him,
striking too short at Greeks:
his antique sword, rebellious
to his arm, lies where it falls,
repugnant to command:
unequal match'd,
Pyrrhus at Priam drives,
in rage strikes wide, but with the
whiff and wind of his fell sword
the unnerved father falls.
Then senseless Ilium,
seeming to feel this
blow, with flaming top
stoops to his base,
and with a hideous crash
takes prisoner Pyrrhus' ear.
For lo! his sword, which was declining
on the milky head of reverend Priam,
seem'd i' the air to stick: so,
as a painted tyrant, Pyrrhus stood,
and, like a neutral to his
will and matter, did nothing.
But as we often see, against some storm,
a silence in the heavens, the rack
stand still, the bold winds speechless,
and the orb below as hush as death,
anon the dreadful thunder
doth rend the region,
so, after Pyrrhus' pause, a roused
vengeance sets him new a-work,
and never did the Cyclops'
hammers fall on Mars's armour
forg'd for proof
eterne, with less remorse
than Pyrrhus' bleeding
sword now falls on Priam.
Out, out, thou strumpet, Fortune!
All you gods, in general
synod, take away her power,
break all the spokes and
fellies from her wheel,
and bowl the round nave
down the hill of heaven,
- as low as to the fiends!'
- This is too long.
It shall to the
barber's, with your beard.
Pr'ythee say on. He's for a jig
or a tale of bawdry, or he sleeps.
Say on,
- come to Hecuba.
- 'But who, o who,
- had seen the mobled queen...'
- 'The mobled queen'?
That's good! 'Mobled queen' is good.
'Run barefoot up and down, threatening
the flames with bisson rheum,
a clout upon that head
where late the diadem stood,
and for a robe, about her
lank and all o'erteemed loins,
a blanket, in the
alarm of fear caught up,
who this had seen, with
tongue in venom steep'd,
'gainst Fortune's state
would treason have pronounc'd:
but if the gods themselves
did see her then,
when she saw Pyrrhus make malicious
sport in mincing with his sword
her husband's limbs, the instant
burst of clamour that she made,
unless things mortal
move them not at all,
would have made milch the
burning eyes of heaven,
and passion in the gods.'
Look, whether he has not turn'd
his colour, and has tears in's eyes.
Pray you, no more!
'Tis well. I'll have thee
speak out the rest of this soon.
Good my lord, will you see the players well
bestowed? Do you hear? Let them be well used,
for they are the abstracts
and brief chronicles of the time,
after your death you were
better have a bad epitaph
than their ill report while you live.
My lord, I will use them
according to their desert.
God's bodykins, man, better!
Use every man after his desert,
and who should scape whipping?
Use them after your
own honour and dignity:
the less they deserve, the
more merit is in your bounty.
- Take them in.
- Come, sirs.
Follow him, friends. We'll
hear a play to-morrow.
Dost thou hear me, old friend? Can
you play 'The Murder of Gonzago'?
- Ay, my lord.
- We'll ha't to-morrow night.
You could, for a need, study a
speech of some dozen or sixteen lines
which I would set down and
insert in't? Could you not?
- Ay, my lord.
- Very well. Follow that lord
and look you:
mock him not.
My good friends, I'll leave you till
night: you are welcome to Elsinore.
- Good my lord!
- Ay, so. Good-bye to you.
Now I am alone.
O, what a rogue and peasant slave am I!
Is it not monstrous
that this player here,
but in a fiction,
in a dream of passion,
could force his soul
so to his own conceit
that from her working
all his visage wan'd,
tears in his eyes, distraction
in's aspect, a broken voice,
and his whole function suiting with
forms to his conceit? And all for nothing!
For Hecuba? What's Hecuba
to him, or he to Hecuba,
that he should weep for her?
What would he do, had he the motive
and the cue for passion that I have?
He would drown the stage with tears
and cleave the general
ear with horrid speech,
make mad the guilty,
and appal the free,
confound the ignorant, and amaze, indeed,
the very faculties of eyes and ears.
Yet I, a dull and muddy-mettled rascal,
peak, like John-a-dreams,
unpregnant of my cause,
and can say nothing.
No, not for a king
upon whose property and most dear
life a damn'd defeat was made.
Am I a coward? Who calls me
villain? Breaks my pate across?
Plucks off my beard
and blows it in my face?
Tweaks me by the nose? Gives
me the lie i' the throat
as deep as to the lungs?
Who does me this, ha?
'Swounds! I should take it: for it
cannot be but I am pigeon-liver'd,
and lack gall to make
oppression bitter, or ere this
I should have fatted all the region
kites with this slave's offal,
bloody, bawdy villain!
Remorseless, treacherous,
lecherous, kindless villain!
O, vengeance!
Why, what an ass am I!
This is most brave, that I,
the son of a dear father murder'd,
prompted to my revenge by heaven
and hell, must, like a whore,
unpack my heart with words and fall
a-cursing like a very drab, a scullion!
Fie upon't! Foh! About, my brain!
I have heard that guilty
creatures, sitting at a play,
have by the very cunning of the
scene been struck so to the soul
that presently they have
proclaim'd their malefactions,
for murder, though it have
no tongue, will speak with most
miraculous organ,
I'll have these players play
something like the murder
of my father before mine uncle:
I'll observe his looks,
I'll tent him to the quick.
If he but blench, I know my course.
The spirit that I have
seen may be the devil,
and the devil hath power to
assume a pleasing shape, yea,
and perhaps out of my
weakness and my melancholy,
as he is very potent with such spirits,
abuses me to damn me:
I'll have grounds
more relative than this.
The play's the thing wherein I'll catch
the conscience of the king.
And can you, by no drift of conference,
get from him why he puts on this confusion,
grating so harshly all his days of quiet
with turbulent and dangerous lunacy?
He does confess he feels
himself distracted,
but from what cause
he will by no means speak.
Nor do we find him
forward to be sounded,
but, with a crafty madness, keeps aloof
when we would bring him on to
some confession of his true state.
- Did he receive you well?
- Most like a gentleman.
But with much forcing
of his disposition.
Niggard of question, but, of our
demands, most free in his reply.
Did you assay him to any pastime?
Madam, it so fell out that certain
players we o'er-raught on the way:
of these we told him, and there did
seem in him a kind of joy to hear of it:
they are about the court, and, as I
think, they have already order
- this night to play before him.
- 'Tis most true,
and he beseech'd me
to entreat your majesties
- to hear and see the matter.
- With all my heart!
And it doth much content me
to hear him so inclin'd.
Good gentlemen, give him a further edge,
and drive his purpose in to these delights.
We shall, my lord.
Sweet Gertrude, leave us too,
for we have closely sent for Hamlet
hither, that he, as 'twere by accident,
may here affront Ophelia:
her father and myself, lawful espials,
will so bestow ourselves
that, seeing, unseen,
we may of their encounter frankly judge,
and gather by him, as he is behav'd,
if't be the affliction of his love
or no that thus he suffers for.
I shall obey you.
And for your part, Ophelia, I do wish
that your good beauties be the
happy cause of Hamlet's wildness,
so shall I hope your virtues will
bring him to his wonted way again,
- to both your honours.
- Madam, I wish it may.
Ophelia, walk you here. Gracious, so
please you, we will bestow ourselves.
Read on this book, that show of such
an exercise may colour your loneliness.
We are oft to blame in this,
'tis too much prov'd,
that with devotion's visage
and pious action
- we do sugar o'er the Devil himself.
- O, 'tis too true!
How smart a lash that speech
doth give my conscience!
The harlot's cheek,
beautied with plastering art,
is not more ugly to
the thing that helps it
than is my deed
to my most painted word.
- O heavy burden!
- I hear him coming: let's withdraw, my lord.
To be, or not to be,
that is the question:
whether 'tis nobler in the mind
to suffer the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune or to take
arms against a sea of troubles,
and by opposing end them?
To die, to sleep, no more,
and by a sleep to say
we end the heartache,
and the thousand natural
shocks that flesh is heir to,
'tis a consummation
devoutly to be wish'd.
To die, to sleep...
To sleep!
Perchance to dream:
ay, there's the rub,
for in that sleep of death
what dreams may come,
when we have shuffled off this
mortal coil, must give us pause:
there's the respect that
makes calamity of so long life,
for who would bear the
whips and scorns of time,
the oppressor's wrong,
the proud man's contumely,
the pangs of despis'd
love, the law's delay,
the insolence of office, and the spurns
that patient merit
of the unworthy takes,
when he himself might his
quietus make with a bare bodkin?
Who would these fardels bear,
to grunt and sweat under a weary life,
but that the dread
of something after death...
The undiscover'd country, from
whose bourn no traveller returns,
puzzles the will,
and makes us rather
bear those ills we have
than fly to others
that we know not of?
Thus conscience doth make
cowards of us all, and thus
the native hue of resolution
is sicklied o'er with
the pale cast of thought,
and enterprises of great pith
and moment, with this regard,
their currents turn awry,
and lose the name
of action.
Soft you now! The fair Ophelia!
Nymph...
in thy orisons
be all my sins remember'd.
Good my lord, how does your
honour for this many a day?
I humbly thank you.
Well,
well,
well.
My lord,
I have remembrances of yours that
I have longed long to re-deliver.
- I pray you, now receive them.
- No.
- Not I, I never gave you aught.
- My honour'd lord,
you know right well you did,
and with them words of so sweet breath
compos'd as made the things more rich.
Their perfume lost, take these again,
for to the noble mind rich gifts
wax poor when givers prove unkind.
There, my lord.
Ha?
- Are you honest?
- My lord?
- Are you fair?
- What means your lordship?
That if you be honest and fair, your honesty
should admit no discourse to your beauty.
Could beauty, my lord, have
better commerce than with honesty?
Ay, truly, for the power of beauty
will sooner transform honesty
from what it is to a bawd
than the force of honesty
can translate beauty into his likeness:
this was sometime a paradox,
but now the time gives it proof.
- I did love you once.
- Indeed, my lord,
- you made me believe so.
- You should not have believ'd me,
for virtue cannot so inoculate our old stock
but we shall relish of it: I loved you not.
- I was the more deceived.
- Get thee to a nunnery.
Why wouldst thou be
a breeder of sinners?
I am myself indifferent honest, but
yet I could accuse me of such things
that it were better my mother had not
borne me: I am very proud, revengeful,
ambitious, with more
offences at my beck
than I have thoughts to put them in,
imagination to give them shape,
or time to act them in.
What should such fellows as I do
crawling between
earth and heaven?
We are arrant knaves, all, believe
none of us. Go thy ways to a nunnery.
Where's your father?
At home, my lord.
Let the doors be shut upon him,
that he may play the fool
nowhere but in's own house.
Farewell.
O, help him, you sweet heavens!
If thou dost marry, I'll give
thee this plague for thy dowry,
be thou as chaste as
ice, as pure as snow,
thou shalt not escape calumny.
Get thee to a nunnery, go: farewell.
Or, if thou wilt needs
marry, marry a fool,
for wise men know well enough
what monsters you make of them.
To a nunnery, go, and
quickly too. Farewell.
O heavenly powers, restore him!
I have heard of your paintings too,
well enough, God hath given you one face,
and you make yourselves another:
you jig, you amble, and you lisp,
and nickname God's creatures, and
make your wantonness your ignorance.
Go to, I'll no more on't,
it hath made me mad.
I say,
we will have no more marriages.
Those that are married already,
all but one, shall live.
The rest shall keep as they are.
To a nunnery,
go.
O, what a noble mind
is here o'erthrown!
The courtier's, soldier's, scholar's,
eye, tongue, sword,
the expectancy and
rose of the fair state,
the glass of fashion
and the mould of form,
the observ'd of all observers,
quite, quite down!
And I, of ladies most
deject and wretched
that suck'd the honey of his music vows,
now see that noble and
most sovereign reason,
like sweet bells jangled,
out of tune and harsh,
that unmatch'd form and
feature of blown youth
blasted with ecstasy.
O, woe is me, to have
seen what I have seen,
- see what I see!
- Love?
His affections do not that way tend,
nor what he spake, though it lack'd
form a little, was not like madness.
There's something in his soul o'er
which his melancholy sits on brood,
and I do doubt the hatch and
the disclose Will be some danger:
which for to prevent, I have in
quick determination thus set it down:
he shall with speed to England for
the demand of our neglected tribute:
haply the seas, and countries
different, with variable objects,
shall expel this something-settled
matter in his heart,
whereon his brains still beating
puts him thus from fashion of himself.
- What think you on't?
- It shall do well,
but yet do I believe the origin
and commencement of his grief
sprung from neglected love.
How now, Ophelia! You need not
tell us what Lord Hamlet said,
we heard it all.
My lord, do as you please,
but if you hold it fit,
after the play, let his queen mother
all alone entreat him to show his grief:
let her be round with him,
and I'll be plac'd, so please you,
in the ear of all their conference.
If she find him not,
to England send him,
or confine him where your
wisdom best shall think.
It shall be so:
madness in great ones
must not unwatch'd go.
Speak the speech, I pray you,
as I pronounced it to you,
trippingly on the tongue: but if you
mouth it, as many of your players do,
I had as lief the town
crier spoke my lines.
Nor do not not saw the air too much
with your hand, thus, but use all gently:
for in the very torrent, tempest, and,
as I may say, whirlwind of your passion,
you must acquire and beget a
temperance that may give it smoothness.
O, it offends me to the soul, to
hear a robustious periwig-pated fellow
tear a passion to tatters, to very rags,
to split the ears of the
groundlings, who, for the most part,
are capable of nothing but
inexplicable dumb shows and noise.
I would have such a fellow
whipped for o'erdoing Termagant,
it out-herods Herod:
pray you avoid it.
- I warrant your honour.
- Be not too tame neither, but
let your own discretion be your
tutor: suit the action to the word,
the word to the action,
with this special observance,
that you o'erstep not
the modesty of nature:
for anything so overdone is
from the purpose of playing,
whose end, both at the
first and now, was and is,
to hold, as 'twere,
the mirror up to nature,
to show virtue her own
feature, scorn her own image,
and the very age and body of
the time his form and pressure.
Now, this overdone, or come tardy off,
though it make the unskilful laugh,
cannot but make the judicious grieve,
the censure of the which
one must in your allowance,
o'erweigh a whole theatre of others.
O, there be players
that I have seen play,
and heard others praise, and that
highly, not to speak it profanely,
that, neither having
the accent of Christians,
nor the gait of Christian,
pagan, nor man, have so...
strutted and bellowed
that I have thought
some of nature's
journeymen had made men,
and not made them well, they
imitated humanity so abominably.
I hope we have reform'd
that indifferently with us.
O, reform it altogether. And
let those that play your clowns
speak no more than
is set down for them:
for there be of them
that will themselves laugh,
to set on some quantity of
barren spectators to laugh too,
though in the meantime some
necessary question of the play
be then to be considered: that's villanous
and shows a most pitiful ambition
in the fool that uses
it. Go make you ready.
How now, my lord! Will the
king hear this piece of work?
- And the queen too, and that presently.
- Bid the players make haste.
- Will you two help to hasten them?
- We will, my lord.
- What, ho, Horatio!
- Here, sweet lord, at your service.
Horatio, thou art e'en as just a man
as e'er my conversation cop'd withal.
- O, my dear lord,
- Nay, do not think I flatter
for what advancement may I hope
from thee, that no revenue hast,
but thy good spirits,
to feed and clothe thee?
Why should the poor be flatter'd?
No, let the candied
tongue lick absurd pomp,
and crook the pregnant hinges of the
knee where thrift may follow fawning
Dost thou hear? Since my dear
soul was mistress of her choice,
and could of men distinguish, her
election hath seal'd thee for herself:
for thou hast been as one, in
suffering all, that suffers nothing,
a man that Fortune's buffets and
rewards hast ta'en with equal thanks:
and bles'd are those whose blood
and judgment are so well commingled
that they are not a pipe for Fortune's
finger to sound what stop she please.
Give me that man that
is not passion's slave,
and I will wear him in my heart's core,
ay, in my heart of heart,
as I do thee.
Something too much of this. There
is a play to-night before the king,
one scene of it comes near the circumstance,
which I have told thee, of my father's death:
I pr'ythee, when thou
see'st that act a-foot,
even with the very comment
of thy soul observe mine uncle.
If his occulted guilt do not
itself unkennel in one speech,
it is a damned ghost
that we have seen, and my
imaginations are as foul
as Vulcan's stithy.
Give him heedful note, for I
mine eyes will rivet to his face,
and, after, we will both our judgments
join in censure of his seeming.
Well, my lord:
if he steal aught the whilst this
play is playing, and scape detecting,
I will pay the theft.
They are coming to the play. I
must be idle: get you a place.
- How fares our cousin Hamlet?
- Excellent, i' faith,
of the chameleon's dish: I
eat the air, promise-crammed.
You cannot feed capons so.
I have nothing with this answer,
Hamlet, these words are not mine.
No, nor mine now.
My lord,
you play'd once i' the
university, you say?
That did I, my lord, and
was accounted a good actor.
- What did you enact?
- I did enact Julius Caesar,
I was kill'd i' the
Capitol, Brutus killed me.
It was a brute part of him
to kill so capital a calf there.
- Be the players ready?
- Ay, my lord, they stay upon your patience.
Come hither, my good Hamlet, sit by me.
No, good mother, here's
metal more attractive.
O, ho! Do you mark that?
- Lady, shall I lie in your lap?
- No, my lord.
- I mean, my head upon your lap?
- Ay, my lord.
- Do you think I meant country matters?
- I think nothing, my lord.
That's a fair thought to
lie between maids' legs.
- What is, my lord?
- Nothing.
- You are merry, my lord.
- Who, I? O, your only jig-maker!
What should a man do but be merry? For
look you how cheerfully my mother looks,
and my father died within 's two hours.
Nay, 'tis twice two months, my lord.
So long?
Nay then, let the devil wear black,
for I'll have a suit of sables.
O heavens! die two months
ago, and not forgotten yet?
Then there's hope a great man's memory
may outlive his life half a year:
but, by'r lady, he must build churches then,
or else shall he suffer not thinking on,
with the hobby-horse,
whose epitaph is
'For, O, for, O, the
hobby-horse is forgot!'
- What means this, my lord?
- Marry, this is miching mallecho,
it means mischief.
Belike this show imports
the argument of the play.
We shall know by this fellow:
the players cannot keep
counsel, they'll tell all.
Will he tell us what
this show meant?
Ay, or any show
that you'll show him:
show, he'll not shame
to tell you what it means.
You are naught, you are naught:
- I'll mark the play.
- For us, and for our tragedy,
Here stooping to your clemency,
We beg your hearing patiently.
Is this a prologue,
or the posy of a ring?
- 'Tis brief, my lord.
- As woman's love.
Full thirty times hath
Phoebus' cart gone round
Neptune's salt wash and
Tellus' orbed ground,
and thirty dozen moons
with borrow'd sheen
about the world have
times twelve thirties been,
since love our hearts,
and Hymen did our hands,
unite commutual in most sacred bands.
So many journeys may the sun and moon
make us again count
o'er ere love be done!
but, woe is me, you are so sick of late, so
far from cheer and from your former state
that I distrust you. Yet,
though I distrust, discomfort
you, my lord, it nothing must:
for women's fear and
love hold quantity,
in either naught, or in extremity.
Now, what my love is,
proof hath made you know,
and as my love is siz'd, my fear is so:
where love is great, the
littlest doubts are fear,
where little fears grow great,
great love grows there.
Faith, I must leave thee,
love, and shortly too,
my operant powers their
functions leave to do:
and thou shalt live in
this fair world behind,
honour'd, belov'd,
and haply one as kind
- for husband shalt thou,
- O, confound the rest!
Such love must needs
be treason in my breast:
in second husband
let me be accurst!
None wed the second
but who kill'd the first.
- That's wormwood, wormwood.
- The instances that second marriage move
are base respects of
thrift, but none of love.
A second time
I kill my husband dead
when second husband
kisses me in bed.
I do believe you think
what now you speak,
but what we do
determine oft we break.
Purpose is but
the slave to memory,
of violent birth,
but poor validity:
which now, like fruit
unripe, sticks on the tree,
but fall unshaken
when they mellow be.
Most necessary
'tis that we forget
to pay ourselves what
to ourselves is debt:
what to ourselves
in passion we propose,
the passion ending,
doth the purpose lose.
The violence of either grief or joy
their own enactures
with themselves destroy:
where joy most revels,
grief doth most lament,
grief joys, joy grieves,
on slender accident.
This world is not for aye,
and 'tis not strange that even our
loves should with our fortunes change,
for 'tis a question
left us yet to prove,
whether love lead fortune,
or else fortune love.
The great man down,
you'll mark his favourite flies,
poor men advanc'd
make friends of enemies,
and hitherto does love
on fortune tend:
for who not needs
shall never lack a friend,
and who in want
a hollow friend doth try,
directly seasons him his enemy.
But, orderly to end where I begun,
our wills and fates
do so contrary run
that our devices
still are overthrown,
our thoughts are ours,
their ends none of our own:
so think thou wilt
no second husband wed,
but die thy thoughts
when thy first lord is dead.
Nor earth to me give
food, nor heaven light!
sport and repose lock
from me day and night!
To desperation
turn my trust and hope!
An anchor's cheer
in prison be my scope!
Each opposite that
blanks the face of joy
meet what I would have
well, and it destroy!
Both here and hence
pursue me lasting strife,
if, once a widow, ever I be wife!
If she should break it now!
'Tis deeply sworn. Sweet,
leave me here awhile,
my spirits grow dull,
and fain I would beguile
the tedious day with sleep.
Sleep rock thy brain, and never
come mischance between us twain!
- Madam, how like you this play?
- The lady does protests too much, methinks.
O, but she'll keep her word.
Have you heard the argument?
Is there no offence in't?
No, no! They do but jest, poison
in jest, no offence i' the world.
- What do you call the play?
- "The Mouse-trap". Marry, how?
Tropically. This play is the
image of a murder done in Vienna:
Gonzago is the duke's name,
his wife, Baptista, you shall see anon,
'tis a knavish piece of work:
but what o' that?
Your majesty, and we that
have free souls, it touches us not:
let the gall'd jade wince,
our withers are unwrung.
This is one Lucianus,
nephew to the King.
You are a good chorus, my lord.
I could interpret between you and your
love, if I could see the puppets dallying.
You are keen, my lord.
You are keen.
It would cost you a groaning
to take off my edge.
- Still better, and worse.
- So you must take your husbands.
Begin, murderer, pox, leave
thy damnable faces, and begin.
Come: 'The croaking raven
doth bellow for revenge.'
Thoughts black, hands apt,
drugs fit, and time agreeing,
confederate season,
else no creature seeing,
thou mixture rank, of
midnight weeds collected,
with Hecate's ban thrice
blasted, thrice infected,
thy natural magic and dire property
on wholesome life usurp immediately.
He poisons him i' the
garden for's estate.
His name's Gonzago: the story is extant,
and written in very choice Italian,
you shall see anon
how the murderer
gets the love of Gonzago's wife!
The king rises!
What, frighted with false fire!
- How fares my lord?
- Give o'er the play!
Give me some light.
- Away!
- Lights, lights, lights!
Horatio!
Why, let the strucken deer go
weep, the hart ungalled play,
for some must watch, while some
must sleep: thus runs the world away.
Would not this, sir,
and a forest of feathers
if the rest of my fortunes
turn Turk with me,
with two Provincial
roses on my razed shoes,
get me a fellowship
in a cry of players?
- Half a share.
- A whole one, I.
For thou dost know, o Damon dear,
this realm dismantled
was of Jove himself,
- and now reigns here a very, very pajock.
- You might have rhymed.
O good Horatio,
I'll take the ghost's word for
a thousand pound! Didst perceive?
- Very well, my lord.
- Upon the talk of the poisoning?
- I did very well note him.
- Ah, ha!
Come, some music!
Come, the recorders!
For if the king like not the comedy,
why then, belike he likes it not, perdy.
Come, some music!
Good my lord, vouchsafe
me a word with you.
- Sir, a whole history.
- The king, sir...
- Ay, sir, what of him?
- Is, in his retirement,
marvellous distempered.
- With drink, sir?
- No, my lord, rather with choler.
Your wisdom should show itself more
richer to signify this to his doctor.
For, for me to put him
to his purgation
might perhaps plunge him
into far more choler.
Good my lord, put your
discourse into some frame,
- and start not so wildly from my affair.
- I am tame, sir: pronounce.
The queen, your mother, in most great
affliction of spirit, hath sent me to you.
- You are welcome.
- Nay, good my lord,
this courtesy is not
of the right breed.
If it shall please you to make
me a wholesome answer,
I will do your mother's
commandment: if not...
your pardon and my return
shall be the end of my business.
- Sir, I cannot.
- What, my lord?
Make you a wholesome
answer, my wit's diseased:
but, sir, such answer as I
can make, you shall command,
or rather, as you say, my
mother: therefore no more,
but to the matter:
my mother, you say,
Then thus she says:
your behaviour hath struck her
into amazement and admiration.
O wonderful son, that
can so stonish a mother!
But is there no sequel at the heels
of this mother's admiration? Impart.
She desires to speak with you
in her closet ere you go to bed.
We shall obey, were she
ten times our mother.
Have you any further
trade with us?
- My lord, you once did love me.
- And so I do still,
by these pickers and stealers.
Good my lord, what is
the cause of your distemper?
You do, surely, bar the door
upon your own liberty
if you deny your griefs
to your friend.
- Sir, I lack advancement.
- How can that be,
when you have the voice of the king
himself for your succession in Denmark?
Ay, sir, but 'While the grass grows'
the proverb is something musty.
O, the recorders: let me see
one. To withdraw with you:
why do you go about to
recover the wind of me,
as if you would
drive me into a toil?
O my lord, if my duty be too
bold, my love is too unmannerly.
I do not well understand that.
Will you play upon this pipe?
- My lord, I cannot.
- I pray you.
- Believe me, I cannot.
- I do beseech you.
- I know, no touch of it, my lord.
- 'Tis as easy as lying.
Govern these ventages with your finger
and thumb, give it breath with your mouth,
and it will discourse most eloquent
music. Look you, these are the stops.
But these cannot I command to any
utterance of harmony, I have not the skill.
Why, look you now, how unworthy
a thing you would make of me!
You would play upon me, you
would seem to know my stops,
you would pluck out
the heart of my mystery,
you would sound me from my lowest
note to the top of my compass,
and there is much music, excellent
voice, in this little organ,
yet cannot you make it speak.
'Sblood, do you think I am easier
to be played upon than a pipe?
Call me what instrument you will!
Though you can fret me,
yet, you cannot play upon me.
God bless you, sir!
My lord, the queen would
speak with you, and presently.
Do you see yonder cloud that's
almost in shape of a camel?
By the mass, and 'tis
like a camel indeed.
- Methinks it is like a weasel.
- It is backed like a weasel.
- Or like a whale.
- Very like a whale.
Then will I come
to my mother by and by.
They fool me to the top of my
bent. I will come by and by.
- I will say so.
- By-and-by is easily said.
Leave me, friends.
I like him not, nor stands it safe
with us to let his madness range.
Therefore prepare you, I your
commission will forthwith dispatch,
and he to England shall along with you:
the terms of our estate may not
endure hazard so dangerous
as doth hourly
grow out of his lunacies.
We will ourselves provide:
most holy and religious fear it is
to keep those many many bodies safe
that live and feed upon your majesty.
The single and peculiar life is bound, by
all the strength and armour of the mind,
to keep itself from 'noyance,
but much more that spirit upon whose
weal depend and rest the lives of many.
The cease of majesty dies not alone, but
like a gulf doth draw what's near it with it:
it is a massy wheel, fix'd on
the summit of the highest mount,
to whose huge spokes ten thousand
lesser things are mortis'd and adjoin'd,
which, when it falls,
each small annexment,
petty consequence,
attends the boisterous ruin.
Never alone did the king
sigh, but with a general groan.
Arm you, I pray you,
to this speedy voyage,
for we will fetters put upon this
fear, which now goes too free-footed.
- We will haste us.
- My lord...
he's going to his mother's closet:
behind the arras I'll convey myself
to hear the process, I'll
warrant she'll tax him home:
and, as you said,
and wisely was it said,
'tis meet that some more
audience than a mother,
since nature makes them partial,
should o'erhear the speech, of vantage.
Fare you well, my liege: I'll call upon you
ere you go to bed, and tell you what I know.
Thanks, dear my lord.
'Tis now the very witching time
of night, when churchyards yawn,
and hell itself breathes
out contagion to this world:
now could I drink hot blood, and
do such bitter business as the day
would quake to look on.
Soft! Now to my mother.
O heart, lose not thy nature,
let not ever the soul of
Nero enter this firm bosom:
let me be cruel, not unnatural,
I will speak daggers
to her, but use none,
my tongue and soul
in this be hypocrites,
how in my words
somever she be shent,
to give them seals
never, my soul, consent!
O, my offence is rank,
it smells to heaven,
it hath the primal eldest curse upon't,
a brother's murder!
Pray can I not, though
inclination be as sharp as will:
my stronger guilt
defeats my strong intent,
and, like a man to double business bound,
I stand in pause where I shall first begin,
and both neglect.
What if this cursed hand were thicker
than itself with brother's blood?
Is there not rain enough in the sweet
heaven to wash it white as snow?
Whereto serves mercy but to
confront the visage of offence?
And what's in prayer
but this twofold force,
to be forestalled ere we come
to fall, or pardon'd being down?
Then I'll look up, my fault is past.
But, o, what form of
prayer can serve my turn?
Forgive me my foul
murder! That cannot be,
since I am still possess'd of those
effects for which I did the murder,
my crown, mine own
ambition, and my queen.
May one be pardon'd
and retain the offence?
In the corrupted currents of this world
offence's gilded hand may shove by justice,
and oft 'tis seen the wicked
prize itself buys out the law,
but 'tis not so above,
there is no shuffling,
there the action lies
in his true nature,
and we ourselves compell'd,
even to the teeth and forehead
of our faults, to give in evidence.
What then? What rests?
Try what repentance
can: what can it not?
Yet what can it when one cannot repent?
O wretched state! O
bosom black as death!
O limed soul, that, struggling
to be free, art more engag'd!
Help, angels! Make assay:
bow, stubborn knees,
and, heart, with strings of steel, be
soft as sinews of the new-born babe!
All may be well.
Now might I do it pat,
now he is praying, and now I'll do't,
and so he goes to heaven,
and so am I reveng'd.
That would be scann'd:
a villain kills my father,
and for that, I, his sole son,
do this same villain send to heaven?
O, this is hire and salary, not revenge.
He took my father
grossly, full of bread,
with all his crimes broad
blown, as flush as May,
and how his audit stands,
who knows save heaven?
But in our circumstance and course
of thought, 'tis heavy with him:
and am I, then, reveng'd, to take
him in the purging of his soul,
when he is fit and
season'd for his passage?
No!
Up, sword, and know
thou a more horrid hent:
when he is drunk, asleep, or in his rage,
or in the incestuous pleasure
of his bed, at gaming, at swearing,
or about some act that has
no relish of salvation in't,
then trip him, that his
heels may kick at heaven,
and that his soul may be as damn'd
and black as hell, whereto it goes.
My mother stays:
this physic but
prolongs thy sickly days.
My words fly up, my
thoughts remain below:
words without thoughts
never to heaven go.
He will come straight.
Look you lay home to him:
tell him his pranks have
been too broad to bear with,
and that your grace hath screen'd
and stood between much heat and him.
I'll silence me even here.
Pray you, be round with him.
- I'll warrant you, fear me not!
- Mother, mother, mother!
Withdraw, I hear him coming.
Now, mother, what's the matter?
Hamlet, thou hast
thy father much offended.
Mother, you have
my father much offended.
Come, come, you answer
with an idle tongue.
Go, go, you question
with a wicked tongue.
- Why, how now, Hamlet!
- What's the matter now?
- Have you forgot me?
- No, by the rood, not so:
you are the queen, your
husband's brother's wife,
and, would it were not
so, you are my mother...
Nay, then, I'll set those
to you that can speak.
Come, come, and sit you
down, you shall not budge,
you go not till I set you up a glass
where you may see the inmost part of you.
What wilt thou do?
Thou wilt not murder me?
- Help, help, ho!
- What, ho! help, help, help!
Dead, for a ducat, dead!
O, I am slain!
O me, what hast thou done?
Nay, I know not: is it the king?
O, what a rash and bloody deed is this!
A bloody deed! Almost as bad, good mother,
as kill a king, and marry with his brother.
- As kill a king!
- Ay, lady, 'twas my word.
Thou wretched, rash,
intruding fool, farewell!
I took thee for thy
better: take thy fortune,
thou find'st to be too
busy is some danger.
Leave wringing of your hands.
Peace! Sit you down,
and let me wring your heart
for so I shall, if it be
made of penetrable stuff,
if damned custom have not brass'd it so
that it is proof and bulwark against sense.
What have I done, that thou darest wag
thy tongue in noise so rude against me?
Such an act that blurs the
grace and blush of modesty,
calls virtue hypocrite,
takes off the rose from the fair forehead
of an innocent love and sets a blister there,
makes marriage-vows
as false as dicers' oaths:
o, such a deed as from the body of
contraction plucks the very soul,
and sweet religion makes
a rhapsody of words:
heaven's face doth glow:
yea, this solidity and compound mass,
with tristful visage, as against
the doom, is thought-sick at the act!
Ay me, what act, that roars so
loud, and thunders in the index?
Look here, upon this
picture, and on this,
the counterfeit
presentment of two brothers.
See, what a grace was
seated on this brow,
Hyperion's curls, the
front of Jove himself,
an eye like Mars, to
threaten and command,
a station like the herald Mercury
new-lighted on a heaven-kissing hill,
a combination and a form indeed, where
every god did seem to set his seal,
to give the world assurance of a man:
this was your husband.
Look you now, what follows:
here is your husband,
like a mildew'd ear,
blasting his wholesome
brother. Have you eyes?
Could you on this fair mountain leave
to feed, and batten on this moor?
Ha! have you eyes? You
cannot call it love,
for at your age the hey-day
in the blood is tame,
it's humble, and waits
upon the judgment:
and what judgment would
step from this to this?
Sense, sure, you have, else
could you not have motion,
but sure, that sense is apoplex'd,
for madness would not err,
nor sense to ecstasy was ne'er so thrall'd
but it reserved some quantity of choice,
to serve in such a difference.
What devil was't that thus hath
cozen'd you at hoodman-blind?
Eyes without feeling, feeling without
sight, ears without hands or eyes,
smelling sans all, or but a
sickly part of one true sense
could not so mope.
O shame!
Where is thy blush?
Rebellious hell, if thou canst
mutine in a matron's bones,
to flaming youth let virtue be as wax,
and melt in her own
fire: proclaim no shame
when the compulsive
ardour gives the charge,
since frost itself as actively
doth burn and reason panders will!
O Hamlet, speak no more: thou
turn'st mine eyes into my very soul,
and there I see such black and grained
spots as will not leave their tinct.
Nay, but to live in the rank
sweat of an enseamed bed,
stew'd in corruption, honeying
and making love over the nasty sty,
O, speak to me no more, these words,
like daggers, enter in mine ears!
- No more, sweet Hamlet!
- A murderer and a villain,
a slave that is not twentieth part
the tithe of your precedent lord,
a vice of kings, a cutpurse
of the empire and the rule,
that from a shelf the precious diadem
stole, and put it in his pocket!
- No more!
- A king of shreds and patches!
Save me,
and hover o'er me with your
wings, you heavenly guards!
- What would your gracious figure?
- Alas, he's mad!
Do you not come
your tardy son to chide,
that, lapsed in time and passion,
lets go by the important
acting of your dread command?
- O, say!
- Do not forget:
this visitation is but to whet
thy almost blunted purpose.
But, look, amazement on thy mother sits.
O, step between her
and her fighting soul.
Conceit in weakest bodies
strongest works.
Speak to her, Hamlet.
- How is it with you, lady?
- Alas, how is't with you,
that you do bend your eye on vacancy and
with the incorporal air do hold discourse?
Forth at your eyes your
spirits wildly peep,
and, as the sleeping soldiers in the alarm,
your bedded hair, like life in excrements,
starts up, and stands on end.
O gentle son, upon the heat
and flame of thy distemper
sprinkle cool patience.
Whereon do you look?
On him.
On him!
Look you, how pale he glares!
His form and cause conjoin'd,
preaching to stones,
would make them capable.
Do not look upon me,
lest with this piteous action
you convert my stern effects:
then what I have to do
will want true colour,
tears perchance for blood.
- To whom do you speak this?
- Do you see nothing there?
- Nothing at all, yet all that is I see.
- Nor did you nothing hear?
- No, nothing but ourselves.
- Why, look you there!
Look, how it steals away!
My father, in his habit as he lived!
Look, where he goes,
even now, out at the portal!
This the very
coinage of your brain:
this bodiless creation
ecstasy is very cunning in.
Ecstasy!
My pulse, as yours, doth
temperately keep time,
and makes as healthful music: it
is not madness that I have utter'd:
bring me to the test, and
I the matter will re-word,
which madness would gambol from.
Mother, for love of grace...
lay not that flattering
unction to your soul,
that not your trespass,
but my madness speaks:
it will but skin and
film the ulcerous place,
whilst rank corruption, mining
all within, infects unseen.
Confess yourself to
heaven, repent what's past,
avoid what is to come, and do not spread the
compost on the weeds, to make them ranker.
Forgive me this my virtue,
for in the fatness of these pursy times
virtue itself of vice must pardon beg,
yea, curb and woo for
leave to do him good.
O Hamlet...
thou hast cleft my heart in twain.
O, throw away the worser part of it,
and live the purer with the other half.
Good night: but go not
to mine uncle's bed,
assume a virtue, if you have it not.
That monster, custom,
who all sense doth eat,
of habits devil, is angel yet in this,
that to the use of actions
fair and good
he likewise gives a frock or
livery, that aptly is put on.
Refrain to-night, and that shall lend a
kind of easiness to the next abstinence:
the next more easy, for use almost
can change the stamp of nature,
and either shame the devil, or
throw him out with wondrous potency.
Once more, good night:
and when you are
desirous to be bless'd,
I'll blessing beg of you.
For this same lord, I do repent,
but heaven hath pleased it so,
to punish me with this and this with me,
that I must be their
scourge and minister.
I will bestow him,
and will answer well
the death I gave him.
So, again, good night.
I must be cruel, only to be kind:
thus bad begins
and worse remains behind.
- One word more, good lady.
- What shall I do?
Not this, by no means,
that I bid you do:
let the bloat king
tempt you again to bed,
pinch wanton on your
cheek, call you his mouse,
and let him, for a pair
of reechy kisses, or
paddling in your neck
with his damn'd fingers,
make you to ravel all this matter out,
that I essentially am not in madness,
but mad in craft. 'Twere
good you let him know,
for who, that's but a
queen, fair, sober, wise,
would from a paddock, from a bat,
a gib, such dear concernings hide?
Who would do so? No, in
despite of sense and secrecy,
unpeg the basket on the
house's top. Let the birds fly,
and, like the famous
ape, to try conclusions,
in the basket creep, and
break your own neck down.
Be thou assured,
if words be made of
breath, and breath of life,
I have no life to breathe
what thou hast said to me.
I must to England, you know that?
Alack, I had forgot.
- 'Tis so concluded on.
- There's letters seal'd,
and my two schoolfellows, whom I
will trust as I will adders fang'd,
they bear the mandate, they must sweep
my way, and marshal me to knavery.
Let it work, for 'tis the sport to have
the engineer hoist with his own petard:
and 't shall go hard
but I will delve one
yard below their mines,
and blow them at the moon.
O, 'tis most sweet, when in one
line two crafts directly meet.
This man shall set me packing: I'll
lug the guts into the neighbour room.
Mother, good night indeed.
This counsellor is now most still,
most secret and most grave,
who was in life
a foolish prating knave.
Come, sir,
to draw toward an end with you.
Good night, mother.
There's matter in these
sighs, these profound heaves:
you must translate: 'tis fit we
understand them. Where is your son?
Bestow this place on us a little while.
Ah, my good lord,
what have I seen to-night!
What, Gertrude?
How does Hamlet?
Mad as the sea and wind, when
both contend which is the mightier.
In his lawless fit, behind the
arras hearing something stir,
whips out his rapier,
cries, 'A rat, a rat!'
and, in this brainish apprehension,
kills the unseen good old man.
O heavy deed!
It had been so with us,
had we been there!
His liberty is full of threats to all,
to you yourself, to us, to every one.
Alas, how shall this
bloody deed be answer'd?
It will be laid to us,
whose providence should
have kept short, restrain'd and...
out of haunt, this mad young man.
But so much was our love, we would
not understand what was most fit,
but, like the owner of a foul
disease, to keep it from divulging,
let it feed even on the pith of life.
- Where is he gone?
- To draw apart the body he hath kill'd:
o'er whom his very madness, like some
ore among a mineral of metals base,
shows itself pure, he
weeps for what is done.
O Gertrude, come away!
The sun no sooner shall the mountains
touch, but we will ship him hence:
and this vile deed we must,
with all our majesty and skill,
both countenance and excuse.
Ho, Guildenstern! Friends both,
go join you with some further aid.
Hamlet in madness
hath Polonius slain,
and from his mother's closet
hath he dragg'd him.
Go seek him out, speak fair, and
bring the body into the chapel.
Come on! I pray you, haste in this!
Come, Gertrude, we'll
call up our wisest friends,
and let them know, both what we
mean to do, and what's untimely done.
So envious slander, whose
whisper o'er the world's diameter
as level as the cannon to his
blank, transports the poisoned shot
may miss our name
and hit the woundless air.
O, come away!
My soul is full of discord and dismay.
- Safely stowed.
- Hamlet! Lord Hamlet!
But soft, what noise?
Who calls on Hamlet?
- Hamlet!
- O, here they come.
What have you done, my lord,
with the dead body?
Compounded it with dust,
whereto 'tis kin.
Tell us where 'tis, that we may take
it thence and bear it to the chapel.
- Do not believe it.
- Believe what?
That I can keep your counsel and not mine
own. Besides, to be demanded of a sponge!
What replication should be
made by the son of a king?
Take you me for a sponge, my lord?
Ay, sir, that soaks up the king's
countenance, his rewards, his authorities.
But such officers do the
king best service in the end.
He keeps them, like an ape,
an apple, in the corner of his jaw,
first mouthed, to be last swallowed.
When he needs what you have
gleaned, it is but squeezing you,
- and, sponge, you shall be dry again.
- I understand you not, my lord.
I am glad of it: a knavish
speech sleeps in a foolish ear.
My lord, you must tell us where the
body is, and go with us to the king.
The body is with the king, but
the king is not with the body.
- The king is a thing...
- A thing, my lord!
...of nothing. Bring me to him.
- My lord!
- Hide fox, and all after.
My lord!
My good lord Hamlet!
My good lord!
Hamlet!
I have sent to seek him,
and to find the body.
How dangerous is it
that this man goes loose!
Yet must not we put the strong law on him:
he's loved of the distracted multitude,
who like not in their
judgment, but their eyes,
and, where 'tis so, the offender's scourge
is weigh'd, but never the offence.
To bear all smooth and even,
this sudden sending him away
must seem deliberate pause.
Diseases desperate grown by desperate
appliance are relieved, or not at all.
How now! What hath befall'n?
Where the dead body is bestow'd,
my lord, we cannot get from him.
- But where is he?
- Without, my lord,
- guarded, to know your pleasure.
- Bring him before us.
Ho, Guildenstern! Bring in my lord.
- Now, Hamlet, where's Polonius?
- At supper.
- At supper! Where?
- Not where he eats, but where he is eaten.
A certain convocation of
politic worms are e'en at him.
Your worm is your only emperor for diet:
we fat all creatures else to fat
us, and we fat ourselves for maggots:
your fat king and your lean
beggar is but variable service,
two dishes, but to one
table That's the end.
- Alas, alas!
- A man may fish with the worm
that hath eat of a king, and eat of
the fish that hath fed of that worm.
- What dost you mean by this?
- Nothing but to show you how a king
may go a progress through
the guts of a beggar.
Where is Polonius?
In heaven. Send hither to see...
If your messenger
find him not there,
seek him i' the other place
yourself. But if indeed
you find him not within this month,
you shall nose him as you
go up the stairs into the lobby.
Go seek him there.
- He will stay till ye come.
- Hamlet...
this deed, for thine especial
safety, which we do tender,
as we dearly grieve for
that which thou hast done,
must send thee hence with fiery
quickness. Therefore prepare thyself,
the bark is ready, and the wind at help,
the associates tend, and every thing
- is bent for England.
- For England!
- Ay, Hamlet.
- Good.
- So is it, if thou knew'st our purposes.
- I see a cherub that sees them.
But, come, for England!
Farewell, dear mother.
- Thy loving father, Hamlet.
- Mother.
Father and mother is man and
wife. Man and wife is one flesh,
and so, my mother.
Come, for England!
Follow him at foot, tempt
him with speed aboard,
delay it not, I'll have him
hence to-night. Away!
For every thing is seal'd and done
that else leans on the affair.
Pray you, make haste!
And, England, if my love
thou hold'st at aught
as my great power thereof
may give thee sense,
since yet thy cicatrice looks raw
and red after the Danish sword,
and thy free awe
pays homage to us
thou mayst not coldly set our sovereign
process, which imports at full,
by letters congruing to that
effect, the present death of Hamlet.
Do it, England, for like the
hectic in my blood he rages,
and thou must cure me!
Till I know 'tis done,
howe'er my haps, my
joys were ne'er begun.
Go, captain, from me
greet the Danish king.
Tell him that, by his licence,
Fortinbras craves the conveyance
of a promised march over his
kingdom. You know the rendezvous.
If that his majesty would aught with us,
we shall express our duty in his eye,
- and let him know so.
- I will do't, my lord.
Go softly on.
- Good sir, whose powers are these?
- They are of Norway, sir.
- How purposed, sir, I pray you?
- Against some part of Poland.
- Who commands them, sir?
- The nephew of old Norway, Fortinbras.
Goes it against
the main of Poland, sir, or...
- for some frontier?
- Truly to speak,
and with no addition,
we go to gain a little patch of ground
that hath in it no profit but the name.
To pay five ducats,
five, I would not farm it,
nor will it yield to Norway or the Pole
a ranker rate, should it be sold in fee.
- Why, then the Polack never will defend it.
- Yes, it is already garrison'd.
Two thousand souls and
twenty thousand ducats
will not debate the
question of this straw.
This is the imposthume
of much wealth and peace,
that inward breaks, and shows
no cause without why the man dies.
- I humbly thank you, sir.
- God be wi' you, sir.
- Wilt please you go, my lord?
- I'll be with you straight.
Go a little before.
How all occasions do inform against me,
and spur my dull revenge!
What is a man,
if his chief good and market of
his time be but to sleep and feed?
A beast, no more.
Sure, he that made us
with such large discourse,
looking before and after,
gave us not that
capability and god-like reason
to fust in us unused!
Now, whether it be bestial
oblivion, or some craven scruple
of thinking too precisely on the event,
a thought which, quarter'd, hath but one
part wisdom and ever three parts coward,
I do not know why yet I live
to say 'This thing's to do',
sith I have cause and will
and strength and means to do't.
Examples gross as earth exhort me:
witness this army of
such mass and charge
led by a delicate and tender prince,
whose spirit with divine ambition puff'd
makes mouths at the invisible event,
exposing what is mortal and unsure
to all that fortune,
death and danger dare,
even for an egg-shell.
Rightly to be great is not
to stir without great argument,
but greatly to find quarrel in a straw
when honour's at the stake.
How stand I then, that have a
father kill'd, a mother stain'd,
excitements of my reason and my blood,
and let all sleep? While, to my shame,
I see the imminent death
of twenty thousand men,
that, for a fantasy and trick of fame,
go to their graves like beds,
fight for a plot whereon the
numbers cannot try the cause,
which is not tomb enough
and continent to hide the slain?
O, from this time forth,
my thoughts be bloody,
or be nothing worth!
When sorrows come, they
come not single spies
but in battalions.
First, her father slain,
next, your son gone
and he most violent author
of his own just remove,
the people muddied, thick and unwholesome
in their thoughts and whispers,
for good Polonius' death and we have done
but greenly, in hugger-mugger to inter him.
Poor Ophelia divided from
herself and her fair judgment,
without the which we are
pictures, or mere beasts.
Last, and as much containing as all these,
her brother is in secret come from France
feeds on his wonder,
keeps himself in clouds,
and wants not buzzers to infect his ear
with pestilent speeches of his father's
death wherein necessity, of matter beggar'd,
will nothing stick our person
to arraign in ear and ear.
O my dear Gertrude, this, like to
a murdering-piece, in many places
gives me superfluous death.
- I will not speak with her.
- She is importunate,
indeed distract, her
mood will needs be pitied.
- What would she have?
- She speaks much of her father
says she hears there's tricks i' the
world and hems, and beats her heart
spurns enviously at straws speaks things
in doubt, that carry but half sense.
Her speech is nothing, yet the unshaped use
of it doth move the hearers to collection
they aim at it, and botch the words
up fit to their own thoughts which,
as her winks, and nods,
and gestures yield them,
indeed would make one think
there might be thought,
though nothing sure, yet much unhappily.
'Twere good she were spoken with for
she may strew dangerous conjectures
- in ill-breeding minds.
- Let her come in.
To my sick soul,
as sin's true nature is,
each toy seems prologue
to some great amiss,
so full of artless jealousy is guilt,
it spills itself in fearing to be spilt.
Where is the beauteous
majesty of Denmark?
- How now, Ophelia!
- How should I your true love know
from another one?
By his cockle hat and
staff, and his sandal shoon.
Alas, sweet lady,
what imports this song?
Say you? Nay,
pray you, mark.
He is dead and gone, lady,
he is dead and gone
at his head a grass-green turf,
at his heels a stone.
- Nay, but, Ophelia,
- Pray you, mark.
- White his shroud as the mountain snow,
- Alas, look here, my lord.
Larded with sweet flowers,
which bewept to the grave
did go with true-love showers.
How do you, pretty lady?
Well, God 'ild you! They say
the owl was a baker's daughter.
Lord, we know what we are,
but know not what we may be.
- God be at your table!
- Conceit upon her father.
Pray you!
Let's have no words of this!