Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
There is an old proverb which says:
Don't try to do two things at
once and expect to do justice to both.
This is the story of a boy
who tried it.
While employed as a moving
picture operator is a small town...
theater he was also studying
to be a detective.
How to be a detective.
Say Mr. Detective
before you clean up any mysteries,
clean up this theater.
The girl in the case.
The girl's father had
nothing to do so...
he got a hired man to help him.
To day, "Hearts and Pearls" or...
The Lounge Lizard's.
Lost Love in Five Parts.
Confectionery.
1.00 $ Per Box.
3.00 $ Per Box.
The local sheik.
I lost a dollar.
Did you find it?
Describe it.
I lost a dollar.
I. Goldman & Co. -- Pawn Brokers.
Buy and sell every thing.
Money Loaned.
Diamonds and Jewelry.
3.00 $ Per Box.
Some one has stolen my watch.
How to be a detective.
Rule 1. Search Everybody.
It looks like a job for the police.
I'll take charge of this case
and start by searching everybody.
Hey!
I'm the fellow who lost the watch.
Why don't you search him, too?
I. Goldman & Co. Pawn Brokers.
Watch and Chain,  4 $
I'm sorry, my boy,...
but we never want to see
you in this house again.
Rule 5.
Shadow your man closely.
As a detective he was all wet,
so he went back to see what
he could do to his other job.
Can you describe the man who
pawned this watch?
Veronal Film Co. Presents:
"Hearts and Pearls"
Some one has stolen the pearls.
We are lost!
He is sending for the world's
greatest detective, Sherlock Jr.!
The crime-crushing criminologist
Sherlock Jr.
Don't bother to explain,
this is a simple case for me.
Poison.
Pardon, sir. I think there is
something in your drink.
By the next day the master mind
had completely solved the mystery...
with the exception of locating
the pearls and finding the thief.
His assistant: Gillette.
A Gem who was Ever-Ready
in a bad scrape.
That's a detective. When he's
dead I'll put you in there.
And now I'll tell you where
our little sweetie is this minute!
And she's waiting there for me.
Be careful or one of
us will get hurt.
Street-closed.
I never thought you'd make it.
Four wheel brakes.
Father sent me to tell you that
we've made a terrible mistake.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org