THE BATTLESHIP POTEMKIN
Film of the series "1905"
production
1 - the factory Goskino.
Producer
Yacob M. Blioch
scenario
N. F. Agadzhanovoy -
Shutko.
Director:
S. M. Eisenstein
Assistant director:
Grigori ALEXANDROV
Camera: Edward TISSE
Assistants:
A. ANTONOV, M. GOMOROV,
A. LEVSHIN, M. SHTRAUKH
administrators:
A. P. Kryukov
I. R. Kotoshyev
PART ONE
THE MEN AND THE MAGGOTS
"Revolution is war. Of all the wars known in history
it is the only lawful, rightful, just and truly great war.
In Russia, this war has been declared and begun."
Lenin, 1905
Sailors Matyushenko
and Vakulinchuk.
We, the sailors of "Potemkin",
must support our brothers the workers.
We must stand in the front ranks of the revolution!
The men slept heavily
after the watch.
Watchful but clumsy.
It is easy to vent one's
rage on a recruit.
it is offensive...
Vakulintchuk.
Comrades! The time has come
for us to speak out.
What are we waiting for?
All of Russia has risen.
Are we to be the last to do so?
On the following morning.
We've had enough rotten
meat!
It's not fit for pigs!
Ship's doctor Smirnov.
The meat could crawl
overboard on its own!
Those are not worms.
They are only maggots.
Wash them out with brine.
Russian POW's in Japan
are fed better!
We've had enough rotten meat!
Stop that talk! It's good meat.
Gilyarovsky, a senior officer.
Boiling soup.
The men seethed with rage.
The ship's store.
The men refused to eat the soup.
Give us this day...
our daily bread.
PART TWO
DRAMA IN THE HARBOUR
All hands on deck!
Ship's captain Golikov.
All who enjoyed their soup,
step forward!
The pretty officers.
Step back!
I'll string the rest of
you up on the yard!
Call the guard!
Matyusshenko instructed the
men to meet by the turret.
To the turret!
Most of the men gathered by the turret.
Halt!
Stay where you are!
The men tried to escape
through the Admiral's hatch.
Back! The hatch is not
for the likes of you.
I'll shoot you down like dogs!
Cover them with tarpaulin.
Aye-aye, sir!
Cover them!
Attention!
Bring the unruly to reason, O Lord...
At the tarpaulin.
Vakulinchuck decided to act.
Fire!
Brothers!
Who are you shooting at?
The rifles wavered.
Fire!
Fire, you swine!
Take your rifles, mates!
Let those blackguards have it!
Give it to them!
Remember the Lord!
Out of my way!
He's gone to feed the fishes!
We've won, mates!
Vakulinchuk is overboard!
He who was the first to call for an uprising,
fell at the hands of a butcher.
To the shore.
Odessa.
A tent on the new pier:
Vakulinchuk's last moorings.
Killed for a plate of soup.
PART THREE
A DEAD MAN CALLS FOR JUSTICE
A mist spread over the sea.
A rumour spread from the pier...
The news reached town with the sunrise.
There's an uprising on the "Potemkin"...
An uprising!...
We won't forget!
Killed for a plate of soup.
"People of Odessa! "Here lies Vakulinchuk
a sailor, brutally "murdered by an officer
of the battleship "Potemkin".
"Prince of Tauride.""Death to the opressors!
"We shall take revenge!"
The ship's crew.
Eternal glory to those who
died for the revolution!
All for one!
And one
for all.
Down with the butchers!
Down with tsarism!
Mothers, sisters, brothers!
Let nothing divide us!
Kill the Jews!
Shoulder to shoulder.
The land is ours!
The future is ours!
Delegates from Odessa.
We must deal the enemy
a decisive blow.
Together with the workers
of Russia
we shall fight and win!
Odessa followed the progress
of the uprising...
PART FOUR
THE ODESSA STAIRCASE
Odessa was with
the sailors.
Boats streamed to the battleship.
Suddenly...
Let's go and talk them out of it.
Do you hear that?
Don't shoot!
My boy is very ill.
The Cossacks.
The ship's guns roared in
reply to the massacre.
The target
- the Odessa Opera House.
At the enemy stronghold!
PART FIVE
THE MEETING WITH THE SQUADRON
Stormy meetings went on all day.
Odessa awaits her liberators!
If you land, the troops will join you.
We cannot land. The flag
squadron is moving on us.
The "Potemkin" prepared
to meet the squadron.
Night fell, a night
fraught with anxiety.
The squadron approached
in the dark.
The men were silent.
Squadron sighted!
All hands on deck!
To action stations!
Full steam ahead!
Meet them head on!
The "Potemkin" was escorted
by destroyer 267.
The attack began!
The squadron bore down
on the battleship.
Signal to them
to join us!
Join...
...us!
The enemy is within
firing range!
All against one.
One against all.
Will they...
open fire?
Brothers!
A thunderous hurrah
rang out.
The "Potemkin" passed through the squadron,
the flag of freedom fluttering over her.
THE END
director
Sergej M. Eisenstein
cast:
members of the Proletkult Theatre
sailors of the Black Sea fleet
Fishermen's association Sewastopol
inhabitants of Odessa
motto after Leo Trotzki,
Russia during the revolution
a reconstruction of the Russian premiere version,
Enno Patalas supervising,
Anna Bohn assistant