The Western and Atlantic Flyer
speeding into Marietta, Ga., in
Spring of 1861.
There were two loves in his life.
His engine,
And ---
'Fort Sumter has been fired upon.'
'Then the war is here.'
'Yes, dad, and I'm going to be
one of the first to enlist.'
'Aren't you going to enlist?'
'Your name?'
'Occupation?'
'Engineer on the Western and
Atlantic Railroad.'
'Don't enlist him. He is more
valuable to the South as an engineer.'
'We can't use you.'
'Occupation?'
'Bartender.'
'If you lose this war
don't blame me.'
'Did Johnnie enlist?'
'He didn't even get in line.'
'He's a disgrace to the South.'
'Why didn't you enlist?'
'They wouldn't take me.'
'Please don't lie -- I don't want
you to speak to me again until
you are in uniform.'
A year later. In a Union encampment
just North of Chattanooga.
General Thatcher, and his chief
spy, Captain Anderson.
'I know every foot of this railroad
from Marietta to Chattanooga -- and
with ten picked men I cannot fail.'
'We will enter the South as civilians coming
from the neutral state of Kentucky to
join the Southern cause.'
'At Big Shanty we will steal the
train while the passengers and
crew are at dinner, and proceeding '...
...' North we will burn every bridge,
cutting off the supplies of the
army now facing you.'
'Then the day you steal the train
I will have General Parker
advance to meet you.'
'As soon as I arrive I will let
you know how seriously father
is wounded.'
'Big Shanty. Twenty minutes
for dinner.'
'Three men stole my General.
I think they are deserters.'
'Why not stop and fight them?'
'I'm afraid they have us
greatly outnumbered.'
The Southern army facing
Chattanooga is ordered to
retreat.
General Parker's victorious
Nothern army advancing.
'There is only one man on that engine.'
In the enemy's country --
hopelessly lost, helplessly
cold and horribly hungry.
'At nine o'clock tomorrow
morning our supply trains will
meet and unite with General '...
...' Parker's army at the Rock River
bridge.'
'Then the army, backed by our supply
trains, will advance for a surprise
attack on the rebel's left flank.'
'Once our trains and troops cross
that bridge, nothing on earth can
stop us.'
'This girl was in the baggage
car when we stole the train, so
I thought it best to hold her.'
'We had better stay here until
daybreak to see where we are.'
'It was so brave of you to risk
your life, coming into the enemy's
country, just to save me.'
After a nice, quiet, refreshing
night's rest.
'We've got to get back to our
lines somehow and warn them of
this coming attack.'
'I will get that spy BEFORE he reaches
the Southern lines. You follow
with the supply trains as planned.'
'We must pick up more firewood.'
The Rock River bridge
The Northern division nearing
the bridge to meet the supply trains
'That bridge is not burned enough
to stop you, and my men will
ford the river.'
Heroes of the day.
'Is that your uniform?'
'I had to wear it to get
through the lines.'
'Take it off!'
'Enlist the Lieutenant.'
'Occupation?'
'Soldier.'