My name is Max.
My world is fire and blood.
Water Wars!! Water Wars!
Once, I was a cop.
A road warrior searching
for a righteous cause.
As the world fell...
each of us in our own way was broken.
It was hard to know who was more crazy.
Me...
Or everyone else.
Hello?
Where are you?
Where are you Max?
Here they come again.
Worming their way into the
black matter of my brain.
Help us Max! /
You promised to help us!
I tell myself...
they cannot touch me.
They are long dead.
I am the one...
who runs from both
the living AND the dead.
Hunted by scavengers...
Haunted by those I could not protect.
So I exist in this wasteland...
A man, reduced to a single instinct:
Survive.
Blood group O negative, high octane.
Universal donor.
Max?
Is that you?
Help us!
Max Where are you?!
Save me.
He made us die!
Tune!
We are War Boys!
War Boys!
Kamakrazee War Boys!
Fukushima.
Kamakrazee!
Hooked On!
Today we're headed to Gas Town!
Gas Town!
Today we haulin' Aqua Cola.
Aqua Cola!
Today we carry fruits and vegetables! /
Fruits and vegetables!
And today we carry mother's milk!
Mother's Milk!
Joe! Joe! Joe! Immortan Joe!
Give it up, for the Immortan Joe!!!
Once again, we send off my
War Rig to bring back...
guzzoline from Gas Town...
and bullets from the Bullet Farm!
Once again, I salute
to my Imperator...
Furiosa!
And I salute...
my half-life War Boys...
who will ride with me, eternal...
on the highways of Valhalla.
V8! V8! V8! V8!
I AM YOUR REDEEMER!
It is by my hand...
you will rise from the ashes...
of this world!
It's coming. Get ready.
Yes. Yes. The water comes.
Do not, my friends...
become addicted to water.
It will take hold of you...
and you will resent, it's absence.
Get out!
Get rid of them all!
Signal Gas Town.
Convoy's on it's way.
I got a War Boy
running on empty.
Hook-up that full-life.
Hey, careful!!
He's a universal donor.
Boss, we're not going to Gas Town?
Bullet Farm?
We're heading east!
I'll pass it down the line.
New orders!
Thunder up! Thunder up!
This is not a supply run!!
Go! Go!
What is this? What's going on??/
We're heading east.
Why? /
I don't know, that's the orders.
Hey Pa!!
You know about this?
You're produce ain't going to Gas Town.
She's gone off road...
into hostile territory.
Why would she do that Dad?
Lemme see! Lemme see!! I Rictus!
I wanna see!! I Rictus.
Go see what's agitating DAD!!
Splendid?!
Angharad?!!
OUR BABIES WILL NOT BE WARLORDS.
WHO KILLED THE WORLD?
Where are they?
They are not your property!!
Miss Giddy!!
You cannot own a human being.
WE ARE NOT THINGS.
Sooner or later someone pushes back!
WHERE IS SHE TAKING THEM?!!!
She didn't take them.
They begged her to go!
Where is she taking them?
A long way from you!!!
What's happened?
Slit!
What's going on? Slit!! I Treason!
Betrayal! An Imperator gone rogue.
Imperator? Who?
Furiosa! She took a lot of stuff
from Immortan Joe.
What stuff?
Breeders! His prized Breeders!!
He wants them back!
Not a hand laid on 'em.
By my deeds I honor him.
V8.
V8! V8! V8!
That's my wheel!! I I'm driving!
You're my lancer. /
I just promoted myself!!!
Not today. Today is my day!
Look at you. If you can't stand up,
you can't do war!!
He's right, son.
I'm not staying here dying a sloth!!
You're already a corpse.
I just need a little top-up. /
There's no time!!!
We take my Blood Bag.
We'll take my Blood Bag
and string him to the lancer's perch.
It's got a muzzle on it. It's a
raging feral!! I That's right!
High-octane crazy blood filling me up.
If I'm gonna die...
I'm gonna die historic
on the Fury Road!
Yeah! Yeah!!
Organic, hitch up his Blood Bag.
Right-o.
What else can they take from me?
They have my blood.
Now it's my car!
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
He looked at me!
He looked right at me! /
He was staring at your Blood Bag!
He turned his head! He looked
me straight in the eye!!
He was scanning the horizon!
No.
I am awaited!
I am awaited in Valhalla!!!!
FUCK!!!!!
Immortan!
Look! Hey look!!
Look!!
Boss!
We got vehicles from the Citadel.
They're firing flares.
They want reinforcements from
Gas Town and the Bullet Farm.
What is this??
Backup? Decoy??
It's a detour.
Eyes right!
Buzzards!!!
Buzzards right!! Eyes on! Eyes on!!
Should we turn around and
run 'em into our backup?
No! We're good.
We fang it!!
Thunder up! Here we go!!
Prepare the shooter!
Morsov!
War!
Ready!
She's ours Slit! She's ours!!
First, we get the buzzards off her back!
Ready to throw!
That's my head!!!
Get up! You can do it!
Morsov!
Morsov! I No!
WITNESS ME!!!
Witness! I Witness!!!
Witness!!! I Witness!
Mediocre Morsov!!
Mediocre!!!!
Get me in!
They are coming!
We can't breathe down there!!
Stay outta sight!!
NOW!!!
Back!
What happened?!
Hydraulics! Hydraulics!!
Now we bring home the booty.
She thinks she can lose us Dad!
She thinks we're stupid.
She thinks she can lose us
in there!
Fang it!
FANG IT!!!
Why can't you stop?
You! Outta the way! Out of the way!!!
What have you done?!
We need a counterweight.
Get the Blood Bag toward the back.
Burn them! Burn them!
Hey there!
Say bye bye to the neck!
We're going in Slit!
Come on! We almost got it!
Come on! Hold!
Oh what a day!
WHAT A LOVELY DAY!!
I'm the man...
who grabbed the sun...
riding to Valhalla!!!!
Witness me Blood Bag!!
Witness!!!
I live, I die, I live again!!
We're not going back.
Water.
You.
Angharad, is that just the wind...
or a furious fixation?
I got it!
Glory me Blood Bag!
We snagged her alive.
He's gonna shred her.
Shred Her!!
Bolt cutters.
Chain.
Hey, hey, HEY!!
Ohh look at them.
So shiny! So chrome.
He's gonna be so grateful!
We could ask for anything.
I want to drive the War Rig.
What will you ask for? /
That's MY Jacket!!
Sure.
I mean, you could ask for
more than a jacket.
We're going to the Green Place.
We're going to the Green Place
of Many Mothers.
How does it feel?
It hurts!
Out here everything hurts.
You wanna get through this?
Do as I say.
Now pick up what you can and run.
Filth!
Kill switches.
I set the sequence myself.
This Rig goes nowhere without me.
You can get in.
Not without them.
So we wait.
You're relying on the gratitude
of a very bad man.
You've already damaged one of his wives.
How grateful do you think he's gonna be?
You're sitting on 2000 horsepower
of Nitro-boosted war machine.
I think you've got a five minute headstart.
You want that thing off your face?!
Let's go!
Of all the legs you had to shoot,
that one was attached to his favorite.
You don't have to do it
just because he tells you.
What choice does she have? /
He's not gonna hurt us. He needs us.
Why? I To bargain.
He'll hurt us alright.
Do you think he's coming
to the Green Place?
He's a crazy lunatic who
likes to eat schlanger!
Ahh stay outta there.
Behind you.
Gas Town Boys.
Don't damage the goods.
What do you see?
Big rigs...
Polecats...
Flamers...
and there's the People Eater himself!
Coming to count the cost.
We dragging something out back!
I think it's the fuel pod.
No. NO!
I'll go.
Bitch! You traitored him!
No unnecessary killing!!
This War Boy wants me dead!! /
We agreed!!
He's kamakrazee!!
He just a kid at the end of his half-life!!
No! I live,
I die, I live again!!
Hold him! I Tie him up!
Throw him out!
Throw him!
You got more friends.
Bullet Farmer.
They're coming from the Bullet Farm. /
Yeah?
It's over. You can't defy him!
Just watch us mate!
He is the one who grabbed the sun. /
Look how slick he's fooled you War Boy!
He's a lying old man.
By his hand we'll all be lifted up!
That's why we have
his logo seared on our backs!
"Breeding stock!"
"Battle fodder!"
No, I am awaited!!
You're an old man's battle fodder.
Killing everyone and everything!!
We are not to blame.
Then who killed the world?!!
I made a deal up ahead.
Safe passage.
I don't know if it's still any good.
Get back in the hold.
Keep the hatch open.
I need you here.
You may have to drive the rig.
You.
You stay.
You stay there.
Whatever you do,
you can't be seen.
I'm supposed to be alone.
That was the deal.
Down here.
Hey.
What's your name?
What do I call you?
Does it matter?
Fine.
When I yell "Fool"...
you drive outta here
as fast as you can.
This is the sequence:
One. One. Two.
One.
Red. Black. Go.
You have it?
It's all here!
3000 gallons of guzzoline,
just like you asked!
I'm gonna unhitch the pod.
You drop the rocks.
You said:
"A few vehicles in pursuit.
Maybe."
We count three war parties!!!
Yeah well I got unlucky.
Let's do this!
FOOL!!!!!
That's our fuel!!!
Open the way for Ripsaw!
Once I'm over...
clear the rocks
and lead everyone through.
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
I got a War Boy!
Say's he was on the War Rig.
You! Climb aboard!
Hey! HEY!
I got his boot!
I got the Blood Bag's boot!!
Take me!
I've got his boot!!!
All of this for a family squabble.
Healthy babies.
Reload the clip.
I can't.
Gun!!!
Give me the gun!! /
It's not loaded yet!!
Now!
We had a deal!
Rictus!
The wives!
No more flames!!
Splendid!
That's my child!
MY PROPERTY!!!!
Immorta...
Immortan. If I get on the rig,
there's a way inside.
What is your name? I It's Nux.
I'll pike her in the spine.
Keep her breathing for ya!!
No.
Put a bullet in her skull.
Stop the rig. Return my property...
and I myself...
will carry you to the Gates of Valhalla!
Am I awaited?
You will ride eternal...
shiny and chrome.
Rictus!
Help him aboard!
Ready?
Here we go!
Mediocre!
Schlanger!
Look out!
Angharad!
Look out!!!
NO!!! I Angharad!!!
Stop!! Turn the rig around!!
Go back for her!!!
No.
Tell him to turn the rig around!!
Did you see it?
She went under the wheels.
Did you SEE it?!
She went under the wheels!
We keep moving!
NO!! I WE KEEP MOVING!!
He doesn't know what he's talking about!
Whatever happens,
we're going to the Green Place!
What stupid Green Place!
We don't even know where it is!
Are you alright? GO ON! GO ON!!!
Cheedo!
Cheedo, don't be stupid.
Stop!
He'll forgive us.
I know he will.
There's no going back!
We were his treasures! I Cheedo!
We were protected!
He gave us a life of luxury!
What's wrong with that? /
We are not things!!
No!
Cheedo, we are not things!
We are not THINGS. /
I don't want to hear that again!
They were her words!
And now she's dead!
Wring your hands and tear your hair,
but you're not going back there.
You're not going back to him.
Angharad!
Come on!
So um...
where is this...
this Green Place?
It's a long night's run, heading east.
We need inventory.
I want you to match every
gun with it's bullets.
I'm gonna go down and do some repairs.
We need someone down the back.
I'll go.
No.
I want you to stay together.
I can do it.
What are you doing here?
He saw it.
He saw it all.
My own blood bag driving
the rig that killed her.
Stop doing that.
Stop.
Three times the gates were open to me.
What gates?
I was awaited in Valhalla.
They were calling my name.
I should be walking with the Immortan.
Feasting with the heroes of all time.
I'd say it was your
manifest destiny not to.
I thought I was being
spared for something great.
I got to... drive a pursuit vehicle.
For a while even Larry and Barry
stop chewing on my windpipe.
Who're Larry and Barry?
My mates.
Larry and Barry.
If they don't get me,
the Night Fevers will.
We only got four for big boy here,
so he's all but useless.
But...
we can squirt off this little pinky
about 29 times.
Angharad used to call it Anti-seed.
Plant one and watch the thing die.
We are down 30000 units of gasoline...
19 canisters of nitro...
12 assault bikes...
7 pursuit vehicles.
My deficit mounts.
And now, sir...
you, have us stuck in a quagmire!
Hey Joe!
Boss!
Your girl is breathing her last!
What about the child?
Are you coming Brother?!
Wait!
It's gone awful quiet in there.
Take it out!
Get it Out!!!
Come on! I've been called to the torture!
Patience!
Oh you stay here with your grief daddy!
I'll fetch 'em for ya. /
Be careful! Protect the assets!!
Just one angry shot!...
for Furiosa.
Hut!
Crying shame.
Another month...
could've been a viable human!
Was it a male?
A-One Alpha Prime.
Hey Rictus!
You lost a baby brother!
Perfect in every way.
I had a baby brother!!
I had a little baby brother!!!
And he was perfect!!
Perfect in every way!!!
Come on.
You wouldn't wanna shoot the wives sir.
He wants to help!
Who?!
The War Boy!!
Where did he come from?! /
I thought we threw him off the rig!!
There is high ground,
just beyond that thing!
He means the tree.
Yeah. Tree!
Leave him to me!
Say, anyone notice that bright light?
Approaching gunfire?
Get out. /
I can do this. I know this machine.
He does. He's a Revhead.
You got two left!
On him.
Don't breathe.
Hey! Hey!! Hey!!!
War Boy!!
I'll use the winch! Around the tree thing.
Take this.
Let's get the engine plates.
You drive the rig!
Hold the flare! /
I am holding the flare!!
Closer! /
It's right in front of your eyes!!
Hut! HUTTT!!!!
Blood Bag!
I am the scales of justice!
Conductor of the choir of death!
Sing for the flock!!
Sing Brother! Sing!! SINGGGG!!!!
Don't they know they're shooting at us?!
Guns reload!!!
I never thought I would do
something as shiny as that!
How're the engines?
Very hot and real thirsty.
Hey. You need to take the rig
half a click down the track.
What if you're not back
by the time the engines are cooled?
Well you keep moving!
What do you suppose he's gonna do?
Retaliate first.
Let's go!
Are you hurt?
You're bleeding.
That's not his blood.
What is this?
It's Mother's Milk.
It's okay.
Sleep.
Get some rest.
How do you know this place even exists?
I was born there.
Why'd you leave?
I didn't.
I was taken as a child.
Stolen.
You've done this before?
Many times.
Now that I drive a War Rig...
this is the best shot
I'll ever have.
And them?
They are looking for hope.
What about you?
Redemption.
Hey. What's that?
I remember something like that.
Help me!
HELP ME!!!!
Please, help me!
Please!
That's bait.
Stay in the Rig.
Hurry! Please, hurry up!
They will be back!
I'm one of the Vuvalini!
From the Many Mothers!
My initiate mother was Katie Concannon!
I am the daughter of Mary Jo Bassa.
My clan was Swaddle Dog!
It's me.
There's something in the eyes.
Perhaps she is Jo Bassa's child.
This is our Furiosa.
How long has it been?
Seven thousand days.
Plus the ones I don't remember.
Furiosa.
What happened to your mother?
She died.
On the 3rd day.
From where did you come?
The West. Citadel.
Beyond the mountains.
The men. Who are they?
They're reliable.
They helped us get here.
Where did you find
such creatures?
So soft.
This one has all her teeth!
I can't wait for them to see it.
See?
See what?
Home.
The Green Place.
But if you came from the West...
you passed it.
The crows.
The creepy place with all the crows.
The soil. I We had to get out.
We had no water. /
And water was filth.
It was sour.
Then the crows came.
We couldn't grow anything.
Where are the others?
What others?
The Many Mothers.
We're the only ones left.
Look.
That's what you'd call a satellite.
Miss Giddy told us about those.
They used to bounce messages
across the Earth.
Shows. Everyone in the old world
had a show.
Do you think there's still
somebody out there?
Sending shows?
Who knows?
Those are the Plains of Silence.
Stay right where you are little Joey.
Kinda lost it's novelty out here.
You having a baby?
Warlord Junior.
Gonna be so ugly.
It could be a girl.
You killed people with that do ya?
Killed everyone I met out here.
Headshots. All. Snap!
Right in the medulla.
I thought you girls were above all that.
Come here.
Take a peek in.
Seeds!
These are from home.
Heirlooms. The real thing!
I plant one every chance I get.
Where?
So far nothings took.
Earth's too sour.
Ohh so many different kinds.
Trees, flowers, fruit.
Back then everyone had their fill!
Back then, there was no
need to snap anybody!
Can I talk to you?
I've talked with the others.
We're never going to have a better chance
to make it across the salt.
If we leave the rig here, and load the
motorcycles up with as much as we can...
we can be able to ride for 160 days.
One of those bikes is yours.
Fully loaded.
You're more than welcome to come with us.
N..No, I make my own way.
You know, hope is a mistake.
If you can't fix what's broken, you'll...
You'll go insane.
Where are you, Max?
Where are you?
Help us.
You promised to help us.
Come on Pa! Let's go!
Alright.
THIS, is your way home.
We go back?
Back? I Yeah.
I thought you weren't insane anymore.
What are they saying?
He wants to go back from where they came.
The Citadel.
What's there to find at the Citadel??
Green.
And water!
There is a ridiculous amounts of
clear water. And a lot of crops.
It's got everything you need.
As long as you're not afraid of heights.
Where does the water come from?
He pumps it out from deep under the earth.
Calls it 'Aqua Cola',
and claims it all for himself.
And because he owns it,
he owns all of us.
I don't like him already.
It'll take two weeks just to
scale a wall of mountains.
No.
I suggest we go back the same way we came.
Through the canyon.
It's open. We know that. Right?
He brought all his war parties through!
So, we take the War Rig and we charge
it right through the middle of 'em.
We can decouple the tank at the pass...
shut it off behind us.
Ka-Boom!!
And how exactly do we take the Citadel?
Assuming we're still alive by then?
If we can block the pass,
it'll be easy.
All that's left are his War Pups,
and War Boys too sick to fight.
And we'll be with Nux.
He's a War Boy.
He'll be bringing us home.
Bringing back what's
stolen, as he's meant to.
Yeah.
Feels like hope.
I like this plan.
We can start again!
Just like the old days!
Look.
It will be a hard day.
But I guarantee you 160
days riding that way...
there's nothing but salt.
At least that way, y'know
we might be able to...
together...
come across some kind of redemption.
War Rig!
It's the War Rig!
That's them.
Why're they going back?
Do they wish to surrender?
They're heading for the canyon.
They're going back, to the Citadel!!!
They know it's undefended!!
Bollocks!
What are you doing? I Praying.
To whom?
Anyone that's listening.
Here we go girls!
That's mine!!
They'll try to get in front of us!
Spike our wheels!!
Don't blow my engines!
Gonna nudge 'em. Just a little.
You filth!! You traitored him?!
Go.
Gotta back off! Engine one is gone!
Two's about to blow!
Great!
Are you a Black Thumb?
Alright, engine one. Now!
You and me. 5th wheel.
We'll unhook the tank.
One man, one bullet.
I can't see. I Maadi.
I can't see.
Hey!
They've got spears and plows!
They're holding us back!
Leave three bolts. Three.
Hey, you!
Are you okay?!
I think she's hurt!
Hey!
NO!!!
Hey! Stay with me!
Stay with me.  / Stay with me!
Hey! Are you there?
VALHALLA!!!!!
Hey!
Engine one's good.
For now.
She's hurt!!!
She's hurt real bad!!
Do you hear that?
We're gonna see two airborne V8s!
I'm gonna need you to drive.
I'll get him out of our way.
Rictus!
Take me!
Cheedo! What are you doing?
Good girl.
Come here! I NO!!!!
Big Boy.
Here! Here!!
Remember me?!!
He's dead!
When you're across safe, I'll
jam the throttle and follow you!
Come on!
Hurry! We're nearly at the pass.
W I t n e s s M e!!
Rictus!
Why's she making that noise?
She's pumping air into her chest cavity.
She's collapsing her lungs...
one breath at a time.
I know.
I'm so sorry!
I know. I know!
Hold.
Okay.
Put there. Press firmly.
Hey!
Hey!!
Home!
No. No! No, no! No!!
She's exsanguinated.
Drained all her blood!!
Hold this.
Needle.
Come on!
Take this!
Keep her awake.
Furiosa!!
Okay!
That's it.
Hold it up!
Okay.
Sorry.
There you go. Okay!
Max.
My name is Max!
That's my name.
Brake!
Reveal yourself!
He's got something.
It's Immortan Joe!
IMMORTAN JOE IS DEAD!!!
Furiosa!
She's back!
Let them up!!
Let them up!!!
Let them up!!!!
LET THEM UP!!!!!
'Where must we go...
we who wander this wasteland
in search of our better selves?'
The First History Man.