These hills here are full of Apaches.
They've burnt every
ranch building in sight.
He had a brush with them last night.
Says they're being stirred up
by Geronimo.
How do we know he isn't lying?
No. He's a Cheyenne.
They hate Apaches worse than we do.
- Clear the wires for Lordsburg.
- That's Lordsburg now, sir.
They seem to have something
very urgent to tell you, sir.
- Well, what's wrong?
- The line went dead, sir.
- What have you got there?
- Only the first word, sir.
- How'd it go, Buck?
- Oh, so-so.
Got the payroll for the mining company?
Yes sir, right here in this box.
Good, give me a lift here, Jim,
would you?
Jim, I'll pay you that two bits
when I come through.
- Okay, Buck.
- Now you kids get away from that wheel.
Well sir, we ran into a little snow
up there. It weren't bad, though.
But you fellows better prepare
for a good frost.
Passengers out for Tonto.
You better get out and stretch
your legs, I mean your limbs, ma'am.
We're gonna change horses here.
Is there a place here where
I can get a cup of tea?
Well yes, ma'am, you can get a cup of
coffee at the hotel across the street.
- Thank you, driver.
- You look a little...
- I'll be all right, thank you.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Why, Lucy Mallory!
- Nancy!
- How are you, Captain Whitney?
- Fine thanks, Mrs. Mallory.
Why, whatever are you doing in Arizona?
I'm joining Richard in Lordsburg.
He's there with his troops.
He's a lot nearer than that.
He's been ordered to Dry Fork.
Why that's the next stop
of the stagecoach.
You'll be with your husband
in a few hours.
I'm so glad to see you, Lucy.
Sit down and have a cup of coffee.
- You must be tired from that long trip.
- Who is that gentleman?
- Hardly a gentleman, Mrs. Mallory.
- I should think not!
He's a notorious gambler.
Hello Mitch, howdy Frank. Marshall,
I'm looking for my shotgun guard.
Is he here?
Out with the posse, Buck,
trying to catch the Ringo Kid.
- I thought Ringo was in the pen.
- He was.
Busted out? Well, good for him.
My guess, the Kid's aimin' to get even
with them Plummer boys.
Their testimony sent him
to the penitentiary.
Well all I got to say is he better stay
away from that there Luke Plummer.
By gosh, Luke's run all of
Ringo's friends out of Lordsburg.
Why, the last trip there I seen him
hit a rancher on the head...
...with the barrel of his gun.
He just laid it wide open
like a butchered steer.
- You seen Luke Plummer in Lordsburg?
- Yes siree!
You boys take care of the office
for a couple of days.
I'm going to Lordsburg with Buck.
I'm going to ride shotgun!
Oh gosh, when'll I learn to keep
my big mouth shut?
Here's the payroll, Mr. Gatewood.
You know, ever since I opened this bank,
I've been trying to tell those people...
...to deposit their payroll
six months in advance.
It's good sound business.
It's good business for you,
Mr. Gatewood.
Well, there's your receipt, $50,000.
And remember this: What's good
for the banks, is good for the country.
Get out.
I'm keeping your trunk, 'cause
you ain't paid your rent!
"Is this the face that wrecked
a thousand ships...
"...and burned the towerless
tops of llium?
"Farewell, fair Helen!"
Can they make me leave town
when I don't want to go?
- Do I have to go?
- Dallas, don't you go makin' no fuss.
Do I have to go, Doc,
just because they say so?
Now Dallas, I've got my orders.
Don't blame these ladies.
- It ain't them.
- It is them!
Doc, haven't I any right to live?
What have I done?
We're the victims of a foul disease
called social prejudice, my child.
These dear ladies of
the Law and Order League...
...are scouring out
the dregs of the town.
Come on, be a proud,
glorified dreg, like me.
You get goin', Doc, you're drunk.
Two of a kind.
Just two of a kind.
Take my arm, Madame la Comtesse!
The tumbrel awaits, to the guillotine!
Wait till I get my badge, girls.
I'll join you.
If ever you go east, brother,
come out to our house for dinner.
No one in Kansas City, Kansas, sets
a better table than my dear wife Violet.
Jerry, I admit as one man
to another, that...
...economically, I haven't been
of much value to you, but...
...suppose you could put one on credit.
If talk was money, Doc,
you'd be the best customer I got.
- I'm leaving town, Jerry.
- Honest?
Yes, old friend, and I thought you might,
out of memory of our many happy...
All right, Doc. Just this one.
Thank you, Jerry.
Here's a man goin' on
the stagecoach with you.
He's an easterner from
Kansas City, Missouri.
Kansas City, Kansas, brother.
Your health, Reverend.
I'm not a clergyman.
My name is Peacock. I'm a...
He's a whisky drummer.
- Well how are you Mr. Haycock?
- Peacock.
Don't tell me sir, I know, I know.
A familiar name and an honored name.
I never forget the face of a friend.
Samples?
Rye.
I want $5, Henry.
Certainly, my dear. Certainly.
Well, what is it to be this time,
my dear? A pair of shoes...
I want to pay the butcher.
Dinner is at 12 o'clock.
Don't worry, my dear. I'll be there.
I've invited the ladies
of the Law and Order League.
All aboard for Dry Fork,
Apache Wells...
...Lee's Ferry and Lordsburg!
- I'll take that, Dallas.
- Oh, thanks.
In you go, Dallas,
and a pleasant voyage.
- Here's your baggage, Doc.
- Thank you, thank you my friend.
Curley, my shingle.
Carry it with honor.
- I'll take it, Doctor.
- Oh no, no trouble at all.
No trouble at all.
I'll carry it on my lap.
Here we go! Here we go, Reverend.
Mrs. Whitney, you're not going to let
your friend travel with that creature!
She's right, Lucy. And besides,
you're not well enough to travel.
It's only a few hours, Nancy.
I'm quite all right.
But you shouldn't travel a step
without a doctor.
There is a doctor, dear.
The driver told me.
Doctor? Doc Boone?
Why, he couldn't doctor a horse!
Lucy darling, you must be very careful.
Take good care of yourself.
- Lady folks ride faces forward, please.
- There you go!
- Pleasant journey, Mrs. Mallory.
- Thank you. Good-bye!
Like an angel in the jungle.
- A very wild jungle.
- What are you doing, Hatfield?
Talking to yourself?
You wouldn't understand, cowboy.
You've never seen an angel.
Nor a gentlewoman.
Nor a great lady. I raise, gentlemen.
Captain Sickels asks for you to deliver
this despatch in Lordsburg...
...the moment you arrive.
The telegraph line has been cut.
We're going with you as far as
the noon station at Dry Fork.
There'll be a troop of Cavalry there,
and they'll take you on to Apache Wells.
From Apache Wells you'll have another
escort of soldiers into Lordsburg.
You must warn your passengers that
they travel at their own risk.
At their own risk?
Well, what's the trouble, Lieutenant?
Geronimo.
Geronimo? Well, then I ain't goin'...
Will you sit down?
Of course the Army has no authority
over you gentlemen.
If you think it's unsafe
to make the trip...
This stage is going to Lordsburg.
If you think it ain't safe
to ride along with us...
...I figure we can get there
without you soldier boys.
I have my orders, sir.
And I always obey orders.
Did you all hear what
the Lieutenant said?
Yes, we heard.
Well me and Buck are taking
this coach through...
...passengers or not. Now whoever
wants to get out, can get out.
Courage, courage, Reverend.
Ladies first.
How 'bout you, Dallas?
What are they trying to do?
Scare somebody?
They got me in here, now let them
try to put me out.
There are worse things than Apaches.
If you'll take my advice, ma'am...
...you won't take this trip.
My husband is with his troops
in Dry Fork.
If he's in danger,
I want to be with him.
You see, brother, I have a wife
and five children...
Then you're a man. By all the powers
that be, Reverend, you're a man.
- All right, folks.
- Marshall!
Make room for one more.
I'm offering my protection
to this lady.
I can shoot fairly straight
if there's need for it.
That's been proved
too many times, Hatfield.
All right, get in. We're late.
- May I trouble you to move over, sir?
- Oh yes, yes of course.
Close the door.
Oh Curley, we...
Get going, Buck!
Bessie, Barney, Belle!
Farewell, ladies!
Sweetheart, come on now, girl!
- Room for another passenger?
- Sure is, Mr. Gatewood.
- Going to Lordsburg?
- Yes, I just got a telegram.
Had to stop to pack this bag...
If there's anything I don't like
it's driving a stagecoach...
...through Apache country.
Funny catching Gatewood
outside of town that way.
I just took this job ten years ago
so I could make enough money...
...to marry my Mexican girl, Julietta...
...and I been workin' hard at it
ever since.
- At marriage?
- Why certainly.
My wife's got more relatives
than anyone you ever did see.
I bet I'm feedin'
half the state of Chihuahua.
Didn't it seem funny to you
about Gatewood?
Yeah, and then what do I get to eat
when I get home in Lordsburg?
Nothin' but frijole beans, that's all.
Nothin' but beans, beans, beans!
Excuse me, ladies.
Close quarters.
Warm today.
Your wife made it warm
for me, Gatewood.
She was chairman of
our farewell committee.
Fine looking bunch of
soldier boys back there.
Always gives me great pride
in my country...
...when I see such fine young men
in the U.S. Army.
Anybody know where they're going?
Brother, aren't you aware
of what's happened?
Happened? I don't follow you, Reverend.
I'm not a clergyman, I'm a...
My friend's a whisky drummer.
We're all going to be scalped, Gatewood.
Massacred in one fell swoop.
That's why the soldiers are with us.
He's joking, of course.
Oh no, he's not. Oh dear no.
I wish he were.
It's that old Apache butcher...
...Geronimo.
Nice name for a butcher.
He's jumped the reservation.
He's on the war path.
Geronimo? Why weren't the passengers
notified? Why wasn't I told?
We were told, Gatewood.
Weren't you told...
...when you got that message
from Lordsburg?
Oh yes. Yes, of course.
I forgot.
Now, doggone it, they're bringing up
her grandfather...
...all the way from Mexico
to live with us.
I can't figure out how
he got that message.
- Who, her grandfather?
- No, Gatewood.
He said he got a message.
The telegraph line ain't workin'.
Hold it!
Hey look, it's Ringo!
- Hello, Kid.
- Hello, Curley.
Hi ya, Buck. How's your folks?
Oh, just fine Ringo...
...except my grandfather came up...
- Shut up!
Didn't expect to see you ridin' shotgun
on this run, Marshall.
- Goin' to Lordsburg?
- I figured you'd be there by this time.
No.
Lame horse.
Well, it looks like you've
got another passenger.
I'll take the Winchester.
You may need me and
this Winchester, Curley.
I saw a ranch house burnin' last night.
You don't understand, Kid.
You're under arrest.
- Everything all right, Marshall?
- Everything's all right, Lieutenant.
Hope I ain't crowdin' you folks none.
The more the merrier.
Ain't Ringo a fine boy?
I think so.
You're just smarter than a trade rat.
You knew all the time
that he was going to Lordsburg.
Reckon what he meant,
he saw ranch houses burnin'?
Apaches.
So you're the notorious Ringo Kid.
My friends just call me Ringo.
Nickname I had as a kid.
Right name's Henry.
Seems to me I knew your family, Henry.
Didn't I fix your arm when you were...
oh, bucked off a horse?
- Are you Doc Boone?
- I certainly am.
Let's see. I just been honorably
discharged from the Union Army...
...after the War of the Rebellion.
You mean the war for
the Southern Confederacy, sir.
I mean nothing of the kind, sir.
That was my kid brother, broke his arm.
You did a good job, Doc.
Even if you was drunk.
Thank you, son.
Professional compliments
are always pleasing.
What happened to that boy,
whose arm I fixed?
He was murdered.
Put out that cigar!
You're annoying this lady.
Excuse me, madam.
Being so partial to the weed myself,
I sometimes forget that...
...it disagrees with others.
A gentleman doesn't smoke
in the presence of a lady.
Three weeks ago I took a bullet out of
a man who was shot by a gentleman.
The bullet was in his back!
- Do you mean to insinuate...
- Sit down, Mister.
The Doc don't mean no harm.
Be careful of old Bessie
up there, now.
If it isn't my old friend
Sergeant Billy Pickett!
- How are you, Billy?
- He's fine, Doctor!
Mighty glad to see you!
Great heavens above!
We didn't figure on no stagecoach
coming through.
With them Apaches raisin' Cain.
- I was just tellin' Billy to hitch up...
- Now wait a minute!
Do you mean to say that there are
no troops at this station?
Ain't no soldiers here,
but what you see.
But my husband, Captain Mallory,
I was told he was here.
Well deary, got orders to drive
the soldiers to Apache Wells.
- Well that means we gotta go back.
- I can't go back!
Now look here, driver, you started
this coach for Lordsburg...
...and it's your duty to get there!
And it's your duty, young man,
to come along with us!
It's my duty, Mr. Gatewood,
to obey orders. I'm sorry, sir.
If the soldiers go back, Lieutenant,
that means we all have to go back?
My orders are to return
from here immediately.
And I can't disobey those orders.
I think we can get through
all right, Curley.
Oh, now don't egg him on, Kid.
I'm drivin' this here outfit, and...
...well, if the soldiers go back,
so am I.
I call this a desertion of duty!
I'll report you to
your superior officer!
And if necessary,
I'll take the matter up at Washington.
That's your privilege, sir.
But if you give us any trouble here...
...l'll have to put you under restraint.
Now don't lose your temper.
Don't lose your temper.
I'll tell you how we'll settle it.
We'll take a vote. Inside, everybody.
- Come on, Buck.
- Oh, Curley, I don't want to go.
Now you girls set yourselves down,
and I'll get you something to eat.
Now folks, if we push on, we can be
in Apache Wells by sundown.
The soldiers there will give us
an escort as far as the ferry.
Then it's only a hoot an' a holler
into Lordsburg.
We've got four men
who can handle firearms.
Five with you, Ringo.
Doc can shoot, if sober.
I can shoot? I can shoot?!
Now, Mrs. Mallory, I ain't
gonna put a lady in danger...
...without she votes for it.
I've traveled all the way here
from Virginia.
I'm determined to get to my husband.
I won't be separated any longer.
- What's your vote, mister?
- Where are your manners, Curley?
Ain't you gonna ask
the other lady first?
Well, what do you say?
What difference does it make?
It doesn't matter.
I vote that we go on.
I demand it.
I'm standing on my legal rights.
What do you say, Hatfield?
- Lordsburg.
- Four.
- You, Doc?
- I'm not only a philosopher, sir.
I'm a fatalist. Somewhere, sometime
there may be the right bullet...
...or the wrong bottle...
...waiting for Josiah Boone.
- Why worry when or where?
- Yes or no?
Having that philosophy, sir,
I've always courted danger.
During the late war, when I had
the honor to serve the Union...
...under our great president,
Abraham Lincoln...
...and General Phil Sheridan,
well sir...
...I fought 'mid shock and shell
and cannon roar.
Do you want to go back or not?
No.
I want another drink.
That's five.
How about you, Mr. Hancock?
Peacock. I'd like to go on,
brother. I want to reach...
...the bosom of my dear family,
in Kansas City, Kansas...
...as quickly as possible. But I may
never reach that bosom if we go on.
So, under the circumstances,
you understand, brother...
...I think it best we go back
with the bosoms...
...I mean, the soldiers.
One against.
Well, Buck?
Buck says "aye", that's six.
I'm voting your proxy, Kid,
and you go with me.
Ain't nothin' keepin' me out
of Lordsburg, Curley.
There sure ain't. Well folks,
that settles it, we're goin' through.
Sit down, folks, and eat your grub.
Come on Buck, we'll change them horses.
- But Curley, ain't we gonna eat?
- You can eat later!
Here you go, folks.
Food's on the table, help yourselves.
You've got a long ride ahead of you.
You ain't drinkin' Billy?
Sit down here, ma'am.
Thanks.
May I find you another place,
Mrs. Mallory?
It's cooler by the window.
Thank you.
Looks like I got the plague, don't it?
- No... no it's not you.
- Well, I guess you can't...
...break out of prison and into society
in the same week.
Please... please.
- You're ill, Mrs. Mallory.
- No, it's just that I...
I'll be all right.
You've been very kind. Why?
In the world I live in, one doesn't
often meet a lady, Mrs. Mallory.
Have you ever been in Virginia?
I was in your father's regiment.
I should remember your name.
You're Mr. Hatfield.
That's what I'm called, yes.
Why do you look at me like that?
I'm just trying to remember.
Ain't I seen you
someplace before, ma'am?
No, you haven't.
I wish I had, though.
I know you, I mean...
...I know who you are. I guess
everybody in the territory does.
Well, I used to be
a good cowhand, but...
...things happen.
Yeah, that's it.
Things happen.
So now they'll take you back to prison.
Not till I finish a job, in Lordsburg.
But you can't.
You're going there as a prisoner.
All aboard for Apache Wells, Lee's...
Ready folks, the horses are changed.
We better get going.
...and Lordsburg, maybe.
All right get going, Ringo.
Mrs. Pickett, tell Billy
the buckboard is all ready.
- Right, Marshall, we're ready.
- Come on, folks, let's go.
- What did you say?
- Nothin'.
Well why don't you say somethin'?
A fella gets nervous...
...sittin' here like a dummy, with
nothin' to think about but the Indians.
You say something, you've been
sittin' there all day talkin'...
...without makin' any sense!
All right, I'll say somethin'
that makes sense.
If I was you, I'd let 'em shoot it out.
- Let who?
- Luke Plummer and the Kid.
There'd be a lot more peace in
this territory if that Luke Plummer...
...was so full of lead
he couldn't hold his liquor!
I ain't sayin' I don't share
your sentiments, Buck.
- But you're a born fool.
- Oh, I know that.
In the first place, Luke would kill
the Kid in a gun fight.
In the second place,
if Luke did get shot...
...he's got two brothers
just as ornery as he is.
No, the only safe place for Ringo
is in the pen.
And I aim to get him there
in one piece.
Well I'll be doggoned if I didn't
do you an injury, Curley.
- I figured you were after the reward.
- Reward?
Why, the Kid's old man and me
was friends.
We used to punch cattle together.
Besides, I could use that $500 in gold.
I can't get over the impertinence
of that young lieutenant.
I'll make it warm for that shavetail!
I'll report him to Washington!
We pay taxes to the government
and what do we get?
Not even protection from the Army!
I don't know what
the government is coming to.
Instead of protecting businessmen,
it pokes its nose into business.
Why they're even talking now
about having bank examiners.
As if we bankers don't know
how to run our own banks!
At home I actually have a letter
from a popinjay official...
...saying they were going
to inspect my books!
I have a slogan that should be placed
on every newspaper in the country.
America for Americans! The government
must not interfere with business!
Reduce taxes! Our national debt
is something shocking!
Over one billion dollars a year!
What this country needs is
a businessman for president.
What this country needs is more fuddle.
What?
Fuddle!
You're drunk, sir!
I'm happy, Gatewood.
How come you're taking this route?
It's gonna be cold up there.
I'm using my head. Those beach-crowd
Apaches don't like snow.
Maybe you'd like to...
sit next to me.
You could put your head on my shoulder.
No, thank you.
How are you feeling, Mrs. Mallory?
Is there any water?
Driver, canteen please.
Just a minute, Mrs. Mallory.
Haven't I seen this crest before?
Isn't this from Greenfield Manor?
I wouldn't know, Mrs. Mallory.
I won this cup on a wager.
How about the other lady?
Thanks.
Sorry...
...no silver cups.
This is fine!
Please, Doctor.
Howdy, Chris, seven hours from
Dry Fork, pretty fast drivin', amigo!
Get the folks a bite to eat,
while we change the horses.
We're pushing right on to Lordsburg.
You come without soldiers?
Oh, we weren't scared. We didn't see
one Apache, did we Curley?
- Where's the cavalry, Chris?
- Where's the soldiers?
There ain't no soldiers.
Soldiers are gone!
Where's Captain Mallory?
Where's my husband? Where is he?
- You his wife, I think?
- Yes, where is he?
- Did he go with his men?
- S, seora.
A little, what you call, skirmish...
...with the Apaches last night.
Soldiers take Captain Mallory
to Lordsburg.
I think he get hurt, maybe.
Badly?
S, seora. I think so.
I think so.
I'm awfully sorry.
If there's anything I can...
I'm quite all right, thank you.
Marshall, come here quickly!
Come on, Doc.
Let's go, Doc.
A sick woman on our hands!
That's all we needed!
We're in a fine fix, my friends.
It's a fine country we're living in!
The Army has no right to leave
a public place like this undefended.
It looks to me like the Army's
got its hands pretty full, mister.
- Have you a wife?
- S, seora. I think...
Call her.
Ringo, go in the kitchen and get
some hot water. Lots of hot water.
- Please.
- Yes, ma'am.
A fine member of the medical profession.
Drunken beast!
Give me coffee.
Black coffee.
Lots of it.
More, more, more!
Blacker, stronger.
Keep it comin', Curley!
You'll have it comin' out
your ears in a minute.
- Now drink it down, Doc.
- Get it down.
Isn't that drunken swine sober yet?
He's doing the best he can!
Well, hurry!
- How do you feel?
- Fine.
Thanks, again.
Sit down here, Doc.
Keep the fire going, Chris.
Plenty of hot water.
Savages!
That's my wife, Yakima, my squaw.
Yes, but she's... she's... savage!
S, seor, she a little bit savage,
I think.
Something funny about this.
That woman's an Apache.
Sure, she one of Geronimo's people.
I think, maybe not so bad
to have Apache wife, eh?
Apache don't bother me, I think.
- All right, Doc?
- All right.
All right, Dallas.
It's them vaqueros,
they've run away.
Yeah, with the spare horses.
Them coyotes give me
the creeps. That sounds...
...well it sounds just like a baby.
It's a baby!
It's a little girl.
Well, I'll be doggoned!
Why didn't somebody tell me?
How's Mrs. Mallory?
She's going to be all right.
Well, I'll be doggoned.
Did you know?
Don't do that!
Come on, boys,
three cheers for old Doc Boone!
- Hip hip...
- Quiet!
- Well we oughta be...
Mrs. Mallory.
I know why you want
to go to Lordsburg.
I like you.
I know your papa.
He was good friend of mine.
If you know who in Lordsburg,
you stay away, I think.
- You mean Luke Plummer?
- Luke, lke and Hank.
All there together. I saw them.
- Sure of that, Chris?
- Sure, I can tell you the truth.
- I know.
- Thanks. That's all I wanted to know.
You crazy if you go.
I think you stay away, Kid.
Three against one is no good!
Startin' to go too far, Ms. Dallas.
Apaches like to sneak up
and pick off strays.
You... visitin' in Lordsburg?
No, I have friends there.
And maybe I can find work.
Look, Kid, why don't you try
to escape? Why don't you get away?
I aim to, in Lordsburg.
Why Lordsburg? Why don't you make
for the border now?
My father and brother were shot down
by the Plummer boys.
Guess you don't know how it feels
to lose your own folks that way.
I lost mine when I was a kid.
There was a massacre
on Superstition Mountain.
That's tough.
Especially on a girl.
Well, you gotta live,
no matter what happens.
Yeah, that's it.
Look, Ms. Dallas.
You got no folks.
Neither have I, and well...
...maybe I'm takin' a lot
for granted, but...
...I watched you with that baby.
That other woman's baby.
You looked...
I still got a ranch across
the border...
...and it's a nice place.
A real nice place.
Trees, grass, water...
There's a cabin, half-built.
A man could live there.
And a woman.
Will you go?
But you don't know me.
You don't know who I am.
I know all I want to know.
Will you go?
Don't talk like that!
What are you doing out here, Kid?
Stick close to the reservation.
- What's wrong, Chris?
- My wife Yakima, she ran away!
When I woke up she was gone!
The way you come bustin' in here,
you'd think...
Excuse me, Kid.
Come bustin' in here,
you'd think we were being attacked!
You can find another wife.
Sure I can find another wife.
But she take my rifle and my horse.
Oh, I never sell her.
I love her so much.
I beat her with a whip
and she never get tired.
- Your wife?
- No, my horse.
I can find another wife, easy yes.
But not a horse like that.
I knew that woman was a thief, l...
- What's the matter with you, Gatewood?
- My valise! Where's my valise?
Which one of you's got it?
Here it is, I was usin' it as a pillow.
I didn't think...
I thought I told you to keep
your hands off my things!
That squaw of yours'll find some Apaches
and bring 'em back here.
My wife's people
don't bother me, I think.
Well, they bother me, I think.
Is this bar open?
Sure, all the time, seor, s!
Here you are, Doc.
Well, what are we wasting time for?
Let's make a break for it.
We've got a sick woman to think of.
You want her to stay here
and be butchered with the rest of us?
Why don't you think of
somebody else for once in your...
Easy, easy! Keep it quiet, boys.
Quiet!
We ain't been butchered yet!
You're right.
We'd better get going for Lordsburg
as soon as we can.
It might be a good idea, Curley if...
...the Doc took a look
at the patient.
Yeah, and little Coyote.
You'll join me, Doctor?
No, thanks.
Good morning.
Well, you're looking pretty chipper.
You're up early, Dallas.
She didn't go to bed, Doctor.
I'm afraid she sat up all night,
while I slept.
Oh, I slept a lot in the chair.
Well, anyway it was nice
to stay awake and hold the baby.
Well, we've got to get you
to Lordsburg, little Coyote.
That's what the boys christened her
last night when she squalled.
- Little Coyote. How do you feel?
- Fine, thanks.
A little tired.
- Doctor, do you think my husband...
- Never mind him.
The best medicine he can have
is to see you two safe and sound.
You just make up your mind
you're going to get there.
- I have made up my mind.
- That's the stuff.
- I am going to get there.
- You'll need strength...
...so get all the rest you can.
Dallas, do you suppose
you could fix up a little broth?
- She has already.
- Good.
How 'bout making some coffee
for the boys?
Now you get some sleep, Mrs. Mallory.
Don't look so proud.
I've brought hundreds of those
little fellas into the world...
...once upon a time.
The new one was always the prettiest.
Ringo asked me to marry him.
Is that wrong for a girl like me?
If a man and a woman
love each other...
...it's all right, ain't it Doc?
You're going to be hurt, child.
Worse than you've ever been hurt.
'Cause you know that boy's headed
back to prison.
Besides, if you two go
into Lordsburg together...
...he's going to know all about you.
He's not going into Lordsburg.
All I want is for you
to tell me it's all right.
Gosh, child, who am I to tell you
what's right or wrong?
All right.
Go ahead.
Do it if you can.
Good luck.
Thanks, Doc.
Both doing nicely.
She's a real soldier's wife,
that young lady.
Good, good, then we can
leave immediately!
Well, not for a day or so,
if you want my professional advice.
What do you mean a day?
Stay another day? Why?
Where were you when
the stork came last night, Gatewood?
I refuse to allow Mrs. Mallory to travel
till she and the child are out of danger.
What do you mean, danger?
Aren't we in worse danger here?
I don't wish to intrude,
but I've had five children.
I mean, my dear wife has...
...and much as I dislike discussing it
in this hour of our trial...
...I believe the Doctor is right.
Spoken like a man, Reverend.
I say we ought to leave here before the
Apaches find us! That's common sense.
I wish you were
ten years younger, Gatewood!
Don't let my white hair stop you...
- Now Curley, I haven't said a word...
- Will you shut up?!
If we argue this thing out right,
we can get somewhere.
Let's all sit down and talk sensible.
Come on, Buck, sit down.
There's a young woman in the kitchen
making coffee. She needs help.
Thanks, Doc.
How old were you
when you went to the pen?
Oh, I was goin' on 17.
Mornin' ma'am.
Morning.
I...
...lied awake most of the night...
...wonderin' what you'd have said
if Curley hadn't busted in.
Guess you was up kinda late, too.
I could hear you movin' around.
You didn't answer
what I asked you last night.
Look, Kid, why don't you try to escape?
There's a horse out there in the corral.
Curley won't go after you...
...because he can't leave the passengers
in a fix like this.
I gotta go to Lordsburg.
Why don't you go to my ranch,
and wait for me?
Wait for a dead man.
You haven't got a chance.
It was three against one
when the Plummers swore...
...that you killed their foreman,
and got you sent up.
It'll be three against one
in Lordsburg.
Well, there's some things a man
just can't run away from.
How can you talk about your life and
my life when you're throwing them away?
Yeah, mine too.
That's what you're throwin' away
if you go to Lordsburg.
What do you want me to do?
Would it make us any happier
if Luke Plummer was dead?
One of his brothers would be
after you with a gun.
We'd never be safe.
I don't want that kinda life, Ringo.
Well, I don't see what else I can do.
Go now, get away.
Forget Lordsburg.
Forget the Plummers!
Make for the border
and I'll come to you.
- Do you mean that?
- Yes, I do!
Will you go with me, Dallas?
I can't leave Mrs. Mallory
and the baby.
I'll come to you from Lordsburg,
I swear it.
- Well, I oughta have a rifle and some...
- I've got one!
Right here. I got it last night,
when they were all asleep.
You mean you thought of this last night?
Yeah, don't ask anymore questions.
Not now.
There ain't no Apaches behind us.
We can still go back to Tonto.
- No, I insist we go on to Lordsburg.
- What do you think, Chris?
Geronimo between here and Lordsburg,
with my horse, I think.
Quiet, Doc. This is
a serious matter, ain't it?
My dear Buck, if I have only one hour
to live, I'm going to enjoy myself!
Doctor, I don't begrudge you
my samples, but l...
Now, you hush, I stood enough of you.
Now this is a serious problem...
...and I'm the only one that's
talking sense. Now Curley...
...if we can get across that ferry,
we'll be all right.
The question is, what are we gonna do
about the lady and her baby?
Doctor Boone has
settled that for us, sir.
And I demand respect for
his professional opinion!
Ringo, don't stop! Go on, go on!
Keep riding!
Ringo, go on! Go on!
You don't need them, Curley.
I ain't gonna run away.
- I'll say you ain't!
- Look at them hills.
- Apaches.
- War signals.
Why don't you take the cuffs off
the Kid? He's mighty handy with a gun.
You drive them horses,
I'll take care of the Kid!
Can't you drive any faster?
Thick-headed lout!
We've got to make that ferry!
A man works all his life
to get hold of some money...
...so that he can enjoy life,
and has to run into a trap like this!
Trap, brother?
You mean the Apaches?
There's been no sign of them.
You don't see any sign of them.
They strike like rattlesnakes.
If you hadn't insisted
on waiting for her...
...we'd have been past the ferry
by this time!
You talk too much, Gatewood.
Your threats don't faze me, Hatfield!
You're nothing but a tinhorn gambler!
How would you like
to get out and walk?
You can't put me out of
a public conveyance!
Now, now, gentlemen!
Gentlemen!
Take it easy, Gatewood. We may need
that fight before we get to the ferry.
You wouldn't be much good
in a fight, you jailbird!
Oh, leave the Kid alone.
He's handcuffed!
Gentlemen, please...
...let's not forget the ladies.
Bless them.
Let's have a little Christian charity
one for the other.
Well, folks, we're coming into
Lee's Ferry now!
Lordsburg, next stop!
Curley, look! Look at the ferry!
It's burnt too!
Hatfield, stand guard over there.
Where's the Army?
What are the soldiers doing?
Curley, what can I do?
I need you. Will you give me your word
you won't try to escape again?
I'll give you my word,
till Lordsburg.
Get in the coach with them women!
- I gave my word.
- Ringo, don't!
Buck, drive into the river
up to the hubs!
Take your suspenders
and crosstie them wheels.
Sorry about the saddle, Kid.
- Ready, Kid?
- All set!
- Ready Buck?
- All ready, Curley. All aboard!
Just sit quiet, folks,
we'll be all right!
"All aboard for Lordsburg,
Lordsburg..."
You think I oughta charge
Mrs. Mallory's baby half fare?
Well, we'll soon be in Lordsburg.
Sorry I flew off the handle, Hatfield.
My apologies, Doctor.
No hard feelings, I hope.
All in all, it's been an exciting,
a very interesting trip, has it not?
- Now that the danger's past, Mr...
...Peacock.
Ladies and gentlemen, since it's most
unlikely that we'll ever have...
...the pleasure of
meeting again socially...
...l'd like to propose a toast.
- Your health.
- Thank you, sir.
I warned you about this danger!
Will you shut up?!
I've got a patient here!
The leader, Kid!
Get the leader!
Curley, more ammunition!
Do you hear it?
It's a bugle!
They're blowing the charge!
If you see Judge Ringfield...
...tell him his son...
- Thank heaven you're safe, Lucy!
- Where's Richard? Is he all right?
Oh, he's all right.
Don't you worry.
- It isn't a bad wound.
- We'll take you to him immediately.
Where's the baby, dear?
I'll take the baby.
If there's ever anything I can do for...
I know.
It's the Ringo Kid!
Aces and eights.
Dead man's hand, Luke.
- Ringo Kid's in town.
- Yeah, drivin' the stage!
Cash in.
Good-bye, Ms. Dallas.
If you ever come to Kansas City,
Kansas, I want you to come to see us.
- Well thanks, Mr...
- Peacock.
Hello, Buck. You got through all right!
Here you are Doctor,
will you sign this?
- Lordsburg.
- Thank you.
Curley, how long will they give me
for breakin' out?
Oh, about another year.
You know where my ranch is?
Yeah.
Will you see that
she gets there all right?
This is no town for a girl like her.
Will you do it?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
How are you, Marshall? Get my man
through all right?
- I don't need them.
- Lf you don't want to lose...
...your prisoner, Sheriff, you'd better
take care of him yourself!
- What's your name, mister?
- Gatewood! Elsworth H. Gatewood!
You didn't think they'd have
the telegraph wires fixed, did you?
Can I meet you back here
in ten minutes?
I gave you my word, Curley.
I ain't goin' back on it now.
No ammunition.
I lied to you, Curley.
I got three left.
Good night, Kid.
- Is this where you live?
- No.
I gotta know where you live, don't I?
No, don't come any further.
It's all been a crazy dream.
I've been out of my mind, just hoping.
Say good-bye here, Kid.
We ain't never gonna say good-bye.
Could I have that?
Give me the shotgun.
Luke, please don't!
Well, Kid I... I told you
not to follow me.
I asked you to marry me, didn't I?
I'll never forget you asked me, Kid.
That's somethin'.
Wait here.
Ringo said he'll be passing this way
in... six or seven minutes.
Come on!
I'll take that shotgun, Luke.
You'll take it in the belly,
if you don't get out of my way.
I'll have you indicted for murder
if you step outside with that shotgun.
We'll attend to you later.
Don't ever let me do that again.
Billy, kill that story about the
Republican Convention in Chicago...
...and take this down:
"The Ringo Kid
was killed on Main Street...
"...in Lordsburg tonight! And among
the additional dead were..."
- I'll leave that blank for a spell.
- I didn't hear any shootin', Ed.
You will, Billy. You will.
Hank missed him, at four feet!
Ready, Kid?
Thanks, Curley.
Curley's going to see that you get
to my place across the border.
Good-bye, Dallas.
Maybe you'd like to ride
a ways with the Kid.
Please.
Well...
...they're saved from
the blessings of civilization.
I'll buy you a drink.
Just one.