CAPTAIN AMERICA
CIVIL WAR
Subtitle created by - Aorion -
"Captain America: Civil War (2016)" ^ (Run time 02:17:49)
NOOOOOOO !!!
NOOOOO !
Longing.
Rusted.
Seventeen.
Daybreak.
Furnace.
Nine.
Benign.
Homecoming.
One.
Freight car.
Good morning, soldier.
I am ready.
I have a mission for you.
Elimination and extraction.
No witnesses.
Well done, soldier.
LAGOS
PRESENT DAY
Alright, what do you see?
Standard beat cops.
A small station.
Quiet street.
It's a good target.
There's an ATM in the south corner,
which means...
Cameras.
Both cross streets leading one way?
So compromise the escape routes.
Means our guy doesn't care
about being seen
he isn't afraid to make a mess
on the way out.
You see that ranger rover
over half way up the block.
You mean the red one.
It's cute.
It's also bullet proof,
which means private security,
which means more guns, which means
more headaches for somebody, probably us.
You guys know I can move things
with my mind, right?
Looking over your shoulder
needs to become a second nature.
Anybody ever tell you,
you're a little paranoid.
Not to my face.
Why, did you hear something?
Eyes on target, folks.
The best lead we have on Rumlow
in 6 months.
I don't want to lose him.
Maybe he sees us coming
there won't be a problem,
he kind of hate us.
Sam, see that garbage truck?
Take it.
Give me X-ray.
MAX CAPACITY
Yeah, the truck's loaded for max weight,
and the driver's armed.
- It's a battling ram.
- Go now.
Where?
He's not aiming the police.
INSTITUTE FOR
INFECTIOUS DISEASES
Body armor.
AR15s
I make 7 hostiles.
I make 5.
Sam.
4.
Rumlow's on the third floor.
- Wanda. Just like we practice.
- What about the gas?
Get it out.
Pack it up.
He's here.
- Rumlow has a biological weapon.
- I'm on it.
I don't work like that no more.
Fire in the hole.
Sam.
He's in the main humvee heading north.
Take this to the extract.
We're not going to out run him.
Lose the truck.
- Where are you going to meet us?
- I'm not.
I got 4,
they're splitting up.
I got the two on the left.
They ditch their gear.
It's a shell game now.
One of them has the payload.
There you are,
you son of a bitch.
I've been waiting for this!
He doesn't have it.
I'm empty.
Out of the way!
Drop it.
Or I'll drop this.
- Drop it!
- He'll do it!
Payload secured.
Thanks, Sam.
Don't thank me.
- I'm not thanking that thing.
- His name is Redwing.
- I'm still not thanking it.
- He's cute.
Come on!
This is for dropping
a building on my face.
I think it look pretty good,
all things considered.
Who's your buyer?
He knew we knew you.
You pal, your buddy,
your Bucky.
- What did you say?
- He remembered you.
I was there.
He got all weepy about it.
Till they put put his brain
back in the blender.
He wanted you to know something.
He said to me,
"Please tell Rogers,"
"When you got to go,
you got to go."
And you're coming with me.
Oh my...
Sam.
We need...
Fire and rescue,
on the south side of the building.
We got to get up here.
Try to remember
the kind of September
When grass was green...
Wake up, dear.
Say goodbye to your father.
Who's the homeless person
on the couch?
This is why I love
coming over for Christmas.
Right before you leave town.
Be nice, dear.
He's been studying abroad.
Really, which broad?
What's her name?
Candice.
Do me a favour. Try not to burn
the house down before Monday.
Okay, so it's Monday.
That is good to know.
I will plan my totem party accordingly.
Where're you going?
You father's flying us to the Bahamas
for a little get away.
We might have to make a
quick stop.
At the Pentagon.
Right?
Don't worry. You're going to love
the holiday menu at the commissure.
You know, they say sarcasm
is a metric for potential.
If that's true,
you'll be a great man some day.
I'll get the bags.
He does miss you
when you are not here.
And frankly,
you're going to miss us.
Because this is the last time
we're all going to be together.
You know what's about to happen.
Say something.
If you don't, you'll regret it.
I love you, Dad.
And I knew you did
the best you could.
That's how I wished it happened.
By merely augmented
retro framing or "BARF".
God, I got to work on that acronym.
An extremely costly method,
of hijacking the hippocampus
to clear... traumatic memories.
It doesn't change the fact that
they never made it to the airport,
or the things I did
to avoid processing my grief.
Plus, 611 million dollars for
my little therapeutic experiment.
No one in the right mind
would ever funded it.
Help me out.
What's the MIT admission statement.
To generate, disseminate
and preserve knowledge,
and work with others,
to bring to bear on the
world's great challenges.
Well, you,
or the others.
And quite as it kept
the challenges facing you
are the greatest mankind
has ever known.
Plus, most of you are broke.
also, I rather you work.
As of this moment, every student
has been made an equal recipient
of the Inaugural September Foundation Grant.
As in, all of your projects have
just been approved and funded.
No strings.
No taxes.
Just... reframe the future.
Starting now.
Go break some eggs.
That uh...
That took my breathe away.
Tony, so generous,
so much money.
Wow! I...
Out of curiosity and...
Will any portion of that grant be
made available to faculty?
I know, ooo, gross,
but hear me out.
I have got this killer idea
for a self cooking hotdog.
Basically, chemical detonator embedded...
- The Restroom this way, yeah?
- Yeah. Embedding in the meat shaft.
Mr. Stark, I am so sorry
about the telepromter.
I didn't know Miss Potts has canceled.
They didn't have time to fix it.
It's... fine.
I'll be right back.
We'll catch up later.
That was really sweet,
what you did for the young people.
Oh, they deserve it.
'Cos it helps to ease my conscious.
They say, there's a correlation
between generosity and guilt.
But, you got the money.
Break as many eggs as you like.
It's brilliant.
Are you going up?
I'm right where I wanted to be.
Okay, okay.
Hey!
I'm sorry.
It's my occupation hazard.
I work for the State department.
Human resources.
I know it's boring.
But, it enabled me to raise a son.
I'm very proud
of what he grew up to be.
His name was Charlie Spencer.
Your murdered him.
In Sokovia.
Not that it matters
in the least to you.
You think you fight for us.
You just fight for yourself.
Who's going to avenge my son, Stark?
He's dead.
And I blame you.
11 Wakandans were among those killed
during a confrontation
between the Avengers
and a group of mercenaries
in Lagos, Nigeria, last month.
The traditionally reclusive Wakandans
were on an outreach mission in Lagos
when the attack occurred.
Our people's blood is spilled
on foreign soil.
Not only the cause of
the actions are criminals,
but by the indifference of those
pledge to stop them.
Victory at the expense of the innocent,
is no victory at all.
The Wakanda king went on to...
What legal authority does
an enhanced individual
like Wanda Maximoff have
to operate in Nigeria?
- It's my fault.
- That's no true.
Then turn the TV back on,
you're being very specific.
I should've grabbed that bomb
as I'm the leader to deal with it.
Rumlow said 'Bucky' and...
All of a sudden, I was
a 16 year old kid again in Brooklyn.
People died.
- It's on me.
- It's on both of us.
This job...
We try to save as
many people as we can.
Sometimes that doesn't mean everybody,
but, if we can find a way
to live with that,
Next time...
maybe who we can save.
Vis, we talked about this.
Yes. But the door was opened
so I assumed...
Captain Rogers wished to know
when Mr. Stark was arriving.
Thank you.
I'll be right down.
I'll... use the door.
Oh, and apparently,
he's brought a guest.
You know who it is?
The secretary of State.
Oh. 5 years ago,
I had a heart attack.
I dropped right in the middle
of my batting swing.
Turned out, it was the
best round of my life
because after 13 hours of surgery
and a triple bypass.
I found something 40 years
in the army never taught me:
Perspective.
The world owes the Avengers
an unpayable debt.
You've... fought for us.
Protected us.
Risked your lives.
While a great many people
see you as heroes.
There are some...
would prefer the word "vigilantes."
And what word would you use,
Mr. Secretary.
How about "Dangerous?"
What would you call a group of
US-based, enhanced individuals,
who routinely ignores sovereign borders
and inflict their will
wherever they choose
and who, frankly,
seem unconcerned about
what they leave behind them.
New York.
Washington DC.
Sokovia.
Lagos.
Okay.
That's enough.
For the past 4 years, you operated
with unlimited power and no supervision.
That's an arrangement the governments
of the world can no longer tolerate.
But I think we have a solution.
The Sokovia accords.
Approved by 117 countries.
It states, that the Avengers shall
no longer be a private organization.
Instead, they'll operate under the
supervision of a United Nations Panel,
only when and if that Panel
deems it necessary.
The Avengers were formed
to make the world a safer place.
I feel we've done that.
Tell me captain, do you know where
Thor and Banner are right now?
If I misplaced a couple of
30 mega tonne nukes,
you can bet there'd be consequences
Compromise. Reassurance.
That's how the world works.
Believe me, this is the middle ground.
So, there are contingencies
3 days from now, the UN meets
in Vienna to ratify the Accords.
So, talk it over.
And if we come to
a decision you don't like?
Then you retire.
CLEVELAND
Hello?
Is this your car out front?
I jumped the curb.
Maybe we could,
take care of it ourselves.
If you prefer to call the cops,
then, that's okay too, I guess.
No.
No cops.
Thank you.
You kept your looks, colonel.
Congratulations.
Mission report: December 16, 1991
Who are you?
My name is Zemo.
I will repeat my question.
Mission report.
December 16, 1991
How did you find me?
When SHIELD fell,
Black widow released
HYDRA files to the public.
Millions of pages
much of it encrypted,
not easy to decipher.
But,
I have experience.
And patience.
A man can do anything
if he has those.
What do you want?
Mission report.
December 16, 1991
Go to hell.
HYDRA deserves its place
on the ashtray,
so your death would not bother me.
But I have to use this book,
and other bloodier methods
to find what I need.
I don't look forward to that.
You know, maybe you're dying for...
your pride.
Hail, HYDRA.
Secretary Ross, has a Congressional Medal of Honor,
which is 1 more than you have.
So, let's say we agree to this thing.
How long is it gonna be
before they lo-jack us
like a bunch of common criminals?
A 117 countries want to sign this.
117, Sam, and you're just like,
"No, it's cool."
How long are you
going to play both sides?
- I have an equation.
- Oh, this will clear it up.
In the 8 years since Mr. Stark
announced himself as Iron Man,
the number of noted enhanced persons
has grown exponentially.
And during the same period,
the number of potentially
world-ending events
has risen at a commissive rate.
Are you saying it's our fault?
I'm saying there maybe a causality.
Our very strength invites challenge.
Challenge incites conflict.
And conflict... breeds catastrophe.
Oversight.
Oversight is not an idea that
could be dismissed out-of-hand.
Boom.
Tony, you're being
uncharacteristically non-hyper verbal.
That's because he's already
made up his mind.
Boy, you know me so well.
Actually, I'm nursing my
electromagnetic headache.
That's what's going on, Cap.
It's just pain...
says Humphrey.
Who's putting coffee grounds
in the disposal?
Am I running a bed and breakfast
for a biker gang?
Oh, that's Charles Spencer by the way.
He's a great kid.
Computer engineering degree.
3.6 GPA.
But first, he wanted to
put a few miles on his soul.
Before he park and prime
in a desk.
See the world and
maybe be of service.
Charlie didn't want to go to Vegas
which is what I would do.
He didn't go to Paris or Amsterdam.
Sounds fun.
He decided to spend his summer,
building sustainable housing for the poor.
Guess where, Sokovia.
He want to make a difference, I suppose.
I mean, we won't know
because we dropped a building on him
while we were kicking ass.
There's no decision making process here.
We need to be put in check.
Whatever form that takes, I'm game.
If we can't accept limitations,
we're bounderless,
we're no better than the bad guys.
Tony, someone dies on you watch,
you don't give up.
Who said we're giving up?
We are, for not taking responsibility
for our actions.
- These documents just shifts the blames.
- Sorry. Steve, that...
That is dangerously arrogant.
This is the United Nations
we're talking about.
It's not the world security council,
it's not SHIELD, it's not HYDRA.
No, but it's run by people with agendas
and agendas change.
That's good.
That's why I'm here.
When I realized what my weapons
were capable of in the wrong hands,
I shut it down and
stop manufacturing them.
Tony.
You chose to do that.
If we sign these,
we surrender our right to choose.
What if this Panel sends us somewhere
we don't think we should go.
What if it's somewhere we need to go,
and they don't let us.
We may not be perfect,
but the safest hands are still our own.
If we don't do this now,
it's going to be done to us later.
That's a fact.
That won't be pretty.
- You're saying they will come for me.
- We will protect you.
Maybe Tony is right.
If, we have one hand on the wheel
that can still steer.
Aren't you the same woman who told
the government to kiss our ass a few years ago.
I'm just...
monitoring.
We have made
some very public mistakes.
We need to win our trust back.
I'm sorry, did I just mishear you or
did you agree with me.
- Oh, I want to take it back.
- No, no, no. You can't retract it.
Thank you.
I'm impress by what you did.
Okay, case close.
- I win.
- [She's gone. In her sleep.]
I have to go.
LONDON
MARGARET "PEGGY" CARTER
And now,
I would like to invite Sharon Carter,
to come up and say a few words.
Margaret Carter was known to most
as a founder of SHIELD.
But I just knew her
as Aunt Peggy.
She had a photograph in her office.
Aunt Peggy standing next to JFK.
As a kid, that was pretty cool.
But, it was a lot to live up to.
Which is why I never
told anyone we were related.
I asked her once how she managed
to master diplomacy and espionage
at a time when no one wanted
to see a woman succeed at either.
And she said,
compromise when you can.
When you can't, don't.
Even if everyone is telling you that
something wrong is something right.
Even if the whole world
is telling you to move.
It is your duty,
to plant yourself like a tree,
look them in they eye
and say, " No...
... you move.
When I came out of the ice,
thought I wanted to ignore
she was gone.
When I found out she was alive,
it is just lucky to have her.
She'd have you're back too.
Who else sign it.
Tone, Rhodey,
Vision.
Clint?
Says he's retired.
- Wanda?
- TBD. (To Be Determined)
I'm off to Vienna
for the signing of the Accords.
There is plenty of room
on the jet.
Just because it's the path of least resistance
does mean it's the wrong path.
Staying together is more important
than how we stay together.
What are we giving up to do it?
Sorry, Nat.
I can't sign it.
I know.
Well, then.
What are you doing here?
I didn't want you to be alone.
Come here.
VIENNA
At a specially United Nations congress,
117 countries have come together
to ratify Sokokia Accords.
- Excuse me, Miss Romanoff?
- Yes.
I just need your signature.
Thank you.
I suppose neither of us
is used to the spot light.
Well.
It's not always so flattering.
You seem to be doing alright so far.
Considering your last trip to Capitol Hill.
I wouldn't think you would be
particularly comfortable in this company.
Well, I'm not.
That alone, makes me glad you're here,
Miss Romanoff.
Why?
You don't approve of all this?
The Accords, yes.
The politics, not really.
Two people, in a room,
can get more done than a 100.
Unless you need to move a piano.
- Father.
- Son.
- Miss. Romanoff.
- King T'Chaka.
Please, allow me to apologize
for what happened in Nigeria.
Thank you.
Thank you for agreeing to all this.
I'm sad to hear that Captain Rogers
will not be joining us today.
Yes, so am I.
- Everyone, please be seated.
This assembly is now in session.
That is the future calling.
Such a pleasure.
Thank you.
For a man
who disapproves of diplomacy...
You're getting better each time.
I'm happy, father.
When a stolen Wakandan vibranium was
used to make a terrible weapon,
we, in Wakanda, were force
to question our legacy.
Those men and women killed in Nigeria,
were part of a good will mission
from a country too long
in the shuttles.
We will not, however,
let misfortune drive us back.
We will fight to improve the world
we wish to join.
I am grateful to the Avengers
for supporting this initiative.
Wakanda is proud to extend
it's hand in peace.
EVERYBODY GET DOWN !
My mom tried to talk me
on enlisting, but...
not aunt Peggy.
She brought me
my first knife holster.
- Very practical.
- And stylish.
CIA has you stationed over here now?
- In Berlin, joint terrorist and task force.
- Right.
- Sounds fun.
- I know, right?
I've been meaning to ask you.
When you were spying on me
from across the hall...
You mean when I was
doing my job?
Did Peggy know?
She kept so many secrets.
I didn't want her to
have to remember you.
- Thanks for walking me back.
- Sure.
Steve.
There's something you got to see.
A bomb hidden in a news van
... blast through the UN building in Vienna.
- Who's coordinating?
More than 70 people have been injured.
At least 12 are dead.
Including Wakanda's King T'Chaka.
Officials have released a video
of a suspect,
identified as James Buchanan Barnes,
the Winter soldier.
The infamous HYDRA agent,
linked to numerous acts of terrorism
and political assassinations.
I have to go to work.
I'm very sorry.
In my culture,
death, is not the end.
It's more of a...
stepping off point.
You reach out with both hands
and bask... and seek amend.
They lead you away into
the green valleys where...
you can run forever.
That sounds very peaceful.
My father thought so.
I am not my father.
T'Challa.
The task force will decide
who brings in Barnes.
Don't bother, Miss. Romanoff.
I'll kill him myself.
- Yeah?
- Are you alright?
Ah, yeah, thanks.
I got lucky.
I know how much Barnes mean to you.
I really do.
Stay at home.
You'll only make this worse
for all of us. Please.
- Are you saying you'll arrest me?
- No.
Someone will, if you interfere.
That's how it works now.
If he's this far gone, then...
I should be the one
to bring him in.
Why?
Because I'm the one
least likely to die trying.
Shit.
Did she tell you
to stay out of it?
- Might have a point.
- He'd do it for me.
1945, maybe.
I just want to make sure
we considered all our options.
The people that shoot at you,
usually wind up shooting at me.
Tips have been pouring in
since the footage went public.
Everybody thinks the Winter soldier
goes to their gym.
Most of it is noise,
except for this.
My boss expects a briefing and
he pretty much knows, so...
that's all the answer
you're going to get.
- Thank you.
- And you're going to have to hurry.
We have orders to shoot on sight.
Mr. Muller
I brought breakfast.
I could smell it before opening the door.
Thank you.
Bacon and black coffee.
Again.
I can fix you something different,
if you like.
It's okay.
This is wonderful.
- I'll put this in the...
- No, no, no.
I'll do it. I'll do it.
Don't worry.
BUCHAREST
Heads up, Cap.
German special forces
approaching from the south.
Understood.
Do you know me?
You're Steve.
I read about you at the museum.
They've set the perimeter.
I know you're nervous.
And you have plenty of reason to be.
But you're lying.
I wasn't in Vienna.
I don't do that anymore.
They're entering the building.
Well, the people who think
you did are coming here now.
And they're not planning
on taking you alive.
That's smart.
Good strategy.
They're on the roof.
I'm compromised.
This doesn't have end in a fight, Buck.
- It always ends in a fight.
- 5 seconds.
You pulled me from the river.
Why?
- I don't know.
- 3 seconds!
Yes, you do.
Breach!
Breach! Breach!
Barnes, stop!
You're gonna kill someone.
I'm not gonna kill anyone.
The suspect has escaped.
Get him!
Come on.
- Sam, south. West rooftop.
- Who the hell is the other guy?
I'm about to find out.
- Sam.
- Got it.
Stand down!
- Sam, I can't shake this guy.
- Right behind you.
Stand down.
Now.
Congratulations, Captain.
You're a criminal.
Your highness.
A pinch of paprika.
A pinch.
Is that Paprikash?
I thought it might...
lift your spirits.
Spirits lifted.
In my defense,
I haven't actually...
- eaten anything before, so...
- Aye, aye.
Please.
- Wanda.
- Hmm.
No one dislikes you, Wanda.
- Thanks.
- Oh, you're welcome.
No. It's a...
involuntary response in their amygdala
they can't help
but be afraid of you.
Are you?
My amygdala is synthetic, so...
I used to think of
myself one way.
But, after this.
I am something else.
And still me, I think.
But...
that's not what everyone else sees.
Do you know,
I don't know what this is.
Not really.
I know it's not of this world.
But it powered Loki staff,
gave you your abilities. But...
its true nature is a mystery.
And yet, it is part of me.
Are you afraid of it?
I wish to understand it.
The more I do,
the less it controls me.
One day,
who knows, I may even control it.
I don't know what's in this
but it is not paprika.
I'm gonna go to the store,
I'll be back in 20 minutes.
Alternatively, we could order a pizza?
Vision, are you not letting me leave?
- It's a question of safety.
- I can protect myself.
Not yours.
Mr. Stark would like to avoid
the possibility of another public incident.
Until the Accords are a...
more secured foundation.
And what do you want?
For people to see you...
as I do.
BERLIN
- So, you like cats?
- Sam.
What? Dude shows up dressed like a cat
and you don't wanna know more?
Your suit.
A Vibranium?
The Black Panther has been
the protector of Wakanda for generations.
A mantle passed
from warrior to warrior.
And now because your friend
murdered my father,
I also wear the mantle of king.
So I ask you,
as both warrior and king,
how long do you think you can keep
your friend safe from me?
What's going to happen?
The same thing that
ought to happen to you.
Psychological evaluation and extradition.
This is Everett Ross,
deputy task force commander.
- What about our lawyer.
- Lawyer, that's funny.
See to their weapons are
placed in the lock up.
Oh, we'll write you a receipt.
I better not look out the window
and see anybody flying around in that.
You will be provided with an office
instead of a cell.
And do me a favour,
stay in it.
I'm not intending
on going anywhere.
For the record. This is what
making things worse looks like.
He's alive.
The remaining of us
are now at court-sec.
And, Colonel Ross is supervising
the clean up.
Try not to break anything
while we fix this.
Consequences?
You bet there will be consequences.
Obviously you can quote me on that
because I just said it.
Anything else?
Thank you, sir.
Consequences?
Secretary Ross wants you both prosecuted.
I have to give him something.
I'm not getting that shield back, am I?
Technically, it's the government's property.
- Wings too.
- That's cold.
Warmer than jail.
Hey, you want to see something cool?
I pulled something from dad's archives.
Well, timely.
FDR signed the Land-Lease bills
with these in 1941.
Provided support to the allies
when they needed most.
Someone said it brought
our country closer to war.
Seen enough of these,
you wouldn't be here.
I'm trying to,
what do you call it?
a... an al'fermage.
Is that what you call it?
Is Pepper here?
I didn't see her.
We are... kinda...
- well not kinda...
- Pregnant?
No, definitely not.
We're taking a break.
It's nobody's fault.
So sorry, Tony.
I didn't know.
Few years ago, I almost lost her,
so I trashed all my suits.
Then, we had to muck up Hydra.
And then Ultron, my fault.
And then, and then, and then.
I never stopped.
Cause the truth is
I don't wanna stop.
I don't want to lose her.
I thought maybe the Accords
can split the difference.
In her defense, I'm her handful.
Yet, dad was a pain in the ass,
but he and mom always made it work.
You know, I'm glad Howard got married.
I only knew him when
he was young and single.
Oh really?
You two know each other?
He never mentioned that.
Maybe only a thousand times.
God, I hated you.
I don't mean to make things difficult.
I know.
Because you're a very polite person.
If I see a situation pointed south,
I can't ignore it.
- Sometimes I wish I could.
- No, you don't.
No, I don't.
Sometimes...
Sometimes I wanna punch you
in your perfect teeth.
But I don't wanna see you gone.
We need you, Cap.
Until further nothing's happen
that can't be undone, please... sign.
We can make the last 24 hours legit.
Barnes gets transferred to an American
psych center instead of a Wakanda prison.
I'm not saying it's impossible.
But there would have to be safeguards
Sure.
She's confined in a compound currently.
Vision's keeping her company.
Oh God, Tony!
Every time.
Every time I think you're seeing
things the right way...
What? It's a 100 acres with a lap pool.
It's got a screening room.
There's worse ways to protect people.
Protection?
Is that how you see this?
This is protection?
It's internment, Tony.
She's not a US Citizen
- Oh, come on, Tony.
- and they don't grant visas to
Weapons of Mass Destruction.
- She's a kid!
- GIVE ME A BREAK!
I'm doing what has to be done
... to save us from something worse.
You keep telling yourself that.
Hate to break up the set.
Hello, Mr. Barnes.
I've been sent by the
United Nations to evaluate you.
Do you mind if I sit?
Your first name is James?
The receipt for your gear.
Bird costume?
Come on.
I didn't write it.
I'm not here to judge you.
I just want to ask you
a few questions.
Do you know where you are, James?
I can't help you
if you don't talk to me, James.
My name is Bucky.
Hello?
Hey.
Okay.
Here.
Just sign here.
- Here?
- Yeah.
Why would the task force
release this photo to begin with?
Get the word out,
involve as many eyes as we can?
Right.
It's a good way to flush
a guy out of hiding.
Set off a bomb,
get your picture taken.
It got 7 million people looking
for the Winter soldier.
You're saying someone
framed him to find him.
Steve, we looked for the guy
for 2 years and found nothing.
We didn't bomb the UN.
That turns a lot of heads.
So? That doesn't guarantee that
whoever framed him
would get him a guarantees
that we would.
Yeah.
Tell me Bucky.
You've seen a great deal, haven't you?
I don't want to talk about it.
You feel that...
if you open your mouth,
the horrors might never stop.
Don't worry.
[MESSAGE INBOX: 1]
STATUS: PACKAGE DELIVERED
We only have to talk about one.
Hey.
What is this?
Great. Come on, guys.
Get me eyes on Barnes.
Go.
Friday.
Give me the source of that damage.
Sub-level 5, east wing.
- What the hell is this?
- Why don't we discuss your home?
Not Romania.
Certainly not Brooklyn, no.
I mean, your real home.
Longing.
Rusted.
Stop.
Seventeen.
Daybreak.
Furnace.
Nine.
Benign.
Homecoming
One.
Freight car.
Soldier?
You're not the one in charge.
Mission report.
December 16, 1991
Help me.
Help?
Get up.
Who are you?
What do you want?
To see the empire fall.
Hey.
Evac all civilians.
Give me a perimeter around the building
and gunships in the air.
Please tell me you have a suit.
Sure did. It's a lovely Tom Ford,
three-Piece, 2 button...
I'm on active duty, non combatant
Follow me.
We're in position.
You really don't recognize me?
Damn it.
He asked me again
if you're going to be there?
I said I wasn't sure.
You should've seen his little face.
Just try, okay?
I'm going to bed.
I love you.
James Barnes, the suspect in the
bombing of the UN in Vienna
escaped from prison today
Also disappeared are the Avengers,
Captain Steve Rogers and Sam Wilson.
GATE 6 - BERLIN AIRPORT>
MOSCOW
Hey, Cap!
Steve.
Which Bucky am I talking to?
Your mother's name is Sarah.
You used to wear newspapers
in your shoes.
You can't read that in a museum.
Just like that,
we're suppose to be cool?
- What did I do?
- Enough.
I knew this would happen.
Everything HYDRA put inside me
is still there.
All he had to do is say
the god damn words.
- Who was he?
- I don't know.
People are dead.
The bombing. The set up.
The doctor did all that
just to get 10 minutes with you.
I need you to do better than
"I don't know."
He wanted to know about Siberia.
Where I was kept.
- He wanted to know exactly where.
- Why would he need to know that?
Because I'm not the only Winter soldier.
Good job.
Get me out of here.
- Who were they?
- The most elite death squad.
More kills than anyone
in the HYDRA history.
- And that was before the serum.
- They all turned out like you?
Worse.
The doctor, can he control them?
Enough.
- He said he wanted to see an empire fall.
- With these guys he can do it.
They speak 30 languages,
can hide in plain sight,
infiltrate, assassinate, destabilize,
They can take a whole country
down in 1 night.
You'd never see them coming.
This would be a lot easier
if we could...
If we call Tony.
- Oh, he won't believe us.
- Even if he did.
Who knows if the Accords
will let him help.
We're on our own.
Maybe not.
I know a guy.
And I don't suppose you have
any idea where they are.
We will.
GSG-9's got the borders covered.
Recons flying 24/7.
They'll get a hit.
We'll handle it
You don't get it, Stark.
It's not yours to handle.
It's clearly you can't be objective.
I'm putting special ops on this.
And what happens when the shooting starts,
let them kill Steve Rogers?
If we are provoked.
Barnes would have been eliminate
in Romania if it wasn't for Rogers.
There are dead people
who would be alive now.
Feel free to check my math.
All due respect, you're not going to
solve this with boys in bullet vest.
You got to let
us bring him in.
And how will that end
any differently from the last time.
Because this time I won't be
wearing Loafers and a silk suit.
72 hours, guaranteed.
36 hours.
Barnes.
Rogers.
Wilson.
Thank you, sir.
My left arm is numb,
is that normal?
You alright?
Always.
36 hours, jeez.
- We're seriously understaffed.
- Oh, yeah.
It would be great if we have a hulk,
right about now. Any shot?
No.
You really think
he'd be on our side?
I know.
- I've an idea.
- Me too.
- What's yours?
- Downstairs.
What's yours?
QUEENS
- Hey, Aunt May.
- Hey.
- How was school today?
- Okay.
This crazy car parked outside...
- Oh, Mr. Parker.
- Umm.
What.
What are you doing...?
Hey.
I'm-I'm-I'm Peter.
- Tony.
- What are...
What are you-What are you-
What are you doing here?
It's about time we met.
You've been getting my e-mails, right?
- Right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Regarding the...
- You didn't tell me about the grant.
- About the grant.
- The September Foundation.
- Right.
- Yeah. Remember when you applied.
- Yeah.
- I approved.
So now, we're in business.
You didn't tell me anything.
What's up with that?
- You're keeping secrets from me?
- Why, I just, I just...
I just know how much
you love surprises,
so I thought I would let you know...
wh...
- Anyway, what did I apply for?
- That's what I'm here to hash out.
Okay.
Hash, hash out, okay.
It's so hard for me to believe
that she's someone's aunt.
We come in all shapes and sizes,
you know.
This walnut bake loaf is exceptional.
- Let me just stop you there.
- Yeah?
Is this grant, like, got money
involved or whatever? No?
- Yeah.
- It's pretty well funded.
- Wow.
Look who you're talking to.
- Can I have 5 minutes with him?
- Sure.
As walnut bake loaves go,
that wasn't bad.
Oh. What do we have here,
retro tech, huh?
- Salvation army?
- Uh, the garbage actually.
- You're a dumpster diver.
- Yeah, I was...
Anyway, look.
Umm.
I definitely did not
apply for your grant.
- Uh,uh. Me first.
- Okay.
Quick question of the rhetorical variety.
That's you, right?
Um, no.
- What do you. What do you...
- Yeah.
Look at you go.
Wow, nice catch!
3000 pounds. 40 miles an hour.
It’s not easy.
You got mad skills.
That's all-That's all
on Youtube though right.
I mean that's where you found it.
Cause' you know that's all fake.
It's all done on a computer?
Mm-Hmm.
It's like that video that records...
Yea yea yea yea...oh you mean
like those UFOs over Phoenix?
Exactly!
What have we here?
Uh...
That's a...
So.
You're this... Spider... ling.
Crime fighting Spider...
You're Spider-Boy?
S... Spider-Man.
Not in that wanzie, you're not.
It's not a wanzie.
You won't believe this. I was actually having
a real good day today, you know, Mr. Stark.
Didn’t miss my trains. This perfectly good
DVD player was just sitting there and...
Algebra test.
Nailed it!
Who else knows?
Anybody?
Nobody.
- Not even your...unusually attractive Aunt?
- No.
No, no. No, no.
If she knew, she would freak out.
And when she freaks out,
I freak out.
You know what I think
is really cool? This webbing.
Tensile strength is off the charts
- Who manufactured them?
- I did.
Climbing the walls.
How are you doing that?
Cohesive gloves.
It's a long story.
I was uh...
Lordy!
Can you even see in these?
Yes. Yes, I can!
I can.
I can-I can see in those. Okay?
It's just that...
when...whatever happened happened,
it's like my senses have been dialed to 11.
There's way too much input, so...
they just kinda help me focus.
You're in dire need of an upgrade.
Systemic, top to bottom.
100-point restoration.
That's why I'm here
Why are you doing this?
I got to know.
What's your MO.
What gets you out of that
twin bed in the morning?
Because...
... because I’ve been me
my whole life,
- and I’ve had these powers for 6 months.
- Mm-Hm.
I read books,
I build computers...
And-And yeah.
I would love to play football.
But I couldn't then
so I shouldn't now.
- Sure. 'Cause you're different.
- Exactly.
But I can't tell anybody that,
so I'm not.
When you can do the things
that I can,
but you don't...
and then the bad things happen,
they happen because of you.
So you wanna look out for the little guy.
You wanna do your part.
Make the world a better place
all that, right?
Yeah. Yeah just looking out...
for the little guy.
That's-That's what it is.
I'm going to sit here,
so you move the leg.
- You got passport?
- Uh, no.
- I don't even have a driving license.
- You ever been to Germany?
- No.
- Oh, you'll love it.
- I can't go to Germany!
- Why?
I got... homework.
Alright, I gonna pretend
you didn't say that.
I'm-I'm being serious!
I can't just drop out of school!
Fighting crime is dangerous.
Better tell Aunt Hottie to
take you on a field trip...
Don’t tell Aunt May.
Alright, Spider-Man.
- Get me out of this.
- I'm sorry, I'll get that.
- What is it?
- Stay here, please.
- Guess I should have knocked.
- Oh my god.
- What are you doing here?
- Disappointing my kids.
I'm suppose to go water skiing.
Cap needs our help, come on.
Clint!
You should not be here.
Really?
I retired for, what, like 5 minutes?
And it all goes to shit.
Please consider the consequences
of your actions.
Okay, they're considered.
Okay, we got to go.
It's this way.
I've caused enough problems.
You got to help me, Wanda.
... you can go to high school.
You want to make amends.
You get off your ass.
Shit.
I know I should have stretch.
- Clint, you can't overpower me.
- I know I can't
But, she can.
Vision.
That's enough, let him go.
- I'm leaving.
- I can't let you.
I'm sorry.
If you do this,
they will never stop
being afraid of you.
I can't control their fear,
only my own.
Oh...
Come on.
We got one more stop.
It's just a matter of time.
Our satellites are running facial, biometric
and behavioral pattern scans.
Move, or you will be moved.
As entertaining as that would be.
You really think you can find him?
Our resources are considerable.
Yeah. It took the world
70 years to find Barnes.
So, you could probably do better
than them by half that time.
You know where they are.
I know someone who does.
I'm not sure you understand
the concept of a get away car.
It's low profile.
Good, 'cause this stuff
tends to draw a crowd.
- Can you move your seat up?
- No.
I owe you again.
I'm keeping a list.
You know, he kind of try to kill me.
Sorry, I'll put it on the list.
They're going to come looking for you.
I know.
Thank you, Sharon.
- That was...
- Late.
Damn right.
- I should go.
- Okay.
Cap.
You know I wouldn't have called
If I had any other choice.
Hey man, you're doing me a favour.
Besides... I'm on your team.
- Thanks for having my back.
- It was time to get off my ass.
About our other recruit.
He's ready to go.
I have to put a little coffee in him,
but...
.. he should be good.
What timezone is this?
Come on.
- Captain America.
- Mr. Lang.
It's an honor.
I'm shaking your hand too long.
Wow. This is awesome.
Captain America.
I know you too, you're great.
Jeez.
Look, I wanted to say.
I know you know a lot of super people,
so...
Thanks for thinking of me.
- Hey, man.
- What's up tic-tac.
Good to see you.
Look. What happened last time was a...
It was a great audition, but it'll...
it'll never happen again.
Did he tell you
what we're up against?
Something about some... psycho assassins.
We're outside the law on this one.
So, if you come with us,
you're a wanted man.
Yeah, well, what else is new?
- We should get moving.
- I got a chopper lining up.
They're evacuating the airport.
- Stark.
- Stark?
Suit up.
Wow, it's so weird how you run
into people at the airport.
- Don't you just feel weird?
- Definitely weird.
Hear me out, Tony.
That doctor, the psychiatrist,
he's behind all of this.
- Captain.
- Your highness.
Anyway.
Ross gave me 36 hours
to bring you in.
That was 24 hours ago.
- Can you help a brother out?
- You're after the wrong guy.
Your judgment is askew.
Your war buddy killed
innocent people yesterday.
And there are 5 more
super soldiers just like him.
I can't let the doctor find them first,
Tony. I can't.
Steve.
You know, what's about to happen.
Do you really want to punch
your way out of this one?
All right, I've run out of patience.
Underoos!
Nice job, kid.
Thanks. Well, I could've stuck
the landing a little better.
It's... just the new suit...
Well, it's nothing, Mr. Stark
It's-It's perfect, thank you.
Yeah, we don't really need to
start a conversation.
Okay.
Cap... Captain.
Big fan, I'm Spider-Man.
Yeah, we'll talk about it later.
Just...
- Hey, everyone.
- ... good job.
- You've been busy.
- And you've been a complete idiot.
Dragging in Clint.
Rescuing Wanda from a place
she doesn't even want to leave.
A safe place.
I'm trying to keep....
I'm trying to keep you from
tearing the Avengers apart.
You did that when you signed.
Alright, I'm done.
You're gonna turn Barnes over
and you're gonna come with us.
NOW!
Because it's us!
We're squaded JSOC, guys,
with no compunction about being impolite.
We found it.
The quinjet's in hanger five,
north runway.
Alright, Lang.
Hey, guys.
Something...
Whoa.
What-What the hell was that?
I believe this is yours, Captain America.
Oh, great.
Alright, there's two on the parking deck.
One of them is Maximoff,
I'm going to grab her.
Rhodey, you want to take Cap?
Got two in the terminal.
Wilson and Barnes.
Barnes is mine!
Hey, Mr. Stark, what should I do?
What we discussed.
Keep your distance. Web em up.
Okay, copy that!
Move, Captain.
I won't ask a second time.
- Look, I really don't want to hurt you.
- I wouldn't stress about it.
- What the hell was that?
- Everyone's got a gimmick now.
You have a metal arm?
That is awesome, dude!
You have the right to remain silent!
Sorry, Cap. This won't kill you
but it ain't gonna tickle either.
- Wanda, I think you hurt Vision's feelings.
- You locked me in my room.
Okay.
First, that's an exaggeration.
Second, I did it to protect you.
- Hey, Clint.
- Hey, man.
Clearly retirement doesn't suit you,
get tired of shooting golf?
Well, I played 18,
I shot 18.
Just can't seem to miss.
- First time for everything.
- Made you look.
- Multiple contusions detected.
- Yeah, I detected that too.
Oh god.
Hey buddy, I think you lost this!
- Are those wings carbon fiber?
- Is this stuff coming out of you?
That would explain
the rigidity flexibility ratio
which, gotta say,
that's awesome man.
I don’t know if
you’ve been a fight before
- but there's usually not this much talking.
- Alright, sorry, my bad.
Guys, look.
I'd love to keep this up
but I've only got one job here today
and I gotta impress Mr. Stark,
so, I’m really sorry.
Wwahhhh !
You couldn't have done that earlier?
I hate you.
Captain, heads up!
Throw it at this.
Now!
Oh, come on!
Oh, man.
I thought it was a water truck.
Uh... sorry.
Alright.
Now, I'm pissed.
Is this, part of the plan?
Well, my plan was to go easy on them.
You want to switch it up?
There's our ride.
Come on!
Captain Rogers.
I know you believe
what you're doing is right.
But, for the collective good,
you must surrender now.
What do we do, Cap?
We fight.
This isn't going to end well.
They're not stopping.
Neither are we.
- We're still friends, right?
- Depends on how hard you hit me.
You're pulling your punches.
- I didn't kill your father.
- Then why did you run?
Take that!
That thing does not obey
the laws of physics at all.
Look kid. There's a lot going on here
that you don't understand.
Stark said you'd say that.
He also said to go for your legs.
Clint, can you get him off me?
- Grapple in?
- Yeah. No, I'm good.
I'm good, arrow-guy.
Let's go. Let's go!
Did Stark tell you anything else?
That you're wrong.
You think you're right.
And that makes you dangerous.
I guess you got a point.
You got heart, kid.
Where're you from?
Queens.
Brooklyn.
- Friday?
- We have some weapon systems offline.
They what?
Oh, you're gonna have to
take this into the shop.
- Who's speaking?
- It's your conscience.
We don't talk a lot these days.
Friday?
Oh oh.
Oh boy.
- We got to go.
- That guy's probably in Siberia by now.
I'm gonna draw all the fliers.
I'll take Vision.
You get to the jet.
No, you get to the jet!
Both of you!
The rest of us
aren't getting out of here.
As much as I hate to admit it,
if we're gonna win this one,
some of us might
have to lose it.
This isn't the real fight, Steve.
- Alright, Sam, what's the plan?
- We need a diversion, something big.
I got something kind of big,
but I can't hold it very long.
On my signal, run like hell.
And if I tear myself in half,
don't come back for me.
- He's tearing himself in half?
- You're sure about this guy?
I do it all the time.
I mean once...
... in a lab.
And I passed out.
Holy shit!
Okay, tiny dude is big now.
He's big now.
I guess that's the signal.
Way to go, tic-tac!
Give me back my Rhodey.
I got him!
Okay. Anybody on our side
hiding any shocking,
and fantastic abilities
they'd like to disclose,
I'm open to suggestion.
You want to get to them?
You got to go through me.
We haven't met yet.
- I'm Clint.
- I don't care.
Get off.
Something just flew in me!
You're not going to stop?
You know I can't.
I'm going to regret this.
Go.
Hey guys.
You ever see that really old movie?
- Empire Strikes Back?
- Jesus Tony, how old is this guy?
I don't know, I didn't carbon date him.
He's on the young side.
You know that part?
When they're on the snow planet?
With the walking thingies?
- Maybe the kid's on to something.
- I know. Tony, go high.
YES!
Ha ha!
That was awesome!
Does anyone have any orange slices?
- Kid, you alright?
- Hey!
- Get of me!
- Guess who?
- Hi.
- Oh.
- Hey man.
- Yeah.
- That was scary.
- You're done. Alright?
- What?
- You did a good job.
-  No, I'm good. I'm fine.
- Stay down.
- No, it's good I gotta get him back!
You're going home
or I'll call Aunt May!
You're done!
Wait.
Mr. Stark, wait!
I'm not done, I'm not...
Okay, I'm done.
I said that I'd help you find him,
not catch him.
There is a difference.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
It's as I said, catastrophe.
Vision, I got a bandit on my six.
Vision, do you copy?
Target his thrusters,
turn him into a glider.
Rhodey?
Tony, I'm flying a dead stick.
RHODES!
Read vitals.
Heartbeat detected.
Emergency medical is on it's way.
I'm sorry.
Good morning.
Room service.
Good morning, Mrs. Leben.
- I mean, room 201.
-  Good morning, Mr. Muller.
Bacon and black coffee again?
You know it well.
Hello, I brought breakfast.
Can I come in?
Mr Muller?
Oh God!
What's gonna happen to your friends?
Whatever it is,
I'll deal with it.
I don't know if I'm worth
all this, Steve.
What you did all those years...
It wasn't you.
You didn't have a choice.
I know.
But I did it.
Vision, how did this happen?
I became distracted.
I didn't think that was possible.
Neither did I.
The doctor said he shattered
L4 to S1.
Extreme laceration in the spinal cord.
Probably looking at some form of paralysis.
Steve's not going to stop.
If you don't rein in, then Rhodey
is going to be the best case scenario.
- You let them go, Nat.
- We played this wrong.
We?
Boy. It must be hard to shake the
whole double agent thing, huh?
Sticks in the DNA.
And you incapable of letting go
of your ego for 1 god damn second.
T'Challa told Ross what you did,
so, they're coming for you.
I'm not the one who needs
to watch their back.
What am I looking at, Friday?
Priority upload from Berlin police.
Fire up the chopper.
The Task Force called for a psychiatrist
as soon as Barnes was captured.
The UN dispatched Dr. Theo Broussard
from Geneva within the hour.
He was met by this man.
- Did you run a facial recognition yet?
-  What do I look like?
I don't know, but I'm
picturing a red head.
You must be thinking
I'm someone else.
I must be.
The fake doctor is actually
Colonel Helmut Zemo
Sokovian intelligence.
Zemo ran EKO Skorpion,
a Sokovian covert kill squad.
So, what happened to the real Broussard?
He was found dead
in a Berlin hotel room.
The police also found a wig
and facial prosthesis
approximating the appearance
of one James Buchanan Barnes.
Son of a bitch.
- Get this to Ross.
- Yes, Boss.
This is the Raft prison control.
You are clear for landing, Mr. Stark.
RAFT PRISON
So?
Did you get the files?
Let's reroute the satellites, and start
facial scanning for this Zemo guy.
You seriously think I'm gonna listen
to you even after that fiasco in Leipzig?
You're luck you're not in
one of these cells.
The futurist, gentlemen!
The futurist is here!
He sees all!
He knows what's best for you,
whether your like it or not.
Give me a break, Barton.
I have no idea they'll put you
in here, come on.
Yeah, well, you knew
they'll put us somewhere, Tony.
Yeah. But, not some
super max floating ocean pokey.
You know, this place is for maniacs.
This is a place for...
Criminals?
Criminals, Tony.
I think that's the word
you're looking for.
Right?
It ain't used to mean me,
or Sam, or Wanda.
- But, here we are.
- 'Cause you broke the law.
- Yeah.
- I didn't make you.
- The law. The law.
- You read it, you broke it.
The law. The law.
The law.
Alright, you're all grown ups.
You got a wife and kids.
I don't understand. Why didn't you think
about them before you choose the wrong side?
You better watch your back
on this guy.
Chances are he's going to break it.
Hank Pym always said,
you never can trust a Stark.
Who are you?
Come on, man.
How's Rhodes?
We're flying him to
Columbia Medical tomorrow.
So...
Fingers cross.
What do you need?
They feed you yet?
You're the good cop now?
I'm just a guy who needs
to know where Steve went.
Well, you better go get a bad cop,
because you would have to go
Mark 'Terminal' on my ass
to get information out of me.
Oh, I just knocked the 'A'
out of their 'AV'.
We got about 30 seconds before
they realized it's not their equipment.
What did you do?
Get it back up!
Just look.
Because that is the fellow who is
suppose to interrogate Barnes.
Clearly, I made a mistake.
Sam, I was wrong.
That's a first.
Cap is definitely off the reservation and
he's about to need all the help he can get.
We don't know each other very well.
You don't have to...
Hey.
It's alright.
Look, I will tell you.
But you have to go alone
and as a friend.
Easy.
Stark, did he give you anything on Rogers?
No, he told me to go to hell.
I'm going back to the compound instead.
But, you can call me anytime.
I'll put you on hold,
I like to watch the line blink.
You remember that time
we had to ride back from
Rockaway Beach in the back
of that freezer truck?
Was that the time we used
our train money to buy hot dogs?
You blew 3 bucks trying to win
that stuffed bear for a redhead.
- What was her name again?
- Dolores. You called her Da.
She's got to be
a hundred years old by now.
So are we, pal.
He can't been here
for more than a few hours.
Long enough to wake them up.
You ready?
Yeah.
You seem more defensively.
It's been a long day.
At ease, soldier.
I'm not coming after you.
Then why are you here?
Maybe, your story is not so crazy.
Maybe.
Ross has no idea I'm here,
I like to keep it that way.
Otherwise, I got to arrest myself.
Well, that sounds like
a lot of paper work.
- It's good to see you, Tony.
- Me too, Cap.
Make sure you can me,
you're killing me.
There's a truce here,
you can drop it.
- I got heat signatures.
- How many?
Uh, one.
If it's any comfort,
they died in their sleep.
Did you really think
I wanted more of you?
What the hell?
I'm grateful to them though,
they brought you here.
Please, Captain.
The Soviets built this chamber
to withstand the launch blast of
no fewer than a 100 rockets.
I'm betting I can beat that.
Oh, I'm sure you could, Mr. Stark.
Given time.
But then you'll never know
why you came.
You killed innocent people
in Vienna just to bring us here?
I thought about nothing else
for over a year.
I studied you,
I followed you.
But now that you are standing here,
I just realized...
There's a bit of green
in the blue of your eyes.
How nice to find a flaw.
You're Sokovian.
Is that what this is about?
Sokovia was a failed state
long before you blew it to hell.
No.
I'm here because I made a promise.
- You've lost someone.
- I've lost everyone.
And so will you.
An empire topple by its enemies
can rise again.
But one which crumples from within...
that's dead
... forever.
I know that road.
[ 16 December 1991 ]
What is this?
Help my wife.
Please.
Help her.
Sergeant Barnes.
Howard.
Howard!
Help.
Tony.
Did you know?
I didn't know it was him.
Don't shit me, Rogers!
Did you know?
Yes.
Get out of here!
It wasn't him, Tony.
Hydra had controlled of his mind!
Move!
It wasn't him!
Left boot-jet failing.
Flight systems compromised.
I hate that crap.
He's not going to stop.
Go.
- Come on. Come on.
- Targeting systems non-responds.
I'm eye balling him.
Do you even remember them?
I remember all of them.
This isn't going to change
what happened.
I don't care.
He killed my mom.
You should've seen his little face.
Just try, okay?
I'm going to bed.
I love you.
I almost kill the wrong man.
Hardly an innocent one.
Is this what you wanted?
To see them ripped each other apart.
My father lived outside the city.
I thought we would be safe there.
My son was excited.
He could see the Iron Man
from the car window.
And I told my wife,
"Don't worry."
"They are fighting in the city.
We are miles from harm."
When the dust cleared,
and the screaming stopped.
It took me two days
after I found their bodies.
My father...
still holding my wife
and son in his arms.
And the Avengers...
they went home.
I knew I couldn't kill them.
More powerful men than me have tried.
But, if I could get them
to kill each other?
I'm sorry about your father.
He seemed a good man.
With a dutiful son.
Vengeance has consumed you.
It's consuming them.
I'm not letting it consume me.
Justice will come soon enough.
Tell that to the dead.
The living are not done
with you yet.
You can't beat him hand to hand.
Analyse his fighting pattern.
Scanning!
Countermeasures ready.
Let's kick his ass.
He's my friend.
So was I.
Stay down.
Final warning.
I can do this all day.
That shield does not belong to you.
You don't deserve it!
My father made that shield!
Meals at eight and five.
Toilet privileges, twice a day.
Raise your voice, zap.
Touch the glass, zap.
You step out of line,
you deal with me.
Please, step out of line.
Hm?
So, how's it feel?
Send all that crime,
all that effort.
And, you seem to fail.
So spectacular.
Did it?
- That's just for the test.
- Yeah.
Give me some feedback.
Anything you can think of.
Shock absorption.
Lateral movement.
Cup holder?
No, I'm thinking about
some AC down there.
Give me your hand.
No, no, don't.
Don't help me. Don't help me.
138.
138 combat missions.
That's how many of my fly time.
Every one of them could've been
my last, but I flew em.
To the fight needed to be fought.
It's the same with these Accords.
I signed because it was
the right thing to do.
And, yeah, this sucks.
This is...
This is a bad beat.
But it hadn't change my mind.
What do you think?
- You okay?
- Oh yeah.
Are you Tony "Stank"?
Yes, this is-this is Tony "Stank"!
You're in the right place.
Thank you for that!
- I'm never dropping that, by the way.
- Oh my god.
Table for one, Mr. "Stank".
Please, by the bathroom.
Tony.
I'm glad you're back
at the compound.
I don't like the idea of you
rattling around in a mansion by yourself
We all need family.
The Avengers are yours,
maybe more so than mine.
I've been on my own
since I was 18.
I never really fit in anywhere.
even in the army.
My fate's in... people, I guess.
Individuals.
And, I am happy to say
for the most part,
they haven't let me down.
Which is why I can't
let them down either.
Lives can be replaced,
but, maybe they shouldn't.
I know I hurt you, Tony.
I guessed I thought by not telling you
about your parents, I was sparing you. But...
I can see now that
I was really sparing myself.
And I'm sorry.
Hopefully one day
you can understand.
I wished we'd agree on the Accords,
I really do.
I know you're doing
what you believe in.
And that's all any of us can do.
That's all any of us should.
Priority call from Secretary Ross.
There's been a breach
at the RAFT prison.
Yeah, put him through.
- Tony, we have a problem.
- Ah, please hold.
No.
Don't...
So, no matter what.
I promise you,
if you need us,
if you need me,
I'll be there.
Captain America
Civil War
- Sure about this?
- Yeah.
I can't trust my own mind.
So, until they figure out how to
get this stuff out of my head
I think going back under
is the best thing,
... for everyone.
Thank you for your help.
Your friend and my father,
they are both victims.
If I could help one of them
to find peace...
If they find out he's here,
they will come to take him.
Let them try.
Subtitle created by - Aorion -