"Quit part-time job"
Thanks for your support so far.
"Sell belongings"
We can pay for 30,000 yen in total.
"Bank"
I'll withdraw all savings.
"I'll pay back your money"
"The last day"
Original: Manga "Koe no Katachi " by Yoshitoki Oima
Movie: Koe no Katachi (A Silent Voice)
Animation: Kyoto Animation
(Elementary school grade 6 class 2)
Director: Naoko Yamada
Hey, sit down all.
We have a new classmate from today.
What?
You're lucky! A girl.
I'm not interested at all.
Well,
Then introduce yourself.
"For written communication"
"Nice to meet you. I am Shoko Nishimiya."
"I want to be friends with you all with this notebook."
"Please use this notebook when you talk to me."
"I can't hear."
Unbelievable...
Super!
"Hi, Nishimiya-san. I am Miki Kawai."
Hi, nice to meet you.
Hey, Nishimiya-san, can you speak Japanese?
Nao-chan, how you say...
"Once again please."
What were you called from friends?
Give up, give up!
I see, "Sho-chan".
That's same as Ishida.
She is called Sho-chan, too.
That's funny.
What? Not funny at all!
Please write down what I'm saying.
From page 20 to page 25, and drills of page 32.
It is the scope of the next small test.
Give me your notebook.
First, "fulcrum". The point that supports the strength.
Next, "the effort point", the point the strength is taken.
"The point of loading", the point that have weight.
With these 3 points, levers can be categorized...
Nishimiya-san,
You are too fast to start.
I will...
teach you the timing, okay?
Then, let's start again.
How should we do the coming chorus competition?
We already lose, don't we?
That's the penalty for saying weird things!
Ouch, ouch!
Ouch!
So today,
I missed what teacher said again due to her...
I'll lend my notebook.
Thank you.
"I am not wrong."
"That's why I will never say sorry."
What a poor reading, Ueno.
Crap. That's enough. Next.
To the hell, ugly glasses.
Nishimiya.
From this sentence.
Okay. Good. Next, Ishida.
Really? Unbelievable.
Hey, Ishida!
"Please let me know what you are talking about."
Let's go home.
Bye-bye, Nishimiya-san.
Hey you,
At this rate, won't you frustrate classmates?
What?
SL: I,
SL: And you,
SL: Friends?
fie-nds...
What?
Disgusting!
I'm Kita, of a special education class.
Today I wanna talk about "Shuwa" - sign language.
Write as "speaking with hands" and pronounce "Shu-wa".
As the word says, Shuwa means speaking using your hands.
Isn't it amazing?
Sign...language...
So I propose a 3-minute lesson of sign language everyday morning,
to understand Shoko-chan even more.
Teacher.
Yes?
Isn't it enough to use her notebook?
It's easier for Shoko-chan using sign language.
It's easier for me using the notebook.
I'll learn sign language.
"Teach me sign language for Sahara Miyoko"
Sa - Ara
I - Jo - ko
Got it!
Sa - a ...
Good job getting brownie points.
I love him so much. He is so handsome.
Agree!
He will be in the drama next week. Must watch!
Don't you think her clothes are ugly?
Stop it, Nao-chan.
The author described through this work,...
After the experiment, manganese dioxide should be...
Hirose, you write that side.
Ni-shi-mi-ya.
What are you doing, Ishida ?
Isn't better to stop that?
Star.
Ishida, you did too much.
No, no, it's what it should be.
You're a bad guy.
Nice, nice.
It's really nice.
Congrats, Nishimiya-san. Sahara-san went away because of you!
That's so bad! Who did such nasty things!
Too bad!
I...will...kindly...
erase...it...for...you...
Okay.
All erased.
"Thank you."
You are welcome.
Let's go.
Joumon-era was...
Hey, Ishida.
Class is not over.
I see. I'm sorry.
Well...I have lost where I was talking at...
Well, what kind of house were they living. They lived..
So surprised, are you?
Hey, Nishimiya-san.
Is this mean you can actually hear?
Yeah, I thought the same thing, too.
Please let me see it for a while?
Ueno.
What is it? Give me.
Oh, what is this?
It's filthy!
Wh--What?
Oh my god,
Nishimiya-san, are you okay?
How should I do....?
Nishimiya-san...
Hey, you did too far.
Crap, so annoying, ugly glasses.
What? Go away.
Don't interrupt.
What is she doing?
Let's go home.
"I'm sorry."
You're a liar!
If you want to say something to me, say it!
What!?
Stop it, you are disgusting!
Oh, Nishimiya-san is funny!
Shoya, you are blushing, aren't you?
No, I'm not!
SL: I,
SL: And you,
SL: Friends?
Let's go.
Oh, is she serious, Nishimiya-san?
It's unbelievable!
See you tomorrow, Shoya.
Well, today I have a topic I want to talk to you all.
It's about Nishimiya-san, who is absent today.
Yesterday we had a call from Nishimiya-san's mother.
She said 8 of Nishimiya-san's hearing aids have gone missing
or been damaged in just 5 months.
Nishimiya-san's mother worries if she is bullied at school.
If any of you know anything about bullying
or similar harassments to Nishimiya-san, please let us know.
We hear her hearing aids are very expensive.
So please confess, before your parents are in trouble.
Hey, Ishida.
We all know it was you.
Stand up right now!
Yes.
Ueno.
How did you thought, seeing next to him?
He might do something to kidding her or so?
How about you, Shimada?
I'd been saying
"hey, stop it" to him,
but Shoya didn't stopped.
Hey, Shimada,
You did with me together, didn't you?
And, girls said bad things about her so many times.
Especially Ueno and Kawai did.
How cruel you are..
I never do such things.
Why you tell such a lie?
Ishida-kun, you are too bad.
He made her cry.
Why it is here...?
I see. Yes.
I'm very sorry.
I see. I see.
Thank you for calling.
Shoya.
Stop now, Shoya!
I got a call from school.
Hey...
Why are you so wet?
Shut up, Jumped in the river like always.
Wait.
Don't you make a trouble with someone?
I don't know.
Is what your teacher said correct?
Y...Yes!
Prepare to go out right now. We have to meet Nishimiya-san's.
(Mizuho Bank)
Sho-chan, let's go home.
Be a good child from tomorrow, okay?
These are missing...
Great men and women experienced hard time, and...
"Shoya Ishida"
What are you doing?
Hey, what are you doing with my desk?
What were you doing. Disgusting!
Same smile again.
Don't pretend to be a good girl!
What?
If you wanna say something to me, say it now!
Every time you show that disgusting smile instead.
You are angry, aren't you!?
Hey!
Say something!
Ouch!
What are you doing!
What?!
Doigg mai bezd...
I'b doigg mai bezd!
What are you saying?!
What!
I can't understand what you say!
"Disappear, Ishida."
Crap...
She is so disgusting...
Nishimiya-san has transferred to another school.
Huh.
Hey, our class journal was not submitted today.
Who is in charge?
And, who is in charge of keeping the flowers?
"Sign language study class"
SL: Hello.
Hi, Shoko-chan. Hello.
Nishimiya!
Do you remember me?
I was your classmate of the elementary school...
Shoya Ishida.
Nishimiya?
Wait!
Nishimiya!
Where?
Nishimiya.
H...Hi.
Well...
Here it is.
I came here to give it to you.
This is "what you left behind."
You say "why sign language?"
I leaned it.
And, here...
You might not want to see this again.
Well...
I...and...
Nishimiya,
can we be
friends?
Damn, what am I saying!?
H...hey, you said so in the past.
I finally understood what you said...
Please don't cry.
Please don't cry, Nishimiya.
Can I be friends with you?
Sho-tan,
Sho-tan, wake up!
Breakfast!
Sho-chan, wake up!
Good morning, Maria.
Sho-tan woke up!
I'll go.
Mama, bye bye!
Here, Sho-chan.
Let's eat.
Dig in!
Huh?
Why you are so smiling.
Because of...
this!
You worked hard,
and you sold everything, even including beddings.
I'm very happy for all of your efforts.
By the way, Sho-chan...
Why did you try to kill yourself?
Yeah, actually,
It's a long story you know,
But it comes to be...
I knew it...
I knew it!
I knew something was going on around you!
Your room was extraordinarily vacant, your phone was out of service,
and the calendar in your room...
Pages after April were torn off...
Right now promise you never try to kill yourself, or I'll burn this.
This 1,700,000 yen you worked hard and earned!
Hey, are you listening to me!?
Don't be stupid, mom...
YOU ARE stupid, what an ungrateful child you are!
Hey, well, ah...
Sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'll stop.
I'll stop. I'm sorry. Really!
You'll stop what, say clearly!
I'll stop trying to kill myself!
Really?
Really.
Okay, that's a promise.
Hey! Mon!
Hey, water, water!
Yesterday, I had thought
to kill myself by jumping into a river from a very high bridge.
The reason I went to meet Nishimiya was also a ceremony before it.
It was my biggest braveness challenge all of my life,
but the story was changed...
"Friend"
Shame! Why did I say such a thing!?
When we just entered junior high school, Shimada said;
You'd better stay away from a guy Shoya Ishida.
He is...
a bully.
What I did would all return to myself.
I fully realized
that I had to owe the responsibility of what I had did.
And I was isolated.
Good morning.
Then
Translate these sentences by the next lesson.
Ishida-kun.
Yes.
Kawai...
Can I gather your math homework if you finish it?
Oh...sorry, I have forgotten it.
Okay, I see.
Please finish it soon as the deadline is coming.
Yes, I will. Sorry.
Let's have lunch outside.
"Ishida-kun is always alone as you can see."
"Everyone knows it."
Oh, really?
"Oh, he is looking at us as always."
"Isn't he feeling desperate always being alone?"
"He will be same as now forever."
"Why is he still living?"
H...Hi, here it is.
I just bought this limited edition, and...
Oops.
Then I'll quit to be a fan of them.
Me too.
That's the reality...
I remember that hair.
Who is he?
By the way,
can I meet Nishimiya again?
She said she feeds carp in the river.
How can I do so by what reason?
Can I see her to apologize what I did?
She said she'll be there every Tuesday.
Am I weird if I visit again?
I'm home.
Sho---chan?
I'm so surprised.
What?
I'm very sorry for what happened in the morning.
I burned money you earned hard.
But I don't want to use any money
you saved to die.
Sorry, I'll save up again.
Thanks.
You can be slower this time, okay?
You are hungry, huh? Let's have dinner.
Hungry!
Tuesday.
Hey you, why don't you lend your bike to me?
Me?
Oh, the guy I remember.
I left something behind. I want to go home to get it.
Huh? What are you saying?
You should use your own one.
I ask you 'cause I don't have my own.
Stop it please.
Hey, don't resist.
Hey, stop it!
Someone please help me!
Someone!
Oh, dear.
Please, please help me! Help! Help!
Shut up!
Stop resisting!
H...hey.
I...I'll lend you my own.
Really!? You are super!
It was ripped off.
Actually, today of all day is Tuesday.
This means I should not see her again?
Of course I still can go on foot,
but it seems as I was advised not to go.
I want a reason.
A smart,
and natural reason to see her again.
"Discount coupon for a brand-new bread ?"
That's it!
Well...Is Nishimiya-san here?
No, she isn't
She is, isn't she?
Shoko Nishimiya isn't here.
Sorry but,
are you really a friend of Shoko?
Bye.
SL: What?
Nothing.
A rat was there.
A big creepy one.
Don't be afraid. It won't come again.
Friend...
Why...is he here?
O--Oh, he is!
Ishida-kun!
Look! Look at this!
A bike! It's yours, isn't it?
Good timing!
It was so lucky that your address was written on the bike.
Wh...where was this bike?
It was abandoned in a rice paddy.
I looked for this all over the time!
I'm glad I got it back to you!
Is something wrong, Ishida-kun?
Well..
Your name?
Oops! I'm Nagatsuka!
I sit just behind you in the class.
Don't you eat some bread?
This is so good, Nagatsuka-kun.
Ishida-kun!
Ishida-kun.
Good morning!
Good morning...
Ishida-kun!
Why don't we hang out after school?
As we are friends now.
Ishida-kun, come here, come here!
What's wrong with you, Ya-sho?
Nothing.
Ya... "Ya-sho"?
Sounds like a "big friend", doesn't it?
Anyway, what are you worrying about?
You can tell anything, 'cause we are real friends.
Nagatsuka-kun,
what is the definition of "friends"?
A kind of license,
or right or something like that,
to become friends with someone.
Hey, Ya-sho.
Give me your hand.
This is friendship.
I think, Ishida-kun,
friendship exists beyond words and logic.
License? No such things are needed.
It's a ridiculous idea.
She is not here.
She is, isn't she?
She isn't.
Huh, who are you anyway?
I'm Shoko's boyfriend.
Oops! ... Dropped.
Haha, that not about me, but a bread.
O...oh, really?
Nishimiya likes younger guys.
I'm a little surprised that.
Okay, then how about giving this bread to her at least?
This is a very good bread.
Hey.
Don't be here again, if you only want to satisfy yourself.
Are you satisfied?
Then bye.
Hey boy!
My friend wants to see Nishimiya-san!
Stop complaining and bring her here right now!
Nagatsuka-kun, why are you here?
I followed you.
Sounds like a behavior of best friends?
Haha, so the friend of a turd had a turd hair.
Hey, you a turd-hair!
Wh---what are you saying?!
Say that again boy!
Turd-hair, turd-hair, turd-hair!
What's happening?
Is that Yuzuru-chan?
Oh, no. They are fighting.
Nagatsuka-kun, Nagatsuka-kun!
Stop it, okay?
Nagatsuka-kun, that's enough, let's go home now.
Nagatsuka-ku...
Oh? Aren't you the boy of the other day?
I--it's not like that!
Nagatsuka-kun, sorry for leaving you!
Oh, crap!
Crap, she found and met him.
Good for you, Ishida-kun!
Hey boy.
You are peeping now, aren't you?
Let me use it now!
What?
SL: Long time no see.
Ishida-kun is waving his hands.
Wouldn't it be sign language?
SL: Have you been well?
Really!?
Wow, I didn't know he has such a skill.
Hey, can you read their sign language?
Then translate it for me!
Who was that turd-hair just now?
SL: I'm glad to see you again.
SL: Are you okay leaving your sign language class?
I don't know such turd.
Oops, he was so creepy!
S-T-O-P J-O-K-I-N-G!
Leave me alone!
Be careful not to fall, boy.
"Honestly,"
"I thought I shouldn't see you again."
"The meaning of being friends."
"I've been thinking of it for all these 2 weeks."
"The reason to..."
"see you again."
"I have been looking for it."
Ishida-kun...
"I'm glad."
"I thought"
"the same thing as you."
"It's strange, isn't it?"
Nishimiya, here it is. A bread.
To feed carp.
Is this feeding fun?
Oh, I was just reminded.
SL: Thank you.
Nishimiya...
Y...you had better not read it...
so much!
Hey! wait, Nishimiya!
Oh! She fell!
What!? Something happened to Ishida-kun!?
Hey!
Hey, boy!
Oops! Ishida-kun fell to the river!
Why!?
Ouch!
Why you do so!
Oops, what is this creepy thing!?
Nishimiya.
Nishimiya!
Sorry for dropping the notebook.
See you.
SL: See you again.
You're stupid, Shoko...
"Any of you got more guts than me?"
"Shoya Ishida"
Stupid!
Did you see this?
Hey, isn't this guy Ishida-kun?
"See you again."
Can I?
Hey.
This is Ishida-kun, isn't it?
This guy.
What?
What's this.
Ishida-kun, come to the teachers' room right now.
"Notice of short-term suspension from school - Shoya Ishida"
"I am very sorry that I jumped into Suimon River from a bridge,"
"where it was prohibited to do so, and..."
"uploaded that photo to the web... "
Hey, Shoya.
Sorry but could you pick Maria back from the nursery?
I'm in a school suspension term and prohibited to go out.
It would be okay if you do it quickly. Please!!
H...hey!!
Maria, let's go home now!
Sho-tan!
Someone is there!
Hey.
Hey, are you okay?
Aren't you Nishimiya's boyfriend?
You'll catch a cold.
Oh, you're the rat.
What are you doing here?
Shoes?
...Why don't you get angry with me?
On what?
It's me who uploaded your photo to the web.
Oh, you did it.
I got it.
I am relieved to hear that.
Why?
I would know the reason why.
Be mad with me.
I cannot.
Originally I am to be blamed.
Sho-tan!
I am hungry!
Okay!
Then I'll go home.
You go home, too.
Haha, you have a kid.
It's not mine, my sis's!
Hey!
Hi Yuzuru-kun,
Please eat enough!
How about sis?
She'll work late today.
Maria, isn't it too hot?
No, it's good!
Yuzuru-kun, why don't you eat?
Hi, Yuzuru-kun!
Please!
SL: You should apologize,
SL: or I don't need you!
Crap...
What's the matter with you.
I was worried as you disappeared in the night.
Hi, umbrella.
Anyway, use it!
Well, please use it now.
Thank you.
Well, excuse me.
I knew that.
I'll give you these.
These were mine, but
I won't use them anymore. I'll give you.
Why you ran away home?
I had an argument with Shoko.
That's a kind of a typical event
for a long-lasting couple, isn't it?
Yes.
Like that I used Shoko's shampoo without her permission.
I see...
I was said she didn't need me.
Hey, you live together with her!?
Use your umbrella for you.
You have only one, don't you?
It's my mistake I brought only one umbrella.
And I feel sorry for Nishimiya if you catch cold.
Hey you.
What kind of a man you intend to be? A hypocrite?
You feel pleasure taking care of a stray cat?
Or you make fun of doing it.
And you also made fun that she couldn't hear.
Then, now you learned sign language huh?
What's this?
Do you think you have changed to be a good guy?
You are disgusting.
I see.
It's natural you know what I did, hearing from Nishimiya.
Yes. You are right.
I'm the worst human being.
I'm the one who don't worth living.
But, at least,
I thought I didn't want Nishimiya to cry again.
Of course, I have no intention to interfere you two.
Never.
But, actually,
It's an issue of myself, too...
Thanks, it's enough here.
Well..
I'm very sorry that you perfectly believe what I said..
But actually I'm Shoko's...
Understood?
You are her little sis!?
Bye!
Oh, Nishimiya-san's mother...
Hey, let's go.
Hey, it pains.
I'm sorry...
I'm home.
Yu-ju,
Hey, sis!
I'b zorry, I'b zorry!
Me too.
I wanna drink grandma's beefsteak plant juice.
Yuzuru.
Don't be friends with such a guy.
Tell same thing to Shoko from you.
We can decide such a thing by ourselves---
both I and sis.
Hey boy!
Nice to see you!
Why are you here today?
To return his umbrella I lend the other day.
Oh boy.
You are doing a good thing.
Nagatsuka-kun, that child is not a boy...
Little sis of Nishimiya.
Of course, I knew it.
I'm glad to see a friend of my best friend Ya-sho.
He is my classmate,
Na-ga-tsu-ka.
I got my new smart phone.
Well..
Do you have a smart phone too?
Then do you enjoy texting?
With your classmates?
Of your current school?
Oh, that's good.
Then do you have someone you want to add to text?
Someone you want to know the address.
Great, then my address is...
What?
Sa...ha...ra.
Sahara-san? Our classmate of the elementary school?
Ya-sho, Ya-sho!
Then?
Are you going to look for Sahara-san?
Don't be joking. I don't intend to be so.
But I really think Kawai-san is very clever.
Kawai-san...
Ya-sho?
But Mashiba-kun is also..
Kawai-san...?
What?
I...I have
something to ask to you.
Do you know phone number or something to contact
of Sahara-san, our classmate of the elementary school?
Sahara-san?
Sorry, I don't know...,
But I know her school,
as she belongs the same school as Nao-chan.
Taiyo female high school...
Oops, my money is not enough.
Ishida-kun.
Use this.
What!? I don't need that much!
Don't mind, Ya-sho.
When you need travel, meal, and then love hotel expenses,
You will be safe to have that much.
Hey!
We are here!
My sis says
she pisses you as you're looking for a past classmate without her.
So take her with you, Ishida.
Title: Are you tired?
"I got your address from Yuzuru. Thank you for today."
"I'm glad to hear that you are looking for Sahara-san!"
"I have heard various news about you from Yuzuru."
"I'm pleased to go together today!"
"Taiyo Female High School"
Well...
Walking from here and...
Sho-chan?
Sorry.
Sho-chan!
I'm Sahara!
Do you remember me?
Hello!
Huh? Ishida-kun?
Long time no see.
SL: Long time no see.
I've continued to study sign language after that.
Is this correct?
I disappeared when we were in the elementary school...
I'm sorry.
I have been thinking of Sho-chan for long time.
I'm happy to see you again.
And I'm surprised.
SL: Me too.
Oh, really?
Huh, and now,
What kind of school you are going to?
I see.
And, hey, your chest got big, you know.
What's your cup size?
I'll check for myself!
Where are you going?
A restroom.
I see.
Hello! We handing out a discount coupon for you!
Discount coupon!
Ueno...
Here it is.
"Mew mew club"...
From: Sahara-san
You are great that you learned sign language.
And thank you for bringing us together!
Sahara is so aggressive.
I cannot behave like her...
Can I bring Ueno together, too?
Huh? Naturally impossible, you know?
I think so, too.
Well...
Let's go, Nagatsuka-kun.
Now is the time to "Mew mew club"!
Can I help you?
How long are you going to stay?
One hour, please.
Can we use this coupon?
Yes, you can.
Oh, unbelievable. He actually comes...
Well, how should I say, but...
What in the world did you expect?
S...so did you?
Don't say stupid things to me.
I was simply interested in your old friend.
Yes, your old friend...
Is she here?
Actually, not a friend.
Then what?
A little complicated.
There were something in the elementary school time.
She seems not here today.
Let's go home then.
"Hearing Test Room"
An insect!
Hi, you were here.
Came to play with Maria.
By the way, will Nishimiya be pleased if I give this pouch?
A cat!
Sis, I've got something for you!
...Sis?
I'll put some present for you here.
U--Ueno...
...san?
Go, go!
Wait, wait, what!?
Long time no see!
Yeah. Long time no see.
Huh? The girl over there is Nishimiya, isn't she?
She seems still alone, haha.
Too poor!
Ishida! It's really a long time not seeing you.
Let's hang out together shortly.
No thank you.
Ishida, you hate me, don't you?
I don't know.
Actually,
I have been thinking
I should have talk earlier.
I'm sorry when we were in the elementary school.
Ueno, get off my bike.
Why she has a pouch of the cat cafe I'm working in?
Why? So weird!
I gave it to her.
Oh...I see.
Good-bye.
Bye.
Ueno?
Nishimiya-san, long time no see! How have you been?
H..hey!!
Huh? Why you wear only one?
Ueno! What are you doing!?
Throwing away to play, as we did in the past.
Sorry, Nishimiya.
Are you joking, Ishida?
Wait! Let us wait a moment!
You two are going together?
No, not like that.
Just friends.
Friends?
Don't make me laugh!
You are friends with a girl who you bullied?
Why?
I cannot follow you!
Oh, understand. A kind of sense of guilt?
No.
Ishida, you have became a so boring guy.
Now I don't stop you two playing friends!
"What did you talk about?"
N--Nothing special.
Well, I have to go now.
See you again.
Yuju,
I'z mornigg.
I'm quite awake. So surprised.
Bregbazt, lez eed now.
Wait, wait, before that..
What's happened?
Sis.
Ponytail today? Why?
What a weird face!
Then make Ishida have a chance to see her!
"So many carp. More bread needed."
"You MUST come."
Nishimiya...
Ponytail!?
Whea are yu goig, Ijida-gun?
"Where are you going?"
I'm going to a bread shop.
Yuzuru asked to buy a bread for feeding carp.
Yuju muzt habe id. Yuju only wand do ead bi herzelb.
Hey, Nishimiya!
Ijida-gun, don'd need do go
Wait. Sign language! Sign language!
Iz Mai voize stranze?
Yes.
Oh, sorry.
It's completely okay.
W--well, I have to go now. Bread.
Then bye.
Nishimiya?
Huh? You give this?
Thanks.
Can I open it here?
...What are these?
Thank you very much.
...ige...oo...
What?
About these?
I...ige...moo...
Huh?...
I lige moo!
Moon?
Yeah.
It's beautiful.
Ni...Nishimiya!?
"From: Big friend Nagatsuka"
"How about watching a movie from now?"
Hey Nagatsuka-kun,
Can you see this as a moon?
Huh? I cannot see that as a moon.
C--Candy?
These are not candies.
Nishimiya gave them just now,
but I'm not sure what they are.
What's the matter, sis?
"I said Ishida-kun that I like him."
Oh, really!?
"But he didn't understand what I said."
Wow, you have changed your hairstyle.
Why changed? What happened?
It matches you so much!
Stop, stop you all.
I was in a bit of rush this morning, that's all.
But that looks great anyway.
Hi, Kawai-san.
Why you have changed your hairstyle?
I don't have any special reason to do it.
I see.
That's what girls do, you know?
Okay.
What?
By the way, Mashiba-kun
said he wants to be friends with you.
Why...why you are here today.
I'm Sahara, nice to meet you.
Me too. I'm Mashiba.
Hey! Stop doing that over my head!
Miyo-chan, long time no see.
By the way, where is Nishimiya today?
Sis went home as she had a stomachache.
I wonder she may be avoiding me...?
Why do you think so?
The other day,
She was trying hard to tell me something,
but I couldn't understand what she said.
Huh, what did sis tried to tell?
Moon.
I couldn't understand very simple words she told.
I guess that would make her mad.
If you want to know if sis is avoiding you or not,
why don't you invite her playing something?
If she is still angry, she will say no.
That's a good idea.
(From: Ishida) We plan to hang out somewhere,
so how about going together?
Hi all, let's start with that roller coaster!
Follow me so that you don't lost!
Hey, why is that girl leading us?
I don't know.
Ishida.
Who's that girl?
She seems too familiar with sis.
Ueno... Why...
Is she Shoko's acquaintaince?
Y--yes,
when we were in the elementary school.
Can I sit next to you, Sahara-san?
Yeah, of course.
Are you all ready?
Yeah!!
Then let's start.
Sahara-san, are you okay to be with Ueno?
Yes.
I'm in the same class of the same high school with her now.
I'm learning a lot from her taste and skills.
I'd been scared to ride when I was in elementary school.
I was a coward at that time.
But I changed my way a bit.
I'd ride first, then I see if it scares me or not.
Honestly, I'm still scared a bit.
Hey, it comes!
Hey, are you okay?
Your legs are so trembling, Sho-chan.
"Are you okay?"
You are fantastic as you can use sign language!
You did your best to learn sign language, Ishida-kun!
SL: Fun!
Hey, is this hand yours?
You are so rude to my best friend Ya-sho!
Huh? I simply want to be friends with him.
No, don't act like a child!
Nagatsuka-kun, you're so funny!
My permission is needed when you speak to Ya-sho!
Nagatsuka-kun, is your hair natural one?
What!? Don't be silly!
Hey! Stop touching my hair!
Wait...
Mashiba-kun, go away faster!
Go, go, Ya-sho, go!
Wait...
Can I...?
Can I enjoy like this?
But it seems like that...
What are you doing?!
It seems like...
Friends!
Ishida.
I want to eat takoyaki snacks.
Let go to buy together.
What!? Hey!
Here's takoyaki. Thank you for buying.
Thank you very much.
Hey you, Ueno,
I don't want such unnecessary kindness.
Shi...Shimada...
Hey, Ishida!
Sorry, but I'll text you later.
Ishida!
You got angry?
No. I'm not angry.
Being angry -- No.
I just thought--
if you two meet again,
you could be friends again.
Things might go well if you two meet again.
Don't do such misplaced kindness.
I did the same things to them...
You and me are alike, huh?
No. we are not.
We are alike.
We are not.
Well.
If Nishimiya-san hadn't come, we all would have been happy.
Don't jump to such a conclusion at your discretion.
But wasn't it correct?
If she had not be there,
I would not have a quarrel with Sahara, and,
friendship between you and Shimada wouldn't have been broken.
I wanna go back to the time before Nishimiya-san came.
As for things with Shimada,
I simply did so intentionally.
Ishida, you hate me?
Perhaps yes.
Now I feel like to ride the ferris wheel.
I wanna ride it with Nishimiya-san.
H--hey!
Nishimiya-san, let's ride the ferris wheel together.
Hey, Ueno!
Sis, sorry but take this camera with you.
I'm going to ride the roller coaster again.
Hi, you are welcome, Yuzuru-chan.
Shoya is in his room.
Hi.
I got a highly confidential movie.
A movie in the ferris wheel?
Yes.
Huh? What do you mean?
Peeping cam.
Well, I...
I hate you.
Let's not use it.
I'll speak clearly so that you can understand, and
I'll carefully listen to what you say.
In the elementary school,
I didn't understand you enough.
But I think you didn't understand us, too.
That's why you bothered me with a weird notebook
and always smiled insincerely.
You always said sorry when something happened.
So I changed the way.
I ignored you and talked about you behind your back.
These were my message not to interfere us any more.
But,
you didn't understand it and got us back--
by ratting on us to adults.
As a result, Ishida lost his friends.
Lot of things around us were broken by you.
I...I'b zorry...
Actually, I don't want you to apologize.
Our views were very narrow in the childhood,
and we did our best within that limitation.
But I don't wanna say you let's be friends now.
I still hate you, and
you still hate me.
But how about being peaceful between us?
So let's shake hands, even each hate each.
Zat'z nod correcd...
I hade myzelf...
So what?
What's that?
Then?
You still say "I'm sorry"!?
After all,
you're shutting your mind talking with me, as you did 5 years ago.
How do you think about it?
I want Nishimiya
to like herself.
Ueno--san, right?
Yeah. Ueno?
Did Nishimiya-san have some troubles with her?
Why do you think so?
Kawai-san said there had been something in the past.
By the way, I was surprised
Nishimiya-san was really unable to hear.
Yes, she is.
Oh, then, I guess,
she was bullied because of that?
I cannot forgive
that kind of bully.
Don't you think so, Ishida-kun?
What do you mean!?
You say I am spreading what you did in the past!?
Hey, you're speaking too loudly...
After all, Ishida-kun hasn't changed at all from the past!
What!?
You've always told me cruel things since the elementary school!
What's the matter, Ya-sho?
Calm down, Kawai-san.
What are you talking about?
Mashiba-kun!
Ishida-kun used to bully a girl in the past.
What are you saying, Kawai-san?
Don't be silly..
It's true!
Kawai-san also said bad things at that time...
I never said bad things to Nishimiya-san!
What!? Nishimiya-san!?
Yes.
Ishida-kun bullied Nishimiya-san!
I asked him please to stop doing that,
but he never listened to what I said.
He scared me so much...
Ya-sho?
Are you okay?
Sorry, Nagatsuka-kun..
Ya-sho...
Ya-sho!
I hate myself, too...
Hi, Ishida.
Hi!
What's wrong?
SL: Are you all right?
No, nothing special.
Nothing...
Hey, Ishida-kun, you are here!
I'm bringing your bag here!
Hey.
Nao-chan..
...I asked her to come.
I'm sorry in the classroom, Ishida-kun.
But,
originally you are to blamed.
SL: What's going on?
if Ishida-kun apologize to Nishimiya-san,
then we can forgive you.
That's Mashiba-kun's idea, so...
Stop it.
That's not proper way.
We have no right to blame Ishida for this matter.
"We"?
That's not correct, Nao-chan.
What?
Different from me,
Nao-chan proactively bullied Nishimiya-san.
You should not treat me like yourself.
Nao-chan...
Yes.
You're right. We are different.
Completely different.
You were just looking on and laughed at her being bullied.
You're so awful!
Hey, Sahara, how do you think about?
Me!?
Nao-chan also said so many bad things to Sahara-san.
I just said true things!
Hey, answer now, Sahara!
I...I was..
at that time...
I was scared to both of you.
What!? Which side you are on!?
I'm not on any side of you!
Stop all.
It's all my fault.
I hate that kind of logic.
Stop, Ueno.
Don't conclude everything by yourself.
Ishida-kun, don't say things in such way...
Stop, Sahara.
You'll ran away after all like the past and regret,
and say "I was a coward".
What's wrong with you, Ishida-kun?
Stop speaking, Kawai.
You simply like yourself the most.
Ya-sho,
I'm always on you side...
Don't say such a thing not knowing me enough!
That's enough! I'm going home!
Ya-sho...
It's all right. I don't mind at all.
Sho-chan,
see you again.
Sorry, Ishida.
I regret to come here.
Ishida-kun, you were too terrible.
Don't be in touch, an outsider.
I had thought we became friends.
Oh, by the way,
from the next week,
summer holidays will start.
Why don't we hang out somewhere?
Yuzu.
You'll hurt your eyes seeing something in such a dark place.
Here.
Yuzu, you still worry about sis?
I'm worrying about you, Yuzuru.
You are always caring about your sis,
and don't caring about yourself.
Aren't you doing the same thing, gramma?
You don't join senior people groups and study sign language all the time.
That's just what I want to do.
Then so do I. I'm also doing so for myself.
Really?
You're a very good granddaughter, Yuzu.
I don't think so.
I'm scolded everyday from mom,
and I've not gone to school for a while.
Yuzu have a very beautiful soul.
Shoko is also doing her best.
I'm proud of having very good granddaughters.
How about a sweet manju?
Yes, of course!
SL: I want to kill myself.
Grandma...
Hi Nishimiya.
Today I got a very good bread.
This bread is--
as wonderful as you,
so...
Hmmm, does it sound strange?
Nishimiya doesn't come today?
Well..
"Hi, Nishimiya, do you have a stomachache again today?"
Hmmm, this message is not good.
Hey, Yuzu...
I'll go home now...
Ishida.
Hey!
What is your outfit?
What? This is my school uniform.
How you feel, how you feel?!
Why?
School.
But it is in the summer vacation now.
What's actually wrong with you?
Nothing.
If I am to explain... a kind of cos-play?
A text from my sis. I have to go.
I'll take you. Where?
No thank you.
I will.
I don't wanna you do so.
I saw you cried just now.
Why?
It's got nothing to do with you, Ishida.
Yes it is.
I want to think it is.
Why?
I'm worring about Yuzuru.
Don't say what my grandma would say...
Then I don't care if you follow me.
Thank you, Ishida.
It's enough here.
"Funeral for Ito Nishimiya"
Bye.
Hold out, Yuzuru!
Ishida.
I found myself still scared a bit.
SL: Grandma...
SL: Yes, it must be grandma.
(To: Nishimiya) How about hanging out somewhere tomorrow?
SL: It's refreshing.
Oh, it's splendid.
Com'on, Nishimiya. Let's go over there.
Nishimiya?
Haha... I was a bit scared.
SL: I'm sorry.
What? Why do you say sorry now?
SL: You'll be unhappy as far as you're with me.
Don't say such a ridiculous thing!
Hey, Nishimiya, how about tomorrow?
Let's hang out tomorrow, too!
Hey, Nishimiya!
Nishimiya said that--
I'd be unhappy as far as I'm with her.
The person who made Nishimiya unhappy--
was I, actually...
I want to see the ocean,
I want to love humans,
even a monster has
a heart...
I cannot imagine how to recover the relationship...
Hey, Nishimiya! Yuzuru is here too today!
Then let's go to watch a movie!
SL: Hello.
Hahaha, how funny it is!
Hey, I'm here today!
What fruitful summer holidays we have this year!
Don't you agree with me, Yuzuru?
I don't know...
It's really full of enjoyment.
Hey, Nishimiya,
how about tomorrow?
Let's go out somewhere tomorrow, too!
We cannot go tomorrow, as we have a thing to do.
What?
SL: Let's make it together.
Really!? Are you serious!?
What are you going to make?
I---is this okay?
Is it okay that I'm here?
Now that Ishida is assigned to help us--
to make a birthday cake for our mother.
Really?
I---is that okay?
Your mom will slap me again, won't she?
It might be even more. She may kill you.
Hey!
Oh, it looks delicious!
What? Why is this guy here?
Shoko, what do you intend to do?
Get out now...
Stop, mom! Today is your celebration day!
Yuzuru...
You looks good with this!
Tastes good!
Good for you Ishida, you didn't get killed.
Y--Yes.
Good for sis, too!
By the way, Yuzuru.
I submitted some of your photos to the prefectural photo contest.
What?
Sho-chan wanted to submit for you.
SL: Mom selected the photo.
But I suppose all the photos are kind of creepy.
Not necessarily so.
Hey, you two did so without asking me!
By the way, there'll be a fireworks festival next Tuesday.
SL: Let's go together.
Hmmm, I'd like to pass.
Hey, let's go together.
Is it okay here?
Well, I'll go to buy fried noodles.
Let's go together.
Oh, thank you.
Well, thank you for inviting me to your apartment the other day.
Your mom...
SL: It was fun.
Did she enjoy the party?
Basically she had no facial expressions, but...
What day is your birthday, Nishimiya?
June...
7th.
Oh, it's already passed!
Then,
Nishimiya is 18 years old already.
Next year, let's celebrate your birthday together.
Oops,
I said "together" unintentionally...
SL: I'm feeling it by the body, instead of ear.
I see.
Understood.
It's interesting.
Oh, what's up?
SL: I'll be going.
But fireworks are not over yet...
"To study"...
I see.
Then I'll go with you.
SL: No, I'm okay.
But...
SL: I'm okay.
I see.
See you again.
SL: Thank you.
Huh? what happened to sis?
By the way, Ishida,
can you go to our apartment to pick up my camera?
Good evening..
Oh, it's dark.
Nishimiya, I'm here...
Here it is.
Is it charged?
Oh, we can see fireworks from here.
You are here, Nishimiya.
Hi, Nishimi...ya...
Nishimiya?
Wait! Wait a moment!
What are you doing?!
Nishimiya?
Nishimiya!
Shoko!
Why...
Why, Nishimiya...
Nishimiya, rails!
Grip the rails!
Please, God...
Give me just one more ounce of strength.
I won't run away from what I hate.
Starting tomorrow,
I'll look at everyone's face.
Starting tomorrow, I'll listen to everyone's voice.
Starting tomorrow, I'll do everything properly...
Ni...Nishimiya..
Oh, a scar I made in the past...
Did I properly apologize for that?
Sorry.
I'm sorry, Nishimiya.
Are you still mad?
Oh, I--
I should have ask Nishimiya--
how you really think of me...
By the way, you know, I---
Sho-chan,
Sis made pancakes for you.
Maria will go out to see fireworks!
SL: Friends.
It's cold...
and warm...
Hi, ma'am.
Hi, Yuzuru-chan.
I finally saw you.
No one answered when I called to the salon, and
entering the room was prohibited...
Oh, that's okay now.
He changed rooms today.
Let's go to the room together, to see him.
Ma'am, well Shoko...
Ishida-san.
Nishimiya-san...
Nishimiya-san...I'm sorry.
Sorry again for troubling like this.
I'm very sorry.
Oh, please stop it.
My son must have done something wrong to Shoko-san, unless...
Ma'am.
Ishida saved my stupid sister.
I owe all the responsibility of mismanagement.
I'm very sorry, too.
Please...
Please raise your heads.
Nothing is better than that Shoko-san is okay, isn't it?
So do you, Yuzuru-chan.
Please...
Why in the world does Ishida have to be injured!
Don't pretend to be a tragedy heroine!
Say something!
"I made lots of troubles and bothered everyone, "
"so I'll apologize by killing myself."
"I'm very sorry." ??
How hubris you are!
Hey, Nishimiya!
You are totally a blight!
A bullshit like you, thinking everything--
from a single selfish point of view--
is the most annoying!
Ouch!
Who are you!
Oh, you must be Nishimiya's mother...
If you cannot bring up your child,
you shouldn't have had her in the first place!
What are you doing?!
Stop it.
Stop it!
Why?
What are you doing!
...Are you Shoko-san?
zorry.
I...I'b zorry.
I'b zorry.
I'b zorry!
What are you doing?
I thought seeing these photo--
would change sis's mind about wanting to die...
What should I have done?
Crap, it can't be opened.
She's holding it shut!
Oh, Nishimiya-san?
How about going to the lobby? I'll buy you a drink.
(Hospital rooms #400-417)
I heard things between you and Ya-sho in the past.
"I destroyed what Ishida-kun created working so hard."
Do you mean what happened at the bridge?
Actually, Ya-sho accepted a trivial guy like me.
I learned what real friends are at that moment--
for the first time.
As Ya-sho is my best friend,
I'm totally at a loss until he wakes up again.
"I want to fix up what I destroyed."
It's silly you tried to kill yourself even if you were hurt!
You're speaking too loud, Kawai-san...
Nishimiya-san can't hear unless we speak loudly!
Everyone worried about you!
We would have hard times as far as we live.
Not only you, everyone would, you know?
So,
we have to go forward, loving ourselves,
as a whole including weaknesses.
I'm relieved to know you are okay now.
I see.
You're visiting around to meet members at the bridge.
You're strong...
Honestly, I'm scared.
Even after Ishida-kun wakes up,
I would have no courage to see him again.
I couldn't change myself.
I ran away again and failed to save you again.
I'm still a coward.
Yu vill chanje vrom now on,
Saara-zan...
Thanks to come to meet me, Sho-chan.
Hey, stop it!
Nishimiya.
I found you.
Are you doing well?
Somewhat--
strange, isn't it? (laugh)
I am--
thinking I'd die.
Oh.
Tuesday is almost over.
Bye.
Nishimiya.
Nishimiya!
What's this?
Hey mom!
This...
Get rid of this!
Nishimiya.
Yo!
Well..
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'm glad to know--
you are okay.
Nishimiya.
I'm okay now too.
...More or less.
Please stop making such a serious face.
And, let me say...
Nishimiya-san.
I'm sorry.
I never really apologized for what I had done in the past.
In addition, for what I did after we met again.
For so many things I did..
Perhaps,
I interpreted you--
to suit my interest.
Actually, I wanted to--
talk more--
with you.
Perhaps that's all.
But my selfish behavior hurt you,
and forced you to choose the worst choice...
No, That'z nod corregd.
Begauze I had nod chenged,
juu fell.
I ab
todally blamed.
I thoughd everizing vould go vell
If I wend away..
I'b zorry...
Please don't cry, Nishimiya.
Well, Nishimiya.
Just now,
I talked to you in my dreams.
In the dream,
I tried to give up many things in my life.
But I realized it was not correct.
I'd been obsessed with the same thought as you,
but,
I realized,
that it still wasn't worth to death.
I wanna apologize to everyone, too.
So, Nishimiya.
I want...
I want you to--
help me--
live.
Nishimiya.
SL: Friends
Oops!
What a creepy thing I just did!
Oh my gosh!
Sorry, and forget all, Nishimiya!
Forget what I did now!
SL: It's promise.
Hey, customer! We're arrived!
Hey, Maria, are you watering flowers?
You are great!
You die? die? dieeeeeee?
Maria, Sho-chan has brought back to life.
I'm not dead, Maria.
Is she Ueno-san?
She had taken care of you when you were unconscious.
Say thanks to her.
I heard you took care of me.
I'm really a no-good one...
I still, or even more,
unable to like Nishimiya-san.
Huh, it may be okay not to force me liking her...
By the way, it was Shimada and the guys--
who saved you when you fell into the river.
They asked me not to tell it to you, but I wanna you to know.
Ishida.
Welcome back!
Then I'll go home.
Thank you.
Oh, it's too short, isn't it!?
No, no, you will be the cutest in such short hair!
Hi, welcome back, Sho-chan.
H...hello.
H--hi, welcome to the salon...
Ishida-kun.
I'm sorry for what happened around.
No, I'm sorry too.
That's right. My son is immortal.
Hi mom, I'll go to pick Maria up.
What!? Who is that guy?
My daughter's husband. He came back from Brazil.
Sho-chan, Yuzu-chan is in your room.
Take some desserts from the refrigerator for her.
Hey.
Hi.
Is that your winter-season uniform? That's fit to you.
By the way, take a look on this.
Oh, my. Great!
And. take another look on this.
Oh, my...great...
Have mercy, kind sir!
You must help me study!
Sure. Of course I will.
You have resumed to go to school, haven't you?
Yes. Shoko gave me a trigger to resume.
Well, I'll do my best.
I wanna meet her expectations.
By the way, a school festival will be held tomorrow?
Yes.
"From: Shoko Nishimiya, Title: Hello"
"It was said everyone's going to the school festival tomorrow."
"I'll meet you at the front gate at 10:00, okay?"
Good morning, everyone!
How have you all been?
I'm sorry for what I said at the bridge!
It's time to go!
I'm going to school!
Bye! Cheer up!
Oh!
These items are used like that!
What?
Nothing. I'll go.
Good luck!
Good morning.
SL: Good morning.
Why don't we get going?
"Welcome to the 45th Tochi High School Festival"
Hey, isn't that Ishida?
Who is he?
Huh? The jumping-into guy?
SL: What's wrong with you?
Honestly, it's the first time I tell you,
I don't really fit in at school.
SL: Why?
I have difficulty at looking everyone in the eyes.
So it is easier for me to look downward.
Huh? It's okay to look downward?
Ni...Nishimiya...
I can walk normally by myself, you know.
Thank you, Nishimiya.
Here is my class.
Is the water boiled?
Not yet, wait a moment.
Ishida-kun? Hey, it's Ishida-kun!
Are you okay now?
Nishimiya...
I'm feeling like a kind of stomachache.
Sorry.
Ya-sho!
Ya-sho?
Nagatsuka--kun?
Ya-sho, are you suffering stomachache?
Ya-sho.
Hi, Nagatsuka-kun. Good morning. How have you been?
Why are you looking downward?
Oh, really? I don't know why.
Actually I went here to raise my face to meet everyone.
But I might be a bit scared...
Hey, Ya-sho...?
Ishida-kun!!
I'm really happy you come back.
If you...
If you hadn't waken up again,
I would have lost everything.
Ya-sho,
Don't be mind any more--
what happened at the bridge.
Such minor troubles will happen again and again as far as we live.
So, Ya-sho, please,
please never go far away leaving me!
Pleeeease!
Nagatsuka-kun...
I'm very sorry--
for so many things.
And,
thank you.
Ya-sho!
By the way, what's happened with your mustache?
This was a pray icon for your recovery.
Nagatsuka-kun...
Why does everyone come...
We heard Nagatsuka-kun was calling Ishida-kun's name.
I see.
Kawai-san, you have the you-know-what to give him,
don't you?
Huh...yes, I have.
But it was a failure, so we cannot give him it...
Why not? Let's give it to him.
Okay...
This is for you...
I really worked hard to collect full thousand of cranes,
but I couldn't. It is far less than that...
I asked all the classmates again and again, but...
I'm very sorry.
N--No, it's amazing!
It's enough.
I've never gotten anything like that before,
so I am really happy.
Thank you Kawai-san.
And, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too, Mashiba-kun.
Not at all. You are amazing.
Ugh!
You are playing friends, that's make me sick!
You are so nasty as always saying such things, Nao-chan!
Huh? Kawai-tchi?
Time to fight?
Hey, stop it, both of two!
Oh...Ishida-kun.
I'm sorry, Ishida-kun.
You have been through so much,
while I have not changed a bit.
Don't say so.
I'm sorry, too...
Hey, we don't talk nothing so negative or serious now!.
SL: I'm sorry.
You said sorry again!
But, I suppose that is your personality.
Stu--pit! (Ha / ka)
Stu--pid. (Ba / ka)
Stupid! (Baka!)
Hey, I'm now hungry.
I'll go out to eat fried chickens!
Oh, she ran away.
No, she got embarrassed.
Hi, everyone,
I have a favor to ask you all.
Is it okay?
I want to go around the school festival together.
Hmmm, it tastes really good!
Let's go to the gym next!
I'm amazed he can even show his face at school.
Hey, hey, the stall by class #B is really good!
Let's go together!
"Fell in love"
Ah...I fell in love...
Well, please raise your face
Then you can see I am here, in front of you
So stop crying any more
You gave me a special time even when my heart had been broken
A red which was a bit tangled
A white which was a color of corridor in these days
The beginning, the last time, and now
I'll convey you carving on petals which are fluttering
Darling,
I and you are reflected on raindrops
No one in the world knows
Ah...I fell in love... I don't remember since when
How many times I cried
If I count it, it will take whole night
I'll be puzzled...
Darling,
What I want to convey to you now
has been same and not changed
since the past time.
Darling,
The only one signpost
we can walk without losing the way