It was 1947,
two years after the war...
when I began my journey
to what my father called...
the "Sodom" of the north:
New York.
Call me Stingo, which was the
nickname I was know by those days.
If I was called anything at all.
I've barely saved enough
money to write my novel...
for I wanted to be and hoped
or dreamed to be a writer.
But my spirit had remained locked...
unacquainted with love
and a stranger to death.
Even back then cheap apartments
were hard to find in Manhattan.
And so began my voyage of discovery...
in a place as strange as Brooklyn.
I know...
You're thinking about the pink.
Everybody does.
See, my late husband Saul,
he's got his bargain.
Hundreds and hundreds of gallons
of this... navy surplus paint.
See, I guess they didn't have
any use for pink on those boats.
Ok, I'll take it.
Walt Whitman.
"Yetta has heralded the arrival in the
Ethnic Kingdom of the pink palace...
of a young novelist from the south.
Your neighbors invite you upstairs
to dine with us in Sophie's room...
directly above yours tonight at eight.
The book is a token of welcome...
from one of Brooklyn's earliest
bards to Brooklyn's newest.
Sophie and Nathan".
- Whore!
- Don't go! Don't go!
Nathan, wait!
Wait! Believe me, Nathan!
I told you to get go away!
Stay away from my work!
Nathan, no!
- I'm not lying, you know!
- You're Lying.
- I'm not!
please, don't go!
Don't go away from me, please!
You know we need each other!
We need each other!
Me, need you?
Let me tell you something!
I need you like a goddamn
disease I can't name!
I need you like a case
of Anthrax, hear me?
Like "triquonosys"!
I need you like a biliary calculus,
palegra, encephalitis...
"Bright's" disease,
for Christ's sake!
"parsinoma" of the brain!
I need you... like death!
- Hear me? Like death!
- No, Nathan!
Go back to Krakow, baby.
Back to Krakow!
Well, good evening
Did you have a good time?
Did you enjoy our little show?
Do you get off on a little bit
of eve's dropping?
My door was open. I just
wondered what was going on.
Your door was open?
You wondered what was going on?
Well, shut my mouth if it isn't our
new literate figure from the South.
Too bad I won't be around for
a little lively conversation.
We would've had great time
shooting this shit.
We could've talked about sports...
Southern sports like...
lynching niggers, or coons
I think you all call them there.
So long cracker.
See you in another life.
Are you OK?
Yes.
Yeah.
I'm very sorry.
That's not the way he...
he really is, you know?
Don't apologize, all right?
I live downstairs here.
If there's anything you want...
Thank you.
You're very kind.
- Come on downstairs here.
- No, I'm all right.
I'm Stingo.
please... forgive us.
Yeah?
We had invited you to dinner.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Listen, I'm very often
working and I type at night.
But if it's going to bother you,
I don't want to...
Oh, no! When I was
little girl my father...
type and I go to sleep
to that sound.
It'll make me fell...
How do you say that?
Secure. Secured.
- Your father was a writer?
- You know, my father was...
my father was professor of law.
He wrote articles...
warning college people
of the Nazi threat...
and trying to get help for those
Jews that "was" persecuted. So...
Yeah, that sound of typing
will make me think of my father...
and of his goodness.
You wouldn't want to
come in, would you?
Maybe some other time.
So, if you forgive me...
Good night.
So, "Stinko", yeah?
- "Stingo".
- "Stingo", yes!
I never hear that name.
There's no "K" in there, though.
- I got it.
- It's a "G".
Yeah, it's nice!
It's a friendly...
you know, happy sound.
I like it.
Nathan!
Oh, Nathan!
Oh, God!
Why can't you see, Sophie?
We are dying.
Rise and shine, honey child.
Lift up your bones.
The grit is on the brittle,
the corn is on the pone.
Hurry up.
You're going to have a picnic
out and down by the seashore.
- Good morning, Stingo.
- Good morning.
We wanted to make friends...
and to take you out on
this beautiful summer day!
We want you to come up and
to have breakfast with us.
- And then...
- Yes.
- Coney Island.
- Coney Island! Oh, boy!
Sorry about last night.
I know what you're thinking:
"These people are strange".
On Sundays we like to dress up
a bit differently and go out.
- OK.
- OK?
I knew you'd understand!
You see, everybody out
there dresses the same.
Look at those poor, pathetic
people out there. Look at them.
Drones. All walking down the
streets looking alike, wearing...
the same dread, boring uniform.
You're boring!
"Good morning"!
Look at this God's gift!
Give me a kiss.
- One kiss.
- All right, one kiss.
- That's all you deserve.
- One more.
- I need one more.
- No.
- I have to have one more.
- Nathan!
Look where my hands have to go.
This is...
No, Nathan Landau!
What do you think of that, Stingo?
Here I am, a nice Jewish boy...
pushing thirty...
I fall crazy in love
with a polish Shiksa.
What is that?
What is a Shiksa?
A Shiksa? Is a "goee" girl.
A lady of a gentile persuasion.
She's a...
All right. I'd just assumed
that she was not...
- Jewish, Jewish?
- Yeah.
Jewish?
No, no, no...
Sophie is Catholic.
That's OK. But I'm
not anymore Catholic, so...
Catholic issue.
When I first met this one here...
she was a rag and bone
and hank of hair.
That was 1 year and a half after the
Russians liberated the camp she was in.
Yeah, it looked like
something that...
scares the birds.
You know, what is that?
Scare... scarecrow.
- I had "scurbut".
- No, no, no!
She means scurvy.
And typhus, anemia, fever...
It was a miracle she's
emerged from that camp alive.
Right! I mean...
He thought that I had leukemia.
I thought I was dying.
But it was Nathan that see
that it was only anemia.
- Are you a doctor?
- No, no.
That's my brother's domain.
- But I'm a biologist.
- Yeah!
I graduated in Science from Harvard.
And he made MA...
in Developmental
and Cellular Biology.
- I do research now.
- He works at Pfizer.
A big pharmaceutical
house in Brooklyn.
Anyway, I took her to
this friend of my brother's...
a doctor who teaches
at Columbia Presbyterian.
- Yeah.
- He confirmed my diagnosis.
And we put the little sweetie here...
on a massive doses
of ferrous sulphate...
and she'd bloomed like a rose.
A rose.
A rose...
A beautiful fucking rose.
You're something!
Thank you for making me
"to" bloom like a rose.
Not "to" bloom, just "bloom".
She's so good.
It's about time she was perfect.
So what? I mean, this is
a ridiculous language!
There's too many words!
The word for "velocity":
OK, there's "fast", "quick"...
"rapid" and they all
mean the same thing.
- "Swift", "Speedy"...
- "Hasty".
- "Flit".
- "Brisk".
- "Expeditious".
- "Accelerated".
"Winged".
No, no! Stop it!
It's ridiculous!
Oh, in French it's so easy.
You say: "vit".
Or in polish, "szybko"
and in Russian, "bistroy"
It's only in English
that it's so complicated!
How many languages do you know?
Well, my father was a Linguistic,
so I mean, I...
He taught me German, French,
Russian, Hungarian...
the Slavic Languages...
So, what language
I'm butchering now?
English!
I bet your father was
a very interesting man.
Yeah, my father was...
a civilized man.
- That's the word, yeah? "Civilized"?
- Very good word.
Yeah? My father was a civilized man
living in a non civilized time.
The civilized,
they "was" the first to die.
Do you play the piano?
No. I used to play, but I...
I no longer play.
I don't, anymore...
My mother was a beautiful pianist.
Nathan surprised me with
that piano on my birthday!
I love that piece.
When I was a little girl, I...
I remember, I'd lay in bed...
and I'd hear my mother
downstairs playing the piano...
and the sound of my
father's typewriter.
I think no child had a more
wonderful father and mother.
And a more beautiful life.
Do you know that song, right?
Stingo, hit it!
Suddenly, I shivered violently.
I remembered Nathan's voice
that night before.
"Dont you see, Sophie?
We 're dying".
I longed desperately to escape...
to pack my bags and flee.
But I did not.
I stayed at Yetta Zimmerman's...
and I helped fulfill Sophie's
prophecy about the three of us.
We became the best of friends.
Here's an example of how
emotionally evocative English can be
Sophie loved to tell
how Nathan saved her life.
Their meeting was, for her...
a miracle.
Because I could not stop for
death, he kindly stopped for me.
The carriage held but just
our selves and Immortality.
Rhymes, rhymes... It's not hard
enough to understand the language?
Just everyday life talk.
He has to read us rhymes!
...what the beauty of
the language can be...
when written by artists.
I look forward to seeing you
next week. And remember...
You must not get discouraged.
You'll see.
One morning you'll wake up and find
you've been dreaming in English!
Excuse me. Who did he
say wrote that poem?
Dickens.
- Emile Dickens.
- Thank you.
Are you all right, Miss Zawistowska?
Yes.
Thank you, I'm very fine.
I'm a little tired.
I noticed that you've been looking...
Well... a little delicate lately.
- I hope I'm not being too personal.
- No! No, I...
Could you help me with that?
Thank you.
Thank you for your...
concern.
Good bye.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you tell me what...
Where would be that listing
in catalog file...
for...
19th century American poet...
- Emile Dickens, please?
- In the catalog room on the left.
But you wont find any such listing.
I wont find that listing?
Why won't I... find it?
Charles Dickens is
an English writer.
There's no American poet
by the name of Dickens.
I'm sorry. No, that is,
I'm sure, American poet.
- Emile Dickens.
- Listen!
- "D-I...
- I told you!
There's no such person. Do you
want me to draw you a picture?
- I'm telling you, you hear me?
- All right.
It's all right, it's all right...
Just lie still.
Let the doctor take
care of everything.
You're so beautiful.
Yes! How did you get
to be so beautiful?
I think...
I think that I'm going to die.
No, no, no...
No, your pulse...
Your pulse is fine.
It's steady.
You're going to live to be a hundred.
Why I am so tired?
The doctor thinks you
need to get some color...
in that beautiful
white skin of yours.
I'm going to take you
to see my brother.
He is the best doctor going.
- No, let you...
- You thought I was a doctor?
No, I'm a biologist.
- You've been eating properly lately?
- Yes! Oh, yes! I am...
I am six months in
here, in U.S. and...
so I eat "more good"
now than in my life.
You could've fallen behind with iron
and never had a chance to catch up.
Look, I'm going to go now.
But may I come back later?
Don't answer that. I'll be back.
OK?
Yeah, OK!
- How long you have been there?
- Enough to get dinner started.
You look much better.
What did you do here?
It looks beautiful.
We're having calf's liver...
prepared "Veneziano" and
special vinaigrette sauce...
loaded with iron.
And leeks... filled with iron.
Also will improve the
timber of your voice.
You know, Nero had
leek served every day...
- to deepen his voice.
- I didn't know that.
So that he could croon while he
had Seneca drown and squirted.
- Let me help you with that.
- No! You're not to move.
The "madame" taste the wine?
"Chateaux Margoux de...
1937"?
My God!
Special day...
special wine.
You know, when you...
When you live a good life...
like a saint and then you die...
that must be what they make
you "to" drink in paradise.
Thomas Wolfe!
It's written in polish!
Oh God! What does Wolfe
sound like in polish?
a stone, a leaf, an unfound door.
Of a stone...
- The door.
- Of all the forgotten faces.
- Forgotten faces.
God! This is a first...
hearing Thomas Wolfe
read aloud in polish.
The first for me too, hearing
Wolfe read in English.
If that poor bastard have heard
you read this aloud in polish...
- he would've written in polish.
- I don't think so.
Oh, yeah! Oh, yes!
You were... You were in
that concentration camp?
Yeah, I can't...
- I can't talk about that, though.
- I'm sorry.
I have a neck to stick my big
nose where it's got no business.
I...
want so much to know you.
To be close to you.
Emily Dickenson?
That's the woman?
Oh, no!
"property of Nathan Landau".
- That's you?
- That's me.
- It's your book?
- No, it's yours.
Thank you!
Thank you.
"Ample make this bed.
Make this bed with awe;
In it wait till judgment break...
excellent and fair.
Be its mattress straight.
Be its pillow round;
Let no sunrise yellow noise...
interrupt this ground".
Nathan, my new and
dear beloved friend...
introduced me to what seemed
the answer to my relentless...
all consuming "hornyness".
Before I went into analysis,
I was completely frigid.
Can you imagine? Now all I
can do is think about fucking.
Wilhelm Reich has turned
me into a nympho.
I mean, sex on the brain!
Her name still crawls
across my tongue.
Lesley Lapidus.
The door is open, came in!
Hello!
- Boy, look excellent.
- Thanks.
- What would like to drink?
- I'll have a...
I don't know, let's see...
- I'd like a red wine.
- Oh, my God!
Fuck!
Fucking fantastic fucking!
Wait! Just let it ring!
Hello, mother.
Fine, fine. I told
you I'd be just fine.
Yeah, plenty. And I'll make sure
that the plants are watered...
and that the dog is fed.
Well, mother...
Yes, Daddy. Your little
princess will be good.
OK. Bye!
They'll go away for the weekend
and the maid is out sick.
And they care about how I will
survive for a weekend in this...
apartment by myself. So they stocked
the fridge, put a lock on every door...
and who knows what else!
Thus I realized that Lesley and I
would be left to frolic here alone.
My cup ran over.
Oh, my cup turned into a spillway
flooding across the spotless carpet...
out the door down
Pierrepot Street...
across all the twilit
carnal reaches of Brooklyn.
Lesley. A weekend
alone with Lesley.
Have you ever read D.H. Lawrence,
"Lady Chatterley's Lover"?
No.
He has the answer.
He knows so much about fucking.
He says...
He says that when you fuck
you go to the Dark Gods.
Stingo, I really mean it.
To fuck is to go to the Dark Gods.
Let's go to the Dark Gods!
What is going on?
You don't understand...
I can't go all the way.
I've reached a plateau
in my analysis.
Before I reach this plateau of
vocalization I could never say...
any of those words.
those Anglo-Saxon four letter words
that everybody should be able to say
Now I'm completely able to vocalize.
Lesley Lapidus could say "fuck"
but she could not do it.
Nathan!? I'm so glad you're...
Yep, little Stingo.
- Stingo?
- Yeah?
You want to come up and
have a night cup with me?
Sure.
When Nathan gets involved
he forgets all about the time...
Stingo, you look... very nice.
You're wearing your "cock sucker".
My seersucker.
Oh yeah.
Right, "seersucker".
I love it here.
I'm glad you couldn't sleep.
You hurt your mouth?
You talk funny.
I bit my tongue.
- You want me to get you something?
- No, please, no.
It just needs to be left alone.
You changed all
the furniture around?
Yeah, you like it? I do that
when I can't sleep, you know?
It's good, because
then you don't have...
You don't have to
think about anything.
- Well, then I'll try that.
- Oh, no.
Stingo... You do not
have to move furniture.
- You will move mountains.
- I can't even move my tongue.
Maybe you moved it too much.
Why aren't all the women
in the world like you?
You'd better thank God they're not.
I see many women in your life.
Many beautiful women...
who adore you and that make
all that love with you.
Sometimes...
I can see myself just
being alone forever.
Oh, Stingo...
I'm not fair with you.
I think Stingo is so young,
he is a talented American.
He doesn't have any real,
real problems, but...
You don't know if I'm talented.
You've never read
anything I've written.
I don't ask about your work...
and what it is about because
I know a writer likes to...
be quite about his work.
It's about a boy...
a twelve-year-old boy...
- And...
- So it's autobiographical?
To a certain extant, maybe it is.
It takes places in a year,
which is the year his mother dies...
I didn't know your mother died.
- When I was 12.
- You loved her very much?
Not enough.
- What do you mean, "Not enough"?
- I mean: "Not enough".
And that's what is
so terrible about...
outliving those people
that we love, I mean that...
- that quilt.
- Your father?
My father, my mother, my husband.
You were married?
Yeah, I was married.
And I was very young.
I was married to a...
disciple of my father.
Assistant at the University.
Your father was writing
Nazi articles?
That probably got him into trouble.
One day I was at the Mass and...
they have a...
I had a...
"presentiment" and I...
have money for you and I...
I run out of the church and
I go to the University...
and I see that the
gate is locked and...
there were many Germans there...
and I saw the professors. They
"was" loading them into the truck...
and this one part of canvas
has moved away...
and I see my father's face and
the face of my husband behind him.
And...
I looked and the...
But the Germans
pulled that away and...
I never saw those faces again.
They took them to Sachsenhausen,
but they shot them the next day.
- And your mother?
- My mother...
My mother got...
t- t-tuberculosis.
Tuberculosis and...
She is very sick, you know?
She's dying. I can't do anything.
But I think if I could get
that meet for my mother...
I would make her strong, so
I go to the country and...
the peasants,
they're selling... ham.
And I go with that black market
money and I buy that and...
I bring it back. But it's forbidden
for all the meet goes to the Germans
If you get caught...
So I hid the ham under
my skirt on the train.
I'm pretending that I'm
pregnant, you know?
I was so afraid!
I was shaking.
And then that German...
who was in the front of
the train and he saw me.
And I'm sitting there
and he "come" up to me...
and he "take" under
my skirt that ham and...
So they sent me to Auschwitz.
You were sent to Auschwitz
because you stole a ham?
No. I was sent to Auschwitz
because they saw that I was afraid.
- You know what that means.
- Yeah.
You tried to commit
suicide in Auschwitz.
No, it was after that.
After that, I was in...
- After liberation.
- After you were safe?
Yes, safe, yeah.
I was safe, I was in Sweden.
I was in that refugee camp.
I mean, that was good.
They try to help you, you know?
They try... but...
I knew that...
Christ had turned his
face away from me...
and that only a Jesus who
no longer cared for me could...
kill those people
that I love, but...
leave me alive...
with my shame? Oh, God.
So I went to that church...
and I took the glass
I knew was there and I...
I've cut my wrist.
But I didn't die, of course!
Of course, not.
Stingo...
there's so many things
you don't understand.
There's so many things
that I can't...
that I cannot... tell you.
I want you to trust me.
Just trust me.
Oh, God! There's Nathan!
Nathan!
- Sophie!
- Astrid?
I'm working night duty at
Brooklyn Hospital this week.
My patient is this old lady
who's meaner than my mother!
Well, good night, Astrid.
I'll go to sleep.
That was Astrid, you know.
Maybe I'll leave the door open in
case he comes, we could hear him.
So you want another drink?
- Your bottle is empty.
- Well...
I know where Nathan
keeps another bottle.
Be careful, it's dark in here.
Oh, God.
You'll feel better if we
just call him at the lab.
I can't do that. He doesn't
like for me to call him.
You know, at work.
So, anyway...
I did it an hour ago!
And there was no answer, so...
I'm sure the switchboard
just shot off.
Yes, I think that's right.
I'm sure of that. You know,
sometimes when he can't sleep...
he goes and walks
all over the city.
He goes into all
these neighborhoods...
I don't know where he goes, but...
Once he came back, he had a...
black eye and his jaw
was all swollen there.
I thought it was broken!
You know, he could be hurt.
I don't know where he is, but I
think we should call the police.
- Right now.
- I think we'd better wait 2 hours.
Wait till someone is
on the switchboard there.
We'll just call him then.
His working lady probably got
tired and fell asleep there.
Yeah. She's probably asleep there.
- I'm sure.
- I'm sure you're right.
Look at this. Nazi primer.
He must have everything written
about the Nazis in those news.
He is obsessed with the Nazis
who are escaping justice.
Do you suppose all this
started after he met you?
Look, I know I shouldn't tell
him about that place, but...
what could I do? I know
it's not my fault that he...
I can understand.
After all, he is a Jew.
Yes, but don't you think
that I'm angry too?
That these men, these terrible
Nazi leaving my father...
Such a good man who tries
to help Jews is killed!
Don't you think that I am angry?
But you don't understand Nathan.
You don't know...
...him.
What he might do, you know?
- Sometimes I think...
- What do you think?
- What do you think, polish baby?
- Oh, Nathan!
- You're all right?
- I am. What about the two of you?
I was so frightened, you know?
I was stupid!
I got so scared that something
had happened to you.
I would've called
but I didn't want to wake you.
We're on to something in our work.
Something big. Very big.
That's wonderful, Nathan.
Yeah, wonderful.
But you were here...
with Sophie.
Stingo, you know, he...
Stingo came home from his date!
So I heard the door
and thought it was you.
So I run out, but...
Anyway, I called him and said
why don't you come up for a drink?
Because I was worried and
he was a very good friend...
and he was keeping me company.
So now you've seen my
"sanctum sanctorum".
Now you know all of Nathan's
darkened hours secrets.
Hardly.
You wipe out six million Jews...
and the world left them escape.
Enjoying our Lynching
party southern boy?
I expect you might have
a lot to teach me there.
I'm going to call it tonight.
Stingo, wait. Stingo is our
best friend, why do you do that?
He is our best friend, he deserves
only our thanks. Listen to me.
I was frightened,
I didn't know what to do here.
It's true.
Forgive me old buddy. I'm sorry.
Of course my beloved Sophie is right
I must've got crazy
with the work, you know?
- We're on to something big.
- I know, darling.
I'm just another mad scientist.
I'm leaving.
Tomorrow.
Thank you.
- Thanks for taking care of Sophie.
- All right.
- Ah, Nathan!
- I'm sorry.
I said I'm sorry already!
Darling, I'm home.
- Right!
- Are you all right?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Don't you catch things in the South?
- How's it going?
- Fine. What's going on?
Think fast!
You came and wreck everything.
Yetta, you know,
always provides the best...
the best you can find in Brooklyn!
Oh, shit!
Sophie should be taking
a nap after work.
She just doesn't sleep anymore.
Not since the war. How's it going?
- Fine. Thank you.
- Let me take a look at those.
.- No.
- Come on!
I won't interfere, I won't make
any comments, I won't even...
Look, I'll show this to no one!
No one is seeing this.
I'm not no one. I'm a friend.
Don't you have those down South?
"Friend", a person attached to
another by feeling and affection.
- A supporter.
- I vowed to my self when I started..
this I was not going to show it
to anyone 'till I finish it.
- Then I'd go for that comfort person.
- Well...
OK. Youre just terrified
that somebody don't like it.
Terrified as in filled with terror.
As sharp over mastering intense fear
All right, all right!
- That will give you some idea.
- Oh, my God!
- What about the page in the typewriter?
- No, this is a...
Nathan! Stop!
All right.
Stingo! What is the
worst that can happen?
I may discover you can't write!
- Bye! Shit! Fuck!
- Nathan, get back here!
I'll give it back, old buddy!
Fine, right!
Stingo, wait a minute!
Wait! Nathan has ordered me
to take you to the movies.
He made me your guardian
while to read that.
Yes, so you can't do no
violence to yourself now.
- Nathan must have finished that.
- Yeah.
- Come on, let's go see.
- I think I'll wait here alone.
- No, come on!
- If he's got something to say...
- let him come down and tell me.
- Don't be silly.
Bravo!
On this bridge on which...
so many great Americans writers
stood and reached out for words...
to give America its voice...
looking toward the land
that gave them Whitman...
from its Eastern edge dreamt his
country's future and gave it words...
on this span of which...
Thomas Wolfe
and Hart Crane wrote...
we welcome Stingo
into that pantheon of the Gods...
whose words are
all we know of immortality.
To Stingo!
How could I've failed to have
the most helpless crush on such...
a generous mind
and life enlarging mentor?
Nathan was utterly,
fatally glamorous.
Sophie!
Where are you?
- Stingo!
- Nathan!
- We did it!
- What? What did you do?
Nathan!
Remember I told you we were on to
something big? Today we cracked it.
What? What, what?
I can't tell you.
You'll hear about it all tonight.
- No, what's a few hours make?
- No, I can't tell you!
pretty soon the whole world
will know...
one of the greatest medical
advances of all time.
I can't tell you!
I'm talking about Stockholm.
Next year, the three of us together.
I'm talking to go
nobel-fucking-prize!
- All right!
- Sorry, kid. I'm going to get there first!
Wait! I got something
for you to celebrate!
Oh, Nathan! What's that?
- One for you.
- What is it?
- These go with that one.
- Oh, God!
- Oh, Nathan! What a beautiful dress!
- Do you like it?
Try it on. put it on.
Come on, try it on!
- Oh, Nathan!
- Come on!
Try it on.
please, I want to see it.
- I'm not going to do that.
- I just want to see it on you!
Hold it up.
- It doesn't have a top.
- You're the top.
Nathan, it's beautiful!
- I've to get back to the laboratory.
- Why don't you stay with us?
- Tonight we'll celebrate.
- Look at all this.
I can't.
I got to get back to work.
Tonight we'll celebrate.
Make sure Sophie gets back home safe.
- Wear those clothes tonight.
- Look at these shoes!
Tonight.
Tonight Ill look at it.
Oh, my darling.
I'm so proud of you.
Tonight!
You were the one who gave
me the idea to get it.
- I think it's like mine.
- It's a beautiful watch, yes?
Dr. Kats, my boss, and his wife...
Her family is in the jewellery
business, so he took me there...
- to get it engraved.
- It opens at the top, like mine.
What? Don't get you fingers...
- You got your fingerprints all over it.
- Nathan won't know.
- Anyway, do you think he will like it?
- Sure, he will.
I think he'll be very pleased.
It... you know, it cost...
a great deal of money.
More than I could afford.
Anyway, who cares?
Today, money doesn't
seem very important.
Get the champagne!