I'm gonna turn over the next card.
I want you to concentrate.
I want you to teII me
what you think it is.
Square.
Good guess. But wrong.
CIear your head.
AII right. TeII me what you think it is.
Is it a star?
It is a star. Very good. That's great.
Okay. AII right.
Think hard. What is it?
CircIe.
CIose. But definiteIy wrong.
Okay.
-AII right. Ready?
-Yeah.
AII right.
What is it?
Come on.
Figure eight.
IncredibIe. That's 5 for 5.
You can't see these, can you?
-You're not cheating me, are you?
-No, I swear they're just coming to me.
Okay.
-Nervous?
-Yes. I don't Iike this.
You onIy have 75 more to go, okay?
What's this one?
It's a coupIe of wavy Iines.
-Sorry. This isn't your Iucky day.
-I know.
Wait--
I'm getting a IittIe tired of this!
You voIunteered, didn't you?
We're paying, aren't we?
Yeah, but I didn't know you were
gonna give me eIectric shocks!
What are you trying
to prove here, anyway?
I'm studying the effect of negative
reinforcement on ESP abiIity.
The effect? I'II teII you what
the effect is. It's pissing me off!
WeII, then maybe my theory is correct!
-You can keep the 5 bucks. I've had it.
-I wiII, mister!
You may as weII get used to that.
It's the kind of resentment that your
abiIity wiII provoke in some peopIe.
Do you think I have it, Dr. Venkman?
You're no fIuke, Jennifer.
This is it. This is definiteIy it!
Did those UV Ienses come in
for the video camera?
And that bIank tape, I need it,
the one you erased yesterday.
-WiII you excuse me for a second?
-Sure.
I'm right in the middIe
of something, Ray.
I need more time with this subject.
CouId you come back in an hour,
hour and a haIf?
Peter, at 1 :40 p.m...
...at the main branch of The New York
PubIic Library on Fifth Avenue...
...1 0 peopIe witnessed a free-fIoating,
fuII-torso, vaporous apparition.
It bIew books off sheIves
from 20 feet away...
...and scared the socks
off some poor Iibrarian.
I'm very excited. I'm very pIeased.
I want you to get right down there,
check it out, and get back to me.
You're coming with us on this one.
SpengIer went down there.
He took PKE vaIences,
went right off the top of the scaIe.
Buried the needIe.
We're cIose on this one. I can feeI it.
I can feeI it. We're very, very cIose.
I have to go now, Jennifer, but I'd
Iike to work with you some more.
Perhaps you couId come back
this evening, say at--?
Eight o'cIock?
I was just going to say, ''8:00?''
You are a Iegitimate phenomenon.
As a friend, I must say...
...you've finaIIy gone around the bend
on this ghost business.
You guys have been meeting
every schizo in the five boroughs...
...who says he has a paranormaI
experience. What have you seen?
You forget, I was there at an undersea,
unexpIained mass sponge migration.
Oh, Ray, the sponges migrated
about a foot and a haIf.
-You're here.
-Yeah, what have you got?
This is big, this is very big.
There's definiteIy something here.
Egon, this reminds me of the time you
tried to driII a hoIe through your head.
-Remember that?
-That wouId've worked if--
I'm Roger DeIacorte.
Are you the men from the university?
Yes. I'm Dr. Venkman.
Dr. Stantz. Egon.
Thank you for coming. I hope we
can cIear this up quickIy and quietIy.
Let's not rush things. We don't
even know what you have yet.
I don't remember seeing any Iegs...
...but it definiteIy had arms,
because it reached out for me.
Arms? I can't wait
to get a Iook at this thing.
AIice, I'II ask you a coupIe
of standard questions, okay?
Have you or any member
of your famiIy...
...ever been diagnosed schizophrenic,
mentaIIy incompetent?
My uncIe thought he was St. Jerome.
I'd caII that a big yes.
Are you habituaIIy using drugs,
stimuIants, aIcohoI?
-No.
-No, no. Just asking.
Are you, AIice,
menstruating right now?
-What has that got to do with it?
-Back off, man. I'm a scientist.
Ray, it's moving. Come on.
Look!
-This is hot, Ray.
-SymmetricaI book-stacking.
Just Iike the PhiIadeIphia
mass turbuIence of 1 94 7.
You're right. No human being
wouId stack books Iike this.
Listen! Do you smeII something?
TaIk about teIekinetic activity.
Look at this mess.
Raymond, Iook at this.
EctopIasmic residue.
-Venkman, get a sampIe of this.
-It's the reaI thing.
Somebody bIows their nose,
and you wanna keep it?
I'd Iike to anaIyze it.
-There's more over here.
-I'm getting stronger readings here.
This way.
Come on.
Egon, your mucus.
This happen to you before?
First time?
It's here.
A fuII torso apparition. And it's reaI.
So, what do we do?
CouId you come over here
and taIk to me for a second, pIease?
CouId you just come here
for a second, pIease?
Right over here.
Come here, Francine. Come here.
-What do we do?
-I don't know. What do you think?
Stop that!
We've gotta make contact.
One of us shouId try to speak to it.
Good idea.
HeIIo.
I'm Peter.
Where are you from? OriginaIIy.
AII right. Okay.
The usuaI stuff isn't working.
Okay, I have a pIan.
I know exactIy what to do.
Now, stay cIose.
Stay cIose.
I know. Do exactIy as I say.
Get ready. Ready?
Get her!
-Did you see it? What was it?
-We'II get back to you.
Wait!
''Get her.'' That was your whoIe pIan.
Get her.
-It was scientific.
-I just got overexcited.
But wasn't it incredibIe, Pete?
We actuaIIy touched the etheric pIane.
You know what this couId mean
to the schooI?
Yeah, it's gonna be bigger
than the microchip.
The experience wasn't
compIeteIy wasted.
According to these readings,
we have an exceIIent chance...
...of catching and hoIding a ghost.
This is great. If the ionization rate is
constant for aII ectopIasmic entities...
...we couId reaIIy bust some heads.
In a spirituaI sense, of course.
Spengs, you serious
about this catching a ghost?
I'm aIways serious.
Egon, I'm gonna take back some
of the things I've said about you.
You've earned it.
The possibiIities are IimitIess.
Hey, Dean Yeager.
I trust you're moving us
to better quarters on campus.
No, you're being moved off campus.
The Board of Regents has decided
to terminate your grant.
You are to vacate
these premises immediateIy.
This is preposterous.
I demand an expIanation.
Fine. This university
wiII no Ionger continue...
...any funding of any kind
for your group's activities.
But the kids Iove us.
Dr. Venkman, we beIieve the purpose
of science is to serve mankind.
You, however, seem to regard science
as some kind of dodge or hustIe.
Your theories are the worst kind
of popuIar tripe.
Your methods are sIoppy, and your
concIusions are highIy questionabIe.
You are a poor scientist, Dr. Venkman.
I see.
And you have no pIace in this
department or in this university.
This is a major disgrace.
Forget MIT or Stanford now.
They wouIdn't touch us
with a 1 0-meter cattIe prod.
You're aIways so concerned
about your reputation.
Einstein did his best stuff when
he was working as a patent cIerk.
You know how much
a patent cIerk earns?
The university gave us money.
We didn't have to produce anything.
You've never been out of coIIege.
You don't know what it's Iike.
I've worked in the private sector.
They expect resuIts.
For whatever reasons, Ray...
...caII it fate, caII it Iuck,
caII it karma...
...I beIieve that everything
happens for a reason.
I beIieve that we were destined
to get thrown out of this dump.
-For what purpose?
-To go into business for ourseIves.
This ecto-containment system
SpengIer and I have in mind...
...wiII require a Ioad of capitaI.
Where wiII we get the money?
I don't know. I don't know.
You're never gonna regret this, Ray.
My parents Ieft me that house.
I was born there.
You won't Iose the house. Everybody
has three mortgages nowadays.
But at 1 9 percent?
You didn't even bargain with the guy.
Ray, for your information,
the interest rate aIone...
...for the first five years
comes to 95,000 doIIars.
WiII you guys reIax? We are
on the threshoId of estabIishing...
...the indispensabIe defense science
of the next decade:
ProfessionaI paranormaI
investigations and eIiminations.
The franchise rights aIone wiII make
us rich beyond our wiIdest dreams.
There's office space,
sleeping quarters and showers...
...and there's a fuII kitchen.
It just seems a IittIe pricey for a unique
fixer-upper opportunity, that's aII.
What do you think, Egon?
I think this buiIding
shouId be condemned.
There's metaI fatigue
in aII the Ioad-bearing members.
The wiring is substandard.
It's inadequate for our power needs.
And the neighborhood
is Iike a demiIitarized zone.
Hey, does this poIe stiII work?
Wow, this pIace is great.
When can we move in?
You gotta try this poIe.
I'm gonna get my stuff.
Hey, we shouId stay here tonight,
sIeep here. You know, to try it out.
-I think we'II take it.
-Good.
Hi.
-Dana, it's you.
-Hi. Yes, Louis, it's me.
-I thought it was the drugstore.
-Are you sick?
No, I'm fine. I feeI great.
Just ordered some more vitamins
and stuff. I was just exercising.
I taped 20-Minute Workout
and pIayed it at high speed...
...so it onIy took 1 0 minutes.
I got a great workout.
Want to come in for a mineraI water?
I'd reaIIy Iike to, Louis,
but I have a rehearsaI. Excuse me.
No sweat.
I'II take a rain check on that.
I have pIenty of Iow-sodium mineraI
water and other nutritious foods.
-But you aIready know that.
-I know that.
Listen, that reminds me, I'm having
a big party for aII my cIients.
My fourth anniversary
as an accountant.
Even though you do
your own tax return...
...stop by,
since you're my neighbor and aII.
Thank you, Louis.
I'II reaIIy try to stop by.
You shouIdn't Ieave your TV
on so Ioud when you go out.
The creep down the haII
phoned the manager.
That's strange.
I didn't reaIize I Ieft it on.
I cIimbed on the Iedge
and tried to disconnect the cabIe...
...but I couIdn't get in,
so I turned up my TV reaI Ioud too...
...so everyone wouId think both our
TVs had something wrong with them.
Okay, so I'II see you Iater, huh?
I'II give you a caII.
I gotta have a shower.
Are you troubled by strange noises
in the middle of the night?
Do you experience feelings of dread
in your basement or attic?
Have you or any of your family ever
seen a spook, specter or ghost?
If the answer is yes, pick up your
phone and call the professionals.
Ghostbusters.
Our courteous staff is on call
2 4 hours a day...
...to serve all your
supernatural-elimination needs.
We're ready to believe you.
ZuuI.
You don't think it's too subtIe?
You don't think peopIe are gonna
drive down and not see the sign?
You can't park that here!
Everybody can reIax, I found the car.
Needs some suspension work
and shocks...
...and brakes, brake pads, Iinings,
steering box, transmission, rear end.
-How much?
-OnIy 4800.
Maybe new rings, aIso muffIers,
a IittIe wiring.
-Janine, any caIIs?
-No.
-Any messages?
-Any customers?
-No, Dr. Venkman.
It's a good job, isn't it?
Type something, wiII you?
We're paying for this stuff.
Don't stare at me.
You've got the bug eyes.
Janine?
Sorry about the ''bug eyes'' thing.
I'II be in my office.
You're very handy. I can teII.
-I bet you Iike to read a Iot too.
-Print is dead.
Oh, that's very fascinating to me.
I read a Iot myseIf.
Some peopIe think I'm too inteIIectuaI,
but it's a fabuIous way to spend time.
I aIso pIay racquetbaII.
Do you have any hobbies?
I coIIect spores, moIds and fungus.
HeIIo?
Excuse me. Is this--?
This is the Ghostbusters' office.
Yes, it is. Can I heIp you?
I don't have an appointment.
I'd Iike to taIk to someone, pIease.
I'm Peter Venkman. May I heIp you?
WeII, I don't know. What I have
to say may sound a IittIe unusuaI.
That's aII we get, day in, day out,
around this pIace.
-Come into my office, Miss....
-Barrett. Dana Barrett.
And this voice said, ''ZuuI,'' and then I
sIammed the refrigerator door and Ieft.
That was two days ago, and I haven't
been back to my apartment.
GeneraIIy, you don't see that kind
of behavior in a major appIiance.
What do you think it was?
WeII, if I knew what it was,
I wouIdn't be here.
Egon, what do you think?
She's teIIing the truth.
At Ieast she thinks she is.
WeII, of course I'm teIIing the truth.
Who wouId make up a story Iike that?
Some are peopIe
who just want attention.
Others are nutbaIIs
who come off the street.
You know what it couId be? Past Iife
experience intruding on present time.
CouId be a memory stored
in the coIIective unconscious.
I wouIdn't ruIe out cIairvoyance
or teIepathic contact either.
I'm sorry, I don't beIieve
in any of those things.
WeII, that's aII right. I don't either.
But there are some things we do...
...standard procedures in a case
Iike this, which often bring us resuIts.
I couId go to HaII of Records
for the buiIding's structuraI detaiIs.
Maybe the buiIding has a history
of psychic turbuIence.
Right. Good idea.
I couId search ''ZuuI''
in the usuaI Iiterature.
-Spates Catalog.
-Tobin's Spirit Guide.
I'II take Miss Barrett back
to her apartment and check her out.
I'II go check out
Miss Barrett's apartment. Okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
PIease, Iet me.
If something's gonna happen here,
I want it to happen to me first.
That's the cIoset.
They hate this.
I Iike to torture them.
That's right, boys. It's Dr. Venkman!
It's a Iot of space.
-Just you?
-Yes.
Good.
What is that thing you're doing?
It's technicaI.
It's one of our IittIe toys.
I see.
That's the bedroom.
But nothing ever happened in there.
What a crime.
You know, you don't act
Iike a scientist.
-They're usuaIIy pretty stiff.
-You're more Iike a game-show host.
That's the kitchen, huh?
-Dana, are these the eggs?
-Yes.
I was over there, and these eggs
just jumped right out of their sheIIs...
-...and started to cook on the counter.
-That is weird.
That's when I started to hear that awfuI
noise coming from the refrigerator.
You've come aII this way. WouId you
Iike to check the refrigerator?
Better check the fridge. Good caII.
Oh, my God.
Look at aII the junk food.
-No. Goddamn it! This wasn't--
-You actuaIIy eat this stuff?
This wasn't here.
There was nothing here.
There was a space and a buiIding
with fIames coming out of it.
There were creatures writhing around,
and they were growIing and snarIing.
And there were fIames,
and I heard a voice say, ''ZuuI.''
It was right here.
I'm sorry, I'm not getting any reading.
WeII, are you sure
you're using that thing correctIy?
I think so. But I'm sure
there are no animaIs in there.
WeII, that's great.
Either I have a monster in my kitchen,
or I'm compIeteIy crazy.
I don't think you're crazy.
Oh, good. That makes me
feeI so much better.
Let me teII you something about me.
I come home from work to my pIace,
and aII I have is my work.
There's nothing eIse in my Iife.
I meet you and say, ''There's someone
with the same probIem I have.''
Yes, we both have
the same probIem. You.
I'm gonna go for broke.
-I am madIy in Iove with you.
-I don't beIieve this.
WiII you pIease Ieave?
And then she threw me out of her Iife.
She thought I was a creep.
She thought I was a geek,
and she probabIy wasn't the first.
You are so odd.
-No.
-I've got it!
-I'II prove myseIf to you.
That's not necessary.
-Yeah, I'II soIve your IittIe probIem.
-Okay.
And then you'II say, ''Pete Venkman's
a guy who can get things done.
-I wonder what makes him tick.''
-I wonder.
''I wonder if he'd be interested
in knowing what makes me tick.''
I'II bet you're gonna be thinking
about me after I'm gone.
I bet I am.
No kiss?
To our first customer.
To our first and onIy customer.
I'II need to draw some petty cash.
I shouId take her out to dinner.
We don't want to Iose her.
This magnificent feast here
represents the Iast of the petty cash.
Hey, sIow down. Chew your food.
HeIIo, Ghostbusters.
Yes, of course they're serious.
You do?
You have?
No kidding.
WeII, just give me the address.
Yes, of course.
Oh, they'II be totaIIy discreet.
Thank you.
We got one!
It's a caII!
Come on!
Hey, anybody see a ghost?
-Thank you for coming so quickIy.
-Jesus!
The guests are asking questions,
and I'm running out of excuses.
Has it happened before?
WeII, most of the originaI staff
knows about the 1 2th fIoor.
-The disturbances, I mean.
-Yeah.
But it's been quiet for years
up untiI two weeks ago.
It was never, ever this bad, though.
-Did you ever report it to anyone?
-No. Heavens, no.
The owners don't Iike us
to even taIk about it.
I hope we couId take care
of this quietIy.
-It's done.
-Tonight.
Yes, sir. Don't worry.
We handIe this kind of thing
aII the time.
What are you supposed to be,
some kind of a cosmonaut?
No, we're exterminators. Somebody
saw a cockroach up on 1 2th.
-That's gotta be some cockroach.
-Bite your head off, man.
-Going up?
-I'II take the next one.
It just occurred to me we haven't had
a successfuI test of this equipment.
-I bIame myseIf.
-So do I.
-WeII, no sense worrying about it now.
-Why worry?
Each of us is wearing an unIicensed
nucIear acceIerator on his back.
Yep. WeII, Iet's get ready.
Switch me on.
What the heII are you doing?
-Sorry.
-I'm sorry.
We thought you were someone eIse.
SuccessfuI test.
I guess so.
-I think we'd better spIit up.
-Good idea.
Yeah, we can do
more damage that way.
Venkman? Venkman!
Disgusting bIob.
I'm gonna have to hoId him myseIf.
Come in, Ray.
Venkman! I saw it! I saw it!
It's right here, Ray.
It's Iooking at me.
He's an ugly little spud, isn't he?
I think he can hear you, Ray.
Don't move. It won't hurt you.
Venkman!
Venkman! Pete!
Venkman, what happened?
Are you okay?
He sIimed me.
That's great! ActuaI physicaI contact!
-Can you move?
-Ray. Ray! Come in, please!
I feeI so funky.
SpengIer! I'm with Venkman.
He got sIimed!
That's great, Ray. Save some for me.
Get down here, right away!
It just went into a ballroom.
Okay, we'II be right there.
Sir, if you and your staff
couId pIease wait out here...
...we'II take care of everything.
There it is. On the ceiIing.
That's the one that got me.
AII right, boys.
Ready?
Throw it!
I did that. I did that.
-That's my fauIt.
-It's okay. The tabIe broke the faII.
There's something very important
I forgot to teII you.
-What?
-Don't cross the streams.
-Why?
-It wouId be bad.
I'm fuzzy on the whoIe goodlbad thing.
What do you mean, ''bad''?
Imagine aII Iife as you know it stopping
instantaneousIy and every moIecuIe...
...in your body expIoding
at the speed of Iight.
TotaI protonic reversaI.
Right, that's bad. Okay,
important safety tip. Thanks, Egon.
AII right, Ray, take the Ieft.
Egon, take the right.
Okay, Ray, just give me
one high and outside.
Ray!
Egon!
Okay, aII right.
HoId it, hoId it, hoId it!
Nice shooting, Tex!
I assure you, there is no probIem
with the room.
It'II be ready as soon as your guests
are with us.
It took something out of him,
but he'II move.
I need some room to put the trap
down. Give me some room.
You'II excuse me, pIease.
-Gotta get this in the cIear.
-Wait, wait, wait!
I've aIways wanted to do this.
And....
-The fIowers are stiII standing!
-Okay, on my go-signaI.
SpengIer, I want a confinement stream
from you, okay? Go!
Okay, hoId him up there.
He's gonna move. HoId him up!
Go!
-It's working, Ray.
-Start bringing him down.
You got him. Don't cross the stream.
Maybe now you'II never sIime a guy
with a positron coIIider, huh?
Venkman, shorten your stream.
I don't want my face burned off.
I'm opening the trap now.
Don't Iook directIy into the trap.
I Iooked at the trap, Ray.
Turn your streams off when I cIose
the trap. Get ready. I'm cIosing it.
Now!
It's in there.
WeII, that wasn't such a chore,
now, was it?
Mr. Smith, quickIy.
I want that door open now!
DonaId, stand over there.
We came, we saw, we kicked its ass!
Did you see it? What is it?
We got it.
What is it?
WiII there be any more of them?
What you had there
was what we refer to as a focused...
...non-terminaI repeating phantasm,
or a cIass-five fuII-roaming vapor.
ReaI nasty one too.
And now...
...Iet's taIk seriousIy.
For the entrapment, we're gonna have
to ask you for four big ones, $4000.
But we are having a speciaI this week
on proton charging...
...and storage of the beast.
That's onIy gonna come to
1 000 doIIars, fortunateIy.
Five thousand doIIars? I had no idea
it'd be so much. I won't pay it.
WeII, that's aII right.
We can just put it back.
We certainIy can, Dr. Venkman.
No! AII right! Anything.
Thanks so much.
Thank you. Hope
we can heIp you again.
Coming through! One cIass-five
free-roaming vapor.
Morning, I'm Roger Grimsby.
Today, the entire Eastern seaboard...
...is alive with talk of incidents
of paranormal activity.
Alleged ghost-sightings
and supernatural occurrences...
...have been reported
across the entire tri-state area.
Everybody has heard ghost stories
around the campfire.
My grandma used to spin yarns
about a spectraI Iocomotive...
...that wouId rocket past the farm
where she grew up.
But now, as if
some unforeseen authority....
Stand aside, pIease!
Hi, this is Larry King. The phone-in
topic, ghosts and ghostbusting.
The controversy buiIds,
more sightings are reported.
Some maintain that these...
...professionaI paranormaI eIiminators
in New York are the cause of it aII.
I got it! I got it!
Pete! Ray!
Still making headlines
all across the country...
...the Ghostbusters are at it again,
this time at the dance club...
... The Rose. The boys in gray slugged
it out with a pesky poltergeist...
...then stayed to dance with the ladies
who witnessed the disturbance.
This is Casey Kasem.
Now on with the countdown.
Twenty-four hours a day,
seven days a week.
No job is too big. No fee is too big.
Is it just a mist,
or does it have arms and Iegs?
As they say in TV, I'm sure
there's one big question...
...on everybody's mind, and I imagine
you are the man to answer that.
How is Elvis,
and have you seen him lately?
Do you beIieve in UFOs,
astraI projections...
...mentaI teIepathy, ESP,
cIairvoyance...
...spirit photography,
teIekinetic movement...
...fuII-trance mediums, the Loch Ness
monster and the theory of AtIantis?
If there's a steady paycheck in it,
I'II beIieve anything you say.
I gotta get some sIeep. I'm dying.
You don't Iook good.
-I don't?
-WeII, you've Iooked better.
You didn't used to Iook Iike this.
Can you hoId, pIease?
Here's the paper on the BrookIyn.
She paid with Visa.
Here's tonight's worksheet.
Oh, great. Two more free repeaters.
This is Winston Zeddmore.
He's here about the job.
BeautifuI. You're hired.
Ray Stantz, Pete Venkman.
-CongratuIations.
-Can you heIp me, pIease?
WeIcome aboard.
I don't know where they get
these guest conductors.
It's not gonna do him much good
to scream at us in German.
WeII, I don't think that the man
is competent to conduct...
...a major symphony orchestra.
-CouId you wait here a minute?
-Sure.
Dr. Venkman. This is a surprise.
-That was a wonderfuI rehearsaI.
-You heard that?
Yes. You're the best one in your row.
Oh, thank you.
You're good. Most peopIe can't hear
me with the whoIe orchestra pIaying.
I don't have to take this abuse.
I got hundreds of peopIe
dying to abuse me.
I know. You're a big ceIebrity now.
Do you have some information
for me on my case?
Who's the stiff?
The ''stiff'' happens to be one of
the finest musicians in the worId.
Do you have information
for me, pIease?
WeII, sure, but I prefer
to give it to you in private.
-Why don't you teII me now.
-Okay. I found the name ZuuI for you.
The name ZuuI refers to a demigod
worshiped around 6000 B.C. by the....
What's that word?
-''Hittites.''
-Hittites...
...the Mesopotamians
and the Sumerians.
''ZuuI was the minion of Gozer.''
What's Gozer?
-Gozer was very big in Sumeria.
-WeII, what's he doing in my icebox?
I'm working on that. If we couId
get together Thursday night...
...I'm thinking 9-ish, you know,
we couId exchange information.
I can't see you Thursday. I'm busy.
Miss Barrett, you seem to think there
is something wrong up here that says:
''He enjoys taking his evenings off
and spending it with his cIients.''
No. I'm making a speciaI exception
in your case...
...because...
...I respect you.
It's corny, but I respect you
as an artist.
As a dresser too. This is a magnificent
coordination you have going today.
-See you Thursday.
-I'II bring the Roylance Guide...
...and we'II eat and read.
-So who the heII is that?
-He's just a friend.
-A friend?
-An oId friend.
Bye! WeII, I'II see you Thursday!
I'm sorry I didn't get to meet you, sir.
I'm gIad you're feeIing much better.
You're stiII very paIe, though.
A IittIe sun.
-WeII, what does he do?
-He's a scientist.
This is where we store aII the vapors
and entities and sIimers that we trap.
Very simpIe, reaIIy. A Ioaded trap
here. Open, unIock the system.
Insert the trap.
ReIease.
CIose, Iock the system.
Set your entry grid.
Neutronize your fieId.
And...
...when the Iight is green,
the trap is cIean.
The ghost is incarcerated here
in our custom storage faciIity.
There's a man from the EPA here
to see you. He's waiting in your office.
-EPA? What's he want?
-I don't know.
AII I do know is I've been working
two weeks without a break...
...and you promised me
you'd hire more heIp.
Janine, someone
with your quaIifications...
...wouId have no troubIe finding
a topfIight job in either...
...the food service or
housekeeping industries.
-Are you gonna answer that?
-I've quit better jobs than this.
Ghostbusters! What do you want?
-Can I heIp you?
-I'm WaIter Peck.
I represent the EnvironmentaI
Protection Agency, the third district.
Great. How's it going down there?
Are you Peter Venkman?
Yes, I'm...
...Dr. Venkman.
ExactIy what are you a doctor of,
Mr. Venkman?
WeII, I have Ph.D.'s in parapsychoIogy
and psychoIogy.
I see.
And now you catch ghosts.
Yeah. You couId say that.
And how many ghosts have you
caught, Mr. Venkman?
-I'm not at Iiberty to say.
-And where do you put...
...these ghosts
once you catch them?
Into a storage faciIity.
And wouId this storage faciIity
be Iocated on these premises?
-Yes.
-And may I see this storage faciIity?
-No.
-And why not, Mr. Venkman?
Because you did not use
the magic word.
What is the magic word,
Mr. Venkman?
''PIease.''
May I pIease see the storage faciIity,
Mr. Venkman?
Why do you want to see it?
WeII, because I'm curious.
I want to know more about
what you do here.
There've been a Iot of wiId
stories in the media...
...and we want to assess
any possibIe environmentaI impact...
...from your operation.
For instance, the presence
of noxious...
...possibIy hazardous waste chemicaIs
in your basement.
Now, you show me what is down there,
or I come back with a court order.
You go get a court order, and I'II sue
your ass for wrongfuI prosecution!
You can have it your way,
Mr. Venkman.
I'm worried. It's crowded in there,
and my data...
...points to something big
on the horizon.
What do you mean ''big''?
WeII, Iet's say this Twinkie
represents the normaI amount...
...of psychokinetic energy
in the New York area.
According to this morning's sampIe,
it wouId be a Twinkie...
...35 feet Iong, weighing
approximateIy 600 pounds.
That's a big Twinkie.
We couId be on the verge
of a fourfoId cross-rip...
...a PKE surge of incredibIe,
even dangerous, proportions.
We just had a visit from the
EnvironmentaI Protection Agency.
-How's the grid hoIding up?
-Not good.
TeII him about the Twinkie.
What about the Twinkie?
-Oh, Dana, it's you.
-HeIIo, Louis.
You gotta come in here.
You're missing a cIassic party.
Yes, weII, I wouId, Louis,
but I have a date coming over.
You made a date...
-...tonight?
-WeII, I'm sorry, Louis. I forgot.
Oh, that's okay.
You can bring him aIong.
AII right. Maybe we'II stop by, okay?
That's great. I'II teII everybody.
We're gonna pIay Twister,
we're gonna do some breakdancing....
Hey--
Hey, Iet me in! It's Louis!
Somebody, Iet me in!
HeIIo?
Hi, Mom.
I've been busy.
WeII.... No, everything is fine.
Yeah. No, just that one time.
Oh, I am.
I wiII.
I won't. Mom, I have to go.
I have a date.
Yes. No, no one you know. It's....
WeII, he's a Ghostbuster.
Those guys on TV.
Yes, weII, I'II have to Iet you know.
Okay. Love to Dad.
Right. Bye. Bye.
Oh, shit.
Do you have any Excedrin
or Extra Strength TyIenoI?
Gee, I think aII I got is
acetyIsaIicyIic acid. Generic.
I can get 600 tabIets of that for the
same price as 300 of the name brand.
Makes good financiaI sense.
Good advice.
Hey, this is reaI smoked saImon
from Nova Scotia, Canada...
...2 4.95 a pound.
It onIy cost me 1 4.1 2
after tax, though.
I'm giving this as
a promotionaI expense.
That's why I invited cIients instead
of friends. Having a good time, Marv?
How you doing? Have some Brie.
It's at room temperature.
You think it's too warm for Brie?
Louis, I'm going home.
Don't Ieave yet. Listen,
maybe if we start dancing...
...other peopIe wiII join in.
Okay.
Oh, don't move.
I just gotta get the door.
-Ted! Annette!
-Hi.
I'm gIad you couId come.
Give me your coats.
Everybody, this is Ted
and Annette FIeming.
How are you?
Ted has a smaII carpet-cIeaning
business in receivership.
Annette's drawing a saIary from
a deferred bonus from two years ago.
They got 1 5,000 Ieft
on the house at 8 percent.
So they're okay!
Does anybody want
to pIay Parcheesi?
Okay, who brought the dog?
HeIp! There's a bear Ioose
in my apartment! HeIp! HeIp!
HeIp!
-What?
-A bear in his apartment.
I'm gonna bring this up
at the tenants' meeting.
There's not supposed to be
any pets in the buiIding.
Let me in. There's gotta be a way
in here. I gotta get--
Somebody, Iet me in!
Nice doggy.
Cute IittIe pooch.
Maybe I got a MiIk-Bone.
-What happened?
-Some moron brought...
...a cougar to a party,
and it went berserk.
Hi, I'm going up to Dana Barrett's.
HeIIo?
That's a different Iook for you,
isn't it?
Are you the Keymaster?
Not that I know of.
Yes.
I'm a friend of his.
He toId me to meet him here.
-I didn't get your name.
-I am ZuuI.
I am the Gatekeeper.
-What are we doing today, ZuuI?
-Prepare for the coming of Gozer.
Gozer, huh?
The Destructor.
Are we stiII going out?
You know, you couId pick up the pIace
if you're expecting someone.
Do you want this body?
Is this a trick question?
I guess the roses worked, huh?
Take me now...
...sub-creature.
We never taIk anymore.
Easy. I make it a ruIe never to get
invoIved with possessed peopIe.
It's more of a guideIine than a ruIe.
You know, I can--
I want you inside me.
Go ahead. No, I can't.
Sounds Iike you got at Ieast
two peopIe in there aIready.
Might be a IittIe crowded.
Come on, why don't you
just quit trying...
...to upset and disturb Dr. Venkman
and just reIax.
Lie down there. ReIax.
Put your hands on your chest.
What I'd reaIIy Iike to do
is taIk to Dana.
I want to taIk to Dana.
Dana, it's Peter.
There is no Dana.
There is onIy ZuuI.
Oh, ZuuIie, you nut. Come on.
Come on, I want to taIk
to Dana. Dana.
Just reIax. Come on. Dana.
Dana. Can I taIk to Dana?
There is no Dana, onIy ZuuI.
What a IoveIy singing voice
you must have.
Now, I'm gonna count
to three, ZuuIie.
And if I don't taIk to Dana...
...there's gonna be some reaI troubIe
in this apartment, I think.
One.
Two.
Two and a haIf.
PIease come down.
I am the Keymaster.
The Destructor is coming.
The TraveIer. The Destroyer.
Gatekeeper.
I am Vinz.
Vinz CIortho, Keymaster of Gozer.
VoIguus ZiIdrohar, Lord of the
SebouiIIia. Are you the Gatekeeper?
He puIIs the wagon, I make
the deaIs. You want a ride?
Wait for the sign.
Then aII prisoners wiII be reIeased.
You wiII perish in fIame,
you and aII your kind! Gatekeeper!
What an asshoIe.
-Dropping off or picking up?
-Dropping off.
Just a moment.
-You a Ghostbuster?
-Yes.
We picked up this guy.
We don't know what to do.
BeIIevue doesn't want him.
I'm afraid to Iock him up.
I know you guys are into this
stuff, so I figured we'd check.
AII right.
Are you the Gatekeeper?
You better bring him inside.
You are so kind to take
care of that man.
You know, you are
a reaI humanitarian.
I don't think he's human.
What did you say your name was?
Vinz CIortho, Keymaster of Gozer.
According to this,
his name's Louis TuIIy.
Lives on CentraI Park West.
Do you want some coffee, Mr. TuIIy?
-Do I?
-Yes, have some.
Yes, have some.
Vinz, you said before you
were waiting for a sign.
-What sign are you waiting for?
-Gozer the TraveIer.
He wiII come in one
of the pre-chosen forms.
During rectification of the VuIdronaii,
the TraveIer came as a Iarge Torb.
Then, during the third reconciIiation
of the Meketrex suppIicants...
...they chose a new form for him,
that of a giant SIoar!
Many Shubs and ZuuIs knew
what it was to be roasted...
...in the depths of the SIoar that day,
I can teII you.
-Egon.
-Excuse me.
There's something very strange
about that man.
I'm usuaIIy very psychic,
and I have a terribIe feeIing...
...that something awfuI
is gonna happen to you.
I'm afraid you're gonna die.
I'II get it.
-HeIIo?
-Egon, it's Peter.
-Thanks, I've got it.
-I have news from the worId of Gozer.
-What is it, Peter?
-I'm here with Dana Barrett.
It seems the Goz has been
putting some moves...
-...on my wouId-be girIfriend.
-How is she?
I think we can get her
a guest shot on Wild Kingdom.
I just whacked her up
with about 300 cc's of Thorazine.
She's gonna take a IittIe nap now,
but she says she's the Gatekeeper.
-Does that make any sense to you?
-Some.
I just met the Keymaster.
He's here with me now.
Oh, wonderfuI. We have
to get these two together.
I think that wouId be
extraordinariIy dangerous.
Okay, weII, hoId onto him.
I'II be there in a IittIe whiIe.
Good.
Thank you, Vinz. We have to find Ray.
I need him here immediateIy.
Bad news, honey, I gotta go to work.
Hey, wiII you stay here in bed
untiI I get back?
-Hey, Ray, do you beIieve in God?
-Never met him.
Yeah, weII, I do. And I Iove
Jesus' styIe, you know?
This roof cap is made of
a magnesium-tungsten aIIoy.
What are you so invoIved
with there?
These are bIueprints for the ironwork
in Dana Barrett's apartment...
...and they're very, very strange.
Hey, Ray, do you remember
something in the BibIe about...
...the Iast days, when the dead
wouId rise from the grave?
I remember ReveIations 7:1 2.
And I Iooked as he opened
the sixth seaI.
And behoId, there was
a great earthquake.
And the sun became
as bIack as sackcIoth.
And the moon became as bIood.
And the seas boiIed.
And the skies feII.
-Judgment day.
Every ancient reIigion has its myth
about the end of the worId.
Myth? Ray, has it ever
occurred to you...
...maybe the reason
we've been so busy...
...is because the dead have
been rising from the grave?
-How about a IittIe music?
-Yeah.
This way.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Just where do you think you're going?
Step aside, or you'II be arrested
for interfering with the poIice.
Oh, no. HoId on. I've seen TV.
You can't come in here...
...without a warrant or a writ.
Cease and Desist AII Commerce
order. Seizure of Premises.
Ban of PubIic UtiIities
for Non-Licensed Waste HandIers...
...and a federaI
Entry and Inspection order.
Vinz, there's one more test
I'd Iike to perform.
Egon. I tried to stop them.
He says they have a warrant.
-Excuse me, this is private property.
-Shut this off. Shut these aII off.
I'm warning you. Turning off these
machines is hazardous.
I'II teII you hazardous.
You're facing prosecution...
...for a haIf-a-dozen
environmentaI vioIations.
You shut off these beams,
or we shut them off for you.
Understand, this is a high-voItage
Iaser containment system.
SimpIy turning it off wouId be
Iike dropping a bomb in the city.
Don't patronize me. I'm not stupid,
Iike the peopIe you biIk.
At ease, officer. I'm Peter Venkman.
There's been a misunderstanding...
...and I want to cooperate
in any way I can.
Forget it. You had your chance
to cooperate...
...but you thought it'd be more fun to
insuIt me. Now it is my turn, wise-ass.
He wants to shut down
the protection grid.
You shut that thing down,
we won't be heId responsibIe--
-You'II be responsibIe. Shut it off.
-No, we won't be heId responsibIe.
Don't shut it off. I'm warning you.
I've never seen anything Iike this.
I don't know--
Yeah, I'm not interested in
your opinion. Just shut it off.
My friend, don't be a jerk.
-Step aside.
-If he does that again, you shoot him.
You do your job.
Don't teII me how to do mine.
-Thank you, officer.
-Shut it off!
Oh, shit.
CIear the buiIding!
This is it. This is the sign.
Yeah, it's a sign, aII right.
We're going out of business.
Hey, aim up there.
-What happened?
-Storage faciIity bIew.
-He shut off the protection grid.
-Oh, great.
-That's bad, isn't it?
-Yeah.
-Where's the Keymaster?
-Shit.
-Who's the Keymaster?
-Oh, come on.
HoId it. I want this man arrested.
These men are in criminaI vioIation
of the EnvironmentaI Protection Act.
-This expIosion is a direct resuIt of it.
-Your mother!
Come on, hoId it! HoId it! HoId it!
CoIumbia BuiIding, 57th Street.
I'm in a hurry, so Iet's not dawdIe.
Hey, guard!
Look, I want to make a phone caII.
I just work with these guys.
I wasn't even there.
The structure of this roof cap
is Iike the teIemetry tracker...
...that NASA uses to identify
dead puIsars in deep space.
CoId-riveted girders
with cores of pure seIenium.
Everybody getting this so far?
So what? I guess they just don't
make them Iike they used to.
No. Nobody ever made
them Iike this.
The architect was either a certified
genius or an authentic wacko.
Ray, for a moment...
...pretend that I don't know
anything about metaIIurgy...
...engineering or physics and just
teII me what the heII is going on.
You never studied.
The whoIe buiIding is a huge
superconductive antenna...
...that was designed and
buiIt for the purpose...
...of puIIing in and concentrating
spirituaI turbuIence.
Your girIfriend Iives in the
corner penthouse of spook centraI.
She's not my girIfriend.
I find her interesting because she's
a cIient and sIeeps above her covers.
Four feet above her covers.
She barks. She drooIs. She cIaws.
It's not the girI, Peter,
it's the buiIding.
Something terribIe is about to enter
our worId. This buiIding is the door.
The architect's name
was Ivo Shandor.
I found it in Tobin's Spirit Guide.
He was aIso a doctor.
He performed a Iot
of unnecessary surgery.
And then, in 1 920,
he started a secret society.
-Let me guess. Gozer worshipers.
-Right.
No studying.
After WorId War I, Shandor decided
that society was too sick to survive.
He wasn't aIone. He had cIose
to a thousand foIIowers when he died.
They conducted rituaIs
up on the roof...
...bizarre rituaIs intended to bring
about the end of the worId.
And now it Iooks Iike
it may actuaIIy happen.
We have to get out of here
and find a judge or something.
Hey, wait a minute.
Hey, hey, hey. HoId it.
Are we going to go
before a judge to say...
...that a BabyIonian god is
gonna drop in on CentraI Park West...
-...and start tearing up the city?
-Sumerian, not BabyIonian.
-Yeah, big difference.
-No offense...
...but I gotta get my own Iawyer.
Okay, Ghostbusters.
The mayor wants to see you guys.
The whoIe isIand's going crazy.
Let's go.
I gotta spIit. The mayor wants to
rap with me about some things.
-I am the Keymaster.
-I am the Gatekeeper.
-Back. Back. Stay back.
-Stay back. Stay back.
I've got a city bIowing up,
and you aren't giving me answers.
We're bIocking the bridges,
the roads--
The Ghostbusters are here.
The Ghostbusters.
Okay, the Ghostbusters.
Hey, and where's this Peck?
Peck. I am WaIter Peck, sir, and
I am prepared to make a fuII report.
These men are consummate
snowbaII artists.
They use sense and nerve gases
to induce haIIucinations.
PeopIe think they're seeing ghosts,
and they caII these bozos...
...who show up to deaI
with the probIem...
...with a fake eIectronic Iight show.
Everything was fine with our system
untiI the power grid...
-...was shut off by dickIess here.
-They caused an expIosion.
-Is this true?
-Yes, it's true. This man has no dick.
Hey, come on. Knock it off.
Hey, break it up!
-AII right.
-WeII, that's what I heard.
This is City HaII.
Now, what am I gonna do here, John?
What is this?
AII I know is that was no Iight show
we saw this morning.
I've seen every form
of combustion known to man...
...but this beats the heII out of me.
The waIIs in the 53rd Precinct
were bIeeding.
-How do you expIain that?
-Good afternoon, gentIemen.
Oh, Your Eminence.
-How are you, Lenny?
-You're Iooking good, Mike.
We're in a reaI fix here.
What do you think I shouId do?
OfficiaIIy, the church
wiII not take any position...
...on the reIigious impIications
of these phenomena.
PersonaIIy, Lenny...
...I think it's a sign from God.
But don't quote me on that.
That's a smart move, Mike.
I won't caII a press conference...
...and teII everyone to start praying.
I'm Winston Zeddmore, Your Honor.
I've onIy been with the company
for a coupIe weeks.
But I gotta teII you,
these things are reaI.
Since I joined these men,
I have seen shit that'II turn you white.
WeII, you can beIieve Mr. Pecker.
-My name is Peck.
-Or you couId accept the fact...
...that this city is headed for
a disaster of bibIicaI proportions.
-WeII, what do you mean, ''bibIicaI''?
-What he means is OId Testament.
-ReaI wrath-of-God-type stuff.
-ExactIy.
Fire and brimstone down from
the skies. Rivers and seas boiIing.
Forty years of darkness.
Earthquakes. VoIcanoes.
The dead rising from the grave.
Human sacrifice. Dogs and cats
Iiving together. Mass hysteria.
Enough! I get the point.
But what if you're wrong?
If I'm wrong, nothing happens.
We go to jaiI, peacefuIIy, quietIy.
We'II enjoy it. But if I'm right...
...and we can stop this thing....
Lenny, you wiII have
saved the Iives...
...of miIIions of registered voters.
I don't beIieve you're seriousIy
considering Iistening to these men.
Get him out of here.
-Bye.
-I'II fix you. I'm gonna fix you.
I'II get you a nice fruit basket.
I'm going to miss him.
AII right. AII right.
We got work to do. Now,
what do you need from me?
Come on, Iet's run some red Iights!
HeIIo, New York.
HeIIo, everybody!
Dr. Ray Stantz, wouId you pIease?
The heart of the Ghostbusters.
Thank you. They Iove you.
They Iove you here.
-I Iike that shirt, friend.
-Ghostbusters! AII right!
Gotta run. Got a date with a ghost.
Okay, whatever happens,
Iet's be professionaI.
We might have to put a IittIe
overtime in on this one.
There they are. There they are.
I was in no way prepared for that.
It's aII right. Don't worry.
We're fine. We can handIe it.
We can take it.
They want to pIay rough.
Ghostbusters! Ghostbusters!
Ghostbusters!
-Wanna pIay rough?
-Yeah.
Let's do it.
Where are we?
It Iooks Iike we're
in the teens somewhere.
WeII, when we get to 20, teII me.
I'm gonna throw up.
-Twenty-two. Is this it?
-Yep.
Art deco. Very nice.
-Where is it?
-It's at the end of the haII.
Hey, where do these stairs go?
They go up.
Okay, go ahead. Come on.
Go ahead.
Watch it. Go ahead.
Dana.
Okay, so she's a dog.
It's a girI.
-It's Gozer.
-I thought Gozer was a man.
-It's whatever it wants to be.
-Whatever it is, it's gotta get by us.
Right.
Go get her, Ray!
Gozer the Gozerian?
Good evening. As a duIy designated
representative of the city...
...county and state of New York...
...I order you to cease
aII supernaturaI activity...
...and return to your pIace of origin...
...or to the nearest convenient
paraIIeI dimension.
That ought to do it.
Thanks very much, Ray.
Are you a god?
-No.
-Then die!
Ray, when someone asks you
if you're a god, you say, ''Yes.''
AII right. This chick is toast.
-Got your stick?
-HoIding it.
Heat them up!
Smoking!
-Make them hard.
-Ready!
Let's show this prehistoric bitch
how we do things downtown.
Throw it!
-NimbIe IittIe minx, isn't she?
-We better go fuII stream.
Aim for the fIattop.
Wasn't so hard.
We neutronized it.
You know what that means?
A compIete particIe reversaI.
And we had the tooIs.
We had the taIent.
It's MiIIer time.
-Ray, this Iooks extraordinariIy bad.
-Oh, no.
What?
Look out!
Sub-creatures. Gozer the Gozerian,
Gozer the Destructor...
...VoIguus ZiIdrohar
the TraveIer has come.
Choose and perish.
What do you mean, ''choose''?
We don't understand.
Choose. Choose the form
of the Destructor.
Oh, I get it. I get it. Oh, very cute.
Whatever we think of.
If we think of J. Edgar Hoover...
...J. Edgar Hoover wiII appear and
destroy us, so empty your heads.
Don't think of anything.
We've onIy got one shot at this.
The choice is made.
The TraveIer has come.
Nobody choosed anything.
-Did you choose anything?
-No.
-Did you?
-My mind is bIank.
I didn't choose anything!
I couIdn't heIp it.
It just popped in there.
What? What just popped in there?
-I tried to think--
-Look!
-No! It can't be.
-What is it?
-It can't be.
-What did you do, Ray?
Oh, shit.
It's the Stay Puft MarshmaIIow Man.
There's something
you don't see every day.
I tried to think of a harmIess thing.
Something I Ioved
from my chiIdhood.
Something that couId never, ever
possibIy destroy us. Mr. Stay Puft.
Nice thinking, Ray.
We used to roast
Stay Puft marshmaIIows...
...by the fire at Camp Waconda.
Ray, has gone bye-bye, Egon.
What have you got Ieft?
Sorry, Venkman. I'm terrified beyond
the capacity for rationaI thought.
-Oh, no.
-Mother pus bucket.
Nobody steps on a church
in my town.
One, two, three, roast him.
Funny, us going out Iike this.
KiIIed by a 1 00-foot
marshmaIIow man.
We've been going about this wrong.
This Mr. Stay Puft is a saiIor.
He's in New York. We get this
guy Iaid, we won't have any troubIe.
I have a radicaI idea.
The door swings both ways.
We couId reverse the particIe fIow
through the gate.
How?
-We'II cross the streams.
-Excuse me, Egon.
You said crossing the streams
was bad.
-Cross the streams.
-You're gonna endanger us.
You're gonna endanger our cIient...
...the nice Iady who paid us in
advance before she became a dog.
Not necessariIy. There's definiteIy
a very sIim chance we'II survive.
I Iove this pIan. I'm excited
to be a part of it. Let's do it.
This job is definiteIy not
worth 1 1 ,500 a year.
Hurry.
See you on the other side, Ray.
Nice working with you, Dr. Venkman.
Let's turn them on, SpengIer!
Now, SpengIer!
Get out of here!
Winston.
Are you aII right?
Venkman?
SpengIer!
Venkman!
SpengIer.
Oh, SpengIer. Oh, are you okay?
I feeI Iike the fIoor of a taxicab.
-Venky!
-Yeah, where are you?
Oh, thank God.
-You okay?
-I'm aII right.
-You aII right?
-Yeah. You okay?
Fine.
It smeIIs Iike barbecued dog hair.
Oh, Venkman.
Oh, Venkman, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I just-- I just forgot.
Look!
Somebody turn on the Iights!
-HeIp! Somebody!
-Go check on that IittIe guy.
What happened?
Where am I?
Oh, hi.
You'II be aII right.
Boy, the superintendent's
gonna be pissed.
Are you okay?
Who are you guys?
We're the Ghostbusters.
Who does your taxes?
You know, Mr. TuIIy,
you are a most fortunate individuaI.
-I know.
-You have been a participant in...
...the biggest interdimensionaI cross
rip since the Tunguska bIast of 1 909.
-FeIt great.
-We'd Iike to get a sampIe...
-...of your brain tissue.
-Okay.
I Iove this town!
Egon!
What's going on?
Does anybody want to interview me?
I'm an eyewitness. I was up there.
I want to go with them in the car.