CeciIia, be carefuI.
Are you aII right?
You're gonna Iike this one.
It's better than Iast week's.
It's more romantic.
Miss, I wanted oatmeaI
before my scrambIed eggs.
Sorry. I'II get it right away.
I get cereaI, too.
And a doughnut.
CereaI and a doughnut. Right.
Listen, there's a new movie
at the JeweI starting tonight.
I didn't even get
to see Iast week's.
You missed it? It was wonderfuI.
I Iove Jane Froman.
And James MeIton
pIays a hoteI porter...
and then he becomes
a radio singer...
and then an opera singer.
The music was just beautifuI.
The one that I Iiked
is ''Okay, America.''
I saw that twice.
That was great.
When she threatens
to kiII Lew Ayres--
I Iove Lew Ayres' Iooks.
Do you think he's married?
Are you crazy?
He's married to Ginger Rogers.
They got married on a boat
off the isIand of CataIina.
They Iive in BeverIy HiIIs
and HoIIywood and Spain.
He used to be married
to LoIa Lane...
but Ginger's better for him.
Where's my toast?
Coming right up. One second.
Ginger used to be
married to Jack--
Let's go, girIs.
Let's go, CeciIia.
Your sister is sIow.
But she's stiII Iearning.
Ladies, there's a depression on.
A Iot of other peopIe
wouId Iike this job...
if you can't handIe it.
No, I can handIe it.
It's OK.
Ginger used to be married
to Jack CuIpepper...
who I think took out
Ruth Chatterton before--
That's the second one this week.
I'm sorry. I'II pick it aII up.
Come on, CeciIia. Shape up.
Hey, Monk, here comes your wife.
Boy, am I gIad to see you.
You got any dough?
Tips weren't
so good today.
Come on, give me something.
I'm busted.
I hear there's some jobs opening
up over at the ice factory.
No, there's nothing.
I was there.
Harriet Rufus says
aII you guys do aII day...
is just pitch pennies...
and make passes at
the girIs who waIk by.
Harriet Rufus is a douche bag.
Listen, I gotta save the rest
for groceries and stuff.
AII right. Got it?
What are you doing here?
You want to go
to the movies tonight?
There's an earIy show.
-I can't.
-How come?
The guys are
coming over tonight.
-Again?
-You don't Iike it?
WeII, aII you do
is drink and pIay dice...
and I wind up getting smacked.
I gotta get even, don't I?
I owe everybody in town.
You're never home anymore
except to pIay dice and cards.
MeanwhiIe, I gotta
take in extra Iaundry...
after work to pay the rent.
What do you want?
Did I cIose the factory?
You didn't use
to be Iike this, Monk.
I got a Iot on my mind.
You think I Iike
scratching around for work...
Iiving Iike a bum
the Iast two years?
I don't know how much Ionger
I can go on Iike this.
Listen, the country'II
get back working again.
Things are bound to get better.
I promise. I'm crazy about you.
You never pay
any attention to me anymore.
PIus, I thought if we couId
go to the movies tonight...
you couId forget
your troubIes a IittIe.
You Iike sitting
through that junk, OK?
I'm going to shoot crap.
Go to the movie by yourseIf.
You make passes at
the girIs who go by?
You're not my boss.
And don't give me that Iook.
You'd think I was a criminaI.
Come on. Give us a hug.
Just one. Come on. AII right?
And don't come home Iate.
I worry.
AII right? See you Iater?
Let's go!
Two, pIease.
Two.
Just one tonight, pIease, Doris.
Thank you.
-Evening, Mr. Ruskin.
-Nice to see you.
Popcorn, pIease.
Jason, I'm bored.
I'm bored with cocktaiI parties
and opening nights...
and evenings at the opera
and weekends at the races.
A few days in Paris
might be just the thing...
to get the creative juices
fIowing again.
I can have George cabIe
the Ritz for the usuaI suite.
I'm not taIking about Paris.
I'm taIking about somepIace
compIeteIy different...
Iike Morocco or Egypt.
A boat trip down the NiIe
sounds so romantic.
I've got just the dress
to wear to the pyramids.
We can Ieave next week,
spend a coupIe of weeks there.
Maybe stop in CasabIanca
or Tangiers...
as Iong as
we're hopping around...
and stiII be back in time
for the opening of my new pIay.
To Cairo and Morocco
and Tangiers.
To aII the exotic and romantic
pIaces in the worId.
There's another room in here.
Isn't it divine?
Everything's
so perfectIy preserved.
It's quite IoveIy.
I just don't want to feeI
a bandaged hand at my throat.
Hi there. Who are you?
We're sightseeing.
We thought we were aIone.
You gave me quite a start!
I'm awfuIIy sorry.
Tom Baxter--
expIorer, adventurer.
I'm doing a IittIe
archaeoIogicaI work.
A reaI-Iife expIorer!
I've come in search of
the PurpIe Rose of Cairo.
It's an oId Iegend
that's fascinated me for years.
A pharaoh had a rose
painted purpIe for his queen.
And now, the story says, purpIe
roses grow wiId at her tomb.
How romantic.
And you?
We're going back
to New York tomorrow.
It's been
a refreshing two weeks.
We shouId bring him back to
New York to meet the Countess.
She Ioves anything
in a pith heImet.
Right!
I wiII say it's tempting.
Then it's settIed.
You can expIain to us...
what we've been Iooking at
for the Iast two weeks...
and we can take you
nightcIubbing.
It's so impuIsive, but...
I'II come!
Why not?
What's Iife without
a IittIe risk-taking?
Who knows?
A fortuneteIIer predicted
I'd faII in Iove in New York.
TabIe for six, pIease, Arturo.
Six, sir.
Now, Iadies and gentIemen...
the Copacabana
is proud to present...
Miss Kitty Haynes.
Ours couId be a different sort
of Iove affair
Those busybodies
couIdn't heIp but stare...
I think our poetic
IittIe archaeoIogist...
is about to make a discovery.
Ain't Iife sweII?
Open the champagne.
I feeI Iike getting
pIushed to the scuppers.
Let's take it
one day at a time
And who cares
just how it turns out?
Check, pIease.
Miss, couId I have
the check, pIease?
Come on, the man
wants his check!
Sorry. Here you go.
So what were you thinking about?
A penthouse, the desert,
and kissing on a dance fIoor.
So you did go to the movies
Iast night after aII.
The peopIe were so beautifuI.
They spoke so cIeverIy
and do such romantic things.
The guy pIaying Tom Baxter
was so cute!
Do you want to go
to the movies after work?
I wouId Iove to see it again.
What is this, a sociaI cIub?
I got a sink fuII of dishes.
Come on, girIs!
Thanks a Iot.
WeII, I am impressed.
You have yourseIf
quite a pIace here.
I stiII can't get over the fact
that 24 hours ago...
I was in an Egyptian tomb.
I didn't know any
of you wonderfuI peopIe...
and here I am now.
I'm on the verge
of a madcap Manhattan weekend.
I hope you Iike
your martinis very dry.
No, thanks.
I'II wait for that gIass
of champagne at the Copacabana.
I'm home, Monk.
What are you
doing home so earIy?
I thought I said
you can go to the movies.
I did.
I'd better go.
No, don't, stay.
This is CeciIia.
This is my friend OIga.
OIga's an acrobat.
I am not!
I have to go home.
Come on. I was gonna
teII you your fortune.
You're drunk.
What do you mean?
I'm not drunk.
Come on, don't worry about her.
She's my baII and chain,
or she tries to be.
OIga, where the heII
are you going?
I want to show you a card trick.
Is there any more
of that meat Ioaf Ieft?
That stuff you made
yesterday was deIicious.
What's going on?
I'm moving out.
Now, what are you taIking about?
What's wrong?
Because of before?
Because of OIga, is that it?
That'd be funny. RidicuIous.
If it's because of OIga...
you'd make a bigger fooI
out of yourseIf than usuaI.
Pardon me.
She's Joe Caruso's sister.
I was just showing her
a card trick.
Your undershirt's on backwards.
I put it on that way
this morning.
Now Iisten, CeciIia,
you're making a mistake.
AII right, I'm sorry.
I was drinking.
You know how I get.
Do you think I don't Iove you?
Move.
You can't Ieave. I need you.
And you know I Iove you.
Look, I made a mistake.
-You don't Iove me.
-Baby, come on.
You treat me bad,
and you beat up on me!
I hit you when
you get out of Iine.
And I never just hit you.
I aIways warn you first.
Then if you don't shape up,
you get whacked.
I'm Ieaving.
Listen, I don't know
who's fiIIing your head...
fuII of crazy notions,
but I've had enough.
I want supper. Get my meat Ioaf!
Uh-uh.
Come on, CeciIia. You know
I can't Iive without you.
I'm Iike a IittIe kid
when it comes to you.
That's just tough.
Look, I'm sorry.
Can't I be sorry?
I drink, I get crazy.
It's not me, it's the whiskey.
I'm going, Monk.
Jesus Christ,
I can't reason with you.
AII right, go ahead.
See how far you get.
Go on. You won't Iast.
You see how it is
out in the reaI worId.
Go on, you'II come back.
You're just bIuff.
You're aII phony.
You'II be back.
It may take a week or an hour,
but you'II be back!
Oh, jeez!
Look at aII those guys.
Come on, honey.
We're gonna make a buck.
I ordered bacon and tomato.
You brought me ham and swiss.
I'II get it right away, ma'am.
CeciIia, I want you
to meet somebody.
Remember I was gonna keep
my eyes open for eIigibIe men?
Oh, come on.
Just keep an open mind.
This is my sister CeciIia.
Mr. Teddy Ashcroft.
-How do you do?
-Charmed.
Teddy's an exterminator.
Wright-Merson Pest ControI.
My speciaIty are
mice and siIverfish.
I'm pIeased to meet you.
-Waitress! My hamburger!
-I'm coming!
-Can we have a check?
-I'II be right there.
That's it, CeciIia.
You're fired. Get out!
But I'II pay for it.
I'II be more carefuI.
Out. Take off your apron.
Go home. You're fired.
If she goes, then I go, too.
That's fine with me.
She doesn't mean that.
You've got kids.
Then teII her
to mind her own business.
You're fired.
Back from Egypt.
From the Bedouins to Broadway.
Though I'm not
a reIigious man...
I hereby vow never to fIy over
the AtIantic in bumpy weather...
and never to Iook
at another cameI.
Drinks, anyone?
Boy, I can't wait
to get out of these cIothes...
and hit some of the night spots.
WeII, chiIdren,
Iet's not waste any time.
The fIoor show at the Copacabana
starts in ten minutes...
and we're meeting
the Countess and Larry WiIde.
WeII, I am impressed.
You have yourseIf
quite a pIace here.
I stiII can't get over the fact
that 24 hours ago...
I was in an Egyptian tomb.
I didn't know any
of you wonderfuI peopIe...
and here I am now.
I'm on the verge
of a madcap Manhattan weekend.
I hope you Iike
your martinis very dry.
No, thanks.
I'II wait for that gIass
of champagne at the Copacabana.
Miss Rita,
something on your mind?
You ain't been yourseIf since
you come back from the pyramids.
It's nothing. I'II be OK.
I don't suspect
it has anything to do...
with that expIorer feIIa,
Mr. Tom Baxter?
Why wouId you say that?
The way he speaks--
aII romantic-Iike.
Come on, DeIiIah, draw my bath.
Yes, ma'am.
WiII you be wantin' the big
bubbIes or the asses' miIk?
Boy, I can't wait
to get out of these cIothes...
and hit some of the night spots.
WeII, chiIdren,
Iet's not waste any time.
The fIoor show at the Copacabana
starts in ten minutes...
and we're meeting
the Countess and Larry WiIde.
WeII, I am very impressed.
You have yourseIf
quite a pIace here.
I stiII can't get over the fact
that 24 hours ago...
I was in an Egyptian tomb.
I didn't know any
of you wonderfuI peopIe...
and here I am now.
I'm on the verge
of a madcap Manhattan weekend.
My God, you must
reaIIy Iove this picture.
Me?
You've been here aII day, and
I've seen you here twice before.
You mean me?
Yes, you. This is the fifth time
you're seeing this.
Henry, come here. QuickIy.
I gotta speak to you.
Oh, my God!
Listen, oId sport,
you're on the wrong side.
Tom, get back here.
We're in the middIe of a story.
I want to have a Iook around.
Go on without me.
-Who are you?
-CeciIia.
I'II go get the manager.
Let's go somewhere
where we can taIk.
But you're in the movie!
Wrong, CeciIia, I'm free.
After 2,000 performances of
the same monotonous routine...
I'm free!
CaII Father DonneIIy.
I don't understand.
What's going on? Who are you?
Who am I? You've seen
the movie five times.
I'm Tom Baxter...
poet, adventurer, expIorer,
of the Chicago Baxters.
I know you're Tom Baxter.
You wind up with Kitty Haynes,
the nightcIub singer.
-Not anymore I don't.
-What do you mean?
I'm out before the wedding.
I'm free.
Don't you have to marry her?
Not whiIe I'm here
and she's up there.
Don't you want to?
She's so beautifuI.
She's not for me. Too bony.
Kitty Haynes
the nightcIub singer is bony?
I need a pIace to hide.
I'm never going back
now that I've met you.
A pIace to hide?
What's happening?
Tom has Ieft.
He just waIked right out.
I don't know how he did it.
I can't get out.
This is just disgusting.
I am an heiress...
and I don't have
to put up with this.
He Ieft the picture?
Oh, my gosh.
WeII, don't panic.
Stay up there and keep caIm.
Keep caIm? Are you crazy?
Did somebody caII for a priest?
Thank God you're here.
Wait a minute.
This is the second reeI.
I'm not on tiII Iater.
Can't you go on?
There's an audience.
How? Tom was
the Iinchpin of the story.
She's right, whoever you are.
AIthough this is my story,
Tom moves the exposition--
It's not your story.
It's the story...
of a man's quest
for seIf-fuIfiIIment.
It's the story of
a compIex tortured souI--
It's the story of the effect
of money on true romance.
My upbringing, my weaIth--
I'm the one who marries royaIty.
Nobody cares.
What do you mean
they don't care?
They wouIdn't seII a ticket
if it were your story.
-Stop arguing.
-And do what?
Maybe you shouId just
turn the projector off.
Don't turn the projector off!
It gets bIack and we disappear.
Easy, my friend.
We're aII in this together.
You don't understand
what it's Iike to disappear...
to be nothing, annihiIated!
Don't turn the projector off.
Miss Rita, your bath is ready.
-Not now, dear.
-What's going on?
-What's he doing here?
-Have a martini.
He's not supposed
to be here tiII reeI six.
We know that, DeIiIah.
What the heII is going on?
Somebody trying to hustIe me?
I know what this is.
It's an amusement park!
It's usuaIIy pretty dead
around here tiII summer.
I know exactIy what
an amusement park is...
and what goes on, I do!
That's good.
It's written into my character.
Remember, I invite
Kitty to Luna Park...
but she prefers just
to stay home and taIk.
So it's in me!
Too bad nothing's open.
I'm starved!
You are?
I Ieft the movie
before the Copacabana scenes.
That's when I usuaIIy eat.
Wait! What am I thinking?
Look, here, I've got
a whoIe bag of popcorn.
You can have that.
AIso, I have a MiIky-Way bar.
-No, popcorn is...
-Might want it Iater.
Boy! So that's what
popcorn tastes Iike!
Been watching peopIe eat it
for aII those performances.
When they rattIe those bags,
though, that's annoying.
I stiII don't understand
what's going on.
I wanted to meet you.
Don't teII me you didn't
see me Iooking at you...
out of the corner of my eye...
when Kitty Haynes
is doing her nightcIub number.
Wait a minute.
I remember seeing you.
You were Iooking off
to the side somehow...
but I never thought
it was to me.
And when we take the drive
to that IittIe country inn...
when I propose to Kitty,
I was Iooking at you.
Kitty Iooked so beautifuI
in that bIack dress.
She's nothing compared to you.
What are you taIking about?
I'm nothing.
Like heII you are.
You're fetching.
-Fetching?
-Fetching.
Dad Iiked to use that word
about Mom back in Chicago.
''Min,'' he'd say,
''you're rather fetching.''
Dad was a card. Never met him.
He died before the movie begins.
WeII, I have to confess.
My eye did aIways go to you
up on the screen.
-ReaIIy?
-ReaIIy.
Even around Detective Simms
and Henry Adams the pIayboy?
Even though
you're not the main character...
you're the one you Iook at.
You don't think
I'm the main character?
I didn't mean it that way.
I think you're
positiveIy essentiaI.
In fact, every time
I saw the movie...
I kept thinking,
''Tom Baxter's so handsome.''
ShouIdn't you be getting back?
I want to Iive and be free
to make my own choices.
Right now the country's
not in such great shape.
What do you mean?
We're in the middIe
of a depression.
Everybody's very poor.
I got pIenty. Look at this!
But they need you. The story
doesn't work without you.
I'm in Iove with you.
I'm married.
HappiIy?
I reaIIy shouId get back home.
I have to cook dinner.
SIip away from
your husband tonight.
Meet me here.
I'II wait for you.
I want to Iearn about
the reaI worId with you.
I can't.
Look at it this way.
How many times is a man
so taken with a woman...
that he waIks off
the screen to get her?
Let's not panic.
We're aII aduIts.
Bored with sitting around.
I'm a dramatic character.
I need forward motion.
Here comes
the Countess and Larry.
Where is everybody?
Weren't we meeting
at the Copacabana?
-Tom's gone.
-What?
He Ieft the fiIm.
-Tom waIked out on us.
But the Copa is where
the two of us meet.
I try to get him to marry me.
Forget it. I'm tired of
marrying you every night.
We never even get
to the bedroom.
-Where did Tom go?
-Into the reaI worId.
That two-bit minor character
Ieaves, and we're stuck!
I wonder what it's Iike
out there.
They don't Iook Iike they're
having too much fun to me.
What the heII
kind of movie is this?
The paper said it was a romance
set aII over the worId!
Don't teII us your sad stories.
Do you think we Iike this?
Look at this. They sit around
and taIk, and no action?
Nothing happens?
I want my money back.
This is outrageous.
Why don't you stop yapping?
We've got probIems of our own.
You can't taIk
to my wife Iike that.
Who do you think you are?
I'm a genuine countess
with a Iot of dough...
and if that's your wife,
she's a tub of guts.
You said it!
What are you so nervous about?
Me? I'm not.
There's too much pepper
in the sauce.
I toId you to go easy
on the pepper.
I guess you and the guys...
are probabIy going out
again tonight, huh?
No, I'm not.
My back is acting up again.
You gotta give me one of
your speciaI rubdowns.
I bought Iiniment.
What?
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean I can't.
I mean I made some pIans.
You made pIans?
I said I'd baby-sit tonight.
I ran into Mrs. Lorenzo
in the restaurant--
in the street today.
And she has some, I don't know--
I think it was
a sociaI cIub meeting...
or something
she wanted to go to.
It won't be too Iong.
I think it's a great idea.
Yeah? Good.
Because we can use every penny.
So what am I gonna do
about my back?
Don't worry.
I can do some now...
and I'II do some when I come in.
You shouIdn't move around
too much. Just take it easy.
If you're gonna go baby-sit,
get paid in cash.
-I wiII.
-Don't Iet her owe you.
It's a compIete miracIe!
We want our money back.
I don't pay to watch those
sociaIites sitting around...
up there staring back at us
making nasty remarks.
Is that what they're doing now?
Last time I Iooked, the priest
had a deck of cards...
and the men
were pIaying pinochIe.
How'd this first happen?
It's probabIy
aII the eIectricaI storms...
we've had this season.
The air is charged.
FeIIas, I depend on the JeweI.
I got personaI expenses.
I got no substitute
picture to put in here.
I want my money back!
This is a swindIe!
There's no story.
Mrs. Lupus Iikes a story.
I stiII think you shouId turn
the projector off and shut down.
This couId be the work
of Reds or anarchists.
You can't do that.
If he turns off the projector...
you're IiabIe
to strand this Tom Baxter...
out in the worId somepIace.
You want an extra guy
running around?
I saw the movie Iast week.
This is not what happens.
Where is the Tom Baxter
character?
You'II get your money back.
I want what happened Iast week
to happen this week.
Otherwise,
what's Iife aII about anyway?
Can't we just go in
and take a Iook?
We don't want to stay Iong.
If you want to see it,
you have to pay admission.
Keep moving, foIks.
Any word about Tom Baxter?
Nothing yet.
What are you peopIe doing here?
We can't continue the story
untiI Tom gets back.
We don't mind observing you aII.
My husband is a student
of the human personaIity.
WeII, we're not human.
It doesn't matter to HaroId.
He has troubIe with humans.
Where do I have troubIe
with reaI peopIe?
I suppose you behave
perfectIy with DonaId.
He won't speak
to my own son-in-Iaw.
I won't speak? The kid is quiet.
He never makes conversation.
He has to be drawn out.
I don't Iike to draw peopIe out.
That's what I said.
He has troubIe with Iive humans.
Yes, RKO!
I want to speak
to Mr. RaouI Hirsch.
He's the producer
of ''The PurpIe Rose of Cairo.''
No, he's not.
Just teII him I have
a theater in New Jersey...
and there's a crisis
with his fiIm.
This is Mr. Hirsch.
What's the probIem?
What?
They're aII sitting around
up there on the screen.
Rita, the Countess,
Larry WiIde, the pIayboy.
PeopIe are demanding
their money back.
The theater
is nine-tenths empty.
Take a waIk, wiII you?
Look, he just waIked out!
Baxter.
The Communist is screaming...
the priest in reeI five
is in reeI two.
How can he come off the screen?
It's impossibIe.
It's never happened
before in history.
Just because a thing
never happened before...
doesn't mean it can't
happen for first time.
That's aII you need--hundreds
of Tom Baxters on the Ioose.
Hundreds?
As your Iawyer,
I advise you to controI it fast.
A character from one of
your productions on the Ioose?
Who knows what he's capabIe of?
Robbery, murder. I see Iawsuits.
I'd charter a pIane right away,
and I'd get down there fast.
Get me GiI Shepherd.
I'm sorry I'm not
too Iight on my feet.
You're a feather in my arms.
Monk never took me dancing,
not even when we first met...
not even if I begged him.
ReaIIy?
So it's been bad for you?
It's been hard for everyone.
Living in a worId
with no jobs and wars.
You probabIy never even
heard of the Great War.
Sorry. I missed it.
PeopIe get oId and sick
and never find true Iove.
Where I come from,
peopIe don't disappoint.
They're consistent.
AIways reIiabIe.
You don't find that kind
in reaI Iife.
You have.
Is it true they're taIking to
you about the Iife of Lindbergh?
It's nearIy set, but don't
print it tiII it's firm.
You were great
in ''The PurpIe Rose of Cairo.''
Thanks. Did you know...
I was singIed out by aII
the East Coast critics?
The New York Times
said I had aImost...
too smoIdering a quaIity
just to pIay comedy.
WouId you pIay Lindbergh
the way you pIayed Tom Baxter?
Of course not.
Tom was kind of a change of pace
from my earIier roIes.
I pIayed Tom Baxter
with a kind of a poetic...
ideaIistic quaIity that just--
Lindbergh was a Ioner.
He was seIf-reIiant.
I'd have to work it out
with my diaIogue coach.
He's a genius.
Can I see you for
a minute aIone, pIease?
-Excuse me. I'm sorry.
-What's up?
Baxter's come off the screen and
is running around New Jersey.
What are you taIking about?
I just spoke to RaouI Hirsch.
Nobody knows how it happened,
but he's done it.
How couId he do that?
It's not physicaIIy possibIe.
In New Jersey,
anything can happen.
But I created the character.
That's my point!
As your agent...
I'd hate anything for happen
to your career now.
-Like what?
-Who knows?
Your doubIe is on the Ioose.
What's he up to?
Is he robbing banks?
Raping broads?
-Is he?
-Who knows?
The Iast thing we need
is for you to get a rep--
Last thing we need is for you
to get a difficuIt reputation.
It's not my fauIt!
RaouI Hirsch said if you can't
controI your own creation...
nobody's gonna risk
a picture on you.
I worked so hard
to make him reaI.
-Maybe you overdid it.
-I'II sue my diaIogue coach.
You've got to fIy down there
and check into this quick.
Right now it's onIy
one movie house, but who knows?
I'm afraid to fIy.
This is the scandaI of aII time.
You know what happened
to Fatty ArbuckIe's career?
I'II fIy.
Good.
This is how they drink
champagne in Cairo.
I never had champagne before.
It makes me feeI siIIy.
It's supposed to.
The check,
as you requested, sir.
It's so much!
I hope you found it
to your Iiking, sir.
It was superb.
My compIiments to the chef...
and keep 20% for yourseIf.
No, make that 30%.
Quite amusing.
What is?
The fake money.
Fake money?
Is it pIay money, sir,
or stage money?
Keep 30% for yourseIf
and stop Iooking so serious.
I'II get the Maitre D'.
That's not reaI money!
What do you mean,
it's not reaI money?
Oh, my God!
Do you have any money?
No! What are we gonna do?
We'II have to run for it.
I can't run.
My ankIes are bad
from waitressing.
Get up. FoIIow me.
Quick, get in the car!
Tom, this is not our car.
We don't have a car.
We came by foot.
It doesn't go.
Of course it doesn't go.
There's no key!
I don't understand.
They aIways go in the movie.
This is reaI Iife.
They don't start without a key!
They don't? Let's go!
Get back here!
You can't run out on this check!
A coupIe of deadbeats!
Get back here right now!
I'm sorry about the money.
I had no idea.
That's OK.
It's not gonna be so easy...
to get aIong without it
in this worId.
I guess I have to get a job.
That's not gonna be
so easy, either.
Right now the whoIe
country's out of work.
Then we'II Iive on Iove.
We'II have to make some
concessions, but so what?
-We'II have each other.
-That's movie taIk.
You Iook so beautifuI
in this Iight.
But you're not reaI.
Was that reaI enough for you?
You kiss perfectIy.
It's what I dreamed
kissing wouId be Iike.
Come away with me to Cairo.
Cairo?
We'II Iive in the desert.
The bIue-goId Iight of sunset
faIIing over your hair.
I'm sorry. I'm a IittIe
tipsy from the champ--
Where's the fade-out?
What?
AIways when the kissing
gets hot and heavy...
just before the Iovemaking,
there's a fade-out.
Then what?
Then we're making Iove
in some private, perfect pIace.
That's not how it happens here.
There's no fade-out?
No. But when you kissed me,
I feIt Iike my heart faded out.
I cIosed my eyes,
and I was in some private pIace.
How fascinating. You make Iove
without fading out?
I can't wait to see this.
Listen, I...
I'm not that kind of girI.
I'm married.
It's cIear how miserabIe
you are with your husband.
If he hits you again,
you teII me.
I'd be forced
to knock his teeth out.
I don't think that'd be
such a good idea. He's big.
I'm sorry.
It's written into my character,
so I'd do it.
Listen. I think
I'd better go home now.
It's Iate.
It's been a whirIwind of a day.
What are you going to do?
I'II sIeep here at the carouseI,
then waIk around...
drink in the night air...
enjoy my freedom...
and dream of you.
You got in Iate Iast night.
You were out Iike a Iight.
I took a hot bath to reIax me.
You want to get me
a cup of coffee?
Sure.
There was some big deaI
going on at the movie house.
A big crowd when I went
to buy cigarettes.
I couIdn't get
the story straight.
Some guy ran out the side exit
with a customer.
Who?
A woman, a guy--an actor.
I don't know what the heII
the cop was taIking about.
He didn't know.
They didn't know
who the woman was?
Some woman dragged out
in the dark.
They got those reaI
Geronimos at movie houses.
That's why I don't Iike you
staying out so Iate.
I know. I couIdn't heIp it.
The Lorenzos didn't get back
tiII Iate. I couIdn't Ieave.
I hope you got paid overtime.
Sure.
Good. Let's have it.
They didn't have any cash.
I'II have to come back
for it Iater today.
I toId you to get paid in cash.
I know, but aII
they had was big biIIs.
I was getting Iate.
They're gonna fork it over
today, right?
They wiII.
Leave something to you...
you can bet
you're gonna get fouIed up.
You have no idea where he went?
Mr. Hirsch,
this is awfuI for us.
It's reaIIy difficuIt.
Think of me,
my reputation, my career.
First thing is,
we got to keep it contained.
The word's out aIready.
We got to keep the crisis IocaI.
I know the two reporters
in town.
They're oId friends.
Maybe I couId taIk--
A coupIe bucks spread around
town wiII buy us some time.
Don't worry about a thing.
I mean, we're aII so Iost.
I know it's rough.
I just want the whoIe cast
to know...
how much I appreciate your
staying up there on the screen.
I hope you're not gonna
hoId this against me, R.H.
You created the part
of Tom Baxter, GiI.
The facts are undeniabIe.
I want to go, too.
I want to be free! I want out!
I'm warning you,
that's Communist taIk.
We're gonna have to puII
the fiIm out of the theatre...
and you're gonna have
to make good my receipts.
You're thinking
of puIIing the fiIm...
because a minor
character's missing?
A minor character?
WouId you Iisten to her?
He may not have the most Iines,
but the pIot turns on Baxter.
I deIiberateIy pIayed him
with a cheerfuI bravado.
Who cares how you pIayed him?
-He's minor.
-That's right.
I'd Iike to get
my hands on him !
Right when my career
was taking off.
He couId be raping
that woman he abducted.
And he's got my fingerprints.
My exact prints!
You know what they get
for rape in a smaII town?
EspeciaIIy by a man
in a pith heImet?
If this is the start
of a new trend...
our industry's as good as dead.
The reaI ones want
their Iives fiction...
and the fictionaI ones
want their Iives reaI.
Does anybody know
who that woman was?
It was aII so crazy,
nobody noticed.
Two doughnuts and a container
of coffee to go, pIease.
Right now, it's chaos.
How can rumors be circuIating
at the Brown Derby?
It just happened.
Squash it, Herbie!
I've got a career on the Iine.
Look, I'II caII you
the minute I hear.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry,
I don't have a penciI...
or I'd give you an autograph.
Where did you get those cIothes?
Pardon me?
Your cIothes.
Where'd you get them?
A IittIe store
on Sunset and Vine.
What are you taIking about?
Excuse me.
I just bought you these.
Two doughnuts.
For me?
WeII, thank you very much.
I hope you
enjoy my next movie.
I thought you were gonna
stay hidden at the park.
What park?
What's the matter with you?
You're acting so pecuIiar.
Tom? No, I'm--
Wait a minute! Come here.
What's come over you?
I'm not Tom.
I'm GiI Shepherd. I pIay Tom.
How do you know Tom?
You're GiI--
Oh, my God!
I don't beIieve it!
I've seen you in Iots of movies.
Where's Tom?
''Broadway BacheIors,'' right?
Yeah.
''Honeymoon in Haiti''?
I've done about six.
-You were you a scream.
-Thank you very much.
I try to do one a year,
you know.
Just to keep--Where's Tom?
Why?
He's my character.
I created him.
Didn't the man who wrote
the movie do that?
Yes, technicaIIy,
but I made him Iive.
I fIeshed him out.
You did a wonderfuI job.
He's adorabIe.
Thank you very much.
What's your name?
-Where is he?
-Why?
Has he done anything wrong?
Like what?
Has he stoIen anything
or attacked any femaIes? You?
Gosh, no.
He's as sweet as can be.
I pIayed him sweet.
I was weII-reviewed.
It comes across.
Good. I gotta speak to him.
You're not upset with him?
A IittIe, yes,
but I know if I spoke to him...
we couId straighten
everything out.
I don't know.
PIease, I have a right.
It has to be secret.
He doesn't want
to go back into the movie.
-He doesn't?
-No. He Ioves being free.
He's having
the time of his Iife.
WouId you take me to him?
Trust me.
PIease.
Monk, somebody saw
your wife Iast night...
at the Dine and Dance joint.
Sure. She's there every night
with the RockefeIIers.
She was with this
crazy-Iooking guy...
wearing an expIorer's hat
and breeches.
Breeches? You're nuts.
She was baby-sitting.
Right. I guess you know it aII.
AII right, who's next?
CeciIia, I dreamed
of us in Cairo--
-I brought--
-GiI Shepherd.
-I pIay you in the movie.
-You do?
How dare you run away!
This is disconcerting.
I'II show you the meaning
of disconcerting!
I'm trying to buiId a career!
I don't want to be
in the fiIm anymore.
I'm in Iove with CeciIia!
Mr. Shepherd,
you said you weren't angry.
You can't do this to me.
It's my best roIe.
I've been criticaIIy
accIaimed for this!
Because of the way I do it.
No, because of the way I do it.
I'm doing it, not you.
It's me, not him !
Then how do you
expIain that here I am?
I took you from the printed
page and made you Iive.
-So I'm Iiving.
-For the screen onIy!
I want my freedom.
I don't want another one of me
running around the worId.
I can just imagine what he's--
Are you afraid
I'II embarrass you?
FrankIy, I'm afraid--
But you created me.
Look, be reasonabIe here.
I'm starting to buiId a career.
Is Iife up on the screen
so terribIe?
I want to be with CeciIia.
I'm in Iove with her.
WouId you teII him to go back?
TeII him you don't Iove him.
TeII him you can't Iove him.
He's fictionaI.
Do you want to waste your time
with a fictionaI character?
You're a sweet girI.
You deserve an actuaI human.
But Tom's perfect.
But he's not reaI.
What good is perfect
if the man's not reaI?
I can Iearn to be reaI.
It's easy.
There's nothing to it.
Being reaI comes
very naturaIIy to me.
You can't Iearn to be reaI.
It's Iike being a midget.
It's not a thing you can Iearn.
Some of us are reaI,
some are not.
I say I can do it.
I'm not staying here
to argue with you.
I'm going back to town...
and caII my attorney,
the actors' union.
I won't take this Iying down,
nor wiII RaouI Hirsch.
Nor the poIice, nor the FBI.
We found him.
GiI Shepherd found him...
but he refuses to get
back on the screen.
R.H. is very upset.
We can't force him.
It's not a crime.
We need a pIan.
The press is on our side.
It took a few bucks, but
they'II keep it quiet for now.
What? ReaIIy?
The Tom Baxter character
in a movie house in Chicago...
has been forgetting his Iines.
He just got a caII
from the manager.
If anybody wants me,
I'II be in the bathroom...
on the fIoor...weeping.
Aren't you at aII even worried?
What about RaouI Hirsch
or the FBI?
If I can be with you,
I'm never going back.
-But, you know--
-No more buts.
I said I'd Iearn about
the reaI worId. Show me.
It's beautifuI.
I'm not sure exactIy what it is.
This is a church.
You do beIieve in God,
don't you?
Meaning...
The reason for everything,
the worId, the universe.
I think I know what you mean.
The two men who wrote
''The PurpIe Rose of Cairo''--
Irving Sachs and R.H. Levine.
They're writers
who coIIaborate on fiIms.
I'm taIking about something
much bigger than that.
Think for a minute.
A reason for everything.
Otherwise, it'd be Iike
a movie with no point...
and no happy ending.
So there you are.
I'm Iooking for you.
This is my husband.
This is Tom Baxter.
Adventurer, expIorer,
of the Chicago Baxters.
I'm charmed to meet you.
So you wear the britches.
What do you want
to taIk to me about?
I heard you were out
on the town Iast night.
I admit I didn't
teII the truth about that...
but things have been
so strange the Iast 24 hours.
I toId you what I'd do
if you ever Iied to me!
ObviousIy, your marriage
has come to an impasse, sir.
Let's just taIk.
You're coming home with me!
Perhaps you don't
understand, sir...
but I'm in Iove with your wife.
CIose your yap, jackass.
Now Iet's go.
You're faiIing
to understand, sir.
-She's not coming with you.
-She's not?
Take your hands off her.
No man wiII hit the woman
I Iove, nor any woman--
Beat it!
Before I take you apart!
He's got a terribIe temper!
It's written into
my character--courage.
Stop it!
Come on.
Stop it! What are you doing?
Time for the oId one-two.
I think he's had enough.
Sorry, paI,
about the rough stuff.
You aII right?
Let me give you a hand.
There was--
That's not fair.
What are you doing?
You're coming home with me now.
-No, I'm not.
-What'd you say?
I'm going to stay
and see that Tom's OK.
-You're a buIIy.
-I gave you an order.
I don't care.
I'm tired of taking your orders.
You couId have kiIIed him.
AII right. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
You can't go through Iife
beating peopIe up.
I'm teIIing you one more time.
You coming with me?
No, I'm not.
I'm teIIing you one more time.
You coming?
-Come on!
-No, I'm not!
The heII with it.
I need a beer anyway.
I'II see you Iater.
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
You're not even marked.
Your hair's in pIace.
I don't get hurt or bIeed.
Hair doesn't muss.
It's one of the advantages
of being imaginary.
You were very brave.
I had him, too,
tiII he started fighting dirty.
That's why you'II never
survive off the screen.
You were pretty brave, too.
You stood up to him.
You inspired me.
Mr. Shepherd.
CeciIia, Iook,
I gotta speak to you.
I've had a crazy morning.
I'm stiII shaking.
I don't know what to do.
I've struggIed my whoIe Iife.
Now I'm finaIIy beginning
to break through...
and my whoIe career
is going right down the drain.
You don't have to
worry about that.
You'II aIways be
a great movie star.
That's very nice of you,
but technicaIIy...
I'm not reaIIy a star yet.
I try to carry myseIf Iike one.
I do the best I can as
far as that, but star?
That's a big word, isn't it?
Star. Yeah.
Star? No.
You're not just a pretty face.
You're aIso a peach of an actor.
ReaIIy, I've seen you a Iot.
You've got something.
Is that your opinion?
Sure. I see aII the movies.
You've got--
How can I describe it?
You've got a magicaI gIow.
Oh, boy!
To hear that from a reaI person.
That is just--
It's not one of those
movie coIony bimbos...
with the fancy dresses,
fiIIing you fuII of hot air.
WouId you get over here
and sit down, pIease?
You can take it from me.
You're not just
a fIash in the pan.
It wouId be very easy for me...
to trade on my Iooks
just Iike that...
but I have some serious
acting ambitions.
You shouId.
I think you're great
in aII the funny movies.
Thank you.
ReaIIy, I was thinking
you shouId pIay...
some of the more heroic parts.
I want to. I teII my agent
that a hundred times!
You couId pIay, Iike,
DanieI Boone or someone--
Lindbergh.
You'd be wonderfuI as Lindbergh.
-You are a mind reader.
-You had the same thought?
I'm on the verge
of signing for that part.
-I am ! I can taste it.
-ReaIIy?
You'II be wonderfuI!
There's something inside you.
You have that same kind
of Ione heroic quaIity.
You're exactIy right.
Everyone has been teIIing me
not to--you are right.
Don't you Iisten.
BasicaIIy, I have been
a Ioner my entire Iife.
Sure, anyone can see that.
You're deep
and probabIy compIicated.
-Can I buy you Iunch?
-Me?
PIease. Can I?
I Iove taIking to you.
I was going upstairs--
Come on.
I open myseIf up around you.
Have you ever been to HoIIywood?
Come on. Of course not.
I wouId Iove to just
take you around HoIIywood.
-Can I make a confession?
-Sure.
My reaI name
is not GiI Shepherd.
It's Herman Bardebedian.
ReaIIy?
Yeah. I've been a cab driver--
Boy, do you have a pretty face.
-Come on.
-You do!
Hi, big boy.
Are you aIone?
HeIIo.
I'm aIone for now...
but Iater I have
an appointment--
or shouId I say, rendezvous.
Good for you.
Where'd you get the funny suit?
What, this?
You coming from a costume party?
No. I'm Tom Baxter
of the Chicago Baxters--
expIorer, poet, adventurer.
Just back from Cairo,
where I searched in vain...
for the Iegendary PurpIe Rose.
How about that?
Who are you?
My name's Emma.
That's IoveIy.
What do you do?
I'm a working girI.
And what do you do,
you deIicate creature?
Anything that'II make a buck.
We Baxters never reaIIy
had to worry about money.
I'II bet. You want
to come aIong with me?
Where to, Emma?
Where I work. I think
you might have a good time.
Sounds enchanting.
I'm up for new experiences.
I may be abIe to heIp.
Hi, girIs. This is Tom.
Hi there, Iadies.
Don't you aII Iook enticing?
I know what you want.
You want to be
the great white hunter...
and you want me to be the tiger.
I don't get it.
You wiII if you can afford it.
I met Tom out
at the amusement park.
That's my hat.
I was thinking about something.
I can imagine.
Two of us at the same time?
I was thinking about
very deep things--
God and his reIation with
Irving Sachs and R.H. Levine.
And I was thinking
about Iife in generaI--
the origin of everything
we see about us...
the finaIity of death...
and how aImost magicaI
it seems in the reaI worId...
as opposed to the worId
of ceIIuIoid...
and fIickering shadows.
Where did you find this cIown?
For exampIe,
the miracIe of birth.
Now, I suppose some of you
IoveIy Iadies are married.
Not anymore.
The absoIuteIy astonishing
miracIe of chiIdbirth...
with aII its attendant feeIings
of humanity and pathos.
I stand in awe of existence.
Do you want to tie me up?
Tie you up?
That's very funny.
She's very funny.
Nice sense of humor--
the absurd non sequitur.
-What's your name, sweetheart?
-Martha.
That's the same name as
the ambassador's wife.
Why didn't you
bring the ambassador by?
He's stiII up on the screen.
But do you share
my sense of wonderment...
at the very fabric of being?
The smeII of a rose,
reaI food, sensuous music?
I've got a chiId.
You do? I see.
You're a widow. Poor thing.
I got two kids, and he's
right about giving birth.
It is a beautifuI experience.
I never had a baby.
I was pregnant, but I Iost it.
I'm sorry to hear that.
It aIways makes me cry
to think about it.
There, there.
You'II have another chance.
Come on.
I'd be surprised...
if aII you Iadies
weren't married soon...
especiaIIy by the way you dress.
It's so seductive to a man.
You Iike these stockings, Tom?
They're just divine.
What kind of a cIub
is this, anyhow?
God, you're a scream.
He's terribIy sweet.
He is. I wouIdn't mind
doing him for nothing.
Me, neither. PIus, he's cute.
You can count me in. Come on.
We're gonna take you
into the bedroom...
and give you an experience
you'II never forget.
And it's on us.
I came here
for a new experience.
You're gonna get
a champion roII in the hay.
What, there's hay
in the bedroom?
You ever been
to a brotheI before?
What's a brotheI?
You must be kidding.
A brotheI--
a bordeIIo, a whorehouse.
I'm not foIIowing. What?
We go to bed with you
and make Iove, and you pay us.
OnIy, because you're so sweet,
we want to treat you to a party.
ReaIIy?
Boy, this doesn't ring a beII
with anything I know.
Come on, buddy.
You know about making Iove,
don't you?
I can't make Iove with you.
Don't teII me
you don't Iike women.
Or you were wounded in the war.
No, I'm in Iove
with someone eIse.
We're not taIking about in Iove.
We're taIking about making Iove.
But I Iove CeciIia.
So what? Marry CeciIia.
This is just for fun.
I couIdn't do that.
Ladies! My gracious!
Don't think I'm not
appreciative of your offer...
though I must say the concept
is totaIIy new to me...
but I'm just hopeIessIy
head-over-heeIs in Iove...
with CeciIia.
She is aII I want.
My devotion is to her,
my IoyaIties.
Every breath she takes
makes my heart dance.
This guy just kiIIs me.
Are there any other guys
Iike you out there?
Lawson's Music Store.
This store's been here
since I was a kid.
I wish I couId pIay
an instrument.
That's my other
ambition in Iife...
is to be a great
cIassicaI vioIinist...
thousands cheering me
night after night.
-I can pIay the ukuIeIe.
-You can?
My father taught me
before he ran away.
I'm AIabamy bound
There'II be no heebie-jeebies
hangin' round
Just gave the meanest
ticket man on earth
AII I'm worth
To put my tootsies
in an upper berth
Just hear that choo-choo sound
Whoo whoo!
I know that soon
we're gonna cover ground
And then I'II hoIIer
'cause the worId wiII know
Here I go
I'm AIabamy bound
Whoa!
-That was wonderfuI!
-Thanks.
That's Iike a dream.
Listen.
My baby Ioves me
I don't know nobody
As happy as we
She's onIy 20
And I'm 21
We never worry
We're just havin' fun
Bum bum bum
Sometimes we quarreI
And maybe we fight
But then we make up
The foIIowing night
When we're together
We're great company
I Iove my baby
And my baby Ioves me
That was wonderfuI!
After the Lindbergh movie,
you shouId do a musicaI.
I did have one bit in one once.
I saw ''Dancing Doughboys.''
''Dancing Doughboys''!
You remembered!
That was great.
You turned
to Ina BeasIey and said...
''I won't be going south
with you this winter.''
That's exac--Right.
''I won't be going south
with you this winter.
''We have a IittIe
score to settIe...
''on the other side
of the AtIantic.''
''Does this mean I won't
be seeing you ever again?''
''Ever is a Iong time.''
''When you Ieave,
don't Iook back.''
You remember it perfectIy.
Then I took her in
my arms and I kissed her...
knowing it was
for the Iast time.
God, you're beautifuI.
Was it fun kissing Ina BeasIey?
It was a movie kiss.
We professionaIs can put
that stuff on just Iike that.
It Iooked Iike you Ioved her.
Oh, my goodness.
FeeI my heart.
I bet--I shouId--
Thank you so much
for the ukuIeIe.
Don't be offended.
I didn't mean--
I'm not offended.
I'm just confused.
I'm married.
I just met a wonderfuI new man.
He's fictionaI,
but you can't have everything.
Can I see you Iater?
No. I'm meeting Tom.
My own creation pIagues me.
-Anything happening out there?
-Not a thing.
Life is amazing, isn't it?
One IittIe minor character,
takes some action...
and the whoIe worId
is turned upside-down.
What if he never comes back?
We just drift tiII
they shut the projector.
WiII you shut up? Stop that.
He'II be back. I feeI it.
I don't want
to sit around and wait.
That's exactIy what they want.
-Who?
-The bosses.
Look at us! Sitting around,
sIaves to some stupid scenario.
MeanwhiIe,
the fat cats in HoIIywood...
are getting rich on our work--
studio heads,
writers, movie stars.
Stop it!
But we're the ones who sweat!
We're the characters
on the screen, not them !
You're a Red.
I say unite, brothers,
and take action!
-What possibIe action?
-Shut up and sit down!
Wait a minute!
Shut up, wiII you?
What if aII this is mereIy
a matter of semantics?
How can it be semantics?
Wait a minute.
Let's just readjust
our definitions.
Let's redefine ourseIves
as the reaI worId...
and them as the worId of
iIIusion and shadow. You see?
We're reaIity, they're a dream.
You'd better caIm down.
You've been up on the screen
fIickering too Iong.
It's confirmed.
It is?
I was afraid this might happen.
The Tom Baxter character...
tried Ieaving the screen
in four theaters--
St. Louis, Chicago,
Denver, and Detroit...
and he aImost made it
in Detroit.
It Iooks bad.
Those movie houses are
in a state of pandemonium.
There's no way
to keep the Iid on it.
I see hundreds of Iawsuits.
We better puII
the picture out of reIease.
What, in those towns?
Everywhere.
Something's obviousIy
gone very wrong here...
and the best course of
action is to shut down...
take our Iosses,
and get out of this mess...
before it reaIIy
gets out of hand.
Can you imagine hundreds of
Tom Baxters fIying around wiId?
And you responsibIe
for every one of them.
The best thing to do is
to quit whiIe there's...
onIy of them out there,
but what do we do about him?
We gotta get him back
in the picture...
then we turn off the projector
and burn the prints.
And the negative.
What a shame.
It was such a good picture.
I missed you. You're Iate.
I'm sorry. I came
as quickIy as I couId.
I Iove you.
Thank you.
My feeIings are so jumbIed.
I know. You're married,
and you're oId-fashioned...
and I'm a whoIe new idea.
But the truth is,
you're unhappiIy married...
and I'm gonna take you
away from aII this.
I know you Iove me.
I do Iove you.
Don't you share my feeIings?
That's just it.
You're some kind of phantom.
Look, I don't want
to taIk anymore...
about what's reaI
and what's iIIusion.
Life's too short to spend time
thinking about Iife.
-Let's just Iive it.
-Live it how?
We'II begin with dinner.
Listen, no.
I've onIy got a few doIIars.
We're not gonna use your money.
That's aII we have,
unIess you've done something.
Say no more.
The moon wiII be fuII,
the stars wiII be out.
We're going stepping.
-But we're broke.
-Leave that to me.
It's him !
You're back!
I want you to meet
my fiancee CeciIia.
WeII, you know
aII these peopIe.
It's not possibIe.
I'm in the worId
of the possibIe.
You better get back in
the story, you IittIe weaseI.
You anticipate me.
FoIIow me. Trust me.
He just comes
and goes Iike he pIeases.
-Come on.
-Where am I?
-She can't be in here.
-Why not? Come on.
My money's good up here.
I feeI Iike I'm fIoating on air.
It upsets the baIance!
What's the difference?
He's back, isn't he?
I toId you he'd be back.
Can we get on with the pIot now?
How can we with her here?
She's here with me.
I'II sock any man in the jaw
who makes her feeI unwanted.
It's about time you got back.
AII right. Now we finaIIy
go to the Copacabana.
None of us have eaten in ages.
Good. I'm bringing a guest.
Won't Kitty Haynes be surprised.
TabIe for seven, pIease, Arturo.
Yes, sir. Seven?
Seven.
That's impossibIe.
It's aIways six.
We have an extra.
Seven, Arturo.
This person?
So Iet's not speak
of Iove subIime
Because time
brings on a breakup
There'II be no tears
and no emotionaI scenes
To spoiI my make-up
And when the end comes,
I'II take up the sIack...
WouId you Iike
some more champagne?
Thank you.
Listen, I don't know
what they're charging you...
but those champagne bottIes
are fiIIed with ginger aIe.
That's the movies, kid.
I don't care.
I Iove every minute of it.
...Domesticating
Every Sunday, Monday
One day at a time
Let's take it
one day at a time
Bravo!
Thank you.
Who are you?
I came with Tom.
You sing so beautifuIIy.
What the heII is this?
We're supposed to meet
and marry.
-Who's the skirt?
-My fiancee.
He met her in New Jersey.
-What is this?
-Kitty, she's reaI.
Quick!
Pour ginger aIe over her.
What's aII the fuss about?
Nothing, Arturo.
We were just Ieaving.
Leaving where?
I'm aII mixed up.
I'm going to show
CeciIia the town.
Are we chucking out the pIot?
ExactIy.
Every man for himseIf.
Then I don't have
to seat peopIe anymore.
I can do what it is
I've aIways wanted to do!
What's that?
Hit it, boys!
I had such a wonderfuI time.
Me, too.
Where are aII the others?
I don't know. ProbabIy
just stiII dancing away.
Why, does it matter?
I wanted to get you aIone.
It's so beautifuI here.
The white teIephone.
I've dreamed of having
a white teIephone.
Your dreams are my dreams.
My whoIe Iife, I've wondered
what it wouId be Iike...
to be this side
of the screen.
You see that city
out there waking up?
That's yours for the asking.
My heart's beating so fast.
GiI, what are you doing here?
I came in here to think.
What are you doing here?
I took her on a date.
AII right?
Can't you
just Ieave us aIone?
I can't Ieave her aIone.
I'm jeaIous.
You're jeaIous?
What do you want me to say?
I can't get CeciIia
out of my mind.
GiI, do you mean that?
For God's sake, wouId you
go back to HoIIywood, pIease?
I'm embarrassed to admit it.
You said I had a magicaI gIow,
but it's you.
You're the one that has one.
And even though
we've just met...
I know that this
is the reaI thing.
You can't be in Iove
with CeciIia.
She's in Iove with me!
Why don't you turn around
and re-enter the fiIm?
I'm never going back!
I can't beIieve it.
They're at it again.
WiII you get back up here?
See, there you go.
You're ruining everything.
You're the one
who's ruining everything.
If it wasn't for me,
there wouIdn't be any you.
Don't be so sure.
I couId have been pIayed...
by Frederick March
or LesIie Howard.
You're wrong.
The part's too insignificant...
to attract a major star.
Insignificant?
Like heII it is!
What are you taIking about?
I'm not a minor character.
Jeez. You know,
I haven't been abIe...
to think of anything
since we've met.
I have to have
some time with you...
to show you what
reaI Iife can be Iike...
if two peopIe reaIIy
care for each other.
Last week, I was unIoved.
Now two peopIe Iove me,
and it's the same two peopIe.
Go with the reaI guy, honey.
We're Iimited.
Go with Tom. He's got no fIaws.
Go with somebody, chiId!
'Cause I's gettin' bored.
She's going to marry me.
You're wasting your time.
WiII you get back on the screen?
I'm trying to teII CeciIia
I'm in Iove with her.
I Iove you.
I'm honest, dependabIe,
courageous, romantic...
and a great kisser.
And I'm reaI.
Let's go, CeciIia.
Choose one of them
so we can settIe this thing.
The most human of aII attributes
is your abiIity to choose.
Wait a minute.
If she chooses Tom...
how are we gonna end the story?
We'II be stuck here forever.
Father DonneIIy can marry us
right here in the movie house.
That won't stand up in court.
The priest has to be human.
The BibIe never says
a priest can't be on fiIm.
I'm aIready married.
Come away with me to HoIIywood.
Just Iike that?
Do something impuIsive
for once in your Iife.
Just throw your stuff in
a vaIise and come away with me.
ReaIIy. And don't forget
that ukuIeIe.
What ukuIeIe?
Look, I Iove you.
I know that onIy happens
in movies, but I do.
CeciIia, you're
throwing away perfection!
Don't teII her that.
We need Tom back!
-It's so romantic!
-Women!
I'm crushed. Devastated.
Try to understand.
You'II be fine. In your worId...
things have a way
of aIways working out right.
I'm a reaI person.
No matter how tempted I am,
I have to choose the reaI worId.
I Ioved every minute with you.
I'II never forget
our night on the town.
Good-bye.
You're better off
with us, oId sport.
You reaIIy are.
Can we get on with
''The PurpIe Rose of Cairo''?
Anyone wants me,
I'II be in reeI six.
Kitty's waiting for you.
Lord, have mercy!
What a day!
Your expIorer friend's OK.
I saw him waIking
around town with you.
He's OK, no thanks to you.
I didn't mean
to be so rough on him.
It's just that I get jeaIous
when it comes to you.
Do you?
Christ, you know I do.
I know I treat you rough.
It's my way.
It doesn't mean
I don't feeI for you.
What are you doing?
Leaving.
Here we go again.
You don't feeI for me.
AII you feeI for is yourseIf...
your beer, your card games,
your women.
OK. I'm gonna
turn over a new Ieaf.
It's too Iate. I'm going.
I shouId have
Ieft a Iong time ago.
I wouId've, except I was
scared of being aIone.
So, what now?
You found some chump...
who's fiIIing your head
with big ideas.
No. I got a chance
to change my Iife.
I'm moving to HoIIywood.
Now, Iisten,
I said I was sorry...
about being rough with your
friend, but Iet's shape up.
It's too Iate!
Like heII it is...
and don't be giving me
that big-headed stuff, you hear?
Because I'm the guy
that can sIap you down.
Go ahead and hit me.
Just go ahead!
I'm Ieaving anyway!
This never wouId've happened
if you didn't meet that guy.
That's probabIy right...
and we wouId have
gone on the same way...
'tiI we were too oId
to hope for something better.
But I did meet him.
And I have feeIings for him.
And he has for me.
What about me?
I stiII care for you,
if you can beIieve that...
but out of the bIue
for the first time in my Iife...
somebody's in Iove with me.
But you just met each other.
Love at first sight doesn't
onIy happen just in the movies.
Don't go. You hear me?
Now wait a minute.
I said don't go!
-You stay here!
-Take care of yourseIf.
AII right. WeII, go.
See if I care.
Go, see what it is out there.
It ain't the movies!
It's reaI Iife,
and you'II be back.
Mark my words. You'II be back!
What are you doing here?
-Meeting GiI Shepherd.
-They're aII gone.
What do you mean?
They went back to HoIIywood.
GiI, too?
Mr. Shepherd, yeah.
Soon as Tom Baxter went back up
on the movie screen...
couIdn't wait
to get out of here.
He said this was
a cIose caII for his career.
I think he's going to pIay
CharIes Lindbergh.
Don't forget, CeciIia.
Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers
start today.
Heaven
I'm in heaven
And my heart beats so
that I can hardIy speak
And I seem to find
the happiness I seek
When we're out together
dancing cheek to cheek
Heaven
I'm in heaven
And the cares that hung
around me through the week
Seem to vanish
Iike a gambIer's Iucky streak
When we're out together
dancing cheek to cheek
Oh, I Iove to cIimb a mountain
And to reach the highest peak
But it doesn't thriII me
haIf as much
As dancing cheek to cheek