I'm going to call.
TRANSPLANT COORDI NATION
National Transplant
Organization.
- Manuela, Ramn y Cajal Hospital.
- Yes.
We've got a possible donor.
We've done the first EEG,
and the family has agreed.
Give me the details.
Male, 35 years old.
Blood group?
''O'' positive.
Weight, about 1 50 pounds.
LIVER
LIVER RECI PI ENTS
Notasingle drop!
- With Dodoti Diapers...
- Dodotis!
you won'tfeela drop!
- Mom!
- What?
The movie's starting.
I'm coming.
Eve Unveiled
They always change the title!
''All About Eve'' should be
''Todo Sobre Eva.''
But that sounds odd.
What areyou writing?
Nothing.
Future Pulitzerwinners.
ALL ABOUT MY MOTHER
Eat up. You have to put on
a few pounds.
Some dayyou may have
to work the street to keep me.
You don't need pounds for that.
You need a big dick.
Where did you learn
to talk like that?
- You asked.
- I wasjoking.
- And you?
- What about me?
Would you prostituteyourself
for me?
I've already done
just about everything foryou.
Eat up!
Autograph fiends!
They'renotpeople.
They're littlebeasts
thatrun inpacks like coyotes.
They'reyour fans.
They'renobody's fans.
They'rejuvenile delinquents,
mentaldefectives.
Fans, indeed!
Theyneverseeaplayoramovie.
They'reneverindoors longenough.
Well, there's oneindoors
rightnow.
Ibroughtherback toseeyou.
Comein, Eve.
I thoughtyou'dforgotten
aboutme.
Notatall.
Margo,
this is Eve Harrington.
- Howdoyoudo, my dear?
- Hello.
Would you like to be
an actress?
It was hard enough
becoming a nurse.
Ifyou were an actress,
I'd write parts foryou.
I was in an amateur group
when I was young.
I wasn't bad.
I must have a picture
somewhere.
I'd love to see it.
I'll look for it later.
Look, Esteban.
I found a picture.
We were doing a show
based on texts by Boris Vian.
Cabaret for intellectuals.
Happy birthday!
- Already?
- It's midnight, sweetheart.
'' Music for Chameleons.''
How did you know I wanted it?
I knowyou like Capote.
Read me something,
like when I was little.
''Preface.
I started writing
when I was eight.''
See? I'm not the only one.
''I didn't know
that I had chained myselffor life...
to a noble
but merciless master.
When God hands you a gift,
he also hands you a whip...
and the whip is intended
only for self-flagellation.''
That's enough
to putyou offwriting.
Don't be so lame.
It's a wonderful preface.
How doyou want
to celebrateyour birthday?
I'd like to see
one ofyour seminars.
Why?
I'm writing a story aboutyou
for a competition.
And I'd like to seeyou act
in those organ donation courses.
Well, I'd have to check
with Mamen.
She's the psychologist
in charge ofthe seminar.
Fine. Do it.
I don't think I likeyou writing
about me.
Your husband is dead, ma'am.
That's impossible.
Wejust saw him in the ICU.
He seemed to be breathing.
We've explained that, ma'am.
A machine is breathing for him.
Wouldyoulike us
to contactyour family?
Idon'thaveany family.
Justmyson.
MyGod!
Howam Igoing to tellhim?
Whenhe wasalive,
didyourhusbandsayanything...
regardingorgan donation?
Did he care about such matters?
When we was alive,
he cared only about living.
But I presume he was concerned
with the lives ofothers.
I don't understand.
What my colleague means
is thatyour husband's organs...
couldsave otherpatients'lives.
But weneed
yourauthorization forthat.
Youcouldgivehim
a transplant?
Notexactly.
The other wayaround, actually.
Now we'll discuss
what happened in the simulation.
Lookwhen you cross the street!
- What wereyou thinking?
- I had an idea.
An idea!
Give him the tickets.
Whyareyoulookingatmelike that?
Do Ilookawful?
No, youlookbetterthan ever.
Look, thatmustbe
thegentlemanyou were expecting.
You aren't Mr. Huntleigh!
Neither areyou!
These fingernails will have
to be trimmed.
Thejacket, Doctor.
Ask her to let go ofme!
Please!
Let her go.
Get up.
Lean on my arm...
Miss DuBois.
Thankyou.
Whoeveryou are...
I have always depended
on the kindness ofstrangers.
Come on, baby.
The worst is over.
Don't touch me.
Don't ever touch me again, bastard!
Watch your language!
Stella, come here.
I'm never coming back
to this house.
Never!
I'd like to get
Huma Rojo's autograph.
- In this weather?
- What's that got to do with it?
What ifnobody comes out?
Let's wait a while.
It's my birthday.
Look, autumn's here already.
- So long.
- Seeyou tomorrow.
Nina Cruz really moved you,
didn't she?
No, not her. Stella.
Twentyyears ago, we did Streetcar
with the drama group in my town.
I played Stella.
Your fatherwas Kowalski.
Some dayyou'll have to tell me
all about my father.
All I know is
he died before I was born.
- It isn't an easy story to tell.
- I guess not.
Oryou'd have told me by now.
I nearly asked for that
as a birthday present.
I'm not sure
it would be a nice present.
You're wrong.
It would be the best one.
Then I'll tell you everything
when we get home.
Working in theater
is worse than being a nun!
You think not being able to get stoned
all day is being a nun!
Yeah, I do!
Alfonso XII Street, number 30.
Come on, forget about it!
My son!
TomorrowI turn 17,
butIlook older.
Boys wholivealone with theirmothers
haveaspeciallook...
moreserious thannormal,
likeanintellectualora writer.
In my case that'snormal,
because I'm alsoa writer.
''Intensive Care Unit''
This is Lola, at Ramn y Cajal.
Yes?
We've got a possible donor.
He's in the ICU.
They've done the first EEG...
but the mother hasn't given
her consentyet.
Can I have the details?
I don't have them.
It's Manuela's son.
The Manuela that I know?
The coordinator?
Yes. He's dead.
It's awful.
Unfortunately...
the result ofthe EEG
is what we'd feared.
We have to make a decision
immediately.
CONSENT BY NEXT OF KI N
OPERATI NG ROOM
HEART
It's from the hospital!
We have to go.
We have to call.
- I'll do it. You calm down.
- I am calm-- but call them.
ALVEDRO AI RPORT, CORUA
REGIONAL HOSPITAL, CORUA
THREE WEEKS LATER
We're outside now,
sweetheart.
We're out at last.
He looks great.
Who'd have believed it?
He certainly didn't.
I feel I can breathe
like before.
- Even better.
- With an 1 8-year-old's heart!
- I'll fixyou some apple fritters.
- No, he has to be careful.
Lastnight, Momshowedme
apicture ofwhenshe wasyoung.
Halfofit wasmissing.
Ididn't want to tellher,
butmylife ismissing thatsamehalf.
I was worried.
I thoughtyou'd never call.
I called
as soon as I got to Madrid.
I mean in Argentina.
I called you loads oftimes...
but I must have got
your aunt's numberwrong.
I wasn't in Argentina, Mamen.
I went to Corua.
Why did you go there?
I went after my son's heart.
Who told you?
How did you know?
I looked in the files...
until I found the name and address
ofthe transplant recipient.
You shouldn't have.
It was wrong,
and the best way to go crazy.
- Look at me, damn it!
- I know that.
The best thing for me
is to quit the NTO and leave Madrid.
- I didn't say that.
- Butyou think it-- and you're right.
I think I won't even unpack.
You're in no shape to travel alone.
You're ill.
You have to rest up
and get better.
I'll stay here tonight.
- Then come home with me.
- I want to be alone, Mamen.
- Try to be reasonable.
- How?
Seventeenyears ago,
Imade thissamejourney...
butin the opposite direction,
from Barcelona to Madrid.
I was runningaway then too...
butI wasn'talone.
I was carrying Esteban
insideme.
I was runningaway
from his fatherthen...
andnowI'mgoing
insearch ofhim.
- Shall I keep going?
- Yes, go on.
Stop!
Son ofa bitch!
You're crazy, you faggot!
- What did you do?
- I hit him with a stone.
- Help me get him up.
- Get up. Come on.
Come on,Juan. Get up.
Areyou all right?
Stand up.
Let's get moving.
Come on, quickly.
What a fucking useless psychopath!
Look.
See that bonfire
where the ''tops'' are?
Ask for Ursula.
Tell herAgrado sentyou.
She'll fixyou up.
Agrado!
It's you!
Manolita!
You're hurt.
No, no, it's your blood.
It isn't becauseyou saved my life,
but how I've missed you!
Eighteen years-- not a word,
not a letter, not a fucking call.
I thoughtyou were dead, bitch!
You can tell me everything
at home.
We'll stop by a drugstore first.
Can we get a taxi here?
Over there.
With any luck,
we won't get mugged on the way.
- You got the knife?
- Yes, and a rock in my purse.
Hey, there, bonanit.
Look, I'm sorry I wokeyou.
- Hey, come over here.
- No. What doyou want?
- We're not going to eatyou.
- What doyou want?
Let me do the talking.
Povidone-iodine,
approximation sutures...
Thrombocid,
sterilized gauze and--
- You got any alcohol?
- No, I drank it all last night.
I mean for disinfecting.
No. I've got Vaseline, condoms
and lots ofbandages.
- Anything else?
- Alcohol, please.
Oh, Manolita!
The Barceloneta!
Those were the days!
You remember?
Yes.
Please, don't moveyour head.
You know anything
about her?
About who? Lola?
- Unfortunately.
- What happened?
I took her in.
She was in a bad way.
As usual,
with all the shit she takes.
I came back from working
the Field all night...
and she'd cleaned the place out.
Watches,jewelry, '70s magazines
that were my inspiration.
300,000 pesetas.
What hurt most was...
she took a statue ofthe Virgin
that my mother gave me.
What for?
She doesn't believe in anything!
Unless she's in a satanic sect
and wanted it for some ritual.
I see she hasn't changed.
To do that to me,
with all she owes me!
Since we met in Paris 20 years ago,
I've been like a sister to her.
We got our tits together.
You know better than anyone.
- You never saw her again?
- No, and I don't want to.
Areyou looking for her?
Yes.
We've got unsettled business.
Why did you go offlike that?
Won'tyou tell me anything?
I can't.
Some other day.
All right.
Just don't disappear again.
I like to say good-bye
to the people I love...
even ifit's only
to cry my eyes out, bitch.
I can't believe it.
I look like the Elephant Man!
Don't exaggerate.
It'sjust a bit swollen.
A bit swollen?
Where can I go with a mug like this?
Come and eat something.
Why did you go
to all this trouble?
Salad-- how wonderful!
It really hurts to chew!
I won't be able to suck.
You shouldn't work today.
What can I do?
Lola cleaned me out.
I have to work.
Look, caramel spread!
And meat pie!
And myprovoleta .
I have to work too.
Ifyou want,
we can look together.
Oh, yes!
Sinceyou left,
I haven't had a decent meal.
Well, also, as a model,
I have to watch my figure.
The worst thing about this work
is you've got to look cute...
and keep up with the latest advances
in surgery and cosmetics.
You look terrific!
Nothing like a Chanel
to makeyou feel respectable.
You look it.
Don't I look a bit ofa slut
in this suit?
All the better.
These nuns only help
whores and transvestites.
Is that a real Chanel?
No! How could I buy a real Chanel
with all the hunger in the world!
All I have that's real
are my feelings...
and these pints ofsilicone
that weigh a ton.
I feel so old, Manolita,
and it isn't my age.
It's because ofthe beating.
The beating I've taken
for the last 40 years!
- Hello.
- Come in.
Areyou looking for someone,
or can I help?
We want to see the girl
who goes to the Field.
The cute one.
Sister Rosa. She's inside.
Go on in.
Thankyou.
Rosa, look. Visitors.
What happened toyour face?
Nothing. A beating.
Occupational hazard.
- Can we talk?
- Ofcourse.
Let's go next door.
It's quieter.
My friend and I want
to quit the street...
but we need to work.
Cleaning stairs, whatever.
We don't care.
There isn't much else.
Well, garbage collector,
or learning handicrafts here.
Embroidered tablecloths,
dried flowers.
I think I prefer
garbage collector.
What can you do,
apart from the street?
I've worked as a cook.
She's practically a surgeon.
Look at this face.
She did it.
Better than Pitanguy.
She's a compatriot of Lola's.
Really? Haveyou heard
anything about her?
I haven't seen her in 1 8 years.
She cleaned out my place.
She was here.
It must have been
about four months ago.
We helped her through detox.
I cared for her
through withdrawal...
but then shejust disappeared.
I'd like to see her
before I go to El Salvador.
El Salvador?
Maybe I'll sign on.
I always thought I could
make it big in the Third World.
Then come with me.
I won't be so alone.
The street's getting worse here
every day.
The whores were bad enough,
but the drag queens are wiping us out.
I can't stand the drag queens.
They're sleazebags.
They confuse transvestism
with a circus.
Worse, with mime!
A woman is her hair,
her nails...
lips for sucking or for bitching.
I mean, haveyou ever seen
a bald woman?
I can't stand them.
They're all sleazebags!
I doubt there are
many drag queens in El Salvador...
but they're
in the middle ofa war.
Yeah? I didn't know that.
I'm replacing some nuns
who were murdered.
I'm not sure
what I need right now is a war.
You're terrible, Agrado.
Soyou were a cook.
Yes.
Who? This one?
The best!
What a surprise!
Hi, Mom.
Are we interrupting?
It doesn't matter.
We seeyou so rarely.
- This is Manuela.
- Pleased to meetyou.
Come inside.
Don'tjust stand there.
Mom, Manuela is a cook...
and as Florinda's gone,
I thought--
Thankyou, darling.
Vicenta and I can manage.
But how?
Dad alone needs two people.
- Where is he?
- Out with the dog.
- On their own?
- Ofcourse.
What ifthey get lost?
The dog knows the way home.
Don't worry.
What a shame!
I reallywanted to see them.
We'll go look for them,
but first we have to talk.
Come into the studio.
I'm sorryyou came for nothing.
- It's all right.
- Try her for a few days.
Think of Dad.
Manuela's a nurse.
- As well as a cook?
- Yes.
I prefer to look
afteryour father myself.
I understand.
Thankyou anyway. I'll go.
Good-bye.
- Manuela.
- Yes?
Wait here.
I won't be long.
How dareyou bring
a whore here!
It isn't easy to find help
who'll put up with you.
But a whore!
That's no reason
to be so rude.
I don't like strangers
to see me forging Chagalls.
Can'tyou understand?
Manuela isn't a whore anymore.
She's given it up.
How long haveyou known her?
Since this morning.
This morning?
You're incredible.
Mywork is to help people...
even ifI'vejust met them.
Well, mine isn't.
Don't look at me like that.
It doesn't mean I'm intolerant.
- I'll makeyou a deal.
- A deal?
I'll give that woman a chance
ifyou don't go to El Salvador.
Mom, don't give me any more doubts.
I've got enough.
And soyou should.
That trip is suicide!
No, it's parricide!
Well, I have to go.
Manuela's waiting.
Sure! Anywhore, any Salvadoran,
is more important than your parents!
- Don't start, Mom.
- You should go see a psychiatrist.
It wouldn't do
either ofus any harm.
Didn'tyou want to see
your father and the dog?
Another day.
Areyou all right?
Good-bye, Mom.
- Hello, Vicenta.
- Rosa, love.
- You're so thin. Aren'tyou eating?
- Yes, I am.
- Did you see a blonde girl downstairs?
- No.
- So long.
- Take care-- and eat!
A STREETCAR NAMEDDESIRE
I'm sorry about my mother.
I'm sorry.
Shall we go?
I can't deal with my mother.
She drives me crazy.
- Haveyou got parents?
- They're dead.
Soyou're alone.
I guess so.
You look awful.
I don't feel verywell.
I want to throw up.
I've got--
Here.
Haveyou seen the doctor?
You should.
It mayjust be gastritis.
Can we go toyour place
until this passes?
Well--
Doyou have a place?
I'vejust rented one,
but it's barely furnished.
It's quite a mess.
I moved in four days ago.
You want to lie down
for a while?
No, I'll just sit here on the sofa...
until it passes.
I'm going to take this off.
Who's this handsome boy?
My son.
I thoughtyou were alone.
He died in an accident.
Oh, I'm sorry!
Don't touch the notebook,
please.
Come on, baby.
The worst is over.
Don't touch me!
Don't ever touch me again, bastard!
Watch your language!
Stella, come here.
I'm never coming back
to this house.
Never!
DRESSI NG ROOMS
Come in, Nina.
I'm not Nina.
I'm Manuela.
You shouldn't be here.
Nina's gone.
What?
Where's Nina?
I don't know.
I just saw her run out.
She said she'd wait for me
in her dressing room!
I can't believe it.
It's only been two weeks.
She can't do this to me.
Haveyou got a car?
No. Where doyou want to go?
I don't know.
Can you drive?
Yes.
Don't tell anyone,
but Nina's got problems withjunk.
Doyou know where she'd go
to score at this time?
No, but it's easy to find out.
Thankyou.
Whoeveryou are...
I have always depended
on the kindness ofstrangers.
I can't drive.
Nina does the driving.
- Want one?
- No, thankyou.
I started smoking
because of Bette Davis.
To imitate her.
At 1 8, I was smoking
like a chimney.
That's why
I called myself Huma.
Huma's a very pretty name.
Smoke is all there's been
in my life.
You've had success too.
Success has got no taste
or smell.
And when you get used to it,
it's as ifit didn't exist.
God, where has that girl gone?
I think that's her!
You stay here. I'll go.
He's a son ofa bitch.
He rips everybody off.
Yeah, and since I'm not
from here--
Don't touch me.
Listen, Nina.
Huma's waiting foryou.
Who the fuck areyou?
She's in the car.
I got everything.
- Fuck, my purse!
- Yeah, I got a purse.
Ecstasy, toot.
- Who is it?
- It's Rosa.
- Hello.
- How areyou?
- Areyou alone?
- I just got up.
This late?
I was out late last night.
- Some breakfast?
- No, thanks.
- Aren'tyou hungry?
- Soyou're back on the street.
Just when I'd found
anotherway foryou to earn money.
Tell me.
I'm not a whore.
I've been fucked around a lot,
but I'm not a whore.
Why did you lie to me?
It was Agrado's idea.
The dress was hers too.
So tell me: What's this otherway
for me to earn money?
I'm dying ofcuriosity.
How much would you charge
to rent me a room?
To rentyou a room?
Why?
I'm going to leave the center
for a few months.
What about El Salvador?
I don't feel well.
I can't travel like this.
Why doyou want to move in here
ifyou're ill?
I'm pregnant.
Pregnant?
What areyou going to do?
Have it, ofcourse.
What doyou expect?
I thought it'd be
less ofa scandal here.
Can't the father
helpyou out?
The father!
God knows where he is.
Butyou know who he is,
don'tyou?
Ofcourse.
Who doyou take me for?
I'm sorry.
It was your compatriot Lola.
That lousy, fucking bitch!
What's come overyou?
What's come over me?
How far along areyou?
Three months, I think.
But I'm veryworried.
Worried?
I'm not surprised!
I had bleeding this morning.
Haveyou seen a doctor?
I'm going
to the Hospital del Mar tomorrow.
I wanted to know
ifyou'd come with me.
Yes, ofcourse.
Thankyou.
What about the room?
I'm sorry.
You can't stay here.
Good evening.
May I come in?
Hello!
I was expecting you.
I didn't know
where to send your purse.
Here it is.
Thankyou.
Is everything there?
Yes, everything.
- Thankyou for last night.
- Not at all.
I'd love to talk more,
but I'm short on time.
- Can I helpyou?
- Could you button this?
Ofcourse.
What was your name?
Would you like
to work for me?
- Doing what?
- Everything.
Everything except sleep with me.
I've got enough with Nina.
Well, the truth is
I was looking for ajob.
I need a personal assistant.
Someone I can trust.
- You don't know me.
- What I saw last night was enough.
But Nina hates me.
Nina hates everyone,
including herselfand me.
Well...
when do I start?
- Right now, ifyou can.
- All right.
Ask Nina what she wants
for dinner.
- I'll just have an esqueixada.
- Anything else?
Could you get a tranquilizer for Nina?
She's real edgy today.
- I've got Lexatin.
- Terrific!
Don't mention the father.
Why doyou dislike Lola so much?
Lola's got the worst ofa man...
and the worst ofa woman.
I'll tell you a story.
I had a friend
who got married veryyoung.
After a year, her husband
went to work in Paris...
and he was to call her
when he got settled.
Twoyears passed.
The husband saved some money
and came to Barcelona to open a bar.
She came here tojoin him.
Twoyears isn't a long time...
but the husband had changed.
He didn't love her anymore.
The change was more physical.
He'd gotten a pair oftits
that were bigger than hers.
Oh, I see.
My friend was veryyoung.
She was in a foreign land.
She had no one.
Apart from the tits,
the husband hadn't changed that much...
so she ended up accepting him.
Women will do anything
to avoid being alone.
Women are more tolerant,
but that's good.
We're assholes...
and a bit lesbo.
Listen to the end
ofthe story.
My friend
and her husband with the tits...
set up a bar here,
on the Barceloneta.
He spent the day in a tiny bikini,
screwing everything he could...
and giving her a hard time
ifshe wore a bikini...
or even a miniskirt.
The bastard!
How could someone act so macho
with a pair oftits like that?
Sit down.
- Who is the patient?
- She is.
Well?
My sister is pregnant.
We reckon she's about
three months along.
This is her first checkup.
Yesterday and today
I bled a little.
Lie down on the couch,
and strip from the waist down.
Don't worry.
- Put this on.
- Thankyou.
According to the ultrasound,
the fetus seems to be fine.
Doyou live together?
- No.
- Yes.
Which is it?
She lives with our mother,
but she hasn't told her anything yet.
Is your blood pressure
usually high?
Yes, I have hypertension.
There's a risk ofmiscarriage.
You must move
as little as possible.
But I've got to do myjob.
Your onlyjob now is to rest
and not do anything stupid.
Tell your mother
to watch her blood pressure.
She has to follow a salt-free diet
and rest.
I'll tell her.
Listen, Doctor, I work
with people who are high-risk...
so I'd like to have
an AI DS test as well.
What's yourjob?
She's a social worker.
When can we pick up
the results?
In two weeks' time.
You have to tell your mother.
You need to be looked after.
I found ajobyesterday,
and I'm going to be busy all day.
Listen.
You've no right
to ask me to beyour mother.
You've already got one,
even ifyou don't like her.
We can't choose our parents.
They are who they are.
Oh, God!
Please, don't blackmail me!
Idon'tknowifI was right
to call the clinic.
Whatelse couldyoudo?
Ican'tbelieveher
andgo onliving withStanley.
Then don't believe her.
What matters is you and your baby.
What ifshe told me
the truth?
Blanche?
Blanche is in no shape
to tell the truth...
even ifshe wanted to,
poor thing.
Where is my heart?
She means herjewel box.
It's heart-shaped.
I think it's here somewhere.
Look, here it is.
- I need a necklace.
- We'll look for it.
What's the gentleman's name?
Huntleigh.
Did he call
while I was in the bathroom?
- No.
- How strange!
Why areyou looking at me like that?
Do I look awful?
No, you look better than ever.
- I'll look betterwith this necklace.
- Shall I helpyou?
Soyou'regoingona trip.
You'resolucky.
I'm green with envy.
Thereheis.
Thatmustbe thegentleman
who's come foryou.
TWO WEEKS LATER
- Second call. Fifteen minutes.
- Come in.
- Aren't they hereyet?
- I don't where they are.
I was at the TV studio all day.
- Where's Nina?
- Wasn't she with you?
I just left her at home, in bed.
- In bed?
- What's wrong?
I think it's food poisoning.
She was so ill this morning.
Why didn'tyou tell me
when I called?
We didn't want to upsetyou.
- Has a doctor seen her?
- Yes.
She's got gastroenteritis,
but she'll be fine tomorrow.
So we cancel the show?
I'd like to speak to Huma,
please.
Yes, wait outside.
Five minutes.
All right!
- Tell me the truth.
- She's bombed. She can't even speak.
She went out afteryou did.
She didn't know I'd drop by.
She thought I'd be with you.
What do we do now?
Ifit won't giveyou a heart attack,
I could do her part.
I know it by heart
from hearing it over the loudspeakers.
But can you act?
I can lie verywell,
and I'm used to improvising.
I've seen that.
My son said
I was a very good actress.
I didn't even know
you had a son!
Third call. Five minutes.
Huma, what'll we do?
We can't wait any longer.
Happy birthday, Blanche.
This is your present.
Thankyou, Stanley.
Why did you bother?
I hopeyou like it.
Why, it's--
A bus ticket.
A return ticket forTuesday.
Areyou insinuating
I should leave?
What doyou think?
- Why did you do that to her?
- I'm sick ofher insults.
I'm tired ofyou two whispering
behind my back all the time!
Please, don't go!
- Let go. You've torn my shirt!
- Brute!
Brute?
I was a brute when we met.
But I'd remind you
that it was never a problem foryou.
One dayyou showed me
a picture ofyour house...
a mansion with lots ofcolumns.
I pulled you down offthose columns
and taughtyou to be happy.
We laughed
and were happy together...
until your sister Blanche
appeared.
What's wrong?
Take me to the hospital, please!
Congratulations on last night.
I heard you were great.
You can't imagine.
What a pityyou weren't there.
I felt awful.
Agrado called to tell me about it.
She must have called
halfof Barcelona!
Areyou doing everything
the doctor told you?
- I just saw him.
- And?
- I went for my results.
- I forgot it was today.
I'm HIV positive.
We'll have the tests redone.
Why the hell
did you screw Lola?
Don'tyou know
she's been shooting up for 1 5 years?
What world doyou think
you're living in?
I don't know.
Haveyou spoken
toyour mother?
Your colleagues?
No.
We'll go foryour things now,
and you'll move in here.
Thankyou.
- Hello.
- Hello, Alex.
You were terrific last night.
Thankyou.
- Good evening.
- Here's Miss GoodyTwo-shoes.
- What's up?
You planned it all, you bitch!
Nina, don't be so rude.
Just like Eve Harrington.
You learned the part on purpose.
It's fucking impossible to learn it
over the loudspeakers.
You think I'm stupid?
The loudspeakers helped me
remember it.
I've known the part ofStella
foryears.
- Really? What a coincidence!
- Ifyou only knew.
What did I tell you?
Whywereyou here
that first night?
Orwas that
a coincidence too?
No, it wasn't a coincidence.
I won't botheryou anymore.
I'll get my things and go.
Manuela, I thinkyou owe us
an explanation.
A StreetcarNamedDesire
has marked my life.
Twentyyears ago, I played Stella
with an amateur group.
That's where I met
my husband.
He was playing Kowalski.
Two months ago,
I sawyourversion in Madrid.
I went with my son.
It was the night
ofhis birthday.
It was pouring rain,
but we waited outside...
because he wanted
your autograph, Huma.
It was crazy
to wait in the rain...
but it was his birthday,
so I couldn't say no.
You two got in a taxi,
and he ran afteryou.
A car coming along the street
ran him down.
He was killed.
That's the explanation.
That's the explanation, Huma.
Move, Rosa.
I can't get past.
What areyou doing here?
Hello. I came to payyou.
You leftyesterday
withoutyour money.
This is my sister Rosa.
- Hello.
- How areyou?
Let me helpyou.
Let's get the elevator.
- Where's Nina?
- I left herwith Mario. She says hi.
Leave the bags here.
You go and rest for a while,
Rosa.
- I'm not tired.
- Don't argue.
Sit down.
- Anything to drink?
- No, thankyou.
She's like a little girl.
I couldn't sleep all night
thinking aboutyour son.
I can remember his face
in the rain perfectly...
and the notebook
in his hand.
I can see him now.
I don't want to talk
about my son.
I can't.
Apart from apologizing,
Nina and and I wantyou to come back.
Rosa's sick.
She needs someone
to look after her all day.
I can't leave her.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what I should do.
Why don'tyou check Nina
into a clinic?
Ifwe don't fulfill the contract,
the companywill sue me.
Find a replacement...
and finish your run
with the company.
I can't do the play
without Nina.
She's hooked onjunk,
but I'm hooked on her.
- Who was it?
- Agrado.
And you let her in?
You should have said
we were busy.
I'm thinking ofyou.
Come on, lie down here
and stop moving around.
What exactly
is wrong with you?
An accident.
What kind?
Why didn't I think ofit before?
Agrado could take my place.
Ofcourse!
The oneyou didn't want
to let in?
That's something between us,
but she's perfect foryou.
How old is Agrado?
Pretty old.
Between thirty and fifty.
Is Agrado her real name?
No, it's a stage name.
Like Huma.
You know why
I took the name Huma?
Yes.
Manuela told me.
What else did she tell you?
Everything.
She told me everything.
Aboutyou and Nina...
thejunk...
and that it'll end badly.
Really?
And what else did she say?
I'm very curious.
That as an actress,
you're wonderful...
but that as a person,
you're very mixed up.
And what else?
That I shouldn't say anything.
What haveyou got
in the bag?
- Cava and ice cream.
- What for?
To celebrateyour success
last night, bitch.
Thankyou. Come in.
Oh, what a surprise!
Three single girls
in an empty house...
always reminds me of
How To MarryA Millionaire.
- How areyou, Sister Rosa?
- Huma, this is Agrado.
My pleasure. I'm ''fans.''
How areyou?
Huma, you're a goddess,
a living legend.
Like I said, I'm ''fans,''
in the plural...
but my Manuela was too much
the other night.
How I bawled
at the evening show!
Shouldn'tyou be
in El Salvador?
Yes, but I'm not going now.
I'm staying here.
Agrado, I don't work
for Huma anymore.
Beforeyou came, we were saying
thatyou could take my place.
Me play Stella?
I see myselfmore as Blanche.
Replacing me, not Nina,
and much less Huma.
Thankyou, Manuela,
but I don't--
Try her for a few days.
She isn't as clueless as she seems.
I am, Huma, and worse.
Right now, I don't get this at all.
So I'll giveyou the bottle
to cheer us up a bit.
I brought ice cream.
Come on, let's have a drink
and relax a bit.
I'll get the glasses.
I'll just have some ice cream.
I can't drink alcohol.
Well, I'll have a drink.
Hey, what's up with Manuela?
She seems very odd.
Success hasn't gone
to her head already, has it?
She wants to dumpyou
on Huma.
I think Prada
is ideal for a nun.
My problem is everything suits me,
so I'm very eclectic.
I've had chilblains
since I came to Barcelona.
Oh, really?
It's finished.
Should I get more?
I'd love some, but no.
- Where's the bathroom?
- Straight ahead.
Excuse me.
Fill me in on what's happening here.
I'm no stranger.
- I'll tell you tomorrow.
- No, don't!
She can't keep her mouth shut.
I know verywell
how to keep it shut.
I played along like an English lady
so she wouldn't catch on.
I'm a model ofdiscretion,
even when I'm sucking someone's cock.
I've sucked a lot ofcocks
in public places...
and no one's noticed,
except the person involved.
It's been ages
since I sucked a cock!
I love the word ''cock.''
And ''prick''!
I have to go.
- Areyou all right?
- What?
- Better than ever.
Can you help her
find a taxi?
I nearly forgot.
This is foryou.
Thankyou.
- Well, good-bye, girls.
- So long.
You have to teach me
how to bark.
I think I was a bit rude to Huma.
I said all sorts ofthings.
Really?
It doesn't matter.
They're very different for sisters,
aren't they?
- Are they sisters?
- That's what Manuela said.
Well, ifshe says so.
- I thinkyou're all bullshitters.
- You have to get to know us.
Can you drive?
- I used to be a truck driver.
- Really?
In Paris, before I got my tits.
Then I gave up the truck
and became a whore.
- How interesting.
- Very.
A check.
-1 50,000.
- How generous!
What is it?
Huma's autograph,
for Esteban.
DearEsteban.: This is
theautograph Inevergaveyou...
andnotbecause
youdidn't try.
Ihavebeen foolish,
casting mypearlsbeforeswine.
- Youmeanme?
- Youandyour friend, Mr. Mitchell.
He came toseeme
andrepeatedtheslanderyou'dtoldhim.
-So I threwhim out.
- You threwMitch out?
He returned with a box ofroses
to beg my forgiveness.
'' Forgive me,'' he said,
but some things are not forgivable.
Cruelty is not forgivable.
It is the one unforgivable thing.
Well?
- Areyou learning the part too?
- Ofcourse not.
- You should,just in case.
- You think so?
May I have some privacy?
Soyou can getyour fix?
Can't wait till the end?
Ifyou know, why ask?
Ifyou don't want me to tell Huma,
do it in the bathroom.
I don't need to see these things.
All right.
Keep an eye on the door.
I know that when you'reyoung--
well, you're no child--
you don't value these things.
Butyou're cute,
nicely proportioned--
kind ofsmall, but cute.
You've lost weight--
well, it's all the drugs--
but the important thing is
you've lost weight.
You've got talent--
limited talent,
butyou've got it.
And, above all,
a woman who loves you.
And you trade it all forjunk.
You think it's worth it?
Well, it isn't.
It isn't worth it.
I trade it for a bit ofpeace.
Come on, help me.
You're getting flat
as a board.
Compared toyou.
What a dirty habit!
Haven'tyou ever thought
ofcutting it off?
I'd get no work.
The clients like us pneumatic
and well-hung.
Rheumatic?
Guys are so odd.
Not rheumatic. Pneumatic.
A pair oftits as hard
as newly inflated tires...
and a big dick as well.
Show meyour cock.
That fix didn't agree with you.
Maybe I'll like it too.
You've got enough problems
as it is.
Go, you're on now.
And don't throw up on anybody.
The audience loves it.
They think it's because I'm pregnant.
You're not pregnant in this scene.
You've had a doll.
That's right.
Will you show me
your cock later?
I'll show it toyou
and you can lick it.
Young people will try anything!
MONTHS LATER
I'm going to call him Esteban.
Your son?
Why?
Afteryours.
This babywill belong
to both ofus.
Ifonly he did.
Ifonlywe were alone
in the world...
without any commitments.
You and your son,
just for me.
Butyou have a family.
I'm going to fixyour hair
and makeyou up a bit.
- Why?
- I like to seeyou look nice.
And I called your mother.
She's coming
to seeyou today.
My mother?
You have a mother.
Don'tyou remember?
What will I tell her?
Thatyou love her--
I don't know.
Come in, Huma.
No, it isn't Huma.
May I come in?
Ofcourse, Mario.
Come in.
- You're very early today.
- Yes.
- What areyou doing?
-Just a bit ofironing.
Is anything wrong?
I didn't sleep verywell
last night.
I've been on edge all day.
Would you give me
a blowjob?
Can'tyou all get it intoyour heads
that I'm retired?
I don't wantyou to think that...
but since I've been
on edge all day...
I think a blowjob
would relax me.
You give me one.
I'm on edge too.
Well, it would be the first time
I've sucked a woman's cock...
but ifthat's what it takes--
The whole company
is obsessed with my cock!
It isn't the only one around.
Don'tyou have a cock?
Yes.
Do people askyou to suck their cocks
becauseyou've got one?
- Do they?
- No.
Well, then?
Look, I'll suckyou off
to showyou how open-minded...
and how sensitive
I am about these things.
Where's the fucking phone?
Hello?
All right, don't worry.
I'll see to everything.
Shall we go to my room?
In case Huma comes--
Huma can't come.
She's in the hospital, along with Nina.
- What's happened?
- They nearly killed each other.
Fuck!
Here.
We'll have to cancel
the performance.
- Don't say anything.
- We have to say something.
Yes, but it doesn't have
to be the truth.
- I'll make something up.
- Right.
And--
- Hello, how areyou?
- Hello.
Come in.
- Where is she?
- There, in the bedroom.
And here I was so worried,
thinking you were in El Salvador.
I seeyou've learned to lie.
I didn't know
how to tell you.
What areyou going to do now?
Leave the order?
Get married?
Mom, the things you ask!
One never knows with you.
At least, I don't.
Even this I had to learn about
through your friend.
What would I have done
without her?
How's Dad?
Same as ever.
I don't know.
Worse.
Ifyou don't mind,
I'd rather not tell him anything.
He wouldn't get it anyway.
- And Sapic?
- Fine.
Rosa, I don't know
what to do.
What doyou expect me
to do?
Nothing, Mom.
You don't expect
anything from me?
It isn't that.
What I mean is
don't make it harder for me.
Would you like anything?
I'm making tea.
No, thankyou.
What exactly is wrong?
I didn't understand over the phone.
According to the ultrasound,
she's got placenta previa.
When the time comes,
she'll need a caesarian.
In the meantime,
she must have complete rest.
Doyou think
I should take her home?
I have to look after her father
as ifhe were a child.
You're her mother...
but I think
Rosa's better-offhere.
That's the impression
she gave me.
Ifyou need money,
just ask me.
- And, please, keep me informed.
- Yes. Don't worry.
Thankyou very much.
- I'll seeyou out.
- No, really.
I don't know
what I did wrong with Rosa.
Ever since she was born,
she's been like an alien.
Doyou have children?
Yes, one.
Doyou get along well
with him?
He died.
I'm sorry.
Due to reasons
beyond their control...
two ofthe actresses
who triumph daily on this stage...
cannot be here tonight--
the poor things.
So the show
has been cancelled.
Those who wish
can get their money back...
but for those who have
nothing better to do...
it's a shame to waste the rare occasion
thatyou make it to the theater.
Ifyou stay...
I promise to entertain you
with my life story.
Good-bye. I'm very sorry.
IfI boreyou, you can pretend
to snore-- like this.
I'll get the idea, and you certainly
won't hurt my feelings.
Honestly.
They call me '' La Agrado''...
because I've always tried
to make people's lives agreeable.
As well as being agreeable,
I'm very authentic!
Look at this body!
All made to measure.
Almond-shaped eyes-- 80,000.
Nose-- 200,000.
A waste ofmoney. Another beating
the following year left it like this.
It gives me character,
but ifI'd known...
I wouldn't have touched it.
I'll continue.
Tits-- two,
because I'm no monster.
70,000 each,
but I've more than earned that back.
Silicone in--
Where?
Lips, forehead, cheeks...
hips and ass.
A pint costs about 1 00,000...
soyou work it out,
because I've lost count.
Jaw reduction-- 75,000.
Complete laser depilation...
because women, like men,
also come from apes.
60,000 a session.
It depends how hairyyou are.
Usually, two to four sessions.
But ifyou're a flamenco diva,
you'll need more.
Well, as I was saying...
it costs a lot
to be authentic, ma'am.
And one can't be stingy
with these things...
becauseyou are more authentic...
the moreyou resemble
whatyou've dreamed ofbeing.
I'll turn you around.
- Please, be careful.
- Don't worry.
We'll lift up a bit.
That's it.
- Areyou all right?
- Yes.
Ifyou can push it over here--
- I'll put this away.
- Thankyou.
- Can you manage?
- Yes.
To the Hospital del Mar,
please.
Can we go
through Medinaceli Square?
Aren't we meeting your mother
at the hospital?
- I just want to see the square.
- All right.
Stop here!
I played here as a child.
Sapic!
Come here, boy!
Hello, Sapic.
That dog would go
with anybody.
Doyou have a dog?
No, but I really like them.
- How old areyou?
- Twenty-six.
- And how tall areyou?
- Not very. Five six.
Come on.
Go on.
Go back to Dad.
Come on.
Good-bye, Dad.
- You aren't in any pain?
- No.
That's great.
Painless childbirth.
When is she going
into surgery?
In an hour and a half.
I've got time to go check
on your father and come back.
You don't have
to come back, Mom.
I want to be here
with you.
Give Dad a kiss for me.
I'm keeping this one.
So long.
Good-bye.
I hope the third Esteban
is the definitive one foryou.
The third Esteban?
Lola was the first...
and your son, the second.
Soyou knew Lola
was the father ofmy son too.
Ofcourse.
It didn't take a genius.
Lola doesn't know
we had a son.
I never told him.
Did your son know?
No, he didn't.
Let's not talk about sad things.
This is a great day.
They've put Videla injail,
and your son's going to be born.
- Promise me one thing.
- What?
- Ifanything happens--
- What could happen?
Promiseyou won't hide anything
from the child.
I don't have to. You can tell him
whateveryou wantyourself.
Promise me.
Ifit makes you happier.
All right.
I promise.
We are here today
to say good-bye to our sister Rosa.
Manuela, I'm so happy
to seeyou.
What a pity
it has to be here.
It couldn't be
anywhere else.
You aren't a human being, Lola.
You're an epidemic!
I was always excessive.
And I'm very tired.
Manuela, I'm dying.
Come.
I'm saying good-bye
to everything.
I robbed Agrado
to pay my ticket to Argentina.
I wanted to take a last look
at the town...
the river...
our street.
And I'm happy
I can say good-bye toyou too.
Now I just have to see
Sister Rosa's child.
My son.
I always dreamed ofhaving a son.
You know that.
When I left Barcelona,
I was carrying your child.
What?
You mean you too-
Did you have it?
A beautiful boy.
I want to see him.
Did you bring him with you?
He's in Madrid,
butyou can't see him.
Even from a distance.
I promise he won't see me.
It's the last thing
I ask ofyou.
You can't see him.
Please!
Six months ago,
he was run over by a car.
He's dead.
I only came to Barcelona
to tell you.
I'm sorry.
The baby!
Where haveyou been?
Haven'tyou taken
Sapic outyet?
- You weren't here.
- I'm here now.
He's hungry.
- The bottle's heating.
- Will you get it, please?
Come here.
Vicenta, don't let my husband
come in here, please.
He's convinced
the baby's yours.
Yes, I know.
He's veryjealous.
I told him
the babywas yours.
I don't dare
tell him the truth.
He wouldn't understand
anyway.
Ifonly he were mine.
What is it?
Who's that woman?
It's Manuela,
the new cook.
She's been with us
four days.
We've fixed up this room
so she can be here with her child.
Remember?
I told you.
- How old areyou?
- Thirty-eight.
- How tall areyou?
- Five seven.
All right.
Nowyou can go
for a walk.
Go on.
Thereyou are.
- The bottle, ma'am.
- Thankyou.
Thankyou.
No, no.
We're going to eat now.
Yes?
Don't tell anyone
about the antibodies.
Do the nuns know?
All right.
ONE MONTH LATER
Hello, Lola.
Take him.
What did the doctor say?
He's fine.
You can see-- he's normal.
You're with Dad.
- Can I give him a kiss?
- Ofcourse.
My son, I'm sorry to leaveyou
such an awful inheritance.
Don't say that.
There's no reason why
he should develop the disease.
This is our Esteban.
You called him Esteban too?
Thankyou.
He wanted to be a writer.
This is his notebook.
He took it with him everywhere.
He wrote this
the morning ofthe day he died.
Read it.
''Last night
Mom showed me a picture.
Halfofit was missing.
I didn't want to tell her,
but my life is missing that same half.''
Keep reading.
''This morning
I looked through her drawers...
and found
a bundle ofpictures.
Theywere all missing
a half.
My father, I suppose.
I want to meet him.
I have to make Mom understand
that I don't care who he is...
orwhat he's like...
or how he behaved towards her.
She can't deny me
that right.''
Keep the picture.
Thankyou.
I don't likejust anyone
kissing the baby.
Who was that woman
in the barwith you?
That woman is his father.
What did you say?
That was his father,
and he's very ill.
That monster is the one
who killed my daughter?
Don't think about that,
Rosa.
There are people who think
children are made in a day.
But it takes a long time--
a very long time.
That's why it's so awful to see
your child's blood on the ground.
A stream that flows for a minute
and yet costs us years.
When I found my son...
he was lying
in the middle ofthe street.
I soaked my hands in his blood
and licked them.
Because it was mine.
Animals lick theiryoung,
don't they?
I'm not disgusted
by my son.
You don't know
what it's like.
In a monstrance
ofglass and topaz...
I would put
the earth soaked by his blood.
Keep kneading.
The sadness should go
intoyour hands.
Work. You have to work.
- You don't notice my cold?
- No, it's fine.
Come on.
You shouldn't be in here.
Hello.
I've got a bouquet
forAgrado and Huma Rojo.
- Really?
- Yes. Sign here, please.
- You sure it's forAgrado?
- Yes, it says so.
Here.
Know why they call me
Agrado?
I've always tried
to make life agreeable for others.
Right.
''DearAgrado and Huma:
Running away once again
with no good-byes...
though I know how much
you like them, Agrado.''
Thesituation with Rosa'sparents
is unbearable.
Thegrandmotherisafraid
ascratch willinfecther.
I'm taking Esteban wherehe won'tbe
surroundedbyhostility.
Agrado, youknow
howmuch Iloveyou.
Takegoodcare
ofyourselfandofHuma.
I'msorrytomiss
the opening...
butI'msure thehomage to Lorca
willbeagreatsuccess.
I'll write toyou...
butit'sbetter
youdon'tknowanymore.
Oh, andtearup theletter.
Your Manuela. ''
TWO YEARS LATER
I'm comingback to Barcelona
aftertwoyears...
but this time
I'm notrunningaway.
I'mgoing toanAIDSconference
organizedby Can Ruti.
My Estebanhasneutralized
the virus in record time...
andthey want tostudy
his case.
I'msohappy.
May I?
Hey, she's mine too!
You look beautiful!
Your hair's gotten so long.
- And so has yours.
- No, this is a wig for the play.
Wait, your earring's loose.
I'll fix it.
Learn, you animal!
An animal, but who
takes care ofyou like I do?
It's great aboutyour son!
So he's neutralized the virus
practically overnight.
Yes. Esteban's case
proves the virus can disappear.
They're still trying to find out why,
but it's a miracle.
I knew it.
How I prayed for that child.
Why not staywith us
whileyou're in Barcelona?
Ofcourse.
We're staying
with his grandparents.
Rosa's mother
is looking forward to it.
She's changed so much.
- Third call, five minutes.
- I have to go.
You've got Esteban's picture.
Lola gave it to me
before she died.
I was keeping it
until you came back.
Keep it.
Thankyou.
And Nina?
I have to go.
Nina got married.
She's back in her home town.
She's got a baby too.
It's fat and horrible.
Really, really ugly.
I'll seeyou later.
''To Bette Davis,
Gena Rowlands, Romy Schneider...
To all actresses
who have played actresses...
to all women who act...
to men who act
and become women...
to all the people
who want to be mothers.
To my mother.''
I N ORDER OF APPEARANCE