GUNS SMUGGLED INTO HONG KONG
Is your wife worried about you?
She's used to it, but she still prays
every time I'm on a job.
Be good to her.
WUEN LOI RESTAURANT
Good morning. Up so early?
–How many Playboys are you reading?
–I don't read the articles.
Be serious.
Are the “bird men” here?
–Three are, but not the “bird king”.
–Keep watch.
Lionheart, can you hear me?
What's happening over there?
Something big.
Stay alert.
This is the real thing.
Sponge pudding.
Have you thought about emigrating?
I haven't.
This is my home.
I want to be buried here.
I can't adjust to life abroad.
You can't get dim sum in the morning.
–You can get dim sum abroad.
–We've got the original.
Your son must be growing up.
He's seven now.
I'll show you a photo.
OK.
–We've been waiting.
–We were in Shenzhen.
Sit down.
–I've got some good stuff.
–Is it any good?
Don't pay if it's no good.
I can't find it.
One shot and the cops
won't know what's hit them.
–Really?
–It's a bargain.
The bullet can go through two
oil barrels and still kill someone.
Are they really that great?
We have nothing but the best.
We'll get rich together.
My treat.
Freeze! Police!
Stay where you are!
Move!
–Are you OK?
–I'm fine.
Move, you bastard!
Move!
Get down!
Old bastard!
Move!
Get down! Get down!
Don't come in!
Are you OK?
Get out of the way!
You're really quite something.
Every time you fire a gun,
you never waste a bullet.
Do you know who you killed?
I'll tell you…
We were investigating them
until we had enough evidence!
Thanks to you,
we don't have anything!
–What a pity.
–Mr Woo.
–What is?
That we didn't catch the triads.
I remember you were
so sensitive in cadet school.
Now you're so hard.
Did I go too far?
No, they went too far.
I lost a good partner.
We have to make sacrifices.
Long, I…
Mr Hui wants to know
why you betrayed him.
Long,
I didn't betray Mr Hui.
Yes, you did.
Do you remember what happened?
It happened so quickly.
It was like a dream.
What's going on?
He's been dead two hours.
Close range shot.
Very professional.
–Have you found the gun?
–Not yet.
I've seen the deceased
on the wanted list.
I want it in half an hour.
The deceased
was a Malay Chinese terrorist.
Arms dealing in Asia
and North Africa from 1978 to 1981.
Wanted by
Malaysia, Thailand and Singapore.
Joined the triads
in Hong Kong in 1985.
He was Mr Hui's
right hand man in arms dealing.
Bought out by Johnny Wong.
The murderer used a.32 Filipino gun.
His style was unique.
We have no further clues.
What? HK$3,000 per square foot
in Sha Tau Kok!
I can't afford that!
If I don't buy a flat,
Madam won't marry me!
I can't get government housing
because I'm unmarried.
I'm going to be on the streets.
Stay at the YMCA.
HK$300 for one day
and discounts for a month.
That's not bad!
I'll sleep at the Jazz Bar.
That's perfect.
You can play before bed.
Shall we investigate
who's sending flowers to Madam?
–It's been happening a lot.
–So what?
–Madam, flowers for you.
–Thank you.
Master,
please help me.
Madam and I have had a few problems.
Please help me.
I'd appreciate a flat, too.
Have you been sick?
You've had so many flowers.
I'm sick alright.
Don't lose hope,
we might get back together.
I don't think so. I was stupid
and I've wasted my youth.
You like white roses?
–You didn't know?
–Have you told me?
I haven't even told him!
How could he have known?
The lyric.
He's asking if you're lonely
and if you need a man.
I just want to know how to sing it.
It's not “re re”.
It's “la la ti le do”.
–Is that all?
–Yes.
Do you want some soup? No.
Your underwear.
Madam likes to get white roses.
Really?
I just found out.
If you likes them,
you should buy her some.
Let's see how she behaves.
What song is this?
I can sing if I what.
What is it, boss?
Any news on the arms case?
Sorry, we don't have anything yet.
Keep at it.
Big Guy.
–Come here!
–OK.
Have some tea.
–What is it, Mr Hui?
–Eat.
–We've eaten a lot already!
–You can't work if you don't eat!
Hi, Long!
Mr Hui.
Beef jerky.
You did well.
–So-so.
–I left the gun there, you know!
Very clever.
I told him to eat more!
Mr Hui treats us like children!
I'm an old man…
Loyalty is the most
important thing to me.
Is that right or wrong?
We wouldn't respect you otherwise.
Long, if I did something wrong,
how would you treat me?
There are worse people than you.
When you're free,
we'll go to Hawaii for a holiday.
If you like it,
you can move out there.
Leave Hong Kong behind.
I do want to see out
my remaining years…
but I still have
a lot of responsibilities here.
I can't leave.
I just want you to take it easy.
–Siu!
–Morning.
–Mr Hui.
–Hi.
You're all dressed up.
Know who's on your side.
Be careful of him.
Sorry I didn't bring
anything with me.
Don't worry.
Long.
What is it?
Johnny wants to talk to you.
We don't have enough arms
for South America.
We'll get them somewhere else.
No one's tougher than us.
Don't do anything.
Let the restaurant incident die down.
This way, please.
Johnny, can we trust Long?
It's worth a risk.
We need to replace Sam
now that he's dead.
Hi, Johnny. Sorry I'm late.
–Johnny.
–This is Long.
–You know each other already.
–We haven't had a chance to talk.
I'm anti-social.
Have a seat.
I really admire you.
–Are you happy with Mr Hui?
–Yes.
You have to look to the future.
You have the talent to go far.
I make money wherever there's a war.
Many things go out of fashion,
but not wars.
You know how much money I make.
We all know you're successful.
Will you work for me?
I'm loyal to Mr Hui.
That's honourable.
That's what I like about you.
I paid a fortune
to get Jimmy to work for me.
He organized a big deal for me.
But you killed him!
I can only admire your talent.
I won't take revenge.
I respect that.
I came here to be your friend
but I'm not here to discuss business.
Fine. You're honest.
I'll be your friend.
–You got a lot of counterfeit goods.
–All thanks to you.
Who did this?
–Wait till I get that bastard!
–I'll kill his whole family!
GANGSTERS AND POLICEMEN
DIE IN SHOOT-OUT
TRIADS' ILLEGAL GUN TRADING—
SMUGGLERS SUSPECTED
Stop!
You bastard!
Who do you think you are?
–What are you doing?
–Get lost!
Your men killed my partner
at the Wuen Loi Restaurant.
He was my friend.
Your men also killed
many innocent people.
I'm onto you.
I'll arrest you one day, you bastard.
Remember me.
Hey.
This is not the best time.
Leave it.
What a waste!
Was it not big enough?
I'm waiting for a big one.
You know your stuff.
That's expensive.
–How much?
–HK$100,000.
The police doesn't have much money.
HK$20,000.
I'm risking my life.
People are pointing guns at me.
–That's not worth 100,000?
–Spare me.
Take it or leave it.
My mum told me
to stay away from cops.
An address.
Johnny is raiding
Hui's cache tonight.
That bastard is ruthless. Be careful.
Find me at the Jazz Bar
if you find Johnny's arsenal.
OK.
I put your mum into the nursing home.
Thank you.
Go and see her.
I'll go
after I've achieved something.
Hey, your money's in the bucket.
Madam, more flowers for you.
Call the armoury
and ask them to make preparations.
–We need them for tonight.
–Shall we ask the boss?
Say it's for me.
Hello, armoury.
My boss wants you
to prepare some guns.
We'll come down later.
Don't ask so many questions.
–Shall we call more people to help?
–No, it's alright.
You two, go outside.
Someone's stolen an officer's gun.
This is your case.
Don't worry about the arms case, OK?
I've been working on it for so long
and you're telling me to leave it?
Can't you listen just once?
Do you have to shout?
Enjoying the show?
This is my office.
Can't you respect me?
So what?
The whole station is mine! Listen…
Do you have to get so worked up?
If you need a shit,
just go to the toilet!
Hello? Wait a minute. It's Long.
Hello?
I need your help tonight.
You won't regret coming.
OK. I'll come.
I'll get someone to pick you up.
Hurry up.
–Are we raiding my boss' cache?
–Yes, and I want you to kill him.
I won't force you.
I want to know if we can be partners.
I've always admired you.
Either we're in this together
or you can kill me.
No regrets.
I have my own.
It's a raid!
Run!
Come here!
Get the guns!
Hurry!
Load up the car!
Long,
I've done my part,
it's your turn now.
You've already ruined him.
Let the old man go.
Do you think he would let me go?
No.
In this world,
the one with the gun always wins.
The old bastard is in the way.
I have to kill him.
He might not
want to make money, but I do.
His low prices
are pushing down the market.
Don't blame me.
People admire success,
not how you made it there.
Load it up.
It all depends on you.
When Mr Hui gets here,
if you can't do it,
I'll do it.
You know what to do.
Let's go!
Don't move!
Don't come any closer!
Long, you traitor!
How dare you? I'll kill you!
Drop your gun!
Drop it!
Drop your guns.
Drop them.
Drop your guns!
Long…
I know I'll die tonight.
Mr Hui.
You've dropped your guns.
Are you giving up or are you scared?
Drop them.
Drop them!
Drop your guns! Drop them!
Johnny,
it doesn't matter if I die,
but will you let my men go?
–Do you want them all to die?
–It's not up to me.
You do what you want to do.
Johnny, you're smart.
I need to speak to Long.
Is that OK?
What's the use of talking?
Long…
life is like this.
Sometimes you have to do things
you don't want to do.
Like I want to quit but I can't.
I knew this day
would come in this business.
I didn't think you would betray me.
I trusted the wrong person.
There's nothing left to say.
I beg you, please let the men go.
I'm happy to die.
It's better than dying
at the hands of those bastards.
Long, do as I say.
–Mr Hui.
–Shoot.
Shoot!
Just do it!
If you don't kill me, I'll kill you!
–Mr Hui!
–Don't move!
Mr Hui! Mr Hui!
–Boss…
–Kill that bastard!
Kill him!
You go, boss.
–Let me kill him!
–It's not worth it.
–Be careful.
–OK.
Who is he?
How come he didn't shoot me?
I told you to leave this case alone.
Tell me who he is!
–A criminal.
You say he's a criminal,
I hope he's a criminal.
Next time I bump into him,
I won't hold back.
Hold on. Stay where you are!
Legally, I'm not obliged
to tell you anything.
But I have to tell you something.
If I hadn't run out of bullets,
I would have killed a cop.
You're overreacting.
Back at the restaurant…
you did kill a cop.
Yes, I did.
Cops have killed other cops before.
You're wrong.
You should have said, he wasn't
the first cop to sacrifice his life.
Sacrifice?
Is that what you call it?
You better tell me who the cops are
and who the triads are…
and why you want us both dead?
Why do you have so many questions?
You're a cop.
Your job is to obey orders,
not question them!
You want to know why?
You can't always ask why.
Why do we need search warrants
and triads don't?
Why do we have to write reports when
we use a gun and the triads don't?
Why are suspects innocent
until proven guilty
and why does the burden of proof
lie on us, not on them?
Why?
If I knew that, I'd be in your place.
Alright?
I'll say this.
I lost my friend, Lung,
at the restaurant.
I don't care whether I die or not…
but I swear I'll arrest
that bastard Johnny.
God help anybody
that tries to stop me.
Stop!
If something bad happens
because of you…
it won't be enough for you to quit.
I'm shaking!
That's a cop's life for you.
You're never good enough.
I asked myself
if I should do the right thing.
But every time I read the newspaper,
I felt uncomfortable.
I felt I had a responsibility.
After the job,
I forgot about being shouted at.
–And if you didn't solve a case?
–I was suicidal.
–That bad?
–Yes.
You should have given me a better
drawing. It turns out I know him.
He lives at Clearwater Bay.
How can I thank you?
With better drawings.
So?
If Superintendent Pang says he's
a triad, then he's undercover.
If you speak to him,
tell him there's no need
to get killed to solve a case.
–Have you got a cop called Vodka?
–He's called Tequila.
He's a tough cop.
I don't care who he is.
Tell him to back off.
He'll ruin everything.
Do you want to go to another funeral?
Don't worry,
I'll stop him.
And get that export license.
I need that shipment
to find Johnny's cache.
Give me a day, OK?
I'll deal with customs.
–Wait for my call.
–And my Swiss bank account?
It's sorted.
What about the house in Guam?
Does it have a garden?
Don't bother with that.
If it's too dangerous, you can quit.
I'll hold you to that.
I knew you'd be like this.
You know I always do a good job.
It's your birthday today.
Did you forget?
It's for you.
I had forgotten.
Birthdays aren't important
when you don't have a real identity.
Only you know when my birthday is.
Don't you forget it.
What? You're still upset
and you want to get revenge?
What are you?
It's hard to call you a triad.
It's even harder to call you a cop.
What rank are you?
Sergeant?
Inspector? Joker?
Should I salute you?
If you like.
To you, I'm a criminal.
To my mum, I'm a son.
To the triads, I'm a boss.
–Should I salute you?
–You've got the gun.
I'll go and milk a cow if you want.
Sorry, I don't drink milk.
Why do you have so many paper cranes?
Are you lonely?
Do they keep you company?
I've always hated making them.
I make one each time I kill someone.
Do you like them?
I'll make you one.
Thank you.
Who will make yours when you die?
Let's team up
and make one for Johnny Wong.
You make it yourself.
I don't have time.
I'm meeting someone.
I hate going to cops' funerals.
Every time a colleague dies…
I play a song for them.
I don't want to have
to play a song for you.
Go! Johnny Wong's coming!
–How do I get in touch?
–I'll send you a crane.
Take care, mate.
You traitor.
And that cop…
Check the place.
I've been after this bastard!
I'll keep an eye out for you.
No one will dare to make a move.
Take him to hospital!
This is my hospital.
You'll get 24 hour protection.
–I'll be alright.
–Don't worry. It's best to be safe.
Thank you.
Nurse! Nurse! Nurse!
–When did he get hurt?
–At the building site.
Can you get a doctor?
They'll take care of you first.
–Is it our turn yet?
–Sit down!
It's not your turn yet!
–This is a deep wound.
–Nurse, can I speak to you?
I don't want any record of this.
I don't want
anyone to know he's here.
Siu betrayed you.
He gave your address to Hui's men.
I'll deal with him.
–I can handle it.
–Wait until you're better.
I'll sort him out.
Are you sure it was Siu?
He's been working for the cops
while working for me.
He told me where Hui's cache was.
Bastard!
He must know
where your firearms are.
How could you tell him so much?
I have to kill
that two-faced bastard!
Let me do it.
How much have you told the cops?
There's no point killing me,
I haven't told them anything.
You bastard!
Stop lying!
How come they knew about the raid?
Why me?
It's all about money these days,
not loyalty.
Who can you trust?
Mr Woo, I have a good friend.
It's doesn't matter
if he's good or bad.
We're both in serious danger now.
If you were me, would you save him?
If he was my friend,
I would definitely save him,
whether he's good or bad.
If I was a cop,
I would still save him.
–Then you're a martyr.
–Not me. It's Him up there.
Siu! Siu!
–What happened?
–Are you OK?
–Johnny's arsenal is at…
–Where is it?
–It's at the Maple Hospital.
–Maple?
Siu!
Can you ask my girlfriend
to meet me at the hospital?
Who brought him in?
I brought him in.
I'm Inspector Yuen, CID. I'll
register him later. I'm responsible.
Hold on.
Sorry.
–How's his blood pressure?
–Low.
80/50.
And his pupils?
Somewhat dilated.
Nurse, give him some oxygen.
Boss, that cop took Siu to hospital.
What's happened?
Siu's still alive.
That cop took him to hospital.
He'll grass us up.
–I'll sort him out.
–You?
Don't worry, I'll kill him this time.
Kill that cop, too.
I'm not convinced.
Send some extra men
to help him.
This patient is my witness.
How is his condition?
Luckily,
the lighter stopped the bullet.
–Can he talk?
–He needs to rest.
How are you feeling?
–Cig…
–What?
Cigarette.
The oxygen might explode.
Turn it off. Turn it off.
You're half dead and smoking?
I'm screwed.
I want to prove
I was one of the best before I die.
You've proved it already.
You've done it.
I found that Johnny's arsenal
is in this hospital's basement.
Wasn't I smart this time?
If I solve this case,
I'll pay you the old fee.
I won't live to spend it.
It's up to you to put on a good show.
Come on now.
Don't smoke.
Get some rest.
–Who's been smoking?
–Me.
It's dangerous.
–That's why I put it out.
–Don't do it again.
Time for your injection.
Hey, don't let her inject me.
They might try to kill me.
Don't worry, I'll keep an eye on you.
The man outside gave me this.
–Where are you taking me?
–To a safe place.
I have a colleague here.
–Which room is he in?
–Room 301.
White roses again.
Was there nothing else?
What's the problem?
You're a bad undercover cop.
It's a matter of taste.
White roses every time.
Even my mum knows what's going on.
Where's Siu?
Next door.
–Do you know where the firearms are?
–I forgot!
I don't have time to joke.
Neither do I.
Where are the firearms?
I let Siu go so he could find you.
I've worked hard these five years.
The police are after me.
I'm always worried
about getting exposed.
I'm forced to kill.
I don't care about dying,
I just want to solve the case.
And you're joking with me?
I don't know how to joke.
So what
if you manage to solve the case?
The police will give you money
and a passport,
but where will you go?
Where are you going?
You've got an operation.
If you die,
they won't give you a grand funeral.
I know that.
That's fine, then. Come on.
–What's going on?
–Nothing.
Walk that way.
–Look out for anyone suspicious.
–OK.
Be careful.
Let's go back up.
My colleague is coming.
–Tequila!
–Have you been here long?
Let's talk inside.
Do you have any news?
The morgue has steel reinforcements.
It took almost four months
to build it.
–Siu said that before he died.
–Siu's dead?
I was too late.
I forgot to introduce you.
She's my girlfriend, Teresa Chang.
You've been sending flowers to her.
–The flowers were lovely.
–Thank you.
I picked them randomly.
–She doesn't like them.
–I want to get more.
–Are you not getting on?
–Not really.
Couples argue all the time.
We'll be alright.
Call the Superintendent. Ask him
to come here. Wait for me here.
–How will we signal her?
–With flowers.
–Flowers?
–Yes.
You, send me flowers?
I taught him.
I just picked it up.
Thank you.
I'll send them in 30 minutes.
You're smart enough
to know what to do.
Shall we go?
B2.
Superintendent,
can you come to Maple hospital?
–Are you new?
–Yes.
–What's your name?
–Ng Yue Lum.
–I'd like to see a doctor.
–What's the problem?
Fever.
Who have you got there?
Don't look, he died horribly
with his guts hanging out.
Massive bleeding.
–Wasn't my timing perfect?
–Not bad. Theirs was better.
Teresa Chang, it's your turn.
Let another patient go first.
It's OK, I'm feeling better now.
–You should see a doctor.
–I don't want to!
Stay calm. Don't forget we're cops.
Where are they?
In the morgue.
Look, these four are empty.
J 1, 2, 3, 4.
Are you crazy?
How are we going to get back out?
I've got no intention of leaving.
How's Long? Has his cover been blown?
Everything depends on him.
I hope it's not too dangerous in
the morgue. May God keep him safe.
Tequila's there too.
You haven't even mentioned him!
He's in danger tool
You're so biased!
You're always having a go at him.
You don't understand
nor care about him.
I didn't realize you still cared.
Really.
–What did he say?
–He said to wait for his signal.
When I get the flowers,
we evacuate the patients.
How come
you can't even open a door?
Why don't you try? Open it.
What are you complaining about then?
You're not helping!
This is not even your case!
It's not my case?
I got this far. I think
it has everything to do with me.
If all cops were as selfish as you,
Hong Kong would be dead.
Don't take it out on me.
Let me open the door.
Which year did you graduate?
Who was your teacher?
Are you testing me?
I'd just like to ask your teacher
how he managed to produce
such a stubborn cop.
Pang said you don't waste bullets.
Are you testing me?
What the hell!
We killed Siu
but Long and that cop have gone.
Call all units now.
Sir…
Evacuate the patients!
I found it in my pocket.
Get the team.
They're in the basement.
Sorry, it was our fault.
There are
two groups of people I hate…
cops and those
who kill their bosses.
You bastard.
If your information is wrong,
it'll cause panic
and patients could be hurt.
–Who's responsible?
–I am.
I'm in charge here.
The patients are my responsibility.
I won't evacuate
unless there's a serious threat.
What's going on?
Calm down!
Return to your rooms!
Doctor, don't you have to evacuate
if there's a fire alarm?
You said it was secure!
–Turn the coolant on.
–OK.
We can't fail now.
We have no choice.
We don't have much time.
We have to move them.
That bastard.
It's all up to me.
No one can challenge me.
–What?
–Evacuate the patients!
Over there!
It's just a drill.
It's just a fire drill.
It's OK. Everyone stay calm.
It's OK.
It's a false alarm!
Everyone back to your rooms.
Are you crazy? Don't get in our way!
I'll arrest you!
–I'll sue you for abuse of power.
–There are 300 lives at stake here.
I'll kill you!
Be careful.
Quickly!
–Why don't you take them out?
–Everyone's gone.
Get some help!
Boss, all the men are here.
We must evacuate!
–Doctor?
–Carry on!
The cops are up to something.
–Cut the mains. Stop them.
–OK.
Get the babies!
–They're shooting!
–I know.
–You've caused all this!
–Take care of the patients!
Doctor! Doctor!
Stop! I'll shoot!
Come back! Come back!
Get out!
Did you hear me?
It's OK, CID!
Come back!
Police! Drop your gun!
The police have us surrounded.
Take the patients hostage.
They're just ordinary people
underneath their uniforms.
They've got guns, so have we.
They've only got .38s.
Hurry!
Get down!
Don't move!
Get out!
Put the babies down! Get out!
Put the babies down!
Hurry!
Did you hear me?
Lower your voice!
You'll scare them.
Be good. Don't be scared.
Now he wants to blow up the hospital.
–How will you send the flowers?
–I already did.
Telepathy?
She doesn't realize
that I go through hell for her.
Do you think you can escape?
Long…
I admired you.
I treated you as a friend.
I never imagined you'd betray me.
You disappoint me.
You'll be even more disappointed
when I kill you.
I've been after you.
Why the hospital?
Do you like killing the innocent?
I like the risk.
I've got hundreds of hostages.
I've got an arms cache down there.
I'll detonate it
if you make me angry.
–Try it.
–I mean it.
My next arsenal
will be in a police station.
That'll be fun.
There are over 100 patients
being held hostage.
The police haven't been able-
–I'm scared!
–Get down!
Unit 3… No filming!
The wall's cold.
The morgue must be on the other side.
Good, that's handy.
Just leave me in there if I die.
There are two of us here.
There's no time for self-pity.
I wanted to protect the innocent.
But I've had to kill them as well.
I wanted to be a regular cop.
There were no other positions.
Undercover in the triads.
Keep quiet.
–Do you have any dreams?
–I do.
I want to move to Antarctica.
It's freezing there. You like that?
At least I can come out of the dark.
There's daylight
24 hours a day there.
You can't just talk about it.
I have dreams, too.
I wanted to be in a band
but I became a cop.
All you can do is laugh. Come on.
Don't move!
The guy's a cop.
Johnny, you're winning.
Why not let the patients go?
It's just us against the cops.
Are you scared?
I'm not scared.
I've been around a long time so
I know when things have gone too far.
I don't care.
Stop!
–Don't move!
–Go and have a look!
Don't move!
Get down!
I've got the cop!
Bring him here!
Go!
Police! Get down!
Get down!
Go!
Help the patients!
Hurry!
I have to save the babies!
I'll go with you.
–There's so many of them.
–Quiet! You'll wake them.
–Put cotton wool in their ears.
–Is that necessary?
Be careful! I'm a cop!
Do you want as many babies as this?
I'm not a machine!
Smile.
–Are you ready?
–Yes.
Inspector Yuen.
Help Madam. Get the babies out.
Over there.
Be careful.
I'm going to help Long.
You're in charge here. Be careful.
Upstairs.
Madam, the exit's blocked!
He's one of us!
Get the babies!
–Take the curtains down.
–Yes, Madam.
Be careful.
Help!
–I'm dropping the baby!
–Pass it to me!
–Over there.
–Put them in a safe place.
Mun! It's OK! Mun!
Did you get shot?
–Can you hold on?
–Yes.
Go!
I just killed a cop.
No…
–I'm sure he was a cop.
–He wasn't!
He had a badge!
You were hallucinating!
How many times do I have to say it?
He wasn't a cop!
You're your own worst enemy.
If you can't conquer your fears,
how can you beat anyone else?
Take this!
I killed a cop
in the course of this investigation.
Pang told me.
I didn't realize until afterwards.
How did you feel?
Worse than you did then.
–Then he really was a cop?
–Yes!
Shit!
Go and save the babies!
Be careful.
–Catch!
–OK, pass it to me!
No reaction.
Whose baby is this?
Go and help!
Pass it to me!
Catch!
Is this your baby?
Someone's coming!
You bitch!
We need help up here
to save the babies!
–I'll go.
–I'll deal with him.
Be careful.
Don't be scared. We'll hide in here.
Quickly!
Careful.
Go quickly.
I left one of the babies!
OK, I'll get it.
–Look after her.
–Be careful!
Put these all around the hospital.
Madam, hold on!
Quiet now.
Quiet now. Be good.
Be quiet!
Be good. I'll rap to you.
I know I can't rap…
so you don't have to pretend.
Don't watch.
Baby…
Sorry.
All this bloodshed
was in a good cause.
You're so cute.
Nurse.
Take the patients out.
Go.
Quickly!
No!
Are you crazy?
Why did you kill them?
I'll kill whoever gets in my way.
Always getting in my way…
–Shoot!
–Drop it!
Shoot!
I'll blow this place up.
You want to take that risk?
We'll all die together.
I can't be beaten. You won't win.
No!
It's too dangerous.
Get the baby out.
You'll die. Come with me!
I'm a cop, too.
Don't go!
Get the injured out of here.
We're going for a ride.
You saved the day.
Thank you.
Over there!
–Tequila, any more babies?
–Thank you!
–My baby!
Thank you!
–Are you OK?
–Where's Long?
Upstairs.
There's someone upstairs.
Get up!
Drop your guns!
Drop your guns.
Drop them!
Move back!
The hard boiled cop.
You're still here.
We both lost some men.
We're about even.
I'll win if I kill him.
Shoot!
Shoot.
I'll blow his head off.
Don't shoot.
You're impotent.
I thought you were a superhero
but you're just an ordinary man.
Slap yourself.
And the other side.
Say, “I'm impotent.”
I'm impotent.
Kneel down.
Drop your gun.
How often does someone
humiliate you like this?
A .38.
Take your trousers off.
You bastard, eat shit.
It's for you.
I had forgotten.
Birthdays aren't important
when you don't have a real identity.
Only you know when my birthday is.
Don't you forget it.
–Do you have any dreams?
–I do.
I want to move to Antarctica.
It's freezing there. You like that?
At least I can come out of the dark.