3 billon human lives
ended on August 29th, 1997.
The survivors of the nuclear fire
called the war Judgment Day.
They lived only
to face a new nightmare,
the war against the machines.
The computer which
controlled the machines, Skynet,
sent two terminators
back through time.
Their mission: to destroy the leader
of the human resistance:
John Connor. My son.
The first terminator was programmed
to strike at me.
in the year 1984,
before John was born.
It failed.
The second was set to strike
at John himself,
when he was still a child.
As before, the Resistance
was able to send a lone warrior.
A protector for John.
It was just a question of which one
of them would reach him first.
I need your clothes, your boots,
and your motorcycle.
You forgot to say 'please'.
Take it.
You can't leave and take
the man's wheels, son.
Now get off before I put you down.
That's it, goddammit!
Art 31 David show me code 6
at the 6th street bridge in Santa F
on an electrical disturbance.
1 0-4. 31 David.
John! Get in there
and clean up that pigsty of yours.
Your foster-parents
are kinda dicks, huh?
I swear I've had it
with that goddamn kid.
Won't even answer me anymore.
- Honey. move!
Would you get off your butt
and help me?
Todd.
- What?
He hasn't cleaned that room of his
in a month.
Oh. it's an emergency.
Hang on, I'll get right on it.
John! Come on get your ass inside,
do what your mother tells you!
She's not my mother. Todd !
This next patient is interesting.
Been following the case for years.
29-year-old female. . .
...diagnosed as acute
schizo-affective disorder.
Depression, anxiety, violent
acting-out, delusions of persecution.
The delusional architecture
is fairly unique.
She believes in a machine
called a ''terminator'',
which looks human of course. was
sent back through time to kill her.
That's original!
And also that the father of her child
was a soldier.
sent back to protect her.
- No.
He was from the future too.
The year 2029,
if I remember correctly.
Here we are.
Morning, Sarah.
Good morning, Dr. Silberman.
How's the knee?
Fine, Sarah.
She stabbed me in the kneecap
with my pen a few weeks ago.
Repeated escape attempts.
Let's move on, shall we?
I don't like to see the patients
disrupting their rooms.
See that she takes her Thorazine.
- Ill take care of it.
Time to take you meds, Connor.
You take it.
You gotta be good.
You're up for review this afternoon.
I'm not taking it.
I don't want any trouble.
- Ain't no trouble. . .
Yeah, zap her.
Last call, sugar.
Sweet dreams.
Are you the legal guardian
of John Connor?
That's right.
What's he done now?
Could l speak with him, please?
Could if he was here.
He took off on his bike.
So he could be anywhere.
Do you have a photo of John?
Yeah, sure. Hold on.
You gonna tell me
what this is about?
I just need to ask him
a few questions.
He's a good looking boy.
Mind if l keep this picture?
- No. go on.
There was a guy here
looking for him too.
Big guy on a bike. Has that
got something to do with this?
No. l wouldn't worry about him.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Please insert your stolen card now!
PIN number...
Hurry up,
this is taking too long!
Go baby, go baby...
Alright! PIN number. . .
Who did you learn this from?
- My mom.
My real mom, l mean.
Withdraw 300 bucks.
Come on, baby. come on. . .
It worked !
Easy money! Come on!
Yeah!
- Piece of cake!
That her?
Yes.
So she's pretty cool, huh?
- No. she's a complete psycho.
That's why she's up at Pescadero,
the mental institute.
Tried to blow up
the computer factory,
but got shot and arrested.
- Oh shit.
She's a total loser.
Come on,
lets go spend some money!
Sarah.
Sarah, wake up.
Kyle?
You're dead.
Where's our son, Sarah?
They took him away from me.
He's the target now.
- l know!
He's alone.
You have to protect him.
I know.
You tell me how l am supposed
to do that.
He doesn't even
believe me anymore.
I've lost him.
You're strong, Sarah.
Stronger than you ever thought.
- No.
On your feet, soldier!
I love you. I always will.
I need you.
- Ill always be with you.
Remember the message?
''The future is not set.
There is no fate
but what we make for ourselves.''
Stay with me.
There's not much time left
in the world, Sarah.
Kyle, don't go!
Kyle!
It's like a giant strobe light,
burning right to my eyes.
Somehow l can still see.
Look,
we know the dream's the same
every night. Why do we have to...
Please continue.
The children look like burnt paper,
black,
not moving.
Then the blast wave hits them...
...and they fly apart like leaves.
Dreams about the end of the world
are very common, Sarah.
It's not a dream, you moron.
It's real.
I know the date it happens!
- I'm sure it feels real to you.
On August 29th, 1997 it's going to
feel pretty fucking real to you too!
Anybody not wearing
two million sunblock
is gonna have
a real bad day, get it?
God, you think
you're safe and alive.
You're already dead. Everybody.
Him. You. You're dead already!
This place,
everything you see, is gone.
You're the one living
in a fucking dream, Silberman!
Because I know it happens.
It happens!
I feel much better now.
Clearer.
Yes. Your attitude has been
much improved lately.
It has helped to have a goal,
something to look forward to.
And what is that?
You said that if I showed
improvement after six months,
you would transfer me
to the minimum security wing
and l could have visitors.
Well, it's been six months.
I was looking forward
to seeing my son.
I see.
Let's go back
to what you were saying
about those terminator machines.
Now you think they don't exist?
They don't exist.
I know that now.
But you've told me
on many occasions
about how you crushed one
in a hydraulic press.
If I had, there would have been
some evidence.
They would've found
something at the factory.
I see.
So you don't believe anymore
that the company covered it up?
No, why would they?
Let's try a new position.
Right, there.
The neuronal sensors are correct,
because it works.
The neurons are all centered.
Maybe the inhibitors failed.
Mr. Dyson?
The materials team. . .
...is running another series
this afternoon, and you have to. . .
You have to sign it out.
Come on. Ill get it.
I know I haven't been here that long,
but I was wondering if you know...
Know what?
Well if you know,
where it came from.
I asked the same question once.
Know what they told me?
''Don't ask.''
Hello, Mr. Dyson. - How's it going?
- Okay.
Insert key.
Left and three, two, one, turn.
How are wife and kids?
- Great, thanks.
So what do you think, Doctor?
I've shown improvement,
haven't I?
Well, Sarah, here's the problem:
I know how smart you are.
You're just telling me
what I want to hear.
I don't think you believe
what you're telling me.
If I put you in minimum security
you'll just try to escape again.
You have to let me see my son.
Please.
He's in great danger.
He's naked without me.
If I could just make a phone call.
- Im afraid not. Not for a while.
I don't see any choice but to
recommend to the review board
that you stay here
for another six months.
You son of a bitch!
You don't know what you're doing!
- Straighten her now!
Model citizen.
You just missed him.
He left fifteen minutes ago.
I think he said he was going to
the Galleria. - Yeah.
The Galleria?
I'll get some quarters.
I'll be back, alright?
Girls, do you know John Connor?
- No.
You know this guy?
No, l don't know him.
John.
- Not now.
There's this cop scoping for you,
check it out.
Split, man, just go.
- Yeah.
I think I saw the kid
you're looking for.
You're not supposed to be here!
Get down!
Come on!
Goddamn!
Okay, time out. Stop the bike!
Come on, stop the bike.
Don't take this the wrong way.
You're a terminator, right?
Yes. Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101 .
Holy shit! You're really real!
You're like a machine underneath,
but sort of alive outside?
I'm a cybernetic organism.
Living tissue
over a metal endoskeleton.
This is intense.
Get a grip, John.
You're not here to kill me.
I figured that out for myself.
So what's the deal?
My mission is to protect you.
Yeah? Who sent you?
You did.
35 years from now
you reprogrammed me
to be your protector here,
in this time.
This is deep.
This other guy,
he's a terminator like you, right?
Not like me. A T-1000.
Advanced prototype.
You mean more advanced
than you are?
Yes. A mimetic polyalloy.
What does that mean?
Liquid metal.
Where are we going?
- We have to get out of the city.
And avoid the authorities.
I gotta stop by my house
and pick up some stuff. - Negative.
The T-1000 will definitely
try to reacquire you there.
You sure?
- l would.
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks
but I gotta warn them.
Shit! You got a quarter?
Hello?
Janelle? It's me.
John?
- Yeah.
Is everything alright?
- Sure.
Are you alright?
- Im fine.
John, it's late. l was
beginning to worry about you.
If you hurry, we can have dinner
together. I'm making beef stew.
Something's wrong.
She's never this nice.
Where are you?
What's the goddamn dog
barking at?
Shut up,
you piece of shit!
The dog's barking.
Tell the kid
to get rid of that mutt.
Honey, it's late.
Could it already be there?
Are you okay?
I'm right here. I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
What's the dog's name?
- Max.
Janelle, what's wrong with Wolfy?
I can hear him barking.
Is he okay?
Wolfy's fine, honey.
Where are you?
Your foster-parents are dead.
I need a minute here.
You're telling me that this thing
can imitate anything it touches?
Anything it samples
by physical contact.
Can't be real!
It could disguise itself
as a pack of cigarettes?
Only objects of equal size.
Why not a bomb
or something to get me?
It can't form complex machines.
Guns, explosives have chemicals,
moving parts.
It doesn't work that way.
But it can form solid metal shapes.
Like what?
- Knives and stabbing weapons.
These were taken
by a video surveillance camera
at the West Highland police station
in 1984.
He killed 17 police officers
that night.
Men with families.
Children.
These were taken
at a mall in Reseda. Today.
Ms. Connor, we know
you know who this guy is.
Look, l just sat here
and told you your son is missing,
that the foster-parents
have been murdered.
We know this guy's involved.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
Don't you care?
We're wasting our time.
Let's go.
Sorry, guys. She's just grown
more and more disconnected
from reality as time goes on.
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
If she clears at all and can give us
anything, Ill call you. - Sure.
Douglas, take her
back to her room, please. - Yes. sir.
Come on, let's go.
We spent a lot of time
in Nicaragua and places like that.
For a while she was
with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy,
running guns.
Then there were some other guys.
She'd shack up with anybody
she could learn from,
so she could teach me
how to be this great military leader.
Then she gets busted and it's like:
''Sorry kid. your mom's a psycho.
Didn't you know?''
Everything Ive been brought up
to believe is all bullshit.
I hated her for that.
But everything she said was true.
She knew.
And nobody believed her.
Not even me.
We gotta get her out of there.
- Negative.
The T-1000's highest
probability for success will be
to copy her and wait
for you to make contact.
Great. What happens to her?
The subject being copied
is terminated.
Why didn't you tell me?
We gotta go now!
Negative.
It's not a priority.
Fuck you.
She's a priority to me!
Goddammit!
What's your problem?
Help!
- This does not help our mission!
Help me! Get this psycho off of me.
Let me go!
Why did you do that?
Because you told me to.
What?
You have to do what I say?
One of my mission parameters.
Prove it.
Stand on one foot.
Cool! My own terminator.
You okay, kid?
Take a hike, bozo.
Let's get out of here.
- What?
Fuck you, little dipshit.
Dipshit?
Put your leg down.
Did you call moi a dipshit?
Just trying to help this punk.
Grab this guy.
Now who's the dipshit,
you jock douchebag?
Put the gun down! Now!
Get out of here!
Come on, let's split!
You were gonna kill that guy!
Of course. Im a terminator.
Listen to me carefully, okay?
You're not
a terminator anymore. Alright?
You got that?
You just can't go round
killing people! - Why?
What do you mean ''why''?
'Cause you can't!
Why?
- Because you just can't, okay?
Trust me on this.
Look, Im gonna go get my mom.
And I order you to help me.
You have a Sarah Connor here?
- You're running kind of late.
They've been in there for an hour.
Hold on a second, Ill buzz you in.
Oh, here come your friends now.
Hey Gwen, you want some coffee?
- No. thanks.
How about a beer?
- Yeah, right.
I got a Full House.
- That's good.
Must be my lucky day.
Yeah, l think you're right
about number 24.
Increase the medication
to 250 milligrams.
Same time?
- Yeah.
You broke my arm !
There's 215 bones
in the human body. That's one.
Now don't move!
What are you gonna do?
Why do we stop now?
You gotta promise
you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
Right.
- Swear.
What?
Just put up your hand and say
''I swear l won't kill anyone.''
I swear l will not kill anyone.
- Alright. Let's go.
Visiting hours is 10 to 4.
Monday through Friday.
What are you doing?
You son of a bitch! You shot me!
He'll live.
Son of a bitch!
Let's all try to remain calm.
- Open it or he'll be dead!
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
Open the door!
- It ain't gonna happen.
Take it easy, Sarah.
It won't work. Sarah.
You're no killer.
You're already dead, Silberman.
Everybody here dies.
So don't fuck with me!
Open the door.
Back off!
Get back or I'll pump him
full of this shit. I swear!
Don't move!
Drop the shit!
Do it! Do it!
Get in the office!
On the floor! Face down! Not you!
Open the door!
On the floor! Hold it open!
Face the wall!
Get her!
Come on, open it!
Come on!
She just broke it off.
- Open it.
Let's go around. come on!
Move it!
No!
Mom! Wait!
Help her.
- Wait here.
He'll kill us all!
Mom, are you okay?
Come with me,
if you want to live.
It's okay. Mom.
He's here to help.
Go!
What the fuck is going on?
Get down!
Out of the car!
Right now!
I'm out.
Come on!
- Here.
Reload !
Next one.
Hang on!
Ready!
Here, drive!
There's nobody behind us.
Are you alright?
- Yeah.
Can you even see anything?
I see everything.
Cool.
Come here.
I said I was okay.
John, it was stupid of you
to go there.
You have to
be smarter than that.
You almost got yourself killed.
What were you thinking?
You cannot risk yourself,
even for me, do you understand?
You're too important!
You understand?
I had to get you
out of that place. I'm sorry.
I didn't need your help.
I can take care of myself.
What's wrong with your eyes?
Nothing.
So what's your story?
You okay?
- Fine.
Say, that's a nice bike.
Hey, watch it, lug nuts.
Listen,
you know what you are doing?
I have detailed files
on human anatomy.
- l bet.
Makes you a more efficient killer,
right? - Correct.
Does it hurt when you get shot?
I sense injuries. The data
could be called pain.
John, help me with the light.
Will these heal up?
- Yes.
Good. If you can't pass for human,
you're not much good to us.
How long do you live,
I mean ''last'', whatever?
120 years with
my existing power cell.
Can you learn stuff you
haven't been programmed with?
So you can be. . .
you know. more human?
Not such a dork all the time?
My CPU is a neural-net processor.
A learning computer,
that Skynet presets to READ
only when we are sent out alone.
Doesn't want you
to do too much thinking.
No.
Can we reset the switch?
Rotate the two locking cylinders
counterclockwise.
Do it.
Now open the port cover.
Pull to break the seal.
Good. Now remove
the shock damping assembly.
You can now access the CPU.
Do you see it?
- Yes.
Pull the CPU by its base tap.
Pull.
Can you see the pin switch?
No!
Out of my way, John!
- Don't kill him!
''It''. John, not ''him''.
Okay, ''it''. But we need ''it''.
Listen to me. Listen.
We're better off on our own.
He's the only proof of
the future, the war and that.
Maybe.
I don't trust it.
But he's my friend, alright?
You don't know what it's like
to kill these things.
If something goes wrong,
this could be our last chance.
If I'm supposed to
be this military leader,
maybe you start listening
to my ideas once in a while.
'Cause if my own mother won't,
how do you expect anyone else to?
Alright, play it your way.
Was there a problem?
No problem.
None whatsoever.
Are we learning yet?
We have to get as far away
from the city as possible.
Just head south.
Keep it under 65.
We don't want to be pulled over.
Affirmative.
No, no, no.
You got to listen to
the way people talk.
You don't say ''affirmative''
or some shit like that.
You say ''No problemo''.
If someone comes up to you
with an attitude, you say ''Eat me''.
And if you want to shine them
on. it's ''Hasta la vista, baby''.
Hasta la vista, baby.
Or ''Later, dickwad''.
If someone gets upset
you say ''Chill out''.
Or do combinations.
Chill out, dickwad.
You're getting it.
No problemo.
You got any cash?
- l got a couple of hundred bucks.
I'll give you half.
Mom!
Get some food.
No sense of humor.
And that's another thing:
lighten up a bit.
This severe routine is getting old.
You're acting like such a geek.
Smile once in a while.
Smile?
Yeah. You know, smile.
Watch.
Hi. Nice place you got here.
How's business?
Gimme a break.
Okay. Bad example.
See that guy over there?
That's a smile.
That's good.
You could practice
in front of a mirror or something.
Want some of my fries?
Do you need any help?
No.
Got you!
- No, you didn't!
- You didn't!
We're not gonna make it, are we?
People. I mean.
It's in your nature
to destroy yourselves.
Yeah. Major drag, huh?
I need to know
how Skynet gets built.
Who's responsible?
The man responsible
is Miles Bennett Dyson.
Who is that?
The director of special projects at
Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
Why him?
In a few months he creates a
revolutionary microprocessor.
Go on. Then what?
In three years Cyberdyne
will become the largest supplier
of military computer systems.
Stealth bombers are upgraded
with Cyberdyne computers.
Becoming unmanned,
they fly
with a perfect operational record.
The Skynet funding bill is passed.
The system goes on-line
on August 4th, 1997.
Human decisions are removed
from strategic defense.
Skynet begins to learn
at a geometric rate.
It becomes self-aware at 2: 14 a.m.
eastern time, August 29.
In a panic,
they try to pull the plug.
Skynet fights back.
Yes. It launches its missiles
against targets in Russia.
Why Russia?
They're our friends now.
Because Skynet knows
that the Russian counterattack
will eliminate its enemies here.
- Jesus.
How much do you know
about Dyson?
I have detailed files.
I want to know everything.
What he looks like.
Where he lives. Everything.
Miles!
You going to work all day?
- Im sorry, baby.
This thing
is kicking my ass.
It's Sunday. You promised to take
the kids to Raging Waters today.
I can't. I'm on a roll.
This is gonna blow 'em away.
It's a neural-net processor.
I know. You told me.
It thinks and learns like we do.
It's superconducting
at room temperature.
Other computers are just
pocket calculators by comparison.
Why is that so important?
I need to know,
'cause sometimes I feel like
I'm going crazy here.
Baby. I am this close.
Come here.
Imagine a jet airliner
with a pilot that never gets tired,
never makes mistakes,
never shows up with a hangover.
Meet the pilot.
Why did we get married?
Have children? You don't need us.
Your heart and your mind
are in here.
But it doesn't love you like we do.
I'm sorry. Really.
How about spending some time
with your other babies?
Raging Waters?
- Yeah!
Wait in the car.
Enrique?
You here?
Pretty jumpy, Connor.
What about you?
Always on the lurk.
Good to see you, Connor.
- l promised to make it back.
Man, l knew it.
Good to see you.
Yolanda. Get out here, we got
company. And bring some tequila!
Oye. Big John?
Que pasa?
- What's up?
Who's your friend?
- He's cool.
He's with me. He is Uncle Bob.
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
Uncle Bob. huh?
Okay.
How are you?
How are you? You've gotten big.
Drink?
Uncle Bob?
Sarahlita, you pretty famous.
All over the TV. Pictures of
you. John, your big friend here.
Cops are going nuts looking for you.
Take the kid, honey, will you?
I just came for my stuff.
I need clothes, food,
and one of your trucks.
How about the fillings out of
my fucking teeth? - Now.
You two, you're on weapons detail.
- Come on. Lets go.
One thing about my mom,
she always plans ahead.
Excellent.
Nothing down here.
This is the best truck I got,
but the starter is gone.
You got the time to change it out?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna wait till dark
to cross the border.
Enrique, it's dangerous for you here.
You get out tonight too, okay?
- Sure.
Just drop by any time
and totally fuck up my life.
See. I grew up in places like this,
so l thought
that's how people lived:
riding around in helicopters,
learning how to blow shit up.
But then, when my mom got busted,
I got put in a regular school.
The other kids were into Nintendo.
Are you ever afraid?
No.
Not even of dying?
You don't feel any emotion about it
one way or another?
No.
I have to stay functional
until the mission is complete.
Then it doesn't matter.
Yeah. l have to stay functional too.
I'm ''too important''.
That's definitely you.
Most of the guys my mom
hung round with were geeks.
But there was this one guy.
He was kinda cool.
He taught me engines.
Hold here.
Mom screwed it up, of course.
She'd always tell
them about Judgment Day
and me being this world leader.
And that'll be all she wrote.
Torque wrench, please.
- Here.
I wish l could've met my real dad.
You will.
Yeah. l guess.
When Im like, 45, I think.
I'll send him back
through time to 1984.
He hasn't even been born yet.
It messes with your head.
The other bolt.
Here.
Mom and him
were only together one night.
She still loves him. I guess.
I see her crying sometimes.
She denies it totally, of course.
Like she got something
stuck in her eye.
Why do you cry?
You mean people?
- Yeah.
I don't know.
We just cry, you know.
When it hurts.
Pain causes it?
No, it's different.
It's when there's nothing wrong
but you hurt anyway.
You get it?
- No.
Alright! My man!
No problemo.
Gimme five.
Put out your hand like this.
Come on.
Alright. Now hit me.
Gimme five. Do the same thing.
- Alright!
Okay, that's good.
Up high. Up high.
Five low.
Too slow.
Just kidding.
One more time.
Watching John with the machine,
it was suddenly so clear.
The Terminator would never stop.
It would never leave him,
never hurt him,
never shout at him
or get drunk and hit him,
or say it was too busy
to spend time with him.
It would always be there.
And it would die to protect him.
Of all the would-be fathers
who came and went.
This thing, this machine,
was the only one who measured up.
In an insane world,
it was the sanest choice.
She said you go south with him.
She'll meet you tomorrow.
- Mom !
Mom! Wait!
''No fate.''
No fate but what we make.
My father told her this.
I mean. I made him memorize it. Up
in the future, as a message to her.
Never mind.
Now okay,
the whole thing goes:
''The future is not set.
There is no fate
but what we make for ourselves.''
She intends to change the future.
Yeah, l guess.
Oh shit!
Dyson.
Yeah, gotta be!
Miles Dyson!
She's gonna blow him away!
Come on! Let's go!
This is tactically dangerous.
- Drive faster.
The T-1000 has
the same files that I do.
It knows what I know.
It might anticipate this move.
I don't care. We've gotta stop her.
Killing Dyson might actually
prevent the war. - I don't care!
Haven't you learnt anything yet?
Why you can't kill people?
Look, maybe you don't care
if you live or die.
But everybody's not like that!
We have feelings.
We hurt. We're afraid.
You gotta learn this stuff.
I'm not kidding. Its important.
Danny, l told you
to go to bed like your sister.
Just a couple of minutes, Mom.
Danny, your time is up.
Come brush your teeth
and get to bed.
Danny, just go!
Oh my God !
Just take Danny and go. Run!
Oh, Jesus. Miles.
Nobody fucking move!
Don't hurt my daddy!
Get on the floor!
Fucking down! Now!
Get out of the way!
Don't hurt him!
Get on the floor! Fast!
Just let the boy go.
Shut up! Shut up!
It's all your fault!
- What?
I'm not gonna let you do it.
Shit, we're too late.
Check them.
Look at me. Mom.
Are you hurt?
Look at me.
I almost. . .
It'll be okay.
We'll figure something out, okay?
Promise.
You came here to stop me?
Yes, l did.
I love you. John.
I always have.
I know.
Clean penetration.
No shattered bone.
Hold here. Compression
should stop the bleeding.
Who are you?
Show him.
Danny, l want you to come with me.
Show me your room.
Oh, my God !
Now listen to me very carefully.
Dyson listened while
the Terminator laid it all down.
Skynet. Judgment Day,
the history of things to come.
It's not every day that you find out
you're responsible
for 3 billion deaths.
He took it pretty well.
I feel like Im gonna throw up.
You're judging me
on things l haven't even done yet.
How were we
supposed to know?
Yeah. Right.
How were you supposed to know?
Fucking men like you
built the hydrogen bomb.
Men like you thought it up.
You think you're so creative.
You don't know what it's like
to create something.
To create a life.
To feel it growing inside you.
All you know how to create
is death and destruction. - Mom!
We need to be a little more
constructive here, okay?
We still have to
stop this from happening.
But I thought...
Aren't we changing things?
Changing the way it goes?
That's right!
There's no way I'm gonna
finish the processor. Not now.
Forget it. Im out of it.
I quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
- Not good enough.
No one must follow your work.
- Right, then...
We have to destroy the stuff
at the lab. The files, drives...
Everything. Everything here.
Everything! l don't care.
Do you know about the chip?
- What chip?
In a vault at Cyberdyne.
From the other one like you.
The CPU from the first terminator.
Son of a bitch. I knew it!
They told us
not to ask where they got it.
Those lying motherfuckers!
It was radically advanced.
It was smashed, it didn't work.
But it gave us ideas.
Took us in new directions.
Things we'd never...
All my work is based on it.
- It must be destroyed.
Can you get us in, past security?
I think so, yeah.
When?
Now?
The future, always so clear to me,
had become like
a black highway at night.
We were
in uncharted territory now,
making up history as we went along.
Hi.
Carl, right?
Friends from outta town,
thought I'd. . .
...show them around.
You know
the rules concerning visitors.
I need authorization...
I insist.
Don't even think about it.
Takes 2 keys to open the vault.
Turned simultaneously.
The other one is
at the security station.
Gibbons.
Come on, man,
you can't leave the desk like that.
Oh, shit.
My card should access this.
What is it?
- Dammit.
The silent alarms been tripped.
It's neutralized
all the codes in the building.
Nothing'll open anywhere now.
We have to abort.
No.
We do it all the way! Okay?
You guys get started on the lab.
I can open this.
I think it's that guy
from the mall. - It is the guy!
Him and the woman.
Just send everything
you've got in the area.
I have a personal entry code
for the lab that may still work.
It's no good.
- Let me try mine.
John! Fire-in-the-hole!
Wait! You can't go in there!
The fire's set off the halo system !
You have to wait a few minutes,
until the gas clears.
Put this on.
Alright, let's get to work.
All units in the vicinity.
All units able to respond:
A 211 in progress at 2144 Kramer
Street, the Cyberdyne building.
Suspect 1 is white, female.
Identified as: last name Connor.
first name Sarah,
escaped from
Pescadero State Hospital.
Suspect 2: white, male. . .
All the disks in my office. All the
disks in that office over there.
Everything behind my desk.
All the processors on my left.
We'll blow it up with the CP4.
Could l . . .
Excuse me...
Could l borrow that thing?
I worked a lot
of years on this thing.
Give me that location again.
- 2111 , Kramer.
The suspects are armed and
considered extremely dangerous.
Alright,
7-2-5-6.
Yes!
Easy money.
Oh, shit.
Not good. Not good.
How we doing?
- Primal cord is set.
One more barrel.
Two more minutes.
How do we set them off?
- Remote control.
Piece of cake.
We got company.
- Police?
How many?
- All of them, l think.
Go! I'll finish here.
I'll take care of the police.
- Wait, you swore. . .
Trust me.
Hey you at the window,
drop your weapon and place
your hands on top of your head.
That's a damn mini-gun!
Come on! Go!
Go! Go!
Fire!
We go the same time to the left.
One, two, three, go!
Alright.
In order to get that out, you. . .
We got Skynet by the balls now,
don't we? Come on, let's book!
Hold your fire!
Ready to rock?
- Ready.
Time to go. Now.
Take this. They'll use gas.
Get started on the door.
Miles, hand me the detonator.
Mom! Mom !
Shit! She's in the clean room.
There's no way out of there.
Get down!
Here.
I don't know how much longer
I can hold this.
Fall back!
Everybody out!
Move it! Now! Go!
We have a war zone here.
Shut your eyes.
Stay here. Ill be back.
Down on the floor, face down!
On the floor, now!
Okay, drop him !
Here, hold this.
Go!
Get out!
Listen, no matter what happens,
you stay under these vests.
You got it?
- Yeah.
Chopper is coming in!
- Its him.
Stay down!
Hello?
Goddamn,
you alright?
Come on, Mom,
we gotta get out.
Take the shotgun.
- Okay.
Are you hurt?
Holy shit. Come on!
We need your truck.
- Hurry!
Hurry!
- Get in.
What the hell...
I'm bleeding bad !
- Keep pressure on it.
Here, this'll work.
He's gaining !
Step on it!
- This is the vehicle's top speed.
I can get out
and run faster than this!
He's coming up, to the right.
Drive a minute.
- Where the hell are you going?
Take the off ramp.
Hold on!
Don't stop!
Go straight!
Get the hell out of here!
Get out of here. Let's go!
Hasta la vista, baby.
We don't have much time.
Let's go!
Come on, we gotta get out of here!
Get up!
Hand me the shotgun.
Put your weight on me, Mom.
Hurry!
Come on, Mom !
Come on, Mom, get up!
This way. Come on!
Wait.
Wait, no, it's too hot.
Go back!
Run!
- No, we stick together.
John, you gotta go now.
Go now!
- No!
Take these steps. Go.
Help me.
- l got you. Come on.
Grab the chain. Grab it!
Grab it! Go!
Mom! Come on!
Call to John.
No.
I know this hurts.
Call John.
Call to John now.
Fuck you.
John! Help!
John!
Help me.
Out of the way, John!
Shoot!
Down!
Get up.
Come on.
Holy shit!
I need a vacation.
Is it dead?
Terminated.
Will this melt in there?
Yes. Throw it in.
Adios.
And the chip.
It's over.
No.
There is one more chip.
And it must be
destroyed also.
Here!
I cannot self-terminate.
You must lower me into the steel.
No!
I'm sorry, John!
It'll be okay. Stay with us!
I have to go away.
- No don't do it, please don't go.
I must go away. John.
- No.
No, wait.
You don't have to.
Sorry.
No, don't do it. Don't go!
It has to end here.
I order you not to go.
I know now why you cry.
But it's something I can never do.
Goodbye.
The unknown future
rolls toward us.
I face it for the first time
with a sense of hope.
Because if a machine, a terminator,
can learn the value of human life,
maybe we can too.