RAISE THE RED LANTERN
Mother, stop!
You've been talking for three days.
I've thought it over.
Alright, I'll get married.
Good! To what sort of man?
What sort of man? Is it up to me?
You always speak of money.
Why not marry a rich man?
Marry a rich man and you'll
only be his concubine.
Let me be a concubine.
Isn't that a woman's fate?
SUMMER
Miss, looking for someone?
I'm Songlian. We met once, remember?
It's our Fourth Mistress! Please wait.
We sent the bridal sedan for you.
Didn't it arrive?
I walked here myself.
- Let me carry it.
- I can manage.
Wait here. I'll go take a look.
Who are you?
Fourth Mistress, please come in.
So the Fourth Mistress is you!
Yes. I'm the Fourth Mistress!
Bring my suitcase inside.
This is where you will live.
My name is Chen Baishun, the housekeeper.
I am at your service.
Why are there so many red lanterns?
Because you're coming!
Fourth Mistress, this is part of
our family custom.
I'm here to serve you.
You'll get used to it.
Fourt Mistress, we're here to do your hair
and help you change.
Master, congratulations on your wedding.
How was the foot massage?
A woman's feet are very important.
When they're comfortable, she is healthier...
...and better able to serve her man.
Pick up that lantern.
Yes, that one.
Higher...
Look up.
Educated girls are different.
Now, undress and get in bed.
Put out the lights.
What? I have all these lanterns so I can see.
I like it bright and formal.
Who's there?
Third Mistress is sick.
She wants you to come.
I'm in bed.
It's an emergency.
She said you must come.
It can wait till tomorrow.
If something serious happens to her,
we'll be blamed.
Damn it! What is she up to?
I'll have to go see.
Or she won't let me sleep tonight.
The Master is leaving?
Going to the third house?
Yes!
Light the lanterns at the third house!
Fourth Mistress...
According to our custom,
you should visit the other three mistress.
Take your breakfast later.
It's our custom t o have all
meetings and meals here.
The Chen family's customs
go back many generations.
It is important that you obey them.
Kowtow to our ancestors.
First, go to greet the master
at the Third Mistress' house.
It seems they're still asleep.
We'll come back.
First Mistress,
the Fourth Mistress is here to visit.
Big sister.
How old are you?
Nineteen.
I heard you went to university.
For six months.
It's good you're educated.
You'll get used to living here.
Get on well with your sisters.
Serve the Master well.
You can go now.
Such sins. Such sins...
What is she, about 100 years old?
Ancient!
Second Mistress,
the fourth Mistress has come to visit.
Fourth sister is here. Come in!
Second sister.
Do come in.
What a pretty face!
What is your name?
Songlian.
A pretty name, too.
I'm Zhuoyun. Just call me by my name.
You look like a student.
I was at university for six months.
Why did you leave?
My father died.
The family couldn't afford it.
How old was your father?
Fifty three.
So young!
Life is so unpredictable!
Tea, Fourth Mistress.
Where are you from?
Fengcheng.
They grow tea there.
My father was in the tea business.
His shop closed down.
Your mother let you marry
someone from so far away?
She's my stepmother.
I see.
So, how was the foot massage last night?
Is it like that every night?
Silly. You can't have it whenever you wish.
Where the master spends the night...
...that mistress gets o foot massage
and lighted lanterns.
With a new wife as young and pretty, as you...
...I'm afraid I won't be enjoying
these privileges for some time.
But don't underestimate
the importance of this custom.
If you can manage to have
a foot massage everyday...
...you'll soon be running this household.
Yizhen, come meet your Fourth Aunt.
Fourth Aunt!
How useless! I only have a daughter.
It's getting late.
We must visit the Third Mistress.
Sorry. I just keep talking.
Of course you must meet the Third Mistress.
She was a famous opera singer.
She sings well and is pretty too.
But she can be so difficult.
Asking for the Master on your wedding night!
So impolite to you!
Wasn't she sick?
Sick? She's just spoiled!
Has the Master left?
Just now. They're putting out the lanterns.
Let's meet the Third Mistress.
Third Mistress says she isn't feeling well...
...and says she'll meet you another day.
Third Mistress' son, Feilan.
Same age as Miss Yizhen.
Come meet your Fourth Aunt.
Fourth Aunt!
Four Mistress...
...this is Yan'er.
Master says she'll be your maid.
Yan'er, come greet the Fourth Mistress.
Fourth Mistress.
I've seen her before.
Bad tempered, isn't she?
No, she's a good girl.
Quick and hardworking too.
Been here for several years.
No lice in her hair, are there?
I hate lice.
Let the Fourth Mistress take a look.
Kneel down. Let's look at your hair.
What is that smell! Go wash your hair!
Didn't you hear?
I only washed it yesterday.
And wash the clothes I just took off
while you're at it.
Go, quickly!
Or the Fourth Mistress will be angry. Go!
Yan'er!
Why haven't you washed your hair?
The Master favours you and you thought
he'd choose you as a wife.
You as our Fourth Mistress?
You were born to be a servant.
Serve the Fourth Mistress well!
Don't waste your time dreaming!
And don't forget to wash your hair!
Where is Meishan?
The Third Mistress is coming.
Doctor Gao is writing her a prescription.
Here comes third sister.
Third sister, this is our fourth sister.
You haven't met, have you?
Third sister!
Songlian is new here.
Take good care of her.
From now on, you sisters must get
on well with each other.
Let's eat.
Why aren't you eating?
I don't like meat.
What vegetable dishes do we have today?
Master, today we have...
...fragrant mushrooms,
chrysan themum moss hair, bird's nest...
...thrice-fried mushrooms,
five-color vegetables...
...vegetarian hot-pot and also heart of cactus.
According to custom...
...the one with lighted lanterns
can have whatever she likes.
What would you like?
I want spinach and beancurd.
Bring some spinach and beancurd.
Also some young been sprouts.
Fourth Mistress...
Master asks you to wait at the door for instructions.
What instructions?
Please wait outside.
The Master may have instructions before he retires.
But why do we have to wait outside?
It's another old family custom.
All the other mistresses ago.
But I wasn't called before.
Not for nine days after the wedding.
This is your 10th day.
Light the lanterns at the fourth house!
Well?
Lighted lanterns, foot massages.
Dou you like it here?
After a few days, you won't want to leave.
Who is it?
Third Mistress says she's sick again.
She wants the master to come over.
Third sister is asking for you again.
You must go.
Meishan is so impossible!
Go, don't come to me again.
You don't mean that.
Tell the Third Mistress
I won't see her tonight!
What am I to hell her?
Nonsense! What do you mean?
Tell her I'll see her tomorrow!
- Who's singing? Third sister?
- Yes.
She was sick last night but
she's singing at this hour.
She won't let us sleep.
She sings when she's happy,
cries when she's mad.
That bitch! Never mind her!
Third sister, have you recovered?
Did I wake you from your sweet dreams?
Yes, you did.
Good, or you'll sleep till you're silly.
Silly, hardly!
I came up to hear third sister sing.
Do continue.
You want to listen...
...but I don't feel like singing anymore.
You went to hear Meishan sing?
I've spoiled her.
When she's angry, she even curses my ancestors.
Bitch!
I must teach her a lesson.
What? Angry?
Don't be childish.
I'll take you to Wumei Lane today to eat dumplings.
Didn't you say you liked the dumplings there?
You really don't want me to stay?
There are others desperate for a foot massage,
you know.
The Master has left! Blow out the lanterns!
Light the lanterns at the third house!
Yan'er!
Yan'er! Yan'er!
Coming!
Can't you walk faster?
Go away if you don't like working for me.
Don't think because the master touched you.
You can behave this way.
Always pulling a long face?
No, I wouldn't dare.
But any face is better than having none!
Why did you come to me?
Tired of your new wife already?
What's so good about my place?
She's mad at me. Of course it's good here.
You are gentle and you'll sing for me.
Well done!
The more you sing, the better it gets. Again!
Fourth sister, come down here!
I've something to say to you.
Second sister.
You don't look well.
No more lighted lanterns and foot massages...
...are you unhappy?
I don't care. I like being alone.
You don't want to be alone in this family.
No foot massages for a few days and the servants
don't treat you the same way.
The master can come and go as he pleases.
Doesn't he find these customs troublesome?
Lighting lanterns is an old family custom.
It was like this when I arrived.
This is silk from Suzhou.
Have some dresses made with it.
I'm embarrassed.
I should be giving you gifts.
Why?
I thought of this silk when I first saw you.
I wouldn't give it to that singer even
if she paid for it.
Did you see how self-satisfied she was just now?
What is that small room for up above?
It's locked with a big chain.
That house of death?
Don't go there.
Several people have died there.
What people?
Women from past generations.
They hanged there.
Don't ask about this.
Nobody here wants to talk about it.
Visit me when you have time.
Don't go there again.
The Master's out.
He said you shouldn't wait from him.
Let's eat then.
Why is there no spinach and beancurd?
There are too many vegetable dishes already.
Go, bring some pork steamed in lotus leaves.
Yes.
Why so many meat dishes today?
The third house had lighted lanterns yesterday.
Didn't the master remarry recently?
Who knows about these things?
It's up to him.
The house with lighted lanterns sets the menu.
We just follow orders.
Who is it?
Yan'er.
Why are you sneaking around like that?
Third Mistress asks you over to play majong.
Me, play majong? What an ideal!
I won't go!
Fourth sister...
...whe need one more player. Come!
I don't like majong.
Come on. Don't stay in your house all day.
Still angry about the spinach and beancurd?
I couldn't care less.
Good. I knew fourth sister wasn't petty.
Don't like losing your money to me too?
Don't worry. I'll let you win.
Since you put it that way, then I must go.
But no need to let me, win.
Who knows how the game will end?
Good!
This is Doctor Gao, a regular visitor.
He is our family doctor.
His friend, Mr. Wang. This is our Fourth Mistress.
Please sit down.
Let's start.
Our Fourth Mistress was a university student.
I'm only an opera singer.
She plays to win today.
Both of you should be careful.
Come, it's just a game.
Third sister's house is decorated like a stage.
No one can forget their past.
The Master's back.
Why wasn't it announced?
I just came in.
The Master must be tired.
Where is she?
Playing majong with the Third Mistress.
I'll call her.
Never mind.
Why can't she stay in her own house?
Light the lanterns at the second house.
The master's back.
He couldn't find you and went to the second house.
Nevermind. Let's play.
Fourth sister has done Zhuoyun a favour.
She is so lonely.
Lend her the Master for one night.
If you lose money, have her pay you back.
Then you're even.
I heard the Fourth Mistress didn't finish university. Why?
What's the use? I'm just one of the Master's robes.
He can wear it or he can take it off.
Efendim, I want to give you a son.
Meishan was famous for singing this opera.
That was years ago.
AUTUMN
This place must be haunted.
Haunted? Nonsense!
That room on the roof.
Two people hanged there, that's all.
Why?
Need you ask?
They were having illicit affairs.
Who were they?
Nobody you know. Two women from past generations.
Concubines?
Don't talk nonsense!
What is it now?
She's peeping at us.
- Who?
- Yan'er.
What's there to look at.
She can't see anything anyway.
You're always on her side.
I can smell her miles away.
- Who is it?
- Master.
What is it?
The Fourth Mistress' spinach and beancurd is ready.
The other mistresses are waiting.
I'm not going. Ask them to bring it here.
That's not right.
We should go or they'll talk.
Them! What do I care if they talk!
Alright, we'll eat here.
Go, tell them to bring the food here.
The Master asks that you go ahead.
He isn't coming.
The food will be taken to the Fourth Mistress' room.
We don't have this custom here.
Is this not the Fourth Mistress' idea?
Third sister, don't be angry.
Let's eat.
Big sister, let me make this clear.
If my lanterns are lit.
I want my food brought to me too.
You want to be as foolish?
How does that make our big sister feel?
What do I matter? I'm just an old woman.
One of these days,
this family will perish in your hands.
Who is playing the flute?
Our young master.
He came back this morning.
Feipu, son of the First Mistress?
I heard he's always away.
He's very busy.
He's going Yunnan in the morning.
Are you Songlian?
You shouldn't call me by my name.
How should I address you?
Fourth Mistress?
Did the music bring you here?
Go on, don't let me stop you.
Can you play too?
Feipu, come down here!
My mother wants me. I must go.
Yan'er!
Come here.
Did you open my suitcase?
Yes, to tidy up your clothes.
Did you see a flute inside?
Flute? No. Only men play the flute.
You stole it.
Why would I want to steal it?
You're always sneaking about.
Stop pretending.
Don't blame it on me.
Ask the other mistress.
Have I even stolen anything?
Fourth Mistress, I really didn't take your flute!
I didn't!
I didn't take it!
Don't go in! I didn't take your flute!
Then what are you afraid of?
I must take a look!
How dare you light lanterns here!
You're only a servant!
Don't you know the rules here?
Do you know what could happen to you?
I beg you. Don't tell anyone!
Alright, then give me back my flute.
I really didn't take you flute.
Fourth Mistress...
"Songlian"
You've put a curse on me!
You want me to die!
Don't cry.
I shouldn't treat you this way.
I'll forget what you did.
You can't read or write.